<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41126988</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1810-522X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>64</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Zoological studies</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Zool Stud</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Temporal Profile of Histological Changes During the Ovarian Cycle, Secretory Cycle of the Colleteric Gland, and Molt Cycle of the Mantle Cavity in the Mature Externa of the Parasitic Barnacle <i>Polyascus planus</i>.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e13</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e13</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e13</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.6620/ZS.2025.64-13</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Rhizocephalans are a group of parasitic barnacles that parasitize other crustaceans. The adult parasite consists of an external reproductive sac (the externa), which is connected by a stalk to a system of ramifying rootlets (the interna) that infiltrates the host. The mature externa of <i>Polyascus planus</i> undergoes a cycle, with its external color changes from yellow, transiently to yellowish brown as the embryos are developing inside a brood chamber (the mantle cavity), then to brown, and return again to yellow, upon the peak release of larvae. Hence, this cycle of <i>P. planus</i> is called the Yellow-Brown cycle after the distinct changes in color; the mature externa typically cycles 3-4 times before it becomes detached from the host. The objectives of the present study are to establish, based on histological observations, temporal profile of three cycles-the ovarian cycle, secretory cycle of the colleteric gland, and the molt cycle of the mantle cavity-that occur concurrently in the mature externa of <i>P. planus</i> and register the changes in chronological order on the timeline of the Yellow-Brown cycle. First, about 2 days after oviposition (1.7 &#xb1; 0.3 days postoviposition, dpo) during the Yellow stage, secondary vitellogenesis begins - a cohort of early vitellogenic oocytes grows in synchrony with significant and rapid accumulation of yolk bodies inside the developing oocytes. Simultaneously, the follicle and muscle cells undergo large-scale spatial rearrangements. By the time the externa is transitioning from the Yellow to Brown stage (7.7 &#xb1; 0.8 dpo), mature follicles with fully developed oocytes tightly enveloped by a single layer of follicle cells are formed and the muscle cells embedded in the inter-follicular tissue. In the colleteric gland, secretory activity of the epithelia begins 3-4 days after oviposition (3.5 &#xb1; 0.5 dpo), with the formation of the reticulated inner zone of the ovisac throughout the remainder of the Yellow stage and into the Brown stage, followed by the beginning of the secretion of the outer zone when the externa reaches the mid-Brown stage (9.8 &#xb1; 0.5 dpo). Finally, the molt cycle of the mantle cavity is initiated later than the other two cycles, entering early pre-molt (D<sub>1</sub>) when apolysis-separation of the cuticle from the underlying epidermis-first becomes visible about 5 days postmolting (4.7 &#xb1; 0.3 days post-molting, dpm), and reaches late pre-molt (D<sub>2</sub>) with deposition of new cuticle during the transition from the Yellow to Brown stage (8.8 &#xb1; 0.8 dpm). By the time the externa returns to the Yellow stage (0 day post-peak release of larvae, dppr), ovarian follicles are rupturing, ovisacs showing signs for imminent detachment, and cuticles in extensive apolysis (very late pre-molt, D<sub>3-4</sub>). Subsequently, within a span of about three days after the externa reaches the Yellow stage, the mantle cavity molts (1.4 &#xb1; 0.2 dppr), followed by ovulation and ovisac detachment (2.5 &#xb1; 0.3 dppr) and finally deposition of the ovulated ova (oviposition) (3.7 &#xb1; 0.3 dppr) into the mantle cavity. Probable modes of endocrine regulation of these cycles are discussed in detail.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Hsiang-Yin</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and Graduate Program of Biotechnology, National Changhua University of Education, Changhua 500207, Taiwan. E-mail: bicylee@cc.ncue.edu.tw (Lee) E-mail: hsiangyin52@gmail.com (Chen).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Hung-Chang</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Land Crabs Ecology Research Laboratory, Jubei City 302050, Taiwan. E-mail: labuanium@gmail.com (Liu).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toullec</LastName><ForeName>Jean-Yves</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, Facult&#xe9; des Sciences, CNRS, UMR 7144, Adaptation et Diversit&#xe9; en Milieu Marin, Station Biologique de Roscoff, Roscoff, France. E-mail: jean-yves.toullec@sb-roscoff.fr (Toullec).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Chi-Ying</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and Graduate Program of Biotechnology, National Changhua University of Education, Changhua 500207, Taiwan. E-mail: bicylee@cc.ncue.edu.tw (Lee) E-mail: hsiangyin52@gmail.com (Chen).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China (Republic : 1949- )</Country><MedlineTA>Zool Stud</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9889708</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1021-5506</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Molt cycle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ovarian maturation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ovisac formation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parasitism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rhizocephala</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41126988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12537383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6620/ZS.2025.64-13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alvarez F, Bortolini JL, H&#xf8;eg JT. 2010. Anatomy of virgin and mature
externae of Loxothylacus texanus, parasitic on the dark blue crab
Callinectes rathbunae (Crustacea: Cirripedia: Rhizocephala:
Sacculinidae). J Morphol 271:190&#x2013;199. 
doi:10.1002/jmor.10790. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmor.10790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19714752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson DT. 1994. Reproductive system, mating and oviposition, p. 127&#x2013;170. In: Barnacles: Structure, Function, Development and Evolution. Chapman and Hall, London, UK.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrieux N. 1969. Remarques pr&#xe9;liminaires sur la glande de mue de Carcinus mediterraneus infest&#xe9;s par Sacculina carcini. Ann Parasitol Hum Comp 44:83&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5371168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrieux N, Porcheron P, Berreur-Bonnenfant J, Dray F. 1976. D&#xe9;termination du taux d'ecdysone au cours du cycle d'intermue chez le crabe Carcinus maenas; comparaison entre individus sains et parasit&#xe9;s par Sacculina carcini. C R Acad Hebd Seances Acad Sci D 283:1429&#x2013;1432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">828537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrieux N, Porcheron P, Berreur-Bonnefant J. 1981. Etudes quantitatives et qualitatives des ecdysteroides presents en vivo chez le crab Carcinus maenas sain ou parasite par Sacculina carcini. Archs Zool Exp Gen 122:99&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbuzova NA, Lianguzova AD, Iliutkin SA, Laskova EP, Gafarova ER et al.
2023. Functional role of lacunar and muscular systems in the externa of
Peltogasterella gracilis (Cirripedia: Rhizocephala). J Morphol
284:e21635. 
doi:10.1002/jmor.21635. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmor.21635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37708509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bebbington PM, Morgan ED. 1977. Detection and identification of moulting
hormone (ecdysones) in the barnacle Balanus balanoides. Comp Biochem
Physiol B 56:77&#x2013;79.  doi:10.1016/0305-0491(77)90225-5. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0305-0491(77)90225-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">830473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortolini JL, Alvarez F. 2008. Hepatopancreas alteration of the blue crab
Callinectes sapidus by the rhizocephalan barnacle
Loxothylacus texanus. J Invertebr Pathol 99:354&#x2013;356.
 doi:10.1016/j.jip.2008.08.004. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jip.2008.08.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18805422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bresciani J, H&#xf8;eg JT. 2001. Comparative ultrastructure of the root system
in rhizocephalan barnacles (Crustacea: Cirripedia: Rhizocephala). J Morphol
249:9&#x2013;42. 
doi:10.1002/jmor.1039. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmor.1039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11410937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charniaux-Cotton H. 1985. Vitellogenesis and its control in  Malacostracan Crustacea. Amer Zool
 <b>25:</b> 197&#x2013;206. doi:10.1093/
icb/25.1.197. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/icb/25.1.197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/icb/25.1.197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/icb/25.1.197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charniaux-Cotton H, Payen G. 1985. Sexual differentiation, p. 217&#x2013;299. In: The Biology of Crustacea. Bliss DE and Mantel LH (eds) Volume 9, Integument, Pigments and Hormonal Processes, Academic Press, Orlando, Florida.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chassard-Bouchaud C, Hubert M. 1976. On the fine structure of the
regressing ecdysial glands of Carcinus maenas L. (Crustacea Decapoda)
parasitized by Sacculina carcini Thompson. Cell Tissue Res
167:351&#x2013;361.  doi:10.1007/BF00219147. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00219147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1268914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HY, Kang BJ, Sultana Z, Wilder MN. 2018. Molecular cloning of red pigment-concentrating hormone (RPCH) from eyestalks of the whiteleg shrimp (Litopenaeus vannamei): Evaluation of the effects of the hormone on ovarian growth and the influence of serotonin (5-HT) on its expression. Aquaculture 495:232&#x2013;240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HY, Lee CH, Tsai CC, Liu HC, Yang SL et al. 2022. Interaction between
the parasitic barnacle Polyascus planus (Cirripedia: Rhizocephala) and
its brachyuran host Metopograpsus thukuhar during the development of
the externa of the parasite: Control of the gonadal development and vitellogenin
synthesis of the host. Front Mar Sci 9:1073459. 
doi:10.3389/fmars.2022.1073459. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmars.2022.1073459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HY, Toullec JY, Lee CY. 2020. The Crustacean Hyperglycemic hormone
duperfamily: Progress made in the past decade.  Front Endocrinol (Lausanne)
 <b>11:</b> 578958. doi:10.3389/
fendo.2020.578958. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2020.578958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2020.578958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2020.578958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7560641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33117290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung PJ, Nigrelli RF. 1974. Ecdysterone-induced molting in isolated penis and appendages of barnacle, Balanus eburneus Gould, kept in sterilized sea water. Amer Zool 14:1266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clare AS. 1987. Endocrinology of cirripedes, pp. 249&#x2013;266. In: Barnacle Biology. Southward AJ (ed) AA Balkema, Rotterdam.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crisp DJ, Lewis AH. 1984. Factors controlling cold tolerance and breeding in Balanus balanoides. J Mar Biol Ass UK 64:125&#x2013; 145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drach P. 1939. Mue et cycle d'intermue chez les crustac&#xe9;s d&#xe9;capodes. Ann Inst Oceanogr (Paris) 19:103&#x2013;391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drach P, Tchernigovtzeff C. 1967. Sur la methode de determination des stades d&#x2019;intermue et son application general aux Crustaces. Vie et Milieu. Serie A: Biologie Marine 18:595&#x2013;610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fazhan H, Waiho K, Glenner H, Moh JHZ, Hassan M et al. 2020. Gonadal
degeneration and hepatopancreas alteration in orange mud crab Scylla
olivacea infected with Sacculina beauforti (Crustacea;
Rhizocephala; Sacculinidae). Front Mar Sci 7:534443. 
doi:10.3389/fmars.2020.534443. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmars.2020.534443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fingerman M. 1997. Roles of neurotransmitters in regulating reproductive
hormone release and gonadal maturation in decapod  crustaceans. Invertebr
Reprod Dev  <b>31:</b> 47&#x2013;54. doi:10.1080/07924
 259.1997.9672562. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07924259.1997.9672562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07924259.1997.9672562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07924259.1997.9672562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07924259.1997.9672562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman JA. 1980. Hormonal control of chitinolytic activity in the integument of Balanus amphitrite, in vitro. Comp Biochem Physiol A Physiol 65:13&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman JA, Costlow JD. 1979. Hormonal control of apolysis in barnacle mantle tissue epidermis, in vitro. J Exp Zool 210:333&#x2013; 345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyhn UEH, Costlow JD. 1977. Histology and histochemistry of the ovary and oogenesis in Balanus amphitrite L. and B. eburneus gould (Cirripedia, Crustacea). Biol Bull 152:351&#x2013;359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glenner H. 2001. Cypris metamorphosis, injection and earliest internal
development of the rhizocephalan Loxothylacus panopaei (Gissler).
Crustacea: Cirripedia: Rhizocephala: Sacculinidae. J Morphol
249:43&#x2013;75. 
doi:10.1002/jmor.1040. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmor.1040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11410938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glenner H, H&#xf8;eg JT. 1995. A new motile, multicellular stage involved in
host invasion by parasitic barnacles (Rhizocephala). Nature
377:147&#x2013;150. 
doi:10.1038/377147a0. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/377147a0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glenner H, H&#xf8;eg JT, O'Brien JJ, Sherman TD. 2000. Invasive vermigon stage
in the parasitic barnacles Loxothylacus texanus and L.
panopae (Sacculinidae): closing of the rhizocephalan lifecycle. Mar Biol
136:249&#x2013;257. 
doi:10.1007/s002270050683. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s002270050683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goddard JHR, Torchin ME, Kuris AM, Lafferty KD. 2005. Host specificity of Sacculina carcini, a potential biological control agent of the introduced European green crab Carcinus maenas in California. Biol Invasions 7:895&#x2013;912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golubinskaya DD, Korn OM, Sharina SN, Selin NI. 2021. Sympatric two-species
infestation by rhizocephalan barnacle parasites in the spider crab Pugettia
aff. ferox Ohtsuchi &amp; Kawamura 2019 from Peter the great
bay (Northwestern Sea of Japan). Zool Stud 60:54. 
doi:10.6620/ZS.2021.60-54. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6620/ZS.2021.60-54</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9121276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35665086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HartnolI RG. 1967. The effects of sacculinid parasites on two Jamaican crabs. J Linn Sot (Zool) 46:275&#x2013;295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf8;eg JT. 1995. The biology and life cycle of the rhizocephala  (Cirripedia). J Mar Biol Ass UK
 <b>75:</b> 517&#x2013;550. doi:10.1017/
S0025315400038996. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0025315400038996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0025315400038996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0025315400038996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf8;eg JT, L&#xfc;tzen J. 1995. Life cycle and reproduction in the Cirripedia Rhizocephala. Oceanogr Mar Biol Annu Rev 33:427&#x2013;485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf8;eg JT, Noever C, Rees DA, Crandall KA, Glenner H. 2020. A new molecular
phylogeny-based taxonomy of parasitic barnacles (Crustacea: Cirripedia: Rhizocephala).
Zool J Linn Soc 190:632&#x2013; 653. 
doi:10.1093/zoolinnean/zlz140. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/zoolinnean/zlz140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsiao CJ, Wu YI, Tung TA, Wang GY, Toullec JY, Liu ST et al. 2016.
Metabolic effects of parasitization by the barnacle Polyascus plana
(Cirripedia: Rhizocephala: Sacculinidae) on a grapsid host, Metopograpsus
thukuhar. Dis Aquat Organ 119:199&#x2013;206.  doi:10.3354/dao03000. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/dao03000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27225203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaglarz MK, Kubrakiewicz J, Bilinski SM. 2014. The ovary structure and
oogenesis in the basal crustaceans and hexapods. Possible phylogenetic significance.
Arthropod Struct Dev 43:349&#x2013;360.  doi:10.1016/j.asd.2014.05.003.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asd.2014.05.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24858464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayasankar V, Tomy S, Wilder MN. 2020. Insights on molecular mechanisms of
ovarian development in Decapod Crustacea: Focus on vitellogenesis-stimulating factors
and pathways.  Front
Endocrinol (Lausanne)  <b>11:</b> 577925. doi:10.3389/
fendo.2020.577925. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2020.577925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2020.577925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2020.577925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7573297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33123094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klepal W, Barnes H, Barnes M. 1977. Studies on the reproduction of cirripedes. VI. Passages of the spermatozoa into the oviducal sac and closure of pores. J Exp Mar Biol Ecol 27:289&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korn OM, Shukalyuk AI, Trofimova AV, Isaeva VV. 2004. Reproductive stage of
the life cycle in the rhizocephalan barnacle Polyascus polygenea
(Crustacea: Cirripedia). Russian J Mar Biol 30:328&#x2013;340.  doi:10.1023/B:RUMB.0000046552.07712.02. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/B:RUMB.0000046552.07712.02</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristensen T, Nielsen AI, J&#xf8;rgensen AI, Mouritsen KN, Glenner H,
Christensen JT, L&#xfc;tzen J, H&#xf8;eg JT. 2012. The selective advantage of host feminization: a
case study of the green crab Carcinus maenas and the parasitic barnacle
Sacculina carcini. Mar Biol 159:2015&#x2013;2023. 
doi:10.1007/s00227-012-1988-4. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00227-012-1988-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lafont R, Balducci C, Dinan L. 2021. Ecdysteroids. Encyclopedia
1:1267&#x2013;1302.  doi:10.3390/encyclopedia1040096. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/encyclopedia1040096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lafont R, Mathieu M. 2007. Steroids in aquatic invertebrates. Ecotoxicology
16:109&#x2013;30.  doi:10.1007/s10646-006-0113-1. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10646-006-0113-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17238002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lange S. 2002. The colleteric glands in sacculinidae (Crustacea,
cirripedia, rhizocephala): an ultrastructural study of ovisac secretion. Contributions
to Zoology 70:229&#x2013;242.  doi:10.1163/18759866-07004004. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1163/18759866-07004004.</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lianguzova A, Arbuzova N, Laskova E, Gafarova E, Repkin E et al. 2023.
Tricks of the puppet masters: morphological adaptations to the interaction with nervous
system underlying host manipulation by rhizocephalan barnacle Polyascus
polygeneus. PeerJ 11:e16348.  doi:10.7717/peerj.16348. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.16348.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10655712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38025701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lianguzova AD, Ilyutkin SA, Korn OM, Miroliubov AA. 2021. Specialised
rootlets of Sacculina pilosella (Rhizocephala: Sacculinidae) used for
interactions with its host&#x2019;s nervous system. Arthropod Struct Dev
60:101009. 
doi:10.1016/j.asd.2020.101009. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asd.2020.101009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33307518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc;tzen J. 1984. Growth, reproduction and life span in Sacculina carcini Thompson (Cinipedia: Rhizocephala) in the Isefjord, Denmark. Sarsia 69:91&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc;tzen J, Takahashi T. 2005. Morphology and biology of Polysaccus japonicus (Crustacea, Rhizocephala, Akentrogonida, Polysaccidae, fam. n.), a parasite of the ghost&#x2010;shrimp Callianassa japonica. Zool Scr 25:171&#x2013;181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meusy JJ. 1980. Vitellogenin, the extraovarian precursor of the protein
yolk in Crustacea: a review. Reprod Nutr Dev 20:1&#x2013;21.  doi:10.1051/rnd:19800101. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/rnd:19800101.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6760272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miroliubov A, Borisenko I, Nesterenko M, Lianguzova A, Ilyutkin S, Lapshin
N, Dobrovolskij A. 2020. Specialized structures on the border between rhizocephalan
parasites and their host&#x2019;s nervous system reveal potential sites for host-parasite
interactions. Sci Rep 10:1128.  doi:10.1038/s41598-020-58175-4. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-58175-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6981121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31980714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mykles DL. 2021. Signaling pathways that regulate the crustacean molting
gland. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 12:674711.  doi:10.3389/fendo.2021.674711. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2021.674711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8256442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34234741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagaraju GP. 2011. Reproductive regulators in decapod crustaceans: an
overview. J Exp Biol 214:3&#x2013;16.  doi:10.1242/jeb.047183. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/jeb.047183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21147963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nesterenko M, Miroliubov A. 2022. From head to rootlet: comparative
transcriptomic analysis of a rhizocephalan barnacle Peltogaster
reticulata (Crustacea: Rhizocephala). F1000Res 11:583.  doi:10.12688/f1000research.110492.2. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/f1000research.110492.2.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9664023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36447930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen SO. 1970. The effects of the rhizocephalan parasites
Peltogaster paguri Rathke and Gemmosaccus sulcatus
(Lilljeborg) on five species of paguridan hosts (Crustacea  decapoda). Sarsia
 <b>42:</b> 17&#x2013;32.
doi:10.1080/00364827.1970.10411  160. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00364827.1970.10411160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00364827.1970.10411160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00364827.1970.10411160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00364827.1970.10411160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nour Eldeen MF, El Gamal ME, Abdelsalam MM, Shoukr FA, Mona MH. 2019.
Histomorphological investigation of the mature externa of Heterosaccus dollfusi
(Crustacea, Rhizocephala). Zoomorphology 138:463&#x2013;473. 
doi:10.1007/s00435-019-00453-5. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00435-019-00453-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien JJ, Skinner DM. 1990. Overriding of the molt-inducing stimulus of
multiple limb autotomy in the mud crab Rhithropanopeus harrisii by
parasitization with a rhizocephalan. J Crus Biol 10:440&#x2013;445.  doi:10.2307/1548333.
 </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/1548333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien J, Van Wyk P. 1985. Effects of crustacean parasitic castrators (epicaridean isopods and rhizocephalan barnacles) on growth of their crustacean hosts, p. 191&#x2013;218. In: Wenner AM (ed) Crustacean issues. Vol. 3, Factors in Adult Growth. A. A. Balkema Press, Rotterdam, The Netherlands.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payen GG, Hubert M, Turquier Y, Rubiliani C, Chassard-Bouchaud C. 1981.
Infestations exp&#xe9;rimentales de crabes juv&#xe9;niles par la sacculine. Ultrastructure des
racines parasitaires en croissance et relations avec la niasse ganglionnaire ventrale de
l'h&#xf4;te. Can J Zool 59:1818&#x2013;1826. 
doi:10.1139/z81-249. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/z81-249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payen GG, Rubiliani C, Hubert M, Chassard-Bouchaud C. 1979. Donn&#xe9;es pr&#xe9;liminaires relatives aux modifications induites par les racines des Rhizoc&#xe9;phales sur le syst&#xe8;me nerveux central des Crabes h&#xf4;tes: aspects structuraux et ultrastructuraux. C R Acad Sci Paris 288D:705&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell A, Rowley AF. 2008. Tissue changes in the shore crab Carcinus maenas as a result of infection by the parasitic barnacle Sacculina carcini. Dis Aquat Org 80:75&#x2212;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18714687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinhard EG. 1956. Parasitic castration of crustacea. Exp Parasitol
5:79&#x2212;107. 
doi:10.1016/0014-4894(56)90007-8. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0014-4894(56)90007-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13305598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowley AF, Davies CE, Malkin SH, Bryan CC, Thomas et al. 2020. Prevalence
and histopathology of the parasitic barnacle, Sacculina carcini in
shore crabs, Carcinus maenas. J Invertebr Pathol
171:107338. 
doi:10.1016/j.jip.2020.107338. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jip.2020.107338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32035933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubiliani C, Payen GG. 1979. Modalit&#xe9;s de la destruction des r&#xe9;gions
neuros&#xe9;cr&#xe9;trices des crabes Carcinus maenas (L.) et C.
mediterraneus Czerniavsky infest&#xe9;s par la sacculine. Gen Comp Endocrinol
38:215&#x2013;228. 
doi:10.1016/0016-6480(79)90209-0.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0016-6480(79)90209-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">488676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubiliani C, Rubiliani-Durozoi, M, Paye GG. 1980. Effets de la sacculine sur les gonades, les glandes androgenes et le systeme nerveux central des crabes Carcinus maenas (L.) et C. mediterraneus czerniavsky. Bull Soc Zool Fr 105:95&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubiliani-Durozoi M, Rubiliani C, Payen GG. 1980. Deroulement des
gametogeneses chez les crabes Carcinus maenas (L.) et C.
mediterraneus czerniavsky parasites par la sacculine. Int J  Invertebr Reprod Dev
 <b>2:</b> 107&#x2013;120.
doi:10.1080/01651269.1980.1  0553346. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01651269.1980.10553346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01651269.1980.10553346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01651269.1980.10553346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01651269.1980.10553346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarojini R, Nagabhushanam R, Fingerman M. 1994. A possible neurotransmitter-neuroendocrine mechanism in naphthaleneinduced atresia of the ovary of the red swamp crayfish, Procambarus clarkii, Comp Biochem Physiol C: Pharmacol Toxicol Endocrinol 108:33&#x2212;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeder PC, Talbot P. 1985. Ovulation in the Animal Kingdom: A review with an emphasis on the role of contractile processes. Gamete Res 11:191&#x2212;221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirley SM, Shirley TC, Meyers TR. 1986. Hemolymph responses of Alaskan king crabs to rhizocephalan parasitism. Can J Zool 64:1774&#x2212;1781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner DM. 1962. The structure and metabolism of a crustacean integumentary tissue during a molt cycle. Biol Bull 123:635&#x2212;647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner DM. 1985. Molting and regeneration, p. 43&#x2013;146. In: The Biology of Crustacea, Volume 9: Integument, Pigments, and Hormonal Processes. Bliss DE and Mantel LH (eds) Academic Press, Orlando, Florida.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi T, Matsuura S. 1994. Laboratory studies on molting and growth of
the shore crab, Hemigrapsus sanguineus de Haan, parasitized by a
rhizocephalan barnacle. Biol Bull 186:300&#x2212;308.  doi:10.2307/1542276.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/1542276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29281350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbot P. 1981a. Collagenase solutions induce in vitro ovulation in lobsters. J Exp Zool 216:181&#x2212;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbot P. 1981b. The ovary of the lobster, Homarus
americanus. I. Architecture of the mature ovary. J Ultrastruct Res
76:235&#x2212;248.  doi:10.1016/s0022-5320(81)80055-x.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-5320(81)80055-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7197730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tighe-Ford DJ, Vaile DC. 1972. The action of crustecdysone on the cirripede Balanus balanoides (L.). J Exp Mar Biol Eco 9:19&#x2212;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinikul Y, Joffre Mercier A, Soonklang N, Sobhon P. 2008. Changes in the
levels of serotonin and dopamine in the central nervous system and ovary, and their
possible roles in the ovarian development in the giant freshwater prawn,
Macrobrachium  <i>rosenbergii</i> . Gen Comp Endocrinol
 <b>158:</b> 250&#x2212;258. doi:10.1016/
 j.ygcen.2008.07.009. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ygcen.2008.07.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ygcen.2008.07.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ygcen.2008.07.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ygcen.2008.07.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ygcen.2008.07.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18713629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomy S, Saikrithi P, James N, Balasubramanian CP, Panigrahi A et al. 2016.
Serotonin induced changes in the expression of ovarian gene network in the Indian white
shrimp,  <i>Penaeus indicus</i> . Aquaculture
 <b>452:</b> 239&#x2013;246. doi:10.1016/
j.aquaculture.2015.11.003. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aquaculture.2015.11.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aquaculture.2015.11.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aquaculture.2015.11.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aquaculture.2015.11.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toyota K, Ito T, Morishima K, Hanazaki R, Ohira T. 2023. SacculinaInduced
morphological feminization in the grapsid crab  <i>Pachygrapsus
crassipes</i> .
Zoolog Sci  <b>40:</b> 36&#x2212;374. doi:10.2108/  zs230022. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2108/zs230022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2108/zs230022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2108/zs230022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2108/zs230022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2108/zs230022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37818885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uglow RF. 1969. Haemolymph protein concentrations in portunid crabs &#x2013; III. The effect of Sacculina. Comp Biochem Physiol 31:969&#x2013;973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5349634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veillet A, Graf F. 1959. Degenerescence de la glande androgene des crustaces decapodes parasites parles rhizocephales. Bull Soc Sci Nancy 18:123&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waiho K, Fazhan H, Glenner H, Ikhwanuddin M. 2017. Infestation of parasitic
rhizocephalan barnacles Sacculina beauforti (Cirripedia, Rhizocephala)
in edible mud crab, Scylla olivacea. PeerJ.
5:e3419. 
doi:10.7717/peerj.3419.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.3419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5494170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28674645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waiho K, Fazhan H, Zhang Y, Afiqah-Aleng N, Moh JHZ et al. 2020. Gonadal
transcriptomic analysis of the mud crab Scylla olivacea infected with
rhizocephalan parasite Sacculina beauforti. Genomics
112:2959&#x2212;2969.  doi:10.1016/j.ygeno.2020.05.007. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ygeno.2020.05.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker G. 1977. Observation by scanning electron microscope (SEM) on the oviducal gland sacs of Balanus balanoides at egg laying. J Mar Biol Assoc UK 57:969&#x2212;972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker G. 1980. A study of the oviducal glands and ovisacs of Balanus balanoides (L), together with comparative observations on the ovisacs of Balanus hameri (Ascanius) and the reproductive biology of the two species. Phil Trans R Soc Lond (B) 191:147&#x2212;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker G. 2001. Introduction to the Rhizocephala (Crustacea: Cirripedia). J
Morphol 249:1&#x2212;8. 
doi:10.1002/jmor.1038. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmor.1038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11410936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walley LJ. 1965. The development and function of the oviducal gland in Balanus balanoides. J Mar Biol Ass UK 45:115&#x2212;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zatylny-Gaudin C, Herv&#xe9; O, Dubos MP, Rabet N, Henry et al. 2023.
Differential analysis of the haemolymph proteome of Carcinus maenas
parasitized by Sacculina carcini (Cirripeda, Rhizocephala)
reveals potential mechanisms of parasite  control. Fish Shellfish Immunol
 <b>141:</b> 109064. doi:10.1016/
j.fsi.2023.109064. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fsi.2023.109064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fsi.2023.109064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fsi.2023.109064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37689227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng H, Bao C, Huang H, Ye H, Li S. 2016. The mechanism of regulation of
ovarian maturation by red pigment concentrating hormone in the mud crab Scylla
paramamosain. Anim Reprod Sci 164:152&#x2212;161.  doi:10.1016/j.anireprosci.2015.11.025. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anireprosci.2015.11.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26679434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zerbib C, Andrieux N, Berreur-Bonnenfant J. 1975. Donn&#xe9;es pr&#xe9;liminaires sur l'ultrastructure de la glande de mue (organe Y) chez le Crabe Carcinus mediterraneus sain en parasit&#xe9; par Sacculina carcini. C R Acad Hebd Seances Acad Sci D 281:1167&#x2212;1169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">813891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>