<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41388373</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2334</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC infectious diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence and risk factors for parasitic infections among internally displaced persons in the North-Central Geopolitical Zone of Nigeria.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>88</StartPage><MedlinePgn>88</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">88</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12879-025-12343-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Internally displaced Persons (IDPs) are exceptionally vulnerable to parasitic infections due to the poor sanitary and socioeconomic conditions of IDPs camps and IDPs host communities, where most IDPs live.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">This study assessed the prevalence, intensity and risk factors for parasitic infections among IDPs in Benue and Nasarawa States, Nigeria.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A total of 403 participants were randomly selected for the study. Stool, urine and blood samples were collected from each participant. Qualitative data were collected via interview-based questionnaires. Parasites from collected samples were identified via microscopy. The data were analysed using SPSS, and P values less than 0.05 were considered significant in all analyses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Of the 403 participants, 309 (76.7%) were infected with at least one parasitic infection as follows: <i>Plasmodium falciparum</i> (40.5%), <i>Schistosoma haematobium</i> (23.0%), Hookworms (22.6%), <i>Ascaris lumbricoides</i> (21.1%), <i>Entamoeba histolytica</i> (20.8%), <i>Giardia lamblia</i> (9.4%) and <i>Schistosoma mansoni</i> (6.0%). The mean intensities of <i>P. falciparum and</i> S. <i>haematobium</i> were 1344&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;311.3 parasites/&#xb5;L of blood and 15.4&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.8 eggs/10 mL of urine, respectively. The mean intensities of <i>A. lumbricoides</i>, hookworm, <i>E. histolytica</i>,<i> Giardia lamblia</i> and <i>S. mansoni</i> infections were 40.8 (epg), 29.0 (epg), 22.0 (cpg), 9.0 (cpg), and 3.3 (epg), respectively. Risk factors for parasitic infections were identified as water contact activities (aORs: 2.8; 95% CI: 2.2&#x2013;3.6), non-use of long-lasting treated networks (aORs: 3.3; 95% CI: 2.1&#x2013;5.7), and walking barefoot (aORs of 2.9; 95% CI: 2.1&#x2013;3.8). The knowledge, attitudes and practices (KAPs) of the IDPs in relation to parasitic infections were poor.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Parasitic infections were highly prevalent among the IDPs in North Central Nigeria; however, the intensity of infections was low. Risk factors for parasitic infection were present in the IDP camp and host communities. Moreover, the IDPs had poor KAPs for parasitic infections. Sustained health education and deworming campaigns, and the provision and maintenance of basic Water, Sanitation and Hygiene (WASH) facilities are recommended.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL NUMBER">Not applicable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12879-025-12343-x.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ikpe</LastName><ForeName>Raphael Terlumun</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology and Parasitology, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile Ife, Nigeria. ikperaphaelt@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Edungbola</LastName><ForeName>Luke Ekundayo</ForeName><Initials>LE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology and Parasitology, University of Ilorin, Ilorin, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nymangee</LastName><ForeName>Amase</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology and Parasitology, University of Ilorin, Ilorin, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2334</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intensity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Internally displaced persons</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nigeria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parasitic infections</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">WASH</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Prior to the study, ethical approval was obtained from the Ethical Review Committee of the Faculty of Basic Clinical Sciences, University of Ilorin, Ilorin (UERC/ASN/2021/2293). Permission was obtained from the Nasarawa and Benue States Ministry of Health prior to field work in the IDP camps and host communities. Informed consent, voluntary participation, confidentiality and safety of all participants were strictly provided. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41388373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12817665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-025-12343-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12879-025-12343-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Salami B, Iwuagwu S, Amodu O, Tulli M, Ndikom C, Gommaa H, et al. The health of internally displaced children in sub-Saharan africa: a scoping review. BMJ Global Health. 2020;5:e002584. 10.1136/bmjgh-2020-002584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2020-002584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32859650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edungbola LD. The Crawling Flyer, The Flying Crawler, The Warring Worm and the Wormy World. 47th University of Ilorin Inaugural Lecture. 1995;30&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amodu OC, Richter MS, Salami BO. A scoping review of the health of Conflict-Induced internally displaced women in Africa. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(4):1280. 10.3390/ijerph17041280. Published 2020 Feb 17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17041280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7068277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32079235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Internal Displacement Monitoring Centre (IDMC) Internal Displacement Index. 2025 Report https://www.internal-displacement.org/global-report/grid2025/. Global Report on Internal Displacement 2025 (accessed November 11, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayuba K, Oti V, Okwoli A, et al. High prevalence of human Gastrointestinal parasitic infections in an internally displaced persons (IDPs) camp in Nasarawa State, nigeria: a cross-sectional study. South Asian J Parasitol. 2019;2(3):173&#x2013;80. 10.47422/sajp.v2i3.56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47422/sajp.v2i3.56</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karshima SN. Prevalence and distribution of soil-transmitted helminth infections in Nigerian children: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Infect Dis Poverty. 2018;7(1):69. Published 2018 Jul 9. 10.1186/s40249-018-0451-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6036687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29983115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evbuomwan IO, Edosomwan EU, Idubor V, et al. Survey of intestinal parasitism among schoolchildren in internally displaced persons camp, Benin City, Nigeria. Sci Afr. 2022;17:e01373. 10.1016/j.sciaf.2022.e01373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sciaf.2022.e01373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yauba SM, Rabasa AF, Abubakar EH, et al. Urinary schistosomiasis in Boko haram-related internally displaced Nigerian children. Saudi J Kidney Dis Transplantation. 2018;29:1395. 10.4103/1319-2442.248286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1319-2442.248286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30588972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umar B, Inuwa Y, Linus I. A study on the epidemiology of schistosomiasis infection in some selected IDP camps, Maiduguri, Borno state. Int J Res Publications. 2018;16(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eshag HA, Elfadel E, Elkhatieb N, et al. Molecular epidemiology of malaria parasite amongst patients in a displaced people&#x2019;s camp in Sudan. Trop Med Health. 2020;48:3. 10.1186/s41182-020-01923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41182-020-01923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6988308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). World malaria report 2019. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization. 2019. ISBN 978-92-4-156572-1 (https://iris.who.int/handle/10665/330011) (accessed August, 4, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teh RN, Sumbele IUN, Meduke DN, et al. Malaria parasitaemia, anaemia and malnutrition in children less than 15 years residing in different altitudes along the slope of Mount cameroon: prevalence, intensity and risk factors. Malar J. 2018;17(1):336. 10.1186/s12936-018-2492-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12936-018-2492-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6154899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30249261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks HM, Paul MKJ, Claude KM, et al. Malaria in an internally displaced persons camp in the Democratic Republic of the congo. Clin Infect Dis. 2017;65:529&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/cix382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28838136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charchuk R, Paul MKJ, Claude KM. Burden of malaria is higher among children in an internal displacement camp compared to a neighbouring village in the Democratic Republic of congo. Malar J. 2016;15:431. 10.1186/s12936-016-1479-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12936-016-1479-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4997722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27557931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou G, Lo E, Zhong D. Impact of interventions on malaria in internally displaced persons along the China&#x2013;Myanmar border: 2011&#x2013; 2014. Malar J. 2016;15(471). 10.1186/s12936-016-1512-.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5024476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27628040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AjakayeOG, Ibukunoluwa MR. Prevalence and Risk of Malaria, Anemia and Malnutrition among Children in IDPs Camp in Edo State, Nigeria. Parasite Epidemiol Control. 2019. 10.1016/j.parepi.2019.e00127 . PMID: 31872094; PMCID: PMC6909050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6909050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31872094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edosomwan EU, Evbuomwan IO, Agbalalah C, et al. Malaria coinfection with Neglected Tropical Diseases (NTDs) in children at internally displaced persons (IDPs) camp in Benin City, Nigeria. Heliyon. 2020;5;6(8):e04604. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2020.e04604 . PMID: 32793830; PMCID: PMC7408312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7408312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32793830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okoli C, Solomon M. Prevalence of hospital-based malaria among children in Jos, North central Nigeria. Br J Med Med Res. 2014;4:3232&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/BJMMR/2014/8068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanvyat N, Mulambalah CS, Ajiji JA, et al. Prevalence of human malaria infection and its transmission pattern in the highlands and lowlands of plateau State, Nigeria. Indian J Sci Technol. 2017;10:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17485/ijst/2017/v10i32/113622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Morales AJ, Bedoya-Arias HA, S&#xe1;nchez-Ram&#xed;rez N, et al. Differences in the incidence of malaria between internally displaced people and general population of Colombia from 2007 to 2016. Int J Infect Dis. 2018;73:3&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2018.04.4141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hailegebriel T, Nibret E, Munshea A. Prevalence of <i>Schistosoma mansoni</i> and <i>S. haematobium</i> in snail intermediate hosts in africa: A systematic review and Meta-analysis. J Trop Med. 2020;2020:8850840. 10.1155/2020/8850840. Published 2020 Sep 7.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/8850840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7492904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32963554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enabulele EE, Platt RN, Adeyemi E, et al. Urogenital schistosomiasis in Nigeria post receipt of the largest single praziquantel donation in Africa. Acta Trop. 2021;219:105916. 10.1016/j.actatropica.2021.105916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actatropica.2021.105916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8428123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33878306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HassanM, Sadiq MA, Tijjani A et al. Urinary schistosomiasis and its associated risk factors among inhabitants of Internally Displaced Peoples&#x2019; (IDP) camps in Maiduguri, North-eastern Nigeria: a cross-sectional study urinary schistosomiasis and its associated risk factors among inhabitants of Internally Displaced Peoples&#x2019; (IDP) camps in Maiduguri, North-eastern Nigeria: a cross-sectional study. Vet Med Public Health J<i>.</i> 2022;3:6-17 10.31559/vmph2022.3.1.2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balogun JB, Adewale B, Balogun SU. Prevalence and associated risk factors of urinary schistosomiasis among primary school pupils in the Jidawa and Zobiya communities of Jigawa State, Nigeria. Annals Global Health. 2022;88(1):71. 10.5334/aogh.3704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5334/aogh.3704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9389954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36062044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Federal Ministry of Health (FMOH). Report on Epidemiological Mapping of Schistosomiasis. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ntonifor HN, Green AE, Bopda MOS, et al. Epidemiology of urinary schistosomiasis and soil transmitted helminthiasis in a recently established focus behind Mount Cameroon. Int J Curr Microbiol Appl Sci. 2015;4(3):1056&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchendu O, Oladoyin V, Idowu M, et al. Urinary schistosomiasis among vulnerable children in a rehabilitation home in Ibadan, Oyo state. Nigeria BMC Infect Diseases. 2017;17. 10.1186/s12879-017-2591-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5504566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28693436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Njunda AL, Ndzi EN, Assob JCN. Prevalence and factors associated with urogenital schistosomiasis among primary school children in barrage, Magba subdivision of Cameroon. BMC Public Health. 2017;17:618. 10.1186/s12889-017-4539-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-017-4539-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5496429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28673343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao CW, Sukati H, Nara T. Eradication of <i>Taenia solium</i> cysticercosis: A role for vaccination of pigs. Int J Parasitol. 2020;40:1183&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20470777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otuneme OG, Akinkuade FO, Obebe OO, et al. A study on the prevalence of <i>Schistosoma haematobium</i> and <i>Schistosoma intercalatum</i> in a rural community of Ogun State, Nigeria. South&#x2013;East Asia. J Public Health. 2014;4:67&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salawu SA, Asaolu SO, Sowemimo OA. Coinfections with schistosoma haematobium and soil- transmitted helminthes among School-aged children in Saki, Oyo State, Nigeria. J Public Health Epidemiol. 2014;6(12):417&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemu A, Yalewayker T, Demekech D, et al. <i>Schistosoma mansoni</i> and soil transmitted helminths among preschool-aged children in Chuahit, Dembia District, Northwest ethiopia: Prevalence, intensity of infection and associated risk factors. BMC Public Health. 2016;16:42.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-016-2864-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4876558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27216255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rupiah M, Berhanu J, Tuma DU. An evaluation of the effect of schistosomiasis on human health. Afr J Parasitol Res. 2015;2(5):98&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wammes LJ, Hamid F, Wiria AE, et al. Community deworming alleviates geohelminth-induced immune hyporesponsiveness. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2016;113(44):12526&#x2013;31. 10.1073/pnas.1604570113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1604570113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5098677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27791067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degarege A, Veledar E, Degarege D. <i>Plasmodium falciparum</i> and soil-transmitted helminth coinfections among children in sub-Saharan africa: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Parasites Vectors. 2016;9:344. 10.1186/s13071-016-1594-2.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13071-016-1594-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4908807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27306987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okonko IO, Soleye FA, Amusan TA. Prevalence of malaria plasmodium in Abeokuta, Nigeria. Malaysian J Microbiol. 2009;5:113&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awosolu OB, Yahaya ZS, Haziqah MF, et al. Prevalence, parasite density and determinants of falciparum malaria among febrile children in some peri-urban communities in Southwestern nigeria: a cross-sectional study. Infect Drug Resist. 2021;14:3219&#x2013;32. 10.2147/IDR.S312519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IDR.S312519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8380643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34434052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooker S, Akhwale W, Pullan R, et al. Epidemiology of plasmodium-helminth Co infection in africa: populations at risk, potential impact on anemia, and prospects for Combining Control. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2007;77:88&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.2007.77.88</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2637949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18165479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babamale OA, Ugbomoiko US. Status of malaria infection in peri- urban community of North central region of Nigeria. J Bacteriol Parasitol. 2016;7:256. 10.4172/2155-9597.1000256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2155-9597.1000256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oluwaseun BA, Yahaya ZS, Farah HMT, et al. Will Nigerians win the war against urinary schistosomiasis? prevalence, intensity, risk factors and knowledge assessment among some rural communities in Southwestern Nigeria. Pathogens. 2020;9:128. 10.3390/pathogens9020128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pathogens9020128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7168148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32079189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Malaria microscopy standard operating procedure (MM-SOP-09): malaria parasite counting. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization; 2021. (assessed July,6 /MM/SOP/2016.09.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawaki S, Al-Mekhlafi HM, Ithoi I, et al. Prevalence and risk factors of schistosomiasis among Hausa communities in Kano State, Nigeria. Rev Inst Med Trop Sao Paulo. 2016;58:54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1678-9946201658054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4964323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27410914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Helminth control in school-age children: a guide for managers of control programmes, 1st ed. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization. 2002. (Accessed April, 3, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrham G, Getaneh A, Animen A. Prevalence and intensity of soil-transmitted helminths and associated factors among adolescents and adults in Bibugn Woreda, Northwest ethiopia: A community-based cross-sectional study. J Trop Med. 2021;12:30&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8718294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34976073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anunobi JT, Okoye IC, Aguzie IO, et al. Risk of Soil-Transmitted helminthiasis among agrarian communities of Kogi State, Nigeria. Annals Global Health. 2019;85(1):18&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5334/aogh.2563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6743035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31517465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tekalign E, Bajiro M, Ayana M, et al. Prevalence and intensity of soil-transmitted helminth infection among rural community of Southwest ethiopia: a community-based study. Biomed Res Int. 2019;2019:3687873. 10.1155/2019/3687873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/3687873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6931019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31915688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyebamiji DA, Ebisike AN, Egede JO, et al. Knowledge, attitude and practice with respect to soil contamination by soil-transmitted helminths in Ibadan, Southwestern Nigeria. Parasite Epidemiol Control. 2018;3(4):e00075. 10.1016/j.parepi.2018.e00075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parepi.2018.e00075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6171486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30306146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alharazi T, Bamaga OA, Al-Abd N, et al. Intestinal parasitic infection: prevalence, knowledge, attitude, and practices among schoolchildren in an urban area of Taiz city, Yemen. AIMS Public Health. 2020;7(4):769&#x2013;77. 10.3934/publichealth.2020059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3934/publichealth.2020059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33294480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasr NA, Al-Mekhlafi HM, Ahmed A, et al. Towards an effective control programme of soil-transmitted helminth infections among Orang Asli in rural Malaysia. Part 2: Knowledge, attitude, and practices. Parasites Vectors. 2013;6:28. 10.1186/1756-3305-6-28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1756-3305-6-28</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3571980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23356968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alo C, Akamike IC, Agbo UN, et al. Prevalence, knowledge, attitude and preventive practices regarding intestinal and urinary parasites among primary school children in a rural community in Ebonyi State, Nigeria. J Epidemiol Soc Niger. 2021;4(1):39&#x2013;50. 10.46912/jeson.39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46912/jeson.39</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>