<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41836017</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1663-9812</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Epigenetic and mitoepigenetic regulation in cancer and therapeutic perspectives.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1760013</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1760013</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1760013</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphar.2026.1760013</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Epigenetic modifications on nuclear and mitochondrial DNA constitute key regulatory layers influencing the transcriptional, metabolic, and phenotypic adaptability of cancer cells. The canonical principles of epigenetic control encompass DNA methylation, histone modification, and non-coding RNA-mediated regulation, which collectively contribute to the silencing of tumor suppressor genes, the activation of oncogenes, and chromatin remodeling. Therefore, epigenetic drugs (epi-drugs) are of great interest in the development of new-generation therapeutics and holistic treatment approaches. Accordingly, this work presents a narrative review that integrates current evidence on the molecular mechanisms, therapeutic developments, and translational relevance of epigenetic and mitoepigenetic regulation in cancer. RNA-mediated regulation collectively contributes to the silencing of tumor suppressor genes and to the activation of oncogenes. The field of mitoepigenetics encompasses mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) methylation, RNA modifications, and post-translational regulation of mitochondrial proteins such as TFAM, DNMT1, and sirtuins, which influence oxidative phosphorylation, redox balance, and apoptotic pathways, thereby affecting tumor initiation, progression, and treatment response. Recent advances in epigenetic drug development include FDA-approved DNMT and HDAC inhibitors and newer agents targeting EZH2, IDH1/2, and DOT1L, which broaden the scope of precision oncology. In addition, modulation of mitochondrial epigenetic mechanisms has been identified as a potential approach for addressing metabolic reprogramming and therapeutic resistance in cancer. The convergence of nuclear and mitochondrial regulatory frameworks reveals the critical need for biomarker-informed, combinatory, and organelle-targeted therapeutic approaches to sustain treatment efficacy. Comprehensive characterization and pharmacological targeting of epigenetic and mitoepigenetic networks provide a structured basis for developing personalized and metabolism-informed interventions in cancer therapy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Celik-Uzuner, Nalkiran, Uzuner and Sevim Nalkiran.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Celik-Uzuner</LastName><ForeName>Selcen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Biology and Genetics, Faculty of Science, Karadeniz Technical University, Trabzon, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nalkiran</LastName><ForeName>Ihsan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biology, Faculty of Medicine, Recep Tayyip Erdogan University, Rize, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uzuner</LastName><ForeName>Ugur</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Biology and Genetics, Faculty of Science, Karadeniz Technical University, Trabzon, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pros Biotechnology Trading Ltd., Trabzon Technology Development Zone Management Inc., University District, Ortahisar, Trabzon, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sevim Nalkiran</LastName><ForeName>Hatice</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biology, Faculty of Medicine, Recep Tayyip Erdogan University, Rize, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101548923</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1663-9812</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DNA methylation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cancer therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epigenetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">histone modification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mitoepigenetics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author UU was employed by Pros Biotechnology Trading Ltd. The remaining author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41836017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12982394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2026.1760013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1760013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abou-Alfa G. K., Macarulla T., Javle M. M., Kelley R. K., Lubner S. J., Adeva J., et al. (2020). Ivosidenib in IDH1-mutant, chemotherapy-refractory cholangiocarcinoma (ClarIDHy): a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 study. Lancet Oncol. 21, 796&#x2013;807. 10.1016/s1470-2045(20)30157-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(20)30157-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7523268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32416072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu Shelbayeh O., Arroum T., Morris S., Busch K. B. (2023). PGC-1&#x3b1; is a master regulator of mitochondrial lifecycle and ROS stress response. Antioxidants (Basel). 12, 1075. 10.3390/antiox12051075</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox12051075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10215733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37237941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonia S., Goldberg S. B., Balmanoukian A., Chaft J. E., Sanborn R. E., Gupta A., et al. (2016). Safety and antitumour activity of durvalumab plus tremelimumab in non-small cell lung cancer: a multicentre, phase 1b study. Lancet Oncol. 17, 299&#x2013;308. 10.1016/s1470-2045(15)00544-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(15)00544-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5500167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26858122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balar A. V., Galsky M. D., Rosenberg J. E., Powles T., Petrylak D. P., Bellmunt J., et al. (2017). Atezolizumab as first-line treatment in cisplatin-ineligible patients with locally advanced and metastatic urothelial carcinoma: a single-arm, multicentre, phase 2 trial. Lancet. 389, 67&#x2013;76. 10.1016/s0140-6736(16)32455-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(16)32455-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5568632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27939400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-Yaacov D., Frumkin I., Yashiro Y., Chujo T., Ishigami Y., Chemla Y., et al. (2016). Mitochondrial 16S rRNA is methylated by tRNA methyltransferase TRMT61B in all vertebrates. PLoS Biol. 14, e1002557. 10.1371/journal.pbio.1002557</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pbio.1002557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5025228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27631568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbato M. I., Bradford D., Ren Y., Aungst S. L., Miller C. P., Pan L., et al. (2024). FDA approval summary: Repotrectinib for locally advanced or metastatic ROS1-Positive non-small cell lung cancer. Clin. Cancer Res. 30, 3364&#x2013;3370. 10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-24-0949</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-24-0949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11326972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38875108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bardia A., Mayer I. A., Diamond J. R., Moroose R. L., Isakoff S. J., Starodub A. N., et al. (2017). Efficacy and safety of Anti-Trop-2 antibody drug conjugate sacituzumab govitecan (IMMU-132) in heavily pretreated patients with metastatic triple-negative breast cancer. J. Clin. Oncol. 35, 2141&#x2013;2148. 10.1200/jco.2016.70.8297</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.2016.70.8297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5559902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28291390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellmunt J., Hussain M., Gschwend J. E., Albers P., Oudard S., Castellano D., et al. (2021). Adjuvant atezolizumab versus observation in muscle-invasive urothelial carcinoma (IMvigor010): a multicentre, open-label, randomised, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 22, 525&#x2013;537. 10.1016/s1470-2045(21)00004-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(21)00004-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8495594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33721560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berdeja J. G., Madduri D., Usmani S. Z., Jakubowiak A., Agha M., Cohen A. D., et al. (2021). Ciltacabtagene autoleucel, a B-cell maturation antigen-directed chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy in patients with relapsed or refractory multiple myeloma (CARTITUDE-1): a phase 1b/2 open-label study. Lancet. 398, 314&#x2013;324. 10.1016/s0140-6736(21)00933-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(21)00933-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34175021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blay J. Y., Serrano C., Heinrich M. C., Zalcberg J., Bauer S., Gelderblom H., et al. (2020). Ripretinib in patients with advanced gastrointestinal stromal tumours (INVICTUS): a double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 21, 923&#x2013;934. 10.1016/s1470-2045(20)30168-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(20)30168-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8383051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32511981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonner J. A., Harari P. M., Giralt J., Azarnia N., Shin D. M., Cohen R. B., et al. (2006). Radiotherapy plus cetuximab for squamous-cell carcinoma of the head and neck. N. Engl. J. Med. 354, 567&#x2013;578. 10.1056/NEJMoa053422</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa053422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16467544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breiling A., Lyko F. (2015). Epigenetic regulatory functions of DNA modifications: 5-Methylcytosine and beyond. Epigenetics Chromatin. 8, 24. 10.1186/s13072-015-0016-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13072-015-0016-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4507326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26195987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgos Fuster L. M., Sandler A. B. (2004). Select clinical trials of erlotinib (OSI-774) in Non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer with emphasis on phase III outcomes. Clin. Lung Cancer. 6, S24&#x2013;S29. 10.3816/CLC.2004.s.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3816/CLC.2004.s.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15638954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camidge D. R., Kim H. R., Ahn M.-J., Yang J.C.-H., Han J.-Y., Lee J.-S., et al. (2018). Brigatinib versus crizotinib in ALK-positive Non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. N. Engl. J. Med. 379, 2027&#x2013;2039. 10.1056/NEJMoa1810171</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1810171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30280657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao K., Feng Z., Gao F., Zang W., Liu J. (2021). Mitoepigenetics: an intriguing regulatory layer in aging and metabolic-related diseases. Free Radic. Biol. Med. 177, 337&#x2013;346. 10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2021.10.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2021.10.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34715295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casali P. G., Garrett C. R., Blackstein M. E., Shah M., Verweij J., McArthur G., et al. (2006). Updated results from a phase III trial of sunitinib in GIST patients (pts) for whom imatinib (IM) therapy has failed due to resistance or intolerance. J. Clin. Oncol. 24, 9513. 10.1200/jco.2006.24.18_suppl.9513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.2006.24.18_suppl.9513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celik Uzuner S. (2020). Mitochondrial DNA methylation misleads global DNA methylation detected by antibody-based methods. Anal. Biochem. 601, 113789. 10.1016/j.ab.2020.113789</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ab.2020.113789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32473121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choueiri T. K., Larkin J., Oya M., Thistlethwaite F., Martignoni M., Nathan P., et al. (2018). Preliminary results for avelumab plus axitinib as first-line therapy in patients with advanced clear-cell renal-cell carcinoma (JAVELIN renal 100): an open-label, dose-finding and dose-expansion, phase 1b trial. Lancet Oncol. 19, 451&#x2013;460. 10.1016/s1470-2045(18)30107-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(18)30107-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29530667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen M. H., Williams G., Johnson J. R., Duan J., Gobburu J., Rahman A., et al. (2002). Approval summary for imatinib mesylate capsules in the treatment of chronic myelogenous leukemia. Clin. Cancer Res. 8, 935&#x2013;942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12006504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly R. M., Zhao F., Miller K. D., Lee M. J., Piekarz R. L., Smith K. L., et al. (2021). E2112: randomized phase III trial of endocrine therapy plus entinostat or placebo in hormone receptor-positive advanced breast cancer. A trial of the ECOG-ACRIN cancer research group. J. Clin. Oncol. 39, 3171&#x2013;3181. 10.1200/jco.21.00944</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.21.00944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34357781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copped&#xe8; F., Stoccoro A. (2019). Mitoepigenetics and neurodegenerative diseases. Front. Endocrinol. (Lausanne). 10, 86. 10.3389/fendo.2019.00086</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2019.00086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6389613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30837953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cramer-Morales K. L., Heer C. D., Mapuskar K. A., Domann F. E. (2020). Succinate accumulation links mitochondrial MnSOD depletion to aberrant nuclear DNA methylation and altered cell fate. J. Exp. Pathol. (Wilmington). 1, 60&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7876477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33585836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czarna M., Jarmuszkiewicz W. (2006). Role of mitochondria in reactive oxygen species generation and removal; relevance to signaling and programmed cell death. Postepy Biochem. 52, 145&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17078504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai W., Qiao X., Fang Y., Guo R., Bai P., Liu S., et al. (2024). Epigenetics-targeted drugs: current paradigms and future challenges. Signal Transduct. Target. Ther. 9, 332. 10.1038/s41392-024-02039-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41392-024-02039-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11627502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39592582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey A., Chitsaz F., Abbasi A., Misteli T., Ozato K. (2003). The double bromodomain protein Brd4 binds to acetylated chromatin during interphase and mitosis. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 100, 8758&#x2013;8763. 10.1073/pnas.1433065100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1433065100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC166386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12840145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhillon S. (2024). Repotrectinib: first approval. Drugs. 84, 239&#x2013;246. 10.1007/s40265-023-01990-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40265-023-01990-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38279972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dillman R. O. (1999). Perceptions of herceptin: a monoclonal antibody for the treatment of breast cancer. Cancer Biother. Radiopharm. 14, 5&#x2013;10. 10.1089/cbr.1999.14.5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cbr.1999.14.5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10850281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinardo M. M., Musicco C., Fracasso F., Milella F., Gadaleta M. N., Gadaleta G., et al. (2003). Acetylation and level of mitochondrial transcription factor A in several organs of young and old rats. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 301, 187&#x2013;191. 10.1016/s0006-291x(02)03008-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0006-291x(02)03008-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12535660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiNardo C. D., Stein E. M., de Botton S., Roboz G. J., Altman J. K., Mims A. S., et al. (2018). Durable remissions with ivosidenib in IDH1-Mutated relapsed or refractory AML. N. Engl. J. Med. 378, 2386&#x2013;2398. 10.1056/NEJMoa1716984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1716984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29860938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Z., Pu L., Cui H. (2020). Mitoepigenetics and its emerging roles in cancer. Front. Cell Dev. Biol. 8, 4. 10.3389/fcell.2020.00004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcell.2020.00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6989428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32039210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du J., Zhou Y., Su X., Yu J. J., Khan S., Jiang H., et al. (2011). Sirt5 is a NAD-dependent protein lysine demalonylase and desuccinylase. Science. 334, 806&#x2013;809. 10.1126/science.1207861</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1207861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3217313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22076378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duvic M., Talpur R., Ni X., Zhang C., Hazarika P., Kelly C., et al. (2007). Phase 2 trial of oral vorinostat (suberoylanilide hydroxamic acid, SAHA) for refractory cutaneous T-cell lymphoma (CTCL). Blood. 109, 31&#x2013;39. 10.1182/blood-2006-06-025999</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2006-06-025999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1785068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16960145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckersley-Maslin M. A., Alda-Catalinas C., Reik W. (2018). Dynamics of the epigenetic landscape during the maternal-to-zygotic transition. Nat. Rev. Mol. Cell Biol. 19, 436&#x2013;450. 10.1038/s41580-018-0008-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41580-018-0008-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29686419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fehrenbacher L., Spira A., Ballinger M., Kowanetz M., Vansteenkiste J., Mazieres J., et al. (2016). Atezolizumab versus docetaxel for patients with previously treated non-small-cell lung cancer (POPLAR): a multicentre, open-label, phase 2 randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 387, 1837&#x2013;1846. 10.1016/s0140-6736(16)00587-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(16)00587-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26970723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenaux P., Mufti G. J., Hellstrom-Lindberg E., Santini V., Finelli C., Giagounidis A., et al. (2009). Efficacy of azacitidine compared with that of conventional care regimens in the treatment of higher-risk myelodysplastic syndromes: a randomised, open-label, phase III study. Lancet Oncol. 10, 223&#x2013;232. 10.1016/s1470-2045(09)70003-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(09)70003-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4086808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19230772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fijardo M., Kwan J. Y. Y., Bissey P. A., Citrin D. E., Yip K. W., Liu F. F. (2024). The clinical manifestations and molecular pathogenesis of radiation fibrosis. EBioMedicine. 103, 105089. 10.1016/j.ebiom.2024.105089</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2024.105089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11002813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38579363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galsky M. D., Arija J&#xe1; A., Bamias A., Davis I. D., De Santis M., Kikuchi E., et al. (2020). Atezolizumab with or without chemotherapy in metastatic urothelial cancer (IMvigor130): a multicentre, randomised, placebo-controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet. 395, 1547&#x2013;1557. 10.1016/s0140-6736(20)30230-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(20)30230-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32416780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesh K., Massagu&#xe9; J. (2021). Targeting metastatic cancer. Nat. Med. 27, 34&#x2013;44. 10.1038/s41591-020-01195-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-020-01195-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7895475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33442008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia Campelo M. R., Zhou C., Ramalingam S. S., Lin H. M., Kim T. M., Riely G. J., et al. (2022). Mobocertinib (TAK-788) in EGFR exon 20 insertion+ metastatic NSCLC: patient-reported outcomes from EXCLAIM extension cohort. J. Clin. Med. 12, 112. 10.3390/jcm12010112</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12010112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9821270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36614913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Manero G., Kazmierczak M., Wierzbowska A., Fong C. Y., Keng M. K., Ballinari G., et al. (2024). Pracinostat combined with azacitidine in newly diagnosed adult acute myeloid leukemia (AML) patients unfit for standard induction chemotherapy: PRIMULA phase III study. Leuk. Res. 140, 107480. 10.1016/j.leukres.2024.107480</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.leukres.2024.107480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38499457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert M. R., Dignam J. J., Armstrong T. S., Wefel J. S., Blumenthal D. T., Vogelbaum M. A., et al. (2014). A randomized trial of bevacizumab for newly diagnosed glioblastoma. N. Engl. J. Med. 370, 699&#x2013;708. 10.1056/NEJMoa1308573</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1308573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4201043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24552317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gogishvili M., Melkadze T., Makharadze T., Giorgadze D., Dvorkin M., Penkov K., et al. (2022). Cemiplimab plus chemotherapy versus chemotherapy alone in non-small cell lung cancer: a randomized, controlled, double-blind phase 3 trial. Nat. Med. 28, 2374&#x2013;2380. 10.1038/s41591-022-01977-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-01977-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9671806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36008722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg S. B., Gettinger S. N., Mahajan A., Chiang A. C., Herbst R. S., Sznol M., et al. (2016). Pembrolizumab for patients with melanoma or non-small-cell lung cancer and untreated brain metastases: early analysis of a non-randomised, open-label, phase 2 trial. Lancet Oncol. 17, 976&#x2013;983. 10.1016/s1470-2045(16)30053-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(16)30053-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5526047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27267608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorsuch S., Bavetsias V., Rowlands M. G., Aherne G. W., Workman P., Jarman M., et al. (2009). Synthesis of isothiazol-3-one derivatives as inhibitors of histone acetyltransferases (HATs). Bioorg Med. Chem. 17, 467&#x2013;474. 10.1016/j.bmc.2008.11.079</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bmc.2008.11.079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19101154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal L., Meric-Bernstam F., Hollebecque A., Valle J. W., Morizane C., Karasic T. B., et al. (2023). Futibatinib for FGFR2-Rearranged intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma. N. Engl. J. Med. 388, 228&#x2013;239. 10.1056/NEJMoa2206834</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2206834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36652354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene K. S., Lukey M. J., Wang X., Blank B., Druso J. E., Lin M.-c.J., et al. (2019). SIRT5 stabilizes mitochondrial glutaminase and supports breast cancer tumorigenesis. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 116, 26625&#x2013;26632. 10.1073/pnas.1911954116</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1911954116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6936584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31843902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grillo-L&#xf3;pez A. J., White C. A., Dallaire B. K., Varns C. L., Shen C. D., Wei A., et al. (2000). Rituximab: the first monoclonal antibody approved for the treatment of lymphoma. Curr. Pharm. Biotechnol. 1, 1&#x2013;9. 10.2174/1389201003379059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1389201003379059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11467356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding J. J., Fan J., Oh D. Y., Choi H. J., Kim J. W., Chang H. M., et al. (2023). Zanidatamab for HER2-amplified, unresectable, locally advanced or metastatic biliary tract cancer (HERIZON-BTC-01): a multicentre, single-arm, phase 2b study. Lancet Oncol. 24, 772&#x2013;782. 10.1016/s1470-2045(23)00242-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(23)00242-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37276871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardwick J. S., Lane A. N., Brown T. (2018). Epigenetic modifications of cytosine: biophysical properties, regulation, and function in mammalian DNA. BioEssays. 40, 1700199. 10.1002/bies.201700199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bies.201700199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29369386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbst R. S., Baas P., Kim D.-W., Felip E., P&#xe9;rez-Gracia J. L., Han J.-Y., et al. (2016). Pembrolizumab versus docetaxel for previously treated, PD-L1-positive, advanced non-small-cell lung cancer (KEYNOTE-010): a randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 387, 1540&#x2013;1550. 10.1016/S0140-6736(15)01281-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(15)01281-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26712084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera A. F., LeBlanc M., Castellino S. M., Li H., Rutherford S. C., Evens A. M., et al. (2024). Nivolumab+AVD in advanced-stage classic hodgkin's lymphoma. N. Engl. J. Med. 391, 1379&#x2013;1389. 10.1056/NEJMoa2405888</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2405888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11488644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39413375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu C., Mi W., Li F., Zhu L., Ou Q., Li M., et al. (2024). Optimizing drug combination and mechanism analysis based on risk pathway crosstalk in pan cancer. Sci. Data. 11, 74. 10.1038/s41597-024-02915-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41597-024-02915-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10791624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38228620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S., H&#xf6;lzel M., Knijnenburg T., Schlicker A., Roepman P., McDermott U., et al. (2012). MED12 controls the response to multiple cancer drugs through regulation of TGF-&#x3b2; receptor signaling. Cell. 151, 937&#x2013;950. 10.1016/j.cell.2012.10.035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2012.10.035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3672971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23178117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang M., Huang J., Zheng Y., Sun Q. (2019). Histone acetyltransferase inhibitors: an overview in synthesis, structure-activity relationship and molecular mechanism. Eur. J. Med. Chem. 178, 259&#x2013;286. 10.1016/j.ejmech.2019.05.078</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejmech.2019.05.078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31195169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung S. K., Lee M. S., Chiou W. Y., Liu D. W., Yu C. C., Chen L. C., et al. (2024). Epigenetic modification in radiotherapy and immunotherapy for cancers. Tzu Chi Med. J. 36, 396&#x2013;406. 10.4103/tcmj.tcmj_3_24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/tcmj.tcmj_3_24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11483092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39421493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issa J.-P. J., Garcia-Manero G., Giles F. J., Mannari R., Thomas D., Faderl S., et al. (2004). Phase 1 study of low-dose prolonged exposure schedules of the hypomethylating agent 5-aza-2&#x2032;-deoxycytidine (decitabine) in hematopoietic malignancies. Blood. 103, 1635&#x2013;1640. 10.1182/blood-2003-03-0687</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2003-03-0687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14604977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong S. M., Xiao C., Finley L. W. S., Lahusen T., Souza A. L., Pierce K., et al. (2013). SIRT4 has tumor-suppressive activity and regulates the cellular metabolic response to DNA damage by inhibiting mitochondrial glutamine metabolism. Cancer Cell. 23, 450&#x2013;463. 10.1016/j.ccr.2013.02.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccr.2013.02.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3650305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23562301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson D. H., Fehrenbacher L., Novotny W. F., Herbst R. S., Nemunaitis J. J., Jablons D. M., et al. (2004). Randomized phase II trial comparing bevacizumab plus carboplatin and paclitaxel with carboplatin and paclitaxel alone in previously untreated locally advanced or metastatic non-small-cell lung cancer. J. Clin. Oncol. 22, 2184&#x2013;2191. 10.1200/jco.2004.11.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.2004.11.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15169807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson J. R., Cohen M., Sridhara R., Chen Y. F., Williams G. M., Duan J., et al. (2005). Approval summary for erlotinib for treatment of patients with locally advanced or metastatic non-small cell lung cancer after failure of at least one prior chemotherapy regimen. Clin. Cancer Res. 11, 6414&#x2013;6421. 10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-05-0790</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-05-0790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16166415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julia E., Salles G. (2021). EZH2 inhibition by tazemetostat: mechanisms of action, safety and efficacy in relapsed/refractory follicular lymphoma. Future Oncol. 17, 2127&#x2013;2140. 10.2217/fon-2020-1244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/fon-2020-1244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9892962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33709777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabbinavar F., Hurwitz H. I., Fehrenbacher L., Meropol N. J., Novotny W. F., Lieberman G., et al. (2003). Phase II, randomized trial comparing bevacizumab plus fluorouracil (FU)/leucovorin (LV) with FU/LV alone in patients with metastatic colorectal cancer. J. Clin. Oncol. 21, 60&#x2013;65. 10.1200/jco.2003.10.066</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.2003.10.066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12506171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabzi&#x144;ski J., Walczak A., Mik M., Majsterek I. (2019). Sirt3 regulates the level of mitochondrial DNA repair activity through deacetylation of NEIL1, NEIL2, OGG1, MUTYH, APE1 and LIG3 in colorectal cancer. Pol. Przegl Chir. 92, 1&#x2013;4. 10.5604/01.3001.0013.5539</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5604/01.3001.0013.5539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32312920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kagan A. B., Garrison D. A., Anders N. M., Webster J. A., Baker S. D., Yegnasubramanian S., et al. (2023). DNA methyltransferase inhibitor exposure-response: challenges and opportunities. Clin. Transl. Sci. 16, 1309&#x2013;1322. 10.1111/cts.13548</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cts.13548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10432879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37345219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantarjian H., Issa J. P., Rosenfeld C. S., Bennett J. M., Albitar M., DiPersio J., et al. (2006). Decitabine improves patient outcomes in myelodysplastic syndromes: results of a phase III randomized study. Cancer. 106, 1794&#x2013;1803. 10.1002/cncr.21792</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.21792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16532500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapl&#xe1;nek R., Kej&#xed;k Z., Hajduch J., Vesel&#xe1; K., Ku&#x10d;nirov&#xe1; K., Skali&#x10d;kov&#xe1; M., et al. (2023). TET protein inhibitors: potential and limitations. Biomed. Pharmacother. 166, 115324. 10.1016/j.biopha.2023.115324</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2023.115324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37598475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katani&#x107; Stankovi&#x107; J. S., Selakovi&#x107; D., Rosi&#x107; G. (2023). Oxidative damage as a fundament of systemic toxicities induced by cisplatin&#x2014;the crucial limitation or potential therapeutic target? Int. J. Mol. Sci. 24, 14574. 10.3390/ijms241914574</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms241914574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10572959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37834021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufman H. L., Russell J., Hamid O., Bhatia S., Terheyden P., D'Angelo S. P., et al. (2016). Avelumab in patients with chemotherapy-refractory metastatic merkel cell carcinoma: a multicentre, single-group, open-label, phase 2 trial. Lancet Oncol. 17, 1374&#x2013;1385. 10.1016/s1470-2045(16)30364-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(16)30364-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5587154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27592805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley R. K., Sangro B., Harris W., Ikeda M., Okusaka T., Kang Y. K., et al. (2021). Efficacy, and pharmacodynamics of tremelimumab plus durvalumab for patients with unresectable hepatocellular carcinoma: randomized expansion of a phase I/II study. J. Clin. Oncol. 39, 2991&#x2013;3001. 10.1200/jco.20.03555</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.20.03555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8445563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34292792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khozin S., Weinstock C., Blumenthal G. M., Cheng J., He K., Zhuang L., et al. (2017). Osimertinib for the treatment of metastatic EGFR T790M mutation-positive non-small cell lung cancer. Clin. Cancer Res. 23, 2131&#x2013;2135. 10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-16-1773</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-16-1773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27923840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King G. A., Hashemi Shabestari M., Taris K. H., Pandey A. K., Venkatesh S., Thilagavathi J., et al. (2018). Acetylation and phosphorylation of human TFAM regulate TFAM-DNA interactions via contrasting mechanisms. Nucleic Acids Res. 46, 3633&#x2013;3642. 10.1093/nar/gky204</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gky204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5909435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29897602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koka K., Verma A., Dwarakanath B. S., Papineni R. V. L. (2022). Technological advancements in external beam radiation therapy (EBRT): an indispensable tool for cancer treatment. Cancer Manag. Res. 14, 1421&#x2013;1429. 10.2147/cmar.S351744</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/cmar.S351744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9012312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35431581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopetz S., Yoshino T., Van Cutsem E., Eng C., Kim T. W., Wasan H. S., et al. (2025). Encorafenib, cetuximab and chemotherapy in BRAF-mutant colorectal cancer: a randomized phase 3 trial. Nat. Med. 31, 901&#x2013;908. 10.1038/s41591-024-03443-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-024-03443-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11922750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39863775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krop I. E., LoRusso P., Miller K. D., Modi S., Yardley D., Rodriguez G., et al. (2012). A phase II study of trastuzumab emtansine in patients with human epidermal growth factor receptor 2-positive metastatic breast cancer who were previously treated with trastuzumab, lapatinib, an anthracycline, a taxane, and capecitabine. J. Clin. Oncol. 30, 3234&#x2013;3241. 10.1200/jco.2011.40.5902</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.2011.40.5902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22649126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H. Z., Kwitkowski V. E., Del Valle P. L., Ricci M. S., Saber H., Habtemariam B. A., et al. (2015). FDA approval: Belinostat for the treatment of patients with relapsed or refractory peripheral T-cell lymphoma. Clin. Cancer Res. 21, 2666&#x2013;2670. 10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-14-3119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-14-3119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25802282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei T., Rui Y., Xiaoshuang Z., Jinglan Z., Jihong Z. (2024). Mitochondria transcription and cancer. Cell Death Discov. 10, 168. 10.1038/s41420-024-01926-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41420-024-01926-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11001877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38589371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lembo V., Bottegoni G. (2024). Systematic investigation of dual-target-directed ligands. J. Med. Chem. 67, 10374&#x2013;10385. 10.1021/acs.jmedchem.4c00838</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jmedchem.4c00838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11215722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38843874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenz H. J., Van Cutsem E., Luisa Limon M., Wong K. Y. M., Hendlisz A., Aglietta M., et al. (2022). First-line nivolumab plus low-dose ipilimumab for microsatellite instability-High/Mismatch repair-deficient metastatic colorectal cancer: the phase II CheckMate 142 study. J. Clin. Oncol. 40, 161&#x2013;170. 10.1200/jco.21.01015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.21.01015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34637336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., Tao Z., Zhao Y., Li L., Zheng J., Li Z., et al. (2022). 5-methylcytosine RNA methyltransferases and their potential roles in cancer. J. Transl. Med. 20, 214. 10.1186/s12967-022-03427-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-022-03427-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9102922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35562754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Gong C., Zhou H., Liu J., Xia X., Ha W., et al. (2024). Kinase inhibitors and kinase-targeted cancer therapies: recent advances and future perspectives. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 25, 5489. 10.3390/ijms25105489</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms25105489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11122109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38791529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F., Feng Y., Yin Z., Wang Y. (2025). Mitochondrial metabolism in T-Cell exhaustion. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 26, 7400. 10.3390/ijms26157400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms26157400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12347488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40806529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Yang Q. (2023). The roles of EZH2 in cancer and its inhibitors. Med. Oncol. 40, 167. 10.1007/s12032-023-02025-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12032-023-02025-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10162908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37148376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y. P., Zheng C. C., Huang Y. N., He M. L., Xu W. W., Li B. (2021). Molecular mechanisms of chemo- and radiotherapy resistance and the potential implications for cancer treatment. MedComm (2020). 2 (2), 315&#x2013;340. 10.1002/mco2.55</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mco2.55</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8554658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34766149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu D., Wang Y., Jing H., Meng Q., Yang J. (2022). Novel DNA methylation loci and genes showing pleiotropic association with Alzheimer's dementia: a network Mendelian randomization analysis. Epigenetics. 17, 746&#x2013;758. 10.1080/15592294.2021.1959735</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15592294.2021.1959735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9336475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34461811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B., Zhou H., Tan L., Siu K. T. H., Guan X.-Y. (2024a). Exploring treatment options in cancer: tumor treatment strategies. Signal Transduct. Target. Ther. 9, 175. 10.1038/s41392-024-01856-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41392-024-01856-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11252281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39013849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z., Chen J., Ren Y., Liu S., Ba Y., Zuo A., et al. (2024b). Multi-stage mechanisms of tumor metastasis and therapeutic strategies. Signal Transduct. Target. Ther. 9, 270. 10.1038/s41392-024-01955-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41392-024-01955-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11467208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39389953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lordick F., Van Cutsem E., Shitara K., Xu R. H., Ajani J. A., Shah M. A., et al. (2024). Health-related quality of life in patients with CLDN18.2-positive, locally advanced unresectable or metastatic gastric or gastroesophageal junction adenocarcinoma: results from the SPOTLIGHT and GLOW clinical trials. ESMO Open. 9, 103663. 10.1016/j.esmoop.2024.103663</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.esmoop.2024.103663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11374961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39146670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu X., Ning Z., Li Z., Cao H., Wang X. (2016). Development of chidamide for peripheral T-cell lymphoma, the first orphan drug approved in China. Intractable Rare Dis. Res. 5, 185&#x2013;191. 10.5582/irdr.2016.01024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5582/irdr.2016.01024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4995415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27672541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Lu S., Kato T., Dong X., Ahn M.-J., Quang L.-V., Soparattanapaisarn N., et al.  (2024). Osimertinib after chemoradiotherapy in stage III <i>EGFR</i>-mutated NSCLC. N. Engl. J. Med.
391, 585&#x2013;597. 10.1056/NEJMoa2402614

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2402614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38828946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makita S., Yamamoto G., Maruyama D., Asano-Mori Y., Kaji D., Ananthakrishnan R., et al. (2022). Phase 2 results of lisocabtagene maraleucel in Japanese patients with relapsed/refractory aggressive B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Cancer Med. 11, 4889&#x2013;4899. 10.1002/cam4.4820</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cam4.4820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9761090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35619325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marabelle A., Le D. T., Ascierto P. A., Di Giacomo A. M., De Jesus-Acosta A., Delord J. P., et al. (2020). Efficacy of pembrolizumab in patients with noncolorectal high microsatellite instability/mismatch repair-deficient cancer: results from the phase II KEYNOTE-158 study. J. Clin. Oncol. 38, 1&#x2013;10. 10.1200/jco.19.02105</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.19.02105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8184060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31682550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Reyes I., Chandel N. S. (2020). Mitochondrial TCA cycle metabolites control physiology and disease. Nat. Commun. 11, 102. 10.1038/s41467-019-13668-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-019-13668-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6941980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31900386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellinghoff I. K., van den Bent M. J., Blumenthal D. T., Touat M., Peters K. B., Clarke J., et al. (2023a). Vorasidenib in IDH1- or IDH2-Mutant low-grade glioma. N. Engl. J. Med. 389, 589&#x2013;601. 10.1056/NEJMoa2304194</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2304194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11445763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37272516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellinghoff I. K., Lu M., Wen P. Y., Taylor J. W., Maher E. A., Arrillaga-Romany I., et al. (2023b). Vorasidenib and ivosidenib in IDH1-mutant low-grade glioma: a randomized, perioperative phase 1 trial. Nat. Med. 29, 615&#x2013;622. 10.1038/s41591-022-02141-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-02141-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10313524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36823302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menghrajani K., Cai S. F., Devlin S. M., Armstrong S. A., Piekarz R., Rudek M., et al. (2019). A phase Ib/II study of the histone methyltransferase inhibitor pinometostat in combination with azacitidine in patients with 11q23-Rearranged acute myeloid leukemia. Blood. 134, 2655. 10.1182/blood-2019-121926</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2019-121926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meric-Bernstam F., Beeram M., Hamilton E., Oh D. Y., Hanna D. L., Kang Y. K., et al. (2022). Zanidatamab, a novel bispecific antibody, for the treatment of locally advanced or metastatic HER2-expressing or HER2-amplified cancers: a phase 1, dose-escalation and expansion study. Lancet Oncol. 23, 1558&#x2013;1570. 10.1016/s1470-2045(22)00621-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(22)00621-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36400106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migden M. R., Rischin D., Schmults C. D., Guminski A., Hauschild A., Lewis K. D., et al. (2018). PD-1 blockade with cemiplimab in advanced cutaneous squamous-cell carcinoma. N. Engl. J. Med. 379, 341&#x2013;351. 10.1056/NEJMoa1805131</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1805131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29863979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min H. Y., Lee H. Y. (2022). Molecular targeted therapy for anticancer treatment. Exp. Mol. Med. 54, 1670&#x2013;1694. 10.1038/s12276-022-00864-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s12276-022-00864-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9636149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36224343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirza M. R., Chase D. M., Slomovitz B. M., dePont Christensen R., Nov&#xe1;k Z., Black D., et al. (2023). Dostarlimab for primary advanced or recurrent endometrial cancer. N. Engl. J. Med. 388, 2145&#x2013;2158. 10.1056/NEJMoa2216334</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2216334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36972026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittendorf E. A., Zhang H., Barrios C. H., Saji S., Jung K. H., Hegg R., et al. (2020). Neoadjuvant atezolizumab in combination with sequential nab-paclitaxel and anthracycline-based chemotherapy versus placebo and chemotherapy in patients with early-stage triple-negative breast cancer (IMpassion031): a randomised, double-blind, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 396, 1090&#x2013;1100. 10.1016/s0140-6736(20)31953-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(20)31953-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32966830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore M. J., Goldstein D., Hamm J., Figer A., Hecht J. R., Gallinger S., et al. (2007). Erlotinib plus gemcitabine compared with gemcitabine alone in patients with advanced pancreatic cancer: a phase III trial of the national cancer institute of Canada clinical trials group. J. Clin. Oncol. 25, 1960&#x2013;1966. 10.1200/jco.2006.07.9525</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.2006.07.9525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17452677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan N. (2025). Nucleoside and non-nucleoside DNA methyltransferase 1 inhibitors in epigenetic and combination therapies in cancer: a scoping review. Undergrad. Res. Nat. Clin. Sci. Technol. (URNCST) J. 9, 1&#x2013;8. 10.26685/urncst.641</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26685/urncst.641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morschhauser F., Tilly H., Chaidos A., McKay P., Phillips T., Assouline S., et al. (2020). Tazemetostat for patients with relapsed or refractory follicular lymphoma: an open-label, single-arm, multicentre, phase 2 trial. Lancet Oncol. 21, 1433&#x2013;1442. 10.1016/s1470-2045(20)30441-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(20)30441-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8427481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33035457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosca L., Vitiello F., Borzacchiello L., Coppola A., Tranchese R. V., Pagano M., et al. (2021). Mutual correlation between non-coding RNA and S-Adenosylmethionine in human cancer: roles and therapeutic opportunities. Cancers (Basel). 13, 3264. 10.3390/cancers13133264</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers13133264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8268931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34209866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motzer R. J., Hutson T. E., Tomczak P., Michaelson M. D., Bukowski R. M., Rixe O., et al. (2007). Sunitinib versus interferon alfa in metastatic renal-cell carcinoma. N. Engl. J. Med. 356, 115&#x2013;124. 10.1056/NEJMoa065044</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa065044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17215529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motzer R. J., Escudier B., McDermott D. F., George S., Hammers H. J., Srinivas S., et al. (2015). Nivolumab versus everolimus in advanced renal-cell carcinoma. N. Engl. J. Med. 373, 1803&#x2013;1813. 10.1056/NEJMoa1510665</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1510665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5719487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26406148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munshi N. C., Anderson L. D., Jr., Shah N., Madduri D., Berdeja J., Lonial S., et al. (2021). Idecabtagene vicleucel in relapsed and refractory multiple myeloma. N. Engl. J. Med. 384, 705&#x2013;716. 10.1056/NEJMoa2024850</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2024850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33626253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagaya T., Nakamura Y. A., Choyke P. L., Kobayashi H. (2017). Fluorescence-guided surgery. Front. Oncol. 7, 314. 10.3389/fonc.2017.00314</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2017.00314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5743791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29312886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neelapu S. S., Locke F. L., Bartlett N. L., Lekakis L. J., Miklos D. B., Jacobson C. A., et al. (2017). Axicabtagene ciloleucel CAR T-Cell therapy in refractory large B-Cell lymphoma. N. Engl. J. Med. 377, 2531&#x2013;2544. 10.1056/NEJMoa1707447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1707447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5882485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29226797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neganova M. E., Klochkov S. G., Aleksandrova Y. R., Aliev G. (2022). Histone modifications in epigenetic regulation of cancer: perspectives and achieved progress. Semin. Cancer Biol. 83, 452&#x2013;471. 10.1016/j.semcancer.2020.07.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semcancer.2020.07.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32814115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitsch S., Zorro Shahidian L., Schneider R. (2021). Histone acylations and chromatin dynamics: concepts, challenges, and links to metabolism. EMBO Reports. 22, e52774. 10.15252/embr.202152774</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15252/embr.202152774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8406397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34159701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noce B., Di Bello E., Fioravanti R., Mai A. (2023). LSD1 inhibitors for cancer treatment: focus on multi-target agents and compounds in clinical trials. Front. Pharmacol. 14, 14&#x2013;2023. 10.3389/fphar.2023.1120911</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2023.1120911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9932783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36817147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nouri Z., Fakhri S., Nouri K., Wallace C. E., Farzaei M. H., Bishayee A. (2020). Targeting multiple signaling pathways in cancer: the rutin therapeutic approach. Cancers (Basel). 12. 10.3390/cancers12082276</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers12082276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7463935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32823876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Leary M. C., Lu X., Huang Y., Lin X., Mahmood I., Przepiorka D., et al. (2019). FDA approval summary: tisagenlecleucel for treatment of patients with relapsed or refractory B-cell precursor acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Clin. Cancer Res. 25, 1142&#x2013;1146. 10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-18-2035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-18-2035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30309857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh D. Y., He A. R., Bouattour M., Okusaka T., Qin S., Chen L. T., et al. (2024). Durvalumab or placebo plus gemcitabine and cisplatin in participants with advanced biliary tract cancer (TOPAZ-1): updated overall survival from a randomised phase 3 study. Lancet Gastroenterol. Hepatol. 9, 694&#x2013;704. 10.1016/s2468-1253(24)00095-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s2468-1253(24)00095-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38823398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira M., Rugo H. S., Howell S. J., Dalenc F., Cortes J., Gomez H. L., et al. (2024). Capivasertib and fulvestrant for patients with hormone receptor-positive, HER2-negative advanced breast cancer (CAPItello-291): patient-reported outcomes from a phase 3, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Oncol. 25, 1231&#x2013;1244. 10.1016/s1470-2045(24)00373-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(24)00373-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39214106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen E. A., Kim Y. H., Kuzel T. M., Pacheco T. R., Foss F. M., Parker S., et al. (2007). Phase IIb multicenter trial of vorinostat in patients with persistent, progressive, or treatment refractory cutaneous T-cell lymphoma. J. Clin. Oncol. 25, 3109&#x2013;3115. 10.1200/jco.2006.10.2434</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.2006.10.2434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17577020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan J., Liu F., Xiao X., Xu R., Dai L., Zhu M., et al. (2022). METTL3 promotes colorectal carcinoma progression by regulating the m6A&#x2013;CRB3&#x2013;Hippo axis. J. Exp. and Clin. Cancer Res. 41, 19. 10.1186/s13046-021-02227-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13046-021-02227-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8744223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35012593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey P., Verma M., Lakhanpal S., Pandey S., Kumar M. R., Bhat M., et al. (2025). An updated review summarizing the anticancer potential of Poly(Lactic-co-Glycolic acid) (PLGA) based curcumin, epigallocatechin gallate, and resveratrol nanocarriers. Biopolymers. 116, e23637. 10.1002/bip.23637</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bip.23637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39417679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel M. R., Ellerton J., Infante J. R., Agrawal M., Gordon M., Aljumaily R., et al. (2018). Avelumab in metastatic urothelial carcinoma after platinum failure (JAVELIN solid tumor): pooled results from two expansion cohorts of an open-label, phase 1 trial. Lancet Oncol. 19, 51&#x2013;64. 10.1016/s1470-2045(17)30900-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(17)30900-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7984727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29217288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paz-Ares L., Dvorkin M., Chen Y., Reinmuth N., Hotta K., Trukhin D., et al. (2019). Durvalumab plus platinum-etoposide versus platinum-etoposide in first-line treatment of extensive-stage small-cell lung cancer (CASPIAN): a randomised, controlled, open-label, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 394, 1929&#x2013;1939. 10.1016/s0140-6736(19)32222-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(19)32222-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31590988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piekarz R. L., Frye R., Turner M., Wright J. J., Allen S. L., Kirschbaum M. H., et al. (2009). Phase II multi-institutional trial of the histone deacetylase inhibitor romidepsin as monotherapy for patients with cutaneous T-cell lymphoma. J. Clin. Oncol. 27, 5410&#x2013;5417. 10.1200/jco.2008.21.6150</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.2008.21.6150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2773225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19826128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piekarz R. L., Frye R., Prince H. M., Kirschbaum M. H., Zain J., Allen S. L., et al. (2011). Phase 2 trial of romidepsin in patients with peripheral T-cell lymphoma. Blood. 117, 5827&#x2013;5834. 10.1182/blood-2010-10-312603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2010-10-312603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3112033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21355097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Planchard D., Yokoi T., McCleod M. J., Fischer J. R., Kim Y. C., Ballas M., et al. (2016). A phase III study of durvalumab (MEDI4736) with or without tremelimumab for previously treated patients with advanced NSCLC: rationale and protocol design of the ARCTIC study. Clin. Lung Cancer. 17, 232&#x2013;236.e231. 10.1016/j.cllc.2016.03.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cllc.2016.03.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27265743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poole R. M. (2014). Belinostat: first global approval. Drugs. 74, 1543&#x2013;1554. 10.1007/s40265-014-0275-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40265-014-0275-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25134672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourzia A. L., Olson M. L., Bailey S. R., Boroughs A. C., Aryal A., Ryan J., et al. (2023). Quantifying requirements for mitochondrial apoptosis in CAR T killing of cancer cells. Cell Death and Dis. 14, 267. 10.1038/s41419-023-05727-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41419-023-05727-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10101951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37055388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puppi M., Sacchetti I., Mancuso K., Tacchetti P., Pantani L., Rizzello I., et al. (2025). Bispecific antibodies and CAR T in multiple myeloma: appropriate selection of patients and sequencing. Mediterr. J. Hematol. Infect. Dis. 17, e2025045. 10.4084/mjhid.2025.045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4084/mjhid.2025.045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12081044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40375902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin S., Chen M., Cheng A. L., Kaseb A. O., Kudo M., Lee H. C., et al. (2023). Atezolizumab plus bevacizumab versus active surveillance in patients with resected or ablated high-risk hepatocellular carcinoma (IMbrave050): a randomised, open-label, multicentre, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 402, 1835&#x2013;1847. 10.1016/s0140-6736(23)01796-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(23)01796-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37871608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu M. Z., Oh D. Y., Kato K., Arkenau T., Tabernero J., Correa M. C., et al. (2024). Tislelizumab plus chemotherapy versus placebo plus chemotherapy as first line treatment for advanced gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction adenocarcinoma: RATIONALE-305 randomised, double blind, phase 3 trial. Bmj. 385, e078876. 10.1136/bmj-2023-078876</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2023-078876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38806195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rad S. M. A., Halpin J. C., Mollaei M., Smith Bell S. W. J., Hirankarn N., McLellan A. D. (2021). Metabolic and mitochondrial functioning in chimeric antigen receptor (CAR)-T cells. Cancers (Basel). 13. 10.3390/cancers13061229</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers13061229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8002030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33799768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rando O. J. (2012). Combinatorial complexity in chromatin structure and function: revisiting the histone code. Curr. Opin. Genet. and Dev. 22, 148&#x2013;155. 10.1016/j.gde.2012.02.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gde.2012.02.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3345062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22440480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raymond E., Dahan L., Raoul J.-L., Bang Y.-J., Borbath I., Lombard-Bohas C., et al. (2011). Sunitinib malate for the treatment of pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors. N. Engl. J. Med. 364, 501&#x2013;513. 10.1056/NEJMoa1003825</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1003825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21306237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid M. A., Dai Z., Locasale J. W. (2017). The impact of cellular metabolism on chromatin dynamics and epigenetics. Nat. Cell Biol. 19, 1298&#x2013;1306. 10.1038/ncb3629</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncb3629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5886854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29058720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizvi N. A., Mazi&#xe8;res J., Planchard D., Stinchcombe T. E., Dy G. K., Antonia S. J., et al. (2015). Activity and safety of nivolumab, an anti-PD-1 immune checkpoint inhibitor, for patients with advanced, refractory squamous non-small-cell lung cancer (checkMate 063): a phase 2, single-arm trial. Lancet Oncol. 16, 257&#x2013;265. 10.1016/s1470-2045(15)70054-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(15)70054-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5726228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25704439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg J. E., Hoffman-Censits J., Powles T., van der Heijden M. S., Balar A. V., Necchi A., et al. (2016). Atezolizumab in patients with locally advanced and metastatic urothelial carcinoma who have progressed following treatment with platinum-based chemotherapy: a single-arm, multicentre, phase 2 trial. Lancet. 387, 1909&#x2013;1920. 10.1016/s0140-6736(16)00561-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(16)00561-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5480242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26952546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royce M., Shah M., Zhang L., Cheng J., Bonner M. K., Pegues M., et al. (2025). FDA approval summary: Datopotamab deruxtecan-dlnk for treatment of patients with unresectable or metastatic, HR-positive, HER2-negative breast cancer. Clin. Cancer Res. 31, 4405&#x2013;4411. 10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-25-1388</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-25-1388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12393668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40864501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rugo H. S., Bardia A., Marm&#xe9; F., Cort&#xe9;s J., Schmid P., Loirat D., et al. (2023). Overall survival with sacituzumab govitecan in hormone receptor-positive and human epidermal growth factor receptor 2-negative metastatic breast cancer (TROPiCS-02): a randomised, open-label, multicentre, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 402, 1423&#x2013;1433. 10.1016/s0140-6736(23)01245-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(23)01245-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37633306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rugo H. S., Oliveira M., Howell S. J., Dalenc F., Cortes J., Gomez H. L., et al. (2024). Capivasertib and fulvestrant for patients with hormone receptor-positive advanced breast cancer: characterization, time course, and management of frequent adverse events from the phase III CAPItello-291 study. ESMO Open. 9, 103697. 10.1016/j.esmoop.2024.103697</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.esmoop.2024.103697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11406080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39241495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryszkiewicz P., Malinowska B., Schlicker E. (2025). Polypharmacology: new drugs in 2023&#x2013;2024. Pharmacol. Rep. 77, 543&#x2013;560. 10.1007/s43440-025-00715-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43440-025-00715-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12066383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40095348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos J. M., Mishra M., Kowluru R. A. (2014). Posttranslational modification of mitochondrial transcription factor A in impaired mitochondria biogenesis: implications in diabetic retinopathy and metabolic memory phenomenon. Exp. Eye Res. 121, 168&#x2013;177. 10.1016/j.exer.2014.02.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exer.2014.02.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4036231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24607487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seiwert T. Y., Burtness B., Mehra R., Weiss J., Berger R., Eder J. P., et al. (2016). Safety and clinical activity of pembrolizumab for treatment of recurrent or metastatic squamous cell carcinoma of the head and neck (KEYNOTE-012): an open-label, multicentre, phase 1b trial. Lancet Oncol. 17, 956&#x2013;965. 10.1016/S1470-2045(16)30066-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(16)30066-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27247226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah V., McNatty A., Simpson L., Ofori H., Raheem F. (2023). Amivantamab-vmjw: a novel treatment for patients with NSCLC harboring EGFR exon 20 insertion mutation after progression on platinum-based chemotherapy. Biomedicines. 11, 950. 10.3390/biomedicines11030950</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines11030950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10046583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36979929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang R., Lee S., Senavirathne G., Lai E. C. (2023). microRNAs in action: biogenesis, function and regulation. Nat. Rev. Genet. 24, 816&#x2013;833. 10.1038/s41576-023-00611-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41576-023-00611-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11087887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37380761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S. V., Lee D. Y., Li B., Quinlan M. P., Takahashi F., Maheswaran S., et al. (2010). A chromatin-mediated reversible drug-tolerant state in cancer cell subpopulations. Cell. 141, 69&#x2013;80. 10.1016/j.cell.2010.02.027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2010.02.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2851638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20371346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Shepherd F. A., Pereira J., Ciuleanu T. E., Tan E. H., Hirsh V., Thongprasert S., et al.  (2004). A randomized placebo-controlled trial of erlotinib in patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) following failure of 1<sup>st</sup> line or 2<sup>nd</sup> line chemotherapy. A national cancer institute of Canada clinical trials group (NCIC CTG) trial. J. Clin. Oncol.
22, 7022. 10.1200/jco.2004.22.90140.7022
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.2004.22.90140.7022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y., Jia B., Xu W., Li W., Liu T., Liu P., et al. (2017). Chidamide in relapsed or refractory peripheral T cell lymphoma: a multicenter real-world study in China. J. Hematol. Oncol. 10, 69. 10.1186/s13045-017-0439-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13045-017-0439-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5351273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28298231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shock L. S., Thakkar P. V., Peterson E. J., Moran R. G., Taylor S. M. (2011). DNA methyltransferase 1, cytosine methylation, and cytosine hydroxymethylation in Mammalian mitochondria. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 108, 3630&#x2013;3635. 10.1073/pnas.1012311108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1012311108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3048134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21321201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirard M.-A. (2019). Distribution and dynamics of mitochondrial DNA methylation in oocytes, embryos and granulosa cells. Sci. Rep. 9, 11937. 10.1038/s41598-019-48422-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-48422-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6695495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31417147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smalley J. P., Cowley S. M., Hodgkinson J. T. (2020). Bifunctional HDAC therapeutics: one drug to rule them all? Molecules. 25. 10.3390/molecules25194394</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules25194394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7583022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32987782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y., Zhu X. Y., Zhang X. M., Xiong H. (2022). Targeted mitochondrial epigenetics: a new direction in Alzheimer's disease treatment. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 23, 9703. 10.3390/ijms23179703</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23179703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9456144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36077101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soria J.-C., Ohe Y., Vansteenkiste J., Reungwetwattana T., Chewaskulyong B., Lee K. H., et al. (2018). Osimertinib in untreated EGFR-mutated advanced Non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. N. Engl. J. Med. 378, 113&#x2013;125. 10.1056/NEJMoa1713137</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1713137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29151359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein E. M., DiNardo C. D., Pollyea D. A., Fathi A. T., Roboz G. J., Altman J. K., et al. (2017). Enasidenib in mutant IDH2 relapsed or refractory acute myeloid leukemia. Blood. 130, 722&#x2013;731. 10.1182/blood-2017-04-779405</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2017-04-779405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5572791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28588020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein E. M., Garcia-Manero G., Rizzieri D. A., Tibes R., Berdeja J. G., Savona M. R., et al. (2018). The DOT1L inhibitor pinometostat reduces H3K79 methylation and has modest clinical activity in adult acute leukemia. Blood. 131, 2661&#x2013;2669. 10.1182/blood-2017-12-818948</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2017-12-818948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6265654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29724899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoccoro A., Copped&#xe8; F. (2021). Mitochondrial DNA methylation and human diseases. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 22, 4594. 10.3390/ijms22094594</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22094594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8123858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33925624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumiyoshi A., Shibata S., Zhelev Z., Miller T., Lazarova D., Aoki I., et al. (2022). Targeting glioblastoma via selective alteration of mitochondrial redox state. Cancers (Basel). 14, 485. 10.3390/cancers14030485</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers14030485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8833725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35158753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X., Vaghjiani V., Jayasekara W. S. N., Cain J. E., St John J. C. (2018). The degree of mitochondrial DNA methylation in tumor models of glioblastoma and osteosarcoma. Clin. Epigenetics. 10, 157. 10.1186/s13148-018-0590-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13148-018-0590-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6296150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30558637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suraweera A., O&#x2019;Byrne K. J., Richard D. J. (2025). Epigenetic drugs in cancer therapy. Cancer Metastasis Rev. 44, 37. 10.1007/s10555-025-10253-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10555-025-10253-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11865116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40011240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swain S. M., Shastry M., Hamilton E. (2023). Targeting HER2-positive breast cancer: advances and future directions. Nat. Rev. Drug Discov. 22, 101&#x2013;126. 10.1038/s41573-022-00579-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41573-022-00579-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9640784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36344672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>To K. K. W., Xing E., Larue R. C., Li P. K. (2023). BET bromodomain inhibitors: novel design strategies and therapeutic applications. Molecules. 28, 3043. 10.3390/molecules28073043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules28073043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10096006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37049806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torrens-Mas M., Hern&#xe1;ndez-L&#xf3;pez R., Pons D.-G., Roca P., Oliver J., Sastre-Serra J. (2019). Sirtuin 3 silencing impairs mitochondrial biogenesis and metabolism in colon cancer cells. Am. J. Physiology-Cell Physiology. 317, C398&#x2013;C404. 10.1152/ajpcell.00112.2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00112.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31188638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner N. C., Oliveira M., Howell S. J., Dalenc F., Cortes J., Gomez Moreno H. L., et al. (2023). Capivasertib in hormone receptor-positive advanced breast cancer. N. Engl. J. Med. 388, 2058&#x2013;2070. 10.1056/NEJMoa2214131</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2214131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11335038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37256976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tykodi S. S., Gordan L. N., Alter R. S., Arrowsmith E., Harrison M. R., Percent I., et al. (2022). Safety and efficacy of nivolumab plus ipilimumab in patients with advanced non-clear cell renal cell carcinoma: results from the phase 3b/4 CheckMate 920 trial. J. Immunother. Cancer 10, e003844. 10.1136/jitc-2021-003844</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jitc-2021-003844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8883262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35210307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Haute L., Dietmann S., Kremer L., Hussain S., Pearce S. F., Powell C. A., et al. (2016). Deficient methylation and formylation of mt-tRNAMet wobble cytosine in a patient carrying mutations in NSUN3. Nat. Commun. 7, 12039. 10.1038/ncomms12039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms12039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4931328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27356879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verweij J., van Oosterom A., Blay J. Y., Judson I., Rodenhuis S., van der Graaf W., et al. (2003). Imatinib mesylate (STI-571 glivec, gleevec) is an active agent for gastrointestinal stromal tumours, but does not yield responses in other soft-tissue sarcomas that are unselected for a molecular target. Results from an EORTC soft tissue and bone sarcoma group phase II study. Eur. J. Cancer. 39, 2006&#x2013;2011. 10.1016/S0959-8049(02)00836-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0959-8049(02)00836-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12957454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Zhou Y., Xu L., Xiao R., Lu X., Chen L., et al. (2015). Molecular basis for 5-carboxycytosine recognition by RNA polymerase II elongation complex. Nature. 523, 621&#x2013;625. 10.1038/nature14482</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature14482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4521995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26123024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Zhang Q., Hu X., Li Q., Sun T., Li W., et al. (2024). a class I selective histone deacetylase inhibitor, plus exemestane for Chinese patients with hormone receptor-positive advanced breast cancer: an overall survival update and long-term safety from the randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. J. Clin. Oncol. 42, 1050. 10.1200/JCO.2024.42.16_suppl.1050</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2024.42.16_suppl.1050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R., Hu B., Pan Z., Mo C., Zhao X., Liu G., et al. (2025). Antibody&#x2013;drug conjugates (ADCs): current and future biopharmaceuticals. J. Hematol. and Oncol. 18, 51. 10.1186/s13045-025-01704-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13045-025-01704-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12044742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40307936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber J. S., D'Angelo S. P., Minor D., Hodi F. S., Gutzmer R., Neyns B., et al. (2015). Nivolumab versus chemotherapy in patients with advanced melanoma who progressed after anti-CTLA-4 treatment (checkMate 037): a randomised, controlled, open-label, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 16, 375&#x2013;384. 10.1016/s1470-2045(15)70076-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(15)70076-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25795410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolchok J. D., Neyns B., Linette G., Negrier S., Lutzky J., Thomas L., et al. (2010). Ipilimumab monotherapy in patients with pretreated advanced melanoma: a randomised, double-blind, multicentre, phase 2, dose-ranging study. Lancet Oncol. 11, 155&#x2013;164. 10.1016/s1470-2045(09)70334-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(09)70334-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20004617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J., Kato K., Raymond E., Hubner R. A., Shu Y., Pan Y., et al. (2023). Tislelizumab plus chemotherapy versus placebo plus chemotherapy as first-line treatment for advanced or metastatic oesophageal squamous cell carcinoma (RATIONALE-306): a global, randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 study. Lancet Oncol. 24, 483&#x2013;495. 10.1016/s1470-2045(23)00108-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(23)00108-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37080222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yalniz F. F., Berdeja J. G., Maris M. B., Lyons R. M., Reeves J. A., Jr., Essell J. H., et al. (2020). A phase II study of addition of pracinostat to a hypomethylating agent in patients with myelodysplastic syndromes who have not responded to previous hypomethylating agent therapy. Br. J. Haematol. 188, 404&#x2013;412. 10.1111/bjh.16173</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjh.16173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31468521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashita T., Sohn J. H., Tokunaga E., Niikura N., Park Y. H., Lee K. S., et al. (2024). Trastuzumab deruxtecan versus treatment of physician's choice in previously treated Asian patients with HER2-low unresectable/metastatic breast cancer: subgroup analysis of the DESTINY-Breast04 study. Breast Cancer. 31, 858&#x2013;868. 10.1007/s12282-024-01600-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12282-024-01600-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11341650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38884900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J. C., Haworth L., Sherry R. M., Hwu P., Schwartzentruber D. J., Topalian S. L., et al. (2003). A randomized trial of bevacizumab, an anti-vascular endothelial growth factor antibody, for metastatic renal cancer. N. Engl. J. Med. 349, 427&#x2013;434. 10.1056/NEJMoa021491</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa021491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2275324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12890841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeruva S. L. H., Zhao F., Miller K. D., Tevaarwerk A. J., Wagner L. I., Gray R. J., et al. (2018). E2112: randomized phase iii trial of endocrine therapy plus entinostat/placebo in patients with hormone receptor-positive advanced breast cancer. NPJ Breast Cancer. 4, 1. 10.1038/s41523-017-0053-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41523-017-0053-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5765007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29354686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Yue Y., Ren L., Zhang C., Miao K., Tan K., Yang Q., et al.  (2022). Mitochondrial genome undergoes <i>de novo</i> DNA methylation that protects mtDNA against oxidative damage during the peri-implantation window. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci.
119, e2201168119. 10.1073/pnas.2201168119

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2201168119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9335330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35858425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng X., Lu Y., Zeng T., Liu W., Huang W., Yu T., et al. (2024). RNA demethylase FTO participates in malignant progression of gastric cancer by regulating SP1-AURKB-ATM pathway. Commun. Biol. 7, 800. 10.1038/s42003-024-06477-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42003-024-06477-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11220007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38956367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Duan S., Jang A., Mao L., Liu X., Huang G. (2021). JQ1, a selective inhibitor of BRD4, suppresses retinoblastoma cell growth by inducing cell cycle arrest and apoptosis. Exp. Eye Res. 202, 108304. 10.1016/j.exer.2020.108304</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exer.2020.108304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33080301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J., Wu S., Wang D., Edwards H., Thibodeau J., Kim S., et al. (2024). Panobinostat sensitizes AraC-resistant AML cells to the combination of azacitidine and venetoclax. Biochem. Pharmacol. 228, 116065. 10.1016/j.bcp.2024.116065</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bcp.2024.116065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12758454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38373594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng B., Fu J., Wang Y., Wu J., Wang J., Li H. (2025a). Preclinical and case series studies on the combination of venetoclax with epigenetic drugs in T-Cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Cancer Manag. Res. 17, 2513&#x2013;2521. 10.2147/cmar.S523414</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/cmar.S523414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12579832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41185639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Z., Lin F., Zhao B., Chen G., Wei C., Chen X., et al. (2025b). ALKBH5 suppresses gastric cancer tumorigenesis and metastasis by inhibiting the translation of uncapped WRAP53 RNA isoforms in an m6A-dependent manner. Mol. Cancer. 24, 19. 10.1186/s12943-024-02223-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12943-024-02223-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11734446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39815301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S., Zhang S., Wang L., Huang S., Yuan Y., Yang J., et al. (2020). BET protein inhibitor JQ1 downregulates chromatin accessibility and suppresses metastasis of gastric cancer via inactivating RUNX2/NID1 signaling. Oncogenesis. 9, 33. 10.1038/s41389-020-0218-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41389-020-0218-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7064486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32157097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu A. X., Macarulla T., Javle M. M., Kelley R. K., Lubner S. J., Adeva J., et al. (2021). Final overall survival efficacy results of ivosidenib for patients with advanced cholangiocarcinoma with IDH1 mutation: the phase 3 randomized clinical ClarIDHy trial. JAMA Oncol. 7, 1669&#x2013;1677. 10.1001/jamaoncol.2021.3836</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoncol.2021.3836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8461552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34554208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>