<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41087903</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2164</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC genomics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Genomics</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative analysis of Chloroplast genomes in 48 samples from 5 species and 2 varieties of Agropyron&#xa0;Gaertn. (Poaceae, Triticeae).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>912</StartPage><MedlinePgn>912</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">912</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12864-025-12026-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Agropyron belongs to Triticeae of the Poaceae family; its plants are rich in nutrients and have good palatability, serving as important forage grasses in the temperate zone of the Northern Hemisphere. The accurate identification of Agropyron germplasm resources is essential for breeding. However, the morphological variation of Agropyron is complex, making identification on the basis of traditional morphological characteristics difficult. Molecular markers are effective tools for the rapid and accurate identification of many forage plants. Therefore, in this study, second-generation high-throughput sequencing, chloroplast genome assembly, chloroplast genome comparison, and phylogenetic analysis were conducted on 48 Agropyron samples from 5 species and 2 varieties.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Using next-generation sequencing reads, the chloroplast genome was assembled and annotated. Analyses of repetitive sequences, codon usage bias, and nucleotide diversity revealed high conservation: the genome length ranged from 135,321 to 135,564&#xa0;bp, the GC content was stable at 38%, and all the genomes encoded 132 consistent genes. Simple repeat sequences (SSRs) were mainly of the A/T type (21-28), and direct repeats were predominant in long repeat sequences (29-31). Each sample harbored 29-34 tandem repeats, with Agropyron mongolicum Keng (0506) showing the maximum (34). The long repeat sequence included 13 palindromic and 29-31 forward repeats in most samples, with no reverse or complementary repeats detected. The codon endings were predominantly A/U (RSCU&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;1 codons accounted for 48.4%). Nucleotide diversity analysis revealed 6 hypervariable regions (e.g., psbA and rpl32), but the hypervariable regions did not contain enough informative sites to distinguish the five species of Agropyron. In the phylogenetic tree, all Agropyron samples formed a highly supported monophyletic clade (bootstrap&#x2009;=&#x2009;100), but the intragenus relationships among the five species and two varieties remained unresolved, most likely due to insufficient phylogenetically informative sites because there were only 178 phylogenetically informative sites in the 135,978 chloroplast effective sites (0.13%). We also did not find species-specific chloroplast genome SNPs or indels. PCA revealed that different species could not be separated on the first two principal components. STRUCTURE analysis based on Angiosperms353 markers showed that K&#x2009;=&#x2009;2 was the optimal grouping result, but the genetic grouping did not match the taxonomy of Agropyron, which was consistent with the results of analysis based on the chloroplast genome.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our study comprehensively revealed the chloroplast genome information of Agropyron plants and its consistency across the genus.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Lina</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inner Mongolia Agricultural University, Hohhot, 010018, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duan</LastName><ForeName>Menglu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>M-Grass Ecology and Environment (Group) Co., Ltd, Hohhot, 010030, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zhongshuai</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Key Laboratory of Tree Genetics and Breeding, Chinese Academy of Forestry, Beijing, 100091, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chunyan</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>M-Grass Ecology and Environment (Group) Co., Ltd, Hohhot, 010030, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhaoming</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center of Pratacultural Technology Innovation (under preparation), Hohhot, 010030, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Guangyan</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Germplasm Bank of Wild Species, Kunming Institute of Botany, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Kunming, 650201, Yunnan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Mingjiu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inner Mongolia Agricultural University, Hohhot, 010018, China. wangmj_0540@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Genomics</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100965258</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2164</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054628" MajorTopicYN="Y">Genome, Chloroplast</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D031702" MajorTopicYN="Y">Agropyron</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010802" MajorTopicYN="N">Phylogeny</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018895" MajorTopicYN="N">Microsatellite Repeats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059014" MajorTopicYN="N">High-Throughput Nucleotide Sequencing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001482" MajorTopicYN="N">Base Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058977" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Sequence Annotation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D023281" MajorTopicYN="N">Genomics</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Agropyron</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chloroplast genome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nucleotide diversity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Phylogeny</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Species identification</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical approval and consent to participate: The samples in this study do not include plants in the list of nationally key protected wild plants. All collections were performed in compliance with local regulations or approved by relevant local departments. None of the Agropyron species or varieties included in this study are listed as endangered or protected under CITES or Chinese national regulations.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41087903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12522725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12864-025-12026-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12864-025-12026-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Soreng RJ, Peterson PM, Romaschenko K, Davidse G, Zuloaga FO, Judziewicz EJ, et al. A worldwide phylogenetic classification of the Poaceae (Gramineae). J Syst Evol. 2015;53(2):117&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jse.12150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellogg EA. Poaceae. In: Kubitzki K, editor. The families and genera of vascular plants. Flowering plants. Monocots. Volume 13. Berlin: Springer; 2015. pp. 1&#x2013;416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SL, Zhu GH. Agropyron. In: Wu ZY, Raven PH, Hong DY, editors. Flora of China. Volume 22. Beijing: Science; St. Louis: Missouri Botanical Garden Press;; 2006. pp. 439&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Che YH, Yang YP, Yang XM, Li XQ, Li LH. Phylogenetic relationship and diversity among <i>Agropyron</i> gaertn. germplasm using SSRs markers. Plant Syst Evol. 2015;301:163&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00606-014-1062-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copete A, Moreno R, Cabrera A. Characterization of a world collection of <i>Agropyron cristatum</i> accessions. Genet Resour Crop Evol. 2018;65:1455&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10722-018-0630-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kartalaei ZM, Kooch Y, Tilaki GAD. Litter and soil properties under woody and non-woody vegetation types: implication for ecosystem management in a mountainous semi-arid landscape. J Environ Manage. 2023;348:119238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2023.119238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37820433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Gao XQ, Wang X, Song WX, Wang Q, Wang XC, et al. Exogenous melatonin ameliorates drought stress in <i>Agropyron Mongolicum</i> by regulating flavonoid biosynthesis and carbohydrate metabolism. Front Plant Sci. 2022;13:1051165.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2022.1051165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9806343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36600908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan XX, Wu XJ, Sun FC, Nie HS, Du XH, Li XL, et al. Cloning and functional study of <i>AmGDSL1</i> in <i>Agropyron Mongolicum</i>. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25(17):9467.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms25179467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11395167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39273413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie J, Liu XQ, Luo MX, Liu FS, Liu S, Zhao YX, et al. Ethnobotanical study of traditional forage plants in the Gansu&#x2013;Ningxia&#x2013;Inner Mongolia junction zone: conservation and sustainable utilization for animal husbandry. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2023;19(1):53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-023-00625-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10652598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37968695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatami Maleki H, Mohammadi R, Firouzkuhi F, Darvishzadeh R, Zeinalzadeh-Tabrizi H. Molecular evidence depicts genetic divergence among <i>Agropyron elongatum</i> and <i>A. cristatum</i> accessions from gene pool of Iran. PLoS One. 2023;18(11):e0294694.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0294694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10688953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38033138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li HY, Li YX, Li J, Wu ZN, Huang F, Zhu L, et al. Phenotypic diversity analysis and comprehensive evaluation of 143 <i>Agropyron</i> germplasm resources in inner mongolia, China. J Plant Genet Resour. 2024;25(8):1254&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barkworth ME. <i>Agropyron</i>. In: Flora of North America Editorial Committee, editors. Flora of North America North of Mexico [Internet]. Vol. 24. New York: Oxford University Press; 2007 [cited 2025 Apr 21]. p. 277. Available from: http://floranorthamerica.org/Agropyron</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosarev M. Variability of characters in <i>Agropyron</i>. Selektsiya I Semenovodstvo. 1949;4:41&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsvelev NN. In: Zlaki SSSR, editor. Poaceae URSS). Leningrad: Nauka; 1976. p. 788. Agropyron L.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schramma N, Perugachi Isra&#xeb;ls C, Jalaal M. Chloroplasts in plant cells show active glassy behavior under low-light conditions. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2023;120(3):e2216497120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2216497120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9934296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36638210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Tian L, Lu CM. Chloroplast gene expression: recent advances and perspectives. Plant Commun. 2023;4(5):100611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xplc.2023.100611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10504595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37147800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrogojski J, Adamiec M, Luci&#x144;ski R. The chloroplast genome: a review. Acta Physiol Plant. 2020;42(6):98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11738-020-03089-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Wang XW, Shi YH, Yin QG, Gao RR, Wang MY, et al. Identification of <i>Laportea bulbifera</i> using the complete chloroplast genome as a potentially effective super-barcode. J Appl Genet. 2023;64(2):231&#x2013;45.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13353-022-00746-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36633756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu S, Liu QZ, Qiu SM, Dai JP, Gao XX. DNA barcoding: an efficient technology to authenticate plant species of traditional Chinese medicine and recent advances. Chin Med. 2022;17(1):112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13020-022-00655-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9514984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36171596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen N, Sha LN, Dong ZZ, Tang C, Wang Y, Kang HY, et al. Complete structure and variation of the chloroplast genome of <i>Agropyron cristatum</i> (L.) Gaertn. Gene. 2018;640:86&#x2013;96.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gene.2017.10.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29030254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han HJ, Qiu R, Liu YF, Zhou XY, Gao CP, Pang YZ, et al. Analysis of chloroplast genomes provides insights into the evolution of <i>Agropyron</i>. Front Genet. 2022;13:832809.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fgene.2022.832809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8821885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35145553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang M, Huang T, Chen XL, Li BY, Luo F, Zhang XM. Chloroplast genome characteristics and codon usage bias analysis of <i>Quercus Austroglauca</i> Y. T. Chang. Plant Sci J. 2023;41(3):322&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia L, Wang H, Zhao XK, Obel HO, Yu XQ, Lou QF, et al. Chloroplast pan-genomes and comparative transcriptomics reveal genetic variation and temperature adaptation in the cucumber. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(10):8943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms24108943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10219501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37240287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Y, Liu JH, Guo MR, Ouyang WZ, Yan JP, Xiong LZ, et al. Drought-responsive dynamics of H3K9ac-marked 3D chromatin interactions are integrated by OsbZIP23-associated super-enhancer-like promoter regions in rice. Genome Biol. 2024;25(1):262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13059-024-03408-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11465533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39390531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian T, Wang SH, Yang SP, Yang ZR, Liu SX, Wang YJ, et al. Genome assembly and genetic dissection of a prominent drought-resistant maize germplasm. Nat Genet. 2023;55(3):496&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41588-023-01297-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36806841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyu ZY, Zhou XL, Wang SQ, Yang GM, Sun WG, Zhang JY, et al. The first high-altitude autotetraploid haplotype-resolved genome assembled (<i>Rhododendron nivale</i> subsp. <i>boreale</i>) provides new insights into mountaintop adaptation. Gigascience. 2024;13:giae052.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gigascience/giae052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11304948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39110622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohanta TK, Mishra AK, Khan A, Hashem A, Abd_Allah EF, Al-Harrasi A. Gene loss and evolution of the plastome. Genes. 2020;11(10):1133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/genes11101133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7650654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32992972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang DZ, Cai XD, Gong M, Xia MQ, Xing HT, Dong SS, et al. Complete chloroplast genomes provide insights into evolution and phylogeny of <i>Zingiber</i> (Zingiberaceae). BMC Genomics. 2023;24(1):30.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12864-023-09115-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9848714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36653780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu F, He LL, Gao SW, Su YC, Li FS, Xu LP. Comparative analysis of two sugarcane ancestors <i>Saccharum officinarum</i> and <i>S. spontaneum</i> based on complete chloroplast genome sequences and photosynthetic ability in cold stress. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;20(15):3828.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms20153828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6696253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31387284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu ZN, Tian CY, Yang YT, Li YH, Liu Q, Li ZY, et al. Comparative and phylogenetic analysis of complete chloroplast genomes in <i>Leymus</i> (Triticodae, Poaceae). Genes. 2022;13(8):1425.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/genes13081425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9408388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36011336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding CX, Dong QM. Characterization of the complete chloroplast genome of <i>Festuca sinensis</i> (Gramineae). Mitochondr DNA B Resources. 2019;5(1):358&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23802359.2019.1704192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7748645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33366555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F, Zhao Y, Luo DJ, Hong DW, Li RB. The complete Chloroplast genome sequence of <i>Oryza rhizomatis</i> (Poaceae). Mitochondr DNA B Resources. 2017;2(2):467&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23802359.2017.1357453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7799503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33473865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang FG, Zhao JR, Dai JR, Yi HM, Kuang M, Sun YM, et al. Selection and development of representative simple sequence repeat primers and multiplex SSR sets for high throughput automated genotyping in maize. Chin Sci Bull. 2007;52(2):215&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11434-007-0038-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu WL, Wang ZY, Tian CY, Yang YT, Liu Q, Feng YM, et al. Codon usage bias analysis of Chloroplast genome in <i>Leymus</i> genus. Chin J Grassl. 2024;46(2):14&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan S, Nie C, Jia SG, Liu TQ, Zhao JM, Peng JH, et al. Complete chloroplast genomes of three wild perennial <i>Hordeum</i> species from central asia: genome structure, mutation hotspot, phylogenetic relationships, and comparative analysis. Front Plant Sci. 2023;14:1170004.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2023.1170004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10405828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37554563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabi R, Tuller T. Modelling the efficiency of codon&#x2013;tRNA interactions based on codon usage bias. DNA Res. 2014;21(5):511&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/dnares/dsu017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4195497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24906480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei YN, Gong MG, Bai N, Su JJ, Jiang X. Analysis of codon preference in chloroplast genome of <i>Dendrocalamus farinosus</i>. J Zhejiang A F Univ. 2024;41(4):696&#x2013;705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yun JF. Research and utilization of <i>Agropyron cristatum</i>. Beijing: Science; 2016. pp. 62&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu R, Song WZ, Qiao ZS, Zhang XL, Yu GD, He CZ, et al. Codon preference analysis of Chloroplast genome in medicinal plants of <i>Poncirus polyandra</i>. Chin Tradit Herb Drugs. 2024;55(20):7093&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewey DR. Historical and current taxonomic perspectives of <i>Agropyron</i>, <i>Elymus</i>, and related genera. Crop Sci. 1983;23(4):637&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2135/cropsci1983.0011183X002300040009x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soreng RJ, Peterson PM, Zuloaga FO, Romaschenko K, Clark LG, Teisher JK, et al. A worldwide phylogenetic classification of the Poaceae (Gramineae) III: an update. J Syst Evol. 2022;60(3):476&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jse.12847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason-Gamer RJ, White DM. The phylogeny of the triticeae: resolution and phylogenetic conflict based on genomewide nuclear loci. Am J Bot. 2024;111(10):e16404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajb2.16404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39279223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carstens BC, Pelletier TA, Reid NM, Satler JD. How to fail at species delimitation. Mol Ecol. 2013;22(17):4369&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/mec.12413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23855767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddison WP, Knowles LL. Inferring phylogeny despite incomplete lineage sorting. Syst Biol. 2006;55(1):21&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10635150500354928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16507521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doyle JJ, Doyle JL. A rapid DNA isolation procedure for small quantities of fresh leaf tissue. Phytochem Bull. 1987;19:11&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon SA, Park JL, Park SJ, Kim JH, Goh SH, Han JY, et al. Comparison between MGI and Illumina sequencing platforms for whole genome sequencing. Genes Genomics. 2021;43:713&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13258-021-01096-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33864614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SF. Ultrafast one-pass FASTQ data preprocessing, quality control, and deduplication using fastp. iMeta. 2023;2(2):e107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/imt2.107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10989850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38868435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin JJ, Yu WB, Yang JB, Song Y, DePamphilis CW, Yi TS, et al. Getorganelle: a fast and versatile toolkit for accurate de novo assembly of organelle genomes. Genome Biol. 2020;21:241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13059-020-02154-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7488116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32912315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boratyn GM, Camacho C, Cooper PS, Coulouris G, Fong A, Madden TL, et al. BLAST: a more efficient report with usability improvements. Nucleic Acids Res. 2013;41(W1):W29&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkt282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3692093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23609542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi LC, Chen HM, Jiang M, Wang LQ, Wu X, Huang LF, et al. CPGAVAS2, an integrated plastome sequence annotator and analyzer. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019;47(W1):W65&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkz345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6602467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31066451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurtz S, Choudhuri JV, Ohlebusch E, Schleiermacher C, Stoye J, Giegerich R. Reputer: the manifold applications of repeat analysis on a genomic scale. Nucleic Acids Res. 2001;29(22):4633&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/29.22.4633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11713313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beier S, Thiel T, M&#xfc;nch T, Scholz U, Mascher M. MISA-web: a web server for microsatellite prediction. Bioinformatics. 2017;33(16):2583&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btx198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5870701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28398459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright F. The &#x2018;effective number of codons&#x2019; used in a gene. Gene. 1990;87(1):23&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0378-1119(90)90491-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2110097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuglsang A. Accounting for background nucleotide composition when measuring codon usage bias: brilliant idea, difficult in practice. Mol Biol Evol. 2006;23(7):1345&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/molbev/msl009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16679346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon JE, Kim JG, Fischer CR, Mehta N, Dufour-Schroif C, Wemmer K, et al. A pathogen-responsive gene cluster for highly modified fatty acids in tomato. Cell. 2020;180(1):176&#x2013;e18719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2019.11.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6956849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31923394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Guo QQ, Xu L, Gao HD, Liu L, Zhou XY. CPJSdraw: analysis and visualization of junction sites of Chloroplast genomes. PeerJ. 2023;11:e15326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.15326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10182761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37193025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katoh K, Rozewicki J, Yamada KD. MAFFT online service: multiple sequence alignment, interactive sequence choice and visualization. Brief Bioinform. 2019;20(4):1160&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bib/bbx108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6781576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28968734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozas J, Ferrer-Mata A, S&#xe1;nchez-DelBarrio JC, Guirao-Rico S, Librado P, Ramos-Onsins SE, et al. DnaSP 6: DNA sequence polymorphism analysis of large data sets. Mol Biol Evol. 2017;34(12):3299&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/molbev/msx248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29029172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang CY, Gao F, Jakovli&#x107; I, Lei HP, Hu Y, Zhang H, et al. Using phylosuite for molecular phylogeny and tree-based analyses. iMeta. 2023;2(1):e87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/imt2.87</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10989932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38868339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamura K, Stecher G, Kumar S. MEGA11: molecular evolutionary genetics analysis version 11. Mol Biol Evol. 2021;38(7):3022&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/molbev/msab120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8233496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Durbin R. Fast and accurate short read alignment with Burrows-Wheeler transform. Bioinformatics. 2009;25(14):1754&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btp324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2705234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19451168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Handsaker B, Wysoker A, et al. The sequence alignment/map format and samtools. Bioinformatics. 2009;25(16):2078&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btp352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2723002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19505943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna A, Hanna M, Banks E, et al. The genome analysis toolkit: a mapreduce framework for analyzing next-generation DNA sequencing data. Genome Res. 2010;20(9):1297&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/gr.107524.110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2928508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20644199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danecek P, Bonfield JK, Liddle J, Marshall J, Ohan V, Pollard MO, et al. Twelve years of samtools and BCFtools. Gigascience. 2021;10(2):giab008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gigascience/giab008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7931819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33590861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CC, Chow CC, Tellier LC, Vattikuti S, Purcell SM, Lee JJ. Second-generation PLINK: rising to the challenge of larger and richer datasets. Gigascience. 2015;4(1):s13742-015-0047-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13742-015-0047-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4342193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25722852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham H. ggplot2. Wiley interdisciplinary reviews: computational statistics. Volume 3. New York: Springer; 2011. pp. 180&#x2013;5. 2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knaus BJ, Gr&#xfc;nwald NJ. Vcfr: a package to manipulate and visualize variant call format data in R. Mol Ecol Resour. 2017;17(1):44&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1755-0998.12549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27401132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie PL, Guo Y, Teng YL, et al. Geneminer: a tool for extracting phylogenetic markers from next-generation sequencing data. Mol Ecol Resour. 2024;24(3):e13924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1755-0998.13924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38197287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page AJ, Taylor B, Delaney AJ, et al. Snp-sites: rapid efficient extraction of SNPs from multi-FASTA alignments. Microb Genom. 2016;2(4):e000056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5320690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28348851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evanno G, Regnaut S, Goudet J. Detecting the number of clusters of individuals using the software STRUCTURE: a simulation study. Mol Ecol. 2005;14(8):2611&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-294X.2005.02553.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15969739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>