<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41671271</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessment of forest fragmentation in the REDD+ priority zones using two land use/land cover (LULC) sources in the tropical Andean landscape of Ecuador.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0342476</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0342476</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0342476</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0342476</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Human-driven deforestation and fragmentation are major threats to global biodiversity and climate stability, particularly in the Amazon rainforest. Ecuador, located in the Andes-Amazon transition zone, hosts some of the world's most biodiverse ecosystems. The REDD+ initiative, the main international mechanism for mitigating forest degradation, has identified six priority conservation areas in Ecuador-87% of which are in the Amazon region and distributed across three zones: northern, central, and southern. This study evaluates landscape fragmentation in REDD+ priority zones of the Ecuadorian Amazon over a 32-year period (i.e., 1990-2022) using a dual approach: statistical analysis with FRAGSTATS v4 and spatial modeling with Guidos Toolbox v2. Two land use/land cover (LULC) datasets were compared-one from Ecuador's Ministry of the Environment and the other from the MapBiomas Ecuador initiative. Results revealed an overall increase in fragmentation, including a higher number of forest patches, greater isolation, and reduced patch size and representativeness. Spatial analysis indicated a clear fragmentation pattern along the north-south E45 highway corridor, which increasingly separates Andean and Amazonian ecosystems. The northern and southern zones were the most affected, due to increased accessibility linked to oil and mining activities, respectively. MapBiomas data more effectively captured fragmentation associated with small-scale deforestation. These findings provide a critical baseline for policymakers to design strategies aligned with REDD+ goals and to develop targeted actions to reduce forest fragmentation and deforestation in the Ecuadorian Amazon.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Paredes et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paredes</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Change Laboratory, Universidad Regional Amaz&#xf3;nica Ikiam, Tena, Ecuador.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fundacion Ecosistemas en Acci&#xf3;n (Eco-Acci&#xf3;n), Tena, Napo, Ecuador.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noh</LastName><ForeName>Jin Kyoung</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tropical Ecosystems and Global Change Research Group, Universidad Regional Amaz&#xf3;nica Ikiam, Tena, Ecuador.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aguirre</LastName><ForeName>Nikolay</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Investigaciones Tropicales del Ambiente y Biodiversidad (CITIAB), Universidad Nacional de Loja, Ecuador.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Youn</LastName><ForeName>Yeo-Chang</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agriculture, Forestry and BioResouces, Seoul National University, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cuenca</LastName><ForeName>Pablo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9707-7562</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Change Laboratory, Universidad Regional Amaz&#xf3;nica Ikiam, Tena, Ecuador.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tropical Ecosystems and Global Change Research Group, Universidad Regional Amaz&#xf3;nica Ikiam, Tena, Ecuador.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004484" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ecuador</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003247" MajorTopicYN="Y">Conservation of Natural Resources</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065928" MajorTopicYN="Y">Forests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044822" MajorTopicYN="N">Biodiversity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065947" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rainforest</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017753" MajorTopicYN="N">Ecosystem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014329" MajorTopicYN="N">Tropical Climate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41671271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12893533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0342476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-06424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Li J. Identifying priority areas for biodiversity conservation based on Marxan and InVEST model. Landsc Ecol. 2022;37(12):3043&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1007/s10980-022-01547-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10980-022-01547-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper DU, Adair EC, Cardinale BJ, Byrnes JEK, Hungate BA, Matulich KL. A global synthesis reveals biodiversity loss as a major driver of ecosystem change. 2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22678289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardinale BJ, Duffy JE, Gonzalez A, Hooper DU, Perrings C, Venail P. Biodiversity loss and its impact on humanity. 2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22678280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley JA, Asner GP, Costa MH, Coe MT, DeFries RS, et al. Amazonia revealed: forest degradation and loss of ecosystem goods and services in the Amazon basin. 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchard ETA. The tropical forest carbon cycle and climate change. 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30046067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuffie K, Henderson-Sellers A, Zhang H, Zhang H, Durbidge TB, Pitman AJ. Global climate sensitivity to tropical deforestation. 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;nggli A, Levy S, Pascual DA, Bovolo I, Brand&#xe3;o J, Rueda X. A systematic comparison of deforestation drivers and policy effectiveness across the Amazon biome. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malhi Y, Roberts JT, Betts R, Killeen TJ, Killeen TJ, Li W. Climate Change, Deforestation, and the Fate of the Amazon. 2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18048654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasserstrom R, Southgate D. Deforestation, agrarian reform and oil development in Ecuador, 1964-1994. 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MG. Disturbance and landscape dynamics in a changing world. 2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21058545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler K, Fuchs R, Rounsevell M, Herold M. Global land use changes are four times greater than previously estimated. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8113269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33976120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GOFC-GOLD. A sourcebook of methods and procedures for monitoring essential biodiversity variables in tropical forests with remote sensing. B O, G-GG editor. Report UNCBD COP-13 ed: OFC-GOLD Land CoverProject Office. Wageningen University. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allan E. Land use intensification alters ecosystem multifunctionality via loss of biodiversity and changes to functional composition. 2015;834&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4744976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26096863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates AE, Newbold T, Hudson LN, Hill SLL, Contu S, Lysenko I. Global effects of land use on local terrestrial biodiversity. 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25832402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad NM, Brudvig LA, Clobert J, et al. Habitat fragmentation and its lasting impact on Earth&#x2019;s ecosystems. 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4643828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26601154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDougall AS, McCann KS, Gellner G, Turkington R. Diversity loss with persistent human disturbance increases vulnerability to ecosystem collapse. 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23389543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peh KSH, Lin Y, Foster WA, Luke SH, Luke S, Luke S. Forest fragmentation and ecosystem functioning. 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders DA, Saunders DA, Hobbs RJ, et al. Biological consequences of ecosystem fragmentation: a review. 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonilla-Bedoya S, Molina JR, Macedo-Pezzopane JE, Herrera-Machuca MA. Fragmentation patterns and systematic transitions of the forested landscape in the upper Amazon region, Ecuador 1990&#x2013;2008. 2014:301&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuenca P, Echeverria C. How do protected landscapes associated with high biodiversity and population levels change? In: Mpodozis JM, editor. Public Library of Science. 2017:e0180537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5495433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28672002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleemann J, Zamora C, Villacis-Chiluisa AB. Deforestation in continental Ecuador with a focus on protected areas. Multidisciplinary Digital Publishing Institute. 2022;268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noh JK, Echeverr&#xed;a C, Gaona G. Forest ecosystem fragmentation in Ecuador: Challenges for sustainable land use in the tropical Andean. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAATE. Bosques para el buen vivir - Plan de acci&#xf3;n REDD Ecuador (2016-2025). 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAATE. Mapa De Cobertura y Uso De La Tierra Del Ecuador Continental a&#xf1;o 1990, 2000, 2008, 2014. Quito - Ecuador. 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAATE. Mapa de cobertura y uso de la tierra del Ecuador continental a&#xf1;o 2016. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAATE. Mapa de cobertura y uso de la tierra del Ecuador continental a&#xf1;o 2018-2019. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAATE. Mapa de cobertura y uso de la tierra del Ecuador continental a&#xf1;o 2020. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borja M, Holgu&#xed;n W, Aguilar C, Ter&#xe1;n K, Rodr&#xed;guez A, Josse C. Documento de bases te&#xf3;ricas de algoritmo (ATBD) RAISG - MapBiomas Ecuador colecci&#xf3;n 1.0 de mapas anuales de cobertura y uso del suelo de Ecuador. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ecociencia F, RAISG. Proyecto MapBiomas Ecuador- colecci&#xf3;n 1.0 de los mapas anuales de cobertura y uso del suelo en Ecuador. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAATE. Protocolo metodol&#xf3;gico para la generaci&#xf3;n de mapas de deforestaci&#xf3;n del Ecuador continental. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurance WF, Lovejoy TE, Vasconcelos HL, Bruna EM, Didham RK, Stouffer PC, et al. Ecosystem Decay of Amazonian Forest Fragments: a 22&#x2010;Year Investigation. Conservation Biology. 2002;16(3):605&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1046/j.1523-1739.2002.01025.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1523-1739.2002.01025.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuenca P, Echeverria C. How do protected landscapes associated with high biodiversity and population levels change?. PLoS One. 2017;12(7):e0180537. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0180537</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0180537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5495433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28672002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleemann J, Zamora C, Villacis-Chiluisa AB, Cuenca P, Koo H, Noh JK, et al. Deforestation in Continental Ecuador with a Focus on Protected Areas. Land. 2022;11(2):268. doi: 10.3390/land11020268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/land11020268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleemann J, Koo H, Hensen I, Mendieta-Leiva G, Kahnt B, Kurze C, et al. Priorities of action and research for the protection of biodiversity and ecosystem services in continental Ecuador. Biological Conservation. 2022;265:109404. doi: 10.1016/j.biocon.2021.109404</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biocon.2021.109404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armenteras D, Gonz&#xe1;lez TM, Retana J. Forest fragmentation and edge influence on fire occurrence and intensity under different management types in Amazon forests. 2013:79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tapia-Armijos MF, Homeier J, Espinosa CI. Deforestation and forest fragmentation in south Ecuador since the 1970s &#x2013; losing a hotspot of biodiversity. Public Library of Science. 2015;1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4557835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26332681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson MC, Chen XY, Corlett RT, Didham RK, Ding P, Holt RD. Habitat fragmentation and biodiversity conservation: key findings and future challenges. 2016:219&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAE-MAGAP. Protocolo metodol&#xf3;gico para la elaboraci&#xf3;n del mapa de cobertura y uso de la tierra del Ecuador continental 2013-2014, escala 1:100.000. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peralvo M, Delgado J. Metodolog&#xed;a para la generaci&#xf3;n del mapa de deforestaci&#xf3;n hist&#xf3;rica 2010. 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IPCC. Climate Change 2007 - Mitigation of Climate Change: Working Group III Contribution to the Fourth Assessment Report of the IPCC. Cambridge University Press. 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-&#xc1;vila S, Ortega E, Mart&#xed;n B. Multiscale fragmentation of forest types in Spain. 2023;121317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hargis CD, Bissonette JA, David JL. The behavior of landscape metrics commonly used in the study of habitat fragmentation. Landscape Ecology. 1998;13(3):167&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1023/a:1007965018633</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/a:1007965018633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGarigal K, Cushman SA. FRAGSTATS v4: Spatial Pattern Analysis Program for Categorical and Continuous Maps. 4 ed. Amherst: University of Massachusetts. 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uuemaa E, Antrop M, Roosaare J, Marja R, Mander &#xdc;. Landscape Metrics and Indices: An Overview of Their Use in Landscape Research. Living Rev Landscape Res. 2009;3. doi: 10.12942/lrlr-2009-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12942/lrlr-2009-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Blanchet FG, Koper N. Measuring habitat fragmentation: An evaluation of landscape pattern metrics. Methods Ecol Evol. 2014;5(7):634&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1111/2041-210x.12198</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/2041-210x.12198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamine S, Petropoulos GP, Singh SK, Szab&#xf3; S, Nour EI, Srivastava PK. Quantifying land use/land cover spatio-temporal landscape pattern dynamics from Hyperion using SVMs classifier and FRAGSTATS&#xae;. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noh JK, Echeverria C, Gaona G, Kleemann J, Koo H, F&#xfc;rst C, et al. Forest Ecosystem Fragmentation in Ecuador: Challenges for Sustainable Land Use in the Tropical Andean. Land. 2022;11(2):287. doi: 10.3390/land11020287</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/land11020287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Wu J. Use and misuse of landscape indices. 2004:389&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt P. GuidosToolbox (Graphical User Interface for the Description of Image Objects and Their Shapes): Digital Image Analysis Software Collection. 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt P. User guide of GuidosToolbox. 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt PM, Riitters KH. GuidosToolbox: universal digital image object analysis. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riitters K, Wickham J, O&#x2019;Neill R, Jones K, Smith E, Coulston J. Fragmentation of Continental United States Forests. 2002;815&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Militar IG. Vias 1:50.000. 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Militar IG. Poblados 1:50.000. 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAATE. Bosques y vegetaci&#xf3;n protectora. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAATE. Area bajo conservaci&#xf3;n PSB. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAATE. Sistema nacional de &#xe1;rea protegida SNAP2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKnight PE, Najab J. Mann&#x2010;Whitney U Test. Wiley Online Library. 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rpv. Rstatix: Pipe-friendly framework for basic statistical tests. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field A. Discovering statistics using SPSS. 3 ed. SAGE Publications. 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lantz B. The large sample size fallacy. 2013. 487&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22862286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Z. Complex heatmap visualization. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10989952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38868715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pryke A, Mostaghim S, Nazemi A. Heatmap visualization of population based multi objective algorithms. Springer. 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baynard CW, Ellis JM, Davis H. Roads, petroleum and accessibility: the case of eastern Ecuador. 2013;675&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mena CF, Laso F, Martinez P, Sampedro C. Modeling road building, deforestation and carbon emissions due deforestation in the Ecuadorian Amazon: the potential impact of oil frontier growth. Taylor &amp; Francis. 2017:477&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilsborrow RE, Barbieri AF, Pan W. Changes in population and land use over time in the Ecuadorian Amazon. Instituto Nacional de Pesquisas da Amaz&#xf4;nia. 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mena CF, Bilsborrow RE, McClain ME. Socioeconomic drivers of deforestation in the Northern Ecuadorian Amazon. Environ Manage. 2006;37(6):802&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1007/s00267-003-0230-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00267-003-0230-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16555027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coronel Vargas G, Au WW, Izzotti A. Public health issues from crude-oil production in the Ecuadorian Amazon territories. 2020. 134647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31837875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega-Andrade HM, Rodes Blanco M, Cisneros-Heredia DF, Guerra Ar&#xe9;valo N, L&#xf3;pez De Vargas-Machuca KG, S&#xe1;nchez-Nivicela JC. Red list assessment of amphibian species of Ecuador: A multidimensional approach for their conservation. Public Library of Science. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8101765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33956885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha EC, Brito D, Silva PM, Silva J, Bernardo PV d S, Juen L. Effects of habitat fragmentation on the persistence of medium and large mammal species in the Brazilian savanna of Goi&#xe1;s state. Instituto Virtual da Biodiversidade | BIOTA - FAPESP. 2018;e20170483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsoy PJ, Zeller KA, Hicke JA, Quigley HB, Rabinowitz AR, Thornton DH. Quantifying the effects of deforestation and fragmentation on a range-wide conservation plan for jaguars. 2016:8&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finer M, Mamani N, Josse C, Villacis S. Plataformas petroleras se acercan a la zona intangible (Parque Nacional Yasun&#xed;, Ecuador). 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lessmann J, Fajardo J, Mu&#xf1;oz J, Bonaccorso E. Large expansion of oil industry in the Ecuadorian Amazon: biodiversity vulnerability and conservation alternatives. Ecol Evol. 2016;6(14):4997&#x2013;5012. doi: 10.1002/ece3.2099</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ece3.2099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4979723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27547329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bass MS, Finer M, Jenkins CN, Kreft H, Cisneros-Heredia DF, McCracken SF, et al. Global conservation significance of Ecuador&#x2019;s Yasun&#xed; National Park. PLoS One. 2010;5(1):e8767. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0008767</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0008767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2808245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20098736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullah SA, Nakagoshi N. Forest fragmentation and its correlation to human land use change in the state of Selangor, peninsular Malaysia. Forest Ecology and Management. 2007;241(1&#x2013;3):39&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1016/j.foreco.2006.12.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foreco.2006.12.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holland MB, de Koning F, Morales M, Naughton-Treves L, Robinson BE, Su&#xe1;rez L. Complex Tenure and Deforestation: Implications for Conservation Incentives in the Ecuadorian Amazon. World Development. 2014;55:21&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1016/j.worlddev.2013.01.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.worlddev.2013.01.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasco C, Bilsborrow R, Torres B, Griess V. Agricultural land use among mestizo colonist and indigenous populations: contrasting patterns in the Amazon. In: Holland M, editor. Public Library of Science. 2018:e0199518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6033409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29975718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casto M, Sierra R, Calva O, Camacho J, Lopez F. Zonas de procesos homog&#xe9;neos de deforestaci&#xf3;n del Ecuador: factores promotores y tendencias al 2020. 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuesta F, Peralvo M, Merino-Viteri A, Bustamante M, Baquero F, Freile JF. Priority areas for biodiversity conservation in mainland Ecuador. Taylor &amp; Francis. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valencia JH, Ortega-Andrade HM, Laborde J, Pineda E. Species richness, composition, distribution and conservation status of the amphibians and reptiles of the Cordillera del C&#xf3;ndor, a region between Ecuador and Peru. 2023:61&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacios Orejuela I, Rodriguez Espinosa F. Economic valuation of environmental goods and services of the Protector Forest Kutuk&#xfa; &#x2013; Shaimi, SE Ecuador. 2021:117&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massa P, Del Cisne Arcos R, Maldonado D, Massa-S&#xe1;nchez P, Cisne Arcos R d, Maldonado D. Miner&#xed;a a gran escala y conflictos sociales: un an&#xe1;lisis para el sur de Ecuador. Universidad Nacional Aut&#xf3;noma de M&#xe9;xico, Instituto de Investigaciones Econ&#xf3;micas. 2018:119&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mestanza-Ram&#xf3;n C, Cuenca-Cumbicus J, D&#x2019;Orio G, Flores-Toala J, Segovia-C&#xe1;ceres S, Bonilla-Bonilla A. Gold Mining in the Amazon Region of Ecuador: History and a Review of Its Socio-Environmental Impacts. Multidisciplinary Digital Publishing Institute. 2022;221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tapia-Armijos MF, Homeier J, Espinosa CI, Leuschner C, de la Cruz M. Deforestation and Forest Fragmentation in South Ecuador since the 1970s - Losing a Hotspot of Biodiversity. PLoS One. 2015;10(9):e0133701. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0133701</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0133701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4557835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26332681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo H, Kleemann J, Cuenca P, Noh JK, F&#xfc;rst C. Implications of landscape changes for ecosystem services and biodiversity: A national assessment in Ecuador. Ecosystem Services. 2024;69:101652. doi: 10.1016/j.ecoser.2024.101652</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoser.2024.101652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley P, Muller P, Rathjens C. Landscape Ecology. The Journal of Applied Ecology. 1980;17(3):848. doi: 10.2307/2402669</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2402669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders DA, Hobbs RJ, Margules CR. Biological Consequences of Ecosystem Fragmentation: A Review. Conservation Biology. 1991;5(1):18&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1111/j.1523-1739.1991.tb00384.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1523-1739.1991.tb00384.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurance WF, Lovejoy TE, Vasconcelos HL, Bruna EM, Didham RK, Stouffer PC, et al. Ecosystem Decay of Amazonian Forest Fragments: a 22&#x2010;Year Investigation. Conservation Biology. 2002;16(3):605&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1046/j.1523-1739.2002.01025.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1523-1739.2002.01025.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad NM, Brudvig LA, Clobert J, Davies KF, Gonzalez A, Holt RD, et al. Habitat fragmentation and its lasting impact on Earth&#x2019;s ecosystems. Sci Adv. 2015;1(2):e1500052. doi: 10.1126/sciadv.1500052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.1500052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4643828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26601154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loaiza T, Nehren U, Gerold G. REDD+ and incentives: An analysis of income generation in forest-dependent communities of the Yasun&#xed; Biosphere Reserve, Ecuador. Applied Geography. 2015;62:225&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1016/j.apgeog.2015.04.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apgeog.2015.04.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>