<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41680242</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Geochemistry of middle jurassic coal-bearing strata from the Xingmei Mine, Xinjiang, and the origin of localized barium enrichment.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8423</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-37408-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Research on the geochemical characteristics of coal-bearing strata in the Yanqi Coalfield, Xinjiang, remains limited. This study investigates the No. 8-&#x2009;2 coal seam and its adjacent strata in the Xingmei Mine, which is located in the Yanqi Coalfield, using mineralogical and geochemical methods to characterize its composition, constrain provenance, and clarify the causes of localized barium enrichment. The coal is characterized by low ash and sulfur, high volatile matter, and is dominated by quartz, kaolinite, and pyrite. Trace element analysis reveals that Ba is slightly enriched in the coal samples, whereas it is enriched in the surrounding roof, parting, and floor samples. Provenance analysis suggests detrital input mainly from the central and south Tianshan region. Paleoenvironmental proxies reveal a humid-arid-humid climate shift from roof to coal to floor, with redox transitions from dysoxic to weakly reducing-oxidizing, returning to dysoxic conditions, under freshwater and terrigenous input. Elevated Ba concentrations are observed in samples collected near the coal-roof/floor interfaces, including XM-5P (15,826&#xa0;&#xb5;g/g) and XM-13 (3,071&#xa0;&#xb5;g/g), hosted in barite. Barite likely formed under freshwater conditions, high ash content, transitional contact zones, and Ba&#xb2;&#x207a; supply from sediment provenance, with SO&#x2084;&#xb2;&#x207b; most likely derived from acid rain.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Yuanzhe</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Coalbed Methane Resources and Reservoir Formation Process, Ministry of Education, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Geosciences, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Qingfeng</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Coalbed Methane Resources and Reservoir Formation Process, Ministry of Education, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221008, China. luqingfeng@cumt.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Geosciences, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221116, China. luqingfeng@cumt.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Key Laboratory of Coal-based Greenhouse Gas Control and Utilization, Carbon Neutrality Institute, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221008, China. luqingfeng@cumt.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Wenfeng</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Coalbed Methane Resources and Reservoir Formation Process, Ministry of Education, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221008, China. wangwenfeng@cumt.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Geosciences, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221116, China. wangwenfeng@cumt.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Key Laboratory of Coal-based Greenhouse Gas Control and Utilization, Carbon Neutrality Institute, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221008, China. wangwenfeng@cumt.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Geology and Mining Engineering, Xinjiang University, Urumqi, 830046, China. wangwenfeng@cumt.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shao</LastName><ForeName>Fengjun</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Geology and Mining Engineering, Xinjiang University, Urumqi, 830046, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Wenlong</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Coalbed Methane Resources and Reservoir Formation Process, Ministry of Education, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Geosciences, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xadethan</LastName><ForeName>Hayerhan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhundong Economic and Technological Development Zone Branch, Changji Natural Resources Bureau, Changji, 133699, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>42402176</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>42472236</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024QN11071</GrantID><Agency>Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022A03014</GrantID><Agency>Major Science and Technology Special Project of Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>5105250180k</GrantID><Agency>Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region Introduction Plan "Tianchi Talent" project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Barium</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Geochemistry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Provenance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Xinjiang</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41680242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12972226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-37408-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-37408-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cui, M. Y., Hou, E. K., Fan, J. C., Hou, P. F. &amp; Feng, D. Dynamic evolution of water conducting fracture zones and roof water hazard early warning based on 3d Spatial clustering. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 35354 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-19305-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12511448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41068205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z., Li, C., Fang, Y., Liu, P. &amp; Peng, T. The paradigm shift in china&#x2019;s energy consumption: a multi-timescale interpretation of coal consumption fluctuations. <i>Energy. Conv. Manag.</i><b>341</b>, 120074 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2025.120074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, R. Y. et al. Geochemistry of middle jurassic coals from the Dananhu Mine, xinjiang: emphasis on sediment source and control factors of critical metals. <i>Minerals</i><b>14</b>, 767 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min14080767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Energy Agency. Coal (2024). https://www.iea.org/reports/coal-2024 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, S. F. et al. Modes of occurrence of elements in coal: A critical evaluation. <i>Earth Sci. Rev.</i><b>222</b>, 103815 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.earscirev.2021.103815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan, P. P. et al. Distribution of As, hg and other trace elements in different size and density fractions of the Reshuihe high-sulfur coal, Yunnan Province, China. <i>Int. J. Coal Geol.</i><b>173</b>, 129&#x2013;141 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2017.02.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, S. F. et al. Resources of critical metals in coal-bearing sequences in china: enrichment types and distribution. <i>Chin. Sci. Bull.</i><b>65</b>, 3715&#x2013;3729 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1360/TB-2020-0112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, B. Q., Zhuang, X. G., Li, J. &amp; Zhao, S. H. Geological controls on coal quality of the Yili Basin, Xinjiang, Northwest China. <i>Int. J. Coal Geol.</i><b>131</b>, 186&#x2013;199 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2014.06.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, R. Y. et al. Mode of occurrence of critical metals in the jurassic coals, Northern Xinjiang, china: based on the sequential chemical extraction procedure. <i>Ore Geol. Rev.</i><b>184</b>, 106730 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2025.106730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, J. et al. Evaluation and influence of coal mining on groundwater resources in arid region: A case study of Dananhu 7 colliery, Xinjiang, Western China. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>499</b>, 145225 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.145225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, S. F. et al. Geochemical and mineralogical evidence for a coal-hosted uranium deposit in the Yili Basin, Xinjiang, Northwestern China. <i>Ore Geol. Rev.</i><b>70</b>, 1&#x2013;30 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2015.03.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai, H. Y. et al. Geological characteristics and control mechanism of uranium enrichment in Coal-Bearing strata in the Yili Basin, Northwest ChinaImplications for resource development and environmental protection. <i>ACS Omega</i>. <b>7</b>, 5453&#x2013;5470 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.1c06754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8851618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35187361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Che, K. X. et al. Occurrence of differences between alkali and alkaline Earth metals (AAEMs), including Sodium, Potassium, Calcium, and Magnesium, in the maceral groups of the Xiheishan Coal, Zhundong Coalfield, Xinjiang, China. <i>Minerals</i><b>14</b>, 525 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min14050525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C. A. et al. Effects of oxy-fuel condition on morphology and mineral composition of Ash deposit during combustion of Zhundong high-alkali coal. <i>J. Energy Inst.</i><b>93</b>, 1216&#x2013;1228 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joei.2019.11.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zi, J. B. et al. Slagging behavior and mechanism of high-sodium-chlorine coal combustion in a full-scale Circulating fluidized bed boiler. <i>J. Energy Inst.</i><b>93</b>, 2264&#x2013;2270 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joei.2020.06.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, C. D. et al. Geochemical characteristics of jurassic coal and significance for the evolution of the environment, Yanqi Basin, China. <i>Progress Nat. Science-Materials Int.</i><b>16</b>, 974&#x2013;982 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10020070612330097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, Y. M., Zhao, F., Zhang, J. M. &amp; Zhao, J. J. Evaluation of organic geochemical characteristics and experiments of thermal pressure simulation of jurassic coal measure source rocks in the Yanqi basin. <i>Front. Earth Sci.</i><b>10</b>, 992013 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feart.2022.992013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini, A., Ebadollahi-Natanzi, A., Foroughi, M. &amp; Shetab-Boushehri, S. V. Barium- and Bismuth-loaded clinoptilolite Micro- and Nano-Particles as proposed new efficient contrast agents. <i>Comb. Chem. High Throughput Screen.</i><b>23</b>, 191&#x2013;195 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1386207323666200218113537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32067613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nooripoor, V., Nazemi, R. &amp; Hashemi, A. Employing Nano-sized additives as filtration control agent in Water-based drilling fluids: study on barium Sulfate, Bentonite, Surface-modified Bentonite, titanium oxide, and silicon oxide. <i>Energy Sources Part. a-Recovery Utilization Environ. Eff.</i><b>46</b>, 13806&#x2013;13822 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari, A. et al. Comparative performance assessment of cenosphere and barium sulphate based friction composites. <i>Wear</i><b>309</b>, 259&#x2013;268 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wear.2013.12.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schott, G. D. Some observations on the history of the use of barium salts in medicine. <i>Med. Hist.</i><b>18</b>, 9&#x2013;21 (1974).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0025727300019190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1081520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4618587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dymond, J., Suess, E. &amp; Lyle, M. Barium in Deep-Sea sediment: A geochemical proxy for paleoproductivity. <i>Paleoceanography</i><b>7</b>, 163&#x2013;181 (1992).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/92PA00181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, J. B., Zhuang, X. G., Alastuey, A., Querol, X. &amp; Li, J. H. Geochemistry and mineralogy of coal in the recently explored Zhundong large coal field in the Junggar basin, Xinjiang province, China. <i>Int. J. Coal Geol.</i><b>82</b>, 51&#x2013;67 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2009.12.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GB/T 482&#x2013;2008. Sampling of Coal Seams. Standard Press of China: Beijing, China. (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM D3173-11. Test Method for Moisture in the Analysis Sample of Coal and Coke. ASTM International: West Conshohocken, PA, USA. (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM D3174-11. Test Method for Ash in the Analysis Sample of Coal and Coke. Annual Book of ASTM Standards. ASTM International: West Conshohocken, PA, USA. (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM D3175-11. Test Method for Volatile Matter in the Analysis Sample of Coal and Coke. ASTM International: West Conshohocken, PA, USA. (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM D3177-02. Standard Test Methods for Total Sulfur in the Analysis Sample of Coal and Coke (Withdrawn 2012). ASTM International: West Conshohocken, PA, USA. (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ISO 7404-3. Methods for the Petrographic Analysis of Coals - Part 3: Method of Determining Maceral Group Composition. International Organization for Standardization, Geneva. (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM D388-12. Standard Classification of Coals by Rank. ASTM International: West Conshohocken, PA, USA. (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, S. F. et al. Geochemistry of trace elements in Chinese coals: A review of abundances, genetic types, impacts on human health, and industrial utilization. <i>Int. J. Coal Geol.</i><b>94</b>, 3&#x2013;21 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2011.02.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, S. F. et al. Enrichment of U-Se-Mo-Re-V in coals preserved within marine carbonate successions: geochemical and mineralogical data from the late permian guiding Coalfield, Guizhou, China. <i>Miner. Deposita</i>. <b>50</b>, 159&#x2013;186 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00126-014-0528-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ketris, M. P. &amp; Yudovich, Y. E. Estimations of Clarkes for carbonaceous biolithes: world averages for trace element contents in black shales and coals. <i>Int. J. Coal Geol.</i><b>78</b>, 135&#x2013;148 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2009.01.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, S. R. &amp; McLennan, S. H. <i>The Continental Crust: its Composition and Evolution</i> p. 312 (Blackwell, 1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, X. Y. et al. Determination of Eu concentrations in coal, fly Ash and sedimentary rocks using a cation exchange resin and inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (ICP-MS). <i>Int. J. Coal Geol.</i><b>191</b>, 152&#x2013;156 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2018.03.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, S. F., Graham, I. T. &amp; Ward, C. R. A review of anomalous rare Earth elements and yttrium in coal. <i>Int. J. Coal Geol.</i><b>159</b>, 82&#x2013;95 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2016.04.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X. H. et al. Geothermochronology and tectonic evolution of Eastern Altyn Tagh mountains Northwestern China (In Chinese). <i>Earth Sci. Front.</i><b>16</b>, 207&#x2013;219 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi, K. I., Fujisawa, H., Holland, H. D. &amp; Ohmoto, H. Geochemistry of &#x223c;1.9 Ga sedimentary rocks from Northeastern Labrador, Canada. <i>Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta</i>. <b>61</b>, 4115&#x2013;4137 (1997).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0016-7037(97)00214-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11540490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradi, A. V., Sari, A. &amp; Akkaya, P. Geochemistry of the miocene oil shale (Hancili Formation) in the Cankiri-Corum Basin, central turkey: implications for paleoclimate conditions, source-area weathering, provenance and tectonic setting. <i>Sed. Geol.</i><b>341</b>, 289&#x2013;303 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sedgeo.2016.05.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winchester, J. A. &amp; Floyd, P. A. Geochemical discrimination of different magma series and their differentiation products using immobile elements. <i>Chem. Geol.</i><b>20</b>, 325&#x2013;343 (1977).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0009-2541(77)90057-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, F. et al. From early paleozoic subduction to end-Carboniferous post-orogenic collapse: new constraints on the tectonic evolution of the central and South Tianshan (NW China). <i>Gondwana Res.</i><b>129</b>, 305&#x2013;331 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gr.2024.01.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. F. Mineral characteristics and metallogenic laws in Haduhulashan area of Yanxian County, Xinjiang (In Chinese). <i>Master dissertation, China University of Geosciences</i>, 13 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wronkiewicz, D. J. &amp; Condie, K. C. Geochemistry of archean shales from the Witwatersrand Supergroup, South africa: Source-area weathering and provenance. <i>Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta</i>. <b>51</b>, 2401&#x2013;2416 (1987).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0016-7037(87)90293-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eugster, H.P. &amp; Hardie, L.A. Saline Lakes. In: Lerman, A. (eds) Lakes. Springer, New York, NY (1978).10.1007/978-1-4757-1152-3_8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, J. L., Liu, Z. J., Bechtel, A., Strobl, S. A. I. &amp; Sun, P. C. Tectonic and climate control of oil shale deposition in the upper cretaceous Qingshankou formation (Songliao Basin, NE China). <i>Int. J. Earth Sci.</i><b>102</b>, 1717&#x2013;1734 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00531-013-0903-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, B. &amp; Manning, D. A. C. Comparison of geochemical indices used for the interpretation of Palaeoredox conditions in ancient mudstones. <i>Chem. Geol.</i><b>111</b>, 111&#x2013;129 (1994).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0009-2541(94)90085-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bond, D. P. G. &amp; Wignall, P. B. Pyrite framboid study of marine Permian&#x2013;Triassic boundary sections: A complex anoxic event and its relationship to contemporaneous mass extinction. <i>GSA Bull.</i><b>122</b>, 1265&#x2013;1279 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1130/B30042.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickard, D. Sedimentary pyrite framboid size-frequency distributions: A meta-analysis. <i>Palaeogeogr., Palaeoclimatol. Palaeoecol.</i><b>522</b>, 62&#x2013;75 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.palaeo.2019.03.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, H., Xiao, J., Yang, H., Yao, L. &amp; Yang, C. Redox conditions of Datangpo-type manganese ores constrained by statistical analysis of pyrite framboids and iron isotopes. <i>Sed. Geol.</i><b>463</b>, 106606 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sedgeo.2024.106606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji, S. et al. Morphology and in-situ sulfur isotope characteristics of pyrite across the Ordovician-Silurian boundary marine shale in South china: indicative significance for sedimentary environment. <i>Mar. Pet. Geol.</i><b>179</b>, 107431 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2025.107431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, Y. et al. Framboidal pyrite evidence for persistent low oxygen levels in shallow-marine facies of the Nanpanjiang basin during the Permian-Triassic transition. <i>Palaeogeogr., Palaeoclimatol. Palaeoecol.</i><b>511</b>, 243&#x2013;255 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.palaeo.2018.08.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, B. et al. Morphology and sulfur isotopes of pyrite in Chang73 shale: indications for redox conditions and enrichment of organic matter and hydrocarbons. <i>Mar. Pet. Geol.</i><b>180</b>, 107484 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2025.107484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, S. F. et al. Recognition of peat depositional environments in coal: A review. <i>Int. J. Coal Geol.</i><b>219</b>, 103383 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2019.103383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bau, M., Koschinsky, A., Dulski, P. &amp; Hein, J. R. Comparison of the partitioning behaviours of yttrium, rare Earth elements, and titanium between hydrogenetic marine ferromanganese crusts and seawater. <i>Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta</i>. <b>60</b>, 1709&#x2013;1725 (1996).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0016-7037(96)00063-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frape, S. K., Blyth, A., Blomqvist, R., McNutt, R. H. &amp; Gascoyne, M. 5.17 - Deep fluids in the continents: II. Crystalline rocks. In <i>Turekian (Editors), Treatise on Geochemistry</i> (ed. Holland, H. D.) 541&#x2013;580 (Pergamon, 2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. N. et al. Early mesozoic crustal evolution in the NW segment of West Qinling, china: evidence from diverse intermediate&#x2013;felsic igneous rocks. <i>Lithos</i><b>396&#x2013;397</b>, 106187 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lithos.2021.106187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dostal, J., Jutras, P. &amp; Solari, L. A. Late devonian felsic magmatism in Southern new Brunswick and its association with a large igneous Province that May have contributed to the Frasnian-Famennian extinction. <i>Lithos</i><b>482&#x2013;483</b>, 107715 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lithos.2024.107715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, Y., Tang, S. H., Zhang, S. H. &amp; Yang, N. Mineralogical and geochemical characteristics of trace elements in the Yongdingzhuang Mine, Datong Coalfield, Shanxi Province, China. <i>Minerals</i><b>8</b>, 297 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min8070297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, Q. C. et al. Source of inorganic components in the middle jurassic inertinite-rich coals of the Southern Ordos Basin, china: with emphasis on formation of Sr- and Ba-bearing minerals. <i>Ore Geol. Rev.</i><b>162</b>, 105703 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2023.105703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, P., Yuan, S. &amp; Liao, P. Mechanisms of hydroxyl radical production from abiotic oxidation of pyrite under acidic conditions. <i>Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta</i>. <b>172</b>, 444&#x2013;457 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gca.2015.10.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xe1;novas, C. R. et al. Metal(loid) release from sulfide-rich wastes to the environment: the case of the Iberian pyrite belt (SW Spain). <i>Curr. Opin. Environ. Sci. Health</i>. <b>20</b>, 100240 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coesh.2021.100240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, B., Wang, X. &amp; Ma, Y. Aluminium clay regulates oxidation dissolution mechanism of pyrite by solid film passivation layer and S, Fe, Al, Si speciation transformation. <i>Process Saf. Environ. Prot.</i><b>200</b>, 107331 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2025.107331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramus, C. The large combustion plant directive: an analysis of European environmental policy. <i>Oxford Institute for Energy Studies 1</i> (1991). https://www.oxfordenergy.org/wpcms/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/EV7-TheLargeCombustionPlantDirectiveAnAnalysisofEuropeanEnvironmentalPolicy-CARasmus-1991.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weimann, L. et al. Carbonaceous matter in &#x223c; 3.5 Ga black bedded barite from the dresser formation (Pilbara Craton, Western Australia) &#x2013; Insights into organic cycling on the juvenile Earth. <i>Precambrian Res.</i><b>403</b>, 107321 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.precamres.2024.107321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y. et al. Evidence of widespread wildfires in coal seams from the middle jurassic of Northwest China and its impact on paleoclimate. <i>Palaeogeogr., Palaeoclimatol. Palaeoecol.</i><b>559</b>, 109819 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.palaeo.2020.109819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. et al. Precession-scale climate forcing of peatland wildfires during the early middle jurassic greenhouse period. <i>Glob. Planet Change</i>. <b>184</b>, 103051 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gloplacha.2019.103051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, J. et al. Multi-proxy records of wildfires and climate-vegetation-wildfire mechanisms during the middle jurassic of the Yili Basin, Northwest China. <i>Glob. Planet Change</i>. <b>254</b>, 104991 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gloplacha.2025.104991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, C. et al. Paleoclimate-induced wildfires in a paleomire in the Ordos Basin, Northern China during the middle jurassic greenhouse period. <i>Chem. Geol.</i><b>637</b>, 121677 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemgeo.2023.121677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branfireun, B. A., Roulet, N. T., Kelly, C. A. &amp; Rudd, J. W. M. In situ sulphate stimulation of mercury methylation in a boreal peatland: toward a link between acid rain and Methylmercury contamination in remote environments. <i>Glob. Biogeochem. Cycles</i>. <b>13</b>, 743&#x2013;750 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/1999GB900033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, H. Y. et al. Impact of the atmospheric deposition of major acid rain components, especially NH4, on carbonate weathering during recharge in typical karst areas of the Lijiang river basin, Southwest China. <i>Appl. Geochem.</i><b>114</b>, 104518 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apgeochem.2019.104518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>USGS. Critical mineral resources of the United States&#x2014;Economic. and environmental geology and prospects for future supply. (2017). 10.3133/pp1802</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffith, E. M. &amp; Paytan, A. Barite in the ocean &#x2013; occurrence, geochemistry and palaeoceanographic applications. <i>Sedimentology</i><b>59</b>, 1817&#x2013;1835 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-3091.2012.01327.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Z. N. et al. Geochemical characteristics and genesis of hydrothermal vein barite hosted in sedimentary caprock in Northern Huangling anticline. <i>Resour. Environ. Eng.</i><b>36</b>, 580&#x2013;587 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolze, C. E., Malone, P. G. &amp; Smith, M. J. Microbial mobilization of barite. <i>Chem. Geol.</i><b>13</b>, 141&#x2013;143 (1974).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0009-2541(74)90006-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brumsack, H. J. &amp; Gieskes, J. M. Interstitial water trace-metal chemistry of laminated sediments from the Gulf of California, Mexico. <i>Mar. Chem.</i><b>14</b>, 89&#x2013;106 (1983).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0304-4203(83)90072-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cecile, M. P., Shakur, M. A. &amp; Krouse, H. R. The isotopic composition of Western Canadian barites and the possible derivation of oceanic sulphate &#x3b4;<sup>34</sup>S and &#x3b4;<sup>18</sup>O age curves. <i>Can. J. Earth Sci.</i><b>20</b>, 1528&#x2013;1535 (1983).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/e83-142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xe9;h&#xe9;ret, J. G. &amp; Brumsack, H. J. Barite concretions as evidence of pauses in sedimentation in the Marnes bleues formation of the Vocontian basin (SE France). <i>Sed. Geol.</i><b>130</b>, 205&#x2013;228 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0037-0738(99)00112-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guanglai, C., Shujin, Q. &amp; Chaodong, W. Jurassic Coal in Yanqi Basin (Xinjiang,China): Geochemical Characteristics of Trace Elements and Their Implications. 40, 594&#x2013;600 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DZ/T 0211&#x2013; Specifications for barite, witherite, fluorite and boron mineral exploration. <i>Geological Press</i>, Beijing, China, 2020 (In Chinese). (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blount, C. W. Barite solubilities and thermodynamic quantities up to 300 degrees C and 1400 bars. <i>Am. Mineral.</i><b>62</b>, 942&#x2013;957 (1977).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhen-Wu, B. Y. et al. Experimental determination of barite dissolution and precipitation rates as a function of temperature and aqueous fluid composition. <i>Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta</i>. <b>194</b>, 193&#x2013;210 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gca.2016.08.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>