<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41449185</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An innovative technique and laboratory protocol for CO<sub>2</sub> storage in water disposal wells and monitoring asphaltene deposition.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3022</StartPage><MedlinePgn>3022</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3022</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-32916-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Injecting CO<sub>2</sub> into water-disposal wells is a promising strategy for geological carbon storage. However, this process can destabilize asphaltenes in residual oil blobs-primarily of the emulsified type - trapped within trapped in the porous rock, leading to precipitation that threatens storage integrity and operational safety. This study introduces a novel high-pressure laboratory apparatus and protocol designed to directly quantify asphaltene precipitation during CO<sub>2</sub> injection into oil-in-water emulsions, which represent water-flooded formations. The system operates at reservoir-relevant conditions (up to 11,000 psi and 210&#xa0;&#xb0;C) and utilizes in situ near-infrared (NIR) light transmission to monitor asphaltene precipitation in real-time. Additionally, this research investigates the behavior of the oil-in-water emulsion (EM) phase as the medium hosting CO<sub>2</sub> gas under different conditions. Quantitative results, expressed as the percentage reduction in NIR transmission, showed that asphaltene precipitation was minimized to 0.8% under optimal conditions (2DSW, 120&#xa0;&#xb0;C, 50&#xa0;mol% CO<sub>2</sub>), compared to a peak of 25.1% in the worst-case scenario (FW, 30&#xa0;&#xb0;C, 35&#xa0;mol% CO<sub>2</sub>). Regarding the CO<sub>2</sub> injection rate, less asphaltene precipitation occurred at higher injection rates. In this case, crude oil vaporized in the EM phase at high CO<sub>2</sub> injection rates (above 35&#xa0;mol%), resulting in fewer crude oil droplets available to interact with CO<sub>2</sub>. Notably, EMs prepared with twice-diluted seawater (2DSW) exhibited the least asphaltene precipitation, a finding strongly correlated with lower oil/water interfacial tension. Overall, the developed protocol provides a critical tool for screening and de-risking CO<sub>2</sub> storage sites in water-disposal zones by enabling accurate prediction of asphaltene-related damage.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jafarbeigi</LastName><ForeName>Ehsan</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Petroleum Engineering, Sharif University of Technology, P.O. Box 11155&#x2009;-&#x2009;9465, Tehran, Iran. e.jafarbigi@ilam.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Petroleum Engineering, Ilam University, Ilam, Iran. e.jafarbigi@ilam.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayatollahi</LastName><ForeName>Shahab</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Petroleum Engineering, Sharif University of Technology, P.O. Box 11155&#x2009;-&#x2009;9465, Tehran, Iran. shahab@sharif.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No.4012741</GrantID><Agency>Iranian National Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Asphaltene precipitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CO2 injection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CO2 storage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oil/Water emulsions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Water disposal zone</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41449185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12827469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-32916-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-32916-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abas, N., Kalair, A., Khan, N. &amp; Kalair, A. R. Review of GHG emissions in Pakistan compared to SAARC countries. <i>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</i><b>80</b>, 990&#x2013;1016 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffry, L. et al. Greenhouse gases utilization: a review. <i>Fuel</i><b>301</b>, 121017 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Commission (EC). Towards an integrated strategic energy technology (SET) plan: research and innovation challenges and needs of the EU energy system. <i>Communication European. Commission</i>. https://setis.ec.europa.eu/set-plan-process/integrated-roadmap-and-action-plan. (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Commission (EC). Towards an integrated strategic energy technology (SET) plan: accelerating the European energy system transformation. <i>Communication European Commission</i>. https://ec.europa.eu/energy/sites/ener/files/documents/1_EN_ACT_part1_v8_0.pd. (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson, E., Nwakile, C. &amp; Hammed, V. O. Carbon capture, utilization, and storage (CCUS) technologies: evaluating the effectiveness of advanced CCUS solutions for reducing CO<sub>2</sub> emissions. <i>Results Surf. Interfaces</i>. <b>18</b>, 100381 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halari, D. et al. Enhanced oil recovery using carbonated polymeric nanofluids: A new age approach to CO<sub>2</sub> utilization and corrosion mitigation. <i>Ind. Eng. Chem.</i><b>149</b>, 801&#x2013;817 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastami, D., Shahrabadi, A., Naderi, H., Taghikhani, V. &amp; Taheri-Shakib, J. Molecular level characterization of interactions between asphaltene and solid surface for forecasting changes in wettability. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 28394 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12322175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40759995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salimi, F., Ayatollahi, S. &amp; Vafaei-Seftie, M. Prediction of asphaltene deposition during turbulent flow using heat transfer approach. <i>Pet. Sci. Technol.</i><b>36</b>, 632&#x2013;639 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameli, F., Hemmati-Sarapardeh, A., Dabir, B. &amp; Mohammadi, A. H. On the evaluation of asphaltene precipitation Titration data: modeling and data assessment. <i>Fluid Phase Equilib.</i><b>412</b>, 235&#x2013;248 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemmati-Sarapardeh, A., Dabir, B., Ahmadi, M., Mohammadi, A. H. &amp; Husein, M. M. Toward mechanistic Understanding of asphaltene aggregation behavior in toluene: the roles of asphaltene structure, aging time, temperature, and ultrasonic radiation. <i>J. Mol. Liq</i>. <b>264</b>, 410&#x2013;424 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazyar, S., Nabipour, M., Azdarpour, A., Honarvar, B. &amp; Esfandiari, N. Experimental investigation of asphaltene precipitation during waterflooding using different aqueous phases. <i>Energy Sources Part. A</i>. <b>45</b>, 4481&#x2013;4500 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehghani, F., Ayatollahi, S., Jafarbeigi, E. &amp; Moradpour, N. Experimental study of asphaltene onset condition and deposition using electrical deposition technique in the presence of various additives: A novel strategy. <i>Fuel</i><b>357</b>, 129514 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafarbeigi, E., Sahraei, E. &amp; Maroufi, K. A novel functionalized nanoparticle for inhibiting asphaltene precipitation and deposition. <i>Phys. Fluids</i>. <b>37</b>, 017164 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehzadeh, M., Husein, M. M., Ghotbi, C., Dabir, B. &amp; Taghikhani, V. In-depth characterization of light, medium and heavy oil asphaltenes as well as asphaltenes subfractions. <i>Fuel</i><b>324</b>, 124525 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shadman, M. M., Badizad, M. H., Dehghanizadeh, M. &amp; Dehaghani, A. H. S. Developing a novel colloidal model for predicting asphaltene precipitation from crude oil by alkane Dilution. <i>J. Mol. Liq</i>. <b>318</b>, 113879 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoudvand, M., Javadi, A. &amp; Pourafshary, P. Brine ions impacts on water-oil dynamic interfacial properties considering asphaltene and maltene constituents. <i>Colloids Surf. A</i>. <b>579</b>, 123665 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eskini, F., Dehaghani, A. S. &amp; Shadman, M. M. Modelling the effect of the inhibitors on asphaltene precipitation using Flory&#x2013;Huggins theory. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>12</b> (1), 18946 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9643540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36347921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razghandi, M. et al. Effect of asphaltene flocculation size on deposition using a modified quartz crystal microbalance in-house setup and microscopic image analysis: model oil, inhibitory and nanoparticle solutions case studies. <i>Geoenergy Sci. Eng.</i><b>237</b>, 212819 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taha, S. M. &amp; Khaksar-Manshad, A. State of asphaltene in crude oil and application of nano-chemicals for aggregation inhibition: A comprehensive review. <i>Fuel</i><b>393</b>, 135004 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amiri-Ramsheh, B., Sahebalzamani, S., Zabihi, R. &amp; Hemmati-Sarapardeh, A. Predicting asphaltene precipitation during natural depletion of oil reservoirs by integrating SARA fractions with advanced intelligent models. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b> (1), 26214 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12276298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40683969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalighi, J. &amp; Cheremisin, A. Robust asphaltene onset pressure prediction using ensemble learning. <i>Results Eng.</i><b>24</b>, 103483 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, M. T. T. et al. Molecular mechanisms of asphaltene dispersion by acrylamide-based polymers: A combined study of molecular dynamics simulations, geometric analysis, and density functional theory calculations. <i>J. Mol. Liq</i>. <b>414</b>, 132215 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez, E. A., Lira-Galeana, C. &amp; Ancheyta, J. Analysis of asphaltene precipitation models from solubility and Thermodynamic-Colloidal theories. <i>Processes</i><b>11</b>, 765 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martyushev, D. A. Modeling and prediction of asphaltene-resin-paraffinic substances deposits in oil production wells. <i>Georesursy</i><b>22</b>, 86&#x2013;92 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lashkarbolooki, M., Riazi, M., Ayatollahi, S. &amp; Hezave, A. Z. Synergy effects of ions, resin, and asphaltene on interfacial tension of acidic crude oil and low&#x2013;high salinity Brines. <i>Fuel</i><b>165</b>, 75&#x2013;85 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khormali, A., Sharifov, A. R. &amp; Torba, D. I. The control of asphaltene precipitation in oil wells. <i>Pet. Sci. Technol.</i><b>36</b>, 443&#x2013;449 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikoo, A. H., Ghaedi, M., Malayeri, M. R. &amp; Riazi, M. Analysis of wellbore clogging by asphaltene deposition using interaction energies. <i>Fuel</i><b>352</b>, 129111 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikoo, A. H., Ghaedi, M. &amp; Malayeri, M. R. Impact of various aggregation kinetics on thermophoretic velocity of asphaltene deposition. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 18430 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11310216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39117792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanganeh, P., Dashti, H. &amp; Ayatollahi, S. Comparing the effects of CH<sub>4</sub>, CO<sub>2</sub>, and N<sub>2</sub> injection on asphaltene precipitation and deposition at reservoir condition: A visual and modeling study. <i>Fuel</i><b>217</b>, 633&#x2013;641 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi, Y., Kharrat, R., Hashemi, A., Bahrami, P. &amp; Mahdavi, S. Effect of temperature on asphaltene precipitation in crude oils from Xinjiang oilfield. <i>ACS Omega</i>. <b>7</b>, 36244&#x2013;36253 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9583088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36278113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi, Y., Akbari, A., Mansouri, M., Alibak, A. H. &amp; Vaferi, B. Innovative Xanthan gum-based nanocomposites for asphaltene precipitation prevention in shale and carbonate rocks. <i>Int. J. Biol. Macromol.</i><b>280</b>, 136331 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39482134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, S. I. et al. Phenomena, factors of wax deposition and its management strategies. <i>Arab. J. Geosci.</i><b>15</b>, 133 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, S. I. et al. Factorial analysis of experimental parameters effecting asphaltene precipitation in dead crude oils. <i>Arab. J. Sci. Eng.</i><b>48</b>, 9519&#x2013;9533 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins, R. G., Martins, L. S. &amp; Santos, R. G. Effects of Short-Chain n-Alcohols on the properties of asphaltenes at Toluene/Air and Toluene/Water interfaces. <i>Colloids Interfaces</i><b>2</b>(2), 3 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi, B., Molaei, A. H., Sahraei, E. &amp; Mohammadi, A. H. Evaluation of competitive and synergistic effects of potential determining ions on interfacial tension reduction and wettability alteration in carbonate oil reservoirs. <i>Colloids Surf. A</i>. <b>713</b>, 136474 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghorbani, M., Gandomkar, A. &amp; Honarvar, B. Experimental investigation of asphaltene content effect on crude Oil/CO. <i>Minimum Miscibility Press. Period Polytech. Chem. Eng.</i><b>64</b> (4), 479&#x2013;490 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandomkar, A., Torabi, F. &amp; Nasriani, H. R. Decreasing asphaltene precipitation and deposition during immiscible gas injection via the introduction of a CO<sub>2</sub>-Soluble asphaltene inhibitor. <i>SPE Journal</i>. <b>28</b>(05), 1&#x2013;13 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi, R., Saeedi Dehaghani, A. H. &amp; Najafi, H. A study on asphaltene adsorption onto two mineral adsorbents in the presence and absence of anionic and ionic inhibitors. <i>Energy Sources Part. A</i>. <b>47</b> (1), 2222&#x2013;2238 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shadervan, A., Jafari, A., Teimouri, A., Gharibshahi, R. &amp; Dehaghani, A. H. S. Mechanistic Understanding of asphaltene precipitation and oil recovery enhancement using SiO<sub>2</sub> and CaCO<sub>3</sub> nano-inhibitors. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b> (1), 15249 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11220011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38956269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farahabadi, Z. T. &amp; Lashkarbolooki, M. Effect of CO<sub>2</sub> on the interfacial tension and swelling of crude oil during carbonated water flooding. <i>J. Pet. Explor. Prod. Technol.</i><b>13</b>, 353&#x2013;364 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamidian, R., Lashkarbolooki, M. &amp; Hezave, A. Z. Interfacial tension and contact angle of asphaltenic and resinous model oil in the presence of binary salts mixtures. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 18018 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11297926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39097601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashiri, R., Garapov, A. &amp; Pourafshary, P. Effect of pH on the dominant mechanisms of oil recovery by low salinity water in fractured carbonates. <i>Energy Fuels</i>. <b>37</b>, 10951&#x2013;10959 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shams, S. M., Dehghan, A. A., Kazemzadeh, Y. &amp; Riazi, M. Experimental investigation of emulsion formation and stability: comparison of low salinity water and smart water effect. <i>J. Dispersion Sci. Technol.</i><b>45</b>, 1646&#x2013;1655 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villero-Mandon, J., Askar, N., Pourafshary, P. &amp; Riazi, M. Importance of Fluid/Fluid interactions in enhancing oil recovery by optimizing Low-Salinity waterflooding in sandstones. <i>Energies</i><b>17</b>, 1073 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villero-Mandon, J., Pourafshary, P. &amp; Riazi, M. Oil/Brine screening for improved Fluid/Fluid interactions. <i>Colloids Interfaces</i>. <b>8</b> (2), 23 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zivar, D., Ishanov, A. &amp; Pourafshary, P. Insights into wettability alteration during low-salinity water flooding by capacitance-resistance model. <i>Pet. Res.</i><b>7</b>, 500&#x2013;510 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seidy-Esfahlan, M., Khodapanah, E. &amp; Tabatabaei-Nezhad, S. A. Production improvement mechanisms in combined low salinity water flooding and preformed particle gel treatment. <i>Results Eng.</i><b>22</b>, 102126 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zapata, Y. et al. Well-based monitoring of CO<sub>2</sub> geological sequestration operations in saline aquifers: critical insights into key questions. <i>Carbon Capture Sci. Technol.</i><b>5</b>, 100079 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suramairy, R. et al. Impact of reservoir organic acid and Brine salinity on CO<sub>2</sub>-rock interfacial tension and wettability in carbonate rocks: insights for geological CO<sub>2</sub> storage. <i>Results Eng.</i><b>27</b>, 105983 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iranfar, S., Sadeghpour, F., Khaksar-Manshad, A., Naderi, M. &amp; Shakiba, M. An Eigenvalue-Driven framework for the ranking and selection of optimal geological CO<sub>2</sub> storage sites. <i>Results Eng.</i><b>27</b>, 106770 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavakkoli, M. et al. Effect of emulsified water on asphaltene instability in crude oils. <i>Energy Fuels</i>. <b>30</b>, 3676&#x2013;3686 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, R., Lai, L. &amp; Zhang, H. Stabilization mechanism of emulsion gels of crude oil with low asphaltene, resin, and wax contents. <i>J. Mol. Liq</i>. <b>417</b>, 126496 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, Y. et al. Effect of asphaltenes on the stability of water in crude oil emulsions. <i>Materials</i><b>18</b>, 630 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11818801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39942296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaseen, S. &amp; Mansoori, G. A. Asphaltene aggregation onset during high-salinity waterflooding of reservoirs (a molecular dynamic study). <i>Pet. Sci. Technol.</i><b>36</b>, 1725&#x2013;1732 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mokhtari, R., Ayatollahi, S. &amp; Fatemi, M. Experimental investigation of the influence of fluid-fluid interactions on oil recovery during low salinity water flooding. <i>J. Pet. Sci. Eng.</i><b>182</b>, 106194 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahsavani, B., Riazi, M. &amp; Malayer, M. R. Asphaltene instability in the presence of emulsified aqueous phase. <i>Fuel</i><b>305</b>, 121528 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tajikmansori, A., Saeedi-Dehaghani, A. H., Sadeghnejad, S. &amp; Haghighi, M. New insights into effect of the electrostatic properties on the interfacial behavior of asphaltene and resin: an experimental study of molecular structure. <i>J. Mol. Liq</i>. <b>377</b>, 121526 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lake, L. W., Lotfollahi, M. &amp; Bryant, S. L. Chapter 2-CO<sub>2</sub> enhanced oil recovery experience and its messages for CO<sub>2</sub> storage. in Science of Carbon Storage in Deep Saline Formations (eds Newell, P. &amp; Ilgen, A.) G.) 15&#x2013;31 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soleymanzadeh, A., Yousefi, M., Kord, S. &amp; Mohammadzadeh, O. A review on methods of determining onset of asphaltene precipitation. <i>Pet. Explor. Prod. Technol.</i><b>9</b>, 1375&#x2013;1396 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peysson, Y., Andre, L. &amp; Azaroual, M. Well injectivity during CO<sub>2</sub> storage operations in deep saline aquifers&#x2013;Part 1: experimental investigation of drying effects, salt precipitation and capillary forces. <i>Int. J. Greenh. Gas Control</i>. <b>22</b>, 291&#x2013;300 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, P. et al. Comparative analysis of CO<sub>2</sub>, N<sub>2</sub>, and gas mixture injection on asphaltene deposition pressure in reservoir conditions. <i>Energies</i><b>11</b>, 2483 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho, J., Kim, T. H., Chang, N. &amp; Lee, K. S. Effects of asphaltene deposition-derived formation damage on three-phase hysteretic models for prediction of coupled CO<sub>2</sub> enhanced oil recovery and storage performance. <i>J. Pet. Sci. Eng.</i><b>172</b>, 988&#x2013;997 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajiabadi, S. H., Bedrikovetsky, P., Borazjani, S. &amp; Mahani, H. Well injectivity during CO<sub>2</sub> geosequestration: A review of Hydro-Physical, Chemical, and Geomechanical effects. <i>Energy Fuels</i>. <b>35</b>, 9240&#x2013;9267 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusof, M. A. M. et al. Experimental study of CO<sub>2</sub> injectivity impairment in sandstone due to salt precipitation and fines migration. <i>Pet. Explor. Prod. Technol.</i><b>12</b>, 2191&#x2013;2202 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razghandi, M., Madani, S. A., Ghotbi, C., Ayatollahi, S. &amp; Dabir, B. A. bdolhossein Hemmati-Sarapardeh. <i>Geoenergy Sci. Eng.</i><b>237</b>, 212819 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sokola, P. et al. Quantitative assessment of ceramic suspension stability using a lumisizer analytical centrifuge. <i>Ceramics</i><b>8</b> (3), 115 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos, D. et al. Study of asphaltene precipitation in crude oils at desalter conditions by Near-Infrared spectroscopy. <i>Energy Fuels</i>. <b>31</b> (5), 5031&#x2013;5036 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacMillan, D., Tackett-Jr, J. E., Jessee, M. A. &amp; Monger-McClure T.G. A unified approach to asphaltene precipitation: laboratory measurement and modeling. <i>J. Petrol. Technol.</i><b>47</b>, 788&#x2013;793 (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratnakar, R., Mantilla, C. &amp; Dindoruk, B. Experimental investigation of the effects of asphaltene stability on interfacial behavior of live-reservoir-fluid systems. <i>SPE J.</i><b>24</b>, 21&#x2013;31 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yonebayashi, H. et al. Determination of asphaltene-onset pressure using multiple techniques in parallel. <i>SPE Prod. Oper.</i><b>33</b>, 486&#x2013;497 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke, N., Hobbs, R. E. &amp; Kashou, S. F. Measurement and modeling of asphaltene precipitation (in-cludes associated paper 23831). <i>J. Petrol. Technol.</i><b>42</b>, 1440e1446 (1990).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamaluddin, A. et al. Laboratory techniques to measure thermodynamic asphaltene instability. <i>J Can. Pet. Technol</i>. <b>41</b>(07). (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandomkar, A. &amp; Nasriani., H. R. The role of direct asphaltene inhibitors on asphaltene stabilization during gas injection. <i>Fuel</i><b>282</b>, 118827 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandomkar, A., Nasriani, H. R., Enick, R. M. &amp; Torabi, F. The effect of CO<sub>2</sub>-philic thickeners on gravity drainage mechanism in gas invaded zone. <i>Fuel</i><b>331</b>, 125760 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, M., Han, C., Wang, S. &amp; Chen, Y. Investigation of density, viscosity and derived thermodynamic properties of CO<sub>2</sub>-free and CO<sub>2</sub>-loaded poly(ethylene imine) aqueous systems at different temperatures and 0.1 MPa. <i>J. Mol. Liq</i>. <b>377</b>, 121523 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badarlis, A., Pfau, A. &amp; Kalfas, A. Measurement and evaluation of the gas density and viscosity of pure gases and mixtures using a micro-cantilever beam. <i>Sensors</i><b>15</b>, 24318&#x2013;24342 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4610587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26402682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandomkar, A., Torabi, F. &amp; Enick, R. M. Enhanced oil recovery via dissolution of low molecular weight PDMS in CO<sub>2</sub> during immiscible gas injection in matrix-fracture system. <i>Chem. Eng. Res. Des.</i><b>203</b>, 18&#x2013;28 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rostami, P., Mehraban, M. F., Sharifi, M., Dejam, M. &amp; Ayatollahi, S. Effect of water salinity on oil/brine interfacial behaviour during low salinity waterflooding: A mechanistic study. <i>Petroleum</i><b>5</b>, 367&#x2013;374 (2019).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>