<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41512070</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2375-2548</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Science advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Responses of extreme fire weather to CO<sub>2</sub> emission reductions and underlying mechanisms.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>eadw4705</StartPage><MedlinePgn>eadw4705</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">eadw4705</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1126/sciadv.adw4705</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>While previous studies have reported an increase in future fire weather under global warming scenarios, there is still a limited understanding on how it may evolve under mitigation scenarios. Using idealized emission-driven climate simulations, this analysis examines changes in the extreme fire weather conditions under net-zero emission (ZeroE) and net-negative emission (NegE) scenarios. Compared to peak CO<sub>2</sub> levels, the NegE scenario achieves substantially greater fire danger mitigation, particularly in climatologically high-fire-danger regions, because of lower temperatures and increased relative humidity. In contrast, the ZeroE scenario leaves fire danger elevated globally, especially in Northern low-latitude regions. Regional responses are shaped by differences in atmospheric moisture supply, influenced by changes in the strength of the Atlantic meridional overturning circulation and the latitudinal position of the intertropical convergence zone. These findings highlight the crucial role of aggressive CO<sub>2</sub> removal strategies in mitigating fire weather dangers and underscore the limitations of ZeroEs alone in addressing global wildfire challenges.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Yujin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9452-2966</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Environmental Science and Engineering, Pohang University of Science and Technology, Pohang, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Climate-Social Science Convergence, Kyung Hee University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Min</LastName><ForeName>Seung-Ki</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6749-010X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Environmental Science and Engineering, Pohang University of Science and Technology, Pohang, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Convergence Research and Education in Advanced Technology, Yonsei University, Incheon, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>An</LastName><ForeName>Soon-Il</ForeName><Initials>SI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0003-429X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Environmental Science and Engineering, Pohang University of Science and Technology, Pohang, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paik</LastName><ForeName>Seungmok</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3655-4227</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Earth and Environmental Sciences, Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mondal</LastName><ForeName>Sanjit Kumar</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2118-6858</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Atmospheric Sciences, Yonsei University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101653440</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2375-2548</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41512070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12787522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.adw4705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cunningham C. X., Williamson G. J., Bowman D. M. J. S., Increasing frequency and intensity of the most extreme wildfires on Earth. Nat. Ecol. Evol. 8, 1420&#x2013;1425 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38914710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turco M., Jerez S., Augusto S., Tar&#xed;n-Carrasco P., Ratola N., Jim&#xe9;nez-Guerrero P., Trigo R. M., Climate drivers of the 2017 devastating fires in Portugal. Sci. Rep. 9, 13886 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6787010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31601820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams A. P., Abatzoglou J. T., Gershunov A., Guzman-Morales J., Bishop D. A., Balch J. K., Lettenmaier D. P., Observed impacts of anthropogenic climate change on wildfire in California. Earth&#x2019;s Future 7, 892&#x2013;910 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias V., Balch J. K., Travis W. R., US fires became larger, more frequent, and more widespread in the 2000s. Sci. Adv. 8, eabc0020 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8926334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35294238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silveira M. V. F., Silva-Junior C. H. L., Anderson L. O., Arag&#xe3;o L. E. O. C., Amazon fires in the 21st century: The year of 2020 in evidence. Glob. Ecol. Biogeogr. 31, 2026&#x2013;2040 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parisien M.-A., Barber Q. E., Bourbonnais M. L., Daniels L. D., Flannigan M. D., Gray R. W., Hoffman K. M., Jain P., Stephens S. L., Taylor S. W., Whitman E., Abrupt, climate-induced increase in wildfires in British Columbia since the mid-2000s. Commun. Earth Environ. 4, 309 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andela N., Morton D. C., Giglio L., Chen Y., van der Werf G. R., Kasibhatla P. S., DeFries R. S., Collatz G. J., Hantson S., Kloster S., Bachelet D., Forrest M., Lasslop G., Li F., Mangeon S., Melton J. R., Yue C., Randerson J. T., A human-driven decline in global burned area. Science 356, 1356&#x2013;1362 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6047075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28663495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burton C., Lampe S., Kelley D. I., Thiery W., Hantson S., Christidis N., Gudmundsson L., Forrest M., Burke E., Chang J., Huang H., Ito A., Kou-Giesbrecht S., Lasslop G., Li W., Nieradzik L., Li F., Chen Y., Randerson J., Reyer C. P. O., Mengel M., Global burned area increasingly explained by climate change. Nat. Clim. Change 14, 1186&#x2013;1192 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pausas J. G., Keeley J. E., Wildfires and global change. Front. Ecol. Environ. 19, 387&#x2013;395 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jolly W. M., Cochrane M. A., Freeborn P. H., Holden Z. A., Brown T. J., Williamson G. J., Bowman D. M. J. S., Climate-induced variations in global wildfire danger from 1979 to 2013. Nat. Commun. 6, 7537 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4803474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26172867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowdy A. J., Climatological variability of fire weather in Australia. J. Appl. Meteorol. Climatol. 57, 221&#x2013;234 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowman D. M. J. S., Kolden C. A., Abatzoglou J. T., Johnston F. H., van der Werf G. R., Flannigan M., Vegetation fires in the Anthropocene. Nat. Rev. Earth Environ. 1, 500&#x2013;515 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain P., Castellanos-Acuna D., Coogan S. C., Abatzoglou J. T., Flannigan M. D., Observed increases in extreme fire weather driven by atmospheric humidity and temperature. Nat. Clim. Change 12, 63&#x2013;70 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IPCC, &#x201c;Summary for policymakers&#x201d; in <i>Climate Change 2021: The Physical Science Basis</i>, V. Masson-Delmotte, P. Zhai, A. Pirani, S. L. Connors, C. P&#xe9;an, S. Berger, N. Caud, Y. Chen, L. Goldfarb, M. I. Gomis, M. Huang, K. Leitzell, E. Lonnoy, J .B. R. Matthews, T. K. Maycock, T. Waterfield, O. Yelek&#xe7;i, R. Yu, B. Zhou, Eds. (Cambridge Univ. Press, 2021), pp. 3&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbero R., Abatzoglou J. T., Pimont F., Ruffault J., Curt T., Attributing increases in fire weather to anthropogenic climate change over France. Front. Earth Sci. 8, 104 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fargeon H., Pimont F., Martin-StPaul N., De C&#xe1;ceres M., Ruffault J., Barbero R., Dupuy J. L., Projections of fire danger under climate change over France: Where do the greatest uncertainties lie? Clim. Change 160, 479&#x2013;493 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruffault J., Curt T., Moron V., Trigo R. M., Mouillot F., Koutsias N., Pimont F., Martin-Stpaul N., Barbero R., Dupuy J. L., Russo A., Belhadj-Khedher C., Increased likelihood of heat-induced large wildfires in the Mediterranean Basin. Sci. Rep. 10, 13790 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7427790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32796945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touma D., Stevenson S., Lehner F., Coats S., Human-driven greenhouse gas and aerosol emissions cause distinct regional impacts on extreme fire weather. Nat. Commun. 12, 212 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7801713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33431844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turco M., Rosa-C&#xe1;novas J. J., Bedia J., Jerez S., Mont&#xe1;vez J. P., Llasat M. C., Provenzale A., Exacerbated fires in Mediterranean Europe due to anthropogenic warming projected with non-stationary climate-fire models. Nat. Commun. 9, 3821 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6168540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30279564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abatzoglou J. T., Williams A. P., Barbero R., Global emergence of anthropogenic climate change in fire weather indices. Geophys. Res. Lett. 46, 326&#x2013;336 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry M. C., Vanvyve E., Betts R. A., Palin E. J., Past and future trends in fire weather for the UK. Nat. Hazards Earth Syst. Sci. 22, 559&#x2013;575 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon S., Plattner G. K., Knutti R., Friedlingstein P., Irreversible climate change due to carbon dioxide emissions. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 106, 1704&#x2013;1709 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2632717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19179281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boucher O., Halloran P. R., Burke E. J., Doutriaux-Boucher M., Jones C. D., Lowe J., Ringer M. A., Robertson E., Wu P., 
Reversibility in an Earth System model in response to CO<sub>2</sub> concentration changes. Environ. Res. Lett.
7, 
024013 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu P., Ridley J., Pardaens A., Levine R., Lowe J., 
The reversibility of CO<sub>2</sub> induced climate change. Clim. Dyn.
45, 
745&#x2013;754 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An S.-I., Shin J., Yeh S.-W., Son S.-W., Kug J.-S., Min S.-K., Kim H.-J., Global cooling hiatus driven by an AMOC overshoot in a carbon dioxide removal scenario. Earth&#x2019;s Future 9, e2021EF002165 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jo S.-Y., Seong M.-G., Min S.-K., Kug J.-S., Yeh S.-W., An S.-I., Son S.-W., Shin J., 
Hysteresis behaviors in East Asian extreme precipitation frequency to CO<sub>2</sub> pathway. Geophys. Res. Lett.
49, 
e2022GL099814 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwinger J., Asaadi A., Goris N., Lee H., Possibility for strong northern hemisphere high-latitude cooling under negative emissions. Nat. Commun. 13, 1095 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8888562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35232955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., An S.-I., Jin F.-F., Shin J., Kug J.-S., Zhang W., Stuecker M. F., Yuan X., Xue A., Geng X., Kim S.-K., 
Hysteresis of the El Ni&#xf1;o&#x2013;Southern oscillation to CO<sub>2</sub> forcing. Sci. Adv.
9, 
eadh8442 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10396313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37531428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song S.-Y., Yeh S.-W., Allan R. P., Xie S.-P., An S.-I., Park H.-S., 
Climate sensitivity controls global precipitation hysteresis in a changing CO<sub>2</sub> pathway. npj Clim. Atmos. Sci.
6, 
156 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kug J.-S., Oh J.-H., An S.-I., Yeh S.-W., Min S.-K., Son S.-W., Kam J., Ham Y.-G., Shin J., 
Hysteresis of the intertropical convergence zone to CO<sub>2</sub> forcing. Nat. Clim. Change
12, 
47&#x2013;53 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S.-K., Shin J., An S.-I., Kim H.-J., Im N., Xie S.-P., Kug J.-S., Yeh S.-W., 
Widespread irreversible changes in surface temperature and precipitation in response to CO<sub>2</sub> forcing. Nat. Clim. Change
12, 
834&#x2013;840 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H.-J., Kim J.-S., An S.-I., Shin J., Oh J.-H., Kug J.-S., Pervasive fire danger continued under a negative emission scenario. Nat. Commun. 15, 10010 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11576758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39562546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C.E. Van Wagner, &#x201c;Development and structure of the Canadian forest fire weather index system&#x201d; (Forestry Technical Report, Canadian Forestry Service, 1987).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones M. W., Veraverbeke S., Andela N., Doerr S. H., Kolden C., Mataveli G., Pettinari M. L., Le Qu&#xe9;r&#xe9; C., Rosan T. M., van der Werf G. R., van Wees D., Abatzoglou J. T., Global rise in forest fire emissions linked to climate change in the extratropics. Science 386, eadl5889 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39418381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quilcaille Y., Batibeniz F., Ribeiro A. F., Padr&#xf3;n R. S., Seneviratne S. I., Fire weather index data under historical and shared socioeconomic pathway projections in the 6th phase of the Coupled Model Intercomparison Project from 1850 to 2100. Earth Syst. Sci. Data 15, 2153&#x2013;2177 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son R., Kim H., Wang S.-Y. S., Jeong J.-H., Woo S.-H., Jeong J.-Y., Lee B.-D., Kim S. H., LaPlante M., Kwon C.-G., Yoon J.-H., Changes in fire weather climatology under 1.5&#xb0;C and 2.0&#xb0;C warming. Environ. Res. Lett. 16, 034058 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S.-Y., Choi Y.-J., Son S.-W., Grise K.-M., Staten P.-W., An S.-I., Yeh S.-W., Kug J.-S., Min S.-K., Shin J., 
Hemispherically asymmetric Hadley cell response to CO<sub>2</sub> removal. Sci. Adv.
9, 
eadg1801 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10371030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37494441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., An S.-I., Zhao J., Son S.-W., Jin F.-F., Zhan R., 
Hemispheric asymmetric response of tropical cyclones to CO<sub>2</sub> emission reduction. npj Clim. Atmos. Sci.
7, 
83 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paik S., An S.-I., Min S.-K., King A.-D., Shin J., 
Hysteretic behavior of global to regional monsoon area under CO<sub>2</sub> ramp-up and ramp-down. Earth&#x2019;s Future
11, 
e2022EF003434 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J.-H., Kug J.-S., An S.-I., Jin F.-F., McPhaden M. J., Shin J., Emergent climate change patterns originating from deep ocean warming in climate mitigation scenarios. Nat. Clim. Change 14, 260&#x2013;266 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao L., Bala G., Caldeira K., Nemani R., Ban-Weiss G., Importance of carbon dioxide physiological forcing to future climate change. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 107, 9513&#x2013;9518 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2906877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20445083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danabasoglu G., Lamarque J.-F., Bacmeister J., Bailey D. A., DuVivier A. K., Edwards J., Emmons L. K., Fasullo J., Garcia R., Gettelman A., Hannay C., Holland M. M., Large W. G., Lauritzen P. H., Lawrence D. M., Lenaerts J. T. M., Lindsay K., Lipscomb W. H., Mills M. J., Neale R., Oleson K. W., Otto-Bliesner B., Phillips A. S., Sacks W., Tilmes S., van Kampenhout L., Vertenstein M., Bertini A., Dennis J., Deser C., Fischer C., Fox-Kemper B., Kay J. E., Kinnison D., Kushner P. J., Larson V. E., Long M. C., Mickelson S., Moore J. K., Nienhouse E., Polvani L., Rasch P. J., Strand W. G., The Community Earth System Model version 2 (CESM2). J. Adv. Model. Earth Syst. 12, e2019MS001916 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hersbach H., Bell B., Berrisford P., Hirahara S., Hor&#xe1;nyi A., Mu&#xf1;oz-Sabater J., Nicolas J., Peubey C., Radu R., Schepers D., Simmons A., Soci C., Abdalla S., Abellan X., Balsamo G., Bechtold P., Biavati G., Bidlot J., Bonavita M., De Chiara G., Dahlgren P., Dee D., Diamantakis M., Dragani R., Flemming J., Forbes R., Fuentes M., Geer A., Haimberger L., Healy S., Hogan R. J., H&#xf3;lm E., Janiskov&#xe1; M., Keeley S., Laloyaux P., Lopez P., Lupu C., Radnoti G., de Rosnay P., Rozum I., Vamborg F., Villaume S., Th&#xe9;paut J.-N., The ERA5 global reanalysis. Q. J. Roy. Meteorol. Soc. 146, 1999&#x2013;2049 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Hall J., Van Wees D., Andela N., Hantson S., Giglio L., van der Werf G. R., Morton D. C., Randerson J. T., Multi-decadal trends and variability in burned area from the 5th version of the Global Fire Emissions Database (GFED5). Earth Syst. Sci. Data Discuss. 15, 5227&#x2013;5259 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matteo A., Garn&#xe9;s-Morales G., Moreno A., Ribeiro A. F. S., Azorin-Molina C., Bedia J., Di Giuseppe F., Dunn R. J. H., Herrera S., Provenzale A., Quilcaille Y., Torres-V&#xe1;zquez M. &#xc1;., Turco M., Challenges in assessing Fire Weather changes in a warming climate. npj Clim. Atmos. Sci. 8, 284 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wang, K. R. Anderson, R. M. Suddaby, &#x201c;Updated source code for calculating fire danger indices in the Canadian Forest Fire Weather Index System&#x201d; (Information Report NOR-X-424, Canadian Forest Service, Northern Forestry Centre, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. C. Hanes, B. M. Wotton, C. McFayden, N. Jurko, &#x201c;An approach for defining physically based Fire Weather Index System classes for Ontario&#x201d; (Information Report GLC-X-29, Natural Resources Canada, Canadian Forest Service, Great Lakes Forestry Centre, 2021).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>