<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41199407</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2057-3804</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardio-oncology (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiooncology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exercise and return-to-play for the adolescent and young adult cardio-oncology athlete: case study and review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>101</StartPage><MedlinePgn>101</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">101</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40959-025-00382-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Evidence-based and/or consensus guidance regarding exercise and return-to-play for the adolescent and young adult (AYA) athlete with cardio-oncology concerns is lacking. Many of the recommendations utilized for the diagnosis, surveillance, and management of cancer therapeutic-related cardiotoxicity in children have been extrapolated from adult literature and myocarditis guidelines, the latter of which are primarily concerned with potential for arrhythmias secondary to inflammation and myocardial scarring. In addition, the athlete's heart itself brings about several diagnostic challenges including physiologic changes due to endurance or isometric training. Exercise-induced cardiac remodeling, with enlarged cavity size, lower resting ejection fraction and increased left ventricular wall thickness, depending on the type of exercise, can mimic disease states including both underlying pathologies and the response to cancer therapeutics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE PRESENTATION" NlmCategory="METHODS">A high school cancer survivor had borderline ejection fraction and abnormal strain indices. He was able to return to competitive sports without complication after clinical evaluation and through a shared decision-making process.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The difficulty in differentiating physiologic from potentially pathologic echocardiographic changes can result in unnecessary disqualification, depriving athletes from social, psychological, and possibly financial benefits. Stress echocardiography indices, such as contractile reserve and mitral E/e' ratio, may inform assessment of systolic and diastolic function, respectively, and may be helpful in risk stratifying and understanding potential performance limitations in AYA athletes with cardio-oncology concerns for exercise and return-to-play. Most recent consensus statements regarding sports participation in the athlete with heart disease focus on a shared decision-making process amongst all stakeholders involved to formulate an informed, safe, and cohesive prescription to enable the athlete to safely re-engage in sports after recovering from a cardiac illness or surgery. Multidisciplinary recommendations emphasize the importance of exercise before, during, and after chemotherapy in an individualized approach to reduce risk factors in oncology patients and improve cardiovascular outcomes. Further research is needed to delineate protocols for the adolescent and young adult cardio-oncology athlete regarding exercise prescriptions and their return-to-play following oncology treatment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Freeman</LastName><ForeName>David J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Division of Pediatric Cardiology, The Johns Hopkins Children's Center The Blalock-Taussig-Thomas Pediatric and Congenital Heart Center, 1800 Orleans Street, Baltimore, MD, 21287, USA. dfreem28@jh.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wood</LastName><ForeName>Scott</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Division of Pediatric Cardiology, The Johns Hopkins Children's Center The Blalock-Taussig-Thomas Pediatric and Congenital Heart Center, 1800 Orleans Street, Baltimore, MD, 21287, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thompson</LastName><ForeName>W Reid</ForeName><Initials>WR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Division of Pediatric Cardiology, The Johns Hopkins Children's Center The Blalock-Taussig-Thomas Pediatric and Congenital Heart Center, 1800 Orleans Street, Baltimore, MD, 21287, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiooncology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101689938</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2057-3804</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardio-oncology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Return-to-play</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Young adult</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: All patient data has been de-identified. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41199407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12590705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40959-025-00382-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40959-025-00382-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Baggish AL, Levine BD et al. Clinical Considerations for Competitive Sports Participation for Athletes With Cardiovascular Abnormalities: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association and American College of Cardiology [published correction appears in Circulation. 2025;151(13):e864. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001326.]. Circulation. 2025;151(11):e716-e761. 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001297</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39973614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maron BJ, Zipes DP, et al. Eligibility and disqualification recommendations for competitive athletes with cardiovascular abnormalities: preamble, principles, and general considerations. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2005;45:1318&#x2013;21. 10.1016/j.jacc.2005.02.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2005.02.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15837280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell JH, Maron BJ, Epstein SE. 16th Bethesda conference: cardiovascular abnormalities in the athlete: recommendations regarding eligibility for competition: October 3&#x2013;5, 1984. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1985;6:1186&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2577752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maron B, Mitchell J. 26th Bethesda Conference: Recommendations for determining eligibility for competition in athletes with cardiovascular abnormalities. JACC. 1994;24(4):845&#x2013;847.10.1016/0735-1097(94)90836-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7798484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maron BJ, Doerer JJ, Haas TS, Tierney DM, Mueller FO. Sudden deaths in young competitive athletes: analysis of 1866 deaths in the united states, 1980&#x2013;2006. Circulation. 2009;119:1085&#x2013;92. 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.108.804617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.108.804617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19221222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelliccia A, Solberg EE, Papadakis M, et al. Recommendations for participation in competitive and leisure time sport in athletes with cardiomyopathies, myocarditis, and pericarditis: position statement of the sport cardiology section of the European association of preventive cardiology (EAPC). Eur Heart J. 2019;40(1):19&#x2013;33. 10.1093/eurheartj/ehy730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehy730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30561613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avila MS, Siqueira SRR, Ferreira SMA, Bocchi EA. Prevention and treatment of Chemotherapy-Induced cardiotoxicity. Methodist debakey cardiovasc J. 2019;15(4):267&#x2013;73. 10.14797/mdcj-15-4-267. PMID: 31988687; PMCID: PMC6977564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6977564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31988687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Committee, Gluckman TJ, Bhave NM, et al. 2022 ACC expert consensus decision pathway on cardiovascular sequelae of COVID-19 in adults: myocarditis and other myocardial involvement, Post-Acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection, and return to play: A report of the American college of cardiology solution set oversight committee. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;79(17):1717&#x2013;56. 10.1016/j.jacc.2022.02.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2022.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8926109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35307156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrhardt MJ, Leerink JM, Mulder RL, et al. Systematic review and updated recommendations for cardiomyopathy surveillance for survivors of childhood, adolescent, and young adult cancer from the international late effects of childhood cancer guideline harmonization group. Lancet Oncol. 2023;24(3):e108&#x2013;20. 10.1016/S1470-2045(23)00012-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(23)00012-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37052966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipshultz SE, Lipsitz SR, Sallan SE, Chronic progressive cardiac dysfunction years after doxorubicin therapy for childhood acute lymphoblastic leukemia. J Clin Oncol., Paradies G, Paradies V, Ruggiero FM, Petrosillo G et al. Role of Cardiolipin in Mitochondrial Function and Dynamics in Health and Disease: Molecular and Pharmacological Aspects. Cells. 2019;8(7):728. 10.3390/cells8070728. PMID: 31315173; PMCID: PMC6678812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6678812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31315173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal N, Amdani S, Lipshultz ER, Lipshultz SE. Chemotherapy-induced cardiotoxicity in children. Expert Opin Drug Metab Toxicol. 2017;13(8):817&#x2013;32. 10.1080/17425255.2017.1351547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17425255.2017.1351547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28679288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bombardini T, Picano E. Step C for Cardiac Reserve in Stress echocardiography. In: Picano E, editor. Stress echocardiography. Cham: Springer. 2023. 10.1007/978-3-031-31062-1_3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie S, Sun Y, Zhao X, Xiao Y, Zhou F, Lin L, Wang W, Lin B, Wang Z, Fang Z, Wang L, Zhang Y. An update of the molecular mechanisms underlying anthracycline induced cardiotoxicity. Front Pharmacol. 2024;15:1406247. PMID: 38989148; PMCID: PMC11234178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2024.1406247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11234178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38989148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giantris A, Abdurrahman L, Hinkle A, et al. Anthracycline-induced cardiotoxicity in children and young adults. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol. 1998;27(1):53&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1040-8428(97)10007-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9548017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipshultz SE, Alvarez JA, Scully RE. Anthracycline associated cardiotoxicity in survivors of childhood cancer. Heart. 2008;94(4):525&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/hrt.2007.136093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18347383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipshultz SE, Colan SD, Gelber RD, et al. Late cardiac effects of doxorubicin therapy for acute lymphoblastic leukemia in childhood. N Engl J Med. 1991;324:808&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM199103213241205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1997853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siaravas KC, Katsouras CS, Sioka C. Radiation treatment mechanisms of cardiotoxicity: A systematic review. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(7):6272. 10.3390/ijms24076272. PMID: 37047245; PMCID: PMC10094086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms24076272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10094086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37047245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ping Z, Peng Y, Lang H, Xinyong C, Zhiyi Z, Xiaocheng W, Hong Z, Liang S. Oxidative stress in Radiation-Induced cardiotoxicity. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2020;2020:3579143. 10.1155/2020/3579143. PMID: 32190171; PMCID: PMC7071808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/3579143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7071808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32190171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis EJ, McKillop A, Banks L. The Morganroth hypothesis revisited: endurance exercise elicits eccentric hypertrophy of the heart. J Physiol. 2012;590(12):2833&#x2013;4. 10.1113/jphysiol.2011.226217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2011.226217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3448147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22707591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maron BJ, Pelliccia A. The heart of trained athletes: cardiac remodeling and the risks of sports, including sudden death. Circulation. 2006;114(15):1633&#x2013;44. 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.106.613562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.106.613562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17030703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Gerche A, Wasfy MM, Brosnan MJ, et al. The athlete&#x2019;s Heart-Challenges and controversies: JACC focus seminar 4/4. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;80(14):1346&#x2013;62. 10.1016/j.jacc.2022.07.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2022.07.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36075838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baggish AL, Battle RW, Beaver TA, et al. Recommendations on the use of multimodality cardiovascular imaging in young adult competitive athletes: A report from the American society of echocardiography in collaboration with the society of cardiovascular computed tomography and the society for cardiovascular magnetic resonance. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2020;33(5):523&#x2013;49. 10.1016/j.echo.2020.02.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.echo.2020.02.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32362332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picano E, Bombardini T, Kova&#x10d;evi&#x107; Preradovi&#x107; T, Cortigiani L, Wierzbowska-Drabik K, Ciampi Q. Left ventricular contractile reserve in stress echocardiography: the bright side of the force. Kardiol Pol. 2019;77(2):164&#x2013;72. 10.5603/KP.a2019.0002. Epub 2019 Jan 15. PMID: 30644080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5603/KP.a2019.0002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30644080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pender A, Lewis-Owona J, Ekiyoyo A, Stoddard M. Echocardiography and heart failure: an echocardiographic decision aid for the diagnosis and management of cardiomyopathies. Curr Cardiol Rep. 2025;27(1):64. 10.1007/s11886-025-02194-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11886-025-02194-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11870920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40019673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine BD, Lane LD, Buckey JC, Friedman DB, Blomqvist CG. Left ventricular pressure-volume and Frank-Starling relations in endurance athletes. Implications for orthostatic tolerance and exercise performance. Circulation. 1991;84(3):1016&#x2013;23. 10.1161/01.cir.84.3.1016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.cir.84.3.1016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1884438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIntosh RA, Silberbauer J, Veasey RA, et al. Tissue doppler-derived contractile reserve is a simple and strong predictor of cardiopulmonary exercise performance across a range of cardiac diseases. Echocardiography. 2013;30(5):527&#x2013;33. 10.1111/echo.12084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/echo.12084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23316786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancellotti P, Pellikka PA, Budts W et al. The clinical use of stress echocardiography in non-ischaemic heart disease: recommendations from the European Association of Cardiovascular Imaging and the American Society of Echocardiography [published correction appears in Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging. 2017;18(8):832. 10.1093/ehjci/jex040]. <i>Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging</i>. 2016;17(11):1191&#x2013;1229. doi:10.1093/ehjci/jew190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27880640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waddingham PH, Bhattacharyya S, Zalen JV, Lloyd G. Contractile reserve as a predictor of prognosis in patients with non-ischaemic systolic heart failure and dilated cardiomyopathy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Echo Res Pract. 2018;5(1):1&#x2013;9. 10.1530/ERP-17-0054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/ERP-17-0054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5744622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29258998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christopoulos G, Barrett-O&#x2019;Keefe Z, Chandrasekaran K. The significance of contractile reserve in the echocardiographic assessment of athletic heart syndrome. J Cardiovasc Echogr 2020;30(1):33&#x2013;4. 10.4103/jcecho.jcecho_48_19. Epub 2020 Apr 13. PMID: 32766104; PMCID: PMC7307621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7307621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32766104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagueh SF, Smiseth OA, Appleton CP, et al. Recommendations for the evaluation of left ventricular diastolic function by echocardiography: an update from the American society of echocardiography and the European association of cardiovascular imaging. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2016;29(4):277&#x2013;314. 10.1016/j.echo.2016.01.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.echo.2016.01.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27037982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson S, Ring L, Oxborough D, et al. The assessment of left ventricular diastolic function: guidance and recommendations from the British society of echocardiography. Echo Res Pract. 2024;11(1):16. 10.1186/s44156-024-00051-2. Published 2024 Jun 3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s44156-024-00051-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11145885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38825710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scully RE, Lipshultz SE. Anthracycline cardiotoxicity in long-term survivors of childhood cancer. Cardiovasc Toxicol. 2007;7(2):122&#x2013;8. 10.1007/s12012-007-0006-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12012-007-0006-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17652816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipshultz SE, Cochran TR, Wilkinson JD. Screening for long-term cardiac status during cancer treatment. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging. 2012;5(5):555&#x2013;8. 10.1161/CIRCIMAGING.112.977751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCIMAGING.112.977751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22991285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilchrist SC, Barac A, Ades PA, et al. Cardio-Oncology rehabilitation to manage cardiovascular outcomes in cancer patients and survivors: A scientific statement from the American heart association. Circulation. 2019;139(21):e997&#x2013;1012. 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7603804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30955352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tranchita E, Murri A, Grazioli E, et al. The beneficial role of physical exercise on anthracyclines induced cardiotoxicity in breast cancer patients. Cancers (Basel). 2022;14(9):2288. 10.3390/cancers14092288. Published 2022 May 3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers14092288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9104319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35565417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>