<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41572396</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2234-0726</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Knee surgery &amp; related research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Knee Surg Relat Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Incidence and geographic mapping of meniscal tears in acute ACL injuries with meticulous posterior arthroscopic evaluation: longitudinal tears at the posterior menisco-capsular junction are the most common tear pattern in acute ACL injuries.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s43019-026-00301-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Meniscal injuries are commonly observed in acute anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injuries, with varying reports on the incidence and location of meniscal tears. In particular, the incidence of posterior menisco-capsular tears may have been underestimated in previous literature owing to the technical challenges associated with posterior arthroscopic evaluation. This study aimed to determine the true incidence and location of posterior menisco-capsular junction tears in patients undergoing anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction (ACLR) up to 6&#xa0;weeks of injury, hypothesizing a higher incidence than previously reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective analysis was conducted on patients who underwent primary ACLR between July 2015 and January 2023, including a total of 139 patients. Arthroscopic findings and surgical records were reviewed, and the posteromedial and posterolateral joint spaces were evaluated via intercondylar notch view with a 70-degree arthroscope or via a posteromedial/posterolateral portal as a viewing portal to confirm posterior menisco-capsular junctional tears in all patients. The Cooper's classification system was used to document tear locations, and radial and longitudinal tear components were analyzed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Meniscal tears were observed in 104 patients (74.8%). Medial meniscus tears occurred in 63 patients (45.3%), while lateral meniscus tears were found in 78 patients (56.1%). Bilateral meniscus tears were identified in 37 patients (26.6%). Radial tears were predominantly observed in the lateral meniscus (22.3%), with a significant portion being lateral meniscus root tears (15.1%). Longitudinal tears, particularly at the menisco-capsular junction, were the most common tear pattern, occurring in 64.7% of patients.The most commonly involved tear sites were Zone A0 (39.6%) and Zone A1 (42.4%) in the medial meniscus, and Zone F0 (36.7%) and Zone F1 (38.1%) in the lateral meniscus.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Longitudinal tears at the menisco-capsular junction are the most common tear pattern in acute ACL injuries, revealing a higher incidence than previously reported. In acute ACL injuries, Zones A0-A1 and F0-F1 should be meticulously evaluated using an intercondylar notch view with a 70-degree arthroscope or via a posteromedial/posterolateral portal as a viewing portal.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Dong Hwi</ForeName><Initials>DH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Chosun University Hospital, Chosun University School of Medicine, Gwangju, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Do Kyung</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6596-1222</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Samsung Changwon Hospital, Sungkyunkwan University School of Medicine, Changwon, Korea. dr-lee331@hanmail.net.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Knee Surg Relat Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101575761</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2234-0726</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute ACL injuries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anterior cruciate ligament</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal tears</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meniscal injuries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Menisco-capsular junction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was approved by the Institutional Review Board (IRB Number SCMC 2024&#x2013;06-011). Consent for publication: All authors have reviewed the manuscript and approved its submission for publication. Competing interests: There is no potential competing interests: none of the authors received or will receive direct or indirect benefits from third parties for the performance of this study. The authors received no financial support for the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41572396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12828943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43019-026-00301-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s43019-026-00301-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang LJ, Zeng N, Yan ZP, Li JT, Ni GX (2020) Post-traumatic osteoarthritis following ACL injury. Arthritis Res Ther 22:57</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13075-020-02156-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32209130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen W, Guenther D, Imhoff AB, Herbort M, Stein T, Schoepp C, Akoto R, Hoher J, Scheffler S, Stoehr A, Stoffels T, Haner M, Hees T, Mehl J, Ellermann A, Krause M, Mengis N, Eberle C, Muller PE, Best R, Lutz PM, Achtnich A (2023) Management after acute rupture of the anterior cruciate ligament (ACL). Part 1: ACL reconstruction has a protective effect on secondary meniscus and cartilage lesions. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 31:1665&#x2013;1674</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-022-06960-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10089999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35445329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonsson H, Riklund-Ahlstrom K, Lind J (2004) Positive pivot shift after ACL reconstruction predicts later osteoarthrosis: 63 patients followed 5-9 years after surgery. Acta Orthop Scand 75:594&#x2013;599</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00016470410001484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15513493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Y, Zhang K, Li J, Fu W (2021) Supplementary lateral extra-articular tenodesis for residual anterolateral rotatory instability in patients undergoing single-bundle anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Orthop J Sports Med 9:23259671211002280</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671211002282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8113943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33997075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaudreuil NJ, Rothrauff BB, de Sa D, Musahl V (2019) The pivot shift: current experimental methodology and clinical utility for anterior cruciate ligament rupture and associated injury. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med 12:41&#x2013;49</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12178-019-09529-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6388573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30706283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez AN, LaPrade RF, Geeslin AG (2022) Combined meniscus repair and anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Arthroscopy 38:670&#x2013;672</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2022.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35248223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato J, Fukushima H, Kensaku A, Hanaki S, Ota K, Kawanishi Y, Kobayashi M, Yoshida M, Takenaga T, Kawaguchi Y, Kuroyanagi G, Sakai H, Murakami H, Nozaki M (2025) Multiple secondary stabiliser injuries increase rotational instability in anterior cruciate ligament-deficient knees. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 10.1002/ksa.12565</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.12565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39756019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn JH, Bae TS, Kang KS, Kang SY, Lee SH (2011) Longitudinal tear of the medial meniscus posterior horn in the anterior cruciate ligament-deficient knee significantly influences anterior stability. Am J Sports Med 39:2187&#x2013;2193</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546511416597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21828365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DePhillipo NN, Moatshe G, Brady A, Chahla J, Aman ZS, Dornan GJ, Nakama GY, Engebretsen L, LaPrade RF (2018) Effect of meniscocapsular and meniscotibial lesions in ACL-deficient and ACL-reconstructed knees: a biomechanical study. Am J Sports Med 46:2422&#x2013;2431</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546518774315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29847148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mouton C, Magosch A, Pape D, Hoffmann A, Nuhrenborger C, Seil R (2020) Ramp lesions of the medial meniscus are associated with a higher grade of dynamic rotatory laxity in ACL-injured patients in comparison to patients with an isolated injury. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 28:1023&#x2013;1028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-019-05579-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31250053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephen JM, Halewood C, Kittl C, Bollen SR, Williams A, Amis AA (2016) Posteromedial meniscocapsular lesions increase tibiofemoral joint laxity with anterior cruciate ligament deficiency, and their repair reduces laxity. Am J Sports Med 44:400&#x2013;408</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546515617454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26657852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YS, Koo S, Kim JH, Tae J, Wang JH, Ahn JH, Jang KM, Jeon J, Lee DK (2023) Greater knee rotatory instability after posterior meniscocapsular injury versus anterolateral ligament injury: a proposed mechanism of high-grade pivot shift. Orthop J Sports Med 11:23259671231188710</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671231188712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10486219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37693803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacquet C, Pioger C, Seil R, Khakha R, Parratte S, Steltzlen C, Argenson JN, Pujol N, Ollivier M (2021) Incidence and risk factors for residual high-grade pivot shift after ACL reconstruction with or without a lateral extra-articular tenodesis. Orthop J Sports Med 9:23259671211003590</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671211003590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8113945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33997078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanaki S, Fukushima H, Abe K, Ota K, Kobayashi M, Kawanishi Y, Kato J, Yoshida M, Takenaga T, Murakami H, Nozaki M (2024) Greater rotational knee laxity observed at second-look arthroscopy in patients with failed meniscal repair performed at the time of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Arthroscopy. 10.1016/j.arthro.2024.12.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2024.12.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39725048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katakura M, Horie M, Watanabe T, Katagiri H, Otabe K, Ohara T, Nakamura K, Katagiri K, Ueki H, Zaffagnini S, Sekiya I, Muneta T, Koga H (2019) Effect of meniscus repair on pivot-shift during anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: objective evaluation using triaxial accelerometer. Knee 26:124&#x2013;131</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2018.11.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30554908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seil R, Mouton C, Coquay J, Hoffmann A, Nuhrenborger C, Pape D, Theisen D (2018) Ramp lesions associated with ACL injuries are more likely to be present in contact injuries and complete ACL tears. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 26:1080&#x2013;1085</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28638970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo B, Lee SH, Yun SJ, Song JG (2020) Diagnostic performance of magnetic resonance imaging for detecting meniscal ramp lesions in patients with anterior cruciate ligament tears: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Sports Med 48:2051&#x2013;2059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546519880528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31684739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnery-Cottet B, Conteduca J, Thaunat M, Gunepin FX, Seil R (2014) Hidden lesions of the posterior horn of the medial meniscus: a systematic arthroscopic exploration of the concealed portion of the knee. Am J Sports Med 42:921&#x2013;926</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546514522394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24567252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slauterbeck JR, Kousa P, Clifton BC, Naud S, Tourville TW, Johnson RJ, Beynnon BD (2009) Geographic mapping of meniscus and cartilage lesions associated with anterior cruciate ligament injuries. J Bone Joint Surg Am 91:2094&#x2013;2103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.H.00888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7002077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19723985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith JP, Barrett GR (2001) Medial and lateral meniscal tear patterns in anterior cruciate ligament-deficient knees. A prospective analysis of 575 tears. Am J Sports Med 29:415&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465010290040501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11476378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keyhani S, Esmailiejah AA, Mirhoseini MS, Hosseininejad SM, Ghanbari N (2020) The prevalence, zone, and type of the meniscus tear in patients with anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injury; does delayed ACL reconstruction affects the meniscal injury? Arch Bone Jt Surg 8:432&#x2013;438</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7358246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32766404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michalitsis S, Vlychou M, Malizos KN, Thriskos P, Hantes ME (2015) Meniscal and articular cartilage lesions in the anterior cruciate ligament-deficient knee: correlation between time from injury and knee scores. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 23:232&#x2013;239</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-013-2497-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23595538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagino T, Ochiai S, Senga S, Yamashita T, Wako M, Ando T, Haro H (2015) Meniscal tears associated with anterior cruciate ligament injury. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg 135:1701&#x2013;1706</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00402-015-2309-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26286641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gracia G, Cavaignac M, Marot V, Mouarbes D, Laumonerie P, Cavaignac E (2022) Epidemiology of combined injuries of the secondary stabilizers in ACL-deficient knees: medial meniscal ramp lesion, lateral meniscus root tear, and ALL tear: a prospective case series of 602 patients with ACL tears from the SANTI study group. Am J Sports Med 50:1843&#x2013;1849</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465221092767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35416066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Feng H, Zhang H, Hong L, Wang XS, Zhang J (2011) Arthroscopic prevalence of ramp lesion in 868 patients with anterior cruciate ligament injury. Am J Sports Med 39:832&#x2013;837</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546510388933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21220541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DePhillipo NN, Cinque ME, Chahla J, Geeslin AG, Engebretsen L, LaPrade RF (2017) Incidence and detection of meniscal ramp lesions on magnetic resonance imaging in patients with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med 45:2233&#x2013;2237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546517704426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28463534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Helou A, Gousopoulos L, Shatrov J, Hopper GP, Philippe C, Ayata M, Thaunat M, Fayard JM, Freychet B, Vieira TD, Sonnery-Cottet B (2023) Failure rates of repaired bucket-handle tears of the medial meniscus concomitant with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a cohort study of 253 patients from the SANTI study group with a mean follow-up of 94 months. Am J Sports Med 51:585&#x2013;595</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465221148497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36734511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SH, Lee SH, Kim KI, Yang JW (2018) Diagnostic accuracy of sequential arthroscopic approach for ramp lesions of the posterior horn of the medial meniscus in anterior cruciate ligament-deficient knee. Arthroscopy 34:1582&#x2013;1589</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2017.12.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29402583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green JS, Moran J, Marcel A, Joo PY, McLaughlin WM, Manzi JE, Yalcin S, Wang A, Porrino J, Jimenez AE, Medvecky MJ, Katz LD (2023) Posteromedial tibial plateau bone bruises are associated with medial meniscal ramp lesions in patients with concomitant anterior cruciate ligament ruptures: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Phys Sportsmed 51:531&#x2013;538</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00913847.2022.2108350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35915996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beel W, Mouton C, Tradati D, Nuhrenborger C, Seil R (2022) Ramp lesions are six times more likely to be observed in the presence of a posterior medial tibial bone bruise in ACL-injured patients. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 30:184&#x2013;191</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-021-06520-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33661324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saint-Etienne A, Benhenneda R, Vieira TD, Fayard JM, Thaunat M (2024) Clinical outcomes of different management techniques for medial meniscal type 3 ramp lesions in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a comparative analysis between all-inside repair, suture hook repair, and lesions left in situ. Am J Sports Med 52:1250&#x2013;1257</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465241232088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38523481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanel L, Thaunat M, Lambrey PJ, Portet A, Vincent A, Vieira TD, Jan N, Fayard JM (2024) Survivorship and outcomes of meniscal ramp lesions repaired through a posteromedial portal during anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: outcome study with a minimum 10-year follow-up. Am J Sports Med 52:3206&#x2013;3211</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465241288233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39439282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peltier A, Lording T, Maubisson L, Ballis R, Neyret P, Lustig S (2015) The role of the meniscotibial ligament in posteromedial rotational knee stability. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 23:2967&#x2013;2973</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-015-3751-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26264383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawanishi Y, Kobayashi M, Yasuma S, Fukushima H, Kato J, Murase A, Takenaga T, Yoshida M, Kuroyanagi G, Kawaguchi Y, Murakami H, Nozaki M (2024) Factors associated with residual pivot shift after ACL reconstruction: a quantitative evaluation of the pivot-shift test preoperatively and at minimum 12-month follow-up. Orthop J Sports Med 12:23259671241230970</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671241230967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10898316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38414663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guimaraes JB, Schwaiger BJ, Gersing AS, Neumann J, Facchetti L, Li X, Joseph GB, Link TM (2021) Meniscal ramp lesions: frequency, natural history, and the effect on knee cartilage over 2 years in subjects with anterior cruciate ligament tears. Skeletal Radiol 50:551&#x2013;558</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00256-020-03596-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7854891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32901305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roe J, Pinczewski LA, Russell VJ, Salmon LJ, Kawamata T, Chew M (2005) A 7-year follow-up of patellar tendon and hamstring tendon grafts for arthroscopic anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: differences and similarities. Am J Sports Med 33:1337&#x2013;1345</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546504274145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16002487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pringle L, Wissman RD (2022) Imaging of noncontact anterior cruciate ligament injuries and associated bone marrow contusion patterns. J Knee Surg 35:475&#x2013;481</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0041-1740393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34902869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Hacke JD, Garrett WE, Liu H, Yu B (2019) Bone bruises associated with anterior cruciate ligament injury as indicators of injury mechanism: a systematic review. Sports Med 49:453&#x2013;462</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01060-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30689129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiapour AM, Demetropoulos CK, Kiapour A, Quatman CE, Wordeman SC, Goel VK, Hewett TE (2016) Strain response of the Anterior Cruciate Ligament to uniplanar and multiplanar loads during simulated landings: implications for injury mechanism. Am J Sports Med 44:2087&#x2013;2096</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546516640499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27159285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoshino Y, Hiroshima Y, Miyaji N, Nagai K, Araki D, Kanzaki N, Kakutani K, Matsushita T, Kuroda R (2020) Unrepaired lateral meniscus tears lead to remaining pivot-shift in ACL-reconstructed knees. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 28:3504&#x2013;3510</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-020-06007-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32328696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone AV, Marx S, Conley CW (2021) Management of partial tears of the Anterior Cruciate Ligament: a review of the anatomy, diagnosis, and treatment. J Am Acad Orthop Surg 29:60&#x2013;70</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5435/JAAOS-D-20-00242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33394613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta R, Singhal A, Sharma AR, Shail S, Masih GD (2021) Strong association of meniscus tears with complete Anterior Cruciate Ligament (ACL) injuries relative to partial ACL injuries. J Clin Orthop Trauma 23:101671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcot.2021.101671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8577485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34790561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>