<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41888231</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Smart control of soil temperature to optimize root-zone conditions for enhancing the physiological performance, growth, and productivity of greenhouse-grown cucumber.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10351</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-40825-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Determining the optimal soil temperature in the active root zone to meet the requirements of different plant growth stages is crucial. Controlled greenhouse producers attempt to heat soil sectors in various ways without determining an appropriate or reliable soil temperature. A suitable smart method can be used to adjust the temperature in the active root zone to determine the optimal temperature and improve crop growth and yield. Cucumber plants grown in a plastic greenhouse were subjected to five different soil temperature treatments (13 as a control, 16, 19, 22, and 25&#xa0;&#xb0;C) over two growing seasons using carbon fiber smart thermal cable connected to a metal thermostat. The thermal cable was installed 10 cm below the soil surface, extended 20 m apart on three branches per replicate, and then buried and compacted well into the soil. The objective of this study was to determine the optimum soil temperature by smart thermal system, to enhance photosynthesis rate, growth parameters, and yield of cucumber, as well as improving the availability of nutrients within active root zone, and to minimize vapor pressure deficit. The experimental design was a completely randomized design with five treatments and three replicates. The smart soil heating system was a feasible economic option, with a benefit&#x2013;cost ratio of 1.75% versus 1.1% for the traditional system, resulting in improved cucumber yield and quality, while saving approximately 30% of energy. Plant photosynthesis was positively correlated with total yield but negatively correlated with vapor pressure deficit, suggesting that the initial or mid-season increases in cucumber yield were partly due to the increased soil temperature at 22&#xa0;&#xb0;C. In conclusion, plants grown at 19 or 22&#xa0;&#xb0;C had significantly similar yields of 3.37&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.09 and 3.71&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.14 kg plant<sup>&#x2212;1</sup>, respectively, and most of these plants had higher yields than plants grown at 16&#xa0;&#xb0;C, with a yield of 2.33&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.03 kg plant<sup>&#x2212;1</sup>. We suggest that a soil temperature of 22&#xa0;&#xb0;C is ideal for cucumber growers in the initial or mid-season, but at the end of the season the plant may not be affected, so a soil temperature of 19&#xa0;&#xb0;C can be used to save energy. Also, the possibility of presenting this intelligent system as an alternative the traditional one.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Refaie</LastName><ForeName>K M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4104-9922</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central Laboratory for Agricultural Climate, Agricultural Research Center, Dokki, Giza, Egypt. Khaled_refaie@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saad</LastName><ForeName>Shereen A H</ForeName><Initials>SAH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-6214-0815</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physics and Chemistry Department, Soils, Water and Environment Research Institute, Agricultural Research Center, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hussein</LastName><ForeName>Nermin S</ForeName><Initials>NS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Agricultural Engineering Research Institute, Agricultural Research Center, Dokki, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cucumis sativus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cucumber growth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Plant photosynthesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Smart management techniques</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Soil temperature</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vapor pressure deficit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Yield</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Consent for publication: The article contains no such material that may be unlawful, defamatory, or which would, if published, in any way whatsoever, violate the terms and conditions as laid down in the agreement. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41888231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13031512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-40825-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-40825-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Homez, T. J. &amp; Arouiee, H. Evaluation of soil temperature under mulches and garlic extract on yield of cucumber (<i>Cucumis sativus</i> L.) in greenhouse conditions. <i>J. Hortic.</i><b>3</b>(1), 175&#x2013;180. 10.4172/2376-0354.1000175 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2376-0354.1000175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liaoa, X. et al. Impact of soil moisture and temperature on potato production using seepage and center pivot irrigation. <i>Agric. Water Manag.</i><b>165</b>, 230&#x2013;236. 10.1016/j.agwat.2015.10.023 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agwat.2015.10.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruda, N., Sallakub, G. &amp; Balliub, A. Plant Production and Protection, FAO-230. https://www.academia.edu (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawson, T., Terashima, I., Fujita, T. &amp; Wang Y. Co-ordination between photosynthesis and stomatal behaviour. In <i>The Leaf: A Platform for Performing Photosynthesis and Feeding the Plant </i>(eds Adams, W. W. III &amp; Terashima, I.) 141&#x2013;161. 10.1007/978-3-319-93594-26 (Springer, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fei, Y. et al. Case study on the application of innovative cultivation techniquesin cucumber production. <i>Int. J. Hortic.</i><b>15</b>(1), 29&#x2013;40. 10.5376/ijh.2025.15.0004 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5376/ijh.2025.15.0004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konopacki, P. J., Waldemar, T. &amp; Krzysztof, K. Comparison of vapour pressure deficit patterns during cucumber cultivation in a traditional high PE tunnel greenhouse and a tunnel greenhouse equipped with a heat accumulator. <i>Span. J. Agric. Res.</i><b>16</b>(1), 1&#x2013;10 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5424/sjar/2018161-11484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgios, N. et al. Energy and water related parameters in tomato and cucumber greenhouse crops in semiarid Mediterranean regions. A review, part I: Increasing energy efficiency. <i>Horticulturae</i><b>7</b>, 521. 10.3390/horticulturae7120521 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/horticulturae7120521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashem, F. A., Medany, M. A., Abd El-Moniem, E. M. &amp; Abdallah, M. M. F. Influence of green-house cover on potential evapotranspiration and cucumber water requirements. <i>Ann. Agric. Sci.</i><b>56</b>, 49&#x2013;55. 10.1016/j.aoas.2011.05.001 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aoas.2011.05.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abuo El-kasem, S. A. A., Salama, Y. A. M. &amp; Suzan, M. F. Growth and production of cucumber plants as affected by colored shade nets and soil covering under Sharm El-Sheikh conditions. <i>SVU-Int. J. Agric. Sci.</i><b>5</b>(3), 41&#x2013;67. 10.21608/svuijas.2023.225051.1300 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/svuijas.2023.225051.1300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X., Gruda, N., Dong, J. &amp; Duan, Z. Greenhouse soil warmed by capillary network and its effect on the growth of cucumber. <i>Acta Hortic.</i><b>1296</b>, 149&#x2013;158. 10.17660/ActaHortic.2020.1296.20 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17660/ActaHortic.2020.1296.20</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes, C., Jose, E. C. &amp; Araujo, J. A. Reference evapotranspiration estimation inside greenhouses. <i>Sci. Agric.</i><b>60</b>(3), 591&#x2013;594. 10.1590/S0103-90162003000300027 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0103-90162003000300027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cucumber Production under Plastic houses, Extension Publish No 524-1999. Protected Cultivation Project. Agricultural Research Center, Ministry of Agriculture and Land Reclamation, Egypt.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A.O.A.C. <i>Official Methods of Analysis: Association of Official Analytical Chemists</i>. 16th ed 577&#x2013;581. https://law.resource.org (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prenger, J. J. &amp; Ling, P. P. Greenhouse Condensation Control. <i>Fact Sheet (Series) AEX-804</i>. https://www.growthindoors.com (Ohio State University Extension, 2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohm, W. <i>Methods of Studying Root Systems</i>https://www.scirp.org (Springer-Verlag, 1979).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills, R. B. H., Lee, T. H., Grahum, D., McGlasson, W. B. &amp; Hall, E. G. <i>Postharvest an Introduction to Physiology and Handling of Fruit and Vegetables</i>. 64. https://www.cabidigitallibrary.org (1982).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO. Soil and plant analysis. <i>Soils Bull.</i> 38, 2&#x2013;250 https://www.fao.org (FAO, 1980).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe, F. S. &amp; Olsen, S. R. Test of an ascorbic acid method for determining phosphorus in water and NaHCO3 extracts from soil. <i>Soil Sci. Soc. Amer. Proc.</i><b>29</b>, 677&#x2013;678. 10.2136/sssaj1965.03615995002900060025x (1965).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2136/sssaj1965.03615995002900060025x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman, H. D. &amp; Pratt, F. <i>Methods of Analysis for Soils, Plants and Water</i> (Univ. of Calif., 1961).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arafat, M. M., Al-Noubi, T., El-Beheiri, U. &amp; Riyad, M. An economic study of vegetable protected hydroponics on small farms (A case study on vegetable protected hydroponics in Giza Governorate). <i>Sci. J. Agric. Sci.</i><b>5</b>(4), 349&#x2013;362. 10.21608/sjas.2023.247645.1359 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/sjas.2023.247645.1359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Technical Bulletin, No. 1 Ventilation, Cooling and Heating in Plastic Greenhouses. UNDP-FAO, Protected Agriculture Project, Agricultural Research Center, Ministry of Agriculture and Land Reclamation. http://www.fao.org/publications (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levene, H. Robust tests for equality of variances. Essays in Honor of Harold Hotelling. In <i>Contributions to Probability and Statistics</i> (eds Olkin, I.) 292. https://www.scirp.org (Stanford University Press, 1960).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, D., Dong, J., Gruda, N. S., Li, X. &amp; Duan, Z. Elevated root-zone temperature promotes the growth and alleviates the photosynthetic acclimation of cucumber plants exposed to elevated [CO<sub>2</sub>]. <i>Environ. Exp. Bot.</i><b>194</b>, 104694. 10.1016/j.envexpbot.2021.104694 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envexpbot.2021.104694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redmond, R. S. et al. Review of optimum temperature, humidity, and vapor pressure deficit for microclimate evaluation and control in greenhouse cultivation of tomato: A review. <i>Int. Agrophys.</i><b>32</b>, 287&#x2013;302. 10.1515/intag-2017-0005 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/intag-2017-0005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tewari, A. K. &amp; Tripathy, B. C. Temperature-stress-induced impairment of chlorophyll biosynthetic reactions in cucumber and wheat. <i>Plant Physiol.</i><b>117</b>(3), 851&#x2013;858 (1998).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.117.3.851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC34939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9662527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havaux,. Short-term responses of photosystem to heat stress. <i>Photosynthesis Res.</i><b>47</b>, 85&#x2013;97. 10.1007/BF00017756 (1996).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00017756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24301710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. Elevated CO<sub>2</sub> mitigates the adverse effects of drought on daytime net ecosystem CO<sub>2</sub> exchange and photosynthesis in a Florida scrub-oak ecosystem. <i>Photosynthetica</i><b>45</b>, 51&#x2013;58 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11099-007-0008-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, R. et al. A photothermal model of leaf area index for greenhouse crops. <i>Agric. For. Meteorol.</i><b>150</b>, 541&#x2013;552. 10.1016/j.agrformet.2010.01.019 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agrformet.2010.01.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka, Y. &amp; Nosaka, A. Y. Generation and detection of reactive oxygen species in photocatalysis. <i>Chem. Rev.</i><b>117</b>, 11302&#x2013;11336. 10.1021/acs.chemrev.7b00161 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemrev.7b00161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28777548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savvides, A., Dimitrios, F. &amp; van, I. W. Co-ordination of hydraulic and stomatal conductances across light qualities in cucumber leaves. <i>J. Exp. Bot.</i><b>63</b>(3), 1135&#x2013;1143. 10.1093/jxb/err348 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jxb/err348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3276089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22121201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogewoning, S. W. et al. Blue light dose&#x2013;responses of leaf photosynthesis, morphology, and chemical composition of <i>Cucumis sativus</i> grown under different combinations of red and blue light. <i>J. Exp. Bot.</i><b>61</b>(11), 3107&#x2013;3117. 10.1093/jxb/erq132 (2010).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jxb/erq132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2892149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20504875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ISO 13788. Hygrothermal performance of building components and building elements - Internal surface temperature to avoid critical surface humidity and interstitial condensation - Calculation methods, https://www.iso.org (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbas, F. et al. Soil temperature and moisture as key determinants of SPAD values in greenhouse-grown cucumber in Qatar. <i>Phyton-Int. J. Exp. Bot.</i>10.32604/phyton.2025.064239 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32604/phyton.2025.064239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsadon, A. A. et al. Growth response of cucumber under greenhouses covered with plastic films. <i>J. Anim. Plant Sci.</i><b>26</b>(1), 139&#x2013;148 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cockshull, K. E., Graves, C. J. &amp; Cave, C. R. J. The influence of shading on yield of glasshouse tomatoes. <i>J. Hortic. Sci.</i><b>67</b>, 11&#x2013;24 (1992).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00221589.1992.11516215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, P., Tao, Z. Q., Chen, Y. Q., Zhang, X. P. &amp; Sui, P. Spring maize kernel number and assimilate supply responses to high temperature stress under field conditions. <i>Agron. J.</i><b>109</b>, 1433&#x2013;1442. 10.2134/agronj2016.11.0662 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2134/agronj2016.11.0662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Z., Han, J., Zhang, Y. &amp; Zhuang, H. Effects of temperature and time treatment on soil characteristics and wheat growth. <i>Front. Sustain. Food Syst.</i><b>9</b>, 1499224. 10.3389/fsufs.2025.1499224 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsufs.2025.1499224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatamian, M., Nejad, R. A., Kafi, M., Souri, M. K. &amp; Shahbazi, K. Nitrate improves hackberry seedling growth under cadmium application. <i>Heliyon</i><b>6</b>, e3247. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2020.e03247 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2020.e03247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6971396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31993522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud, R., Bani-Odeh, A., Bushnaq, B. &amp; Namoura, M. Impact of heating irrigation water on growth and development of cucumber plants cultivated in winter season. <i>Palestine Tech. Univ. Res. J.</i><b>10</b>(4), 11&#x2013;24. 10.55544/sjmars.1.1.11 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55544/sjmars.1.1.11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, F. et al. Effects of different root zone heating systems on microclimate and crop development in solar greenhouse. <i>Int. J. Agric. Biol. Eng.</i><b>15</b>(6), 67&#x2013;72. 10.25165/j.ijabe.20221506.7581 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25165/j.ijabe.20221506.7581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>