<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41805647</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1528-1132</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical orthopaedics and related research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Orthop Relat Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Is Functional Reconstruction Feasible With Modified Hip Transposition Using a Customized 3D-printed Femoral Prosthesis After Pelvic Tumor Resection? A Preliminary Study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CORR.0000000000003899</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Functional reconstruction after resection of malignant pelvic tumors involving zones I + II &#xb1; IV remains a major challenge in orthopaedic oncology. Conventional hip transposition can reduce prosthesis-related complications, but it is often associated with limb shortening and femoral head malrotation. We propose a modified hip transposition technique-femoral lengthening and retroversion hip transposition with a customized three-dimensionally (3D) printed femoral prosthesis-to address deficiencies in limb length, femoral head positioning, and fixation stability, and we evaluate its effectiveness in reducing complications and improving functional outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="QUESTIONS/PURPOSES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">In the context of a small, initial patient series, we asked: (1) What was the postoperative functional outcome, as assessed by Musculoskeletal Tumor Society 1993 (MSTS-93) score, after reconstruction using this technique? (2) What were the frequency and nature of complications associated with the method? (3) How well was limb length restored at a minimum follow-up of 3 years?</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Between January 2019 and December 2021, a total of 49 patients underwent resection and reconstruction for pelvic zone I + II &#xb1; IV tumors. Of these, 18% (9) received the modified hip transposition with a customized 3D-printed femoral lengthening and retroversion prosthesis. This approach was selected for patients in whom sufficient proximal femur was preserved to allow controlled osteotomy and femoral lengthening, who were unsuitable for standard hemipelvic endoprosthetic reconstruction because of extensive bone or soft tissue defects, who had histologically confirmed primary malignant or aggressive pelvic tumors, and who were expected to have long-term survival without distant metastasis. The remaining 82% (40) of patients treated during the same period underwent alternative reconstruction strategies, including hemipelvic endoprosthetic reconstruction, external hemipelvectomy, or conventional hip transposition. No patients were lost to follow-up. Three patients died of pulmonary metastases during follow-up and were included in the analysis with their actual follow-up durations. The six surviving patients had a median (range) follow-up time of 43 months (37 to 50). Among the nine patients included in this study, three were male and six were female, with a median (range) age of 55 years (19 to 73). At final follow-up, functional outcomes were assessed using the MSTS-93 score, complications were recorded and categorized, and limb-length discrepancy (LLD) was measured radiographically.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The six surviving patients achieved a median (range) MSTS-93 score of 24 (21 to 27) with minimal or no pain. Four patients used a cane for ambulation, and two walked independently. Two patients experienced delayed wound healing, which resolved with dressing changes; no prosthetic infections or mechanical failures occurred. Median (range) postoperative LLD was 1.0 cm (0.5 to 2.0) after intraoperative prosthesis adjustment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This modified hip transposition technique utilizing patient-specific osteotomy guides and a 3D-printed femoral lengthening and retroversion prosthesis allowed adjustment of limb length and femoral rotation in this small series, with minimal postoperative LLD and no major complications observed. Larger studies with longer follow-up times will be needed to confirm the feasibility and functional benefit of this method as a valuable complement to existing reconstructive options, particularly for patients with extensive soft tissue defects and high functional demands.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level IV, therapeutic study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by the Association of Bone and Joint Surgeons.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Hongsheng</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Shanghai General Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Jiakang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuo</LastName><ForeName>Dongqing</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Kaiyuan</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Orthop Relat Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0075674</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0009-921X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Two of the authors (HW, WS) designed the device used in this study and received no payment, royalties, or other financial compensation. All other authors certify that there are no funding or commercial associations (consultancies, stock ownership, equity interests, patent/licensing arrangements, etc.) that might pose a conflict of interest in connection with the submitted article related to the author or any immediate family members. All ICMJE Conflict of Interest Forms for authors and Clinical Orthopaedics and Related Research&#xae; editors and board members are on file with the publication and can be viewed on request.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41805647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CORR.0000000000003899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00003086-990000000-02380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abdel MP, von Roth P, Perry KI, Rose PS, Lewallen DG, Sim FH. Early results of acetabular reconstruction after wide periacetabular oncologic resection. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2017;99:e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown TS, Salib CG, Rose PS, Sim FH, Lewallen DG, Abdel MP. Reconstruction of the hip after resection of periacetabular oncological lesions: a systematic review. Bone Joint J. 2018;100 (Suppl) A:22-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bus MP, Szafranski A, Sellevold S, et al. LUMiC&#xae; endoprosthetic reconstruction after periacetabular tumor resection: short-term results. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2017;475:686-695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delloye C, Banse X, Brichard B, Docquier PL, Cornu O. Pelvic reconstruction with a structural pelvic allograft after resection of a malignant bone tumor. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2007;89:579-587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donati D, D&#x2019;Apote G, Boschi M, Cevolani L, Benedetti MG. Clinical and functional outcomes of the saddle prosthesis. J Orthop Traumatol. 2012;13:79-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enneking WF, Dunham WK. Resection and reconstruction for primary neoplasms involving the innominate bone. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1978;60:731-746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evenhuis RE, van de Sande MAJ, Fiocco M, et al. LUMiC endoprosthetic reconstruction of periacetabular tumor defects: a multicenter follow-up study. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2024;106:1309-1316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujiwara T, Medellin Rincon MR, Sambri A, et al. Limb-salvage reconstruction following resection of pelvic bone sarcomas involving the acetabulum. Bone Joint J. 2021;103:795-803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujiwara T, Ogura K, Christ A, et al. Periacetabular reconstruction following limb-salvage surgery for pelvic sarcomas. J Bone Oncol. 2021;31:100396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujiwara T, Ogura K, Kobayashi E, et al. Clinical outcomes of surgical treatments for primary malignant bone tumors arising in the acetabulum. Sarcoma. 2015;2015:430576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebert C, Gosheger G, Winkelmann W. Hip transposition as a universal surgical procedure for periacetabular tumors of the pelvis. J Surg Oncol. 2009;99:169-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebert C, Wessling M, Hoffmann C, et al. Hip transposition as a limb salvage procedure following the resection of periacetabular tumors. J Surg Oncol. 2011;103:269-275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W, Li D, Tang X, Yang Y, Ji T. Reconstruction with modular hemipelvic prostheses for periacetabular tumor. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2007;461:180-188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson ER, O&#x2019;Connor MI, Ruggieri P, et al. Classification of failure of limb salvage after reconstructive surgery for bone tumours: a modified system including biological and expandable reconstructions. Bone Joint J. 2014;96-b:1436-1440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillmann A, Hoffmann C, Gosheger G, R&#xf6;dl R, Winkelmann W, Ozaki T. Tumors of the pelvis: complications after reconstruction. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2003;123:340-344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann C, Gosheger G, Gebert C, J&#xfc;rgens H, Winkelmann W. Functional results and quality of life after treatment of pelvic sarcomas involving the acetabulum. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2006;88:575-582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X, Lu M, Zhang Y, et al. Pelvic-girdle reconstruction with three-dimensional-printed endoprostheses after limb-salvage surgery for pelvic sarcomas: current landscape. Br J Surg. 2023;110:1712-1722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X, Wen Y, Lu M, et al. Biomechanical and clinical outcomes of 3D-printed versus modular hemipelvic prostheses for limb-salvage reconstruction following periacetabular tumor resection: a mid-term retrospective cohort study. J Orthop Surg Res. 2024;19:258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X, Huang D, Lin N, Yan X, Qu H, Ye Z. 3D-printed prosthesis with an articular interface for anatomical acetabular reconstruction after Type I + II (+ III) internal hemipelvectomy: clinical outcomes and finite element analysis. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2025;107:184-195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal T, Shi L, Wang L, et al. Development of finite element model for customized prostheses design for patient with pelvic bone tumor. Proc Inst Mech Eng H. 2017;231:525-533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaiswal PK, Aston WJ, Grimer RJ, et al. Peri-acetabular resection and endoprosthetic reconstruction for tumours of the acetabulum. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2008;90:1222-1227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen JA, van de Sande MA, Dijkstra PD. Poor long-term clinical results of saddle prosthesis after resection of periacetabular tumors. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2013;471:324-331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karim SM, Colman MW, Lozano-Calder&#xf3;n SA, Raskin KA, Schwab JH, Hornicek FJ. What are the functional results and complications from allograft reconstruction after partial hemipelvectomy of the pubis? Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2015;473:1442-1448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunisada T, Fujiwara T, Hasei J, Nakata E, Senda M, Ozaki T. Temporary external fixation can stabilize hip transposition arthroplasty after resection of malignant periacetabular bone tumors. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2019;477:1892-1901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langlais F, Lambotte JC, Thomazeau H. Long-term results of hemipelvis reconstruction with allografts. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2001;388:178-186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei J, Ni M, Gao YS, Wang ZY. Femur performed better than tibia in autologous transplantation during hemipelvis reconstruction. World J Surg Oncol. 2014;12:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menendez LR, Ahlmann ER, Falkinstein Y, Allison DC. Periacetabular reconstruction with a new endoprosthesis. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2009;467:2831-2837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nischal N, Kurisunkal V, Jeys L, Davies M, Botchu R. Incidence of avascular necrosis of native femur following hip transposition surgery for periacetabular malignancies: a single-centre experience. Hip Int. 2024;34:622-627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozaki T, Hillmann A, Bettin D, Wuisman P, Winkelmann W. High complication rates with pelvic allografts. Experience of 22 sarcoma resections. Acta Orthop Scand. 1996;67:333-338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;dl R, Gosheger G, Leidinger B, Lindner N, Winkelmann W, Ozaki T. Correction of leg-length discrepancy after hip transposition. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2003;416:271-277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan L, Li Y, Hu X, et al. Clinical application of 3D-printed custom hemipelvic prostheses with re-entrant chiral structure in reconstruction after pelvic tumor resection. Orthop Surg. 2025;17:3067-3077.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang X, Guo W, Yang R, Yan T, Tang S, Li D. Acetabular reconstruction with femoral head autograft after intraarticular resection of periacetabular tumors is durable at short-term followup. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2017;475:3060-3070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vahabi A, Kaya H, Tosyal&#x131; HK, Ke&#xe7;eci B, Sabah D. Composite reconstruction with irradiated autograft plus total hip replacement after Type II pelvic resections for tumors is feasible but fraught with complications. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2024;482:1825-1835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucicevic RS, Zavras AG, Fice MP, et al. Does adding sacroiliac (Type IV) resection to periacetabular (Type II) resection increase complications or provide worse clinical outcomes? An institutional experience and systematic review. Surg Oncol. 2024;56:102116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Min L, Lu M, et al. What are the complications of three-dimensionally printed, custom-made, integrative hemipelvic endoprostheses in patients with primary malignancies involving the acetabulum, and what is the function of these patients? Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2020;478:2487-2501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson RJ, Freeman TH Jr, Halpern JL, Schwartz HS, Holt GE. Surgical outcomes after limb-sparing resection and reconstruction for pelvic sarcoma: a systematic review. JBJS Rev. 2018;6:e10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witte D, Bernd L, Bruns J, et al. Limb-salvage reconstruction with MUTARS hemipelvic endoprosthesis: a prospective multicenter study. Eur J Surg Oncol. 2009;35:1318-1325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H, Li Y, Zhang Q, Hao L, Yu F, Niu X. Does adding femoral lengthening at the time of rotation hip transposition after periacetabular tumor resection allow for restoration of limb length and function? Interim results of a modified hip transposition procedure. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2021;479:1521-1530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Iwata S, Saito M, et al. Hip transposition can provide early walking function after periacetabular tumor resection: a multicenter study. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2023;481:2406-2416.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>