<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41826388</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dynamics of household water use determinants in selected Local Government Areas in Oyo Zone of Oyo State Nigeria.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9613</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-33339-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Water remains a fundamental resource for sustaining life, health, and livelihoods, yet access and utilisation patterns differ markedly between rural and semi-urban communities. This study empirically compares household water use and its determinants in Afijio (rural) and Oyo East (semi-urban) Local Government Areas (LGAs) of Oyo State, Nigeria. Using a proportional stratified sampling technique, 275 respondents were surveyed in Afijio and 300 in Oyo East. The socio-demographic profile indicates near gender parity (Afijio: 51.1% female; Oyo East: 56.2% female) and a predominantly youthful population (18&#x2013;35 years: Afijio 33.8%; Oyo East 34.8%). Most households are small to medium-sized (1&#x2013;5 members: Afijio 54.2%; Oyo East 42.4%). Groundwater&#x2014;mainly hand-dug wells&#x2014;dominates household supply (Afijio 96%; Oyo East 93%), while access to piped water remains negligible (0.05% in both LGAs). Water use in Afijio centres on essential domestic needs such as drinking, cooking, and bathing, whereas Oyo East exhibits a more diversified pattern, including sanitation, small-scale farming, vehicle washing, and home-based enterprises. These differences reflect variations in infrastructure, economic activity, and water availability. Factor analysis identified four key determinants of water source preference: accessibility, reliability, quality, and household-specific factors. In Afijio, these components explained 63.1% of total variance, with accessibility (distance and ease of collection) as the strongest driver. In Oyo East, they accounted for 65.2% of variance, with reliability (consistency of supply) most influential. The findings underscore both infrastructural constraints and behavioural distinctions in water use. The study recommends context-specific interventions&#x2014;enhancing water infrastructure and accessibility in Afijio, and improving quality assurance and sustainable management in Oyo East.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oyelami</LastName><ForeName>Ayobami Alani</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Environmental Management and Crop Production Unit, College of Agriculture, Engineering and Science, Bowen University, Iwo, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ogunbode</LastName><ForeName>Timothy Oyebamiji</ForeName><Initials>TO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Environmental Management and Crop Production Unit, College of Agriculture, Engineering and Science, Bowen University, Iwo, Nigeria. timothy.ogunbode@bowen.edu.ng.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Owoeye</LastName><ForeName>Michael Olumide</ForeName><Initials>MO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sociology Programme, College of Social and Management Sciences, Bowen University, Iwo, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Factor analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Household water sources</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nigeria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oyo state</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rural-urban comparison</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Water usage patterns</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Informed consent: Informed consent was obtained from all individuals to take part in the survey. Ethical: All ethical considerations were duly observed, and the study protocols as approved by Bowen Research Ethics Committee. All methods were performed in accordance with the relevant guidelines and regulations.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41826388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13009268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-33339-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-33339-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Biggs, E. M. et al. Sustainable development and the water&#x2013;energy&#x2013;food nexus: A perspective on livelihoods. <i>Environ. Sci. Policy</i>. <b>54</b>, 389&#x2013;397. 10.1016/j.envsci.2015.08.002 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envsci.2015.08.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shehu, Nazim Costa, S., Meireles, I., Sousa, V. &amp;, &amp; Understanding residential water demand: insights from a survey in a mediterranean City. <i>Urban Water J.</i><b>21</b> (4), 521&#x2013;537. 10.1080/1573062X.2024.2312501 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1573062X.2024.2312501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunbode, T. O. et al. Assessing water security in Sub-Saharan Africa in the context of climate change threats: A case study. <i>Int. J. Clim. Change Strateg. Manag.</i><b>17</b> (1), 805&#x2013;826 (2025a).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora, N. K. &amp; Mishra, I. Sustainable development goal 6: global water security. <i>Environ. Sustain.</i><b>5</b>, 271&#x2013;275 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42398-022-00246-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edokpayi, J. N. et al. Challenges to sustainable safe drinking water: A case study of water quality and use across seasons in rural communities in Limpopo Province, South Africa. <i>Water</i><b>10</b> (2), 159. 10.3390/w10020159 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w10020159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6310213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30595910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daly, S. W., Lowe, J., Hornsby, G. M. &amp; Harris, A. R. Multiple water source use in low- and middle-income countries: A systematic review. <i>J. Water Health</i>. <b>19</b> (3), 370&#x2013;392. 10.2166/wh.2021.205 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wh.2021.205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34152293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeniran, A., Daniell, K. A. &amp; Pittock, J. Water Infrastructure Development in Nigeria: Trend, Size, and Purpose. <i>Water</i><b>13</b>, 2416. 10.3390/w13172416 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w13172416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunbode, T. O., Odusina, E. K., Oyebamiji, V. O., Owoeye, M. O. &amp; Afolabo, C. O. Estimating domestic water usage in A tropical environment: exploring Socio-Demographic perspectives. <i>Environ. Res. Commun.&#xa0;</i>10.1088/2515-7620/ad33eb&#xa0;(2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, S. A., Guerrero Fl&#xf3;rez, M. &amp; Karanis, P. The impact of water crises and climate changes on the transmission of protozoan parasites in Africa. <i>Pathogens Global Health</i>. <b>112</b> (6), 281&#x2013;293. 10.1080/20477724.2018.1523778 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/20477724.2018.1523778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6381522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30332341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeoti, O. S., Kandasamy, J. &amp; Vigneswaran, S. Water infrastructure sustainability in nigeria: A systematic review of challenges and sustainable solutions. <i>Water Policy</i>. <b>25</b> (11), 1094&#x2013;1111. 10.2166/wp.2023.173 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wp.2023.173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemu, Z. A. et al. Households&#x2019; access to basic sanitation services and associated factors in Geshiyaro project study sites in Ethiopia. <i>Discover Sustain.</i><b>5</b>, 200. 10.1007/s43621-024-00420-1 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43621-024-00420-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunbode, T. O. et al. Assessing water security in Sub-Saharan Africa in the context of climate change threats: A case study. <i>Int. J. Clim. Change Strateg. Manag.</i><b>17</b> (1), 805&#x2013;826 (2025b).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Bureau of Statistics. <i>Nigeria labour force survey: Q2 2023</i>. Socio-economic Assessment of Inhabitants of Residential Densities in Akure, Nigeria. (2016). <i>Civil Engineering and Architecture</i>, 4(4), 221&#x2013;229. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunbode, T. O. &amp; Ifabiyi, I. P. Application of Water Poverty Index (WPI) in Assessing Water Accessibility in the Rural Suburbs of Ogbomoso Zone of Oyo State, Nigeria.<i>Asian Journal of Environment &amp; Ecology.&#xa0;</i>3(2): 1&#x2013;9 https://www.researchgate.net/publication/318056765&#xa0;(2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunbode, T. O., Esan, V. I., Oyebamiji, V. O. &amp; Akande, J. O. Sustainable development goal 6 and the challenge of pipe-borne water connectivity in a growing tropical city: A case study. <i>Discover Sustain.</i><b>5</b>, 53. 10.1007/s43621-024-00239-w (2024a).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43621-024-00239-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunbode, T. O. &amp; Ifabiyi, I. P. Domestic water utilization and its determinants in the rural areas of Oyo State, Nigeria using multivariate analysis. <i>Asian Res. J. Arts Social Sci.</i><b>3</b> (3), 1&#x2013;13 (2017). 2017; Article no.ARJASS.34096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/ARJASS/2017/34096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos, E., Carvalho, M. &amp; Martins, S. Sustainable water management: Understanding the socioeconomic and cultural dimensions. <i>Sustainability</i><b>15</b> (17), 13074. 10.3390/su151713074 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su151713074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clement, J., Aaron, M., TcCright, T. &amp; Sandra, T. A behavioural measure of environmental decision making for social surveys. <i>Environ. sociol.</i><b>1</b>, 27&#x2013;37 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23251042.2015.1020466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopinath, S. &amp; Kumar, A. Environmental Decision-Making models: A scoping review. <i>Int. J. Indian Psychol.</i>, <b>12</b>(1) (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jesse, C., Ribot, N. &amp; Peluso, L. Postscript: A theory of access revisited. <i>Int. J. Soc. Nat. Resour.</i><b>33</b>(2) (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann, R., Kanitsar, G. &amp; Seifert, M. Behavioral barriers impede pro- environmental decision-making: experimental evidence from incentivized laboratory and vignette studies. <i>Ecol. Econ.</i><b>225</b>, 108347. 10.1016/j.ecolecon.2024.108347 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolecon.2024.108347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan, N., Newsham, A., Rigg, J. &amp; Suhardiman, D. A sustainable livelihoods framework for the 21st century. <i>World Dev.</i><b>155</b>, 105898. 10.1016/j.worlddev.2022.10589 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.worlddev.2022.10589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse, S. Having faith in the sustainable livelihood approach. <i>Rev. Sustain.</i><b>17</b> (2), 539. 10.3390/su17020539 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su17020539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kollman, M. &amp; Juli, S. G. <i>The Sustainable Livelihood Approach.</i> (Development Gtudy group, University of Zurich, 2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DFID. <i>Module 2: Agro Biodiversity Management from a Sustainable Livelihoods Perspective.</i>&#xa0;www.livelihoods.org/info/info-guidance sheets.htm (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odedare, K. O. <i>Location of Oyo Region. In Tanimowo N.B eds,Oyo Region SIBIS ventures</i>. Lagos 9&#x2013;13. (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solihu, H. &amp; Bilewu, S. O. Availability, coverage, and access to the potable water supply in Oyo state Nigeria. <i>Environ. Challenges</i>. <b>5</b>, 100335 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envc.2021.100335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weatherspark. <i>Climate and Average Weather Year Round in Oyo, Nigeria.</i> https://weatherspark.com (2025)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memon, M. A., Thurasamy, R., Ting, H. &amp; Cheah, J. H. Purposive sampling: A review and guidelines for quantitative research. <i>J. Appl. Struct. Equation Model.</i><b>9</b> (1), 1&#x2013;23. 10.47263/JASEM.9(1)01 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47263/JASEM.9(1)01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nigeria Demographic and Health Survey. Household population and housing characteristics. (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osinuga, A. et al. Understanding rural women&#x2019;s domestic work experiences (DWE) in Ibadan, nigeria: development of a measurement tool using confirmatory factor analysis. <i>Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health</i>. <b>18</b> (21), 11043. 10.3390/ijerph182111043 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph182111043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8582860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34769564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ologunagba, M. M., Ogunbode, T. O. &amp; Owoeye, O. M. Public perception of environmental sanitation regulations on solid waste management in Owo and Akure cities, Ondo State, Nigeria. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 37799. 10.1038/s41598-025-21714-y (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-21714-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12572144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41162519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Y., Klassert, C., Klauer, B. &amp; Gawel, E. Estimating household water demand and affordability under intermittent supply: an econometric analysis with a water&#x2013;Energy nexus perspective for Pimpri-Chinchwad, India. <i>Water</i><b>17</b> (19), 2917. 10.3390/w17192917 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w17192917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunbode, T. O., Oyelami, A. A., Oyebamiji, V. O., Faboro, O. O. &amp; Adekiya, A. O. Evaluating non-consumptive household water uses in a growing urban centre in Nigeria. <i>Environ. Res. Commun.</i><b>6</b> (7), 075022. 10.1088/2515-7620/ad5e3d (2024b).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2515-7620/ad5e3d</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunbode, T. O., Ogunlaran, O. M., Oyebamiji, V. O. &amp; Akande, J. A. Household water demand Estimation and its implication for water accessibility: A case study. <i>Environ. Resour. Res.</i><b>11</b> (1), 133&#x2013;142. 10.22069/IJERR.2023.21641.1410 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22069/IJERR.2023.21641.1410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordstr&#xf6;m, Y. Water availability challenges in Mozambique &#x2013; implications to the Nexus. KTH School of Industrial Engineering and Management, Division of Energy Systems Analysis, SE &#x2013; 100 44 Stockholm. 1&#x2013;48 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olanrewaju, Samson &amp; Abazu Chinedu and Babajide Racheal. Distribution and Access to Public Pipe-Borne Water in Urban Areas of West Africa: A Case of Ilorin-West Local Government Area, Nigeria. <i>Ghana J. Geogr</i>. 15 (2) 162&#x2013;183. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikelegbe, O. &amp; Okoruwa, O. A. <i>Meeting the Demand for Pipe Borne Water Supply in an Urban Environment: The Case of Benin City.</i>&#xa0;Research Gate.&#xa0;http://www.researchgate.net/publication/245869609 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danert, K. &amp; Healy, A. Monitoring Groundwater Use as a Domestic Water Source by Urban Households: Analysis of Data from Lagos State, Nigeria and Sub- Saharan Africa with Implications for Policy and Practice. <i>Water</i><b>13</b> (4), 568. 10.3390/w13040568 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w13040568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Santos, P., Mart&#xed;n-Loeches, M., D&#xed;az-Alcaide, S. &amp; Danert, K. Manual borehole drilling as a Cost-Effective solution for drinking water access in Low-Income contexts. <i>Water</i><b>12</b> (7), 1981. 10.3390/w12071981 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w12071981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ige, O. O., Ameh, H. O. &amp; Olaleye, I. M. Borehole inventory, groundwater potential and water quality studies in Ayede Ekiti, Southwestern Nigeria. <i>Discover Water</i>10.1007/s43832-020-00001-z (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43832-020-00001-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardo, M. A. &amp; Tekinerdogan, B. Urban water distribution networks: Challenges and solution directions. In <i>Management and engineering of critical infrastructure</i> (Elsevier, 2023). 10.1016/B978-0-323-99330-2.00005-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irene, J., Irene, B. N. &amp; Daniels, C. Not a drop to drink: addressing nigeria&#x2019;s deepening freshwater crisis. <i>Water</i><b>17</b> (12), 1731. 10.3390/w17121731 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w17121731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunbode, T. O. &amp; Ifabiyi, P. I. Temporal Water Balance Analysis in Different Climatic Scenarios in Oyo State, Nigeria. <i>Sustain. Agric. Food Environ. Res.</i><b>7</b>(2), 163&#x2013;177. 10.7770/safer-V0N0-art1476 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7770/safer-V0N0-art1476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masengu, R., Chawuruka, P. &amp; Muchenje, C. Environment attitudes and social influence of sustainable practices: A study on consumer behaviour in Zimbabwe. <i>Future Bus. J.</i><b>11</b>, 87. 10.1186/s43093-025-00499-6 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43093-025-00499-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shehu, B. &amp; Nazim, F. Clean water and sanitation for all: study on SDGs 6.1 and 6.2 targets with state policies and interventions in Nigeria. <i>Environ. Sci. Proc.</i><b>15</b> (1), 71. 10.3390/environsciproc2022015071 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/environsciproc2022015071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunbode, T. O. A nine-year critical review of progress and future strategies for sustainable development goal 6 in Nigeria from 2016 to 2024. <i>Discover Sustain.</i>10.1007/s43621-025-02009-8 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43621-025-02009-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikuemonisan, E. S. Challenges and strategies in Nigerian agribusiness entrepreneurship for sustainable development. <i>CABI Agric. Bioscience</i>. <b>5</b>, 115. 10.1186/s43170-024-00303-5 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43170-024-00303-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwankwo, F. O. &amp; Okeke, C. S. Rural entrepreneurship and rural development in Nigeria. <i>Africa&#x2019;s Public. Service Delivery Perform. Rev.</i><b>5</b> (1), a152. 10.4102/apsdpr.v5i1.152 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4102/apsdpr.v5i1.152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunbode, T. O., Oyebamiji, V. O. &amp; Afolabi, C. O. Achieving SDG 6 targets: evaluating driving forces for philanthropic contributions to water accessibility in southwestern Nigeria. <i>Appl. Water Sci.</i><b>15</b>, 112. 10.1007/s13201-025-02461-x (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13201-025-02461-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amoak, D., Bruser, G., Antabe, R., Sano, Y. &amp; Luignaah, I. Unequal access to improved water and sanitation in a post-conflict context of liberia: evidence from the demographic and health survey. <i>PLOS Water</i>. <b>2</b> (4), e0000050. 10.1371/journal.pwat.0000050 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pwat.0000050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akoteyon, I. S. Factors affecting household access to water supply in residential areas in parts of Lagos metropolis, Nigeria. Bulletin of geography. <i>Socio-economic Ser.</i><b>43</b> (43), 7&#x2013;24. 10.2478/bog-2019-0001 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/bog-2019-0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akpabio, E. M., Takara, K. &amp; Ekanem, A. M. Gender, water, and sanitation in nigeria: A socio-technical exploration. <i>Water Policy</i>. <b>19</b> (5), 990&#x2013;1005 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awoniyi, P. &amp; Eboiyehi, F. Women and rural water management: unequal power relations and gender stereotypes, Ondo State, Nigeria. <i>J. Gend. Power</i>. <b>17</b> (1), 9&#x2013;29 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall, R. P., Van Koppen, B. &amp; Van Houweling, E. The human right to water: the importance of domestic and productive water rights. <i>Sci Eng. Ethics</i>. <b>20</b> (4), 849&#x2013;868. 10.1007/s11948-013-9499-3 (2014).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11948-013-9499-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4237907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24337891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim, M. B., Salisu, I. &amp; Bello, A. M. An assessment of rural water supply in Northern Nigeria. <i>Int. J. Water Resour. Environ. Eng.</i><b>6</b> (4), 101&#x2013;109 (2014).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>