<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41054036</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>104</Volume><Issue>40</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence and determinants of induced abortion among women migrant workers in an industrial zone in Vietnam: A cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e45005</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e45005</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e45005</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000045005</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Migrant women workers in Vietnam face significant barriers in accessing subsidized sexual and reproductive health services, as these are frequently linked to their official residence status. This lack of access increases their vulnerability to unintended pregnancies and unsafe induced abortions due to limited availability of contraception. This study examined the prevalence of induced abortion and associated factors among sexually active women migrant workers working in the industrial zones (IZs) in Vietnam. A cross-sectional study was conducted from January 2019 to November 2020 among 512 sexually active female migrant workers aged 18 to 29 living in rent clusters and dormitories in Thang Long Industrial Park, Hanoi, Vietnam. The primary outcome was self-reported induced abortion. Multivariable logistic regression identified factors associated with induced abortion. Participants had a mean age of 24.8 years; 42.0% were single, and 85.4% lived in rent clusters. Among 512 sexually active female migrant workers, 10.5% reported having had an induced abortion. Compared to single women, married women had significantly higher odds of abortion (adjusted odds ratio [aOR]&#x2005;=&#x2005;8.13, 95% confidence interval [CI]: 2.44-27.05). Longer duration since first sexual intercourse (aOR&#x2005;=&#x2005;1.30, 95% CI: 1.12-1.52), and lower monthly income (aOR&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.994, 95% CI: 0.99-1.00) were also associated with abortion. In addition, belonging to a non-Kinh ethnic group was associated with lower odds of abortion (aOR&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.32, 95% CI: 0.16-0.62). This study reveals significant reproductive health challenges, including a high prevalence of abortion, among sexually active women migrant workers in a Vietnamese IZ, particularly for married women. These findings underscore the urgent need for targeted interventions such as accessible contraception, extending service hours into evenings or weekends, offering mobile sexual and reproductive health services near IZs, culturally sensitive comprehensive education, and programs addressing gender inequities to reduce unintended pregnancies and lower abortion rates. For routine practice, prioritize accessible contraception and culturally sensitive sexuality education in Vietnamese IZs. In addition, stronger monitoring and enforcement of regulations for private clinics are needed to ensure the safety and quality of abortion services. Future research should investigate contraceptive use, cohabitation dynamics, and unsafe abortion rates within this population to inform more effective interventions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ha</LastName><ForeName>Toan</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0574-0804</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases and Microbiology, School of Public Health, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pham</LastName><ForeName>Thien Quy</ForeName><Initials>TQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics and Health Data Science, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Nam</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Social and Medical Studies, Hanoi, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shrestha</LastName><ForeName>Roman</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Allied Health Sciences, University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schensul</LastName><ForeName>Stephen L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health Sciences, University of Connecticut School of Medicine, Farmington, CT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014744" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Vietnam</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000028" MajorTopicYN="Y">Abortion, Induced</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014171" MajorTopicYN="Y">Transients and Migrants</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006297" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Services Accessibility</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vietnam</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">induced abortion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">industrial zones</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">women migrant workers</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41054036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12499793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000045005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202510030-00001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bearak J, Popinchalk A, Ganatra B, et al. Unintended pregnancy and abortion by income, region, and the legal status of abortion: estimates from a comprehensive model for 1990-2019. Lancet Glob Health. 2020;8:e1152&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32710833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuyet HT, Thuy P, Trang HN. Second trimester abortion in Viet Nam: changing to recommended methods and improving service delivery. Reprod Health Matters. 2008;16(31, Supplement):145&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18772095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicole L. Vietnam grapples with an epidemic of sex-selective abortion.
2023. https://www.liveaction.org/news/vietnam-epidemic-sex-selective-abortion/. Accessed February 10 , 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Population Review. Abortion Rates by Country 2024.
2024. https://worldpopulationreview.com/country-rankings/abortion-rates-by-country. Accessed February 22, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NEWS TT. Vietnam&#x2019;s abortion rate among world&#x2019;s highest as contraception fails.
2017. https://tuoitrenews.vn/news/society/20170927/vietnams-abortion-rate-among-worlds-highest-as-contraception-fails/41775.html. Accessed March 3, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinh NT, Tuan PC. Factors influencing unintended pregnancy and abortion among unmarried youth in Vietnam: a literature review. Tap Chi Y Te Cong Cong. 2015;3:3&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5327353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28250849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fllek-Gibson D. Vietnam tackles high abortion rates.
2014. https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2014/8/28/vietnam-tackles-high-abortion-rates. Accessed March 10, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen PH, Nguyen SV, Nguyen MQ, et al. The association and a potential pathway between gender-based violence and induced abortion in Thai Nguyen province, Vietnam. Glob Health Action. 2012;5:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3511781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23195517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg PC. Contraception practices among young unmarried women seeking abortion following unintended pregnancy in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam. Cult Health Sex. 2021;23:1241&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32648816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stimson. Vietnam Country Profile: An overview of policy and trends on energy, transportation, water, and industrial infrastructure in Vietnam 2021.
2021. https://www.stimson.org/2021/vietnam-country-profile/. Accessed March 20, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The World Bank. The World Bank In Viet Nam: overview.
2023. https://www.worldbank.org/en/country/vietnam/overview#:~:text=Economic%20reforms%20since%20the%20launch,times%2C%20reaching%20almost%20US%243%2C700. Accessed March 12, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vietdata. Vietnam currently has 447 established industrial parks.
2024. https://www.vietdata.vn/post/vietnam-currently-has-447-established-industrial-parks#:~:text=In%202024%2C%20the%20Ministry%20of,about%204.16%20million%20direct%20workers. Accessed March 28, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trung TN, Lebailly P, Nguyen Thi D. Migrant workers for the development of industrial zones in Bac Ninh Province, Vietnam. Asian Soc Sci. 2018;14:115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham KTH, Nguyen LH, Vuong Q-H, et al. Health inequality between migrant and non-migrant workers in an industrial zone of Vietnam. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16:1502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6539052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31035337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bui HTT, Duong DM, Pham TQ, Mirzoev T, Bui ATM, La QN. COVID-19 stressors on migrant workers in Vietnam: cumulative risk consideration. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:8757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8391707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34444521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNFPA GSO. The 2015 National Internal Migration Survey: Major Findings. Hanoi, Vietnam: Vietnam News Agency Publishing House; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNFPA. Social-culture influences on the reproductive health of migrant women: a review of literature in Vietnam. 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BATIK International. The lives of women internal migrant workers in vietnam: facts and stories from Vinh Phuc and Hai Duong provinces Vietnam.
2020. https://batik-international.org/data/batik/media/Batik-Women-migrant-EN-Web.pdf. Accessed March 1, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen DT. Migration: Social Protection for Migrants in Vietnam-Lessons from the Pandemic.
2024. https://socialpolicyworldwide.org/post/social_protection_for_migrants_in_vietnam_33. Accessed February 26, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health. Workshop on Dissemination of the Project &#x201c;Counseling and Provision of Reproductive Health Care Services for Workers in Industrial and Export Processing Zones, 2024&#x2013;2030 Period.
2024. https://moh.gov.vn/tin-tong-hop/-/asset_publisher/k206Q9qkZOqn/content/hoi-thao-pho-bien-e-an-tu-van-va-cung-cap-dich-vu-cham-soc-suc-khoe-sinh-san-cho-cong-nhan-lao-ong-tai-cac-khu-cong-nghiep-khu-che-xuat-giai-oan-2024-. Accessed March 2, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman T, Miles L, Mat Yasin S, Ying K, Lai W-T. eds. Sexual and reproductive health (SRH) of women migrant workers in the ASEAN region: a systematic narrative review and synthesis. 19th ILERA World Congress: Making and Breaking Boundaries in Work and Employment Relations, 21-24 Jun 2021, Lund, Sweden; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le KA, Pham LT, Vu LH, Schelling E. Health services for reproductive tract infections among female migrant workers in industrial zones in Ha Noi, Viet Nam: an in-depth assessment. Reprod Health. 2012;9:4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3311076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22369718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loganathan T, Chan ZX, de Smalen AW, Pocock NS. Migrant women&#x2019;s access to sexual and reproductive health services in Malaysia: a qualitative study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:5376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7432037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32722563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo M, Jiang X, Wang Y, et al. Association between induced abortion and suicidal ideation among unmarried female migrant workers in three metropolitan cities in China: a cross-sectional study. BMC Public Health. 2018;18:625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5952593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29764402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zong Z, Sun X, Mao J, Shu X, Hearst N. Contraception and abortion among migrant women in Changzhou, China. Eur J Contracept Reprod Health Care. 2021;26:36&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33006490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syed N. Pregnant migrant workers in Asia face discrimination.
2018. https://www.hcamag.com/asia/news/general/female-migrant-workers-in-asia-face-discrimination/152001. Accessed April 6, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rushing R, Watts C, Rushing S. Living the reality of forced sex work: perspectives from young migrant women sex workers in northern Vietnam. J Midwifery Womens Health. 2005;50:e41&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15973256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo TD, Keogh S, Nguyen TH, Le HT, Pham KH, Nguyen YB. Risk factors for repeat abortion and implications for addressing unintended pregnancy in Vietnam. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2014;125:241&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24726618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tirado V, Chu J, Hanson C, Ekstr&#xf6;m AM, K&#xe5;gesten A. Barriers and facilitators for the sexual and reproductive health and rights of young people in refugee contexts globally: a scoping review. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0236316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7371179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32687519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thang Long Industrial Park Corporation. Thang Long Industrial Park.
2025. https://tlip1.com/en/home-eng/. Accessed March 1, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Japan Bank for International Cooperation. Investing in Vietnam 3.
2023. https://www.jbic.go.jp/en/information/today/today_202305/jtd_202305_sp3.html#:~:text=The%20Thang%20Long%20Industrial%20Park%20(TLIP%20I),companies%2C%20which%20combined%20employ%20some%2060%2C000%20people. Accessed February 27, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killip S, Mahfoud Z, Pearce K. What is an intracluster correlation coefficient? Crucial concepts for primary care researchers. Ann Fam Med. 2004;2:204&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1466680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15209195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha T, Schensul SL, Schensul JJ, Nguyen T, Nguyen N. Sexual risk behaviors, HIV prevalence and access to reproductive health services among young women migrant workers in the industrial zones in Vietnam. Front Reprod Health. 2021;3:775375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9580672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36303970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha T, Givens D, Nguyen T, Nguyen N. Stigmatizing attitudes toward people living with HIV among young women migrant workers in Vietnam. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:6366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9180544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35681951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng J, Zou G, Song X, Ling L. Contraceptive practices and induced abortions status among internal migrant women in Guangzhou, China: a cross-sectional study. BMC Public Health. 2015;15:552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4469005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26076710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba DM, Zhang Y, Pasha-Razzak O, et al. Factors associated with pregnancy termination in women of childbearing age in 36 low-and middle-income countries. PLOS Glob Public Health. 2023;3:e0001509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10021843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36963033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojo IE, Ojo TO, Orji EO. Why do married women procure abortion? Experiences from Ile-Ife, south western Nigeria. Afr Health Sci. 2021;21:327&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8356588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34394314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Napier-Raman S, Hossain SZ, Mpofu E, Lee MJ, Liamputtong P, Dune T. Abortion experiences and perspectives amongst migrants and refugees: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2024;21:312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10970391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38541311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller S, Wherry LR, Foster DG. The economic consequences of being denied an abortion. Am Econ J Econ Policy. 2023;15:394&#x2013;437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghavan S, Ngoc N, Shochet T, Winikoff B. Clinic-level introduction of medical abortion in Vietnam. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2012;119:39&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22877839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganatra B, Bygdeman M, Phan BT, Nguyen DV, Vu ML. From research to reality: the challenges of introducing medical abortion into service delivery in Vietnam. Reprod Health Matters. 2004;12(24 Suppl):105&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15938163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Mo. The national guideline on provision of reproductive health services-2001: updated in 2009, 2016 and 2024. Hanoi, Vietnam: Ministry of Health; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen MP, Wilson A. How could private healthcare better contribute to healthcare coverage in Vietnam? Int J Health Policy Manag. 2017;6:305&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5458791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28812822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vietnamnews. Govement to tighten private health facility oversight.
2017. https://vietnamnews.vn/opinion/375827/gov-t-to-tighten-private-health-facility-oversight.html. Accessed March 12, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo TD, Free C, Le HT, et al. Attributes and perspectives of public providers related to provision of medical abortion at public health facilities in Vietnam: a cross-sectional study in three provinces. Int J Womens Health. 2014;6:789&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4140708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25152635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PSI. Unsafe Abortion: Consequences, Facts &amp; Statistics.
2022. https://www.msichoices.org/latest/unsafe-abortion-consequences-facts-statistics/. Accessed February 10, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Population Review. Abortion Rates by Country.
2025. https://worldpopulationreview.com/country-rankings/abortion-rates-by-country. Accessed March 10, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>News TT. Vietnam&#x2019;s abortion rate among world&#x2019;s highest as contraception fails-The country is reporting Asia&#x2019;s highest rate of abortion.
2022. https://news.tuoitre.vn/vietnams-abortion-rate-among-worlds-highest-as-contraception-fails-10341775.htm. Accessed February 26, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen PT, Nguyen VHA, Truong TK, et al. Vietnamese religiosity, premarital sexual permissiveness, and abortion attitudes: the mediating role of filial piety. Discov Ment Health. 2025;5:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11782748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39883248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang L, Liu J, Ma Q, et al. Prevalence of induced abortion among Chinese women aged 18-49 years: findings from three cross-sectional studies. Front Public Health. 2022;10:926246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9575936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36262243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba DM, Ssentongo P, Agbese E, Kjerulff KH. Prevalence and predictors of contraceptive use among women of reproductive age in 17 sub-Saharan African countries: a large population-based study. Sex Reprod Healthc. 2019;21:26&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31395230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Q, Wang Y, Wang Z, et al. Understanding condom use among unmarried female migrants: a psychological and personality factors modified information-motivation-behavioral skills model. BMC Public Health. 2019;19:223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6385431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30791897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PATH. Developing a total market plan for family planning in Vietnam: An innovative public and private collaboration to enhance equity and sustainability. Hanoi, Vietnam: PATH; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen TTX, Nguyen TTQ, Le LH, Dinh DX. Knowledge, attitudes, and practices toward emergency contraceptive pills among community pharmacists and pharmacy customers: a cross-sectional study in urban Vietnam. Contraception. 2023;128:110275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37657599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park MH, Nguyen TH, Ngo TD. Dynamics of IUD use in Vietnam: implications for family planning services at primary health care level. Int J Womens Health. 2011;3:429&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3256944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22247629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen NTT, Nguyen LH, Nguyen TT, et al. Preference and willingness to pay for reproductive health services among adults in Urban-Rural transition settings of a developing country: evidence from a cross-sectional study in a rural district of Hanoi, Vietnam. BMC Health Serv Res. 2023;23:1196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10623698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37919709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen H. Overcoming Barriers to Ensure Access to Reproductive Health Care in Vietnam.
2023. Podcast. https://www.reprosfightback.com/episodes-blog/overcoming-barriers-to-ensure-access-to-reproductive-health-care-in-vietnam. Accessed April 8, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran TDH, Tuan DK, Anh ND, Le TKA, Bui TTH. Premarital sex, contraceptive use among unmarried women migrant workers in industrial parks in Vietnam, 2015. Health Care Women Int. 2018;39:377&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29252109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le ATK, Tran HTD, Duong TK, Nguyen CC, Bui HTT. Reproductive tract infection and related factors among female migrants working in industrial zones in Vietnam 2013-2014. Health Care Women Int. 2018;39:389&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29210613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha T, Givens D, Shi H, et al. Assessing barriers and utilization of sexual and reproductive health services among female migrant workers in Vietnam. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20:6368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10379987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37510599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNESCO. Viet Nam- Comprehensive Sexuality Education.
2023. https://education-profiles.org/eastern-and-south-eastern-asia/viet-nam/~comprehensive-sexuality-education. Accessed April 2, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallitto CC, Garc&#xed;a-Moreno C, Jansen HA, Heise L, Ellsberg M, Watts C; WHO Multi-Country Study on Women's Health and Domestic Violence. Intimate partner violence, abortion, and unintended pregnancy: results from the WHO Multi-country Study on Women&#x2019;s Health and Domestic Violence. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2013;120:3&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22959631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White J, Oosterhoff P, Huong NT. Deconstructing &#x201c;barriers&#x201d; to access: minority ethnic women and medicalised maternal health services in Vietnam. Glob Public Health. 2012;7:869&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22594915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKinn S, Linh DT, Foster K, McCaffery K. A qualitative analysis of factors that influence Vietnamese ethnic minority women to seek maternal health care. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2019;19:243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6626358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31299937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>