<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41317193</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1912</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Naunyn-Schmiedeberg's archives of pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Viniferin and its derivatives: a comprehensive review of structural variations and promising pharmacological applications in disease prevention and therapeutic development.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00210-025-04678-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Viniferin, a resveratrol-derived compound that belongs to a group of plant-produced stilbenoids, functions as a natural defense against microbial invasion, toxins, infections, and ultraviolet radiation. Alpha-(&#x3b1;-) viniferin (trimer), beta-(&#x3b2;-) viniferin (dimer), delta-(&#x3b4;-) viniferin (oxidative dehydrodimer), epsilon-(&#x3b5;-) viniferin (distinct dehydrodimer), gamma-(&#x3b3;-) viniferin (isomeric oligomer), vitisin A (R-viniferin), and vitisin B (R2-viniferin) are structurally diverse forms with distinct pharmacological activities. Antioxidant studies showed that &#x3b5;-viniferin exhibited a 2,2-diphenyl-1-picrylhydrazyl (DPPH) free radical scavenging half-maximal inhibitory concentration (IC&#x2085;&#x2080;) of about 80&#xa0;&#xb5;M. Also, suppression of nuclear factor kappa B, cyclooxygenase-2, and prostaglandin E&#x2082; are anti-inflammatory mechanisms. R2-viniferin demonstrated an IC&#x2085;&#x2080; of 9.7&#xa0;&#xb5;M against hepatocellular carcinoma HepG2 cells at 72&#xa0;h, mediated through apoptosis and cell-cycle arrest, according to anticancer studies that demonstrated dose-dependent cytotoxicity. There have been reports of additional activity against models of glioblastoma and prostate cancer. In metabolic disorders, oral &#x3b1;-viniferin (20-40&#xa0;mg/kg/day) improved lipid and glucose homeostasis in mice fed a high-fat diet, and it additionally improved liver and renal biomarkers such as blood urea nitrogen, creatinine, alanine aminotransferase, and aspartate aminotransaminase. Several bacterial strains have shown signs of preliminary antimicrobial action. By reducing excitotoxicity and oxidative stress, viniferins also have neuroprotective effects. They also have anti-melanogenic properties by blocking the tyrosinase and melanogenesis pathways. Collectively, viniferins demonstrate pleiotropic pharmacologic activities by defined molecular mechanisms and quantifiable dose-dependent effects. The properties classify viniferins as new multifunctional drug candidates for discovery and nutraceuticals, but they highlight the need for standardized pharmacologic assays, further preclinical validation, and pharmacokinetic optimization towards clinical use.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Dessouki</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmacology and Toxicology Department, Faculty of Pharmacy6 of October City, Ahram Canadian University, Giza, 12566, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Attallah</LastName><ForeName>Kareem A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5886-1466</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Development Department, Biotechnology Research Center, 23 July St., Industrial Zone, New Damietta, 34517, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Department, Damietta Directorate for Health Affairs, Egyptian Ministry of Health and Population, Damietta, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eid</LastName><ForeName>Aya H</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmacology and Toxicology Department, Faculty of Pharmacy, Heliopolis University, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaki</LastName><ForeName>Eman S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmacology and Toxicology Department, Faculty of Pharmacy, Heliopolis University, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khalaf</LastName><ForeName>Samar S</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4986-8567</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biochemistry Department Faculty of Pharmacy, Heliopolis University, Cairo, Egypt. Samar.samir@hu.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Shiekh</LastName><ForeName>Riham A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacognosy, Faculty of Pharmacy, Cairo University, Cairo, 11562, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamel</LastName><ForeName>Nada M</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, Faculty of Pharmacy, Cairo University, Kasr El-Aini Street, Cairo, 11562, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>ElBishbishy</LastName><ForeName>Rana M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, Faculty of Pharmacy, Cairo University, Kasr El-Aini Street, Cairo, 11562, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elosaily</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed H</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacognosy, Faculty of Pharmacy, Ahram Canadian University, Giza, 12573, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0326264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0028-1298</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chemistry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drug discovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional foods</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health benefits</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pharmacology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Viniferin</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41317193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00210-025-04678-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00210-025-04678-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahmat N, Wibowo A, Mohamad SA, Low AL, Sufian AS, Yusof MI, Latip J&#xa0;(2014) new symmetrical tetramer oligostilbenoid containing tetrahydrofuran ring from the stem bark of Dryobalanops lanceolata. J Asian Nat Prod Res 16(11):1099&#x2013;1107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25034352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10286020.2014.938059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aja I, Ruiz-Larrea MB, Courtois A, Krisa S, Richard T, Ruiz-Sanz JI&#xa0;(2020) Screening of natural stilbene oligomers from Vitis vinifera for anticancer activity on human hepatocellular carcinoma cells. Antioxidants 9(6):469</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32492881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7346113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox9060469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akinwumi BC, Bordun K-A, Anderson HD (2018) Biological activities of stilbenoids. Int J Mol Sci 19(3):792</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29522491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5877653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms19030792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Khayri JM, Mascarenhas R, Harish HM, Gowda Y, Lakshmaiah VV, Nagella P, Al-Mssallem MQ, Alessa FM, Almaghasla MI, Rezk AA(2023) Stilbenes, a versatile class of natural metabolites for inflammation&#x2014;an overview. Molecules 28(9):3786</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37175197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10180133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules28093786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhajje K, Golushko N, Erofeeva N, Romanovskaya E, Tupe R, &amp; Frolov A (2024) Anti-Diabetic effects of plant-derived natural products &#x2013; where we are and where to go. preprints. https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202412.1069.v1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aminah NS, Achmad SA, Aimi N, Ghisalberti EL, Hakim EH, Kitajima M, Syah YM, Takayama H (2002) Diptoindonesin A, a new C-glucoside of &#x3b5;-viniferin from Shorea seminis (Dipterocarpaceae). Fitoterapia 73(6):501&#x2013;507</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12385874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0367-326X(02)00179-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anna Malinowska M, Billet K, Drouet S, Munsch T, Unlubayir M, Tungmunnithum D, Giglioli-Guivarc'h N, Hano C, Lanoue A (2020) Grape cane extracts as multifunctional rejuvenating cosmetic ingredient: evaluation of sirtuin activity, tyrosinase inhibition and bioavailability potential. Molecules 25(9): 2203</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora J, Roat C, Goyal S, Ramawat KG&#xa0;(2009) High stilbenes accumulation in root cultures of Cayratia trifolia (L.) Domin grown in shake flasks. Acta Physiol Plant 31:1307&#x2013;1312</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11738-009-0359-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arruri VK, Gundu C, Khan I, Khatri DK, Singh SB (2021) PARP overactivation in neurological disorders. Mol Biol Rep 48(3):2833&#x2013;2841</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33768369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11033-021-06285-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nik Azmina NF, Norizan A, Syah YM, Khairunissa N, Zawawi NA, Yusof MI&#xa0;(2014) A new stilbenoid compound from the lianas of Gnetum microcarpum. Nat Prod Commun 9(12):1743&#x2013;1744.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakrim S, Mssillou I, Balahbib A, Aanniz T, El Kadri K, Muzammil K, Alqahtani TA, Yadav KK, Belayachi L, El Fessikh M, Goh KW&#xa0;(2025) Vitisin a and b: natural sources, chemistry, metabolism, pharmacological properties, and health benefits&#x2013;a comprehensive review. J Funct Foods 127:106774</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jff.2025.106774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bala AE, Kollmann A, Ducrot PH, Majira A, Kerhoas L, Leroux P, Delorme R, Einhorn J&#xa0;(2000) Cis &#x3b5;-viniferin: a new antifungal resveratrol dehydrodimer from Cyphostemma crotalarioides roots. J Phytopathol 148(1):29&#x2013;32</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee C, Barman R, Darshani P, Pillai M, Ahuja S, Mondal R, Pragadheesh VS, Chakraborty J, Kumar D (2024) &#x391;-viniferin, a dietary phytochemical, inhibits Monoamine oxidase and alleviates Parkinson&#x2019;s disease associated behavioral deficits in a mice model. Neurochem Int 174:105698</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38364939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuint.2024.105698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barjot C, Tournaire M, Castagnino C, Vigor C, Vercauteren J, Rossi JF(2007) Evaluation of antitumor effects of two vine stalk oligomers of resveratrol on a panel of lymphoid and myeloid cell lines: comparison with resveratrol. Life Sci 81(23&#x2013;24):1565&#x2013;1574</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18001803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lfs.2007.08.047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaumont P, Courtois A, Atgi&#xe9; C, Richard T, Krisa S&#xa0;(2022) In the shadow of resveratrol: biological activities of epsilon-viniferin. J Physiol Biochem 78(2):465&#x2013;484</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35312966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13105-022-00880-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaumont P, Faure C, Courtois A, Jourdes M, Marchal A, Teissedre PL, Richard T, Atgi&#xe9; C, Krisa S&#xa0;(2021) Trans-&#x3b5;-viniferin encapsulation in multi-lamellar liposomes: consequences on pharmacokinetic parameters, biodistribution and glucuronide formation in rats. Nutrients 13(12):4212</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34959765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8708455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13124212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begh MZA, Khan J, Zehravi M, Sweilam SH, Raja AD, Muthukumar A, Haque MA, Kar NR, Singh LP, Priya BD, Alshehri MA, Ahmad I, Kang S, Moon S, Park MN, Emran TB, Kim B&#xa0;(2024) Targeting neurological disorders with stilbenes: bridging the preclinical-clinical gap. Int J Biol Sci 20(14):5474</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/ijbs.102032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behl T, Upadhyay T, Singh S, Chigurupati S, Alsubayiel AM, Mani V, Vargas-De-La-Cruz C, Uivarosan D, Bustea C, Sava C, Stoicescu M, Radu AF, Bungau SG&#xa0;(2021) Polyphenols targeting MAPK mediated oxidative stress and inflammation in rheumatoid arthritis. Molecules 26(21):6570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34770980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8588006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules26216570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhoyrul S, Lashock J&#xa0;(2008) The physical and fiscal impact of the obesity epidemic: the impact of comorbid conditions on patients and payers. J Manag Care Med 11:10&#x2013;17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgos C, Mu&#xf1;oz-Mingarro D, Navarro I, Mart&#xed;n-Cordero C, Acero N (2020) Neuroprotective potential of verbascoside isolated from Acanthus mollis L. leaves through its enzymatic inhibition and free radical scavenging ability. 9(12):1207</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caillaud M, Guillard J, Richard D, Milin S, Chassaing D, Paccalin M, Page G, Rioux Bilan A&#xa0;(2019) Trans &#x3b5; viniferin decreases amyloid deposits and inflammation in a mouse transgenic Alzheimer model. PLoS One 14(2):e0212663</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30785960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6382128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0212663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho LC, Vidigal P, Am&#xe2;ncio S (2015) Oxidative stress homeostasis in grapevine (Vitis vinifera L.). Front Environ Sci 3:20</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenvs.2015.00020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CI, Chien WC, Huang KX, Hsu JL&#xa0;(2017) Anti-inflammatory effects of vitisinol A and four other oligostilbenes from Ampelopsis brevipedunculata var. Hancei 22(7):1195</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LG, Wang CC, Lee YS, Sie YY, Chang CI, Hou WC. Vitisin A(2022) Vitisin A, a resveratrol tetramer, improves scopolamine-induced impaired learning and memory functions in amnesiac ICR mice. Biomedicines 10(2):273</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35203483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8869728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines10020273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng CY, Lin YK, Yang SC, Alalaiwe A, Lin CJ, Fang JY, Lin CF&#xa0;(2020) Percutaneous absorption of resveratrol and its oligomers to relieve psoriasiform lesions: in silico, in vitro and in vivo evaluations. Int J Pharm 585:119507</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32512223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2020.119507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y, Takeuchi H, Sonobe Y, Jin S, Wang Y, Horiuchi H, Parajuli B, Kawanokuchi J, Mizuno T, Suzumura A (2014) Sirtuin 1 attenuates oxidative stress via upregulation of superoxide dismutase 2 and catalase in astrocytes. J Neuroimmunol 269(1&#x2013;2):38&#x2013;43</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24565075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2014.02.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiou WC, Huang C, Lin ZJ, Hong LS, Lai YH, Chen JC, Huang HC&#xa0;(2022) &#x391;-viniferin and &#x3b5;-viniferin inhibited TGF-&#x3b2;1-induced epithelial-mesenchymal transition, migration and invasion in lung cancer cells through downregulation of vimentin expression. Nutrients 14(11):2294</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35684095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9182810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14112294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury SA, Kishino K, Satoh R, Hashimoto K, Kikuchi H, Nishikawa H, Shirataki Y, Sakagami H&#xa0;(2005) Tumor-specificity and apoptosis-inducing activity of stilbenes and flavonoids. Anticancer Res 25(3B):2055&#x2013;2063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16158945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung EY, Kim BH, Lee MK, Yun YP, Lee SH, Min KR, Kim Y&#xa0;(2003) Anti-inflammatory effect of the oligomeric stilbene alpha-Viniferin and its mode of the action through inhibition of cyclooxygenase-2 and inducible nitric oxide synthase. Planta Med 69(8):710&#x2013;714</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14531020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2003-42787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung EY, Roh E, Kwak JA, Lee HS, Lee SH, Lee CK, Han SB, Kim Y (2010) &amp;alpha;-Viniferin suppresses the signal transducer and activation of transcription-1 (STAT-1)&amp;ndash;inducible inflammatory genes in interferon-&amp;gamma;&amp; ndash;stimulated macrophages. J Pharmacol Sci 112(4):405&#x2013;414</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cicho&#x17c;-Lach H, Michalak A (2014) Oxidative stress as a crucial factor in liver diseases. World J Gastroenterol: WJG 20(25):8082&#x2013;8091</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25009380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4081679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v20.i25.8082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contreras MDM, Feriani A, G&#xf3;mez-Cruz I, Hfaiedh N, Harrath AH, Romero I, Castro E, Tlili N(2023) Grapevine shoot extract rich in trans-resveratrol and trans-&#x3b5;-viniferin: evaluation of their potential use for cardiac health. Foods 12(23):4351</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38231829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10705905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/foods12234351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courtois A, Atgi&#xe9; C, Marchal A, Hornedo-Ortega R, Lap&#xe8;ze C, Faure C, Richard T, Krisa S (2018) Tissular distribution and metabolism of trans-&#x3b5;-viniferin after intraperitoneal injection in rat. Nutrients.&#xa0;10(11):1660</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10111660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30400351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6266173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courtois A , Garcia M , Krisa S , Atgi&#xe9; C , Sauvant P , Richard T , Faure C(2019) Encapsulation of &#x3b5;-viniferin in onion-type multi-lamellar liposomes increases its solubility and its photo-stability and decreases its cytotoxicity on Caco-2 intestinal cells. Food Funct 10(5):2573&#x2013;2582</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30997467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C9FO00420C</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courtois A, Jourdes M, Dupin A, Lap&#xe8;ze C, Renouf E, Biais B, Teissedre PL, M&#xe9;rillon JM, Richard T, Krisa S&#xa0;(2017) In vitro glucuronidation and sulfation of&#x202f;?-viniferin, a resveratrol dimer, in humans and rats. Molecules 22(5):733</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28467376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6154661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules22050733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dilshara MG, Lee KT, Kim HJ, Lee HJ, Choi YH, Lee CM, Kim LK, Kim GY&#xa0;(2014) Anti-inflammatory mechanism of &#x3b1;-viniferin regulates lipopolysaccharide-induced release of proinflammatory mediators in BV2 microglial cells. Cell Immunol 290(1):21&#x2013;29</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24859013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cellimm.2014.04.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dro&#x17c;d&#x17c; D, Dro&#x17c;d&#x17c; M, W&#xf3;jcik M (2023) Endothelial dysfunction as a factor leading to arterial hypertension. Pediatr Nephrol 38(9):2973&#x2013;2985</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36409370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00467-022-05802-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duta-Bratu CG, Nitulescu GM, Mihai DP, Olaru OT&#xa0;(2023) Resveratrol and other natural oligomeric stilbenoid compounds and their therapeutic applications. Plants 12(16):2935</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37631147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10459741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants12162935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dvorakova M, Landa P&#xa0;(2017) Anti-inflammatory activity of natural stilbenoids: a review. Pharmacol Res 124:126&#x2013;145</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28803136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2017.08.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Khawand T, Courtois A, Valls J, Richard T, Krisa S&#xa0;(2018) A review of dietary stilbenes: sources and bioavailability. Phytochem Rev 17(5):1007&#x2013;1029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11101-018-9578-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Empl MT, Albers M, Wang S, Steinberg P&#xa0;(2015) The resveratrol tetramer r-viniferin induces a cell cycle arrest followed by apoptosis in the prostate cancer cell line LNCaP. Phytother Res 29(10):1640&#x2013;1645</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26331691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.5443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esatbeyoglu T, Ewald P, Yasui Y, Yokokawa H, Wagner AE, Matsugo S, Winterhalter P, Rimbach G (2016) Chemical characterization, free radical scavenging, and cellular antioxidant and anti&#x2010;inflammatory properties of a stilbenoid&#x2010;rich root extract of Vitis vinifera. Oxid Med Cell Longev 2016(1):8591286</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26788254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/8591286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esatbeyoglu T, Ewald P, Yasui Y, Yokokawa H, Wagner AE, Matsugo S, Winterhalter P, Rimbach G(2020) Pharmacokinetic and bioavailability studies of &#x3b1;-viniferin after intravenous and oral administration to rats. J Pharm Biomed Anal 188:113376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32502955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpba.2020.113376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feriani A, del Mar Contreras M, Talhaoui N, G&#xf3;mez-Caravaca AM, Taamalli A, Segura-Carretero A, Ghazouani L, El Feki A, Allagui MS(2017) Protective effect of Globularia alypum leaves against deltamethrin-induced nephrotoxicity in rats and determination of its bioactive compounds using high-performance liquid chromatography coupled with electrospray ionization tandem quadrupole&#x2013;time-of-flight mass spectrometry. J Funct Foods 32:139&#x2013;148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jff.2017.02.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes JC et al (2021) Combination of trans-resveratrol and &#x3b5;-viniferin induces a hepatoprotective effect in rats with severe acute liver failure via reduction of oxidative stress and MMP-9 expression. Nutrients 13(11):3677</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34835933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8622851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13113677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Cruz E, Cerezo AB, Cantos-Villar E, Richard T, Troncoso AM, Garcia-Parrilla MC&#xa0;(2019) Inhibition of VEGFR-2 phosphorylation and effects on downstream signaling pathways in cultivated human endothelial cells by stilbenes from Vitis spp. J Agric Food Chem 67(14):3909&#x2013;3918</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30892883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jafc.9b00282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ficarra S, Tellone E, Pirolli D, Russo A, Barreca D, Galtieri A, Giardina B, Gavezzotti P, Riva S, De Rosa MC&#xa0;(2016) Insights into the properties of the two enantiomers of trans-&#x3b4;-viniferin, a resveratrol derivative: antioxidant activity, biochemical and molecular modeling studies of its interactions with hemoglobin. Mol Biosyst 12(4):1276&#x2013;1286</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26883599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C5MB00897B</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freyssin A, Rioux Bilan A, Fauconneau B, Galineau L, Serri&#xe8;re S, Tauber C, Perrin F, Guillard J, Chalon S, Page G&#xa0;(2022) Trans &#x3b5;-viniferin decreases amyloid deposits with greater efficiency than resveratrol in an Alzheimer&#x2019;s mouse model. Front Neurosci 15:803927&#x2013;803927</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35069106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8770934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2021.803927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuloria S, Sekar M, Khattulanuar FS, Gan SH, Rani NNIM, Ravi S, Subramaniyan V, Jeyabalan S, Begum MY, Chidambaram K, Sathasivam KV, Safi SZ, Wu YS, Nordin R, Maziz MNH, Kumarasamy V, Lum PT, Fuloria NK(2022) Chemistry, biosynthesis and pharmacology of viniferin: potential resveratrol-derived molecules for new drug discovery, development and therapy. Molecules 27(16):5072</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36014304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9414909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules27165072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Alonso M, Rimbach G, Rivas-Gonzalo JC, De Pascual-Teresa S(2004) Antioxidant and cellular activities of anthocyanins and their corresponding vitisins a studies in platelets, monocytes, and human endothelial cells. 52(11):3378&#x2013;3384</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge HM, Huang B, Tan SH, Shi da H, Song YC, Tan RX (2006) Bioactive oligostilbenoids from the stem bark of Hopea exalata. J Nat Prod 69(12):1800&#x2013;1802</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17190464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/np060242y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giansanti V, Don&#xe0; F, Tillhon M, Scovassi AI&#xa0;(2010) PARP inhibitors: new tools to protect from inflammation. Biochem Pharmacol 80(12):1869&#x2013;1877</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20417190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bcp.2010.04.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giri BR, Roy B (2015) Resveratrol- and &#x3b1;-viniferin-induced alterations of acetylcholinesterase and nitric oxide synthase in Raillietina echinobothrida. Parasitol Res 114(10):3775&#x2013;3781</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26141435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00436-015-4607-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez-Zorita S, Milton-Laskibar I, Eseberri I, Beaumont P, Courtois A, Krisa S, Portillo MP(2023) Beneficial effects of &#x3b5;-viniferin on obesity and related health alterations. Nutrients 15(4):928</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36839286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9963111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15040928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Barrio R, Beltr&#xe1;n D, Cantos E, Gil MI, Esp&#xed;n JC, Tom&#xe1;s-Barber&#xe1;n FA&#xa0;(2006) Comparison of ozone and UV-C treatments on the postharvest stilbenoid monomer, dimer, and trimer induction in var. &#x2018;Superior&#x2019;white table grapes. J Agric Food Chem 54(12):4222&#x2013;4228</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16756350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jf060160f</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guschlbauer M, Klinger S, Burmester M, Horn J, Kulling SE, Breves G(2013) trans-Resveratrol and &#x3b5;-viniferin decrease glucose absorption in porcine jejunum and ileum in vitro. Comp Biochem Physiol A Mol Integr Physiol 165(3):313&#x2013;318</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23570675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cbpa.2013.03.040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha DT, Long PT, Hien TT, Tuan DT, An NTT, Khoi NM, Van Oanh H, Hung TM (2018) Anti-inflammatory effect of oligostilbenoids from Vitis heyneana in LPS-stimulated RAW 264.7 macrophages via suppressing the NF-&#x3ba;B activation. Chem Cent J 12:1&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13065-018-0386-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutopo H, Noviany N (2009) The isolation of hopeaphenol, a tetramer stilbene, from Shorea ovalis Blume. Adv Nat Appl Sci 107&#x2013;112</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardie DG, Ross FA, Hawley SA (2012) AMPK: a nutrient and energy sensor that maintains energy homeostasis. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol 13(4):251&#x2013;262</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22436748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5726489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrm3311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He YK, Cen XT, Liu SS, Lu HD, He CN&#xa0;(2019) Protective effects of ten oligostilbenes from Paeonia suffruticosa seeds on interleukin-1&#x3b2;-induced rabbit osteoarthritis chondrocytes. BMC Chem 13:1&#x2013;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13065-019-0589-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashi Y (2022) Roles of oxidative stress and inflammation in vascular endothelial dysfunction-related disease. Antioxidants 11(10):1958</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36290681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9598825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox11101958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houill&#xe9; B, Besseau S, Delanoue G, Oudin A, Papon N, Clastre M, Simkin AJ, Gu&#xe9;rin L, Courdavault V, Giglioli-Guivarc'h N, Lanoue(2015) Composition and tissue-specific distribution of stilbenoids in grape canes are affected by downy mildew pressure in the vineyard. J Agric Food Chem 63(38):8472&#x2013;8477</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26373576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jafc.5b02997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh P-H (2016) Anti-inflammatory effect of resveratrol metabolite, &#x3b4;-viniferin, on lipopolysaccharide-stimulated murine macrophage. Master of Science. A thesis submitted to the Graduate School-New Brunswick Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey. https://doi.org/10.7282/T35X2C1Q</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Lin ZJ, Chen JC, Zheng HJ, Lai YH, Huang HC (2023) alpha-Viniferin-induced apoptosis through downregulation of SIRT1 in non-small cell lung cancer cells. Pharmaceuticals (Basel) 16(5): 727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Lin ZJ, Lee CJ, Lai WH, Chen JC, Huang HC(2021) epsilon-Viniferin and alpha-viniferin alone or in combination induced apoptosis and necrosis in osteosarcoma and non-small cell lung cancer cells. Food Chem Toxicol 158:112617</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34728247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fct.2021.112617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang F, Rock JR, Harfe BD, Cheng T, Huang X, Jan YN, Jan LY(2009) Studies on expression and function of the TMEM16A calcium-activated chloride channel. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 106(50):21413&#x2013;21418</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19965375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2781737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0911935106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang HC et al (2021b) Matrix metalloproteinase-9 inhibition or deletion attenuates portal hypertension in rodents. J Cell Mol Med 25(21):10073&#x2013;10087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34647412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8572799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcmm.16940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huber R, Marcourt L, H&#xe9;ritier M, Luscher A, Guebey L, Schnee S, Michellod E, Guerrier S, Wolfender JL, Scapozza L, K&#xf6;hler T, Gindro K, Queiroz EF&#xa0;(2023) Generation of potent antibacterial compounds through enzymatic and chemical modifications of the trans-&#x3b4;-viniferin scaffold. Sci Rep 13(1):15986</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37749179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10520035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-43000-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung MW, Wu CW, Kokubu D, Yoshida S, Miyazaki H&#xa0;(2019) &#x3b5;-Viniferin is more effective than resveratrol in promoting favorable adipocyte differentiation with enhanced adiponectin expression and decreased lipid accumulation. Food Sci Technol Res 25(6):817&#x2013;826</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3136/fstr.25.817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang SJ, Blair PJ, Britton FC, O'Driscoll KE, Hennig G, Bayguinov YR, Rock JR, Harfe BD, Sanders KM, Ward SM&#xa0;(2009) Expression of anoctamin 1/TMEM16A by interstitial cells of Cajal is fundamental for slow wave activity in gastrointestinal muscles. J Physiol 587(Pt 20):4887&#x2013;4904</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19687122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2770154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2009.176198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong W, Ahn EK, Oh JS, Hong SS. Caragasinin C&#xa0;(2017) Caragasinin C: a new oligostilbene from the roots of Caragana sinica. J Asian Nat Prod Res 19(11):1143&#x2013;1147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28347167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10286020.2017.1302941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang S, Wang W, Miner J, Fromm M(2012) Cross regulation of sirtuin 1, AMPK, and PPAR&#x3b3; in conjugated linoleic acid treated adipocytes. PLoS One 7(11):e48874</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23155420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3498327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0048874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnsen PR, Pinna C, Mattio L, Strube MB, Di Nunzio M, Iametti S, Dallavalle S, Pinto A, Fr&#xf8;ki&#xe6;r H&#xa0;(2023) Investigation of the effects of monomeric and dimeric stilbenoids on bacteria-induced cytokines and LPS-induced ROS formation in bone marrow-derived dendritic cells. Int J Mol Sci.&#xa0;1;24(3):2731</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms24032731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36769058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9917081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joydip D, Joydip D, Rashmi R, Rashmi R, Suraju MO (2016) Polyphenol compounds and PKC signaling. Biochim Biophys Acta.1860(10):2107&#x2013;2121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oligostilbenoids from Vatica lowii King (Dipterocarpaceae) and their chemotaxonomic significance (2025) Biochem Syst Ecol 120:104966</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keckeis K, Sarker SD, Dinan L (2000) Resveratrol-type oligostilbenes from Iris clarkei antagonize 20-hydroxyecdysone action in the Drosophila melanogaster BII cell line. Cell Mol Life Sci 57:333&#x2013;336</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10766027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11147012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/PL00000694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HW, Kim SS, Kang KB, Ryu B, Park E, Huh J, Jeon WK, Chae HS, Oh WK, Kim J, Sung SH, Chin YW&#xa0;(2020) Combined MS/MS-NMR annotation guided discovery of Iris lactea var. chinensis seed as a source of viral neuraminidase inhibitory polyphenols. Molecules 25(15):3383</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32722555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7435927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules25153383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JY, Jeong HY, Lee HK, Kim S, Hwang BY, Bae K, Seong YH (2012) Neuroprotection of the leaf and stem of Vitis amurensis and their active compounds against ischemic brain damage in rats and excitotoxicity in cultured neurons. Phytomedicine 19(2):150&#x2013;159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21778042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phymed.2011.06.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SJ, Cheresh P, Jablonski RP, Williams DB, Kamp DW (2015) The role of mitochondrial DNA in mediating alveolar epithelial cell apoptosis and pulmonary fibrosis. Int J Mol Sci 16(9):21486&#x2013;21519</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiselev KV, Aleynova OA, Grigorchuk VP, Dubrovina AS (2017) Stilbene accumulation and expression of stilbene biosynthesis pathway genes in wild grapevine Vitis amurensis Rupr. Planta 245:151&#x2013;159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27686467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00425-016-2598-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitanaka S, Ikezawa T, Yasukawa K, Yamanouchi S, Takido M, Sung HK, Kim IH(1990) (+)-&#x3b1;-Viniferin, an anti-inflammatory compound from Caragana chamlagu root. Chemical and pharmaceutical bulletin 38(2):432&#x2013;435</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokkorakis M, Chakhtoura M, Rhayem C, Al Rifai J, Ghezzawi M, Valenzuela-Vallejo L, Mantzoros CS (2025) Emerging pharmacotherapies for obesity: a systematic review. Pharmacol Rev 77(1):100002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon HS, Koh SH (2020) Neuroinflammation in neurodegenerative disorders: the roles of microglia and astrocytes. Transl Neurodegener 9(1):42</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7689983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40035-020-00221-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam SH, Chen JM, Tsai SF, Lee SS (2019) Chemical investigation on the root bark of Bombax malabarica. Fitoterapia 139:104376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31629048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fitote.2019.104376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert C, Lemaire J, Auger H, Guilleret A, Reynaud R, Cl&#xe9;ment C, Courot E, Taidi B&#xa0;(2019) Optimize, modulate, and scale-up resveratrol and resveratrol dimers bioproduction in Vitis labrusca L. cell suspension from flasks to 20 L bioreactor. Plants 8(12):567</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31817113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6963533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants8120567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langcake P, Pryce RJ (1977) New class of phytoalexins from grapevines. Experientia 33(2):151&#x2013;152</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">844529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02124034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x141;anoszka K, Vl&#x10d;kov&#xe1; N (2023) Natural Sirtuin1 activators and atherosclerosis: an overview. Curr Atheroscler Rep 25(12):979&#x2013;994</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38038821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10770200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11883-023-01165-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurindo LF, Santos AROD, Carvalho ACA, Bechara MD, Guiguer EL, Goulart RA, Vargas Sinatora R, Ara&#xfa;jo AC, Barbalho SM (2023) Phytochemicals and regulation of NF-kB in inflammatory bowel diseases: an overview of in vitro and in vivo effects. Metabolites 13(1):96</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36677021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9862976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/metabo13010096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ee S, Mailar K, Kim MI, Park M, Kim J, Min DH, Heo TH, Bae SK, Choi W, Lee C&#xa0;(2019) Plant-derived purification, chemical synthesis, and in vitro/in vivo evaluation of a resveratrol dimer, viniferin, as an HCV replication inhibitor. Viruses&#xa0;11(10):890</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v11100890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31861492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7020004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Han X, Song J, Dong M, Xie T (2024) Mechanism of action and risk prediction of adiponectin in cardiovascular diseases. 29(8):286</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Liu J, Lin J, Wang T, Huang J, Lin Y, Chen D (2016a) Protective effects of dihydromyricetin against&#x2022; OH-induced mesenchymal stem cells damage and mechanistic chemistry. Molecules 21(5):604</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27171068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6274564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules21050604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Li Z, Cai D, Li Y, Zhu Y, Jiao R, Lai C, Sun J, Bai W (2023) Vitisin A, as a type of pyranoanthocyanin, suppresses inflammation by restricting hematopoietic stem cell differentiation toward monocytes in bone marrow. J Agric Food Chem 71(41):15048&#x2013;15063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37811833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jafc.3c03119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Goto T, Yamakuni K, Takahashi H, Takahashi N, Jheng HF, Nomura W, Taniguchi M, Baba K, Murakami S, Kawada T (2016b) 4-Hydroxyderricin, as a PPARgamma agonist, promotes adipogenesis, adiponectin secretion, and glucose uptake in 3T3-L1 cells. Lipids 51(7):787&#x2013;975</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang D, Liu L, Zhao Y, Luo Z, He Y, Li Y, Tang S, Tang J, Chen N (2023) Targeting extracellular matrix through phytochemicals: a promising approach of multi-step actions on the treatment and prevention of cancer. Front Pharmacol 14:1186712</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37560476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10407561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2023.1186712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim NH, Oh SW, Kwon K, Yu E, Park SH, Cho JY, Lee J (2025) UVB&#x2010;protective effects and its mechanisms of Vitis amurensis Rupr. methanol extract in human primary dermal fibroblasts 2025(1):1507603</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu R , Zhang Y , Yao X , Wu Q , Wei M , Yan Z (2020) &#x395;-viniferin, a promising natural oligostilbene, ameliorates hyperglycemia and hyperlipidemia by activating AMPK in vivo. Food Funct 11(11):10084&#x2013;10093</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33140813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D0FO01932A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu WB, Hu L, Hu Q, Chen NN, Yang QS, Wang F&#xa0;(2013) New resveratrol oligomer derivatives from the roots of Rheum lhasaense. Molecules 18(6):7093&#x2013;7102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23778119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6270142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules18067093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu XY, Zhao Y, Jin LL, Pang Y, Yu B (2023) Trans-epsilon-viniferin as an inhibitor of TMEM16A preventing intestinal smooth muscle contraction. J Asian Nat Prod Res 25(9):867&#x2013;879</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36625145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10286020.2023.2165067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S, Wang X (2015) The role and potential mechanism of resveratrol in the prevention and control of epilepsy. Future Med Chem 7(15):2005&#x2013;2018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26505553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4155/fmc.15.130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu YL, Lin SY, Fang SU, Hsieh YY, Chen CR, Wen CL, Chang CI, Hou WC&#xa0;(2017) Hot-water extracts from roots of Vitis thunbergii var. taiwaniana and identified &#x3b5;-viniferin improve obesity in high-fat diet-induced mice. J Agric Food Chem 65(12):2521&#x2013;2529</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28285527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jafc.7b00327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lulan TYK, Fatmawati S, Santoso M, Ersam T(2020) &#x3b1;-Viniferin as a potential antidiabetic and antiplasmodial extracted from Dipterocarpus littoralis. Heliyon 6(5):e04102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32509997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7264059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2020.e04102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maluchenko NV, Feofanov AV, Studitsky VM (2021) PARP-1-associated pathological processes: inhibition by natural polyphenols. Int J Mol Sci 22(21):11441</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34768872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8584120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms222111441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao P, Lei Y, Zhang T, Ma C, Jin B, Li T (2016) Pharmacokinetics, bioavailability, metabolism and excretion of &#x3b4;-viniferin in rats. Acta Pharm Sin B 6(3):243&#x2013;52</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27175336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4857012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsb.2016.03.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martiniakova M, Sarocka A, Penzes N, Biro R, Kovacova V, Mondockova V, Sevcikova A, Ciernikova S, Omelka R&#xa0;(2025) Protective role of dietary polyphenols in the management and treatment of type 2 diabetes mellitus. Nutrients 17(2):275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39861406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11767469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu17020275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattio LM, Dallavalle S, Musso L, Filardi R, Franzetti L, Pellegrino L, D'Incecco P, Mora D, Pinto A, Arioli S (2019a) Antimicrobial activity of resveratrol-derived monomers and dimers against foodborne pathogens. Sci Rep 9(1):19525</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31862939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6925292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-55975-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattio LM, Marengo M, Parravicini C, Eberini I, Dallavalle S, Bonomi F, Iametti S, Pinto A(2019b) Inhibition of pancreatic &#x3b1;-amylase by resveratrol derivatives: biological activity and molecular modelling evidence for cooperativity between viniferin enantiomers. Molecules. 24(18):3225.&#xa0;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules24183225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31491840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6766848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medina-Leyte DJ, Zepeda-Garc&#xed;a O, Dom&#xed;nguez-P&#xe9;rez M, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Garrido A, Villarreal-Molina T, Jacobo-Albavera L (2021) Endothelial dysfunction, inflammation and coronary artery disease: potential biomarkers and promising therapeutical approaches. Int J Mol Sci 22(8):3850</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8068178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22083850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendon&#xe7;a ELSS, Xavier JA, Fragoso MBT, Silva MO, Escodro PB, Oliveira ACM, Tucci P, Saso L, Goulart MOF&#xa0;(2024) E-stilbenes: general chemical and biological aspects, potential pharmacological activity based on the Nrf2 pathway. Pharmaceuticals 17(2):232</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38399446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10891666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ph17020232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mingwei H (2019) Comparative study on beneficial functions of resveratrol and its dimer epsilon-viniferin in the adipocyte. A Dissertation Submitted to the Graduate School of Life and Environmental Sciences, the University of Tsukuba in Partial Fulfillment of the Requirements for the Degree of Doctor of Philosophy in Agricultural Science</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriyama H, Moriyama M, Ninomiya K, Morikawa T, Hayakawa T&#xa0;(2016) Inhibitory effects of oligostilbenoids from the bark of Shorea roxburghii on malignant melanoma cell growth: implications for novel topical anticancer candidates. Biol Pharm Bull 39(10):1675&#x2013;1682</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27725445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/bpb.b16-00420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris AP, Scott JK, Ball JM, Zeng CQ, O'Neal WK, Estes MK (1999) NSP4 elicits age-dependent diarrhea and Ca2+ mediated I&#x2212; influx into intestinal crypts of CF mice. American Journal of Physiology-Gastrointestinal and Liver Physiology 277(2):G431&#x2013;G444</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpgi.1999.277.2.G431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naia L, Carmo C, Campesan S, F&#xe3;o L, Cotton VE, Valero J, Lopes C, Rosenstock TR, Giorgini F, Rego AC&#xa0;(2021) Mitochondrial SIRT3 confers neuroprotection in Huntington&#x2019;s disease by regulation of oxidative challenges and mitochondrial dynamics. Free Radic Biol Med 163:163&#x2013;179</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33285261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2020.11.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo V, Duennwald ML (2022) Nrf2 and oxidative stress: a general overview of mechanisms and implications in human disease. Antioxidants 11:2345</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36552553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9774434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox11122345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen QT, Furuya Y, Roberts S, Metzger DW (2015) Role of interleukin-12 in protection against pulmonary infection with methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus. 59(10):6308&#x2013;6316</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nopo-Olazabal C, Hubstenberger J, Nopo-Olazabal L, Medina-Bolivar F&#xa0;(2013) Antioxidant activity of selected stilbenoids and their bioproduction in hairy root cultures of muscadine grape (Vitis rotundifolia Michx.). J Agric Food Chem 61(48):11744&#x2013;11758</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23668830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jf400760k</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noviello M, Caputi AF, Squeo G, Paradiso VM, Gambacorta G, Caponio F&#xa0;(2022) Vine shoots as a source of trans-resveratrol and &#x3b5;-viniferin: a study of 23 Italian varieties. Foods 11(4):553</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35206030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8871016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/foods11040553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohara K et al (2015) epsilon-Viniferin, a resveratrol dimer, prevents diet-induced obesity in mice. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 468(4):877&#x2013;82</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26596701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2015.11.047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong ALC, Ramasamy TS (2018) Role of Sirtuin1-p53 regulatory axis in aging, cancer and cellular reprogramming. Ageing Res Rev 43:64&#x2013;80</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29476819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2018.02.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zdemir F, &#x130;ncesu Z, &#x15e;ena M, &#xd6;ndera N&#x130;, Dikme M&#xa0;(2016) Implications of enhanced effectiveness of vincristine sulfate/&#x3b5;-viniferin combination compared to vincristine sulfate only on HepG2 cells. Dicle T&#x131;p Dergisi 43(4):534&#x2013;541</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papuc C, Goran GV, Predescu CN, Tudoreanu L, &#x218;tefan G&#xa0;(2022) Plant polyphenols mechanisms of action on insulin resistance and against the loss of pancreatic beta cells. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr 62(2):325&#x2013;352</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32901517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408398.2020.1815644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavan ME, Lopez NI, Pettinari MJ (2020) Melanin biosynthesis in bacteria, regulation and production perspectives. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol 104(4):1357&#x2013;1370</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31811318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00253-019-10245-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawlus AD, Waffo-T&#xe9;guo P, Shaver J, M&#xe9;rillon JM(2012) Stilbenoid chemistry from wine and the genus Vitis, a review. Oeno One 46(2):57&#x2013;111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20870/oeno-one.2012.46.2.1512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng J, Lu C, Luo Y, Su X, Li S, Ho CT&#xa0;(2024) Hypoglycemic effects and associated mechanisms of resveratrol and related stilbenes in diet. Food Funct&#xa0;15(5):2381-2405</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3FO04761J</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39587935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Y, Zheng X, Zhang S, Luo Z, Song L, Chen H, Yao X&#xa0;(2025) Advances in the activity of resveratrol and its derivatives in cardiovascular diseases. Arch Pharm 358(2):e2400865</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ardp.202400865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez IA (2020) Antitumoral actions of natural stilbenes derived from Vitis vinifera, Universit&#xe9; de Bordeaux; Universidad del Pa&#xed;s Vasco. Facultad de ciencias. PhD thesis in international co-tutelle to apply for the Doctor degree.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picard F, Kurtev M, Chung N, Topark-Ngarm A, Senawong T, Machado De Oliveira R, Leid M, McBurney MW, Guarente L&#xa0;(2004) Sirt1 promotes fat mobilization in white adipocytes by repressing PPAR-gamma. Nature 429(6993):771&#x2013;776</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15175761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2820247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature02583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pic&#xf3; C, Palou M, Pomar CA, Rodr&#xed;guez AM, Palou A&#xa0;(2022) Leptin as a key regulator of the adipose organ. Rev Endocr Metab Disord 23(1):13&#x2013;30</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34523036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11154-021-09687-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pislyagin EA, Tarbeeva DV, Yurchenko EA, Menchinskaya ES, Gorpenchenko TY, Pokhilo ND, Kalinovskiy AI, Aminin DL, Fedoreyev SA&#xa0;(2025) Neuroprotective activity of oligomeric stilbenes from alpha grape stems in in vitro models of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Int J Mol Sci 26(6):2411</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40141054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11942555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms26062411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabha B, Sini S, Priyadarshini TS, Sasikumar P, Gopalan G, Joseph JP, Jithin MM, Sivan VV, Jayamurthy P, Radhakrishnan KV&#xa0;(2021) Anti-inflammatory effect and mechanism of action of ellagic acid-3, 3&#x2032;, 4-trimethoxy-4&#x2032;-O-&#x3b1;-L-rhamnopyranoside isolated from Hopea parviflora in lipopolysaccharide-stimulated RAW 264.7 macrophages. Nat Prod Res 35(18):3156&#x2013;3160</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31711318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14786419.2019.1690486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Privat C, Telo JP, Bernardes-Genisson V, Vieira A, Souchard JP, Nepveu F&#xa0;(2002) Antioxidant properties of trans-&#x3b5;-viniferin as compared to stilbene derivatives in aqueous and nonaqueous media. J Agric Food Chem 50(5):1213&#x2013;1217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11853506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jf010676t</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qader M, Xu J, Yang Y, Liu Y, Cao S&#xa0;(2020) Natural Nrf2 activators from juices, wines, coffee, and cocoa. Beverages 6(4):68</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/beverages6040068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj P, Thandapilly SJ, Wigle J, Zieroth S, Netticadan T. A&#xa0;(2021) A comprehensive analysis of the efficacy of resveratrol in atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease, myocardial infarction and heart failure. Molecules 26(21):6600</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34771008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8587649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules26216600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramawat KG, M&#xe9;rillon J-M (2013) Natural products. Springer-Verlag, Berlin Heidelberg.&#xa0; https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-22144-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahim, Md Abdur, Hoonhee Seo, Sukyung Kim, Yoon Kyoung Jeong, Hanieh Tajdozian, Mijung Kim, Saebim Lee, and Ho-Yeon Song (2021) A clinical trial to evaluate the efficacy of &#x3b1;-viniferin in staphylococcus aureus&#x2013;specific decolonization without depleting the normal microbiota of nares.&#xa0;Pol J Microbiol 70(1): 117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren N, Kim E, Li B, Pan H, Tong T, Yang CS, Tu Y&#xa0;(2019) Flavonoids alleviating insulin resistance through inhibition of inflammatory signaling. J Agric Food Chem 67(19):5361&#x2013;5373</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30612424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jafc.8b05348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xed;os J-L, Schinella GR, Moragrega I (2022) Phenolics as GABAA receptor ligands: an updated review. Molecules 27(6):1770</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35335130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8953830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules27061770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera-Ch&#xe1;vez F, Meader BT, Akosman S, Koprivica V, Mekalanos JJ&#xa0;(2022) A potent inhibitor of the cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator blocks disease and morbidity due to toxigenic Vibrio cholerae. Toxins 14(3):225</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35324722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8948642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/toxins14030225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riviere C, Pawlus AD, Merillon JM (2012) Natural stilbenoids: distribution in the plant kingdom and chemotaxonomic interest in Vitaceae. Nat Prod Rep 29(11):1317&#x2013;1333</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23014926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c2np20049j</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roat C, Saraf M (2020) Isolation and characterization of t-resveratrol and &#x3b1;-viniferin, a bioactive secondary metabolite of an endophytic fungus Aspergillus stellifer ab4, from Vitis vinifera. J Microbiol Biotechnol Food Sci 9(4):708</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15414/jmbfs.2020.9.4.708-713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy B, Giri BR (2015) &#x3b1;-Viniferin-induced structural and functional alterations in Raillietina echinobothrida, a poultry tapeworm. Microsc Microanal 21(2):377&#x2013;384</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25592142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1431927614014603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy B, Pathaw D (2017) Flowcytometric analysis of cell cycle in the liver of mice in vivo exposed to (+)-&#x3b1;-viniferin, a phytostilbene. Clin Exp Pharmacol 7(243):2161-1459</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruze R, Chen Y, Xu R, Song J, Yin X, Wang C, Xu Q&#xa0;(2023) Obesity, diabetes mellitus, and pancreatic carcinogenesis: correlations, prevention, and diagnostic implications. Biochim Biophys Acta Rev Cancer 1:188844</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbcan.2022.188844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahidin I, Wahyuni W, Malaka MH, Imran I(2017) Antibacterial and cytotoxic potencies of stilbene oligomers from stem barks of baoti (Dryobalanops lanceolata) growing in Kendari Indonesia. Asian J Pharm Clin Res 10(8):139&#x2013;143</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22159/ajpcr.2017.v10i8.18664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangiovanni E, Di Lorenzo C, Piazza S, Manzoni Y, Brunelli C, Fumagalli M, Magnavacca A, Martinelli G, Colombo F, Casiraghi A, Melzi G, Marabini L, Restani P, Dell'Agli M (2019) Vitis vinifera L. leaf extract inhibits in vitro mediators of inflammation and oxidative stress involved in inflammatory-based skin diseases. Antioxidants.16;8(5):134</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox8050134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31100904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6562865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasikumar P, Lekshmy K, Sini S, Prabha B, Kumar NA, Sivan VV, Jithin MM, Jayamurthy P, Shibi IG, Radhakrishnan KV(2019) Isolation and characterization of resveratrol oligomers from the stem bark of Hopea ponga (Dennst.) Mabb. and their antidiabetic effect by modulation of digestive enzymes, protein glycation and glucose uptake in L6 myocytes. J Ethnopharmacol 236:196&#x2013;204</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30844488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2019.01.046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo H, Kim M, Kim S, Mahmud HA, Islam MI, Nam KW, Cho ML, Kwon HS, Song HY&#xa0;(2017) In&#xa0;vitro activity of alpha-viniferin isolated from the roots of Carex humilis against Mycobacterium tuberculosis. Pulm Pharmacol Ther 46:41&#x2013;47</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28782713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pupt.2017.08.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sergi D (2021) Anti-apoptotic and anti-inflammatory role of trans &#x3b5;-viniferin in a neuron&#x2013;glia co-culture cellular model of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Foods 10(3):586</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33799534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7998636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/foods10030586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seya K, Kanemaru K, Sugimoto C, Suzuki M, Takeo T, Motomura S, Kitahara H, Niwa M, Oshima Y, Furukawa K(2009) Opposite effects of two resveratrol (trans-3, 5, 4&#x2032;-trihydroxystilbene) tetramers, vitisin A and hopeaphenol, on apoptosis of myocytes isolated from adult rat heart. J Pharmacol Exp Ther 328(1):90&#x2013;98</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18927354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1124/jpet.108.143172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shazmeen, Haq IU, Rajoka MSR, Asim Shabbir M, Umair M, Llah IU, Manzoor MF, Nemat A, Abid M, Khan MR, Aadil RM&#xa0;(2021) Role of stilbenes against insulin resistance: a review. Food Sci Nutr 9(11):6389&#x2013;6405</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34760269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8565239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/fsn3.2553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y, Zhang D, Li S, Xuan X, Zhang L, Li Y, Guo F&#xa0;(2021) Inhibitors of BRD4 protein from the roots of Astilbe grandis stapf ex EH Wilson. Nat Prod Res 35(12):2044&#x2013;2050</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31437007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14786419.2019.1655414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin D, Kwon HY, Sohn EJ, Nam MS, Kim JH, Lee JC, Ryu SY, Park B, Kim SH&#xa0;(2015) Upregulation of death receptor 5 and production of reactive oxygen species mediate sensitization of PC-3 prostate cancer cells to TRAIL induced apoptosis by vitisin A. Cell Physiol Biochem 36(3):1151&#x2013;1162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26111475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000430286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim J, Jang HW, Song M, Kim JH, Lee SH, Lee S&#xa0;(2014) Potent inhibitory effect of alpha-viniferin on human cytochrome P450. Food Chem Toxicol 69:276&#x2013;280</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh D (2022) Astrocytic and microglial cells as the modulators of neuroinflammation in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. J Neuroinflammation 19(1):206</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35978311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9382837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12974-022-02565-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skroza D, Mekini&#x107; IG, Svilovi&#x107; S, &#x160;imat V, Katalini&#x107; V(2015) Investigation of the potential synergistic effect of resveratrol with other phenolic compounds: a case of binary phenolic mixtures. J Food Compos Anal 38:13&#x2013;18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfca.2014.06.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Z, Xiaoli AM, Zhang Q, Zhang Y, Yang EST, Wang S, Chang R, Zhang ZD, Yang G, Strich R, Pessin JE, Yang F(2017) Cyclin C regulates adipogenesis by stimulating transcriptional activity of CCAAT/enhancer-binding protein &#x3b1;. J Biol Chem 292(21):8918&#x2013;8932</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28351837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5448125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M117.776229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein S, Sch&#xe4;fer N, Breitenstein A, Besler C, Winnik S, Lohmann C, Heinrich K, Brokopp CE, Handschin C, Landmesser U, Tanner FC, L&#xfc;scher TF, Matter CM&#xa0;(2010) SIRT1 reduces endothelial activation without affecting vascular function in ApoE-/-mice. Aging 2(6):353</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20606253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2919255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/aging.100162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sy B, Krisa S, Richard T, Courtois A&#xa0;(2023) Resveratrol, &#x3b5;-viniferin, and vitisin B from vine: comparison of their in vitro antioxidant activities and study of their interactions. Molecules 28(22):7521</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38005243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10672907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules28227521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarhan S, &#xd6;zdemir F, &#x130;ncesu Z, Demirkan ES(2016) Direct and protective effects of single or combined addition of vincristine and epsilon-viniferin on human HepG2 cellular oxidative stress markers in vitro. Cytotechnology 68(4):1081&#x2013;1094</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26228177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10616-015-9863-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng BH, Zhu QB, Fan YY, Yao CS&#xa0;(2020) Total synthesis of the active resveratrol dimer dehydro-&#x3b4;-viniferin. J Asian Nat Prod Res 22(10):947&#x2013;955</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32567953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10286020.2020.1776267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian X, Guo S, Zhang S, Li P, Wang T, Ho CT, Pan MH, Bai N (2020) Chemical characterization of main bioactive constituents in Paeonia ostii seed meal and GC-MS analysis of seed oil. J Food Biochem 44(1):e13088</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31646682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jfbc.13088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#x159;&#xed;ska J, Vrchotov&#xe1; N, Horn&#xed;k &#x160;, S&#xfd;kora J, Ku&#x10d;erov&#xe1; A&#xa0;(2024) T&#x159;&#xed;ska J, Vrchotov&#xe1; N, Horn&#xed;k &#x160;, S&#xfd;kora J, Ku&#x10d;erov&#xe1; AStilbenes in Carex acuta and Carex lepidocarpa. Molecules 29(16):3840</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39202919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11357264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules29163840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinet R, Mart&#xed;nez JL, Guzm&#xe1;n L (2016) The therapeutic potential of products based on polyphenols from wine grapes in cardiovascular diseases. Ther Med Plants 331: 12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Jiang B, Lv H, Liang Y, Ma X (2019) Vitisin B as a novel fatty acid synthase inhibitor induces human breast cancer cells apoptosis. Am J Transl Res 11(8):5096&#x2013;5104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31497225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6731432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Jones Voy B, Urs S, Kim S, Soltani-Bejnood M, Quigley N, Heo YR (2004) The huWang Y, Jones Voy B, Urs S, Kim S, Soltani-Bejnood M, Quigley N, Heo YRman fatty acid synthase gene and de novo lipogenesis are coordinately regulated in human adipose tissue. 134(5):1032&#x2013;1038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiskirchen S, Weiskirchen R (2016) Resveratrol: how much wine do you have to drink to stay healthy? Adv Nutr 7(4):706&#x2013;718</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27422505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4942868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/an.115.011627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wibowo A, Ahmat N, Hamzah AS, Sufian AS, Ismail NH, Ahmad R, Jaafar FM, Takayama H. Malaysianol A&#xa0;(2011) Malaysianol A, a new trimer resveratrol oligomer from the stem bark of Dryobalanops aromatica. Fitoterapia 82(4):676&#x2013;681</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21338657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fitote.2011.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CW, Nakamoto Y, Hisatome T, Yoshida S, Miyazaki H (2020) Resveratrol and its dimers &#x3b5;-viniferin and &#x3b4;-viniferin in red wine protect vascular endothelial cells by a similar mechanism with different potency and efficacy. Kaohsiung J Med Sci 36(7):535&#x2013;542</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32118360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11896465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/kjm2.12199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>u L, Botchway BOA, Zhang S, Zhou J, Liu X(2018) Inhibition of NF-&#x3ba;B signaling pathway by resveratrol improves spinal cord injury. Front Neurosci 12:690</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30337851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6180204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2018.00690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S, Ilyas I, Little PJ, Li H, Kamato D, Zheng X, Luo S, Li Z, Liu P, Han J, Harding IC, Ebong EE, Cameron SJ, Stewart AG, Weng J (2021) Endothelial dysfunction in atherosclerotic cardiovascular diseases and beyond: from mechanism to pharmacotherapies. Pharmacol Rev 73(3):924&#x2013;967</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34088867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1124/pharmrev.120.000096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue YQ, Di JM, Luo Y, Cheng KJ, Wei X, Shi Z&#xa0;(2014) Resveratrol oligomers for the prevention and treatment of cancers. Oxid Med Cell Longev 2014:765832</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24799982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3988857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2014/765832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>adav MK, Mailar K, Nagarajappa Masagalli J, Chae SW, Song JJ, Choi WJ&#xa0;(2019) Ruthenium chloride-induced oxidative cyclization of trans-resveratrol to (&#xb1;)-&#x3b5;-viniferin and antimicrobial and antibiofilm activity against Streptococcus pneumoniae. Front Pharmacol 10:890</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31474855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6702469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2019.00890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang JB, Wang AG, Ji TF, Su YL&#xa0;(2014) Two new oligostilbenes from the stem of Parthenocissus quinquefolia. J Asian Nat Prod Res 16(3):275&#x2013;280</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24456249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10286020.2013.877451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu B, Jiang Y, Zhang B, Yang H, Ma T&#xa0;(2018) Resveratrol dimer trans-epsilon-viniferin prevents rotaviral diarrhea in mice by inhibition of the intestinal calcium-activated chloride channel. Pharmacol Res 129:453&#x2013;461</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29155014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2017.11.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu B, Jiang Y, Zhang B, Yang H, Ma T&#xa0;(2019) trans-delta-Viniferin inhibits Ca(2+)-activated Cl(-) channels and improves diarrhea symptoms. Fitoterapia 139:104367(2019) trans-delta-Viniferin inhibits Ca(2+)-activated Cl(-) channels and improves diarrhea symptoms. Fitoterapia 139:104367</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31629045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fitote.2019.104367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuk HJ, Ryu HW, Jeong SH, Curtis-Long MJ, Kim HJ, Wang Y, Song YH, Park KH&#xa0;(2013) Profiling of neuraminidase inhibitory polyphenols from the seeds of Paeonia lactiflora. Food Chem Toxicol 55:144&#x2013;149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23313796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fct.2012.12.053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yun CY, Mi Ko S, Pyo Choi Y, Kim BJ, Lee J, Mun Kim J, Kim JY, Song JY, Kim SH, Hwang BY, Tae Hong J, Han SB, Kim Y&#xa0;(2018) &#x3b1;-Viniferin improves facial hyperpigmentation via accelerating feedback termination of cAMP/PKA-signaled phosphorylation circuit in facultative melanogenesis. Theranostics 8(7):2031&#x2013;2043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29556371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5858515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/thno.24385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zain WZ, Yusoff NA, Rukayadi Y, Aziman N, Windayani N. (2024) Anti-candidal activity of crude extracts and compounds from Dipterocarpus verrucosus Foxw. Ex Sloot, Dipterocarpus cornutus Dyer and Dipterocarpus crinitus Dyer. Malay J Chem 26(1):302&#x2013;313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zawawi NK, Ahmat N, Mazatulikhma MZ, Shafiq RM, Wahid NH, Sufian AS&#xa0;(2013) Bioactive oligostilbenoids from Shorea maxwelliana King and their chemotaxonomic significance. Nat Prod Res 27(17):1589&#x2013;1593</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23035830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14786419.2012.730047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zekar L, Sharman T (2025) Plasmodium falciparum Malaria. StatPearls. StatPearls Publishing LLC, Treasure Island (FL). https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK555962/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zghonda N, Yoshida S, Araki M, Kusunoki M, Mliki A, Ghorbel A, Miyazaki H&#xa0;(2011) Greater effectiveness of &#x3b5;-viniferin in red wine than its monomer resveratrol for inhibiting vascular smooth muscle cell proliferation and migration. Biosci Biotechnol Biochem 75(7):1259&#x2013;1267</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21737923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1271/bbb.110022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zghonda N, Yoshida S, Ezaki S, Otake Y, Murakami C, Mliki A, Ghorbel A, Miyazaki H&#xa0;(2012) &#x395;-viniferin is more effective than its monomer resveratrol in improving the functions of vascular endothelial cells and the heart. Biosci Biotechnol Biochem 76(5):954&#x2013;960</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22738966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1271/bbb.110975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang BP, Zhao J, Li SS, Yang LJ, Zeng LL, Chen Y, Fang J&#xa0;(2014) Mangiferin activates Nrf2-antioxidant response element signaling without reducing the sensitivity to etoposide of human myeloid leukemia cells in vitro. Acta Pharmacol Sin 35(2):257&#x2013;266</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24374812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/aps.2013.165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Rao S, Yang M, Ma C, Hong F, Yang S&#xa0;(2022) Role of mitochondrial pathways in cell apoptosis during he-patic ischemia/reperfusion injury. Int J Mol Sci 23(4):2357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8877300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23042357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Ma Y, Feng J (2020) Neuroprotective mechanisms of &#x3b5;-viniferin in a rotenone-induced cell model of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: significance of SIRT3-mediated FOXO3 deacetylation. Neural Regen Res 15(11):2143&#x2013;2153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32394973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7716051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.282264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Rao S, Yang M, Ma C, Hong F, Yang S&#xa0;(2016) Protective effect of trans-&#x3b4;-viniferin against high glucose-induced oxidative stress in human umbilical vein endothelial cells through the SIRT1 pathway. Free Radic Res 50(1):68&#x2013;83</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26483208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/10715762.2015.1108412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao N, Sun Q, Song Y, Wang L, Zhang T, Meng F&#xa0;(2018) Comparative pharmacokinetics study of orientin in rat plasma by UHPLC-MS/MS after intravenous administration of single orientin and Trollius chinensis Bunge extract. Biomed Chromatogr 32(4):e4142</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bmc.4142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann R, Lass A, Haemmerle G, Zechner R(2009) Fate of fat: the role of adipose triglyceride lipase in lipolysis. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta (BBA) 1791(6):494&#x2013;500</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19010445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbalip.2008.10.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwygart AC, Medaglia C, Huber R, Poli R, Marcourt L, Schnee S, Michellod E, Mazel-Sanchez B, Constant S, Huang S, Bekliz M, Cl&#xe9;ment S, Gindro K, Queiroz EF, Tapparel C&#xa0;(2023) Antiviral properties of trans-&#x3b4;-viniferin derivatives against enveloped viruses. Biomed Pharmacother 163:114825</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37148860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10158552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2023.114825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>