<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41656220</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2229</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC plant biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Plant Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of Bacillus velezensis strain N23 for the control of potato common scab.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">465</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12870-026-08245-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Potato common scab (PCS) is a soil-borne disease caused by <i>Streptomyces</i> spp. It is a serious problem and <i>S. galilaeus</i> is the predominant causal agent of PCS in Inner Mongolia, China. Employing biocontrol agents to manage PCS represents a potentially effective approach. Consequently, there remains substantial room for the exploration of highly efficient biocontrol strains.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">To search for a better biological control agent in controlling PCS, 53 bacterial isolates were assessed for their suppression of <i>S. galilaeus</i> on oatmeal agar (OMA) plates. Among the isolates, strain N23 exhibited the highest level of inhibition against <i>S. galilaeus</i> PS1, with the total area of inhibition being 4.52 cm<sup>2</sup>. N23 metabolites in the fermentation broth inhibited PS1 with an inhibition zone of 2.54 cm<sup>2</sup>. N23 was identified as <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> based on morphological, physiological, and sequence analysis of 16&#xa0;S rDNA and <i>gyrA</i> genes. Optimal conditions for N23 growth included soluble starch as a carbon source, ammonium nitrate as a nitrogen source, pH 7.5, and temperature of 32&#x2103;. N23 increased potato emergence and promoted the growth of potato plantlets. It exhibited 58.41% control of PCS infection in greenhouse trials. In two independent field trials, potato seed treatments with N23 resulted in PCS control ranging from 58.50% to 73.26%, and increased yield by 8.01% to 14.20%; while N23 soil treatments resulted in 56.77% to 66.30% disease control and a 3.32% to 18.10% yield increase.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">In this study, we isolated and identified a strain named <i>B. velezensis</i> N23, which can effectively inhibit the growth of <i>S. galilaeus</i> PS1. The results of greenhouse and field trials indicated that the strain could both inhibit <i>S. galilaeus</i> PS1 and promote potato growth. Thus <i>B. velezensis</i> N23 could be a promising biocontrol agent for the management of PCS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12870-026-08245-y.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Liwei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Horticulture and Plant Protection, Inner Mongolia Agricultural University, Hohhot, 010019, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Biopesticide Creation and Resource Utilization in Higher Educational Institutions of the Autonomous Region, Hohhot , 010052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plant Pathology, MOA Key Lab of Pest Monitoring and Green Management, College of Plant Protection, China Agricultural University, Beijing, 100193, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Horticulture and Plant Protection, Inner Mongolia Agricultural University, Hohhot, 010019, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Biopesticide Creation and Resource Utilization in Higher Educational Institutions of the Autonomous Region, Hohhot , 010052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hao</LastName><ForeName>Jianjun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Food and Agriculture, University of Maine, Orono, ME, 04469, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xing</LastName><ForeName>Xing</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Horticulture and Plant Protection, Inner Mongolia Agricultural University, Hohhot, 010019, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Biopesticide Creation and Resource Utilization in Higher Educational Institutions of the Autonomous Region, Hohhot , 010052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Peng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Horticulture and Plant Protection, Inner Mongolia Agricultural University, Hohhot, 010019, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Biopesticide Creation and Resource Utilization in Higher Educational Institutions of the Autonomous Region, Hohhot , 010052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoyu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Horticulture and Plant Protection, Inner Mongolia Agricultural University, Hohhot, 010019, China. zxy2000@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Biopesticide Creation and Resource Utilization in Higher Educational Institutions of the Autonomous Region, Hohhot , 010052, China. zxy2000@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>XTCX2024-05</GrantID><Agency>the Development and Application of Biocontrol Agents for Potato Common Scab under the Collaborative Innovation Program of Universities and Research Institutes in Hohhot</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>YZ2023006</GrantID><Agency>the Potato New Germplasm Creation and New Variety Breeding of Joint Project for Breeding of Special Varieties in Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Plant Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967807</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2229</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biological control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolites</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Plant growth promotion rhizobacteria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Potato common scab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Streptomyces galilaeus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This article does not contain any studies with human participants or animals. The collection materials of the plants comply the relevant institutional, national, and international guidelines and legislation. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41656220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12983541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12870-026-08245-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12870-026-08245-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wu X, Lin T, Zhou X, Zhang W, Liu S, Qiu H, et al. Potato E3 ubiquitin ligase StRFP1 positively regulates late blight resistance by degrading sugar transporters StSWEET10c and StSWEET11. New Phytol. 2024;243(2):688&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nph.19848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38769723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Kong FY, Zhao TC, Zhang CS, Zhang S, Feng C. First report of tobacco root rot caused by Gelasinospora reticulata. Crop Prot. 2014;66:86&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cropro.2014.08.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations. Rome. http://www.fao.org. Accessed 8 Feb 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montoya-Martinez AC, Ch&#xe1;vez-Luzan&#xed;a RA, Olgu&#xed;n-Mart&#xed;nez AI, Ru&#xed;z-Castrej&#xf3;n A, Moreno-C&#xe1;rdenas JD, Esquivel-Ch&#xe1;vez F, et al. Biological control of <i>Streptomyces</i> species causing common scabs in potato tubers in the Yaqui Valley, Mexico. Horticulturae. 2024;10:865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/horticulturae10080865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Liu Y, Liang Y, Xing X, Zhang JP, Li D, et al. Identification and biological characteristics of pathogens in potato common scab. J Agric Biotechnol. 2019;27:897&#x2013;907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghuffar S, Saeed MS, Anwaar S, Anwar T, Qureshi H, Abdelbacki AMM, et al. Pathogenicity of <i>Streptomyces</i> scabies and identification of tolerant potato cultivars for scab-prone regions. BMC Plant Biol. 2025;25(1):455.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12870-025-06506-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11984041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40211136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi W, Lv M, Wang R, Saleem M, Wang L, Li M, et al. Geocaulosphere soil bacterial community drives potato common scab outcomes beyond pathogen abundance. Npj Biofilms Microbiomes. 2025;11:134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41522-025-00774-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12267564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40670379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao H, Wang SS, Li XY, Li XB, Cai JY, Zhao LF, et al. Biological control of potato common scab and growth promotion of potato by <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> Y6. Front Microbiol. 2023;14:1295107.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2023.1295107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10750399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38149275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill J, Lazarovits G. A mail survey of growers to estimate potato common scab prevalence and economic loss in Canada. Can J Plant Pathol. 2005;17:46&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07060660509507192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang R, Wang SR. Preliminary identification of the pathogen of potato scab in Gansu. Plant Prot. 2013;39:78&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie FJ, Cheng YC, Gong L, Bai XY, Xu LM, Song YX. Biological characterization and identification of the pathogens of potato scab in Northwestern. China Plant Prot. 2019;46:611&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JP, Yin YH, Yan RP, Ha S, Lin TR, Cheng YC, et al. Occurrence and control approach of potato common scab (<i>Streptomyces</i> spp.) in inner Mongolia. Chin Potato J. 2013;27:56&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Yang MJ, Zhang Y, Li TT, Wang ZY, Zeng Y, et al. Progress in potato common scab research. Chin Potato J. 2018;32:240&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen N, Zhou S, Yan S, Yuan X, Jiao W, Wang X, et al. Copper And zinc sulfates suppress <i>Streptomyces</i> spp. And enhance potato resistance via Thaxtomin A Inhibition And defense gene regulation. Microorganisms. 2025;13(6):1288.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms13061288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12195330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40572176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haroun SA. Application of actinomycetes as biocontrol agents in the management of onion bacterial rot disease. Arch Phytopathol Plant Prot. 2013;46:1797&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03235408.2013.778451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng QX, Hanson LE, Douches D, Hao JJ. Managing scab diseases of potato and radish caused by <i>Streptomyces</i> spp. Using <i>Bacillus amyloliquefaciens</i> BAC03 and other biomaterials. Biol Control. 2013;67:373&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biocontrol.2013.09.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larkin RP. Biological control of soilborne diseases in organic potato production using hypovirulent strains of <i>Rhizoctonia Solani</i>. Biol Agric Hortic. 2020;36:119&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01448765.2019.1706636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larkin RP, Tavantzis S. Use of biocontrol organisms and compost amendments for improved control of soilborne diseases and increased potato production. Am J Potato Res. 2013;90:261&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12230-013-9301-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng QX, Jiang HH, Hanson LE, Hao JJ. Characterizing a novel strain of <i>Bacillus amyloliquefaciens</i> BAC03 for potential biological control application. J Appl Microbiol. 2012;113:1165&#x2013;75.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2672.2012.05420.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22924833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SF, Zhang MS, Wang JY, Lv D, Ma YF, Zhou B, et al. Biocontrol effects of <i>Brevibacillus laterosporus</i> AMCC100017 on potato common scab and its impact on rhizosphere bacterial communities. Biol Control. 2017;106:89&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biocontrol.2017.01.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mughrabi KI. Biological control of fusarium dry rot and other potato tuber diseases using <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i> and <i>Enterobacter cloacae</i>. Biol Control. 2010;53(3):280&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biocontrol.2010.01.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mushtaq Z, Alwutayd KM. Siderophore-producing bacteria <i>Bacillus simplex</i> and <i>Acinetobacter calcoaceticus</i> and L-Tryptophan enhance the nutritional, antioxidant activity and volatile compound profiles of potatoes. Potato Res. 2025;68:3865&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11540-025-09900-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaus&#xe9;jour J, Clermont N, Beaulieu C. Effect of <i>Streptomyces melanosporofaciens</i> strain EF-76 and of Chitosan on common scab of potato. Plant Soil. 2003;256:463&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1026177714855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng QX, Yin JF, Rosenzweig N, Douches D, Hao JJ. Culture-based assessment of microbial communities in soil suppressive to potato common scab. Plant Dis. 2012;96:712&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1094/PDIS-05-11-0441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30727529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng M, Gu G, Xiao S, Zhou T, Liu GK. Antagonistic effects of <i>Bacillus</i> FJSC01 on soilborne pathogens of tobacco and its identification. J Fujian Agric Univ (Nat Sci Edn). 2021;50:164&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grosch R, Junge H, Krebs B, Bochow H. Use of <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> as biocontrol agent.&#x2162;.Influence of <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> on fungal root diseases and on yield in soilless culture. J Plant Dis Protect. 1999;106:568&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu DD, Liu HX, Jiang CH, Wang YP, Jin HL, Guo JH. The plant growth-promoting rhizobacterium <i>Bacillus cereus</i> AR156 induces systemic resistance in <i>Arabidopsis Thaliana</i> by simultaneously activating salicylate and jasmonate. Mol Plant Microbe in. 2011;24:533&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1094/MPMI-09-10-0213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21198361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng QX, Hao JJ. Optimizing the application of <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> BAC03 in controlling the disease caused by <i>Streptomyces scabies</i>. Biocontrol. 2017;62:535&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10526-017-9799-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YC, Li BY, You XY, Liu YH, Zhou B, Lin RS. Screening, identification and biocontrol effect of antagonistic bacteria on potato common scab. Biotechnol Bull. 2018;34:116&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao ZF, Zhang BJ, Liu HP, Han JC, Zhang YJ. Identification of endophytic <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> ZSY-1 strain and antifungal activity of its volatile compounds against <i>Alternaria Solani</i> and <i>Botrytis cinerea</i>. Biol Control. 2017;105:27&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biocontrol.2016.11.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagzian A, Riseh RS, Sarikhan S, Ghorbani A, Khodaygan P, Borriss R, et al. Genome mining conformance to metabolite profile of <i>Bacillus</i> strains to control potato pathogens. Sci Rep. 2023;13:19095.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-46672-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10625545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37925555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XX, Wang XH, Shi XY, Wang BP, Li MP, Wang Q, et al. Antifungal effect of volatile organic compounds from <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> CT32 against <i>Verticillium dahliae</i> and <i>Fusarium oxysporum</i>. Processes. 2020;8:1674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr8121674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang XY, Li C, Hao JJ, Li YC, Liang Y. A novel <i>Streptomyces</i> sp. Strain PBSH9 for controlling potato common scab caused by <i>Streptomyces Galilaeus</i>. Plant Dis. 2020;104:1&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1094/PDIS-07-19-1469-RE</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32441579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiltunen LH, Weckman A, Ylhainen A, Rita H, Richter E, Valkonen JPT. Responses of potato cultivars to the common scab pathogens, <i>Streptomyces scabies</i> and <i>S. turgidiscabies</i>. Ann Appl Biol. 2005;146(3):395&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan Z, Ruan J, Li Y, Qiu R. A new model for simulating microbial cyanide production and optimizing the medium parameters for recovering precious metals from waste printed circuit boards. J Hazard Mater. 2018;353:135&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2018.04.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29660699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchanan RE, Bergey DH. Bergey&#x2019;s manual of determinative bacteriology, 8th ed. Beijing: Chinese Science Press; 1984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saitou N, Nei M. The neighbor-joining method: A new method for reconstructing phylogenetic trees. Mol Biol Evol. 1987;4:406&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3447015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grasso LL, Martino DC, Alduina R, Cultural. Physiological, and biochemical identification of actinobacteria. Actinobacteria-Basics and biotechnological applications. London: InTechOpen; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma S, Wang Y, Teng W. <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> K-9 as a potential biocontrol agent for managing potato scab. Plant Dis. 2023;107:3943&#x2013;51.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1094/PDIS-12-22-2829-RE</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37337440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui LX, Yang CD, Wei LJ, Li TH, Chen XY. Isolation and identification of an endophytic bacteria <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> 8&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;4 exhibiting biocontrol activity against potato scab. Biol Control. 2020;14:104156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biocontrol.2019.104156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen ZY. Screening of antagonistic bacteria against <i>Steptomyces scabies</i> and preliminary study on its biocontrol mechanism [master&#x2019;s thesis]. Daqing: Heilongjiang Bayi Agricultural University; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almasoudi NM, Al-Qurashi AD, Elsayed MI, Abo-Elyousr KAM. Native bacterial bioagents for management of potato soft rot disease caused by <i>Pectobacterium Carotovorum</i> subsp. <i>Carotovorum</i>. Egypt J Biol Pest Control. 2024;34:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41938-024-00794-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asaturova A, Shternshis M, Tsvetkova V, Shpatova T, Maslennikova V, Zhevnova N, et al. Biological control of important fungal diseases of potato and raspberry by two <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> strains. Peer J. 2021;9:e11578.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.11578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8210809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34178462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan HH, Qiu Y, Yang S, Wang YQ, Wang KY, Jiang LL, et al. Antagonistic activity of <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> SDTB038 against <i>Phytophthora infestans</i> in potato. Plant Dis. 2021;105:1738&#x2013;47.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1094/PDIS-08-20-1666-RE</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33174798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai XF, Li Q, Zhang D, Zhao Y, Zhao DM, Pan Y, et al. <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> strain HN-Q-8 induced resistance to <i>Alternaria Solani</i> and stimulated growth of potato plant. Biology. 2023;12:856.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biology12060856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10295523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37372140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu CJ, Chen H, Zhu LL, Song Y, Jiang QF, Zhang YM, et al. Profiling of antimicrobial metabolites synthesized by the endophytic and genetically amenable biocontrol strain <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> DMW1. Microbiol Spectr. 2023;11:e0003823.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/spectrum.00038-23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10100683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36809029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin C, Tsai CH, Chen PY, Wu CY, Chang YL, Yang YL, et al. Biological control of potato common scab by <i>Bacillus amyloliquefaciens</i> Ba01. PLoS ONE. 2018;13:e0196520.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0196520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5919641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29698535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Q, Jiang H, Hao JJ. Effects of <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> strain BAC03 in promoting plant growth. Biol Control. 2016;98:18&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biocontrol.2016.03.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J, Zhou Z, Bai X, Zhang D, Zhang L, Wang J, et al. A novel of new class II bacteriocin from <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> HN-Q-8 and its antibacterial activity on <i>Streptomyces scabies</i>. Front Microbiol. 2022;13:943232.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2022.943232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9372549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35966655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choub V, Ajuna HB, Won S, Moon J, Choi S, Maung CEH, et al. Antifungal activity of <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> CE 100 against anthracnose aisease (<i>Colletotrichum gloeosporioides</i>) and growth promotion of walnut (<i>Juglans regia</i> L.) trees. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(19):10438.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms221910438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8508943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34638782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y, He P, Kong H, He P, Wu Y, Tang G, et al. Biocontrol effect of <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> D7-8 on potato common scab and its complete genome sequence analysis. Microorganisms. 2025;13(4):770.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms13040770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12029370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40284607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin XT, Li TG, Jiang XL, Tang XN, Zhang JK, Yuan LF, et al. Suppression of grape white rot caused by <i>Coniella vitis</i> using the potential biocontrol agent <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> GSBZ09. Pathogens. 2022;11:248.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pathogens11020248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8876275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35215191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lankau EW, Xue D, Christensen R, Gevens AJ, Lankau RA. Management and soil conditions influence common scab severity on potato tubers via indirect effects on soil microbial communities. Phytopathology. 2020;110(5):1049&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1094/PHYTO-06-19-0223-R</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31939718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Xu Z, Chen L, Xun W, Shu X, ChenY, et al. Root colonization by beneficial rhizobacteria. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2024;48(1):fuad066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/femsre/fuad066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10786197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38093453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marques HMC, Appy MP, Dest&#xe9;fano SAL. Effect of pH soil and irrigation regimes on management of potato scab. Arq Inst Biol. 2021;88:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1808-1657000552020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagova-Mareckova M, Omelka M, Kopecky J. Sequential analysis of soil factors related to common scab of potatoes. FEMS Microbiol Ecol. 2017;93(1):fiw201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/femsec/fiw201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27694223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao JJ, Ma Y, Fu J, Wang Z, Zhao Y, Zhong N, et al. <i>Bacillus atrophaeus</i> DX-9 biocontrol against potato common scab involves significant changes in the soil Microbiome and metabolome. aBIOTECH. 2025;6(1):33&#x2013;49.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42994-025-00199-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11889282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40060187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui LX, Yang CD, Wei LJ, Xue L, Zhang JL. Isolation, identification and biological characterization of <i>Streptomyces galilaeus</i>, a new pathogen of potato scab in Dingxi City, Gansu Province. Plant Prot. 2018;44:206&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XX, Gao XJ, Zhang SM, Jiang ZY, Yang H, Liu XD, et al. Characterization of a <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> with antibacterial activity and inhibitory effect on common aquatic pathogens. Aquaculture. 2020;523:735165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aquaculture.2020.735165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MH, Kang DU, Lee JW. Construction of a Recombinant <i>Escherichia coli</i> JM109/A-68 for production of carboxymethylcellulase and comparison of its production with its wild type, <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> A-68 in a pilot-scale bioreactor. Biotechnol Bioprocess Eng. 2016;21:601&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12257-016-0468-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang HH, Shen WS, Ma CY, Li SS, Chen J, Mou XF, et al. Simultaneous nitrogen removal and plant growth promotion using salt-tolerant denitrifying bacteria in agricultural wastewater. Microbes Environ. 2022;37(3):ME22025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1264/jsme2.ME22025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9530716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36123022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostafa Y, Alrumman S, Alamri S, Hashem M, Al-izran K, Alfaifi M, et al. Enhanced production of glutaminase-free L-asparaginase by marine <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> and cytotoxic activity against breast cancer cell lines. Electron J Biotechnol. 2019;42:6&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejbt.2019.10.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu XY, Ren BA, Chen M, Wang HB, Kokare CR, Zhou XL, et al. Production and characterization of a group of bioemulsifiers from the marine <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> strain H3. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol. 2010;87:1881&#x2013;93.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00253-010-2653-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20473663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tak&#xe9; A, Matsumoto A, &#x14c;mura S, Takahashi Y. <i>Streptomyces lactacystinicus</i> sp. Nov. And <i>Streptomyces cyslabdanicus</i> sp. Nov., producing lactacystin And cyslabdan, respectively. J Antibiot. 2015;68:322&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ja.2014.162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25491896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwanaga M, Kuyyakanond T. Large production of cholera toxin by vibrio cholerae O1 in yeast extract peptone water. J Clin Microbiol. 1987;25:2314&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/jcm.25.12.2314-2316.1987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC269478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3429623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong XZ, Cai MY. Manual of identification of common bacterial systems. China: Science; 2001.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>