<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41055720</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-5233</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>63</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta diabetologica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Diabetol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Blunted cortisol and altered antioxidant defense as biomarkers of systemic stress in hyperglycemic Zebrafish.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>389</StartPage><EndPage>398</EndPage><MedlinePgn>389-398</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00592-025-02585-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND/AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Emerging evidence links hyperglycemia, a "hallmark of diabetes mellitus" not only to peripheral metabolic dysfunction but also to its detrimental impact on brain health, often contributing to stress-related pathologies such as depression and cognitive decline. Zebrafish, with their well-characterized vascular system and behavioral assays, offer a unique model to study the impacts of sucrose-induced hyperglycemia. This study aims to investigates the effects of sucrose-induced hyperglycemia on stress mechanisms in type 2 diabetes using the zebrafish.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Male zebrafish were divided into two groups: control, and 55.5mM sucrose immersed. Over two weeks, these were subjected to behavioural assays- the novel tank test (NTT) and the light/dark test (LDT). The NTT assessed anxiety-related behaviour by measuring the time spent in different vertical zones of a novel tank, while the light/dark test evaluated anxiety responses based on the time spent in illuminated versus dark compartments. Trajectory body coordinates and tail kinematics were quantified using ZebraZoom software to asses locomotor metrics status. Cortisol levels were measured to assess HPA axis function. Antioxidant enzymes, including superoxide dismutase (SOD) and catalase (CAT), were quantified to evaluate oxidative stress.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The results revealed that zebrafish exposed to sucrose exhibited significant hyperglycemia (**p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01) and behavioural changes compared to those on control. Specifically, in the NTT, the hyperglycemic group demonstrated heightened anxiety-like behaviour, spending more time at the bottom zone of the tank. In the light/dark test, male zebrafish showed increased anxiety by spending more time in the dark compartment. Hyperglycemic zebrafish showed a significant blunting of the cortisol response, indicating impaired stress regulation. Additionally, SOD activity was increased, while CAT activity was decreased, suggesting an imbalance in antioxidative defense mechanisms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The zebrafish system effectively models the negative impacts of sucrose-induced hyperglycemia, providing valuable insights into the stress mechanisms associated with type 2 diabetes. These findings demonstrate that hyperglycemia alters both endocrine stress response and antioxidant systems, potentially serving as biomarkers of systemic stress.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. Associazione Medici Diabetologi / Association of Diabetologists (AMD), Societa Italiana di Diabetologia / Italian Society of Diabetology (SID).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Minz</LastName><ForeName>Roseleena</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9549-0441</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Life Sciences, Central University of Jharkhand, Cheri- Manatu, Kamare, Ranchi, Jharkhand, 835222, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Praveen Kumar</ForeName><Initials>PK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7020-3570</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Life Sciences, Central University of Jharkhand, Cheri- Manatu, Kamare, Ranchi, Jharkhand, 835222, India. pksharma@cuj.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Diabetol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9200299</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0940-5429</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>WI4X0X7BPJ</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006854">Hydrocortisone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000975">Antioxidants</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>57-50-1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013395">Sucrose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.15.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013482">Superoxide Dismutase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.11.1.6</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002374">Catalase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015027" MajorTopicYN="N">Zebrafish</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006854" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hydrocortisone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006943" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hyperglycemia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000975" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antioxidants</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018384" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative Stress</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013395" MajorTopicYN="N">Sucrose</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013482" MajorTopicYN="N">Superoxide Dismutase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001522" MajorTopicYN="N">Behavior, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002374" MajorTopicYN="N">Catalase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003924" MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Behaviour</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cortisol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hyperglycemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SOD and CAT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sucrose</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Zebrafish</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41055720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00592-025-02585-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00592-025-02585-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mittal K, Mani RJ, Katare DP (May 2016) Type 3 diabetes: cross talk between differentially regulated proteins of type 2 diabetes mellitus and alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Sci Rep 6. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep25589</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng X et al Type 3 diabetes and metabolic reprogramming of brain neurons: causes and therapeutic strategies. Dec 01 2025 BioMed Cent Ltd. https://doi.org/10.1186/s10020-025-01101-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H et al (Jan. 2022) IDF diabetes atlas: global, regional and country-level diabetes prevalence estimates for 2021 and projections for 2045. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 183:109119. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabres.2021.109119</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong KL et al (2023) Global, regional, and national burden of diabetes from 1990 to 2021, with projections of prevalence to 2050: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021, The Lancet 402(10397): 203&#x2013;234, https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(23)01301-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu S, Yoffe P, Hills N, Lustig RH (Feb. 2013) The relationship of sugar to Population-Level diabetes prevalence: an econometric analysis of repeated Cross-Sectional data. PLoS ONE 8(2). https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0057873</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang A, Kuss O, Filla T, Schlesinger S (2021) Association between per capita sugar consumption and diabetes prevalence mediated by the body mass index: results of a global mediation analysis, Eur J Nutr, 60(4) 2121&#x2013;2129. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00394-020-02401-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y et al (2023) Dietary sugar consumption and health: umbrella review. BMJ. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj-2022-071609</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2022-071609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37793693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10548259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;iz-Ramirez A, Garcia-Campoy AH, Guti&#xe9;rrez RMP, B&#xe1;ez EVG, Flores JMM (2021) Evaluation of the antidiabetic and antihyperlipidemic activity of spondias purpurea seeds in a diabetic zebrafish model. Plants 10(7). https://doi.org/10.3390/plants10071417</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capiotti KM, Antonioli R, Kist LW, Bogo MR, Bonan CD, Da Silva RS (2014) Persistent impaired glucose metabolism in a zebrafish hyperglycemia model. Comp Biochem Physiol B Biochem Mol Biol 171(1):58&#x2013;65. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cbpb.2014.03.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cbpb.2014.03.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24704522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okazaki F et al (Dec. 2019) Microbiome alteration in type 2 diabetes mellitus model of zebrafish. Sci Rep 9(1). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-37242-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjan S, Sharma PK (Nov. 2020) Study of learning and memory in type 2 diabetic model of zebrafish (Danio rerio). Endocr Metabolic Sci 1:3&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.endmts.2020.100058</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai G, Jia J, Bereketoglu C, Yin Z, Pradhan A (2022) Sex-specific differences in zebrafish brains, Dec. 01, BioMed Central Ltd. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13293-022-00442-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorsemans AC, Lefebvre d&#x2019;hellencourt C, Ait-Arsa I, Jestin E, Meilhac O, Diotel N (Jun. 2017) Acute and chronic models of hyperglycemia in zebrafish: A method to assess the impact of hyperglycemia on neurogenesis and the biodistribution of radiolabeled molecules. J Visualized Experiments 2017(124). https://doi.org/10.3791/55203</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Audira G, Sampurna BP, Juniardi S, Liang ST, Lai YH, Hsiao CD (2018) A versatile setup for measuring multiple behavior endpoints in zebrafish. Inventions 3(4). https://doi.org/10.3390/inventions3040075</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maximino C (2018) Light/dark preference test for adult zebrafish (Danio rerio). Protoc Io. https://doi.org/10.17504/protocols.io.srfed3n</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17504/protocols.io.srfed3n</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirat O, Sternberg JR, Severi KE, Wyart C (2013) ZebraZoom: An automated program for high-throughput behavioral analysis and categorization, Front Neural Circuits, no. JUNE, Jun. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncir.2013.00107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canavello PR et al (2011) Measuring endocrine (cortisol) responses of zebrafish to stress, Neuromethods, 51: 135&#x2013;142. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-60761-953-6_11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradford MM (1976) A rapid and sensitive method for the quantitation of microgram quantities of protein utilizing the principle of protein-Dye binding</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weydert CJ, Cullen JJ (2010) Measurement of superoxide dismutase, catalase and glutathione peroxidase in cultured cells and tissue, Nat Protoc, 5(1): 51&#x2013;66. https://doi.org/10.1038/nprot.2009.197</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T, Zhang B (2016) Measurements of proline and malondialdehyde content and antioxidant enzyme activities in leaves of drought stressed cotton. Bio Protoc 6(17). https://doi.org/10.21769/bioprotoc.1913</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey P, Ramanujam R, Venkatesan G, Nagarathnam R (2019) Sodium alginate potentiates antioxidant defense and PR proteins against early blight disease caused by Alternaria solani in Solanum lycopersicum Linn., PLoS One, 14(9). https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0223216</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uthaiah CA, Devaru NC, Shivakumar NH, R. R, and, Madhunapantula SRV (Nov. 2022) Vitamin D mitigates Hyperglycemia-Induced cognition decline in Danio rerio (Zebrafish) through the activation of antioxidant mechanisms. Antioxidants 11(11). https://doi.org/10.3390/antiox11112114</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacques A, Chaaya N, Beecher K, Ali SA, Belmer A, Bartlett S (2019) The impact of sugar consumption on stress driven, emotional and addictive behaviors, Aug. 01, Elsevier Ltd. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2019.05.021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Itoh H, Tanaka M (Mar. 2022) Greedy organs hypothesis&#x2019; for sugar and salt in the pathophysiology of non-communicable diseases in relation to sodium-glucose co-transporters in the intestines and the kidney. Metabol Open 13:100169. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.metop.2022.100169</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan RR, Chan CB, Louie JCY (2022) Current WHO recommendation to reduce free sugar intake from all sources to below 10% of daily energy intake for supporting overall health is not well supported by available evidence, Jul. 01, Oxford University Press. https://doi.org/10.1093/ajcn/nqac084</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Sun H, Liu Z, Yang J, Liu Y (Dec. 2024) Association between dietary sugar intake and depression in US adults: a cross-sectional study using data from the National health and nutrition examination survey 2011&#x2013;2018. BMC Psychiatry 24(1). https://doi.org/10.1186/s12888-024-05531-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedley N, Ramirez FE Nedley depression hit hypothesis: identifying depression and its causes. Nov 01 2016 SAGE Publications Inc https://doi.org/10.1177/1559827614550779</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JJ et al (Jan. 2020) High-glucose/high-cholesterol diet in zebrafish evokes diabetic and affective pathogenesis: the role of peripheral and central inflammation, microglia and apoptosis. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry 96. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnpbp.2019.109752</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angiulli E et al (Dec. 2020) Increase in environmental temperature affects exploratory behaviour, anxiety and social preference in Danio rerio. Sci Rep 10(1). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-62331-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontana BD, Alnassar N, Parker MO (Jan. 2022) The zebrafish (Danio rerio) anxiety test battery: comparison of behavioral responses in the novel tank diving and light&#x2013;dark tasks following exposure to anxiogenic and anxiolytic compounds. Psychopharmacology 239(1):287&#x2013;296. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00213-021-05990-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherchi S et al (2020) Sex-Gender Differences in Diabetic Retinopathy, Diabetology, 1(1): 1&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.3390/diabetology1010001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middel CS, Hammes HP, Kroll J (2021) Advancing diabetic retinopathy research: Analysis of the neurovascular unit in zebrafish, Jun. 01, MDPI. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells10061313</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakstygal AM et al Zebrafish models of diabetes-related CNS pathogenesis. Jun 08 2019 Elsevier Inc https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnpbp.2018.11.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modlinska K, Chrzanowska A, Goncikowska K, Pisula W (Jan. 2023) Influence of excessive sucrose consumption on exploratory behaviour in rats&#x2014;Possible implications for the brain reward system. Behav Brain Res 436. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbr.2022.114085</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying Z et al (2018) Biglycan gene connects metabolic dysfunction with brain disorder, Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Basis Dis, 1864(12): 3679&#x2013;3687, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbadis.2018.10.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteleone AM, D&#x2019;Agostino G, Cascino G, Marciello F, Monteleone P, Maj M (2022) Cortisol awakening response in bipolar patients with comorbid type 2 diabetes mellitus. World J Biol Psychiatry 23(4):278&#x2013;286. https://doi.org/10.1080/15622975.2021.1973280</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15622975.2021.1973280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34467828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misiak B (Jan. 2020) Stress, allostatic load, and psychosis: one step forward in research but where to go next? Front Psychiatry 10. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00937</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDonald D, Wetherell MA (2019) Competition stress leads to a blunting of the cortisol awakening response in elite rowers, Front Psychol, 10. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2019.01684</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deveci O et al (Apr. 2023) Prediabetes and mild hepatosteatosis are associated with blunted cortisol response to glucagon but not to growth hormone. Ann Endocrinol (Paris) 84(2):254&#x2013;259. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ando.2022.11.003</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>