<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41742870</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1943-3670</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of periodontology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Periodontol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of bioactive membrane in alveolar ridge preservation: A double-blind randomized clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jper.70094</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This randomized controlled trial aims to evaluate alveolar ridge preservation (ARP) with or without a biologically active amnion-chorion membrane (BACM).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Thirty patients requiring tooth extraction in the esthetic zone were randomly assigned to 2 groups. Both groups underwent tooth extraction and collagenated bovine bone grafting, while the test sites received an additional BACM. Cone-beam computed tomography (CBCT) and intraoral scans (IOS) were performed before extraction and at 4 months post-extraction. Patient-reported outcomes (PROs) were assessed. The primary endpoint was the change in vertical and horizontal hard and soft tissue dimensions as measured by CBCT and clinically.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">All patients completed implant placement. CBCT measurements at 2&#xa0;mm demonstrated that control and test groups exhibited reductions in horizontal ridge width with median decreases of 1.19&#xa0;mm and 2.41&#xa0;mm, respectively, with no significant differences (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.126). For vertical height changes, the control and test groups experienced mean reductions of 0.99&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;1.08&#xa0;mm and 1.33&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.73&#xa0;mm, respectively, with no significant differences (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.250). IOS analyses showed that mean soft tissue thickness at the alveolar crest was 2.67&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.699&#xa0;mm (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.370) in the control versus 2.13&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.807&#xa0;mm (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.846) in the test group, with no significant differences (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.325).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The addition of a BACM did not improve the mean horizontal or vertical bone dimentional changes or have a measurable effect on the soft tissue outcome during ARP.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Journal of Periodontology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American Academy of Periodontology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orlowska</LastName><ForeName>Magdalena</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-0695-6273</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Periodontics and Oral Medicine, University of Michigan School of Dentistry, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saleh</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad H A</ForeName><Initials>MHA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5067-7317</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Periodontics and Oral Medicine, University of Michigan School of Dentistry, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Decker</LastName><ForeName>Ann</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7508-2096</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Periodontics and Oral Medicine, University of Michigan School of Dentistry, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Junying</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Periodontics and Oral Medicine, University of Michigan School of Dentistry, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ou</LastName><ForeName>Alice</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Periodontics and Oral Medicine, University of Michigan School of Dentistry, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zambrana</LastName><ForeName>Nataly</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5516-9810</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Periodontics and Oral Medicine, University of Michigan School of Dentistry, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nava</LastName><ForeName>Paolo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-6177-3000</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Periodontics and Oral Medicine, University of Michigan School of Dentistry, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deller</LastName><ForeName>Fernanda A da Costa</ForeName><Initials>FADC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6640-2630</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State University of Maringa, Maringa, Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Hom-Lay</ForeName><Initials>HL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4238-1799</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Periodontics and Oral Medicine, University of Michigan School of Dentistry, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Biohorizons</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Periodontol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8000345</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3492</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>In this clinical study, adults who needed a front tooth or premolar extracted and later replaced with an implant had the socket filled with the same bone graft plug but were randomly assigned to either to receive a standard collagen plug (control) or the same collagen plug covered with a biologically active amnion&#x2013;chorion membrane (test). Thirty patients completed treatment, and the researchers used 3D X&#x2010;rays (cone&#x2010;beam computed tomography [CBCT]) and clinical measurements taken at extraction and about 4 months later to track how much bone and gum tissue was lost. They also measured how well the sites healed, how much pain patients felt, whether extra grafting was needed, and how satisfied patients were. Both groups showed some normal shrinkage of the ridge over time, but the amount of horizontal and vertical bone loss and soft tissue thickness was very similar between the 2 treatments, and differences were not statistically significant. Wound healing scores and pain levels improved over time in both groups, with the BACM group looking a bit better at some time points, but again without meaningful statistical differences. The takeaway is that adding an amnion&#x2013;chorion membrane on top of a xenograft and collagen plug in these uncomplicated extraction sites did not produce clearly superior hard&#x2010; or soft&#x2010;tissue outcomes or patient&#x2010;reported experience compared with the simpler collagen plug approach.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Journal of Periodontology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American Academy of Periodontology.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bone regeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dental implants</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heterografts</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tooth extraction</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41742870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jper.70094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Atieh MA, Alsabeeha NH, Payne AG, Ali S, Faggion CMJ, Esposito M. Interventions for replacing missing teeth: alveolar ridge preservation techniques for dental implant site development. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;4:CD010176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couso&#x2010;Queiruga E, Weber HA, Garaicoa&#x2010;Pazmino C, et&#xa0;al. Influence of healing time on the outcomes of alveolar ridge preservation using a collagenated bovine bone xenograft: a randomized clinical trial. J Clin Periodontol. 2023;50:132&#x2010;146. doi:10.1111/jcpe.13744</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mealey BL, Keeling F, Palaiologou AA. Histologic wound healing in studies using different ridge preservation protocols: a review. Clin Adv Periodontics. 2024;14:52&#x2010;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barootchi S, Tavelli L, Majzoub J, Stefanini M, Wang HL, Avila&#x2010;Ortiz G. Alveolar ridge preservation: complications and cost&#x2010;effectiveness. Periodontol 2000. 2023;92:235&#x2010;262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara&#xfa;jo MG, Lindhe J. Ridge alterations following tooth extraction with and without flap elevation: an experimental study in the dog. Clin Oral Implants Res. 2009;20:545&#x2010;549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardaropoli D, Tamagnone L, Roffredo A, Gaveglio L. Evaluation of dental implants placed in preserved and nonpreserved postextraction ridges: a 12&#x2010;month postloading study. Int J Periodontics Restorative Dent. 2015;35:677&#x2010;685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Han HS, Ghanaati S, Zadeh HH, Kim S, Cho YD. Alveolar ridge preservation using a collagenated xenograft: a randomized clinical trial. Int Dent J. 2025;75:1155&#x2010;1164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barone A, Toti P, Quaranta A, et&#xa0;al. Clinical and histological changes after ridge preservation with two xenografts: preliminary results from a multicentre randomized controlled clinical trial. J Clin Periodontol. 2017;44:204&#x2010;214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canullo L, Del Fabbro M, Khijmatgar S, et&#xa0;al. Dimensional and histomorphometric evaluation of biomaterials used for alveolar ridge preservation: a systematic review and network meta&#x2010;analysis. Clin Oral Investig. 2022;26:141&#x2010;158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iasella JM, Greenwell H, Miller RL, et&#xa0;al. Ridge preservation with freeze&#x2010;dried bone allograft and a collagen membrane compared to extraction alone for implant site development: a clinical and histologic study in humans. J Periodontol. 2003;74(7):990&#x2010;999. doi:10.1902/jop.2003.74.7.990</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook DC, Mealey BL. Histologic comparison of healing following tooth extraction with ridge preservation using two different xenograft protocols. J Periodontol. 2013;84:585&#x2010;594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siu TL, Dukka H, Saleh MHA, et&#xa0;al. Flap versus flapless alveolar ridge preservation: a clinical and histological single&#x2010;blinded, randomized controlled trial. J Periodontol. 2023;94:184&#x2010;192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go YY, Kim SE, Cho GJ, Chae SW, Song JJ. Differential effects of amnion and chorion membrane extracts on osteoblast&#x2010;like cells due to the different growth factor composition of the extracts. PLoS One. 2017;12:e0182716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashraf H, Font K, Powell C, Schurr M. Antimicrobial activity of an amnion&#x2010;chorion membrane to oral microbes. Int J Dent. 2019;2019:1269534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiany F, Moloudi F. Amnion membrane as a novel barrier in the treatment of intrabony defects: a controlled clinical trial. Int J Oral Maxillofac Implants. 2015;30:639&#x2010;647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miki T, Lehmann T, Cai H, Stolz DB, Strom SC. Stem cell characteristics of amniotic epithelial cells. Stem Cells. 2005;23:1549&#x2010;1559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Y, Hoffman T, Singh&#x2010;Varma A, et&#xa0;al. Antimicrobial peptides secreted from human cryopreserved viable amniotic membrane contribute to its antibacterial activity. Sci Rep. 2017;7:13722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Kedige SD, Jain K. Amnion and chorion membranes: potential stem cell reservoir with wide applications in periodontics. Int J Biomater. 2015;2015:274082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askar H, Di Gianfilippo R, Ravida A, Tattan M, Majzoub J, Wang HL. Incidence and severity of postoperative complications following oral, periodontal, and implant surgeries: a retrospective study. J Periodontol. 2019;90:1270&#x2010;1278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen PY, Qin L, Barnes C, et&#xa0;al. FGF regulates TGF&#x2010;&#x3b2; signaling and endothelial&#x2010;to&#x2010;mesenchymal transition via control of let&#x2010;7 miRNA expression. Cell Rep. 2012;2:1684&#x2010;1696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wetzell B, Ork B, Softic D, et&#xa0;al. Characterization of a full&#x2010;thickness decellularized and lyophilized human placental membrane for clinical applications. Int Wound J. 2024;21:e14888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhide VM, Tenenbaum HC. Treatment of gingival fenestration with a double pedicle flap approach and dehydrated amnion&#x2010;chorion membrane: a case report. Clin Adv Periodontics. 2020;10:200&#x2010;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan M, Prakasam S, Bain C, Ghoneima A, Liu SS. A randomized split&#x2010;mouth clinical trial on effectiveness of amnion&#x2010;chorion membranes in alveolar ridge preservation: a clinical, radiologic, and morphometric study. Int J Oral Maxillofac Implants. 2017;32:1389&#x2010;1398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tonetti MS, Sanz M, Avila&#x2010;Ortiz G, et&#xa0;al. Relevant domains, core outcome sets and measurements for implant dentistry clinical trials: the Implant Dentistry Core Outcome Set and Measurement (ID&#x2010;COSM) international consensus report. J Clin Periodontol. 2023;50 Suppl 25:5&#x2010;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz KF, Moher D, Altman DG. Consort. Guidelines for Reporting Health Research: A User's Manual. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.; 2014:80&#x2010;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silness J, Loe H. Periodontal disease in pregnancy. II. correlation between oral hygiene and periodontal condtion. Acta Odontol Scand. 1964;22:121&#x2010;135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu SJ, Sarnachiaro GO, Hochman MN, Tarnow DP. Subclassification and clinical management of extraction sockets with labial dentoalveolar dehiscence defects. Compend Contin Educ Dent. 2015;36(7):516, 518&#x2010;520, 522 passim.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Leary TJ, Drake RB, Naylor JE. The plaque control record. J Periodontol. 1972;43:38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;e H. The gingival index, the plaque index and the retention index systems. J Periodontol. 1967;38(6):610&#x2010;616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez AB, Alhachache S, Velasquez D, Chan HL. A systematic review of oral wound healing indices. PLoS One. 2024;19(2):e0290050. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0290050</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landry RG. Effectiveness of Benzydamine HC1 in the Treatment of Periodontal Post&#x2010;Surgical Patients: Faculty of Dentistry. University of Toronto; 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sculean A, Stavropoulos A, Bosshardt DD. Self&#x2010;regenerative capacity of intra&#x2010;oral bone defects. J Clin Periodontol. 2019;46(Suppl 21):70&#x2010;81. doi:10.1111/jcpe.13075</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avila&#x2010;Ortiz G, Gubler M, Romero&#x2010;Bustillos M, Nicholas CL, Zimmerman MB, Barwacz CA. Efficacy of alveolar ridge preservation: a randomized controlled trial. J Dent Res. 2020;99(4):402&#x2010;409. doi:10.1177/0022034520905660</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Weijden F, Dell'Acqua F, Slot DE. Alveolar bone dimensional changes of post&#x2010;extraction sockets in humans: a systematic review. J Clin Periodontol. 2009;36(12):1048&#x2010;1058. doi:10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;051X.2009.01482.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jambhekar S, Kernen F, Bidra AS. Clinical and histologic outcomes of socket grafting after flapless tooth extraction: a systematic review of randomized controlled clinical trials. J Prosthet Dent. 2015;113(5):371&#x2010;382. doi:10.1016/j.prosdent.2014.12.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindhe J, Cecchinato D, Donati M, Tomasi C, Liljenberg B. Ridge preservation with the use of deproteinized bovine bone mineral. Clin Oral Implants Res. 2014;25:786&#x2010;790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleh MHA, Couso&#x2010;Queiruga E, Ravida A, et&#xa0;al. Impact of the periodontal phenotype in premolar and molar sites on bone loss following full&#x2010;thickness mucoperiosteal flap: a 1&#x2010;year prospective clinical trial. J Periodontol. 2022;93(7):966&#x2010;976. doi:10.1002/JPER.21&#x2010;0591</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couso&#x2010;Queiruga E, Stuhr S, Tattan M, Chambrone L, Avila&#x2010;Ortiz G. Post&#x2010;extraction dimensional changes: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Clin Periodontol. 2021;48(1):126&#x2010;144. doi:10.1111/jcpe.13390</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>