<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41533716</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Climate-driven shifts in avocado suitability zones in India: Insights from ensemble modelling and niche hypervolume.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0338518</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0338518</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0338518</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0338518</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Avocado (Persea americana Mill.), a nutrient-rich tropical fruit, is gaining prominence in India due to rising domestic demand and export potential. However, its cultivation remains fragmented, largely confined to southern states, with limited knowledge of ecological requirements under diverse agro-climatic zones and climate change scenarios. This study aimed to identify key bioclimatic and non-bioclimatic factors influencing avocado suitability, model its current and future distribution using ensemble species distribution modelling (ESDM), assess niche dynamics under four Representative Concentration Pathways (RCPs 2.6, 4.5, 6.0, and 8.5) for 2050 and 2070, and evaluate implications for climate-resilient agroforestry planning. Using 35 spatially thinned occurrence records and high-resolution environmental predictors, ESDM integrating eight machine learning algorithms was applied. Model performance was robust (AUC: 0.86-0.91), with Random Forest and Maxent performing best. Critical predictors included isothermality, minimum temperature of the coldest month, precipitation in the coldest quarter, urbanization, and forest cover. Current suitability hotspots were concentrated in Kerala and Tamil Nadu. Future projections under RCPs 2.6 and 6.0 indicated northward and altitudinal expansion into the Western Ghats, northeastern hills, and eastern India, whereas RCP 8.5 suggested increased fragmentation and instability. Niche analysis revealed ecological breadth expansion under low to moderate emissions, but contraction and displacement under high-emission conditions. These findings highlight scope for expanding avocado cultivation under low to moderate emissions, provided thermal and precipitation stability is maintained. The study offers a geospatial foundation for climate-smart avocado production, conservation, and policy, emphasizing the protection of climatic refugia in southern India and adaptive agroecological strategies for long-term sustainability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 G. et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G</LastName><ForeName>Karunakaran</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Fruit Crops, ICAR-Indian Institute of Horticultural Research, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mathur</LastName><ForeName>Manish</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR Central Arid Zone Research Institute, Jodhpur, Rajasthan, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>C</LastName><ForeName>Kanupriya</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1604-5401</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Fruit Crops, ICAR-Indian Institute of Horticultural Research, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M</LastName><ForeName>Senthilkumar</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central Coffee Research Institute, Coffee Research Station Post, Chikkamagaluru, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>T</LastName><ForeName>Sakthivel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Fruit Crops, ICAR-Indian Institute of Horticultural Research, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G</LastName><ForeName>Kadirvel</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-Agricultural Technology Application Research Institute, Zone VI, Guwahati, Assam, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>B M</LastName><ForeName>Murlidhara</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-Indian Institute of Horticultural Research, Central Horticultural Experimental Station, Chettalli, Kodagu, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M</LastName><ForeName>Kavino</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6789-1774</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Fruit Science, Horticultural College and Research Institute, Tamil Nadu Agricultural University, Coimbatore, TamilNadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>T K</LastName><ForeName>Hazarika</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Horticulture Aromatic and Medicinal Plants, Mizoram University, Aizawl, Mizoram, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>T</LastName><ForeName>Ruchitha</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Fruit Crops, ICAR-Indian Institute of Horticultural Research, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D027421" MajorTopicYN="Y">Persea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007194" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">India</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057231" MajorTopicYN="Y">Climate Change</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017753" MajorTopicYN="N">Ecosystem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000383" MajorTopicYN="N">Agriculture</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41533716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12803459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0338518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-40251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Galindo-Tovar ME, Ogata-Aguilar N, Arzate-Fern&#xe1;ndez AM. Some aspects of avocado (Persea americana Mill.) diversity and domestication in Mesoamerica. Genet Resour Crop Evol. 2007;55(3):441&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1007/s10722-007-9250-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10722-007-9250-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergh BO, Ellstrand NC. Taxonomy of the avocado. Calif Avocado Soc Yearb. 1986;70:135&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Morrell PL, Ashworth VETM, de la Cruz M, Clegg MT. Tracing the geographic origins of major avocado cultivars. J Hered. 2009;100(1):56&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1093/jhered/esn068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jhered/esn068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18779226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muralidhara BM, Sakthivel T, Reddy DL, Karunakaran G, Venkatravanappa V, Savadi S, et al. Genetic diversity and population structure analysis in avocado (Persea americana) accessions of India. Agric Res. 2024;1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO). FAO: FAOSTAT: Avocado Production Statistics; 2023. Available from: https://www.fao.org/faostat</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO). Resilience assessment of avocado and pineapple value chains. Rome: FAO; 2023. 10.4060/cc5967en</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4060/cc5967en</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreher ML, Davenport AJ. Hass avocado composition and potential health effects. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. 2013;53(7):738&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1080/10408398.2011.556759</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408398.2011.556759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3664913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23638933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karunakaran G, Arivalagan M, Tripathi PC, Kumar PC, Shameena A, Ruchitha T, et al. Promising high value fruit crops for northeastern region. Indian Hortic. 2023;68(6):35&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IMARC. Avocado market: Global industry trends, share, size, growth, opportunity and forecast 2024&#x2013;2032. 2024. Available from: https://www.imarcgroup.com</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathi PC, Karunakaran G, Sakthivel T, Sankar V, Senthilkumar R, Muralidhara SR. Bull Cent Hortic Exp Stn Indian Inst Hortic Res. 2014;14:xx&#x2013;xx.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murthy BNS, Sankaran M, Nitin PS. Fruit breeding in India: Achievements and way forward. Int J Innov Hortic. 2022;11(1):11&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathi PC. Status and prospects of avocado cultivation in India. Braz J Dev. 2024;10(2):e67059.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Horticulture Board (NHB). Horticultural statistics at a glance. New Delhi: Ministry of Agriculture &amp; Farmers Welfare, Government of India; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muralidhara BM, Sakthivel T, Shivashankara KS, Karunakaran G, Honnabyraiah MK, Savadi S, et al. Morpho-biochemical characterization of a unique avocado (Persia americana Mill.) accession PA-026 (IC0644455). J Hortic Sci. 2024;18(2). doi: 10.24154/jhs.v18i2.1675</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24154/jhs.v18i2.1675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agricultural and Processed Food Products Export Development Authority (APEDA). Avocado export data. 2023. Available from: https://apeda.gov.in</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Horticulture Board (NHB). Post-harvest loss estimates for fruits in India. New Delhi: NHB; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xfc;ter R, Trachsel T, Laube P, Jaisli I. Expected global suitability of coffee, cashew and avocado due to climate change. PLoS One. 2022;17(1):e0261976. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0261976</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0261976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8791496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35081123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiley AW, Schaffer B, Wolstenholme BN. The avocado: Botany, production and uses. 2nd edition. Wallingford: CABI; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-Gil JG, Garc&#xed;a CR, Morales OL. A multivariate analysis of the ecological requirements of avocado (Persea americana) and its potential distribution in Colombia. Acta Hortic. 2014;1000:755&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-Gil JG, Morales OL, Garc&#xed;a CR. Ecological zoning of avocado crops in Colombia using species distribution modeling. Agron Colomb. 2017;35(2):168&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-Gil JG, Morales OL, Garc&#xed;a CR, G&#xf3;mez JA. Current status of avocado production systems and research priorities in Colombia. J Agric Rural Dev Trop Subtrop. 2017;118(1):39&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesa RG, Pe&#xf1;aranda A. Agro-ecological zoning for avocado (Persea americana) in Antioquia, Colombia. Rev UDCA Actual Divulg Cient. 2015;18(1):209&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson AT, Sober&#xf3;n J, Pearson RG, Anderson RP, Mart&#xed;nez-Meyer E, Nakamura M. Ecological niches and geographic distributions. Princeton: Princeton University Press; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barve N, Barve V, Jim&#xe9;nez-Valverde A, Lira-Noriega A, Maher SP, Peterson AT, et al. The crucial role of the accessible area in ecological niche modeling and species distribution modeling. Ecol Model. 2011;222(11):1810&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2011.02.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2011.02.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kariuki JG. Embracing Avocado (Persea americana) Farming Among Smallholder Farmers in Rural Households in Kenya: Challenges, Opportunities and Strategies for Sustainable Growth. J Agribus Rural Dev. 2025;75(1):110&#x2013;24. doi: 10.17306/j.jard.2025.00002r1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17306/j.jard.2025.00002r1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivaraj N, Anitha K, Parameswari B, Saravanan L, Holajjer P, Bhaskar B. Potential avocado-growing region in India: An ecological niche modelling approach. J Plant Dev Sci. 2023;15(3):157&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachman S, Moat J, Hill AW, de Torre J, Scott B. Supporting Red List threat assessments with GeoCAT: geospatial conservation assessment tool. Zookeys. 2011;(150):117&#x2013;26. doi: 10.3897/zookeys.150.2109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3897/zookeys.150.2109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3234434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22207809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopi V, Ananthan M, Rani MSA, Kumar M, Jeyakuma P, Krishnamoorthy V. Correlation analysis of avocado (Persea americana Mill.) genotypes from Lower Pulney Hills of Tamil Nadu. Biol Forum Int J. 2021;13(4):468&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;oban HO, &#xd6;r&#xfc;c&#xfc; &#xd6;K, Arslan ES. MaxEnt Modeling for Predicting the Current and Future Potential Geographical Distribution of Quercus libani Olivier. Sustainability. 2020;12(7):2671. doi: 10.3390/su12072671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su12072671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiello&#x2010;Lammens ME, Boria RA, Radosavljevic A, Vilela B, Anderson RP. spThin: an R package for spatial thinning of species occurrence records for use in ecological niche models. Ecography. 2015;38(5):541&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1111/ecog.01132</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ecog.01132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zizka A, Antunes Carvalho F, Calvente A, Rocio Baez-Lizarazo M, Cabral A, Coelho JFR, et al. No one-size-fits-all solution to clean GBIF. PeerJ. 2020;8:e9916. doi: 10.7717/peerj.9916</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.9916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7528811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33062422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Tang J, Ren G, Zhao K, Wang X. Global potential distribution prediction of Xanthium italicum based on Maxent model. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):16545. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-96041-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-96041-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8368065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34400696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathur M, Mathur P. Comparative assessment of different Earth system models for habitat suitability of Cuminum cyminum (Linn.) crop: A machine learning evaluation from arid and semi-arid hot areas of India. Indian J Plant Genet Resour. 2024;37(2):316&#x2013;40. doi: 10.61949/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riahi K, Rao S, Krey V, Cho C, Chirkov V, Fischer G, et al. RCP 8.5&#x2014;A scenario of comparatively high greenhouse gas emissions. Clim Change. 2011;109(1&#x2013;2):33&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1007/s10584-011-0149-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10584-011-0149-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotrina S&#xe1;nchez A, Rojas Brice&#xf1;o NB, Bandopadhyay S, Ghosh S, Torres Guzm&#xe1;n C, Oliva M, et al. Biogeographic Distribution of Cedrela spp. Genus in Peru Using MaxEnt Modeling: A Conservation and Restoration Approach. Diversity. 2021;13(6):261. doi: 10.3390/d13060261</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/d13060261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr MKV. The water relations and irrigation requirements of avocado (persea americana mill.): a review. Ex Agric. 2013;49(2):256&#x2013;78. doi: 10.1017/s0014479712001317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/s0014479712001317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer G, Nachtergaele F, Prieler S, van Velthuizen HT, Verelst L, Wiberg D. Global agro-ecological zones assessment for agriculture (GAEZ 2008). Laxenburg: IIASA &amp; FAO; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy CM, Oakleaf JR, Theobald DM, Baruch-Mordo S, Kiesecker J. Managing the middle: A shift in conservation priorities based on the global human modification gradient. Glob Chang Biol. 2019;25(3):811&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1111/gcb.14549</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gcb.14549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30629311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy CM, Oakleaf JRD, Theobald M, Baruch-Mordo S, Kiesecker J. Documentation for the global human modification of terrestrial systems. Palisades, NY: NASA Socioeconomic Data and Applications Center (SEDAC); 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathur M, Sundaramoorthy S. Woody perennial diversity at various landforms of the five agro-climatic zones of Rajasthan, India. In: Ramawat K, editor. Biodiversity and chemotaxonomy. Vol. 24. Springer; 2019. p. xx&#x2013;xx.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuanmu M, Jetz W. A global 1&#x2010;km consensus land&#x2010;cover product for biodiversity and ecosystem modelling. Global Ecology and Biogeography. 2014;23(9):1031&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1111/geb.12182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/geb.12182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khadanga SS, Dar AA, Jaiswal N, Dash PK, Jayakumar S. Elevation patterns of tree diversity, composition and stand structure in Mahendragiri Hill Forest, Eastern Ghats of Odisha, India. J Asia-Pac Biodivers. 2023;16(3):391&#x2013;405. doi: 10.1016/j.japb.2023.04.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.japb.2023.04.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieben EJJ, Steenhuisen S, Vidal JD, Martin G, le Roux PC. Modelling landscape-scale occurrences of common grassland species in a topographically complex mountainous environment. Plant Ecol. 2024;225(10):1095&#x2013;108. doi: 10.1007/s11258-024-01457-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11258-024-01457-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simoes M, Romero-Alvarez D, Nu&#xf1;ez-Penichet C, Jim&#xe9;nez L, E. Cobos M. General Theory and Good Practices in Ecological Niche Modeling: A Basic Guide. Biodiv Inf. 2020;15(2):67&#x2013;8. doi: 10.17161/bi.v15i2.13376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17161/bi.v15i2.13376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osorio&#x2010;Olvera L, Lira&#x2010;Noriega A, Sober&#xf3;n J, Peterson AT, Falconi M, Contreras&#x2010;D&#xed;az RG, et al. ntbox: An r package with graphical user interface for modelling and evaluating multidimensional ecological niches. Methods Ecol Evol. 2020;11(10):1199&#x2013;206. doi: 10.1111/2041-210x.13452</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/2041-210x.13452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathur M, Mathur P. Predictive sustainability analysis of installed commercial solar energy parks: a temporal and spatial machine learning assessment. Arab J Geosci. 2025;18(2). doi: 10.1007/s12517-025-12195-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-025-12195-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt S, Pouteau R, Justeau D, de Boissieu F, Birnbaum P. ssdm: An r package to predict distribution of species richness and composition based on stacked species distribution models. Methods Ecol Evol. 2017;8(12):1795&#x2013;803. doi: 10.1111/2041-210x.12841</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/2041-210x.12841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thuiller W, Lavorel S, Ara&#xfa;jo MB, Sykes MT, Prentice IC. Climate change threats to plant diversity in Europe. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2005;102(23):8245&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1073/pnas.0409902102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0409902102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1140480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15919825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathur M, Mathur P. Ecological niche modelling of Tecomella undulata (Sm.) Seem: an endangered (A2a) tree species from arid and semi-arid environment imparts multiple ecosystem services. Trop Ecol. 2023;65(1):59&#x2013;80. doi: 10.1007/s42965-023-00311-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42965-023-00311-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathur P, Mathur M. Machine learning ensemble species distribution modeling of an endangered arid land tree Tecomella undulata: a global appraisal. Arab J Geosci. 2023;16(2). doi: 10.1007/s12517-023-11229-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-023-11229-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajamanickam V, Babel H, Montano-Herrera L, Ehsani A, Stiefel F, Haider S, et al. About Model Validation in Bioprocessing. Processes. 2021;9(6):961. doi: 10.3390/pr9060961</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr9060961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan AM, Li Q, Saqib Z, Khan N, Habib T, Khalid N, et al. MaxEnt Modelling and Impact of Climate Change on Habitat Suitability Variations of Economically Important Chilgoza Pine (Pinus gerardiana Wall.) in South Asia. Forests. 2022;13(5):715. doi: 10.3390/f13050715</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f13050715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright AJ, Wardle DA, Callaway R, Gaxiola A. The Overlooked Role of Facilitation in Biodiversity Experiments. Trends Ecol Evol. 2017;32(5):383&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1016/j.tree.2017.02.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tree.2017.02.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28283253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaky E, Nolan V, Alatawi A, Gilbert F. A comparison between Ensemble and MaxEnt species distribution modelling approaches for conservation: A case study with Egyptian medicinal plants. Ecol Inform. 2020;60:101150. doi: 10.1016/j.ecoinf.2020.101150</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoinf.2020.101150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathur M, Mathur P, Purohit H. Ecological niche modelling of a critically endangered species Commiphora wightii (Arn.) Bhandari using bioclimatic and non-bioclimatic variables. Ecol Process. 2023;12(1). doi: 10.1186/s13717-023-00423-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13717-023-00423-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thuiller W, Lafourcade B, Engler R, Ara&#xfa;jo MB. BIOMOD &#x2013; a platform for ensemble forecasting of species distributions. Ecography. 2009;32(3):369&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0587.2008.05742.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0587.2008.05742.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elith J, Leathwick JR. Species Distribution Models: Ecological Explanation and Prediction Across Space and Time. Annu Rev Ecol Evol Syst. 2009;40(1):677&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1146/annurev.ecolsys.110308.120159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.ecolsys.110308.120159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marmion M, Parviainen M, Luoto M, Heikkinen RK, Thuiller W. Evaluation of consensus methods in predictive species distribution modelling. Divers Distrib. 2008;15(1):59&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1111/j.1472-4642.2008.00491.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1472-4642.2008.00491.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guisan A, Thuiller W, Zimmermann NE. Habitat suitability and distribution models: With applications in R. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapira O, Chernoivanov S, Neuberger I, Levy S, Rubinovich L. Physiological Characterization of Young &#x201c;Hass&#x201d; Avocado Plant Leaves Following Exposure to High Temperatures and Low Light Intensity. Plants (Basel). 2021;10(8):1562. doi: 10.3390/plants10081562</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants10081562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8400502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34451607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzatzani T-T, Morianou G, T&#xfc;l S, Kourgialas NN. Air Temperature as a Key Indicator of Avocado (Cvs. Fuerte, Zutano, Hass) Maturation Time in Mediterranean Climate Areas: The Case of Western Crete in Greece. Agriculture. 2023;13(7):1342. doi: 10.3390/agriculture13071342</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture13071342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De la Vega-Rivera A, Merino-P&#xe9;rez L. Socio-Environmental Impacts of the Avocado Boom in the Meseta Pur&#xe9;pecha, Michoac&#xe1;n, Mexico. Sustainability. 2021;13(13):7247. doi: 10.3390/su13137247</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su13137247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lilli MA, Efstathiou D, Koukianaki EA, Paranychianakis N, Nikolaidis NP. Optimizing the water-ecosystem-food nexus of avocado plantations. Front Water. 2024;6. doi: 10.3389/frwa.2024.1412146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frwa.2024.1412146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee A, Jhariya MK, Yadav SK, Khan N, Raj A, Meena RS, et al. Climate Change Vulnerability and Agroecosystem Services. In: Sustainable Intensification for Agroecosystem Services and Management. Springer Singapore; 2021, p. 163&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1007/978-981-16-3207-5_6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-16-3207-5_6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath AJ, Kumar R, Devi NB, Rocky P, Giri K, Sahoo UK, et al. Agroforestry land suitability analysis in the Eastern Indian Himalayan region. Environ Chall. 2021;4:100199. doi: 10.1016/j.envc.2021.100199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envc.2021.100199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demb&#xe9;l&#xe9; JB, Dimobe K, Konda B, Emmanuel Traor&#xe9; IC, Boussim IJ. Modelling the current and future geographical distribution of Combretum glutinosum Perr. ex DC. Under climate change in Burkina Faso: Future challenges and conservation opportunities. J Nat Conserv. 2025;86:126911. doi: 10.1016/j.jnc.2025.126911</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnc.2025.126911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madhavan AP, Bhat K, Kasinathan S, Mudappa D, Page N, Raman TRS. Distribution model predicts climate-related range alteration or extinction of eleven threatened tropical rainforest trees in the Western Ghats. bioRxiv. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashwini K, Sil BS. Impacts of Land Use and Land Cover Changes on Land Surface Temperature over Cachar Region, Northeast India&#x2014;A Case Study. Sustainability. 2022;14(21):14087. doi: 10.3390/su142114087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su142114087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathore P, Roy A, Karnatak H. Predicting the future of species assemblages under climate and land use land cover changes in Himalaya: A geospatial modelling approach. Clim Change Ecol. 2022;3:100048. doi: 10.1016/j.ecochg.2022.100048</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecochg.2022.100048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma MK, Ram B, Chawla A. Ensemble modelling under multiple climate change scenarios predicts reduction in highly suitable range of habitats of Dactylorhiza hatagirea (D.Don) Soo in Himachal Pradesh, western Himalaya. South Afr J Bot. 2023;154:203&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1016/j.sajb.2022.12.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sajb.2022.12.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thampan J, Srivastava J, Saraf PN, Samal P. Habitat distribution modelling to identify areas of high conservation value under climate change for an endangered arid land tree Tecomella undulata. J Arid Environ. 2025;227:105317. doi: 10.1016/j.jaridenv.2025.105317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaridenv.2025.105317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S, Verma S. Ensemble modeling to predict the impact of future climate change on the global distribution of Olea europaea subsp. cuspidata. Front For Glob Change. 2022;5. doi: 10.3389/ffgc.2022.977691</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/ffgc.2022.977691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aravind CK, Priti H, Harikrishnan S, Ravi C, Mapping Malabar Tree Toad Programme, Gururaja KV. Revisiting current distribution and future habitat suitability models for the endemic Malabar Tree Toad (Pedostibes tuberculosus) using citizen science data. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):18856. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-60785-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-60785-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11324762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39143090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhyani A, Kadaverugu R, Nautiyal BP, Nautiyal MC. Predicting the potential distribution of a critically endangered medicinal plant Lilium polyphyllum in Indian Western Himalayan Region. Reg Environ Change. 2021;21(2). doi: 10.1007/s10113-021-01763-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10113-021-01763-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pramanik M, Paudel U, Mondal B, Chakraborti S, Deb P. Predicting climate change impacts on the distribution of the threatened Garcinia indica in the Western Ghats, India. Clim Risk Manag. 2018;19:94&#x2013;105. doi: 10.1016/j.crm.2017.11.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.crm.2017.11.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chhetri PK, Gaddis KD, Cairns DM. Predicting the Suitable Habitat of Treeline Species in the Nepalese Himalayas Under Climate Change. Mount Res Dev. 2018;38(2):153. doi: 10.1659/mrd-journal-d-17-00071.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1659/mrd-journal-d-17-00071.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell A, Kapos V, Scharlemann JPW, Bubb P, Chenery A, Coad L, et al. Review of the literature on the links between biodiversity and climate change: Impacts, adaptation and mitigation. Montreal: Secretariat of the Convention on Biological Diversity; 2009. (Technical Series No. 42).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tawde SA, Singh C. Investigation of orographic features influencing spatial distribution of rainfall over the Western Ghats of India using satellite data. Int J Climatol. 2014;35(9):2280&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1002/joc.4146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/joc.4146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjitkar S, Sujakhu NM, Merz J, Kindt R, Xu J, Matin MA, et al. Suitability Analysis and Projected Climate Change Impact on Banana and Coffee Production Zones in Nepal. PLoS One. 2016;11(9):e0163916. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0163916</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0163916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5045210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27689354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chitale VS, Behera MD, Roy PS. Future of endemic flora of biodiversity hotspots in India. PLoS One. 2014;9(12):e115264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4264876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25501852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das A, Nagendra H, Anand M, Bunyan M. Topographic and Bioclimatic Determinants of the Occurrence of Forest and Grassland in Tropical Montane Forest-Grassland Mosaics of the Western Ghats, India. PLoS One. 2015;10(6):e0130566. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0130566</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0130566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4488301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26121353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh B, Jeganathan C, Rathore VS, Behera MD, Singh CP, Roy PS, et al. Resilience of the Central Indian Forest Ecosystem to Rainfall Variability in the Context of a Changing Climate. Remote Sens. 2021;13(21):4474. doi: 10.3390/rs13214474</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs13214474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee A, Jhariya MK, Yadav S, Mechergui T. Climate change vulnerability and agro-ecosystem services. In: Jhariya MK, Banerjee A, Meena RS, Kumar S, Raj A, editors. Sustainable intensification for agroecosystem services and management. Springer; 2021. p. xx&#x2013;xx.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petitpierre B, Kueffer C, Broennimann O, Randin C, Daehler C, Guisan A. Climatic niche shifts are rare among terrestrial plant invaders. Science. 2012;335(6074):1344&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1126/science.1215933</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1215933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22422981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Tao Y, Huang W, Wang B, Liu S, Cong B, et al. Assessment of future habitat suitability and ecological vulnerability of Collichthys at population and species level. BMC Ecol Evol. 2025;25(1):1. doi: 10.1186/s12862-024-02339-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12862-024-02339-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11694423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39743516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>