<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41505728</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1940-5480</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of the American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Am Acad Orthop Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Further Displacement After Initial Nonsurgical Treatment of Minimally Displaced Olecranon Fractures in Children.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e1021</StartPage><EndPage>e1027</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e1021-e1027</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5435/JAAOS-D-25-00821</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Pediatric olecranon fractures are uncommon periarticular injuries with unclear treatment guidelines for varying magnitudes of intra-articular displacement. Similar to other pediatric elbow fractures, minimally displaced fractures are treated nonsurgically, and potential for further displacement following nonsurgical treatment exists. This study assesses the incidence and risk factors for further displacement after nonsurgical treatment of minimally displaced pediatric olecranon fractures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective review was conducted on patients aged 0 to 15 years with isolated olecranon fractures treated nonsurgically at a single institution. Radiographic measurements of intra-articular and nonarticular displacement on lateral views were collected with follow-up imaging done until confirmed radiographic union. Patients with more than 1-mm change in displacement on the articular side during treatment were identified. Fractures were classified at specified locations, including zone 1 (proximal 1/3), zone 2 (middle 1/3), and zone 3 (distal 1/3).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 64 patients met inclusion criteria, 42 (65.6%) were males, and the average age at injury was 8.25 years. Casting without closed reduction was the definitive treatment method in 59 patients (92.2%). Of the fractures observed, 30 (46.9%) occurred in zone 1, followed by 23 patients (35.9%) in zone 2 and 11 patients (17.2%) in zone 3. Interval displacement was seen in 14 patients at follow-up visits (21.9%) with greater body mass index observed in the redisplacement group ( P = 0.053). Change in management was required in two patients (3.1%). Displacement of &#x2265;1 mm at initial evaluation did not affect the rate of subsequent displacement at follow-up visit ( P = 0.571). Neither fracture zone nor fracture configuration were statistically significant for change in fracture displacement.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Further displacement was observed in 20% of minimally displaced olecranon fractures regardless of the zone and magnitude of initial displacement with a small percentage leading to a change in the management. Close radiographic follow-up for nonsurgically treated olecranon fractures is recommended.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by the American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siddabattula</LastName><ForeName>Rohit</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9568-5628</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Orthopaedics, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Habib</LastName><ForeName>Feross</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pereira</LastName><ForeName>Daniel E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wall</LastName><ForeName>Lindley B</ForeName><Initials>LB</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goldfarb</LastName><ForeName>Charles A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Najera Saltos</LastName><ForeName>Diego</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hosseinzadeh</LastName><ForeName>Pooya</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Am Acad Orthop Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9417468</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1067-151X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056740" MajorTopicYN="Y">Olecranon Process</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014458" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ulna Fractures</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002370" MajorTopicYN="N">Casts, Surgical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000092464" MajorTopicYN="N">Elbow Injuries</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004551" MajorTopicYN="N">Elbow Joint</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000092470" MajorTopicYN="N">Olecranon Fracture</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41505728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5435/JAAOS-D-25-00821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124635-990000000-01587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Evans MC, Graham HK: Olecranon fractures in children: Part 1: A clinical review; part 2: A new classification and management algorithm. J Pediatr Orthop 1999;19:559-569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landin LA, Danielsson LG: Elbow fractures in children. An epidemiological analysis of 589 cases. Acta Orthop Scand 1986;57:309-312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Maio F, Gorgolini G, Caterini A, Luciano C, Covino D, Farsetti P: Treatment of olecranon fractures in childhood: A systematic review. Front Pediatr 2022;10:1046243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persiani P, Ranaldi FM, Graci J, et al.: Isolated olecranon fractures in children affected by osteogenesis imperfecta type I treated with single screw or tension band wiring system: Outcomes and pitfalls in relation to bone mineral density. Medicine (Baltimore) 2017;96:e6766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caterini R, Farsetti P, D'Arrigo C, Ippolito E: Fractures of the olecranon in children. Long-term follow-up of 39 cases. J Pediatr Orthop B 2002;11:320-328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang W, Zhang X, Sun D, Jin S, Chen J, Li Y: Outcomes of olecranon fractures in adolescents: Comparison of tension band wiring and Herbert screw fixations. Front Pediatr 2023;11:1269628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holme TJ, Karbowiak M, Arnander M, Gelfer Y: Paediatric olecranon fractures: A systematic review. EFORT Open Rev 2020;5:280-288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkins CA, Busch MT, Christino MA, et al.: Olecranon fractures in children and adolescents: Outcomes based on fracture fixation. J Child Orthop 2018;12:497-501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed W, Waseem M: Elbow fractures overview. StatPearls. Treasure Island, FL, vol 7. StatPearls Publishing, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newell RL: Olecranon fractures in children. Injury 1975;7:33-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews JG: Fractures of the olecranon in children. Injury 1980;12:207-212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zale C, Winthrop ZA, Hennrikus W: Rate of displacement for Jakob type 1 lateral condyle fractures treated with a cast. J Child Orthop 2018;12:117-122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirker ME, Weinberg AM, H&#xf6;llwarth ME, Haberlik A: Subsequent displacement of initially nondisplaced and minimally displaced fractures of the lateral humeral condyle in children. J Trauma 2005;58:1202-1207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knapik DM, Gilmore A, Liu RW: Conservative management of minimally displaced (&#x2264;2 mm) fractures of the lateral humeral condyle in pediatric patients: A systematic review. J Pediatr Orthop 2017;37:e83-e87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badelon O, Bensahel H, Mazda K, Vie P: Lateral humeral condylar fractures in children: A report of 47 cases. J Pediatr Orthop 1988;8:31-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bast SC, Hoffer MM, Aval S: Nonoperative treatment for minimally and nondisplaced lateral humeral condyle fractures in children. J Pediatr Orthop 1998;18:448-450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsson MK, Hasserius R, Karlsson C, Besjakov J, Josefsson PO: Fractures of the olecranon during growth: A 15-25-year follow-up. J Pediatr Orthop B 2002;11:251-255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corradin M, Marengo L, Andreacchio A, et al.: Outcome of isolated olecranon fractures in skeletally immature patients: Comparison of open reduction and tension band wiring fixation versus closed reduction and percutaneous screw fixation. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol 2016;26:469-476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalbitz M, Weber B, Lackner I, Beer M, Pressmar J: Olecranon fractures in children: Treatment of a rare entity. Eur J Trauma Emerg Surg 2022;48:3429-3437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaddy BC, Strecker WB, Schoenecker PL: Surgical treatment of displaced olecranon fractures in children. J Pediatr Orthop 1997;17:321-324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schenker ML, Mauck RL, Ahn J, Mehta S: Pathogenesis and prevention of posttraumatic osteoarthritis after intra-articular fracture. J Am Acad Orthop Surg 2014;22:20-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson DD, Marsh JL, Brown TD: The pathomechanical etiology of post-traumatic osteoarthritis following intraarticular fractures. Iowa Orthop J 2011;31:1-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abzug JM, Dua K, Kozin SH, Herman MJ: Current concepts in the treatment of lateral condyle fractures in children. J Am Acad Orthop Surg 2020;28:e9-e19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borrelli J Jr, Goldfarb C, Catalano L, Evanoff BA: Assessment of articular fragment displacement in acetabular fractures: A comparison of computerized tomography and plain radiographs. J Orthop Trauma 2002;16:449-457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfarb CA, Rudzki JR, Catalano LW, Hughes M, Borrelli J Jr: Fifteen-year outcome of displaced intra-articular fractures of the distal radius. J Hand Surg Am 2006;31:633-639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiegand L, Bernstein J, Ahn J: Fractures in brief: Olecranon fractures. Clin Orthop Relat Res 2012;470:3637-3641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubik J, Schneider P, Buckley R, Korley R, Duffy P, Martin R: Evaluating the utility of the lateral elbow radiograph in central articular olecranon reduction: An anatomic and radiographic study. J Orthop Trauma 2018;32:e81-e85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voto SJ, Weiner DS, Leighley B: Redisplacement after closed reduction of forearm fractures in children. J Pediatr Orthop 1990;10:79-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younger AS, Tredwell SJ, Mackenzie WG: Factors affecting fracture position at cast removal after pediatric forearm fracture. J Pediatr Orthop 1997;17:332-336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang JJ, Chang JH, Lin KY, Lin LC, Kuo CL: Redisplacement of diaphyseal fractures of the forearm after closed reduction in children: A retrospective analysis of risk factors. J Orthop Trauma 2012;26:110-116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eismann EA, Parikh SN, Jain VV: Rereduction for redisplacement of both-bone forearm shaft fractures in children. J Pediatr Orthop 2016;36:405-409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera AE, Cummings JL, Pereira DE, Oladeji AK, Landau AJ, Hosseinzadeh P: Displaced Tibia fractures in adolescents: Closed reduction and casting versus flexible intramedullary nails. J Pediatr Orthop 2023;43:7-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummings JL, Rivera AE, Pereira DE, Oladeji AK, Landau AJ, Hosseinzadeh P: Nonoperative management of closed displaced Tibia shaft fractures in patients under 18 years of age: Low failure rate. J Pediatr Orthop 2022;42:421-426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perhomaa M, St&#xf6;ckell M, Pokka T, Lieber J, Niinim&#xe4;ki J, Sinikumpu JJ: Clinical Follow-Up without radiographs is sufficient after Most nonoperatively treated distal radius fractures in children. Children (Basel) 2023;10:339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molokwu B, Eraky F, Weintraub M, et al.: Are routine post-cast removal radiographs and a second Follow-up appointment necessary in the management of nondisplaced or minimally displaced distal radius fractures? J Pediatr Soc North Am 2025;11:100170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nihalani S, Bloodworth A, Frith K, Ashley P, Williams KA, Conklin MJ: Utility of follow-up radiographs in type 1 supracondylar humerus fractures. J Pediatr Orthop 2024;44:e530-e535.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim AE, Chi H, Kammen B, Livingston K, Zapala M, Swarup I: Utility of fast MRIs in pediatric elbow injuries. J Pediatr Soc North Am 2024;7:100026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varga M, Papp S, Kassai T, Bodzay T, G&#xe1;ti N, Pint&#xe9;r S: Standardized sonographic examination of pediatric elbow injuries is an effective screening method and improves diagnostic efficiency. Injury 2021;52(suppl 1):S25-S30.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>