<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41868948</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1943-8141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of translational research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Transl Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Differential impact of hemiplegia severity stratification on post-hemiarthroplasty dislocation in elderly intertrochanteric fracture patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1473</StartPage><EndPage>1488</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1473-1488</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.62347/YANN5570</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the impact of hemiplegia due to cerebral infarction sequelae on postoperative dislocation after hemiarthroplasty (HHA) in elderly patients with intertrochanteric fractures, identify associated risk factors, and compare dislocation risks between moderate-to-severe and mild hemiplegia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We retrospectively analyzed 305 patients aged &#x2265;70 years with intertrochanteric fractures who underwent HHA from January 2020 to May 2023. Inclusion criteria required confirmed cerebral infarction with hemiplegia, Evans-Jensen Type III/IV fracture, and &#x2265;1-year follow-up. Postoperative dislocation was diagnosed radiographically, and preoperative motor dysfunction was assessed by the Fugl-Meyer Scale (mild &#x2265;22, moderate-to-severe &lt;22). Statistical analyses included chi-square and t-tests, Lasso regression, and logistic regression. A risk prediction model was developed and its discriminative capacity assessed by ROC analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Dislocation occurred in 81 patients (26.6%). Significant factors included age &#x2265;75 years, disease duration &#x2265;6 months, fall-related injury, preoperative motor dysfunction, Evans-Jensen Type IV, diabetes mellitus, adverse lifestyle habits, inadequate nursing care, and posterolateral approach (all P&lt;0.05). Multivariate analysis identified age (OR=3.164), preoperative motor dysfunction (OR=2.695), diabetes (OR=2.501), adverse lifestyle (OR=2.181), inadequate nursing care (OR=4.276), and posterolateral approach (OR=3.216) as independent predictors. In moderate-to-severe hemiplegia, age and diabetes were risk factors, whereas in mild hemiplegia, fall-related injury and diabetes predominated. The prediction model showed good performance (AUC=0.811; sensitivity 77.8%, specificity 71.9%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Hemiplegia from cerebral infarction sequelae significantly increases dislocation risk after HHA in elderly intertrochanteric fracture patients. Independent risk factors vary by hemiplegia severity, and the proposed risk model may aid preoperative risk stratification and clinical decision-making.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>AJTR Copyright &#xa9; 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Xinxing</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Trauma, Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital Affiliated to Northwest University No. 777 Xitai Road, High Tech Zone, Xi'an 710100, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qu</LastName><ForeName>Lijuan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Xijing Hospital, Air Force Medical University No. 127, Changle West Road, Xincheng District, Xi'an 710032, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duan</LastName><ForeName>Yonghong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery, Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital Affiliated to Northwest University No. 777 Xitai Road, High Tech Zone, Xi'an 710100, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Transl Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101493030</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1943-8141</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebral infarction sequelae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dislocation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hemiarthroplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hemiplegia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intertrochanteric fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk prediction model</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41868948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13000822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62347/YANN5570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhi-Ling C, Qi L, Jun-Yong Y, Bang-Qing Y. The prevalence and risk factors of posttraumatic cerebral infarction in patients with traumatic brain injury: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Bioengineered. 2022;13:11706&#x2013;11717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9275913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35521755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rost NS, Brodtmann A, Pase MP, van Veluw SJ, Biffi A, Duering M, Hinman JD, Dichgans M. Post-stroke cognitive impairment and dementia. Circ Res. 2022;130:1252&#x2013;1271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35420911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu ZL, Shen TY, Sun Z, Li H, Shan H, Cao LL, Zhang JB. Effects of zhongfeng cutong moxibustion on motor function and corticospinal tract in the patients with motor dysfunction during the recovery period of cerebral infarction. Zhongguo Zhen Jiu. 2023;43:1358&#x2013;1362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38092532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Xu J. Comparison of proximal femoral nail antirotation and total hip arthroplasty in the treatment of femoral intertrochanteric fracture. Pak J Med Sci. 2022;38:1016&#x2013;1020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9121941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35634608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czerwonka N, Desai SS, Gupta P, Shah RP, Geller JA, Cooper HJ, Neuwirth AL. Perioperative outcomes of intramedullary nail vs hemiarthroplasty vs total hip arthroplasty for intertrochanteric fracture: an analysis of 31,519 cases. Arthroplast Today. 2024;30:101513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11531633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39492996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco JF, da Casa C, Fidalgo H, Garc&#xed;a-Iglesias MA, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Garc&#xed;a L, Bur&#xf3;n-&#xc1;lvarez I, Sa&#xf1;udo S, Garc&#xed;a-Alonso M. Effect of hip hemiarthroplasty dislocation on mortality after hip fracture surgery. Rev Esp Cir Ortop Traumatol. 2023;67:T3&#x2013;T11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36265783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimberley TJ, Plow EB. Rehabilitation drives post-stroke motor recovery. Lancet Neurol. 2025;24:373&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40157381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suethanapornkul S, Kuptniratsaikul PS, Kuptniratsaikul V, Uthensut P, Dajpratha P, Wongwisethkarn J. Post stroke shoulder subluxation and shoulder pain: a cohort multicenter study. J Med Assoc Thai. 2008;91:1885&#x2013;1892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19133525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stolzenberg D, Siu G, Cruz E. Current and future interventions for glenohumeral subluxation in hemiplegia secondary to stroke. Top Stroke Rehabil. 2012;19:444&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22982832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslanov VA, Linnik SA, Ponomarenko GN, Gumanenko EK, Kucheev IO, Slabospitskii MA, Romashov PP, Shtanko VA, Luzanov AA, Kovalchuk GL. Optimization of rehabilitation of elderly and senile patients with primary traumatic dislocation of the shoulder. Adv Gerontol. 2022;35:429&#x2013;434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36169372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YS, Kim DS, Jung JW, Jo YH, Lee CH, Lee BG. Risk factors of loss of reduction after acromioclavicular joint dislocation treated with a hook plate. J Orthop Traumatol. 2023;24:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10039153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36961582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charissoux JL, Asloum Y, Marcheix PS. Surgical management of recurrent dislocation after total hip arthroplasty. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2014;100(Suppl):S25&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24434366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonough CM, Harris-Hayes M, Kristensen MT, Overgaard JA, Herring TB, Kenny AM, Mangione KK. Physical therapy management of older adults with hip fracture. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2021;51:CPG1&#x2013;CPG81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33522384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pratson L, Pekas DR, Kilinc M, Patel N, Moskal JT, Adrados M. Risk factors for dislocation after direct anterior total hip arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty. 2025;40:S265&#x2013;S269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40473053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou YM, Raman N, Proietti T, Arnold J, Pathak P, Pont-Esteban D, Nuckols K, Rishe K, Doshi-Velez F, Lin D, Walsh C. Estimating upper extremity fugl-meyer assessment scores from reaching motions using wearable sensors. IEEE J Biomed Health Inform. 2025;29:4134&#x2013;4146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40031831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bue M, Jakobsen SS, Barckman J, T&#xe1;bori-Jensen S. Dislocation rate, revisions and other complications of primary cemented hemiarthroplasty for displaced femoral neck fractures: a single-center cohort study of 743 unselected hips with a mean 2.7-year follow-up. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2022;142:3797&#x2013;3802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34779885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jobory A, K&#xe4;rrholm J, Hansson S, &#xc5;kesson K, Rogmark C. Dislocation of hemiarthroplasty after hip fracture is common and the risk is increased with posterior approach: result from a national cohort of 25,678 individuals in the Swedish Hip Arthroplasty Register. Acta Orthop. 2021;92:413&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8381924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33821752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Liu H, Zhu Y, Yan L, Li JJ, Zhao B. Risk factors with multilevel evidence for dislocation in patients with femoral neck fractures after hip hemiarthroplasty: a systematic review. Indian J Orthop. 2020;54:795&#x2013;804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7573085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33133402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fakler JKM, Rositzka M, Schopow N, Roth A, Zajonz D, Ghanem M, Kleber C, Osterhoff G. Factors associated with dislocation after bipolar hemiarthroplasty through an (antero-)lateral approach in elderly patients with a femoral neck fracture: a retrospective cohort study with a nested case-control subanalysis of radiographic parameters. Eur J Trauma Emerg Surg. 2022;48:3981&#x2013;3987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9532330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35355090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edelstein AI, Dillingham TR, McGinley EL, Pezzin LE. Hemiarthroplasty versus total hip arthroplasty for femoral neck fracture in elderly patients: twelve-month risk of revision and dislocation in an instrumental variable analysis of medicare data. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2023;105:1695&#x2013;1702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10609704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37678258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Tekaya A, Rezgui S, Tbini H, Bellil M, Bouden S, Rouached L, Tekaya R, Mahmoud I, Saidane O, Abdelmoula L. Risk factors for atlantoaxial dislocation in rheumatoid arthritis: a comparative study. Musculoskeletal Care. 2023;21:592&#x2013;599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36300878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi N, Mankar S, Deshkmukh S, Harkare VV. Outcomes of osteosynthesis versus hemiarthroplasty in elderly patients with Arbeitsgemeinschaft Fur Osteosynthesefragen-Orthopedic Trauma Association (AO-OTA) 31A2 hip fractures. Cureus. 2023;15:e39795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10313342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37398806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apinyankul R, Satravaha Y, Mokmongkolkul K, Phruetthiphat OA. Comparison of dislocation and outcome between piriformis-sparing and conventional posterior approach after bipolar hemiarthroplasty for femoral neck fracture in patients over 60 years. J Arthroplasty. 2023;38:732&#x2013;736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36273711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles T, Bloemers N, Kapanci B, Jayankura M. Complication rates after direct anterior vs posterior approach for hip hemiarthroplasty in elderly individuals with femoral neck fractures. World J Orthop. 2024;15:22&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10824065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38293256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page BJ, Parsons MS, Lee JH, Dennison JG, Hammonds KP, Brennan KL, Lee Brennan M, Lee Stahl D. Surgical approach and dislocation risk after hemiarthroplasty in geriatric patients with femoral neck fracture with and without cognitive impairments-does cognitive impairment influence dislocation risk? J Orthop Trauma. 2023;37:450&#x2013;455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37053111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CS, Pai YW, Lin CH, Lee IT, Chen HH, Chang MH. Diabetic peripheral neuropathy: age-stratified glycemic control. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2024;15:1377923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11061506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38694945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elafros MA, Andersen H, Bennett DL, Savelieff MG, Viswanathan V, Callaghan BC, Feldman EL. Towards prevention of diabetic peripheral neuropathy: clinical presentation, pathogenesis, and new treatments. Lancet Neurol. 2022;21:922&#x2013;936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10112836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36115364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen T, Gangal A, Hijab E, Barrett D, Yeung H, Cao Y, Switchenko J, Blalock TW. Postoperative surgical site infection rate in patients with diabetes following Mohs micrographic surgery: a retrospective analysis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2022;36:927&#x2013;931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12448325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35122334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostafa SM, Elebrashy I, Haddad HE, Shaker O, Razek NA, Fayed A. Association between bone turnover markers, bone mineral density, and serum osteoglycine in middle-aged men with Type 2 Diabetes mellitus. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2024;16:155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11232153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38982537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Chung YY, Baek SN, Park TG. Hemiarthroplasty through direct anterior approach for unstable femoral intertrochanteric fractures in the elderly: analysis of early cases. Hip Pelvis. 2022;34:79&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9204240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35800131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer H, Maleitzke T, Eder C, Ahmad S, St&#xf6;ckle U, Braun KF. Management of proximal femur fractures in the elderly: current concepts and treatment options. Eur J Med Res. 2021;26:86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8335457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34348796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco JF, da Casa C, Fidalgo H, Garc&#xed;a-Iglesias MA, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Garcia L, Bur&#xf3;n-Alvarez I, Sa&#xf1;udo S, Garc&#xed;a-Alonso M. Effect of hip hemiarthroplasty dislocation on mortality after hip fracture surgery. Rev Esp Cir Ortop Traumatol. 2023;67:3&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35973555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajeev A, Gravett E, Koshy G, Devalia K. The outcomes of constrained total hip arthroplasty for recurrent dislocation of hip hemiarthroplasty. Injury. 2023;54:110970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37595486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan G, Curlewis K, Aladwan R, Hook SE, Rogers BA, Ricketts DM, Stott P. Outcomes of the dislocated hip hemiarthroplasty: a multi-centre study. Hip Int. 2025;35:315&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40226873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migliorini F, Maffulli N, Trivellas M, Eschweiler J, Hildebrand F, Betsch M. Total hip arthroplasty compared to bipolar and unipolar hemiarthroplasty for displaced hip fractures in the elderly: a Bayesian network meta-analysis. Eur J Trauma Emerg Surg. 2022;48:2655&#x2013;2666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9360085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35182161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>