<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41305074</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>22</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Experimental Analysis of Seismic Damage to the Frame Structure-Site System Crossing a Reverse Fault.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">6866</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s25226866</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Buildings crossing active faults often suffer severe damage due to fault dislocation during direct-type urban earthquakes. This study employs physical model tests to systematically investigate the dynamic response mechanisms of the integrated "surface rupture zone-overburden-foundation-superstructure" system subjected to bedrock dislocation. A testing apparatus capable of simulating reverse faults with adjustable dip angles (45&#xb0; and 70&#xb0;) was developed. Using both sand and clay as representative overburden materials, the experiments simulated the processes of surface rupture evolution, foundation deformation, and structural response under varying fault dislocation magnitudes. Results indicate that the fault rupture pattern is governed by the bedrock dislocation magnitude, soil type, and fault dip angle. The failure process can be categorized into three distinct stages: initial rupture, rupture propagation, and rupture penetration. The severity and progression of structural damage are primarily determined by the building's location relative to the fault trace. Structures located entirely on the hanging wall exhibited tilting angles that remained below the specified code limit throughout the dislocation process, demonstrating behavior dominated by rigid-body translation. In contrast, buildings crossing the fault exceeded this limit even at low dislocation levels, developing significant tilt and strain concentration due to differential foundation settlement. The most severe damage occurred in high-angle dip sand sites, where the maximum structural tilt reached 5.5&#xb0;. This research elucidates the phased evolution of seismic damage in straddle-fault structures, providing experimental evidence and theoretical support for the seismic design of buildings in near-fault regions. The principal theoretical and methodological contributions are (1) developing a systematic "fault-soil-structure" testing methodology that reveals the propagation of fault dislocation through the system; (2) clarifying the distinct failure mechanisms between straddle-fault and hanging-wall structures, providing a quantitative basis for targeted seismic design; and (3) quantifying the controlling influence of fault dip angle and soil type combinations on structural damage severity, identifying high-angle dip sand sites as the most critical scenario.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Institute of Disaster Prevention, Sanhe 065201, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Building Collapse Mechanism and Disaster Prevention, China Earthquake Administration, Sanhe 065201, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Haonan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Earthquake Engineering and Engineering Vibration, Institute of Engineering Mechanics, China Earthquake Administration, Harbin 150080, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qu</LastName><ForeName>Shihang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Longnan Mineral Exploration Institute, Gansu Nonferrous Metals Geological Exploration Bureau, Longnan 742500, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jianyi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-7444-6237</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Geological Engineering, Institute of Disaster Prevention, Sanhe 065201, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Hongjuan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1802-7194</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Geophysics, China Earthquake Administration, Beijing 100081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Zhijie</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Geological Engineering, Institute of Disaster Prevention, Sanhe 065201, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Yijie</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Geological Engineering, Institute of Disaster Prevention, Sanhe 065201, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ran</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Geological Engineering, Institute of Disaster Prevention, Sanhe 065201, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. 8242022</GrantID><Agency>Beijing Natural Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 52578615</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 51608118</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cross-fault structure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dynamic response mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">isolated foundation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical model test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reverse fault</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing financial interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41305074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12656109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25226866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s25226866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kelson K.I., Kang K.H., Page W.D., Lee C.T., Cluff L.S. Representative styles of deformation along the Chelungpu fault from the 1999 Chi-Chi (Taiwan) earthquake: Geomorphic characteristics and responses of man-made structures. Bull. Seismol. Soc. Am. 2001;91:930&#x2013;952. doi: 10.1785/0120000741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1785/0120000741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin F.-T. Spatial relationship between Chenlungpu fault and damage buildings areas. J. Chin. Inst. Eng. 2000;23:465&#x2013;472. doi: 10.1080/02533839.2000.9670567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02533839.2000.9670567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulusay R., Aydan &#xd6;., Hamada M. The behaviour of structures built on active fault zones: Examples from the recent earthquakes of Turkey. Seism. Fault Induc. Fail. 2002;19:149s&#x2013;167s. doi: 10.2208/jsceseee.19.149s.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2208/jsceseee.19.149s</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J.Y. Active Fault Setback Research on Engineering Sites. Institute of Engineering Mechanics, China Earthquake Administration; Harbin, China: 2015. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou R.J. Surface Rupture and Hazard Characteristics of Wenchuan Earthquake with Magnitude 8.0 in Sichuan Province. Chin. J. Rock Mech. Eng. 2008;27:2173&#x2013;2183. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao B.M. An Analysis on the Fault and Seismic Disaster of the MS 8.0 Wenchuan Earthquake. Seismol. Geol. 2008;30:839&#x2013;854. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang J.Y. Analysis of Damage Reason in Beichuan County of MS8.0 Wenchuan Earthquake. J. Seismol. Res. 2009;32 (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song T.S. Comparison of the near fault factor between Chinese building seismic design code and American Uniform Building Code. Earthq. Eng. Eng. Dyn. 2016;36:55&#x2013;64. doi: 10.13197/j.eeev.2016.05.55.songts.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13197/j.eeev.2016.05.55.songts.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart E.W., Bryant William A. Fault-Rupture Hazard Zones in California-Alquist-Priolo Earthquake Fault Zoning Act with Index to Special Studies Zones Maps. Californnia Div. Mines Geol. 1997;42:38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christenson G.E., Darlene B.L., Nelson V. Guidelines for Evaluating Surface-Fault-Rupture hazard in Utah.  [(accessed on 25 September 2025)];Geol. Surv. 2003 :5&#x2013;23. Available online:  https://ugspub.nr.utah.gov/publications//misc_pubs//mp-n.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr J., Nathan S., Van Dissen R., Webb P., Brunsdon D., King A. Planning for Development of Land on or Close to Active Faults. Institute of Geological &amp; Nuclear Science Client Report; Ministry for the Environment; Wellington, New Zealand: 2003. pp. 2&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouckovalas G. Geotechnical Evaluation and Application of the Seismic Eurocode EC8. National Technical University; Athens, Greece: 2006. pp. 55&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borchardt G. Establishing appropriate setback widths for active faults. Environ. Eng. Geosci. 2010;16:47&#x2013;53. doi: 10.2113/gseegeosci.16.1.47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2113/gseegeosci.16.1.47</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fadaee M. 3&#x2013;Storey building subjected to reverse faulting: Analysis and experiments. Soil Dyn. Earthq. Eng. 2020;138:106297. doi: 10.1016/j.soildyn.2020.106297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soildyn.2020.106297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galandarzadeh A., Ashtiani M., Towhata I. Centrifuge modeling of shallow embedded foundations subjected to reverse fault rupture. Can. Geotech. J. 2016;53:505&#x2013;519. doi: 10.1139/cgj-2014-0444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/cgj-2014-0444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowkandeh M.J., Ashtiani M. A novel mitigation measure for normal fault-induced deformations on pile-raft systems. Earthq. Eng. Eng. Vib. 2024;23:15&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1007/s11803-024-2225-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11803-024-2225-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasopoulos I., Callerio A., Bransby M.F., Davies M.C.R., El Nahas A., Faccioli E., Gazetas G., Masella A., Paolucci R., Pecker A., et al. Numerical analyses of fault&#x2013;foundation interaction. Bull. Earthq. Eng. 2008;6:645&#x2013;675. doi: 10.1007/s10518-008-9078-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10518-008-9078-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasopoulos I., Gerolymos N., Gazetasnand G., Bransby M.F. Simplified approach for design of raft foundations against fault rupture. Part II: Soil-structure interaction. Earthq. Eng. Eng. Vib. 2008;7:165&#x2013;179. doi: 10.1007/s11803-008-0836-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11803-008-0836-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasopoulos I., Gerolymos N., Gazetasnand G., Bransby M.F. Simplified approach for design of raft foundations against fault rupture. Part I: Free field. Earthq. Eng. Eng. Vib. 2008;7:148&#x2013;164. doi: 10.1007/s11803-008-0835-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11803-008-0835-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasopoulos I., Gazetas G. Foundation-structure systems over a rupturing normal fault: Part I. Observations after the Kocaeli 1999 earthquake. Bull. Earthq. Eng. 2007;5:253&#x2013;275. doi: 10.1007/s10518-007-9029-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10518-007-9029-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray J.D. Developing Mitigation Measures for the Hazards Associated with Earthquake Surface Fault Rupture; Proceedings of the Workshop on Seismic Fault-Induced Failures&#x2014;Possible Remedies for Damage to Urban Facilities; Tokyo, Japan. 11&#x2013;12 January 2001; pp. 55&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray J.D., Seed R.B., Cluff L.S., Seed H.B. Earthquake fault rupture propagation though soil. J. Geotech. Eng. ASCE. 1994;120:543&#x2013;561. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)0733-9410(1994)120:3(543).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)0733-9410(1994)120:3(543)</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hitchcock C., Lettis W., Unruh J., Bachhuber J. Fault-Rupture Hazard Characterization: Applications of Paleoseismic Trenching for Detailed Mitigation Designs; Proceedings of the Geotechnical Earthquake and Engineering and Soil Dynamics IV Congress; Sacramento, CA, USA. 18&#x2013;22 May 2008; pp. 523&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/40975(318)29</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faccioli E., Anastasopoulos I., Gazetas G., Callerio A., Paolucci R. Fault rupture-foundation interaction: Selected case histories. Bull. Earthq. Eng. 2007;6:557&#x2013;583. doi: 10.1007/s10518-008-9089-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10518-008-9089-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Q.D. Remarks on urban active faults exploration and association activity assessment. Seismol. Geol. 2007;29:189&#x2013;200. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z.Q. Introduction to Seismic Engineering Geology. Seismological Press; Beijing, China: 1983. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Building Seismic Design Standards. China Architecture &amp; Building Press; Beijing, China: 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of Seismic Safety for Engineering Sites. China Architecture &amp; Building Press; Beijing, China: 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Code for Investigation of Geotechnical Engineering. China Architecture &amp; Building Press; Beijing, China: 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Code for design of Building Foundation. China Architecture &amp; Building Press; Beijing, China: 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H.B., Fu X.F. Co-seismic Surface Rupture and Dextral-slip Oblique Thrusting of the MS8.0 Wenchuan Earthquake. Acta Geol. Sin. 2008;82:1623&#x2013;1643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu S.B., Kuo L.C., Kuo L.-C., Hsu Y.-J., Su H.-H., Liu C.-C., Hou C.-S., Lee J.-F., Lai T.-C., Liu C.-C., et al. Preseismic deformation and coseismic displacements associated with the 1999 Chi-Chi, Taiwan, earthquake. Bull. Seismol. Soc. Am. 2001;91:995&#x2013;1012. doi: 10.1785/0120000722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1785/0120000722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Z., Zhang H. Mechanism of postseismic deformation of ground surface following the 1999 Chi-Chi earthquake, Taiwan earthquake. Chin. J. Geophys. 2013;56:2681&#x2013;2689. doi: 10.6038/cjg20130817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6038/cjg20130817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J.W. An experimental study on earthquake fault rupture propagation through a sandy soil deposit. Struct. Eng./Earthq. Eng. JSCE. 2005;22:1S&#x2013;13S. doi: 10.2208/jscej.2005.780_1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2208/jscej.2005.780_1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adam J. Shear localization and strain distribution during tectonic faulting-new insights from granular-flow experiments and high-resolution optical image correlation techniques. J. Struct. Geol. 2005;27:283&#x2013;301. doi: 10.1016/j.jsg.2004.08.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsg.2004.08.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmatz J. Clay smear in normal fault zones: The effect of multilayers and clay cementation in water-saturated model experiments. J. Struct. Geol. 2010;32:834&#x2013;1849. doi: 10.1016/j.jsg.2009.12.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsg.2009.12.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X.Z. Modeling test of normal fault rupture propagation in sandy soil. J. Eng. Geol. 2012;20:700&#x2013;705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T. Normal fault rupture propagation in overburdened rock and its impact on the ground deformation profile based on a model experimental approach. Soil Dyn. Earthq. Eng. 2023;169:107865. doi: 10.1016/j.soildyn.2023.107865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soildyn.2023.107865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C.T. Surface rupture and deformation phenomena of the 921 Chi-chi earthquake. Geotech. Technol. 2000;81:5&#x2013;16. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X.W. The Ms8.0 Wenchuan Earthquake Surface Ruptures and Its Seismogenic Structure. Seismol. Geol. 2008;30:597&#x2013;629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moosavi S.M., Jafari M.K., Kamalian M., Shafiei A. Experimental Investigation of Reverse Fault Rupture&#x2014;Rigid Shallow Foundation Interaction. Int. J. Civ. Eng. 2010;8:85&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1097/01.NURSE.0000446632.85961.5a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.NURSE.0000446632.85961.5a</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bransby M.F., Davies M.C.R., El Nahas A., Nagaoka S. Centrifuge modelling of reverse fault&#x2013;foundation interaction. Bull. Earthq. Eng. 2008;6:607&#x2013;628. doi: 10.1007/s10518-008-9080-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10518-008-9080-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCalpin J. Recommended setback distances from active normal faults; Proceedings of the 23rd Symposium on Engineering Geology and Soils Engineering; Logan, UT, USA. 6&#x2013;8 April 1987;  [(accessed on 25 September 2025)]. pp. 35&#x2013;56. Available online:  https://www.academia.edu/28859123/Recommended_setback_distances_from_active_normal_faults.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilgin H. Effects of near-fault and far-fault ground motions on nonlinear dynamic response and seismic damage of masonry structures. Eng. Struct. 2024;300:117200. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2023.117200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2023.117200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hisada Y., Kubo T., Matsuzawa K. Investigation of building damage near the surface faults of 2011 fukushima-ken-hama-dori earthquake. Jpn. Assoc. Earthq. Eng. 2014;14:6_142&#x2013;6_169. doi: 10.5610/jaee.14.6_142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5610/jaee.14.6_142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>