<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41348812</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative effects of French Contrast Method vs. Complex Training on explosive power and its endurance in youth badminton athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0338383</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0338383</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0338383</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0338383</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Badminton players normally prioritize technical and tactical training over physical conditioning before competition, presenting a challenge in enhancing physical fitness within a constrained timeframe. While evidence have indicated complex contrast training can enhance strength and power, it is still unclear whether the French Contrast Method Training (FCMT) can bring greater explosive power gains to young badminton players. This study evaluated the effects of French Contrast Method Training versus Complex Training on lower limb explosive strength and its endurance in elite adolescent male badminton players. In a single-blind randomized controlled trial, 20 athletes were allocated to either an FCMT group (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;10) or a CT group (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;10) and completed an 8-week intervention. Performance was assessed pre- and post-intervention using standardized tests, including countermovement jump (CMJ), squat jump (SJ), drop jump (DJ), 10-m sprint, 5-0-5 agility test, eccentric utilization ratio (EUR), one-repetition maximum (1RM) squat, and lower extremity explosive endurance (LEEE). Subjective fatigue was monitored using the rating of perceived exertion (RPE) scale. Results demonstrated that while both training modalities improved explosive strength, the French Contrast Method Training led to significantly greater improvements in CMJ, DJ, Reaction Strength Index (RSI), EUR, agility, and LEEE (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). The French Contrast Method Training also induced a larger effect size across most performance indicators. In contrast, the Complex Training improved strength and speed-related measures but showed limited effects on stretch-contraction cycle (SSC) utilization and endurance. Perceived fatigue was consistently higher in the CT group than in the FCMT group. These findings suggest that adaptation occurred more rapidly in the CT group (after roughly 3 weeks), whereas the FCMT group showed a more prolonged adaptation period (~1 month). The findings suggest that the French Contrast Method Training is more effective than the Complex Training in developing reactive strength, agility, SSC efficiency, and explosive endurance in youth badminton athletes within a short-term training period. Given its neuromechanical advantages across the force-velocity spectrum, the French Contrast Method Training is recommended for use in the pre-competition phase of training, while Complex Training may be more suitable for foundational strength development. These results provide practical insights for coaches and support the strategic integration of French Contrast Method Training into performance enhancement programs for adolescent athletes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Huang et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Ruiyin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangzhou Sport University, Guangzhou, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Yuhua</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8644-263X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangzhou Sport University, Guangzhou, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Ke</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Purple Tea Middle School, Jiangmen, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mo</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangzhou Sport University, Guangzhou, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Yongren</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Youth Competitive Sports School, Guangdong Provincial Sports Bureau, Guangzhou, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Zhan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Capital University of Physical Education and Sports, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015865" MajorTopicYN="Y">Racquet Sports</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016037" MajorTopicYN="N">Single-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064797" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Conditioning, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41348812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12680223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0338383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-41210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zatsiorsky VM, Kraemer WJ, Fry AC. Science and practice of strength training. Human Kinetics; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatouros IG, Jamurtas AZ, Leontsini D, Taxildaris K, Aggelousis N, Kostopoulos N, et al. Evaluation of Plyometric Exercise Training, Weight Training, and Their Combination on Vertical Jumping Performance and Leg Strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2000;14(4):470&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1519/00124278-200011000-00016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00124278-200011000-00016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Channell BT, Barfield JP. Effect of Olympic and traditional resistance training on vertical jump improvement in high school boys. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(5):1522&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318181a3d0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318181a3d0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18714236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturgess S, Newton RU. Design and Implementation of a Specific Strength Program for Badminton. Strength Cond J. 2008;30(3):33&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1519/ssc.0b013e3181771008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/ssc.0b013e3181771008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi CH, Tan A, Ahmad A, Kwong KW, Sompong R, Ghazali KAM, et al. Physiological characteristics of elite and sub-elite badminton players. J Sports Sci. 2009;27(14):1591&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1080/02640410903352907</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640410903352907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19967588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tajik R, Dhahbi W, Fadaei H, Mimar R. Muscle synergy analysis during badminton forehand overhead smash: integrating electromyography and musculoskeletal modeling. Front Sports Act Living. 2025;7:1596670. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2025.1596670</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2025.1596670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12170632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40529409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Babault N. Post-activation Potentiation Versus Post-activation Performance Enhancement in Humans: Historical Perspective, Underlying Mechanisms, and Current Issues. Front Physiol. 2019;10:1359. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2019.01359</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.01359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6838751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31736781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormier P, Freitas TT, Loturco I, Turner A, Virgile A, Haff GG, et al. Within Session Exercise Sequencing During Programming for Complex Training: Historical Perspectives, Terminology, and Training Considerations. Sports Med. 2022;52(10):2371&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1007/s40279-022-01715-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01715-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35816233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebben WP. Complex training: a brief review. J Sports Sci Med. 2002;1(2):42&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3963241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24688269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebben WP, Watts PB. A Review of Combined Weight Training and Plyometric Training Modes: Complex Training. Strength Cond. 1998;20(5):18&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1519/1073-6840(1998)020&lt;0018:arocwt&gt;2.3.co;2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/1073-6840(1998)020&lt;0018:arocwt&gt;2.3.co;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietz C, Peterson B. Triphasic training: A systematic approach to elite speed and explosive strength performance. 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C. The design and implementation of physical training for the Chinese national badminton team in preparation for the 2012 London Olympics. J Beijing Univ Phys Educ. 2016;5(5):86&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abi&#xe1;n P, Castanedo A, Feng XQ, Sampedro J, Abian-Vicen J. Notational comparison of men&#x2019;s singles badminton matches between Olympic Games in Beijing and London. Int J Perf Analysis Sport. 2014;14(1):42&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1080/24748668.2014.11868701</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24748668.2014.11868701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller MG, Herniman JJ, Ricard MD, Cheatham CC, Michael TJ. The effects of a 6-week plyometric training program on agility. J Sports Sci Med. 2006;5(3):459&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3842147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24353464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luders JG, Garrett JM, Gleadhill S, Mathews LO, Bennett HJ. Comparative Effects of Complex Contrast Training and Traditional Training Methods on Physical Performance Within Female, Semiprofessional Australian Rules Football Players. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38(11):1917&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000004888</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39178129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luders J, Gleadhill S, Garrett J, Bennett H. Enhancing athletic performance with complex contrast training: A Delphi study of elite strength and conditioning coaches. Int J Sport Sci Coach. 2024;19(6):2321&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1177/17479541241272256</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17479541241272256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argus CK, Gill ND, Keogh JWL, McGuigan MR, Hopkins WG. Effects of two contrast training programs on jump performance in rugby union players during a competition phase. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2012;7(1):68&#x2013;75. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.7.1.68</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.7.1.68</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22461463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbadry N, Hamza A, Pietraszewski P, Alexe DI, Lupu G. Effect of the French Contrast Method on Explosive Strength and Kinematic Parameters of the Triple Jump Among Female College Athletes. J Hum Kinet. 2019;69:225&#x2013;30. doi: 10.2478/hukin-2019-0047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2019-0047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6815088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31666904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Preciado JA, Baz E, Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C, Marchante D, Santos-Concejero J. Potentiation Effects of the French Contrast Method on Vertical Jumping Ability. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(7):1909&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002437</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29351162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K V IN, Vasanthi G, Elayaraja M, Murugesan R, Govindasamy K, Gogoi H. Impact of french contrast training on field hockey players&#x2019; biomotor and physiological parameters: a pretest-posttest study. Retos. 2024;58:1097&#x2013;105. doi: 10.47197/retos.v58.106974</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47197/retos.v58.106974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q. An experimental study on the effect of French Contrast Method Training method on the explosive power of the lower limbs of students majoring in long jump in physical education in general colleges and universities. Beijing Sports University; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welch ML, Lopatofsky ET, Morris JR, Taber CB. Effects of the french contrast method on maximum strength and vertical jumping performance. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsoukos A, Bogdanis GC, Terzis G, Veligekas P. Acute Improvement of Vertical Jump Performance After Isometric Squats Depends on Knee Angle and Vertical Jumping Ability. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(8):2250&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001328</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26808841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Liu J, Yang L, Zheng B. Can Maturation Level Influence Long-Term Physiological and Physical Adaptations in Youth Female Soccer Players Exposed to Combined Sided Games and HIIT? A Comparison Across Maturation Statuses. J Sports Sci Med. 2025;24(3):634&#x2013;44. doi: 10.52082/jssm.2025.634</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2025.634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12418192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40933321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balyi I, Hamilton A. Long-term athlete development: trainability in childhood and adolescence. Olympic Coach. 2004;16(1):4&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdanis GC, Tsoukos A, Veligekas P, Tsolakis C, Terzis G. Effects of muscle action type with equal impulse of conditioning activity on postactivation potentiation. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(9):2521&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000444</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24584048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarosz J, Gawel D, Grycmann P, Aschenbrenner P, Spieszny M, Wilk M, et al. How repeatable is PAPE effect: the impact of in-season isometric squat activation on countermovement jump performance enhancement in national level soccer players. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2025;17(1):115. doi: 10.1186/s13102-025-01148-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01148-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12051318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40325482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarosz J, Szwarc A. Isometric Conditioning Activity and Jump Performance: Impact of Training Status in Male Participants. J Clin Med. 2025;14(17):6214. doi: 10.3390/jcm14176214</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm14176214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12429130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40943974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas-Molina S, Salgado-Ram&#xed;rez U, Chulvi-Medrano I, Carbone L, Maroto-Izquierdo S, Ben&#xed;tez-Porres J. Comparison of post-activation performance enhancement (PAPE) after isometric and isotonic exercise on vertical jump performance. PLoS One. 2021;16(12):e0260866. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0260866</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0260866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8639083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34855891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovic G, Dizdar D, Jukic I, Cardinale M. Reliability and factorial validity of squat and countermovement jump tests. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(3):551&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1519/1533-4287(2004)18&lt;551:RAFVOS&gt;2.0.CO;2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/1533-4287(2004)18&lt;551:RAFVOS&gt;2.0.CO;2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15320660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young W. Laboratory strength assessment of athletes. New Stud Athlete. 1995;10:88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuigan MR, Doyle TLA, Newton M, Edwards DJ, Nimphius S, Newton RU. Eccentric utilization ratio: effect of sport and phase of training. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(4):992&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1519/R-19165.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/R-19165.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17194252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff G, Ruben R, Molinari M, Painter K, Stone MH. The relationship between the eccentric utilization ratio, reactive strength, and pre-stretch augmentation and selected dynamic and isometric muscle actions. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hetzler RK, Stickley CD, Lundquist KM, Kimura IF. Reliability and accuracy of handheld stopwatches compared with electronic timing in measuring sprint performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(6):1969&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318185f36c</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318185f36c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18978613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killip JSM. Reliability and validity of the 505 agility test. Evolution of the Athlete Coach Education Conference, 4th; Brisbane, Australia: University of the Sunshine Coast, Queensland, Australia; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart PF, Turner AN, Miller SC. Reliability, factorial validity, and interrelationships of five commonly used change of direction speed tests. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24(3):500&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1111/sms.12019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23176602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young WB, Dawson B, Henry GJ. Agility and Change-of-Direction Speed are Independent Skills: Implications for Training for Agility in Invasion Sports. Int J Sport Sci Coach. 2015;10(1):159&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1260/1747-9541.10.1.159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1260/1747-9541.10.1.159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hespanhol JE, Silva Neto LG, Arruda Md, Dini CA. Assessment of explosive strength-endurance in volleyball players through vertical jumping test. Revista Brasileira de Medicina do Esporte. 2007;13:181&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, O&#x2019;Bryant HS, McCoy L, Coglianese R, Lehmkuhl M, Schilling B. Power and maximum strength relationships during performance of dynamic and static weighted jumps. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17(1):140&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1519/1533-4287(2003)017&lt;0140:pamsrd&gt;2.0.co;2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/1533-4287(2003)017&lt;0140:pamsrd&gt;2.0.co;2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12580669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apanukul S, Suwannathada S, Intiraporn C. The Effects of Combined Weight and Pneumatic Training to Enhance Power Endurance in Tennis Players. J Exer Physiol Online. 2015;18(2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahbi W, Padulo J, Russo L, Racil G, Ltifi M-A, Picerno P, et al. 4-6 Repetition Maximum (RM) and 1-RM Prediction in Free-Weight Bench Press and Smith Machine Squat Based on Body Mass in Male Athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38(8):1366&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000004803</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38888595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J. NSCA&#x2019;s Guide to Program Design (NSCA Science of Strength &amp; Conditioning) (English Edition) 1st Edition, Kindle Edition. Human Kinetics; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo D-I, Kim E, Fahs CA, Rossow L, Young K, Ferguson SL, et al. Reliability of the one-repetition maximum test based on muscle group and gender. J Sports Sci Med. 2012;11(2):221&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen MJ, Fan X, Moe ST. Criterion-related validity of the Borg ratings of perceived exertion scale in healthy individuals: a meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2002;20(11):873&#x2013;99. doi: 10.1080/026404102320761787</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/026404102320761787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12430990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner JS, Hutsler R, Bergsteinov&#xe1; V, Buskirk ER. The validity and reliability of a rating scale of perceived exertion. Med Sci Sports. 1973;5(2):94&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1249/00005768-197300520-00018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-197300520-00018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4721013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Chen Q, China Z. Application of Excel to complete the calculation and evaluation of intra-group correlation coefficient ICC. Health Stat China. 2008;25:314&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges LV. A random effects model for effect sizes. Psychol Bullet. 1983;93(2):388&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1037/0033-2909.93.2.388</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-2909.93.2.388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cureton EE. Rank-Biserial Correlation. Psychometrika. 1956;21(3):287&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1007/bf02289138</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/bf02289138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco C, Viitasalo JT, Komi PV, Luhtanen P. Combined effect of elastic energy and myoelectrical potentiation during stretch-shortening cycle exercise. Acta Physiol Scand. 1982;114(4):557&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1111/j.1748-1716.1982.tb07024.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.1982.tb07024.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7136784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco C. The Effect of Prestretch on Skeletal Muscle Behavior. J Appl Biomech. 1997;13(4):426&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1123/jab.13.4.426</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jab.13.4.426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahbi W, Materne O, Chamari K. Rethinking knee injury prevention strategies: joint-by-joint training approach paradigm versus traditional focused knee strengthening. Biol Sport. 2025;42(4):59&#x2013;65. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2025.148544</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2025.148544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12490306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41048234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillin NA, Bishop D. Factors modulating post-activation potentiation and its effect on performance of subsequent explosive activities. Sports Med. 2009;39(2):147&#x2013;66. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200939020-00004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200939020-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19203135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball NB, Stock CG, Scurr JC. Bilateral contact ground reaction forces and contact times during plyometric drop jumping. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(10):2762&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181cc2408</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181cc2408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20613651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laffaye G, Wagner P. Eccentric rate of force development determines jumping performance. Comput Methods Biomech Biomed Engin. 2013;16(Suppl 1):82&#x2013;3. doi: 10.1080/10255842.2013.815839</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10255842.2013.815839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23923859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan CP, Lovell DI, Gass GC. The role of rate of force development on vertical jump performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(2):379&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181be305c</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181be305c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20093963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xenofondos A, Bassa E, Vrabas IS, Kotzamanidis C, Patikas DA. Muscle Twitch Torque During Two Different in Volume Isometric Exercise Protocols: Fatigue Effects on Postactivation Potentiation. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(2):578&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002311</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29084091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollhofer A, Komi P, Miyashita M, Aura O. Fatigue during stretch-shortening cycle exercises: changes in mechanical performance of human skeletal muscle. Int J Sport Med. 1987;8(02):71&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3596879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicol C, Komi PJKP, Fepne O. Ciclo de alongamento-encurtamento e sua influ&#xea;ncia na produ&#xe7;&#xe3;o de for&#xe7;a e pot&#xea;ncia. UK: Blackwell Publishing Co.; 2006. p. 219&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rixon KP, Lamont HS, Bemben MG. Influence of type of muscle contraction, gender, and lifting experience on postactivation potentiation performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(2):500&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1519/R-18855.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/R-18855.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Liu M, Zhou J, Bao D, Li B, Zhou J. Acute Effects of Fatigue on Cardiac Autonomic Nervous Activity. J Sports Sci Med. 2023;22(4):806&#x2013;15. doi: 10.52082/jssm.2023.806</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2023.806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10690502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38045744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia SC. Spinal and supraspinal factors in human muscle fatigue. Physiol Rev. 2001;81(4):1725&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1152/physrev.2001.81.4.1725</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.2001.81.4.1725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherni Y, Mzita I, Oranchuk DJ, Dhahbi W, Hammami M, Ceylan HI, et al. Effects of loaded vs unloaded plyometric training combined with change-of-direction sprints on neuromuscular performance in elite U-18 female basketball players: a randomized controlled study. Sport Sci Health. 2025;21(4):2899&#x2013;911. doi: 10.1007/s11332-025-01498-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-025-01498-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady C, Comyns T, Harrison A, Warrington G. Focus of Attention for Diagnostic Testing of the Force-Velocity Curve. Strength Cond J. 2017;39(1):57&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1519/ssc.0000000000000271</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/ssc.0000000000000271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Y-H, Chou Y-C, Chang Y-C, Tan K-H, Wu M-H. The Effects of High-Intensity Power Training versus Traditional Resistance Training on Exercise Performance. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(15):9400. doi: 10.3390/ijerph19159400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19159400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9367759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35954756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaldau NC, Kerr S, McCaig S, H&#xf6;lmich P. Training and injuries among world elite junior badminton players - Identifying the problems. Asia Pac J Sports Med Arthrosc Rehabil Technol. 2021;26:21&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.asmart.2021.07.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asmart.2021.07.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8367832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34458102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu D, Song D, Huang Z. Comparing Individualized vs. Non-Individualized Locomotor Profiling on High-Intensity Interval Training Adaptations in Soccer Players: A Randomized Parallel Study. J Sport Sci Med. 2025;24(3):503&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12418199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40933332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouzouraa E, Dhahbi W, Ferchichi A, Geant&#x103; VA, Kunszabo MI, Chtourou H, et al. Single-Night Sleep Extension Enhances Morning Physical and Cognitive Performance Across Time of Day in Physically Active University Students: A Randomized Crossover Study. Life (Basel). 2025;15(8):1178. doi: 10.3390/life15081178</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/life15081178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12387293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40868825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>