<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41730979</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A hybrid empirical and semi analytical inversion approach for remote sensing estimation of SPM in Ebinur Lake China.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10273</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-40250-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The suspended particulate matter (SPM) is a key parameter influencing the quality of aquatic habitats. SPM directly impacts the habitat of the "soft gold" (Artemia) in Ebinur Lake and is a major contributor to saline dust within its watershed. However, significant variations among inversion models present a challenge for SPM monitoring via remote sensing. Using Ebinur Lake as a case study, this study identify an optimal strategy for SPM monitoring. The findings are as follows: (1) Ebinur Lake water shows complete absorption at 695&#xa0;nm. (2) ESTARFM achieved a Red-band spatiotemporal fusion R<sup>2</sup> &#x2265;0.79, leading to an SPM inversion R<sup>2</sup> of 0.75. (3) Compared to the empirical model (R<sup>2</sup> &#x2265; 0.72, RMSE&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;78.95&#xa0;mg/L), the QAA (Quasi-Analytical Algorithm) demonstrated superior adaptability (R<sup>2</sup> &#x2265; 0.74, RMSE&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;61.12&#xa0;mg/L). (4) The red-band reflectance consistency among Landsat sensors reaches R<sup>2</sup> &#x2265; 0.76, with a cross-platform correlation of R<sup>2</sup>= 0.73 between Landsat 8 and Sentinel 2. (5) The QAA_655(665) model is effective for Landsat 8 and Sentinel 2, whereas the EXPM (the exponential model) is more suitable for Landsat 5/7 and fusion images. This study primarily addresses the challenge of spatiotemporal inadaptability in the long-term SPM inversion process for Ebinur Lake. It can serve as a reference for water color parameter retrieval via remote sensing in globally similar environmental contexts.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Changjiang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Geographic Sciences and Tourism, Xinjiang Normal University, Urumqi, 830054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Technology Innovation Center for Integrated Applications in Remote Sensing and Navigation, Ministry of Natural Resources, Nanjing, 210044, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xinjiang Laboratory of Lake Environment and Resources in Arid Zone, Urumqi, 830054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Xingbin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Geographic Sciences and Tourism, Xinjiang Normal University, Urumqi, 830054, China. xuxingbin0214@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xinjiang Laboratory of Lake Environment and Resources in Arid Zone, Urumqi, 830054, China. xuxingbin0214@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Yingxiu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Geographic Sciences and Tourism, Xinjiang Normal University, Urumqi, 830054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Fei</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Geography and Environmental Sciences, Zhejiang Normal University, Jinhua, 321004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Wenming</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Geographic Sciences and Tourism, Xinjiang Normal University, Urumqi, 830054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Mou Leong</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GeoInformatic Unit, Geography Section, School of Humanities, Universiti Sains Malaysia, USM, 11800, Penang, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Ye</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mental Health, Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, 325035, China. yuanye017@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Statistics, Chonnam National University, Gwangju, 61186, South Korea. yuanye017@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>TICIARSN-2023-05</GrantID><Agency>the Open Fund of Technology Innovation Center for Integrated Applications in Remote Sensing and Navigation, Ministry of Natural Resources</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024D01A86</GrantID><Agency>the Radiation transfer simulation of lakes and reservoirs on the northern slope of Tianshan Mountains, time series reconstruction of water color parameters</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>IDM2024002</GrantID><Agency>the National Natural Science Foundation of China (42561063), the Estimation of water storage and evaporation of typical lakes in Xinjiang and its impact on regional precipitation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>IDM2024002</GrantID><Agency>the Estimation of water storage and evaporation of typical lakes in Xinjiang and its impact on regional precipitation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024KFKT014</GrantID><Agency>the Open Foundation of the Key Laboratory of Coupling Process and Effect of Natural Resources Elements</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>42561063</GrantID><Agency>the National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atmospheric correction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Data fusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High-turbidity water</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lake</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Model selection strategy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41730979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13032013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-40250-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-40250-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Niu, L. et al. Role of suspended particulate matter for the transport and risks of organic micropollutant mixtures in rivers: A comparison between baseflow and high discharge conditions. <i>Environ. Sci. Technol.</i><b>59</b> (10), 4857&#x2013;4867 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.4c13378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11924229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39933915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng, W. et al. High spatial-resolution satellite mapping of suspended particulate matter in global coastal waters using particle composition-adaptive algorithms. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>323</b>, 114745 (2025a).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2025.114745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. &amp; Wang, M. Global daily gap-free ocean color products from multi-satellite measurements. <i>Int. J. Appl. Earth Obs. Geoinf.</i><b>108</b>, 102714 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, Z. et al. Quantitative inversion of suspended particulate matter in ebinur lake, an arid region: Evidence based on radiative transfer mechanism model. <i>J. Hydrology: Reg. Stud.</i><b>61</b>, 102714 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, Z. et al. MODIS observations reveal decrease in lake suspended particulate matter across China over the past two decades. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>295</b>, 113724 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2023.113724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. et al. Confounding effects of seasonality and anthropogenic river regulation on suspended particulate matter-driven mercury transport to coastal seas. <i>J. Hazard. Mater.</i><b>469</b>, 133979 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.133979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38492396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen, Z. et al. Remote estimates of suspended particulate matter in global lakes using machine learning models. <i>Int. Soil. Water Conserv. Res.</i><b>12</b> (1), 200&#x2013;216 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.iswcr.2023.07.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, H. et al. Satellite canopy water content from Sentinel-2, Landsat-8 and MODIS: Principle, algorithm and assessment. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>326</b>, 114801 (2025a).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2025.114801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagan, V. et al. Monitoring inland water quality using remote sensing: Potential and limitations of spectral indices, bio-optical simulations, machine learning, and cloud computing. <i>Earth Sci. Rev.</i><b>205</b>, 103187 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.earscirev.2020.103187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng, X. et al. Photochemical transformation and interaction of octachlorodibenzofuran (OCDF) with microplastics in suspended particulate matter-water system. <i>Water Res.</i>10.1016/j.watres.2025.123766 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2025.123766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40334378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, K. et al. Long-term remote monitoring of total suspended matter concentration in lake Taihu using 250 m MODIS-aqua data. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>164</b>, 43&#x2013;56 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2015.02.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadpour, G. &amp; Pirasteh, S. Interference of CDOM in remote sensing of suspended particulate matter (SPM) based on MODIS in the Persian Gulf and Oman sea. <i>Mar. Pollut. Bull.</i><b>173</b>, 113104 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpolbul.2021.113104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34872170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, C. et al. Controlled and driving mechanism of the SPM variation of shallow brackish lakes in arid regions. <i>Sci. Total Environ.</i><b>878</b>, 163127 (2023a).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.163127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37001663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. et al. High spatial resolution inversion of chromophoric dissolved organic matter (CDOM) concentrations in Ebinur Lake of arid Xinjiang, China: Implications for surface water quality monitoring. <i>Int. J. Appl. Earth Obs. Geoinf.</i><b>132</b>, 104022 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson, K. T., Sagan, V. &amp; Sloan, J. J. Deep learning-based water quality estimation and anomaly detection using Landsat-8/Sentinel-2 virtual constellation and cloud computing. <i>GISci. Remote Sens.</i><b>57</b>(4), 510&#x2013;525 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15481603.2020.1738061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu, Z. et al. Improving the observations of suspended sediment concentrations in rivers from Landsat to Sentinel-2 imagery. <i>Int. J. Appl. Earth Obs. Geoinf.</i><b>134</b>, 104209 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradi, M., Arabi, B., Hommersom, A., van der Molen, J. &amp; Samimi, C. Quality control tests for automated above-water hyperspectral measurements: Radiative transfer assessment. <i>ISPRS J. Photogramm. Remote Sens.</i><b>215</b>, 292&#x2013;312 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2024.07.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harringmeyer, J. P. et al. A hyperspectral view of the nearshore Mississippi River Delta: Characterizing suspended particles in coastal wetlands using imaging spectroscopy. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>301</b>, 113943 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2023.113943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, M. et al. Summer patterns of global lake total suspended solids under climate-hydrology-topography forcing. <i>Water Res.</i><b>291</b>, 125274 (2026).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2025.125274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41456589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noori, A., Mohajeri, M. H., Mehraein, M. &amp; Sharafati, A. Lake total suspended matter retrieval by wind speed: A machine learning model trained by time-series satellite imagery. <i>Ecol. Inform.</i><b>81</b>, 102565 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoinf.2024.102565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavora, J. et al. Recipes for the derivation of water quality parameters using the high-spatial-resolution data from sensors on board sentinel-2A, sentinel-2B, Landsat-5, Landsat-7, Landsat-8, and Landsat-9 satellites. <i>J. Remote Sens.</i><b>3</b>, 0049 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34133/remotesensing.0049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan, P. et al. High-resolution planetscope imagery and machine learning for estimating suspended particulate matter in the Ebinur Lake, Xinjiang, China. <i>IEEE J. Sel. Top. Appl. Earth Obs. Remote Sens.</i><b>16</b>, 1019&#x2013;1032 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSTARS.2022.3233113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, N. et al. Estimation of dissolved organic carbon using Sentinel-2 in the eutrophic Ebinur Lake, China. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>16</b>(2), 252 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs16020252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renosh, P. R. et al. Construction of multi-year time-series profiles of suspended particulate inorganic matter concentrations using machine learning approach. <i>Remote Sensing</i><b>9</b>(12), 1320 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs9121320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, N., Qiu, Z., Zhang, C., Liu, J. &amp; Liu, D. Observing water turbidity in Chinese rivers using Landsat series data over the past 40 years. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>494</b>, 145001 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.145001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J., Chen, X., Tian, L., Huang, J. &amp; Feng, L. Improved capabilities of the Chinese high-resolution remote sensing satellite GF-1 for monitoring suspended particulate matter (SPM) in inland waters: Radiometric and spatial considerations. <i>ISPRS J. Photogramm. Remote Sens.</i><b>106</b>, 145&#x2013;156 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2015.05.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petit, T. et al. Inherent optical properties and optical characteristics of dissolved organic and particulate matter in an Arctic fjord (Storfjorden, Svalbard) in early summer. <i>Ocean Sci. Discuss.</i><b>2021</b>, 1&#x2013;28 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, C. et al. Feasibility of the spatiotemporal fusion model in monitoring Ebinur Lake&#x2019;s suspended particulate matter under the missing-data scenario. <i>Remote Sensing</i><b>13</b>(19), 3952 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs13193952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, C. et al. High spatiotemporal resolution reconstruction of suspended particulate matter concentration in arid Brackish lake, China. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>414</b>, 137673 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.137673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. et al. Satellite observations of suspended particulate matter concentration in Lake Gaoyou in the past four decades. <i>Water Res.</i><b>254</b>, 121442 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2024.121442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38484550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, Z. et al. Quantitative inversion of suspended particulate matter in Ebinur lake, an arid region: Evidence based on radiative transfer mechanism model. <i>J. Hydrol. Reg. Stud.</i><b>61</b>, 102714 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejrh.2025.102714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X., He, X. &amp; Pan, X. Application of gaofen-6 images in the downscaling of land surface temperatures. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>14</b>(10), 2307 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs14102307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qing, L. I. N. &amp; Wenqiang, X. U. Analysis of the effect of the quantity of inflow into Ebinur Lake on its ecological security. <i>Environ. Res.</i><b>266</b>, 120517 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2024.120517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39638024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, G. et al. Decoupling of surface water storage from precipitation in global drylands due to anthropogenic activity. <i>Nat. Water</i><b>3</b>(1), 80&#x2013;88 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s44221-024-00367-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, R., Liu, S., Chen, S., Zhao, L. &amp; Yang, D. Satellite observations reveal anthropogenic pressure significantly affects the suspended particulate matter concentrations in coastal waters of Hainan Island. <i>J. Environ. Manage.</i><b>365</b>, 121617 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38968896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gackstetter, D., Yu, K. &amp; Krner, M. Self-attention and frequency-augmentation for unsupervised domain adaptation in satellite image-based time series classification. <i>ISPRS J. Photogramm. Remote Sens.</i><b>224</b>, 113&#x2013;132 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2025.03.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, C., Zhang, F., Johnson, V. C., Duan, P. &amp; Kung, H. T. Spatio-temporal variation of oasis landscape pattern in arid area: Human or natural driving?. <i>Ecol. Indic.</i><b>125</b>, 107495 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2021.107495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, N. et al. Spatio-temporal analysis of colored dissolved organic matter over Ebinur Lake in Xinjiang, China. <i>Ecol. Inform.</i><b>78</b>, 102339 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoinf.2023.102339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju, J. et al. The harmonized Landsat and Sentinel-2 version 2.0 surface reflectance dataset. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>324</b>, 114723 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2025.114723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, J. et al. Projected response of algal blooms in global lakes to future climatic and land use changes: Machine learning approaches. <i>Water Res.</i><b>271</b>, 122889 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2024.122889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39644838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, X., Chen, J., Gao, F., Chen, X. &amp; Masek, J. G. An enhanced spatial and temporal adaptive reflectance fusion model for complex heterogeneous regions. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>114</b>(11), 2610&#x2013;2623 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2010.05.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Qin, B. &amp; Yang, L. Spectral absorption coefficients of particulate matter and chromophoric dissolved organic matter in Meiliang Bay of Lake Taihu. <i>Acta Ecol. Sin.</i><b>12</b>, 3969&#x2013;3979 (2006) (<b>(in chinese)</b>).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleveland, J. S. &amp; Weidemann, A. D. Quantifying absorption by aquatic particles: A multiple scattering correction for glass&#x2010;fiber filters. <i>Limnol. Oceanogr.</i><b>38</b>(6), 1321&#x2013;1327 (1993).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4319/lo.1993.38.6.1321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Song, Y., Liu, P., Lai, L. &amp; Zhang, Y. Concerns about the temporal matching windows in satellite-ground synchronization for lacustrine environment mapping. <i>Water Res.</i><b>286</b>, 124208 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2025.124208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40701054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitarch, J. &amp; Vanhellemont, Q. The QAA-RGB: A universal three-band absorption and backscattering retrieval algorithm for high resolution satellite sensors. Development and implementation in ACOLITE. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>265</b>, 112667 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2021.112667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, Z. et al. Water clarity changes in Lake Taihu over 36 years based on Landsat TM and OLI observations. <i>Int. J. Appl. Earth Obs. Geoinf.</i><b>102</b>, 102457 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Polito, C. et al. On the potential of robust satellite techniques approach for SPM monitoring in coastal waters: Implementation and application over the Basilicata Ionian Coastal Waters using MODIS&#x2010;Aqua. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>8</b>(11), 922 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs8110922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, D. et al. Observations of water transparency in China&#x2019;s lakes from space. <i>Int. J. Appl. Earth Obs. Geoinf.</i><b>92</b>, 102187 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J., Chen, X., Tian, L., Huang, J. &amp; Feng, L. Improved capabilities of the Chinese high-resolution remote sensing satellite GF-1 for monitoring suspended particulate matter (SPM) in inland waters: Radiometric and Spatial considerations. <i>ISPRS J. Photogramm. Remote Sens.</i>. <b>106</b>, 145&#x2013;156 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2015.05.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gernez, P. et al. Toward Sentinel-2 high resolution remote sensing of suspended particulate matter in very turbid waters: SPOT4 (Take5) experiment in the Loire and Gironde estuaries. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>7</b> (8), 9507&#x2013;9528 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs70809507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odermatt, D., Gitelson, A., Brando, V. E. &amp; Schaepman, M. Review of constituent retrieval in optically deep and complex waters from satellite imagery. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>118</b>, 116&#x2013;126 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2011.11.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsushita, B. et al. A hybrid algorithm for estimating the chlorophyll-a concentration across different trophic States in Asian inland waters. <i>ISPRS J. Photogram. Remote Sens.</i><b>102</b>, 28&#x2013;37 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2014.12.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, Z. et al. Seamless observations of chlorophyll-a from OLCI and VIIRS measurements in inland lakes. <i>Water Res.</i><b>270</b>, 122825 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2024.122825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39580942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffer, M. M. et al. Satellite remote sensing to assess cyanobacterial bloom frequency across the United States at multiple Spatial scales. <i>Ecol. Ind.</i><b>128</b>, 107822 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2021.107822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9088058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35558093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, H. et al. A novel quad-modality deep neural network for estimating chlorophyll-a concentrations in Lianyungang&#x2019;s lakes and reservoirs using Sentinel-2 MSI data. <i>Water Res.</i>10.1016/j.watres.2025.124246 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2025.124246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40695019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, J. et al. Global estimation of suspended particulate matter from satellite ocean color imagery. <i>J. Geophys. Res. Oceans</i><b>126</b>(8), e2021JC017303 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2021JC017303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9285372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35844263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nechad, B., Ruddick, K. G. &amp; Park, Y. Calibration and validation of a generic multisensor algorithm for mapping of total suspended matter in turbid waters. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>4</b> (114), 854&#x2013;866 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2009.11.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamun, M., Hasan, M. &amp; An, K. G. Advancing reservoirs water quality parameters Estimation using Sentinel-2 and Landsat-8 satellite data with machine learning approaches. <i>Ecol. Inf.</i><b>81</b>, 102608 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoinf.2024.102608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, Y. et al. A two-step random forest algorithm for deriving dissolved inorganic carbon in lakes from Landsat satellite data. <i>Environ. Res.</i><b>271</b>, 121068 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2025.121068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39923823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>