<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41589217</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1866-9557</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Archaeological and anthropological sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Archaeol Anthropol Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluating the potential of in-depth chrono-cultural and functional analysis of pottery in European cave archaeology: a case study from the prehistoric Grotte Di Sant'angelo Cave Complex (Cassano allo Ionio - Calabria, Italy).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>30</StartPage><MedlinePgn>30</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">30</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12520-025-02332-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">This paper evaluates the potential of in-depth chronological and functional analysis of prehistoric pottery (4th millennium BCE) from the Grotte di Sant'Angelo Cave Complex, located in the municipality of Cassano allo Ionio (Calabria, Southern Italy). The underground system, formed by sulfuric acid speleogenesis, features a floor scattered with depressions, holes, and fractures of different depths hosting archaeological materials. A number of these contexts in the so-called 'Trivio' area, excavated in 2017 and reported on here, provide an excellent opportunity to pioneer a combined archaeological and scientific contextual approach to unravelling the use of pottery in the Grotte di Sant'Angelo Cave Complex through time. The approach chosen first establishes the chronology of pots through typological comparisons with sites offering key stratigraphic sequences for prehistoric material culture present in the Italian peninsula and islands. Next, a functional study is presented that focusses on the use-related morphological properties of the pots, their performance characteristics, and preserved organic residues. Based on presentation and evaluation of the resulting data, the authors then proceed to propose hypotheses on the use and meaning of the various pottery shapes present in individual contexts from the Trivio zone cave floor contexts. At a more general level, the aim of the authors is to show how a contextual approach, combining several research tools for pottery analysis can make an important contribution to the toolbox of scholars working in European cave archaeology, thereby increasing the discipline's potential of resolving theoretically informed questions about human-cave entanglements in later prehistory.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1007/s12520-025-02332-1.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carloni</LastName><ForeName>Delia</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1006-8650</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Groningen Institute of Archaeology, University of Groningen, Groningen, Netherlands.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/012p63287</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.4830.f</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0407 1981</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro di Ricerca speleo-archeologica 'Enzo dei Medici', Roseto Capo Spulico, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Larocca</LastName><ForeName>Felice</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Bari Aldo Moro, Gruppo di ricerca speleo-archeologica, Bari, Italy.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/027ynra39</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.7644.1</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0120 3326</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro di Ricerca speleo-archeologica 'Enzo dei Medici', Roseto Capo Spulico, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Attema</LastName><ForeName>Peter A J</ForeName><Initials>PAJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1360-5757</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Groningen Institute of Archaeology, University of Groningen, Groningen, Netherlands.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/012p63287</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.4830.f</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0407 1981</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Luca</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratorio di spettrometria di massa analitica ed isotopica, Dipartimento di Beni Culturali, Universit&#xe0; del Salento, Lecce, Italy.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/03fc1k060</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.9906.6</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2289 7785</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Breglia</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6975-0561</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro di Ricerca speleo-archeologica 'Enzo dei Medici', Roseto Capo Spulico, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dipartimento di Geoscienze, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Padova, Padova, Italy.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/00240q980</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.5608.b</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 1757 3470</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pacciarelli</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8510-3652</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dipartimento di Studi Umanistici, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Napoli Federico II, Napoli, Italy.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/05290cv24</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.4691.a</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0790 385X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Benedetto</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe E</ForeName><Initials>GE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0832-5470</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratorio di spettrometria di massa analitica ed isotopica, Dipartimento di Beni Culturali, Universit&#xe0; del Salento, Lecce, Italy.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/03fc1k060</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.9906.6</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2289 7785</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Archaeol Anthropol Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101606755</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1866-9557</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cave archaeology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Contextual approach</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Copper Age</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pottery analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prehistory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Residue analysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interestsThe authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41589217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12831680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12520-025-02332-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agnolin AM (2021) Variability in the use of caves and rockshelters among ethnographic hunter-gatherers and its archaeological implications. J Anthropol Archaeol 64:101359. 10.1016/j.jaa.2021.101359</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaa.2021.101359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelucci DE, Boschian G, Fontanals M et al (2009) Shepherds and karst: The use of caves and rock-shelters in the Mediterranean region during the Neolithic. World Archaeol 41:191&#x2013;214. 10.1080/00438240902843659</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00438240902843659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anta JM, Kennedy JF (1991) Chemical changes during food processing. Carbohydr Polym 16:235&#x2013;236. 10.1016/0144-8617(91)90109-P</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0144-8617(91)90109-P</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anzidei AP, Carboni G (eds) (2020) Roma prima del mito. Abitati e necropoli dal Neolitico alla prima et&#xe0; dei metalli nel territorio di Roma (VI-III millennio a.C.). Archaeopress, Oxford</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur JW (2003) Brewing Beer: Status, Wealth and Ceramic Use Alteration among the Gamo of South-Western Ethiopia. World Archaeol 34:516&#x2013;528</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attema PAJ, Ippolito F (2017) Il Progetto Archeologico Raganello (RAP) - Sviluppo insediativo di lunga durata nell&#x2019;hinterland della Sibaritide protostorica. In: Cicala L, Pacciarelli M (eds) Centri fortificati indigeni della Calabria dalla protostoria all&#x2019;et&#xe0; ellenistica:&#x202f;: Atti del Convegno Internazionale Napoli, 16-17 gennaio 2014. Naus Editoria, Pozzuoli, pp 69&#x2013;80</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attema PAJ, van Leusen PM (2004) Intra-regional and inter-regional comparison of occupation histories in three italian regions: The RPC project. In: Alcock SE, Cherry JF (eds) Side-by-side survey: Comparative regional studies in the Mediterranean world. Oxbow, Oxford, pp 86&#x2013;100</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attema PAJ, Burgers GJ, van Leusen M (2012) Regional pathways to complexity: Settlement and land-use dynamics in Early Italy from the Bronze Age to the Republican Period. Amsterdam University Press</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aurino P, Pacciarelli M, Salerno A (2023) Orizzonti culturali e dinamiche di occupazione nelle Grotte della Campania tra Neolitico ed et&#xe0; del Bronzo. In: Di Franco L, Perrella R (eds) Le grotte tra Preistoria, et&#xe0; classica e Medioevo. Capri, la Campania, il Mediterraneo. Edizioni Quasar, Roma, pp 179&#x2013;201</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailo Modesti G, Salerno A (1998) Pontecagnano II.5 La necropoli eneolitica. L&#x2019;et&#xe0; del Rame in Campania nei villaggi dei morti. Istituto Universitario Orientale, Napoli</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benzi M (2011) Daskalio (Vathy), Kalymnos: A Late Bronze I sacred cave in the East Aegean. In: Gau&#xdf; W, Lindblom M, Smith RAK, Wright JC (eds) Our Cups Are Full: Pottery and Society in the Aegean Bronze Age. Papers Presented to Jeremy B. Rutter on the Occasion of his 65th Birthday. Archaeopress, Oxford, pp 13&#x2013;24</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergsvik KA, Skeates R (2012a) Caves in context: an introduction. In: Bergsvik KA, Skeates R (eds) Caves in context: The cultural significance of caves and rockshelters in Europe. Oxbow Books, Oxford, pp 1&#x2013;17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergsvik KA, Skeates R (eds) (2012b) Caves in context: The cultural significance of caves and rockshelters in Europe. Oxbow Books, Oxford</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernabei M, Grifoni Cremonesi R (1995) I culti delle acque nella preisroria dell&#x2019;Italia peninsulare. Riv Sci Preistoriche XLVII:331&#x2013;366</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernab&#xf2; Brea M, Revedin A (eds) (2004) Antichi segni dell&#x2019;uomo. Nel cinquantenario della fondazione dell&#x2019;Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria, catalogo della mostra</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernab&#xf2; Brea L, Cavalier M (1960) Meligun&#xec;s Lip&#xe0;ra I. La stazione preistorica della contrada Diana e la necropoli protostorica di Lipari. Flaccovio, Palermo</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernab&#xf2; Brea L, Cavalier M (1980) Meligun&#xec;s Lip&#xe0;ra IV. L&#x2019;acropoli di Lipari nella preistoria. Flaccovio, Palermo</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernab&#xf2; Brea L, Cavalier M (2000) La Grotta del Santuario della Madonna (Praia a Mare - Cosenza). Livelli olocenici. Il Calamo, Roma</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernab&#xf2; Brea L, Bidittu I, Cassoli PF, et al (1989) La Grotta Cardini (Praia a Mare - Cosenza): giacimento del Bronzo. Il Calamo, Roma</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biddittu I, Bruni N, Cerqua M, et al (2004) Ritrovamenti neolitici e dell&#x2019;et&#xe0; del rame nell&#x2019;Altopiano Silano. In: Preistoria e Protostoria della Calabria. Atti della XXXVII Riunione Scientifica dell&#x2019;Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria. Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria, Firenze, pp 761&#x2013;764</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjerck HB (2012) On the outer fringe of the human world: Phenomenological perspectives on anthropomorphic cave paintings in Norway. In: Bergsvik KA, Skeates R (eds) Caves in context: The cultural significance of caves and rockshelters in Europe. Oxbow Books, Oxford, pp 48&#x2013;64</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonsall C, Tolan-Smith C (1997) The human use of caves. BAR Publishing, Oxford</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boschian G, Montagnari-Kokelj E (2000) Prehistoric shepherds and caves in the Trieste Karst (Northeastern Italy). Geoarchaeology 15:331&#x2013;371. 10.1002/(SICI)1520-6548(200004)15:4%3C331::AID-GEA3%3E3.0.CO;2-H</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1520-6548(200004)15:4&lt;331::AID-GEA3&gt;3.0.CO;2-H</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breglia F, Arena F (2015) Le grotte dell&#x2019;Alta Valle dell&#x2019;Esaro (Calabria) dalla Preistoria al Medioevo. In: De Nitto L, Maurano F, Parise M (eds) Atti XXII Congresso Nazionale di Speleologia &#x2013; Euro Speleo Forum 2015 &#x201c;Condividere i dati&#x201d; 30 Maggio-2 Giugno 2015, Pertosa, Auletta (SA). Memorie dell&#x2019;Istituto italiano di Speleologia, Bologna, pp 516&#x2013;521</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breglia F, Veneziano M (2021) Grotta del Caprio (Francavilla Marittima, CS): un contesto sotterraneo di et&#xe0; eneolitica alle pendici del Monte Sellaro. In: Mittica G, Colelli C, Larocca A, Larocca F (eds) Dal Pollino all&#x2019;Orsomarso. Ricerche archeologiche fra Ionio e Tirreno. Edizioni Quasar, Roma, pp 93&#x2013;105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budja M (2014) Neolithic pottery and the biomolecular archaeology of lipids. Doc Praehist 41:196&#x2013;224. 10.4312/dp.41.11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4312/dp.41.11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;ster L, Warmenbol E, Mleku&#x17e; D (2019) Between Worlds: Bridging the Divide Between Method and Theory in Understanding the Ritual Use of Caves in Later Prehistory. In: B&#xfc;ster L, Warmenbol E, Mleku&#x17e; D (eds) Between Worlds: Understanding Ritual Cave Use in Later Prehistory. Springer International Publishing, Cham, pp 1&#x2013;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carancini GL, Guerzoni RP (1987) Gli scavi nella Grotta Pavolella presso Cassano allo Jonio. In: Vv.Aa. (ed) Atti della XXVI Riunione Scientifica IIPP, Il Neolitico in Italia. Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria, Firenze, pp 783&#x2013;792</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castagna MA, Schiappelli A (2004) La sequenza stratigrafica di Acri Colle Dogna (CS), tra Eneolitico e Bronzo antico. In: Vv.Aa. (ed) Preistoria e Protostoria della Calabria, Atti della XXXVII Riunione Scientifica dell&#x2019;Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria. Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria, Firenze, pp 295&#x2013;307</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charri&#xe9;-Duhaut A, Connan J, Rouquette N et al (2007) The canopic jars of Rameses II: Real use revealed by molecular study of organic residues. J Archaeol Sci 34:957&#x2013;967. 10.1016/j.jas.2006.09.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jas.2006.09.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clottes J (2012) Ritual cave use in European Paleolithic caves. In: Moyes H (ed) Sacred darkness: A global perspective on the ritual use of caves. University Press of Colorado, Boulder, pp 15&#x2013;26</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cocchi Genick D (2008) La tipologia in funzione della ricostruzione storica. Le forme vascolari dell&#x2019;et&#xe0; del rame dell&#x2019;Italia centrale. Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria, Firenze</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cocchi Genick D (2009) Correlazioni tra l&#x2019;Eneolitico siciliano e peninsulare. Origini XXXI:129&#x2013;154</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colonese AC, Hendy J, Lucquin A et al (2017) New criteria for the molecular identification of cereal grains associated with archaeological artefacts. Sci Rep 7:6633. 10.1038/s41598-017-06390-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-06390-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5529501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28747692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connan J, Nieuwenhuyse OP, Van As A, Jacobs L (2004) Bitumen in early ceramic art: Bitumen-painted ceramics from Late Neolithic Tell Sabi Abyad (Syria). Archaeometry 46:115&#x2013;124. 10.1111/j.1475-4754.2004.00147.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1475-4754.2004.00147.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copley MS, Berstan R, Dudd SN et al (2003) Direct chemical evidence for widespread dairying in prehistoric Britain. Proc Natl Acad Sci 100:1524&#x2013;1529. 10.1073/pnas.0335955100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0335955100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC149865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12574520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coppola D, Curci A, Del Fattore FR, Genchi F (2011) Grotta S. Biagio (Ostuni, BR): Nuove prospettive di ricerca per l&#x2019;Eneolitico dell&#x2019;Italia sud-orientale. In: Vv.Aa. (ed) L&#x2019;et&#xe0; del rame in Italia, Atti XLIII Riunione Scientifica&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig OE (2021) Prehistoric fermentation, delayed-return economies, and the adoption of pottery technology. Curr Anthropol 62:S233&#x2013;S241. 10.1086/716610</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/716610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig OE, Allen RB, Thompson A et al (2012) Distinguishing wild ruminant lipids by gas chromatography/combustion/isotope ratio mass spectrometry. Rapid Commun Mass Spectrom 26:2359&#x2013;2364. 10.1002/rcm.6349</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rcm.6349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22956328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cramp LJE, Evershed RP (2015) Reading the residues: The use of chromatographic and mass spectrometric techniques for reconstructing the role of kitchen and other domestic vessels in Roman antiquity. In: Spataro M, Villing A (eds) Ceramics, cuisine and culture: the archaeology and science of kitchen pottery in the ancient Mediterranean world. Oxbow Books, Oxford, pp 125&#x2013;140</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cremonesi G (1976) Gli scavi nella grotta n. 3 di Latronico (Nota preliminare). In: Vv.Aa. (ed) Basilicata, Atti XX Riunione Scientifica dell&#x2019;Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria. Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria, Firenze, pp 177&#x2013;198</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Neef W, Larocca A, Attema PAJ (2021) Pollino Archaeological Landscape Project (PALP), un progetto archeologico internazionale. Apollinea 25:20&#x2013;23</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Waele J, Audra P, Madonia G, et al (2016) Sulfuric acid speleogenesis (SAS) close to the water table: examples from southern France, Austria, and Sicily. Geomorphology 253:452&#x2013;467</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debels P, Jallot L, Borgnon C (2020) Water and food management in late Neolithic plateau caves and lowland substructures in the south of France (3500-2300 BCE). J Archaeol Sci Rep 31:102341. 10.1016/j.jasrep.2020.102341</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jasrep.2020.102341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debono Spiteri C, Gillis RE, Roffet-Salque M et al (2016) Regional asynchronicity in dairy production and processing in early farming communities of the Northern mediterranean. Proc Natl Acad Sci 113:13594&#x2013;13599. 10.1073/pnas.1607810113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1607810113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5137723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27849595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowd M (2015) The archaeology of caves in Ireland. Oxbow Books, Oxford and Philadelphia</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowd M, Hensey R (eds) (2016) The archaeology of darkness. Oxbow Books, Oxford</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drieu L, Rageot M, Wales N et al (2020) Is it possible to identify ancient wine production using biomolecular approaches? STAR Sci Technol Archaeol Res 6:16&#x2013;29. 10.1080/20548923.2020.1738728</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/20548923.2020.1738728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drieu L, Regert M, Mazuy A, et al (2022) Relationships Between Lipid Profiles and Use of Ethnographic Pottery: an Exploratory Study. J Archaeol Method Theory 29:1294&#x2013;1322. 10.1007/s10816-021-09547-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10816-021-09547-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duma G (1972) Phosphate content of ancient pots as an indicator of use. Curr Anthropol 13:127&#x2013;131</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunnell RC, Hunt TL (1990) Elemental composition and inference of ceramic vessel function. Curr Anthropol 31:330&#x2013;336</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evershed RP (1993) Biomolecular archaeology and lipids. World Archaeol 25:74&#x2013;93. 10.1080/00438243.1993.9980229</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00438243.1993.9980229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16471029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evershed RP (2008) Organic residue analysis in archaeology: The archaeological biomarker revolution. Archaeometry 50:895&#x2013;924. 10.1111/j.1475-4754.2008.00446.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1475-4754.2008.00446.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evershed RP, Heron C, Goad LJ (1991) Epicuticular wax components preserved in potsherds as chemical indicators of leafy vegetables in ancient diets. Antiquity 65:540&#x2013;544. 10.1017/S0003598X00080145</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0003598X00080145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evershed RP, Dudd SN, Copley MS et al (2002) Chemistry of archaeological animal fats. Acc Chem Res 35:660&#x2013;668. 10.1021/ar000200f</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ar000200f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12186571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evershed RP, Dudd SN, Anderson-Stojanovic VR, Gebhard ER (2003) New chemical evidence for the use of combed ware pottery vessels as beehives in ancient Greece. J Archaeol Sci 30:1&#x2013;12. 10.1006/jasc.2001.0827</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/jasc.2001.0827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evershed RP, Dudd SN, Copley MS, Mutherjee A (2016) Identification of animal fats via compound specific &#x3b4;13C values of individual fatty acids: Assessments of results for reference fats and lipid extracts of archaeological pottery vessels. Doc Praehist 29:73&#x2013;96. 10.4312/dp.29.7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4312/dp.29.7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faraco M, Pennetta A, Fico D et al (2016) Bitumen in potsherds from two Apulian Bronze Age settlements, Monopoli and Torre Santa Sabina: Composition and origin. Org Geochem 93:22&#x2013;31. 10.1016/j.orggeochem.2016.01.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.orggeochem.2016.01.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faulkner CH (1988) Painters of the dark zone. Archaeology 41:30&#x2013;38</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forte V, Nunziante Cesaro S, Medeghini L (2018) Cooking traces on Copper Age pottery from central Italy: An integrated approach comprising use wear analysis, spectroscopic analysis and experimental archaeology. J Archaeol Sci Rep 18:121&#x2013;138. 10.1016/j.jasrep.2017.12.052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jasrep.2017.12.052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franc&#xe9;s-Negro M, Iriarte E, Galindo-Pellicena MA, et al (2021) Neolithic to Bronze Age economy and animal management revealed using analyses lipid residues of pottery vessels and faunal remains at El Portal&#xf3;n de Cueva Mayor (Sierra de Atapuerca, Spain). J Archaeol Sci 131:105380. 10.1016/j.jas.2021.105380</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jas.2021.105380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galdenzi S (1997) Initial geologic observation in caves bordering the Sibari plain. J Cave Karst Stud 59:81&#x2013;86</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galdenzi S, Maruoka T (2019) Sulfuric acid caves in Calabria (South Italy): Cave morphology and sulfate deposits. Geomorphology 328:211&#x2013;221. 10.1016/j.geomorph.2018.12.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geomorph.2018.12.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galdenzi S, Menichetti M (2017) Hypogenic Caves in the Apennine Mountains (Italy). In: Klimchouk A, N. Palmer A, De Waele J, et al. (eds) Hypogene Karst Regions and Caves of the World. Springer International Publishing, Cham, pp 127&#x2013;142</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasparo F (1979) Nota preliminare sulle ricerche della commissione Grotte &#xab;E. Boegan &#xbb; nel Comune di Cassano allo Jonio (Cosenza). Atti E Mem Comm Grotte &#xab;E Boegan&#xbb; 18:121&#x2013;127</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasparo F (1980) Il fenomeno carsico nel territorio comunale di Cassano allo Jonio (Provincia Di Cosenza). Atti E Mem Della Comm Grotte E Boegan 19:79&#x2013;116</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geniola A, Tunzi AM (1980) Espressioni culturali e d&#x2019;arte nella Grotta di Cala Scizzo presso Torre a Mare (Bari). Riv Sci Preistoriche XXXV:125&#x2013;146</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandinetti G, Lo Torto A, Pacciarelli M et al (2004) Gli insediamenti di Gallo e Colarizzi (promontorio Di Tropea): Primi dati su un nuovo aspetto ceramico dell&#x2019;Et&#xe0; del rame. In: Vv.Aa. (ed) Preistoria e Protostoria della Calabria, Atti XXXVII Riunione Scientifica dell&#x2019;Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria. Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria, Firenze, pp 275&#x2013;294</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grifoni Cremonesi RG (2007) Notes on some cultic aspects of Italian Prehistory. Doc Praehist 34:221&#x2013;230. 10.4312/dp.34.17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4312/dp.34.17</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerra-Doce E (2015) Psychoactive Substances in Prehistoric Times: Examining the Archaeological Evidence. Time Mind 8:91&#x2013;112. 10.1080/1751696X.2014.993244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1751696X.2014.993244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerzoni P (2004) La facies di Piano Conte nella Grotta Pavolella: la sequenza cronologica sulla base della ceramica vascolare. In: Vv.Aa. (ed) Preistoria e Protostoria della Calabria, Atti XXXVII Riunione Scientifica dell&#x2019;Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria. Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria, Firenze, pp 235&#x2013;249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerzoni RP, Amodio F (2011) Nuove testimonianze insediative del Neolitico finale e delle prime et&#xe0; dei metalli nella Sibaritide meridionale. In: L&#x2019;et&#xe0; del rame in Italia, Atti XLIII Riunione Scientifica dell&#x2019;Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria. Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria, Firenze, pp 669&#x2013;674</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gull&#xec; D (2013) L&#x2019;occupazione delle grotte in et&#xe0; preistorica nel territorio agrigentino. In: Cucchi F, Guidi P (eds) Diffusione delle conoscenze: Atti del XXI Congresso Nazionale di Speleologia, Trieste, 2&#x2013;5 giugno 2011. EUT Edizioni Universit&#xe0; di Trieste, Trieste, pp 258&#x2013;267</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gull&#xec; D (2018) Characteristics of the cult and funerary caves in the Agrigento territory. In: Herring E, O&#x2019;Donoghue E (eds) Papers in Italian Archaeology VII: the Archaeology of Death: Proceedings of the Seventh Conference of Italian Archaeology Held at the National University of Ireland, Galway, April 16&#x2013;18 2016. Archaeopress, Oxford, pp 410&#x2013;418</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammann S, Cramp LJE (2018) Towards the detection of dietary cereal processing through absorbed lipid biomarkers in archaeological pottery. J Archaeol Sci 93:74&#x2013;81. 10.1016/j.jas.2018.02.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jas.2018.02.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansel FA, Copley MS, Madureira LAS, Evershed RP (2004) Thermally produced &#x3c9;-(o-alkylphenyl)alkanoic acids provide evidence for the processing of marine products in archaeological pottery vessels. Tetrahedron Lett 45:2999&#x2013;3002. 10.1016/j.tetlet.2004.01.111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tetlet.2004.01.111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harry KG, Frink L, O&#x2019;Toole B, Charest A (2009) How to make an unfired clay cooking pot: Understanding the technological choices made by Arctic potters. J Archaeol Method Theory 16:33&#x2013;50. 10.1007/s10816-009-9061-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10816-009-9061-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heron C, Evershed RP (1993) The analysis of organic residues and the study of pottery use. Archaeol Method Theory 5:247&#x2013;284</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heron C, Nemcek N, Bonfield KM et al (1994) The chemistry of neolithic beeswax. Naturwissenschaften 81:266&#x2013;269. 10.1007/BF01131579</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01131579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingravallo E (2002) Grotta Cappuccini (Galatone) Tra eneolitico e primo Bronzo. Congedo, Galatina</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Insoll T (2004) Archaeology, ritual, religion. Routledge, London</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ionescu C, Hoeck V (2020) Ceramic technology. How to investigate surface finishing. Archaeol Anthropol Sci 12:204. 10.1007/s12520-020-01144-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12520-020-01144-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ippolito F (2016) Before the Iron Age The oldest settlements in the hinterland of the Sibaritide (Calabria, Italy. PhD thesis, University of Groningen</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ippolito F (2017) La Galleria dei Vasi della Grotta di S. Angelo II. Nuovi dati sul Protoappenninico della Sibaritide e sulle sue relazioni con le sponde adriatiche. In: Vv.Aa. (ed) XLVII Riunione Scientifica Preistoria e Protostoria della Puglia. Ostuni, pp 1119&#x2013;1024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ippolito F, Attema PAJ (2018) Connettivit&#xe0; regionale e interregionale in et&#xe0; preistorica e protostorica nella Valle del Raganello. In: Colelli C, Larocca A (eds) Il Pollino Barriera naturale e crocevia di culture. Universita&#x2019; della Calabria, pp 29&#x2013;37</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaksson S, Karlsson C, Eriksson T (2010) Ergosterol (5, 7, 22-ergostatrien-3&#x3b2;-ol) as a potential biomarker for alcohol fermentation in lipid residues from prehistoric pottery. J Archaeol Sci 37:3263&#x2013;3268. 10.1016/j.jas.2010.07.027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jas.2010.07.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones MK, Briggs DEG, Eglington G et al (1999) Use and trade of bitumen in antiquity and prehistory: molecular archaeology reveals secrets of past civilizations. Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci 354:33&#x2013;50. 10.1098/rstb.1999.0358</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rstb.1999.0358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klimchouk A, Palmer N, De Waele A J, et al (eds) (2017) Hypogene karst regions and caves of the world. Springer International Publishing, Cham</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larocca F (ed) (2005) La Miniera pre-protostorica di Grotta della Monaca (Sant&#x2019;Agata Di Esaro - Cosenza). Centro Regionale di Speleologia "Enzo dei Medici," Roseto Capo Spulico</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larocca F (2017) Cassano allo Ionio 2017. Un progetto di ricerca speleo-archeologica. Speleologia 76:48&#x2013;49</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larocca F (2018) Dal Pollino all&#x2019;Orsomarso. L&#x2019;uso funerario delle cavit&#xe0; naturali in et&#xe0; pre-protostorica. In: Colelli C, Larocca A (eds) Il Pollino. Barriera naturale e crocevia di culture. Universit&#xe0; della Calabria, Cosenza, pp 13&#x2013;27</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larocca F, Breglia F (2014) L&#x2019;alta Valle dell&#x2019;Esaro e le sue miniere preistoriche. Speleologia 71:30&#x2013;36</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis-Williams JD (2002) The mind in the cave: Consciousness and the origins of art. Thames &amp; Hudson, London</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez SM, Skeates R (2022) Caves, Senses, and Ritual Flows in the Iberian Iron Age: The territory of Edeta. Open Archaeol 8:1&#x2013;29. 10.1515/opar-2022-0222</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/opar-2022-0222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucquin A, Colonese AC, Farrell TFG, Craig OE (2016) Utilising phytanic acid diastereomers for the characterisation of archaeological lipid residues in pottery samples. Tetrahedron Lett 57:703&#x2013;707. 10.1016/j.tetlet.2016.01.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tetlet.2016.01.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marino DAM, Nicoletti G (2023) Ricerche archeologiche nei laghi della Sila (Calabria, Italia). Comunit&#xe0; di agricoltori e pescatori tra Neolitico ed Eneolitico. In: La Rocca R (ed) Atti del VI convegno nazionale di archeologia subacquea, 10&#x2013;12 Ottobre 2019, Taormina. Palermo University, Palermo, pp 453&#x2013;472</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarroll D, Loader NJ (2004) Stable isotopes in tree rings. Quat Sci Rev 23:771&#x2013;801</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGovern P, Jalabadze M, Batiuk S et al (2017) Early Neolithic Wine of Georgia in the South Caucasus. Proc Natl Acad Sci 114:E10309&#x2013;E10318. 10.1073/pnas.1714728114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1714728114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5715782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29133421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michel RH, McGovern PE, Badler VR (1993) The first wine &amp; beer. Chemical detection of ancient fermented beverages. Anal Chem 65:408A&#x2013;413. 10.1021/ac00056a002. A</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ac00056a002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milisauskas S (ed) (2011) European Prehistory. Springer, New York, NY</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milisauskas S, Kruk J (2011a) Middle Neolithic/Early Copper Age, Continuity, Diversity, and greater Complexity, 5500/5000&#x2013;3500 BC. In: Milisauskas S (ed) European prehistory. Springer, New York, NY, pp 223&#x2013;291</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milisauskas S, Kruk J (2011b) Late Neolithic/Late Copper Age 3500&#x2013;2200 BC. In: Milisauskas S (ed) European prehistory. Springer, New York, NY, pp 293&#x2013;325</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minelli A, Guglielmi S (eds) (2020) Nel regno del fango: speleoarcheologia della Grotta di Polla (Salerno, Italia): Risultati delle prime campagne di scavo. Archaeo, Oxford</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mottram HR, Dudd SN, Lawrence GJ et al (1999) New chromatographic, mass spectrometric and stable isotope approaches to the classification of degraded animal fats preserved in archaeological pottery. J Chromatogr A 833:209&#x2013;221. 10.1016/S0021-9673(98)01041-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0021-9673(98)01041-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moyes H (2012a) Introduction. In: Moyes H (ed) Sacred darkness: A global perspective on the ritual use of caves. University Press of Colorado, Boulder, pp 1&#x2013;11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moyes H (ed) (2012b) Sacred darkness: A global perspective on the ritual use of caves. University Press of Colorado, Boulder</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nardella F, Landi N, Degano I et al (2019) Chemical investigations of bitumen from Neolithic archaeological excavations in Central-Southern Italy by gas chromatography/mass spectrometry combined with principal component analysis. Anal Methods 11. 10.1039/C8AY02429D</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natali E, Agrostelli M, Feriozzi F et al (2021) I livelli neolitici della Grotta San Michele di Saracena (CS). In: Mittica G, Colelli C, Larocca A, Larocca F (eds) Dal Pollino all&#x2019;Orsomarso. Ricerche archeologiche fra Ionio e Tirreno. Edizioni Quasar, Roma, pp 33&#x2013;59</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicoletti G (2004) Medio versante Ionico calabrese: aspetti della prima et&#xe0; dei metalli. In: Vv.Aa. (ed) Preistoria e Protostoria della Calabria, Atti della XXXVII Riunione Scientifica dell&#x2019;Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria. Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria, Firenze, pp 773&#x2013;779</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orton C, Tyers P, Vince A (1993) Pottery in archaeology. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacciarelli M (ed) (1997) Acque, grotte e dei: 3000 anni di culti preromani in Romagna, Marche e Abruzzo. Musei Civici di Imola, Imola</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacciarelli M (2011) L&#x2019;Eneolitico della Calabria tirrenica: Nuovi dati sull&#x2019;articolazione cronoculturale. Riv Orig XXXIII Nuova Serie V:249&#x2013;288</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacciarelli M, Talamo P (2011) Sull&#x2019;articolazione dell&#x2019;et&#xe0; del rame nell&#x2019;italia meridionale tirrenica. In: Vv.Aa. (ed) L&#x2019;et&#xe0; Del Rame in Italia. Atti della XLIII Riunione Scientifica dell&#x2019;Istituto Italiano di preistoria e Protostoria. Istituto italiano di preistoria e protostoria, Firenze, pp 87&#x2013;94</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patrizi G, Rageot M, Cafisso S et al (2025) Signs of the sacred at the sanctuary of Gravisca, Italy: Reconstruction of an Etruscan ritual through a multidisciplinary approach. Archaeometry 67:235&#x2013;247. 10.1111/arcm.13005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/arcm.13005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pecci A, Giorgi G, Salvini L, Cau Ontiveros M&#xc1; (2013) Identifying wine markers in ceramics and plasters using gas chromatography&#x2013;mass spectrometry. Experimental and archaeological materials. J Archaeol Sci 40:109&#x2013;115. 10.1016/j.jas.2012.05.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jas.2012.05.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennetta A, Fico D, Eramo G et al (2020a) Extending the inter-Adriatic trade of bitumen beyond the fifth millennium BCE. Org Geochem 142:104013. 10.1016/j.orggeochem.2020.104013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.orggeochem.2020.104013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennetta A, Fico D, Lucrezia Savino M et al (2020b) Characterization of Bronze age pottery from the Grotte di Pertosa-Auletta (Italy): Results from the first analysis of organic lipid residues. J Archaeol Sci Rep 31:102308. 10.1016/j.jasrep.2020.102308</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jasrep.2020.102308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perruchini E, Glatz C, Hald MM et al (2018) Revealing invisible brews: A new approach to the chemical identification of ancient beer. J Archaeol Sci 100:176&#x2013;190. 10.1016/j.jas.2018.05.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jas.2018.05.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pessina A, Tin&#xe9; V (2008) Archeologia del neolitico: l&#x2019;Italia tra VI e IV millennio a.C. Carocci editore, Roma</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce C (2005) Reverse engineering the ceramic cooking pot: cost and performance properties of plain and textured vessels. J Archaeol Method Theory 12:117&#x2013;157. 10.1007/s10816-005-5665-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10816-005-5665-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poli A, Zanellati A, Piano E et al (2024) Cultivable fungal diversity in two karstic caves in Italy: Under-investigated habitats as source of putative novel taxa. Sci Rep 14:4164. 10.1038/s41598-024-54548-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-54548-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10879487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38378919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prijatelj A, Skeates R (2019) Caves as vibrant places: A theoretical manifesto. In: B&#xfc;ster L, Warmenbol E, Mleku&#x17e; D (eds) Between worlds: Understanding ritual cave use in later prehistory. Springer International Publishing, Cham, pp 9&#x2013;28</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rageot M, Lep&#xe8;re C, Henry A et al (2021) Management systems of adhesive materials throughout the Neolithic in the North-West Mediterranean. J Archaeol Sci 126:105309. 10.1016/j.jas.2020.105309</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jas.2020.105309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reber EA (2022) An archaeologist&#x2019;s guide to organic residues in pottery. University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regert M (2011) Analytical strategies for discriminating archeological fatty substances from animal origin. Mass Spectrom Rev 30:177&#x2013;220. 10.1002/mas.20271</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mas.20271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21337597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renfrew C (2007) The archaeology of ritual, of cult, and of religion. In: Kyriakidis E (ed) The Archaeology of Ritual. Cotsen Institute of Archaeology Press at UCLA, Los Angeles, pp 109&#x2013;122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice PM (1987) Pottery analysis: A sourcebook. University of Chicago Press, Chicago and London</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice PM (2015) Pottery analysis, second edition: A sourcebook. University of Chicago Press, Chicago, IL</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roffet-Salque M, Dunne J, Altoft DT et al (2017) From the inside out: Upscaling organic residue analyses of archaeological ceramics. J Archaeol Sci Rep 16:627&#x2013;640. 10.1016/j.jasrep.2016.04.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jasrep.2016.04.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarret M, Adam P, Schaeffer P et al (2017) Organic substances from Egyptian jars of the Early Dynastic period (3100&#x2013;2700 BCE): mode of preparation, alteration processes and botanical (re)assessment of "cedrium." J Archaeol Sci Rep 14:420&#x2013;431. 10.1016/j.jasrep.2017.06.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jasrep.2017.06.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffer MB (1988) The effects of surface treatment on permeability and evaporative cooling effectiveness of pottery. In: Farquhar R, Hancock R, Pavlish L (eds) Proceedings of the 26th international archaeometry symposium. University of Toronto press, Toronto, pp 22&#x2013;29</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffer MB (1990) The influence of surface treatment on heating effectiveness of ceramic vessels. J Archaeol Sci 17:373&#x2013;381. 10.1016/0305-4403(90)90002-M</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0305-4403(90)90002-M</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffer MB, Skibo JM (1989) A provisional theory of ceramic abrasion. Am Anthropol 91:101&#x2013;115</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffer MB, Skibo JM, Boelke TC et al (1994) New perspectives on experimental archaeology: Surface treatments and thermal response of the clay cooking pot. Am Antiq 59:197&#x2013;217. 10.2307/281927</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/281927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skeates R (1994) Ritual, context, and gender in neolithic South-Eastern Italy. J Eur Archaeol 2:199&#x2013;214. 10.1179/096576694800719102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1179/096576694800719102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skeates R (2016) Experiencing darkness and light in caves: Later prehistoric examples from Seulo in central Sardinia. In: Dowd M, Hensey R (eds) The archaeology of darkness. Oxbow Books, pp 39&#x2013;49</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skibo JM (1992) Pottery function: A use-alteration perspective. Plenum, New York</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skibo JM (2013) Understanding pottery function. In: Skibo JM (ed) Understanding pottery function. Springer, New York, NY, pp 1&#x2013;25</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skibo JM (2015) Pottery use-alteration analysis. In: Marreiros JM, Gibaja Bao JF, Ferreira Bicho N (eds) Use-Wear and residue analysis in archaeology. Springer International Publishing, Cham, pp 189&#x2013;198</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skibo JM, Schiffer M (2008) People and things: A behavioral approach to material culture. Springer Science &amp; Business Media, Brooklyn</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;oberl L, Horvat M, Ga&#x161;pari&#x10d; A&#x17d; et al (2014) Neolithic and Eneolithic activities inferred from organic residue analysis of pottery from Mala Triglavca, Moverna Vas and Ajdovska jama, Slovenia. Doc Praehist 41:149&#x2013;179. 10.4312/dp.41.9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4312/dp.41.9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele VJ, Stern B (2017) Red Lustrous Wheelmade Ware: Analysis of organic residues in Late Bronze Age trade and storage vessels from the eastern Mediterranean. J Archaeol Sci Rep 16:641&#x2013;657. 10.1016/j.jasrep.2017.06.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stern B, Heron C, Serpico M, Bouiau J (2000) A comparison of methods for establishing fatty acid concentration gradients across potsherds: A case study using Late Bronze Age Canaanite amphorae. Archaeometry 42:399&#x2013;414</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straus LG (1990) Underground archaeology: Perspectives on caves and rockshelters. J Archaeol Method Theory 2:255&#x2013;304</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straus LG (1997) Convenient cavities: Some human uses of caves and rock shelters. In: Bonsall C, Tolan-Smith C (eds) The human uses of caves. Archaeo, Oxford, pp 1&#x2013;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talamo P (2008a) Le aree interne della Campania centro-settentrionale durante le fasi evolute dell&#xb4;Eneolitico: Osservazioni sulle dinamiche culturali. Orig Preistoria E Protostoria Delle Civilt&#xe0; Antiche XXX:187&#x2013;220</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talamo P (2008b) Dinamiche culturali nelle aree interne della Campania centro-settentrionale durante le prime fasi dell&#x2019;Eneolitico. Riv Sci Preistoriche LVIII 2008 125&#x2013;164. 10.1400/206240</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanasi D (2014) Lighting up the dark: the role of G&#x127;ar Mirdum in Maltese prehistory. In: Gull&#xec; D (ed) From cave to dolmen: ritual and symbolic aspects in the prehistory between Sciacca, Sicily and the central mediterranean. Archaeo, Oxford, pp 287&#x2013;310</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarquini S, Isola I, Favalli M, Battistini A (2007) TINITALY, a digital elevation model of Italy with a 10 m-cell size (Version 1.0) [Data set]. Istituto Na zionale di Geofisica e Vulcanologia (INGV). 10.13127/TINITALY/1.0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tin&#xe9; S (1962) Successione delle culture preistoriche in Calabria alla luce dei recenti scavi in provincia di Cosenza. Klearchos 13&#x2013;14:38&#x2013;48</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tin&#xe9; S (1964) La grotta di Sant&#x2019;Angelo III a Cassano Ionio. Atti E Mem Soc Magna Grecia Nuova Serie V:11&#x2013;55</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tin&#xe9; S (1987) Il Neolitico. In: Settis S (ed) Storia della Calabria Antica, I. Gangemi Editore, Reggio Calabria-Roma, pp 39&#x2013;63</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tin&#xe9; V, Natali E (2004) La Grotta di San Michele di Saracena (CS): Una sequenza statigrafica dal Neolitico antico al Bronzo medio. In: Vv.Aa. (ed) Preistoria e Protostoria della Calabria. Atti della XXXVII Riunione scientifica dell&#x2019;Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria. Istituto Italiano di Preistoria e Protostoria, Firenze, pp 693&#x2013;702</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomkins P (2009) Domesticity by default. Ritual, ritualization and cave-use in the Neolithic Aegean. Oxf J Archaeol 28:125&#x2013;153. 10.1111/j.1468-0092.2009.00322.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-0092.2009.00322.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ustinova Y (2009) Caves and the ancient Greek mind: Descending underground in the search for ultimate truth. Oxford University Press, Oxford</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Leusen PM, Attema PAJ (2002) Regional archaeological patterns in the Sibaritide; preliminary results of the RPC field survey campaign 2000. Palaeohistoria 397&#x2013;416</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vykukal R, Mavridis F, Tankosi&#x107; &#x17d; (2021) Lipid analysis of pottery from the Early Bronze Age II burials at Ayia Triada Cave, Southern Euboea, Greece: Evidence for ritualized consumption? Archaeometry 63:1342&#x2013;1362. 10.1111/arcm.12672</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/arcm.12672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson PJ (2001) Theory in cave archaeology. Midcont J Archaeol 26:139&#x2013;143</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whelton HL, Hammann S, Cramp LJE et al (2021) A call for caution in the analysis of lipids and other small biomolecules from archaeological contexts. J Archaeol Sci 132:105397. 10.1016/j.jas.2021.105397</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jas.2021.105397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitehouse RD (1992) Underground religion: Cult and culture in prehistoric Italy. Accordia Research Centre, University of London, London</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young LC, Stone T (1990) The thermal properties of textured ceramics: An experimental study. J Field Archaeol 17:195&#x2013;203. 10.1179/009346990791548295</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1179/009346990791548295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>