<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41179247</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2377-9608</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Jan-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>SAGE open nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>SAGE Open Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Implementation of Evidence-Based Intrapartum Care and its Associated Factors Among Obstetric Care Providers Working in South Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23779608251393755</StartPage><MedlinePgn>23779608251393755</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23779608251393755</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/23779608251393755</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Despite the availability of clear guidelines, evidence from low- and middle-income countries, including Ethiopia, shows persistent gaps in implementing evidence-based intrapartum practices, contributing to high maternal and neonatal morbidity and mortality. In southern Ethiopia, including the Wolaita Zone, where resource constraints are common, the extent of adherence to these practices and factors influencing their implementation is not well understood. Therefore, this study aimed to assess the implementation level of evidence-based intrapartum care practice and its associated factors among obstetric care providers working in hospitals in Wolaita Zone in 2022.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A facility-based cross-sectional study was conducted from August 1-31, 2022, among 332 obstetric care providers in the hospitals of the Wolaita Zone. The data were collected using structured interviewer-administered questionnaires and non-participatory observation with a standard checklist supplemented with record review. Data were entered into EpiData version 4.6.0.2 and then exported to Stata Version 15 for analysis. Binary logistic regression analyses were conducted to identify factors associated with evidence-based intrapartum care among obstetric care providers. An adjusted odds ratio (AOR) with a 95% confidence interval was reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The implementation of evidence-based intrapartum practice was 52.5% [95% CI (47.1%-57.9%)]. Work experience &gt;5 years [AOR:1.74;95%CI (1.04,2.91)], knowledge [AOR:1.77; 95% CI (1.06,2.95)], in-service training [AOR = 1.83; 95% CI (1.05,3.17)], access to EBP guidelines [AOR:1.70; 95% CI (1.01,2.85)], and managerial support [AOR:3.1; 95% CI (1.11,8.67)] were associated with the implementation of evidence-based intrapartum care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Evidence-based intrapartum care practice implementation was low in the study area. Years of work experience, knowledge, in-service training, availability of EBP guidelines, and support from managers were the factors with a significant association with evidence-based intrapartum care practice. Strengthening these enabling factors may help creating an environment that facilitates greater adherence to recommended intrapartum care practices, thereby improving maternal and newborn outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Girma</LastName><ForeName>Senait</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Reproductive Health and Human Nutrition, College of Health Sciences and Medicine, Wolaita Sodo University, Wolaita Sodo, Ethiopia.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">435721</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Assele</LastName><ForeName>Desalegn Dawit</ForeName><Initials>DD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2006-6368</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Hawassa University, Hawassa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ganta</LastName><ForeName>Abera Gezume</ForeName><Initials>AG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-9975-4947</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, College of Health Science and Medicine, Jinka University, Jinka, Ethiopia.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">644278</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wabeto</LastName><ForeName>Ermias</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6079-2642</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, College of Health Science and Medicine, Jinka University, Jinka, Ethiopia.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">644278</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>SAGE Open Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101724853</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2377-9608</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">evidence-based intrapartum care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obstetric care</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41179247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12579183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23779608251393755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_23779608251393755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abebe A. H., Mmusi-Phetoe R. (2023). Quality of obstetric and newborn care in health centers of Addis Ababa city: Using the WHO quality framework. BMC Health Services Research, 23(1), 459. 10.1186/s12913-023-09414-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-023-09414-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10169211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37161461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham J. M., Melendez-Torres G. (2023). A realist review of interventions targeting maternal health in low- and middle-income countries. Women's Health, 19, 17455057231205687. 10.1177/17455057231205687</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17455057231205687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10617292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37899651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajegbile M. L. (2023). Closing the gap in maternal health access and quality through targeted investments in low-resource settings. Journal of Global Health Reports, 7, 1&#x2013;5. 10.29392/001c.88917</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29392/001c.88917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asrese K. (2020). Quality of intrapartum care at health centers in Jabi Tehinan district, North West Ethiopia: Clients&#x2019; perspective. BMC Health Services Research, 20, 1&#x2013;12. 10.1186/s12913-020-05321-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-020-05321-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32429907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chauke L. (2025). Improving access to emergency obstetric care in low- and middle-income countries. Best Practice &amp; Research Clinical Obstetrics &amp; Gynaecology, 98, 102572. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bpobgyn.2024.102572</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39667291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes C. T., Oliveira S., Santos R., Francisco A. A., Riesco M. L. G., Shimoda G. T. (2018). Implementation of evidence-based practices in normal delivery care. Revista Latino-americana de Enfermagem, 26, e2988. 10.1590/1518-8345.2177.2988</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1518-8345.2177.2988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5863276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29538583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degu A. B., Yilma T. M., Beshir M. A., Inthiran A. (2022). Evidence-based practice and its associated factors among point-of-care nurses working at the teaching and specialized hospitals of northwest Ethiopia: A concurrent study. PLoS One, 17(5), e0267347. 10.1371/journal.pone.0267347</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0267347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9070954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35511810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dessie G., Jara D., Alem G., Mulugeta H., Zewdu T., Wagnew F., Bigley R., Burrowes S. (2020). Evidence-Based practice and associated factors among health care providers working in public hospitals in northwest Ethiopia during 2017. Current Therapeutic Research, 93, 100613. 10.1016/j.curtheres.2020.100613</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.curtheres.2020.100613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7708748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewana Z. (2017). Quality of delivery service at public health facilities in arba minch district, gamo gofa zone, southern Ethiopia. Journal of Gynecology and Obstetrics, 5(2), 31. 10.11648/j.jgo.20170502.12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11648/j.jgo.20170502.12</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EPHI, &amp; ICF . (2019). Ethiopian public health institute (EPHI) [Ethiopia] and ICF. Ethiopia mini demographic and health survey 2019: Key indicators. Rockville, maryland, USA: EPHI and ICF. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figa Z., Zemeskel A. G., Alemu A., Abebe M. (2024). Evidence-based intrapartum care practice and associated factors among obstetrics workers in Ethiopia, systematic review and meta-analysis. SAGE Open Medicine, 12, 20503121241261210. 10.1177/20503121241261210</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20503121241261210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11289799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39086555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisseha G., Berhane Y., Worku A. (2019). Quality of intrapartum and newborn care in tigray, northern Ethiopia. BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth, 19(1), 37. 10.1186/s12884-019-2184-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-019-2184-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6339373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30658706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FMoH . (2022). National Guideline on Prevention and Management of Postpartum Hemorrhage.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudeta T. G., Terefe A. B., Mengistu G. T., Sori S. A. (2024). A systematic review and meta-analysis of evidence-based practice and its associated factors among health professionals in Ethiopia. BMC Health Services Research, 24(1), 1518. 10.1186/s12913-024-11957-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-024-11957-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11608491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39616330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyengar K., Gupta M., Pal S., Kaur K., Singla N., Verma M., Dhiman A., Singla R., Rohilla M., Suri V., Aggarwal N., Singh T., Goel P., Goel N. K., Pant R., Gaur K. L., Gehlot H., Bhati I., Verma M., Patel S. (2022). Baseline assessment of evidence-based intrapartum care practices in medical schools in 3 states in India: A mixed-methods study. Global Health: Science and Practice, 10(2), 1&#x2013;17. 10.9745/GHSP-D-21-00590</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9745/GHSP-D-21-00590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9053154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35487543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabakian-Khasholian T., Bashour H., El-Nemer A., Kharouf M., Elsheikh O., Group L. C. S., Sheikha S., Saleh S., Jaffa M., Barazi R. (2018). Implementation of a labour companionship model in three public hospitals in arab middle-income countries. Acta Paediatrica, 107, 35&#x2013;43. 10.1111/apa.14540</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apa.14540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30570794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassahun F., Anteneh M., Wanzahun G. (2017). Evidence based intrapartum care and factors among obstetric care providers, northwest Ethiopia: An institution based cross-sectional study, 2015. Primary Health Care Open Access, 07(03), 1&#x2013;7. 10.4172/2167-1079.1000274</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2167-1079.1000274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levin R. F., Fineout-Overholt E., Melnyk B. M., Barnes M., Vetter M. J. (2011). Fostering evidence-based practice to improve nurse and cost outcomes in a community health setting: A pilot test of the advancing research and clinical practice through close collaboration model. Nursing Administration Quarterly, 35(1), 21&#x2013;33. 10.1097/NAQ.0b013e31820320ff</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NAQ.0b013e31820320ff</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21157261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masuda C., Ferolin S. K., Masuda K., Smith C., Matsui M. (2020). Evidence-based intrapartum practice and its associated factors at a tertiary teaching hospital in the Philippines, a descriptive mixed-methods study. BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth, 20(1), 1&#x2013;10. 10.1186/s12884-020-2778-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-020-2778-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7003416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32024504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihretie G. N., Ayele A. D., Liyeh T. M., Beyene F. Y., Kassa B. G., Arega D. T., Belay H. G., Worke M. D. (2023). Active management of the third stage of labour in Ethiopia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One, 18(4), e0281343. 10.1371/journal.pone.0281343</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0281343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10118110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37079501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller S., Abalos E., Chamillard M., Ciapponi A., Colaci D., Comand&#xe9; D., Diaz V., Geller S., Hanson C., Langer A., Manuelli V., Millar K., Morhason-Bello I., Castro C. P., Pileggi V. N., Robinson N., Skaer M., Souza J. P., Vogel J. P., Althabe F. (2016). Beyond too little, too late and too much, too soon: A pathway towards evidence-based, respectful maternity care worldwide. Lancet, 388(10056), 2176&#x2013;2192. 10.1016/s0140-6736(16)31472-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(16)31472-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27642019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukamurigo J., Dencker A., Nyirazinyoye L., Ntaganira J., Berg M. (2019). Quality of intrapartum care for healthy women with spontaneous onset of labour in Rwanda: A health facility-based, cross-sectional study. Sexual &amp; Reproductive Healthcare, 19, 78&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.srhc.2019.01.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30928139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nori W., Kassim M. A. K., Helmi Z. R., Pantazi A. C., Brezeanu D., Brezeanu A. M., Penciu R. C., Serbanescu L. (2023). Non-pharmacological pain management in labor: A systematic review. Journal of Clinical Medicine, 12(23), 1&#x2013;21. 10.3390/jcm12237203</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12237203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10707619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38068274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarikhani Y., Najibi S. M., Razavi Z. (2024). Key barriers to the provision and utilization of maternal health services in low-and lower-middle-income countries; a scoping review. BMC Women's Health, 24(1), 325. 10.1186/s12905-024-03177-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-024-03177-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11151574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38840156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semrau K. E. A., Miller K. A., Lipsitz S., Fisher-Bowman J., Karlage A., Neville B. A., Krasne M., Gass J., Jurczak A., Pratap Singh V., Singh S., Marx Delaney M., Hirschhorn L. R., Kodkany B., Kumar V., Gawande A. A. (2020). Does adherence to evidence-based practices during childbirth prevent perinatal mortality? A post-hoc analysis of 3,274 births in uttar pradesh, India. BMJ Global Health, 5(9), e002268. 10.1136/bmjgh-2019-002268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2019-002268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7490951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32928798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sendekie D. A., Belay M. A., Ayalew Yimer S., Degu Ayele A. (2022). Evidence-Based intrapartum practice and associated factors among obstetric care providers working in public hospitals of South Wollo Zone North-Central Ethiopia: An institutional-based cross-sectional study. International Journal of Women's Health, 14, 719&#x2013;730. 10.2147/IJWH.S351795</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJWH.S351795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9126653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35615384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw-Battista J., Fineberg A., Boehler B., Skubic B., Woolley D., Tilton Z. (2011). Obstetrician and nurse&#x2013;midwife collaboration: Successful public health and private practice partnership. Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, 118(3), 663&#x2013;672. 10.1097/AOG.0b013e31822ac86f</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0b013e31822ac86f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21860298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonia T., Robina k., Hussain M., Ishrat S., Ali W., Syed A. (2017). Nurses&#x2019; awareness, perception and barriers for implementation of evidence based practices at Govt. hospital Lahore. Saudi Journal of Medical and Pharmaceutical Sciences, 3(6), 615&#x2013;621. 10.21276/sjmps</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21276/sjmps</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tolu L. B., Jeldu W. G., Feyissa G. T. (2020). Effectiveness of utilizing the WHO safe childbirth checklist on improving essential childbirth practices and maternal and perinatal outcome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One, 15(6), e0234320. 10.1371/journal.pone.0234320</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0234320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7292415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNICEF.  (2025). Neonatal mortality. Retrieved September 13, 2025, from https://data.unicef.org/topic/child-survival/neonatal-mortality/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakjira D., Andualem E. M., Bekele A., Beyene D. T. (2025). Evidence-based intrapartum care practice and associated factors among obstetric care providers in Jimma Zone public hospitals, southwest Ethiopia: A cross-sectional study. SAGE Open Medicine, 13, 20503121251358969. 10.1177/20503121251358969</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20503121251358969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12301604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40726839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weerasingha T. K., Ratnayake C., Abeyrathne R. M., Tennakoon S. U. B. (2024). Evidence-based intrapartum care during vaginal births: Direct observations in a tertiary care hospital in Central Sri Lanka. Heliyon, 10(7), 1&#x2013;12. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e28517</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e28517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10988013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38571647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO  (2018a). 
WHO recommendations Intrapartum care for a positive childbirth experience Transforming care of women and babies for improved health and well-being Executive summary
. 
<i>World Health Organization</i>
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO . (2018b). WHO recommendations: intrapartum care for a positive childbirth experience. WHO.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30070803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO.  (2025). Maternal mortality. Retrieved September 13, 2025, from https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/maternal-mortality</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wodajo S., Mosisa A., Misganaw D., Minayehu A., Teklay B., Gashaw Y., Gardie Y., Dagnaw Y., Olani A. (2023). Evidence-based intrapartum care practice and associated factors among obstetric care providers working in hospitals of the four Wollega Zones, Oromia, Ethiopia. PLoS One, 18(1), e0275506. 10.1371/journal.pone.0275506</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0275506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9879444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36701302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolaita Wonal Health Department report . (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zakar R., Iqbal S. (2024). Editorial: Social determinants of women's health in low and middle income countries. Frontiers in Global Women's Health, 5, 1482047. 10.3389/fgwh.2024.1482047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fgwh.2024.1482047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11551108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39530038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeleke A. M., Ferede Y. A., Tassew W. C., Gonete Y. A. (2025). Practice of pharmacological labor pain management and associated factors among healthcare providers in Ethiopia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. AJOG Global Reports, 5(2), 100456. 10.1016/j.xagr.2025.100456</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xagr.2025.100456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11993160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40226350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelka M. A., Yalew A. W., Debelew G. T. (2023). Effectiveness of a continuum of care in maternal health services on the reduction of maternal and neonatal mortality: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Heliyon, 9(6), e17559. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e17559</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10318503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37408879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>