<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41652473</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6963</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC health services research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Health Serv Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Late antenatal care initiation and its associated factors among pregnant women attending antenatal care at public hospitals of Kellem Wollega zone, Western Ethiopia: a facility-based cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">342</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12913-026-14142-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Late antenatal care initiation refers to the beginning of antenatal care for the first time during pregnancy after 12 weeks of gestation. Beginning antenatal care services after the first trimester misses opportunities to offer preventive measures, screening, and effective interventions early in the pregnancy. There is limited evidence on the magnitude of late antenatal care initiation in the Kellem Wollega Zone, Western Ethiopia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The objective of this study was to assess the magnitude of late antenatal care initiation and its associated factors among pregnant women attending antenatal care at public hospitals in the Kellem Wollega Zone from August 10 to September 10, 2023.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY" NlmCategory="METHODS">A facility-based cross-sectional study was conducted in public hospitals of Kellem Wollega Zone from August 10 to September 10, 2023. Four public hospitals were selected for this study. A total of 410 pregnant women participated in the study. A structured questionnaire was used to collect data on sociodemographic characteristics, obstetric and medical history, ANC-related factors, and health facility-related factors. The statistical analysis comprised descriptive statistics, and multivariable logistic regression was used to assess late antenatal care initiation and its associated factors. Statistical significance was determined using multivariable logistic regression analysis with a p-value of &lt;&#x2009;0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among 410 pregnant women, the magnitude of late first antenatal care initiation was 61.7% (95% CI 57.1-66.3%) with a mean gestational age of 17.27 weeks. Rural residence (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.83; 95% CI: 1.01-3.30), perceived appropriate time of first ANC initiation after 12 weeks of gestation (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;6.89; 95% CI: 3.44-13.8), means of pregnancy recognition by missed period (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.6; 95% CI: 1.25-5.40), and lack of decision-making power for ANC services (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;5.2; 95% CI: 2.86-9.5) were significantly associated with increased odds of late ANC initiation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION AND RECOMMENDATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The magnitude of late antenatal care initiation was high. Rural residence, perceived appropriate time of first ANC initiation after 12 weeks of gestation, means of pregnancy recognition, and lack of decision-making power for ANC services were significantly associated with increased late ANC initiation. Stakeholders working in maternal and child healthcare need to focus on creating awareness of the recommended ANC starting time, empowering women to decide by themselves about antenatal care initiation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eticha</LastName><ForeName>Mulatu Werkina</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Midwifery, Bedele General Hospital, Bedele, Ethiopia. yomiyusabaaf12@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayele</LastName><ForeName>Habtamu Molla</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Maternal and Child Health Directorate, Federal Ministry of Health, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Obssie</LastName><ForeName>Gadisa Fitala</ForeName><Initials>GF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Institute of Health Science, Dambi Dollo University, Dambi Dollo, Dambi Dollo, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shiferaw</LastName><ForeName>Desalegn</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Institute of Health Science, Dambi Dollo University, Dambi Dollo, Dambi Dollo, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Health Serv Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088677</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6963</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011295" MajorTopicYN="Y">Prenatal Care</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006779" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hospitals, Public</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010342" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Acceptance of Health Care</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antenatal care,</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kellem wollega zone,</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Late first ANC initiation,</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Western Ethiopia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted in full accordance with the ethical principles outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki. An ethical approval letter was obtained from the ethical review committee of Dambi Dollo University. A formal letter explaining the objectives, rationale, and expected outcomes of the study was then written to the health institutions included in the study. The respondents were informed of the objective and purpose of the study and verbal consent was obtained from each respondent. In addition, confidentiality and privacy of the study population were assured and respected. Consent for publication: Not Applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41652473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12973663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-026-14142-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12913-026-14142-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>National Antenatal Care. National antenatal care guideline ensuring positive pregnancy experince. Federal ministry of health; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>2016 WHO ANC, Recommendations WHO. Antenatal Care for a Positive Pregnancy Experience.; 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28079998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO ANC. WHO Recommendations on Antenatal Care for a Positive Pregnancy Experience. Summary Textbook. 2018;10(January):1&#x2013;10. 10.1186/1742-4755-10-19.5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1742-4755-10-19.5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oshinyemi TE, Aluko JO, Oluwatosin OA. Focused antenatal care: Re-appraisal of current practices. 2018;10(August):90&#x2013;8. 10.5897/IJNM2018.0312</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudayu, et al. Timing and factors associated with first antenatal care booking among pregnant mothers in Gondar town. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2014;14(287):1&#x2013;7. 10.1186/1471-2393-14-287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2393-14-287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4152591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25154737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yezengaw TY. Late initiation of antenatal care and associated factors among antenatal care attendees in governmental health centers of Harar town Ethiopia. J Women&#x2019;s Health Care. 2022;11:561. 10.35248/2167-0420.22.11.561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.35248/2167-0420.22.11.561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grum T, Brhane E. Magnitude and factors associated with late antenatal care booking on first visit among pregnant women in public health centers in central zone of Tigray Region, Ethiopia: a cross sectional study. PLoS One. 2018;13(12):1&#x2013;9. 10.1371/journal. pone.0207922 Editor.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6281255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30517182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Bank Group. Trends in Maternal Mortality 2000 to 2020. estimates by WHO, UNICEF, UNFPA., World Bank Group and UNDESA/Population Division.Geneva: World Health Organization; 2023; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiferaw K, Mengiste B, Gobena T, Dheresa M. The effect of antenatal care on perinatal outcomes in Ethiopia: a systematic review and. 2021;42:1&#x2013;19. 10.1371/journal.pone.0245003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33444374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO, WORLD BANK. Strategies toward ending preventable maternal mortality (EPMM). (Department of reproductive health and research. ed.). Human reproduction programme research for impact. UNDP, UNFPA; 2015. http//www.who.int/reproductivehealth.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Bank Group, World Bank Group and the United Nations Population Division. Executive Summary Trends in Maternal Mortality 2000 to 2017 Estimates by WHO, UNICEF,UNFPA,. World health organization; 2017. www.who.int/reproductivehealth/publications/maternal-mortality-2017/en/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World bank. Trends in Maternal Mortality: 1990 to 2015. Published online 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manyeh AK, Amu A, Williams J, Gyapong M. Factors associated with the timing of antenatal clinic attendance among first-time mothers in rural Southern Ghana. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2020;20(1):47. 10.1186/s12884-020-2738-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-020-2738-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6972022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31959137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amsalu A, Ferede G, Assegu D. High Seroprevalence of syphilis infection among pregnant women in Yiregalem hospital Southern Ethiopia. BMC Infect Dis. 2018;18(1):109. 10.1186/s12879-018-2998-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-018-2998-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5840736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29510664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadele F, Getachew N, Fentie K, Amdisa D. Late initiation of antenatal care and associated factors among pregnant women in Jimma zone public hospitals, Southwest. BMC Health Serv Res Published Online 2022:1&#x2013;8. 10.1186/s12913-022-08055-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9097060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35549700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tola W, Negash E, Sileshi T, Id NW. Late initiation of antenatal care and associated factors among pregnant women attending antenatal clinic of Ilu Ababor Zone, Southwest Ethiopia: a cross-sectional study. Published Online 2021:1&#x2013;11. 10.1371/journal.pone.0246230</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7845970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33513182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birhanu A, Id T, Tesema GA. Prevalence and associated factors of delayed first antenatal care booking among reproductive age women in Ethiopia: a multilevel analysis of EDHS 2016 data. Published Online 2020:1&#x2013;13. 10.1371/journal.pone.0235538</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7337309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32628700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debelo BT, Danusa KT, Level of Late Initiation of Antenatal Care Visit and Associated Factors Amongst Antenatal Care Attendant Mothers in Gedo General Hospital. West Shoa Zone Oromia Region. 2022;10(June):1&#x2013;8. 10.3389/fpubh.2022.866030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2022.866030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9251194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35795708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sema A, Alemayehu T, Belay Y, Desalew A, Tekle Y, Roba KT. Late initiation of antenatal care and its associated factors among pregnant women in dire Dawa, Eastern Ethiopia. East Afr J Health Biomedical Sci. 2020;4(2):47&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Som&#xe9; A, Baguiya A, Coulibaly A, Bagnoa V, Kouanda S. Prevalence and factors associated with late first antenatal care visit in Kaya health district, Burkina Faso. Afr J Reprod Health. 2020;24(2):19&#x2013;26. 10.29063/ajrh2020/v24i2.2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29063/ajrh2020/v24i2.2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34077088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanna GYB. Timing of first antenatal care visit and its associated factors among pregnant women attending public health facilities in addis Ababa, Ethiopia. Ethiop J Health Sci. 2017;27(2):139&#x2013;46. 10.4314/ejhs.v27i2.6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ejhs.v27i2.6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5440828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28579709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfaye M, Dessie Y, Demena M, Yosef T. Late antenatal care initiation and its contributors among pregnant women at selected public health institutions in Southwest Ethiopia. Pan Afr Med J. 2021;39(1). 10.11604/pamj.2021.39.264.22909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8520420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34707765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abuka T, Alemu A. Assessment of timing of first antenatal care booking and associated factors among pregnant women who attend antenatal care at health facilities in Dilla town, Gedeo Zone, Southern Nations, Nationalities, and peoples Region, Ethiopia, 2014. J Pregnancy Child Heal. 2016;3(3). 10.4172/2376-127x.1000258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali N, Elbarazi I, Alabboud S, Al-maskari F, Loney T. Antenatal care initiation among pregnant women in the united Arab Emirates: the Mutaba &#x2019; ah study. 2020;8(June):1&#x2013;7. 10.3389/fpubh.2020.00211</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7300181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32596198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peprah MO, Yeboah FA, Danquah M. Factors influencing late initiation of antenatal visits among pregnant women in the dormaa central municipality in the Bono region of Ghana. 2022;10(01). 10.53075/Ijmsirq/665775376545</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolde, et al. Late initiation of antenatal care and associated factors among pregnant women in addis Zemen primary hospital. South BMC. 2019;16(73):1&#x2013;8. 10.1186/s12978-019-0745-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12978-019-0745-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6544982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31151402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adulo LA, Hassen SS. Magnitude and factors associated with late initiation of antenatal care booking on first visit among women in rural parts of Ethiopia. J Racial Ethnic Health Disparities. 2023;10(4):1693&#x2013;702. 10.1007/s40615-022-01354-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40615-022-01354-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35761146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebonwu J, Mumbauer A, Uys M, Wainberg ML, Medina-Marino A. Determinants of late antenatal care presentation in rural and peri-urban communities in South africa: A cross-sectional study. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(3):e0191903. 10.1371/journal.pone.0191903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0191903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5843210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29518082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ewunetie AA, Munea AM, Meselu BT, Simeneh MM, Meteku BT. DELAY on first antenatal care visit and its associated factors among pregnant women in public health facilities of Debre Markos town, North West Ethiopia. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2018;18(1):173. 10.1186/s12884-018-1748-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-018-1748-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5956942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29769122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girma N, Abdo M, Kalu S, et al. Late initiation of antenatal care among pregnant women in addis Ababa city, Ethiopia: a facility based cross &#x2013; sectional study. BMC Womens Health Published Online 2023:1&#x2013;8. 10.1186/s12905-022-02148-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9832813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36627620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolde F, Mulaw Z, Zena T, Biadgo B, Limenih MA. Determinants of late initiation for antenatal care follow up: the case of Northern Ethiopian pregnant women. BMC Res Notes Published Online 2018:1&#x2013;7. 10.1186/s13104-018-3938-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6260707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30482244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudayu TW. Proportion and factors associated with late antenatal care booking among pregnant mothers in Gondar town, North West Ethiopia. Afr J Reprod Health. 2015;19(2):93&#x2013;9. https://hdl.handle.net/10520/EJC174363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26506661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>