<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41145578</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Wear behaviour of hybrid ceramic reinforced FSP surface composite at varying temperatures.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>37454</StartPage><MedlinePgn>37454</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">37454</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-21162-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The greater challenges in the manufacturing and machine tool sectors are the periodic replacement of moving components due to wear, and its subsequent escalated product cost. The present research aims to address the issue by developing of novel lightweight surface composite reinforced with hybrid particles SiC and Y<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> processed through the Friction Stir Process (FSP). The test specimens were prepared by FSP by following four different wt.% of hybrid particles. The sliding tribological examination was executed to examine the wear characteristics of the surface composite at both ambient and elevated temperature environments. The achievement of dynamic recrystallisation is acknowledged through microstructure and grain size analysis results that reveal the finer grain structure at the nugget zone with the smaller grain size. The wear assessment outcomes endorse the improved wear characteristics of the Al-3SC-1Yo variant by upholding its 126% and 53.88% higher wear resistance than the base material at ambient and elevated temperatures, subject to the normal load of 45&#xa0;N. The post-worn-out surface analyses proclaim that ambient wear is driven by adhesion, two and three-body abrasion, whereas elevated temperature wear is driven by pure abrasion. It is comprehended from the wear results that 90% more wear loss is recorded during the elevated temperature than the same in the ambient environment. The quantitative comparison of ambient and elevated temperature wear through the observation of surface topography, and the inclusion of hybrid reinforcement on unique base materials are the key novelties of the proposed study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chenrayan</LastName><ForeName>Venkatesh</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Excellence-Advanced Materials Synthesis (CoE-AMS), (AU-STIC), Department of Mechanical Engineering, Alliance School of Applied Engineering, Alliance University, Bengaluru, 562106, India. venkyachvsh@yahoo.co.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahapurkar</LastName><ForeName>Kiran</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Excellence-Advanced Materials Synthesis (CoE-AMS), (AU-STIC), Department of Mechanical Engineering, Alliance School of Applied Engineering, Alliance University, Bengaluru, 562106, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Natarajan</LastName><ForeName>Panneerselvam</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Dhirajlal Gandhi College of Technology, Salem, 63840, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhaviripudi</LastName><ForeName>Vijayabhaskara Rao</ForeName><Initials>VR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de F&#xed;sica, Facultidad de Ciencias Naturales Matem&#xe1;tica y del Medio Ambiente, Universidad Tecnol&#xf3;gica Metropolitana, 7800002, Macul, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tirth</LastName><ForeName>Vineet</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mechanical Engineering Department, College of Engineering, King Khalid University, Abha, 61421, Asir, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Engineering and Technology Innovations, King Khalid University, Abha, 61421, Asir, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Algahtani</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Advanced Materials Science (RCAMS), King Khalid University, Guraiger, Abha, 61413, Asir, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petr&#x16f;</LastName><ForeName>Jana</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Machining, Assembly and Engineering Metrology, Faculty of Mechanical Engineering, V&#x160;B Technical University of Ostrava, Ostrava, Czech Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bashir</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Nasir</ForeName><Initials>MN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Machining, Assembly and Engineering Metrology, Faculty of Mechanical Engineering, V&#x160;B Technical University of Ostrava, Ostrava, Czech Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, College of Engineering, King Faisal University, Al-Ahsa, 31982, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soudagar</LastName><ForeName>Manzoore Elahi M</ForeName><Initials>MEM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering and University Centre for Research &amp; Development, Chandigarh University, Mohali, 140413, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Promotion of Research, Graphic Era (Deemed to be University), Clement Town, Dehradun, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coefficient of friction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dynamic recrystallisation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Grain size</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hardness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wear rate</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41145578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12559340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-21162-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-21162-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Patel, M. et al. Lightweight composite materials for automotive&#x2014;A review. <i>Carbon</i><b>1</b>(2500), 151 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal, J. et al. Progress of novel techniques for lightweight automobile applications through innovative eco-friendly composite materials: A review. <i>J. Thermoplast. Compos. Mater.</i><b>33</b>(7), 978&#x2013;1013 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0892705718815530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulei, C., Stojanovic, B. &amp; Utu. D. Developments of discontinuously reinforced aluminium matrix composites: Solving the needs for the matrix. In: <i>Journal of Physics: Conference Series</i>. <b>2212</b>(1), p. 012029, IOP Publishing. (2022)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, S. K. et al. Progress in aluminum-based composites prepared by stir casting: Mechanical and tribological properties for automotive, aerospace, and military applications. <i>Lubricants</i><b>12</b>(12), 421 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/lubricants12120421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenali, N., Ganesan, G. &amp; Babu, P. An investigation on the mechanical and tribological properties of an ultrasonic-assisted stir casting Al-Cu-Mg matrix-based composite reinforced with agro waste ash particles. <i>Appl. Eng. Lett.</i><b>9</b>(1), 46&#x2013;63 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46793/aeletters.2024.9.1.5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milojevi&#x107;, S. &amp; Stojanovi&#x107;, B. Determination of tribological properties of aluminum cylinder by application of Taguchi method and ANN-based model. <i>J. Braz. Soc. Mech. Sci. Eng.</i><b>40</b>(12), 571 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40430-018-1495-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krsti&#x107;, J. et al. Application of metal matrix nanocomposites in engineering. <i>Adv. Eng. Lett.</i><b>3</b>(4), 180&#x2013;190 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46793/adeletters.2024.3.4.5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babic, M. et al. Wear properties of A356/10SiC/1Gr hybrid composites in lubricated sliding conditions. <i>Tribol. Ind.</i><b>35</b>(2), 148&#x2013;154 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gajevi&#x107;, S. et al. Optimization of dry sliding wear in hot-pressed Al/B4C metal matrix composites using Taguchi method and ANN. <i>Materials</i><b>17</b>(16), 4056 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17164056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11356596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39203234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellor, B. G. <i>Surface Coatings for Protection Against Wear</i> (Woodhead Publishing, 2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakhtiari, M., Fayazi Khanigi, A. &amp; Farnia, A. Improving the wear properties of AISI4130 steel using laser surface hardening treatment. <i>Arab. J. Sci. Eng..</i><b>48</b>(9), 11801&#x2013;11818 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13369-022-07551-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chenrayan, V. et al. Effect of powder composition, PTAW parameters on dilution, microstructure and hardness of Ni&#x2013;Cr&#x2013;Si&#x2013;B alloy deposition: Experimental investigation and prediction using machine learning technique. <i>Heliyon</i><b>10</b>(16), e36087 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e36087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11378951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39247355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komarov, P. et al. Wetting behavior of wear-resistant WC-Co-Cr cermet coatings produced by HVOF: The role of chemical composition and surface roughness. <i>J. Therm. Spray Technol.</i><b>30</b>, 285&#x2013;303 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11666-020-01130-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regev, M. &amp; Spigarelli, S. A study of the metallurgical and mechanical properties of friction-stir-processed cu. <i>Metals</i><b>11</b>(4), 656 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met11040656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, H. et al. Effect of shot peening on the surface properties and wear behavior of heavy-duty-axle gear steels. <i>J. Market. Res.</i><b>17</b>, 22&#x2013;32 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Z.-Y. et al. Research on the mechanism of the two-dimensional ultrasonic surface burnishing process to enhance the wear resistance for aluminum alloy. <i>Friction</i><b>12</b>(3), 490&#x2013;509 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40544-021-0777-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, L. et al. Research on the mechanism of NiCrBSi-WC/Co coatings wear resistance improvement by low-energy laser shock peening. <i>Tribol. Int.</i><b>199</b>, 109957 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.triboint.2024.109957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C. et al. Microstructure and wear resistance property of laser cladded CrCoNi coatings assisted by ultrasonic impact treatment. <i>J. Market. Res.</i><b>22</b>, 853&#x2013;864 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raza, A. &amp; Kumar, S. A critical review of tool design in burnishing process. <i>Tribol. Int.</i><b>174</b>, 107717 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.triboint.2022.107717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, T. L. et al. Grinding-and robotic hammer peening-induced modifications in the near-surface regions of laser-cladded Inconel 718 coatings. <i>Surf. Coat. Technol.</i><b>489</b>, 131130 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surfcoat.2024.131130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, A. et al. Effects of in-process cryocooling on metallurgical and mechanical properties of friction stir processed Al7075 alloy. <i>Mater. Charact.</i><b>144</b>, 440&#x2013;447 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2018.08.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raaft, M. et al. Microstructural, mechanical and wear behavior of A390/graphite and A390/Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> surface composites fabricated using FSP. <i>Mater. Sci. Eng. A</i><b>528</b>(18), 5741&#x2013;5746 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2011.03.097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil, N. A., Pedapati, S. R. &amp; Marode, R. V. Wear analysis of friction stir processed AA7075-SiC-graphite hybrid surface composites. <i>Lubricants</i><b>10</b>(10), 267 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/lubricants10100267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafi, S. M. et al. Synergistic effect of FSP and TiB<sub>2</sub> on mechanical and tribological behavior of AA2024 surface composites. <i>J. Tribol.</i><b>145</b>(11), 114501 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4062517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanani, B. B. &amp; Abdollahzadeh, A. Fabrication of reinforced Al&#x2013;Mg composite by TiC particles via FSW: Microstructure and tribology study. <i>J. Market. Res.</i><b>30</b>, 6787&#x2013;6801 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelhady, S. S., Elbadawi, R. E. &amp; Zoalfakar, S. H. Investigation of the microstructure, mechanical and wear performance of friction stir-processed AA6061-T6 plate reinforced with B4C particles surface composite. <i>J. Compos. Mater.</i><b>57</b>(14), 2297&#x2013;2310 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00219983231171286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra, M. et al. Microstructural and mechanical studies of multi-walled CNTs/Mg composite fabricated through FSP. <i>J. Compos. Mater.</i><b>55</b>(22), 3023&#x2013;3033 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00219983211007545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nathan, S. R. et al. Investigations on microstructure, thermo-mechanical and tribological behavior of graphene oxide reinforced AA7075 surface composites developed via friction stir processing. <i>J. Manuf. Process.</i><b>90</b>, 139&#x2013;150 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2023.01.084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H. et al. A review on microstructures and properties of graphene-reinforced aluminum matrix composites fabricated by friction stir processing. <i>J. Manuf. Process.</i><b>68</b>, 126&#x2013;135 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2021.07.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, A., Sharma, S. K. &amp; Batish, A. Microstructure and mechanical behavior of coal-derived reduced graphene oxide reinforced AA7075 fabricated via friction stir processing. <i>Mater. Today Commun.</i><b>39</b>, 108973 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel, S. K. et al. Microstructural, mechanical and wear behavior of A7075 surface composite reinforced with WC nanoparticle through friction stir processing. <i>Mater. Sci. Eng. B</i><b>276</b>, 115476 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mseb.2021.115476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel, S. K. et al. Microstructural, mechanical and wear behavior of A7075 surface composite reinforced with WC and ZrSiO<sub>4</sub> nanoparticle through friction stir processing. <i>J. Manuf. Process.</i><b>71</b>, 85&#x2013;105 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2021.09.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, T. S. et al. A study on microstructural, mechanical properties, and optimization of wear behaviour of friction stir processed AZ31/TiC composites using response surface methodology. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>(1), 18729 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-69348-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11319588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39134620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaya, N. et al. Effect of process parameters of Al5083/SiC surface composites fabricated by FSP on microstructure, mechanical properties and wear behaviors. <i>Mater. Chem. Phys.</i><b>315</b>, 128991 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.128991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M. et al. Impact of multiple FSP passes on structure, mechanical, tribological and corrosion behaviors of AA6061/316 stainless-steel reinforced Al matrix composites. <i>Surf. Coat. Technol.</i><b>447</b>, 128801 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surfcoat.2022.128801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbari, M., Asadi, P. &amp; Asiabaraki, H. R. Investigation of wear and microstructural properties of A356/TiC composites fabricated by FSP. <i>Surf. Rev. Lett.</i><b>29</b>(10), 2250130 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S0218625X2250130X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharti, S., Ghetiya, N. D. &amp; Dutta, V. Investigating microhardness and wear behavior of Al5052/ZrO<sub>2</sub> surface composite produced by friction stir processing. <i>Mater. Today Proc.</i><b>44</b>, 52&#x2013;57 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2020.06.318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chittoriya, B. S., Jayant, A. &amp; Kumar, R. Effect of multipass FSP and (SiC&#x2009;+&#x2009;TiB<sub>2</sub>) nanoparticles on the mechanical and metallurgical characteristic of the hybrid metal matrix composite. <i>SILICON</i><b>15</b>(18), 7927&#x2013;7941 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12633-023-02635-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boopathi, S. et al. Friction stir processing of boron carbide reinforced aluminium surface (Al-B<sub>4</sub>C) composite: Mechanical characteristics analysis. <i>Mater. Today Proc.</i><b>50</b>, 2430&#x2013;2435 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2021.10.261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, R. &amp; Thakur, L. Influence of micro-sized Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> particles on mechanical and wear performance of an AA7075-Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> composite coating developed by friction surfacing. <i>Int. J. Interact. Design Manuf. IJIDeM</i><b>18</b>(8), 5583&#x2013;5597 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12008-024-01961-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharti, S., Ghetiya, N. D. &amp; Patel, K. M. A review on manufacturing the surface composites by friction stir processing. <i>Mater. Manuf. Process.</i><b>36</b>(2), 135&#x2013;170 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10426914.2020.1813897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan, P. et al. The effect of SiC and Y<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> inclusion on microstructure and mechanical properties of Al 5052 composite fabricated through friction stir process. <i>Heliyon</i><b>11</b>(1), e41665 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2025.e41665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11761344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39866432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, G. et al. Excellent performance of W-Y<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> composite via powder process improvement and Y<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> refinement. <i>Mater. Des.</i><b>212</b>, 110249 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2021.110249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapiro, I. et al. Effects of Y<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> additives and powder purity on the densification and grain boundary composition of Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/SiC nanocomposites. <i>J. Eur. Ceram. Soc.</i><b>29</b>(9), 1613&#x2013;1624 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jeurceramsoc.2008.09.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi, P. et al. Effects of SiC particle size and process parameters on the microstructure and hardness of AZ91/SiC composite layer fabricated by FSP. <i>J. Mater. Eng. Perform.</i><b>20</b>, 1554&#x2013;1562 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11665-011-9855-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashmi, A. W. et al. Mechanical properties and microstructure evolution of AA6082/sic nanocomposite processed by multi-pass FSP. <i>Trans. Indian Inst. Met.</i><b>75</b>(8), 2077&#x2013;2090 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12666-022-02582-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouaeshi, W. &amp; Li, D. Effects of Y<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> addition on microstructure, mechanical properties, electrochemical behavior, and resistance to corrosive wear of aluminum. <i>Tribol. Int.</i><b>40</b>(2), 188&#x2013;199 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.triboint.2005.09.030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Y. P. et al. Effect of rare earth Y<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> on the corrosion and friction properties of Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> ceramic coatings prepared via microarc oxidation. <i>Int. J. Electrochem. Sci.</i><b>15</b>(8), 7682&#x2013;7692 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20964/2020.08.11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macerl, M. et al. Microstructure and properties after friction stir processing of twin-roll cast Al&#x2013;Mn&#x2013;Cu&#x2013;Be alloy. <i>Crystals</i><b>12</b>(5), 630 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cryst12050630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, V., Prakash, U. &amp; Kumar, B. M. Surface composites by friction stir processing: A review. <i>J. Mater. Process. Technol.</i><b>224</b>, 117&#x2013;134 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2015.04.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chenrayan, V. et al. Tribological performance of TiB<sub>2</sub>-graphene Al 7075 hybrid composite processed through squeeze casting: At room and high temperature. <i>Tribol. Int.</i><b>185</b>, 108486 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.triboint.2023.108486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9502332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36144912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaishnav, V., Kumar, R. P. &amp; Venkatesh, C. Influence of nano MoS<sub>2</sub> particle on the mechanical and tribological properties of Al-TiB<sub>2</sub>-Gr hybrid composite. <i>J. Mech. Sci. Technol.</i><b>36</b>(2), 857&#x2013;867 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12206-022-0133-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chenrayan, V. et al. Frictional stability of pumice-reinforced lightweight magnesium composite in ambient and elevated temperature environments. <i>J. Market. Res.</i><b>32</b>, 3465&#x2013;3475 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen, N. Hall&#x2013;Petch relation and boundary strengthening. <i>Scr. Mater.</i><b>51</b>(8), 801&#x2013;806 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scriptamat.2004.06.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shekhar, C., Wani, M. &amp; Sehgal, R. Fabrication and self-lubricating tribological characterisation of Cu&#x2013;Ni/TiC/CaF<sub>2</sub> composite for railway switch slide baseplate. <i>Wear</i><b>526</b>, 204890 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wear.2023.204890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shekhar, C. et al. Recent progress in particulate reinforced copper-based composites: fabrication, microstructure, mechanical, and tribological properties&#x2014;A review. <i>Adv. Eng. Mater.</i><b>27</b>(2), 2401748 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adem.202401748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shekhar, C. et al. A novel ceramic reinforced metal matrix composite (Cu&#x2013;Ni/TiC&#x2013;CaF<sub>2</sub>): Fabrication, microstructure, mechanical and tribological characterization. <i>Metall. Mater. Trans. B</i><b>56</b>, 1&#x2013;27 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11663-024-03418-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narimani, M., Lotfi, B. &amp; Sadeghian, Z. Evaluation of the microstructure and wear behaviour of AA6063-B4C/TiB<sub>2</sub> mono and hybrid composite layers produced by friction stir processing. <i>Surf. Coat. Technol.</i><b>285</b>, 1&#x2013;10 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surfcoat.2015.11.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora, H., Singh, H. &amp; Dhindaw, B. Wear behaviour of a Mg alloy subjected to friction stir processing. <i>Wear</i><b>303</b>(1&#x2013;2), 65&#x2013;77 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wear.2013.02.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajaram, G. et al. Studies on high temperature wear and its mechanism of Al&#x2013;Si/graphite composite under dry sliding conditions. <i>Tribol. Int.</i><b>43</b>(11), 2152&#x2013;2158 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.triboint.2010.06.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>