<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41758817</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Stability analysis of dam grouting reinforcement based on FLAC3D.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0342938</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0342938</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0342938</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0342938</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ill reservoirs have significant safety hazards, it is urgent to grout and strengthen the dangerous reservoir dams. In order to effectively evaluate the stability of the dam after grouting reinforcement, this paper carried out numerical simulation analysis work. Firstly, the action mechanism of penetration grouting, compression grouting and splitting grouting is described, and it is pointed out that these modes of action are intermixed and interconverted, and they may exist simultaneously in the same grouting process. Next, based on the FLAC3D finite difference program, the analysis and calculation of the stability of seepage control reinforcement of a dangerous reservoir in Guangxi Province were carried out. The calculation results show that, a complete grout curtain zone is formed inside the dam body after grouting reinforcement treatment, the dam stress is adjusted twice, the area of plastic zone decreased 23%, and the stability of the dam body is significantly enhanced. This article has certain guiding significance for the analysis and evaluation of safety and stability of similar projects.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Pengfei Qin. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qin</LastName><ForeName>Pengfei</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-3207-5636</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Department of Huanghe University of Science and Technology, Zhengzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014881" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water Supply</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008962" MajorTopicYN="Y">Models, Theoretical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003198" MajorTopicYN="N">Computer Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>No.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41758817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12948064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0342938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-58604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gan L, Xu C, Shen Z, Xu L, Zhang H, Liu Y. Numerical investigation of seepage dissolution evolution of the bottom expansion cutoff wall in deep overburden. Construction and Building Materials. 2023;386:131510. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131510</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan Z, Sun X, Zhang G, Li G, Huang P, Zhang B, et al. Deformation and damage behavior of the deep concrete cut-off wall in core earth-rock dam foundation based on plastic damage model - A case study. Structures. 2022;46:1480&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2022.10.136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2022.10.136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youssef AA, Awotunde AA. Modelling fluid flow in karst reservoirs using Darcy Model with estimated permeability distribution. Computers &amp; Geosciences. 2019;133:104311. doi: 10.1016/j.cageo.2019.104311</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cageo.2019.104311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Gong JK, Qiu HT. Experimental study on application of foam fluids in restraining seepage failure of soils. Journal of Geotechnical Engineering. 2024;2:366&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang WB, Li QM, Li MC. Study on the long-term service performance of anti-seepage walls of earth-rock dams under coupled effect of seepage and calcium leaching. Journal of Hydraulic Engineering. 2025;10:1314&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y, Wang HS, Li A. Permeation-compaction diffusion mechanism of shield tail synchronous grouting slurry in water-rich fine sand layer. Rock and Soil Mechanics. 2023;44(5):1319&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu GX, Zhang QS, Feng X. Study on the filtration mechanism in permeation grouting using the particle deposition probability model. Advanced Engineering Sciences. 2020;52(5):125&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou JF, Li L, Yang XL. Method of energy analysis for compaction grouting. Geotechnics. 2020;3:475&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan J, Sharma P, Shukla S, Pancholi V, Dwivedi VK. Cyclic Behaviour and Durability Analysis of Sand Grouted with Optimum Colloidal Silica Content. Arab J Sci Eng. 2020;45(10):8129&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1007/s13369-020-04643-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13369-020-04643-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong L, Quan X, Luo W, Chen Y, Yang B, Wang H, et al. Exploration of molecular dynamics for the adsorption of anionic emulsifier on the main chemical composition surface of aggregate. Construction and Building Materials. 2021;292:123210. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123210</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YJ. Principles and methods of compaction and splitting grouting to strengthen foundations. Chinese Journal of Geotechnical Engineering. 2019;2:22&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou JF, Li L, Yang XL. Mechanism analysis of fracture grouting in soil. Geotechnics. 2016;4:625&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun F, Zhang DL, Yao HB. Study on the effect of splitting grouting reinforcement at the bottom of earth dams. Geotechnics. 2019;4:1187&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu K, Ma XY, Zhao Q. Application of FLAC3D in the analysis of seepage stability of splitting grouting of earth dams. Geotechnics. 2015;3:484&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YM, Xu DP. FLAC/FLAC3D Foundation and Engineering Example. Chinese Journal of Geotechnical Engineering. 2019;7:71&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin DL. Compilation of experience in geological survey of small and medium-sized water conservancy and hydropower projects. Changsha: Preparation Group of Specification of Experience in Geological Survey of Small and Medium-sized Water Conservancy and Hydropower Projects. 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Itasca Consulting Group Inc. Fast language analysis of continua in 3 dimensions, version 3.0, user&#x2019;s manual. Itasca Consulting Group, Inc. 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan H, Guo Y, Zou F, Jian S, Ma B, Zhi Z. Effect of borax on rheology of calcium sulphoaluminate cement paste in the presence of polycarboxylate superplasticizer. Construction and Building Materials. 2017;139:277&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.02.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.02.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telesca A, Marroccoli M, Coppola L, Coffetti D, Candamano S. Tartaric acid effects on hydration development and physico-mechanical properties of blended calcium sulphoaluminate cements. Cement and Concrete Composites. 2021;124:104275. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.104275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.104275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye JH. Manual of Rock Mechanics Parameters. Beijing: Water &amp; Power Press. 2015. 425&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>