<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41383058</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2053-1095</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Veterinary medicine and science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Vet Med Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessment of Breeding Practices and Productive and Reproductive Performance of Multiple Livestock Species in Mixed Farming System in Majang Zone, Southwest Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70712</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70712</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e70712</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/vms3.70712</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Livestock plays significantly role in the livelihoods of the majority of smallholder farmers in Ethiopia. Understanding breeding practices and the productive and reproductive performance of livestock is crucial for designing successful genetic improvements and ensuring the sustainability of the livestock farming system. However, there is lack of documented information on the breeding practices and productive and reproductive performance of multiple livestock species in the current study area.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The objective of this study was to assess the breeding practices and selected productive and reproductive performances of various indigenous livestock species in two agro-ecological zones (AEZs) of the Majang Zone, southwest Ethiopia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS OF DATA COLLECTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Data were collected from 168 livestock farmers through face-to- face interviews using a semi-structured questionnaire. The data were analysed using the Statistical Package for Social Sciences software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The results showed that approximately 89.45% of respondents used natural service (NS) for breeding cattle, 5.55% used artificial insemination (AI) and 5.0% used both AI and NS. All respondents (100%) relied on NS for breeding equines and small ruminants. Across both AEZs, about 88.7% of respondents practiced uncontrolled mating for cattle, and 100% did so for equines and small ruminants. The overall mean age at first calving (AFC), calving interval (CI), lactation length (LL), daily milk yield (DMY) and reproductive life span (RLS) of cattle were 3.02&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.023 years, 2.01&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0 years, 9.77&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.05 months, 1.79&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.05&#xa0;L and 13.78&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.08 years, respectively. AFC, LL, DMY and RLS were higher (p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05) in ML than in the LL AEZs. For sheep and goats, the average age at first lambing and kidding, lambing and kidding intervals and RLS were 1.35&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.011 and 1.26&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.01 years, 8.36&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.05 and 8.51&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.04 months and 118.71&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.74 and 104.66&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.63 months, respectively. Lambing interval, age at first kidding, kidding interval and RLS were higher (p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05) in the ML than in LL AEZs. For female donkeys and horses, the average ages at first foaling, foaling interval and age at first packing loads were 4.33&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.14 and 3.70&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.12 years, 2.81&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.14 and 2.10&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.09 years and 3.93&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.09 and 2.90&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.09 years, respectively. Age at first foaling and foaling interval of horses were higher (p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05) in ML than in the LL AEZs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The performance variables of the livestock species were relatively better in the ML than in the LL AEZ. However, the performance of the various livestock species in the study area was low due to late age at first parturition and long parturition interval. Further research is needed to identify potential causes of the low performances and to implement appropriate interventions to enhance the productive and reproductive performances of livestock in the study area.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Veterinary Medicine and Science published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Assefa</LastName><ForeName>Shimelis</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Majang Zone Agricultural Development Office, Gambella National Regional State, Gambella, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duguma</LastName><ForeName>Belay</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Science, Jimma University College of Agriculture and Veterinary Medicine, Jimma, Oromia, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Worku</LastName><ForeName>Zemene</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Science, Jimma University College of Agriculture and Veterinary Medicine, Jimma, Oromia, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Vet Med Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101678837</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2053-1095</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000822" MajorTopicYN="Y">Animal Husbandry</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001947" MajorTopicYN="Y">Breeding</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012098" MajorTopicYN="Y">Reproduction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002417" MajorTopicYN="N">Cattle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058751" MajorTopicYN="Y">Livestock</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006736" MajorTopicYN="N">Horses</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006041" MajorTopicYN="N">Goats</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012756" MajorTopicYN="N">Sheep</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000067565" MajorTopicYN="N">Farmers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cattle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">donkey</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">goats</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">horse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">productive and reproductive performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">productive life span</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sheep</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41383058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12698957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/vms3.70712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abebe, T. 2020. &#x201c;Sheep Breeding Practices and Reproductive Performance in Lagambo District, South Wollo Zone, Amhara Region in Ethiopia.&#x201d; International Journal of Advanced Research in Biological Sciences 7, no. 10: 125&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrha, B. H. , Niraj K., Berihu G., Kiros A., and Gebregiorgis A. G.. 2020. &#x201c;Productive and Reproductive Performance of Local Cows Under Farmer's Management in Central Tigray, Ethiopia.&#x201d; NJAS 22, no. 3: 70&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc5;by, B. , Aass L., Sehested E., and Vangen O.. 2012. &#x201c;Effects of Changes in External Production Conditions on Economic Values of Traits in Continental and British Beef Cattle Breeds.&#x201d; Livestock Science 150, no. 1&#x2013;3: 80&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amelmal, A. 2011. &#x201c;Phenotypic Characterization of Indigenous Sheep Types of Dawuro Zone and Konta Special Woreda of SNNPR, Ethiopia.&#x201d; MSc thesis, Haramaya University.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ampong, E. , Obese F. Y., and Ayizanga R. A.. 2019. &#x201c;Growth and Reproductive Performance of West African Dwarf Sheep (Djallonk&#xe9;) at the Livestock and Poultry Research Centre, University of Ghana.&#x201d; Livestock Research for Rural Development 31, no. 1: 27&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asaduzzaman, M. , and Miah G.. 2004. &#x201c;A Comparative Performance of Crossbred and Indigenous Dairy Cows Under Smallholder Dairy Farming Condition.&#x201d; Journal of Agriculture and Rural Development 7: 12&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assan, N. 2020. &#x201c;Indicators of Reproductive Performance in Goats and Sheep Meat Production.&#x201d; Scientific Journal of Animal Science 9, no. 5: 608&#x2013;619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assefa, S. , Duguma B., and Worku Z.. 2024. &#x201c;Assessment of Husbandry Practices and Livestock Production Constraints Among Smallholder Mixed Crop&#x2010;Livestock Farmers in the Majang Zone, Southwest Ethiopia.&#x201d; Heliyon 10, no. 19: e37400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11456831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39381094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayou, E. , Haile A., Gizaw S., and Mekasha Y.. 2015. &#x201c;Evaluation of Nongenetic Factors Affecting Calf Growth, Reproductive Performance and Milk Yield of Traditionally Managed Sheko Cattle in Southwest Ethiopia.&#x201d; SpringerPlus 4, no. 1: 568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4628024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26543703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CSA (Central Statistics Agency) . 2021. Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia, Agricultural Sample Survey 2021/22 [2014 E.C.] Volume II. Report on Livestock and Livestock Characteristics (Private Peasant Holdings) . Statistical Bulletin 594. CSA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabi, S. E. 2020. &#x201c;Milk Yield and Reproductive Performances of Dairy Cows at Bako Agricultural Research Center.&#x201d; International Journal of Research in Agricultural Sciences 7, no. 1: 32&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dematawewa, C. M. B. , and Beger P. J.. 1998. &#x201c;Genetic and Phenotypic Parameters for 305&#x2010;DayYield, Fertility, and Survival in Holsteins.&#x201d; Journal of Dairy Science 81: 2700&#x2013;2709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9812275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>

Deng, L.
, Shi S., Li J., Tang C., Liao Q., and Xie P.. 2020. &#x201c;A Cross&#x2010;Sectional Survey of Foaling&#x2010;Related Parameters of Jennies (<i>Equus asinus</i>) Under Smallholder Farm Conditions in Northeast China.&#x201d; Journal of Equine Veterinary Science
87: 102928.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32172918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dereje, T. , Mengistu U., Getachew A., and Yoseph M.. 2015. &#x201c;A Review of Productive and Reproductive Characteristics of Indigenous Goats in Ethiopia.&#x201d; Livestock Research for Rural Development 27, no. 2: 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deribe, B. , and Taye M.. 2014. &#x201c;Reproductive Performance of Abergelle Goats Raised Under Traditional Management Systems in Sekota District, Ethiopia.&#x201d; Iranian Journal of Applied Animal Science 4: 59&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24505995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinka, H. 2012. &#x201c;Reproductive Performance of Crossbred Dairy Cows Under Smallholder Condition in Ethiopia.&#x201d; International Journal of Livestock Production 3, no. 3: 25&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duguma, B. 2021. &#x201c;Productive and Reproductive Performance of Crossbred and Indigenous Dairy Cows at Smallholdings in Selected Towns of Jimma Zone, Ethiopia.&#x201d; Animal Production Science 61, no. 1: 92&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes J&#xfa;nior, G. A. , Garcia D. A., Hortolani B., and de Albuquerque L. G.. 2019. &#x201c;Phenotypic Relationship of Female Sexual Precocity With Production and Reproduction Traits in Beef Cattle Using Multivariate Statistical Techniques.&#x201d; Italian Journal of Animal Science 18, no. 1: 182&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fsahatsion, H. , Aberra M., and Sandip B.. 2013. &#x201c;Traditional Sheep Production and Breeding Practice in Gamogofa Zone, Southern Ethiopia.&#x201d; International Journal of Livestock Production 1, no. 3: 26&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatew, H. 2014. &#x201c;On&#x2010;Farm Phenotypic Characterization and Performance Evaluation of Bati, Borena and Short Eared Somali Goat Population of Ethiopia.&#x201d; MSc. thesis, Haramaya University.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gbangboche, A. B. , Adamou&#x2010;Ndiaye M., Youssao A. K. I., et&#xa0;al. 2006. &#x201c;Nongenetic Factors Affecting the Reproduction Performance, Lamb Growth and Productivity Indices of Djallonke Sheep.&#x201d; Small Ruminant Research 64: 133&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebeyew, K. , Amakelew S., Eshetu M., and Animut G.. 2016. &#x201c;Production, Processing and Handling of Cow Milk in Dawa Chefa District Amhara Region, Ethiopia.&#x201d; Journal of Veterinary Science &amp; Technology 7, no. 1: 286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getachew, T. 2008. &#x201c;Characterization of Menz and Afar Indigenous Sheep Breeds of Smallholders and Pastoralists for Designing Community&#x2010;Based Breeding Strategies in Ethiopia.&#x201d; Doctoral dissertation, Haramaya University.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getahun, K. , Hunde D., Tadesse M., and Tadesse Y.. 2019. &#x201c;Reproductive Performances of Crossbred Dairy Cattle at Holetta Agricultural Research Center.&#x201d; Livestock Research for Rural Development 31, no. 9: 138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gizaw, S. , Komen H., Hanotte O., and van Arendonk J. M. A.. 2008. &#x201c;Indigenous Sheep Resources of Ethiopia: Types, Production Systems and Farmers Preferences.&#x201d; Animal Genetic Resources Information 43: 25&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haile, A. , Ayalew W., Kebede N., Dessie T., and Tegegne A.. 2011. Breeding Strategy to Improve Ethiopian Boran Cattle for Meat and Milk Production. IPMS (Improving Productivity and Market Success) of Ethiopian Farmers Project Working Paper 26. ILRI.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain, M. M. , Alam M. M., Rashid M. M., Asaduzzaman M., and Rahman M. M.. 2005. &#x201c;Small Scale Dairy Farming Practice in a Selective Area of Bangladesh.&#x201d; Pakistan Journal of Nutrition 4: 222&#x2013;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husen, M. M. , Kechero Y., and Molla M.. 2016. &#x201c;Characterization of Livestock Production System in Three Selected Districts of Jimma Zone, Southwest Ethiopia.&#x201d; Journal of Reproduction &amp; Infertility 7, no. 2: 47&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jembere, T. , Haile A.., Dessie T., Kebede K., Mwai O. A., and Barbara R.. 2019. &#x201c;Productivity Benchmarks for Community Based Genetic Improvementof Abergelle, Central Highland and Woyto&#x2010;Guji Indigenous Goatbreeds in Ethiopia.&#x201d; Livestock Research for Rural Development 31: Article#74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jose, S. C. , Maga&#xf1;a&#x2010;Monforte J. G., Ak&#xe9;&#x2010;L&#xf3;pez J. R., Segura&#x2010;Correa M. V., Hinojosa&#x2010;Cuellar A. J., and Osorio&#x2010;Arce M. M.. 2017. &#x201c;Breed and Environmental Effects on Birth Weight, Weaning Weight and Calving Interval of Zebu Cattle in South Eastern Mexico.&#x201d; Tropical and Subtropical 20, no. 2: 297&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellogg, D. W. , Pennington J. A., Johnson Z. B., and Panivivat R.. 2001. &#x201c;Survey of Management Practices Used for the Highest Producing DHI Herds in the United States.&#x201d; Journal of Dairy Science 84: 120&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krp&#xe1;lkov&#xe1;, L. , Cabrera V. E., Kvapil&#xed;k J., Burdych J., and Crump P.. 2014. &#x201c;Associations Between Age at First Calving, Rearing Average Daily Weight Gain, Herd Milk Yield and Herd Dairy Production, Reproduction, and Profitability.&#x201d; Journal of Dairy Science 97: 6573&#x2013;6582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25064657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legese, G. , and Fadiga M.. 2014. Small Ruminant Value Chain Development in Ethiopia: Situation Analysis and Trends. ICARDA/ILRI Project Report. International Center for Agricultural Research in the Dry Areas/International Livestock Research Institute.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombebo, W. A. , and Sebro E.. 2019. &#x201c;Reproductive and Productive Performances of Local Cows Under Farmer's Management in Soro District, Hadiya Zone, Southern Ethiopia.&#x201d; Research &amp; Reviews, JRRJAAS 8, no. 1: 55&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melku, M. , Kefyalew A., and Solomon G.. 2017. &#x201c;Milk Production Performances of Local and Crossbred Dairy Cows in West Gojam Zone, Amhara Region, Ethiopia.&#x201d; Journal of Applied Animal Research 10: 35&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mengiste, T. 2008. &#x201c;On&#x2010;Farm Performance of Washera Sheep at Yilmanadensa and Quarit Districts of the Amhara National Regional State.&#x201d; MSc thesis, Hawassa University.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miah, G. , Sohel M. S. H., Hossain M. I., et&#xa0;al. 2018. &#x201c;Productive and Reproductive Potentialities of Different Genetic Groups of Crossbred Cows Reared Under Different Farming Conditions, Iran.&#x201d; Journal of Applied Animal Science 8, no. 2: 201&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukasa&#x2010;Mugerwa, E. 1989. A Review of Reproductive Performance of Female Bos Indicus (Zebu) Cattle. International Livestock Centre for Africa.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musa, L. M. A. 2007. Characterization and Utilization of Dairy Cattle in Sudan. University of Khartoum.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nigussie, H. , Makasha Y., Kebede K., Abegaz S., and Kumar Pal S.. 2013. &#x201c;Production Objectives, Breeding Practices and Selection Criteria of Indigenous Sheep in Eastern Ethiopia.&#x201d; Livestock Research for Rural Development 25, no. 9: 1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuraddis, I. , and Ahmed S.. 2017. &#x201c;Review on Reproductive Performance of Crossbred Dairy Cattle in Ethiopia.&#x201d; Journal of Reproduction &amp; Infertility 8: 88&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regassa, M. 2018. &#x201c;Performances of Highland Sheep Under Community&#x2010;Based Breeding Program in Atsbi Wenberta District, Tigray, Ethiopia.&#x201d; Doctoral dissertation, (Bahir Dar University; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapiro, B. I. , Gebru G., Desta S., et&#xa0;al. 2017. &#x201c;Ethiopia Livestock Sector Analysis: A 15 Year Livestock Sector Strategy.&#x201d; ILRI Project Report. ILRI (International Livestock Research Institute).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swai, E. S. , Kyakaisho P., and Ole Kawanara M. S.. 2007. &#x201c;Studies on the Reproductive Performance of CB Dairy Cows Raised on Smallholder Farms in Eastern Usambara Mountains, Tanzania.&#x201d; Livestock Research for Rural Development 19: 61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tegegne, A. , Dejen E., Hoekstra D., and Teka W.. 2009. Matching Genotype With the Environment Using Indigenous Cattle Breed: Introduction of Borana Cattle From Southern Ethiopia Into the Lowlands of North&#x2010;Western Ethiopia. IAEA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfa, A. , Kumar D., Abegaz S., et&#xa0;al. 2016. &#x201c;Growth and Reproductive Performance of Fogera Cattle Breed at Andassa Livestock Research Center.&#x201d; Livestock Research for Rural Development 28, no. 1: 4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfahun, B. 2013. &#x201c;Phenotypic and Production System Characterization of Woyto Guji Goats in Lowland Areas of South Omo Zone.&#x201d; M.Sc. Thesis, Haramaya University, Ethiopia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tonamo, A. , Tamir B., Goshu G., and Belete E.. 2015. &#x201c;Characterization of Husbandry Practices in Essera Woreda, Dawuro Zone, Southern Ethiopia.&#x201d; African Journal of Agricultural Research 10, no. 34: 3421&#x2013;3435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yetera, A. , Urge M., and Nurfeta A.. 2018. &#x201c;Productive and Reproductive Performance of Local Dairy Cows in Selected Districts of Sidama Zone, Southern Ethiopia.&#x201d; International Journal of Livestock Production 9, no. 5: 88&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelalem, A. 2016. &#x201c;Review of the Reproductive Performances of Indigenous Sheep in Ethiopia.&#x201d; JBAH 6, no. 9: 117&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelealem, T. , Anal A. K., and Gebrezgiher G.. 2012. &#x201c;Assessment of the Sheep Production System of Northern Ethiopia in Relation to Sustainable Productivity and Sheep Meat Quality.&#x201d; International Journal of Advanced Biological Research 2, no. 2: 302&#x2013;313.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>