<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41062580</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Displacement response of ancient marine sedimentary soils to boring construction of triaxial cement mixing piles adjacent to metro.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>35089</StartPage><MedlinePgn>35089</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">35089</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-18937-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In foundation pit projects adjacent to Wenzhou Metro Line S1, controlling the disturbance of ancient marine sedimentary soils caused by the boring construction of triaxial cement mixing piles is crucial to safeguarding the operational safety of rail transit. This study systematically investigates the influencing mechanisms of boring parameters on surrounding soil displacements via a combination of field monitoring, numerical simulation, and parametric optimization. Based on the typical geological conditions of the coastal alluvial-lacustrine plain in Longwan District, Wenzhou-characterized by a narrow separation between the foundation pit and the metro station, and by highly sensitive marine sedimentary soft soils-this research reveals the disturbance characteristics of boring construction through monitoring the horizontal displacements of retaining structures and surface settlement. The results show that shallow soil displacements are significantly affected by time-dependent effects, deep-soil displacements remain relatively stable, and surface settlement increases as the distance from the foundation pit decreases. A finite element model integrating the Mohr-Coulomb model and Biot's consolidation theory was developed in COMSOL, where simulation results exhibited high degrees of consistency with field data (R<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.92 and 0.96, respectively), thus verifying the model's reliability. Orthogonal simulation experiments were conducted to analyze the coupled effects of boring depth and radius, indicating that increasing the boring radius significantly increases deep-soil horizontal displacements but reduces near-zone surface settlements; increasing the boring depth exerts a notable influence on upper-soil horizontal displacements, whereas bottom-soil displacements undergo only minor changes. To achieve differentiated protection objectives, a "Construction Drilling Safety Evaluation Coefficient" is proposed, which comprehensively accounts for the deformation control requirements of above-ground buildings, underground structures, and near- and far-zone environments. The optimal construction scheme is identified as one adopting a smaller boring depth and a moderate radius. This research provides theoretical support and engineering guidance for deformation control during the construction of triaxial cement mixing piles in marine sedimentary soils adjacent to metro lines within coastal cities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Daoming</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering, Zhejiang University of Technology, Hangzhou, 310023, China. daomingpan@foxmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Boring parameters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Displacement monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Marine sedimentary soils</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metro protection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Numerical simulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Triaxial cement mixing piles</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41062580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12508033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-18937-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-18937-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tsumita, N. et al. Urban railway network expansion on transit oriented development: improvement in accessibility in four Asian developing cities. <i>Asian Transp. Stud.</i><b>9</b>, 100097 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eastsj.2023.100097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, K. et al. Urban rail transit in china: progress report and analysis (2015&#x2013;2023). <i>Urban Rail Transit.</i><b>11</b>, 1&#x2013;27 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40864-024-00231-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, P. et al. Development of urban underground space in coastal cities in china: A review. <i>Deep Undergr. Sci. Eng.</i><b>2</b>, 148&#x2013;172 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dug2.12034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, B., Wu, W., Lu, H., Chen, S. &amp; Zhang, D. Effect and control of foundation pit excavation on existing tunnels: A state-of-the-art review. <i>Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol.</i><b>147</b>, 105704 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2024.105704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voottipruex, P. et al. Performances of SDCM and DCM walls under deep excavation in soft clay: field tests and 3D simulations. <i>Soils Found.</i><b>59</b>, 1728&#x2013;1739 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sandf.2019.07.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, T. et al. Deformation characteristics of soft soil induced by deep excavation and its impact on adjacent tunnels: A case study in Shanghai. <i>KSCE J. Civ. Eng.</i><b>28</b>, 1715&#x2013;1728 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12205-024-0487-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, T. et al. Comprehensive sedimentary studies of mid-late quaternary strata in the outer shelf of the East China sea: facies architecture, chronology, sediment sources, and depositional model. <i>Mar. Pet. Geol.</i><b>173</b>, 107274 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2024.107274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. Holocene transgression and Neolithic human adaptations in the Zhejiang Coastal Plain, East China. <i>CATENA</i><b>245</b>, 108340 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, C. M., Zhuo, H. C. &amp; Gao, S. Sedimentary facies and evolution in the qiantang river incised valley, Eastern China. <i>Mar. Geol.</i><b>219</b>, 235&#x2013;259 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.margeo.2005.06.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J. et al. Late pleistocene to holocene facies architecture and sedimentary evolution of the Zhejiang Coast, East China Sea. <i>Mar. Geol.</i><b>459</b>, 107027 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.margeo.2023.107027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, G., Bi, S., Gugliotta, M., Liu, J. &amp; Liu, J. P. Dispersal mechanism of fine-grained sediment in the modern mud belt of the East China Sea. <i>Earth Sci. Rev.</i><b>240</b>, 104388 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.earscirev.2023.104388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei, H., Yang, X., Feng, S. &amp; Ma, T. Softening and deformation characteristics of Tianjin soft soil under principal stress rotation induced by traffic loading. <i>Soil Dyn. Earthq. Eng.</i><b>164</b>, 107587 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soildyn.2022.107587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, Y., Chen, Z. &amp; Airey, D. Compression index versus natural water content relationships for China&#x2019;s coastal soft clays. <i>KSCE J. Civ. Eng.</i><b>23</b>, 4611&#x2013;4620 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12205-019-1652-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X., Lin, C. M., Dalrymple, R. W., Gao, S. &amp; Canas, D. T. Use of the cone penetration testing (CPT) method to interpret late quaternary tide-dominated successions: A case study from the Eastern China Coastal Plain. <i>Cont. Shelf Res.</i><b>161</b>, 49&#x2013;57 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csr.2018.03.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, C., Yu, L., Huang, Z., Liu, Z. &amp; Zhang, L. Analysis of microstructure and spatially dependent permeability of soft soil during consolidation deformation. <i>Soils Found.</i><b>61</b>, 708&#x2013;733 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sandf.2021.02.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J., Zhu, Z., Zhu, X., Meng, Y. &amp; Chu, W. Study on the influence of uneven settlement and small curve radius on metro train running safety and riding comfort. <i>Structures</i><b>51</b>, 1806&#x2013;1820 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2023.03.094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi, H., Zhou, Z., Yuan, J., Li, N. &amp; Zhou, J. Accident pattern recognition in subway construction for the provision of customized safety measures. <i>Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol.</i><b>137</b>, 105157 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2023.105157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvadurai, A. P. S. Irreversibility of soil skeletal deformations: the pedagogical limitations of Terzaghi&#x2019;s celebrated model for soil consolidation. <i>Comput. Geotech.</i><b>135</b>, 104137 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compgeo.2021.104137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, J., Zhang, H., Liu, Z. &amp; Liang, J. Seismic performance of segmented tunnel in water-saturated poroelastic soil using a novel fluid&#x2013;solid coupling FEM based on Biot theory. <i>Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol.</i><b>146</b>, 105655 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2024.105655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao, N. C., Lee, J. W. &amp; Lo, W. Gravity effect on consolidation in poroelastic soils under saturated and unsaturated conditions. <i>J. Hydrol.</i><b>566</b>, 99&#x2013;108 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhydrol.2018.08.081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, Z. et al. Unveiling multimodal consolidation process of the newly reclaimed HKIA 3rd runway from satellite SAR interferometry, ICA analytics and Terzaghi consolidation theory. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>318</b>, 114561 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2024.114561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia, F. &amp; Xia, T. One-dimensional consolidation analysis of normally consolidated soft clays under vibratory loads. <i>Soil Dyn. Earthq. Eng.</i><b>191</b>, 109241 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soildyn.2025.109241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, K. et al. Nonlinear consolidation finite element analysis of a layered soft soil foundation under multistage loading based on the continuous drainage boundary. <i>Comput. Geotech.</i><b>169</b>, 106220 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compgeo.2024.106220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, P., Cao, W., Xu, Z., Li, H. &amp; Hu, M. One-dimensional nonlinear rheological consolidation analysis of soft ground under continuous drainage boundary conditions. <i>Comput. Geotech.</i><b>156</b>, 105283 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compgeo.2023.105283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, K. S. et al. Disturbance to adjacent marine deposit by offshore DCM construction. <i>Ocean Eng.</i><b>289</b>, 116305 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oceaneng.2023.116305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, S. L. &amp; Miura, N. Soil fracturing of the surrounding clay during deep mixing column installation. <i>Soils Found.</i><b>39</b>, 13&#x2013;22 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3208/sandf.39.5_13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. et al. Investigation of metro tunnel response to multiple adjacent large excavations in soft soils. <i>Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol.</i><b>152</b>, 105935 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2024.105935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing, Y., Li, L., Li, J. &amp; Chen, H. Performances of a large-scale deep excavation with multi-support types and zoned excavation technique in Shanghai soft soil. <i>Can. Geotech. J.</i>10.1139/cgj-2023-0719 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/cgj-2023-0719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazir, R. Deformation model of deep soil mixing using finite element method. <i>J. Teknol.</i> (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, Z., Chen, Y. &amp; Liu, D. Y. Investigating the effectiveness of deep cement mixing in deep sea: A static load testing case study. <i>Appl. Ocean Res.</i><b>141</b>, 103773 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apor.2023.103773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phutthananon, C., Jongpradist, P., Yensri, P. &amp; Jamsawang, P. Dependence of ultimate bearing capacity and failure behavior of T-shaped deep cement mixing piles on enlarged cap shape and pile strength. <i>Comput. Geotech.</i><b>97</b>, 27&#x2013;41 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compgeo.2017.12.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di, H. et al. Observed long-term differential settlement of metro structures built on soft deposits in the Yangtze River Delta Region of China. <i>Can. Geotech. J.</i><b>57</b>, 840&#x2013;850 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/cgj-2018-0524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng, C. W. W., Liu, G. B. &amp; Li, Q. Investigation of the long-term tunnel settlement mechanisms of the first metro line in Shanghai. <i>Can. Geotech. J.</i><b>50</b>, 674&#x2013;684 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/cgj-2012-0298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z., Huang, M. &amp; Wang, W. Evaluation of deformation response for adjacent tunnels due to soil unloading in excavation engineering. <i>Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol.</i><b>38</b>, 244&#x2013;253 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2013.07.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Y., Hu, Z. Z. &amp; Zhang, W. Z. Development and application of an industry foundation classes-based metro protection information model. <i>Math. Probl. Eng.</i><b>2018</b>, 1820631 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, W., Ju, S. &amp; Wang, H. Protection of ground buildings (structures) and treatment technologies of underground obstacles. In <i>Shield Tunneling Technology in Mixed Face Ground Conditions</i> (eds Zhu, W., Ju, S. &amp; Wang, H.). 401&#x2013;445. 10.1007/978-981-19-4112-2_13 (Springer, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, B., Shao, C. &amp; Xu, W. Influenced zone of deep excavation on adjacent tunnel displacement and control effect of ground improvement in soft soil. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>12</b>, 9047 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app12189047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beijing Lizheng Software Co., Ltd. <i>Lizheng Deep Foundation Pit Support Structure Design Software V7.5</i>. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural &amp; Development, PRC. <i>Code for Construction of Building Foundation Engineering</i>. (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinkgreve, R. B. J., Broere, W. &amp; Waterman, D. <i>Plaxis 2D - Version 9.0</i>. (Plaxis 2D - Version 9.0, 2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentley Systems Inc. <i>PLAXIS Tutorial Manual 2D</i>. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentley Systems Inc. <i>PLAXIS Material Models Manual 2D</i>. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COMSOL, Inc. <i>COMSOL Documentation</i>. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renard, P. &amp; de Marsily, G. Calculating equivalent permeability: a review. <i>Adv. Water Resour.</i><b>20</b>, 253&#x2013;278 (1997).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0309-1708(96)00050-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, G., Liu, H., Dai, G., Chen, X. &amp; Deng, Y. Dynamic analysis of a Concrete-Cored deep cement mixing pile under horizontal dynamic loads. <i>Buildings</i><b>13</b>, 1378 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings13061378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, P. et al. Variations of undrained shear strength of EPB mud and a calculation model based on consistency index. <i>Adv. Civ. Eng.</i> 6707015 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahetaji, M. &amp; Brahma, J. Prediction of minimum mud weight for prevention of breakout using new 3D failure criterion to maintain wellbore stability. <i>Rock. Mech. Rock. Eng.</i><b>57</b>, 2231&#x2013;2252 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-023-03679-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, X. et al. Research on horizontal displacement monitoring of deep soil based on a distributed optical fibre sensor. <i>J. Mod. Opt.</i><b>65</b>, 158&#x2013;165 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09500340.2017.1382594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. Displacement monitoring during the excavation and support of deep foundation pit in complex environment. <i>Adv. Civ. Eng.</i><b>2021</b>, 5715306 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, L. et al. Displacement and internal force response of mechanically connected precast piles subjected to horizontal load based on the m-method. <i>Buildings</i><b>14</b>, 1943 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings14071943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, T. A., Nguyen, D. T. &amp; Nguyen, A. D. A novel approach to use Soil-Cement piles for steel sheet pile walls in deep excavations. <i>Cea</i><b>9</b>, 301&#x2013;316 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13189/cea.2021.090204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. Bearing characteristics of deep cement mixing integrated drilling, mixing and jetting piles based on numerical simulation. <i>Sustainability</i><b>16</b>, 9198 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su16219198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soomro, M. A., Memon, K. F., Soomro, M. A., Memon, A. &amp; Keerio, M. A. Single pile settlement and load transfer mechanism due to excavation in silty clay. <i>Eng. Technol. Appl. Sci. Res.</i><b>8</b>, 2485&#x2013;2492 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48084/etasr.1666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, C., Chen, Z. &amp; Zhou, J. Numerical investigations of pile group foundations under different pile length conditions. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>14</b>, 1908 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app14051908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodair, Y. &amp; Abdel-Mohti, A. Numerical analysis of Pile&#x2013;Soil interaction under axial and lateral loads. <i>Int. J. Concr Struct. Mater.</i><b>8</b>, 239&#x2013;249 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40069-014-0075-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, F. et al. Recycling waste soils for stability enhancement in bored pile construction. <i>Buildings</i><b>15</b>, 272 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings15020272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Q. Q., Zhang, Z. M. &amp; He, J. Y. A simplified approach for settlement analysis of single pile and pile groups considering interaction between identical piles in multilayered soils. <i>Comput. Geotech.</i><b>37</b>, 969&#x2013;976 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compgeo.2010.08.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, P. &amp; Mehndiratta, S. Exploring the efficacy of slope stabilization using piles: A comprehensive review. <i>Indian Geotech. J.</i>10.1007/s40098-024-01119-w (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40098-024-01119-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, G. et al. Risk assessment of deep foundation pit construction based on analytic hierarchy process and fuzzy mathematics. <i>Adv. Civ. Eng.</i><b>2020</b>, 8840043 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong, Z. Q. et al. Disturbance sensitivity of proximity construction in subway protection zone. <i>Civ. Eng.</i><b>6</b>, 28 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, B., Shao, C., Wang, N. &amp; Zhang, D. Influenced zone of deep excavation and a simplified prediction method for adjacent tunnel displacement in thick soft soil. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>13</b>, 4647 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app13074647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, J. et al. Study on the impact of deep foundation pit construction on nearby elevated structures&#x2014;Case study. <i>Buildings</i><b>14</b>, 2541 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings14082541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley, J. J. Fuzzy hierarchical analysis. <i>Fuzzy Sets Syst.</i><b>17</b>, 233&#x2013;247 (1985).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0165-0114(85)90090-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, J. Analytic hierarchy process for assessing factors influencing the stability of soil slopes reinforced with piles. <i>Environ. Earth Sci.</i><b>70</b>, 1507&#x2013;1514 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-013-2236-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J., Du, Z., Ma, L. &amp; Liu, C. Identification and assessment of subway construction risk: An integration of AHP and experts grading method. <i>Adv. Civ. Eng.</i><b>2021</b>, 6661099 (2021).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>