<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41321949</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2167-8359</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PeerJ</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PeerJ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Elemental pollution and risk assessment of soils and <i>Gundelia tournefortii</i> in a multi-sector industrial zone with a history of agricultural use.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e20374</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e20374</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e20374</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7717/peerj.20374</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The study provides new insights into elemental enrichments in soil and <i>Gundelia tournefortii</i> (<i>GT</i>) parts in a complex land use region where intensive agricultural activities were carried out in the past and 343 industrial facilities from various sectors have been operating for the last 32 years. The levels of crustal elements (aluminum (Al), iron (Fe), potassium (K), sodium (Na), titanium (T)), heavy metals (cadmium (Cd), chromium (Cr), copper (Cu), manganese (Mn), nickel (Ni), lead (Pb), zinc (Zn)), sulfer (S) and phosphorus (P) were determined in the sample matrices, their possible sources and the health risks associated with their human consumption were investigated. Significant enrichments in Cr, Ni, Pb, and Zn were observed in the soils, with the exceptionally high Pb enrichment (EF: 81.34) being noteworthy. The soil pollution index values (PI:2.06-6.82) confirm significant anthropogenic contamination. Bioconcentration factors (BCF) for Cu, K, Na, Mg, P and S were found to be &gt;1 in all roots and stems, Zn showed high accumulation in all roots and most stems, while Cd, Cr, Pb and Mn accumulated in a more limited number of samples. Principal component analysis (PCA) showed that the elements found in the geochemical composition of the region and those representing agricultural chemicals used throughout the long agricultural history overlap and form clusters that cannot be fully separated, while the analysis of the datasets from <i>GT</i> parts yielded similar results. However, the effects of industrial emissions and solid fuel use were clearly evident in the <i>GT</i> root and stem samples. High Nemerow Compound Pollution Index values (NCPIs) indicated contamination in plant parts. Estimated daily intake (EDI) values for Cu and Mn exceeded the tolerable upper intake level (TUIL) for children in many root and stem samples, while EDI values for Cr, Fe, and Zn also exceeded the limit value in several samples. Risk assessments for non-carcinogenic effects showed that numerous samples surpassed the safety limit for children as a result of elevated levels of Cr, Cu, Pb, Zn, Fe and Mn. Estimates for carcinogenic risk (CR) suggested that Cd and Cr in the majority of samples, along with Ni in some samples, could pose a lifetime cancer risk for children. The results reveal that geogenic influences, as well as pressures from past agricultural production and current industrial and fossil fuel-related pressures, are evident on the region's soils and <i>GT</i> crops. The accumulation of toxic elements in edible plant parts poses a risk to food security, necessitating detailed risk assessments. The findings provide a scientific basis for land-use planning and agricultural management, emphasizing the importance of effective emissions monitoring, agricultural production in areas away from polluting sources, and implementing stricter land-use policies for protecting the environment and public health.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;2025 &#xd6;zuysal et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xd6;zuysal</LastName><ForeName>Ay&#x15f;enur</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University, Department of Environmental Engineering, Buca, &#x130;zmir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fadaeivash</LastName><ForeName>Fariborz</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University, The Graduate School of Natural and Applied Sciences, Environmental Engineering, Buca, &#x130;zmir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ak&#x131;nc&#x131;</LastName><ForeName>G&#xf6;rkem</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University, Department of Environmental Engineering, Buca, &#x130;zmir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dokuz Eylul University, Science and Technology Application and Research Center, Buca, &#x130;zmir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PeerJ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101603425</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2167-8359</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012989">Soil Pollutants</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012987">Soil</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019216">Metals, Heavy</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018570" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Assessment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012989" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soil Pollutants</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012987" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soil</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000383" MajorTopicYN="Y">Agriculture</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019216" MajorTopicYN="N">Metals, Heavy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004784" MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental Monitoring</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004787" MajorTopicYN="Y">Environmental Pollution</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gundelia tournefortii</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heavy metals</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Industrial emissions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PCA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Soil</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare there are no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41321949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12659707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.20374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">20374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahmad I, Gul I, Irum S, Manzoor M, Arshad M. Accumulation of heavy metals in wild plants collected from the industrial sites&#x2014;potential for phytoremediation. International Journal of Environmental Science and Technology. 2023;20(5):5441&#x2013;5452. doi: 10.1007/s13762-022-04340-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13762-022-04340-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akinci G, Gok G, Bilgin M. Heavy metals bioconcentration and translocation in plants: the influence of a thermal power site. Environmental Engineering and Management Journal. 2019;18(8):1625&#x2013;1637. doi: 10.30638/eemj.2019.153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30638/eemj.2019.153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akinci G, Ozuysal A. Source identification of heavy metals and arsenic in biodegradable fractions of municipal solid waste: a case study of Izmir metropolitan city. Journal of Material Cycles and Waste Management. 2022;24(1):386&#x2013;401. doi: 10.1007/s10163-021-01329-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10163-021-01329-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almasoud FI, Usman AR, Al-Farraj AS. Heavy metals in the soils of the Arabian Gulf coast affected by industrial activities: analysis and assessment using enrichment factor and multivariate analysis. Arabian Journal of Geosciences. 2015;8(3):1691&#x2013;1703. doi: 10.1007/s12517-014-1298-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-014-1298-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM International . ASTM D2974-13- standard test methods for moisture, ash, and organic matter of peat and other organic soils. West Conshohocken, PA: ASTM International; 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1520/D2974-13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azeez OH, Kheder AE. Effect of Gundelia tournefortii on some biochemical parameters in dexamethasone-induced hyperglycemic and hyperlipidemic mice. Iraqi Journal of Veterinary Sciences. 2012;26(2):73&#x2013;79. doi: 10.33899/ijvs.2012.67458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33899/ijvs.2012.67458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baka&#xe7; M. Factor analysis applied to a geochemical study of. Environmental Geochemistry and Health. 2000;22:93&#x2013;111. doi: 10.1023/A:1006773305149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1006773305149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bati B, Celik I, Vuran NE, Turan A, Alkan EE, Zirek AK. Effects of Gundelia tournefortii L. on biochemical parameters, antioxidant activities and DNA damage in a rat model of experimental obesity. Brazilian Journal of Biology. 2023;83:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1590/1519-6984.251198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1519-6984.251198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34550296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behtash F, Abedini F, Ahmadi H, Mosavi SB, Aghaee A, Morshedloo MR, Lorenzo JM. Zinc application mitigates copper toxicity by regulating Cu uptake, activity of antioxidant enzymes, and improving physiological characteristics in summer squash. Antioxidants. 2022;11(9):1688. doi: 10.3390/antiox11091688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox11091688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9495343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36139763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatti RC, Kaur R, Kumar A, Kumar V, Singh S, Kumar P, Sharma S, Nirmala C, Singh AN. Nutrient component analyses of selected wild edible plants from Hamirpur district of Himachal Pradesh, India: an evaluation for future food. Vegetos. 2022;35(2):545&#x2013;550. doi: 10.1007/s42535-021-00336-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42535-021-00336-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bizzo G, Fabbri K, Gajdzinska M. FOOD 2030 pathways for action 2.0. European Commission, Directorate-General for Research and Innovation. 2023 doi: 10.2777/365011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2777/365011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradl HB. Sources and origins of heavy metals. In: Bradl HB, editor. Heavy metals in the environment. Issue C. Vol. 6. Amsterdam; Boston: Elsevier Academic Press; 2005. pp. 1&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1573-4285(05)80020-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunetti G, Soler-Rovira P, Farrag K, Senesi N. Tolerance and accumulation of heavy metals by wild plant species grown in contaminated soils in Apulia region, Southern Italy. Plant and Soil. 2009;318(1&#x2013;2):285&#x2013;298. doi: 10.1007/s11104-008-9838-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11104-008-9838-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buat-Menard P, Chesselet R. Atmospheric flux on the trace metal chemistry of oceani. Earth and Planetary Science Letters. 1979;42:399&#x2013;411. doi: 10.1016/0012-821X(79)90049-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0012-821X(79)90049-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bvenura C, Sivakumar D. The role of wild fruits and vegetables in delivering a balanced and healthy diet. Food Research International, 99(March) 2017;1:5&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1016/j.foodres.2017.06.046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodres.2017.06.046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28784471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>California Office of Environmental Health Hazard Assessment (OEHHA)  Cadmium.  [22 May 2024];https://oehha.ca.gov/chemicals/cadmium 2009 </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canada Government  The Canadian system of soil classification. 1998.  [01 December 2024]. https://sis.agr.gc.ca/cansis/taxa/cssc3/index.html https://sis.agr.gc.ca/cansis/taxa/cssc3/index.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;evik &#xd6;, Dirican M, Ulubey A, Vuru&#x15f;kan O. The Galena objects from neolithic Ulucak: the earliest metallic finds in Western Turkey. Adalya. 2020;23:7&#x2013;23. doi: 10.47589/adalya.837448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47589/adalya.837448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;oruh N, Sa&#x1e7;di&#xe7;o&#x1e7;lu Celep AG, &#xd6;zg&#xf6;k&#xe7;e F, I&#x15f;can M. Antioxidant capacities of Gundelia tournefortii L. extracts and inhibition on glutathione-S-transferase activity. Food Chemistry. 2007;100(3):1249&#x2013;1253. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2005.12.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2005.12.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Champion B. Chemical abundances and properties. 2008.  [09 August 2024]. https://demonstrations.wolfram.com/ChemicalAbundancesAndProperties/#related-demonstrations https://demonstrations.wolfram.com/ChemicalAbundancesAndProperties/#related-demonstrations</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chehregani A, Mohsenzade F, Vaezi F. Introducing a new metal accumulator plant and the evaluation of its ability in removing heavy metals. Toxicological and Environmental Chemistry. 2009;91(6):1105&#x2013;1114. doi: 10.1080/02772240802541403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02772240802541403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Wong CUI, Zhang H. Analysis and pollution evaluation of heavy metal content in soil of the Yellow River Wetland Reserve in Henan. PeerJ. 2023;11:1&#x2013;17. doi: 10.7717/peerj.16454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.16454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10725677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38107560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chhabra R. Classification of salt-affected soils. Arid Land Research and Management. 2005;19(1):61&#x2013;79. doi: 10.1080/15324980590887344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15324980590887344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danin A, Fragman-Sapir O. Gundelia tournefortii L. about analytical flora of Israel. 2007.  [10 August 2025]. https://flora.org.il/en/plants/guntou/ https://flora.org.il/en/plants/guntou/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edelstein M, Ben-Hur M. Heavy metals and metalloids: sources, risks and strategies to reduce their accumulation in horticultural crops. Scientia Horticulturae. 2018;234(February):431&#x2013;444. doi: 10.1016/j.scienta.2017.12.039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2017.12.039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Commission  Brussels, Belgium: European Commission [24 July 2024];https://food.ec.europa.eu/system/files/2020-05/f2f_action-plan_2020_strategy-info_en.pdf Farm to fork strategy COM(2020) 381 final. 2020 </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Commission  The EU pathway towards sustainable food systems transformation. 2023a.  [06 August 2024]. https://knowledge4policy.ec.europa.eu/publication/eu-pathway-towards-sustainable-food-systems-transformation_en https://knowledge4policy.ec.europa.eu/publication/eu-pathway-towards-sustainable-food-systems-transformation_en</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Commission  EU missions: soil deal for Europe. 2023b.  [06 August 2024]. https://mission-soil-platform.ec.europa.eu/home https://mission-soil-platform.ec.europa.eu/home</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evni G, Kan M. Evaluation of the Liquid Organic and Mineral Fertilizer Market Used in Agriculture; A Rural City Example. Ahi Evran Akademi (AEA) 2024;5(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facchinelli A, Sacchi E, Mallen L. Multivariate statistical and GIS-based approach to identify heavy metal sources in soils. Environmental Pollution. 2001;114(3):313&#x2013;324. doi: 10.1016/S0269-7491(00)00243-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0269-7491(00)00243-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11584630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farhang HR, Vahabi MR, Allafchian AR. Chemical compositions of the essential oil of Gundelia tournefortii L. (Asteraceae) from Central Zagros, Iran Hamid. Journal of Herbal Drug. 2016;6(4):227&#x2013;233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations  FAO strategic framework, 2022-31. 2021.  [24 July 2024]. https://www.fao.org/3/cb7099en/cb7099en.pdf https://www.fao.org/3/cb7099en/cb7099en.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations  Agrifood solutions to climate change. 2023a.  [24 July 2024]. http://www.fao.org/documents/card/en/c/cc8055en http://www.fao.org/documents/card/en/c/cc8055en</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations  General standard for contaminants and toxins in food and feed CXS 193-1995. 2023b.  [24 July 2024]. https://www.fao.org/fao-who-codexalimentarius/sh-proxy/fr/?lnk=1&amp;url=https%253A%252F%252Fworkspace.fao.org%252Fsites%252Fcodex%252FStandards%252FCXS%2B193-1995%252FCXS_193e.pdf https://www.fao.org/fao-who-codexalimentarius/sh-proxy/fr/?lnk=1&amp;url=https%253A%252F%252Fworkspace.fao.org%252Fsites%252Fcodex%252FStandards%252FCXS%2B193-1995%252FCXS_193e.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gemici &#xdc;. Evaluation of the water quality related to the acid mine drainage of an abandoned mercury mine (Ala&#x15f;ehir, Turkey) Environmental Monitoring and Assessment. 2008;147(1&#x2013;3):93&#x2013;106. doi: 10.1007/s10661-007-0101-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10661-007-0101-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18075780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>General Directorate of Mineral Research and Exploration . Mineral map of &#x130;zmir. 2024. [18 November 2024].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghaderian SM, Ghotbi Ravandi AA. Accumulation of copper and other heavy metals by plants growing on Sarcheshmeh copper mining area, Iran. Journal of Geochemical Exploration. 2012;123:25&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1016/j.gexplo.2012.06.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gexplo.2012.06.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf6;kta&#x15f; F, Hakyemez Y. Kemalpa&#x15f;a (&#x130;zmir) Pliyo-Kuvaterner Havzas&#x131;n&#x131;n Stratigrafik Evrimi. T&#xfc;rkiye Jeoloji B&#xfc;lteni / Geological Bulletin of Turkey. 2015;58(2):1&#x2013;28. doi: 10.25288/tjb.298498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25288/tjb.298498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goorani S, Koohi MK, Seydi N, Zangeneh A, Zangeneh MM. Protection of alloxan monohydrate-induced testicular toxicity by Gundelia tournefortii aerial parts aqueous extract in male mice. Iranian Journal of Pharmacology and Therapeutics. 2018;16(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grivetti LE, Ogle BM. Value of traditional foods in meeting macro- and micronutrient needs: the wild plant connection. Nutrition Research Reviews. 2000;13(1):31&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1079/095442200108728990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1079/095442200108728990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19087432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;l P. The evaluation of land use consciousness at Kemalpa&#x15f;a Basin. Thesis. 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haghi G, Hatami A, Arshi R. Distribution of caffeic acid derivatives in Gundelia tournefortii L. Food Chemistry. 2011;124(3):1029&#x2013;1035. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2010.07.069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2010.07.069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajizadeh-Sharafabad F, Alizadeh M, Mohammadzadeh MHS, Alizadeh-Salteh S, Kheirouri S. Effect of Gundelia tournefortii L. extract on lipid profile and TAC in patients with coronary artery disease: a double-blind randomized placebo controlled clinical trial. Journal of Herbal Medicine. 2016;6(2):59&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1016/j.hermed.2016.02.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hermed.2016.02.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hani N, Abulaila K, Howes MJR, Mattana E, Bacci S, Sleem K, Sarkis L, Eddine NS, Baydoun S, Apostolides NA, Ulian T. Gundelia tournefortii L. (Akkoub): a review of a valuable wild vegetable from Eastern Mediterranean. Genetic Resources and Crop Evolution. 2024;71:0123456789. doi: 10.1007/s10722-024-01927-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10722-024-01927-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan MF, Nur-E-alam M, Salam MA, Rahman H, Paul SC, Rak AE, Ambade B, Towfiqul Islam ARM. Health risk and water quality assessment of surface water in an urban river of Bangladesh. Sustainability. 2021;13(12):1&#x2013;22. doi: 10.3390/su13126832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su13126832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain S, Shafiq I, Skalicky M, Brestic M, Rastogi A, Mumtaz M, Hussain M, Iqbal N, Raza MA, Manzoor S, Liu W, Yang W. Titanium application increases phosphorus uptake through changes in auxin content and root architecture in soybean (Glycine Max L.) Frontiers in Plant Science. 2021;12(November):1&#x2013;18. doi: 10.3389/fpls.2021.743618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2021.743618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8631872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34858450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Agency for Researchon Cancer (IARC)  Agents classified by the IARC monographs, volumes 1&#x2013;138. 2025.  [ 19 August 2025]. https://monographs.iarc.who.int/agents-classified-by-the-iarc/ https://monographs.iarc.who.int/agents-classified-by-the-iarc/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izmir Provincial Culture and Tourism Directorate  Kemalpasa&#x327;. 2025.  [05 August 2024]. https://izmir.ktb.gov.tr/TR-77457/kemalpasa.html https://izmir.ktb.gov.tr/TR-77457/kemalpasa.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalali M, Fakhri R. Evaluation of macro and trace elements content of wild edible Iranian plants and their contribution to dietary reference intakes. Journal of Food Composition and Analysis. 2021;102(June):104049. doi: 10.1016/j.jfca.2021.104049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfca.2021.104049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamshidzadeh A, Fereidooni F, Salehi Z, Niknahad H. Hepatoprotective activity of Gundelia tourenfortii. Journal of Ethnopharmacology. 2005;101(1&#x2013;3):233&#x2013;237. doi: 10.1016/j.jep.2005.04.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2005.04.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15955646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia L, Wang W, Li Y, Yang L. Heavy metals in soil and crops of an intensively farmed area: a case study in Yucheng City, Shandong Province, China. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2010;7(2):395&#x2013;412. doi: 10.3390/ijerph7020395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph7020395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2872287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20616981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kad&#x131;o&#x11f;lu &#x130;. T&#xfc;rkiye Tar&#x131;m&#x131;nda Bitki Koruma ve Baz&#x131;G&#xfc;ncel Yakla&#x15f;&#x131;mlar&#x131;n De&#x11f;erlendirilmesi. Ziraat M&#xfc;hendisli&#x11f;i. 2012;359:18&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemalpasa District Governorship  Kemalpa&#x15f;a historical and geographical structure. 2016.  [05 August 2024]. http://www.kemalpasa.gov.tr/kemalpasa-tarihi-ve-cografi-yapi http://www.kemalpasa.gov.tr/kemalpasa-tarihi-ve-cografi-yapi</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemalpa&#x15f;a Municipality  Kemalpa&#x15f;a. 2024.  [05 August 2024]. https://www.izmir-kemalpasa.bel.tr/kemalpasa-izmir-tarihi-tarim-sanayi-kiraz https://www.izmir-kemalpasa.bel.tr/kemalpasa-izmir-tarihi-tarim-sanayi-kiraz</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keskin M, Kaya G, Keskin &#x15e;. Gundelia Tournefortii L. (Kenger): determination of in vitro antidiabetic activities. Progress in Nutrition. 2021;23(4):e2021163. doi: 10.23751/pn.v23i4.11079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23751/pn.v23i4.11079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan A, Khan MS, Egozcue JJ, Shafique MA, Nadeem S, Saddiq G. Irrigation suitability, health risk assessment and source apportionment of heavy metals in surface water used for irrigation near marble industry in Malakand, Pakistan. PLOS ONE. 2022;17(12 December):1&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0279083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0279083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9770375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36542623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan A, Khan MS, Shafique MA, Khan Q, Saddiq G. Assessment of potentially toxic and mineral elements in paddy soils and their uptake by rice (Oryza sativa L.) with associated health hazards in district Malakand, Pakistan. Heliyon. 2024;10(7):e28043. doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e28043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e28043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10998073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38586322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanzadeh F, Khodaparast MHH, ElhamiRad AH, Rahmani FR. Physiochemical properties of gundelia tournefortii L. seed oil. Journal of Agricultural Science and Technology. 2012;14(SUPPL.):1535&#x2013;1542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kharazi A, Leili M, Khazaei M, Alikhani MY, Shokoohi R. Human health risk assessment of heavy metals in agricultural soil and food crops in Hamadan, Iran. Journal of Food Composition and Analysis. 2021;100(2020):103890. doi: 10.1016/j.jfca.2021.103890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfca.2021.103890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konak M, Ate&#x15f; M, &#x15e;ahan Y. Determination of antioxidant properties of the edible wild plant Gundelia tournefortii. Journal of Uludag University Faculty of Agriculture. 2017;31(2):101&#x2013;108. [In Turkish]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>KOSBI  Companies in KOSBI. 2023a.  [05 August 2024]. https://kosbi.org.tr/resimler/aktuel/rakamlarla_kosbi/mobile/html5forpc.html https://kosbi.org.tr/resimler/aktuel/rakamlarla_kosbi/mobile/html5forpc.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>KOSBI  Information about KOSBI. 2023b.  [05 August 2024]. https://kosbi.org.tr/firmalar https://kosbi.org.tr/firmalar</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>KOSBI. Halkbankas&#x131;  &#x130;zm&#x131;r kemalpa&#x15f;a organi&#x17c;e sanayi&#x307; b&#xf6;lgesi&#x307;, Turkishtime. 2020.  [19 November 2024]. https://turkishtimedergi.com/ortak-akil/kemalpasa-organize-sanayi-bolgesi-kosbi/ https://turkishtimedergi.com/ortak-akil/kemalpasa-organize-sanayi-bolgesi-kosbi/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kukusamude C, Sricharoen P, Limchoowong N, Kongsri S. Heavy metals and probabilistic risk assessment via rice consumption in Thailand. Food Chemistry. 2021;334(2020):127402. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2020.127402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2020.127402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32711260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai J, Liu J, Wu D, Xu J. Pollution and health risk assessment of rare earth elements in Citrus sinensis growing soil in mining area of southern China. PeerJ. 2023;11:e15470. doi: 10.7717/peerj.15470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.15470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10252884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37304884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai J, Ni Y, Xu J, Wu D. Health and ecological risk of heavy metals in agricultural soils related to Tungsten mining in Southern Jiangxi Province, China. PeerJ. 2024;12:1&#x2013;24. doi: 10.7717/peerj.17200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.17200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10993887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38577416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laptiev V, Apori SO, Giltrap M, Tian F, Ryzhenko N. Bioaccumulation of Cr, Zn, Pb and Cu in Ambrosia artemisiifolia L. and Erigeron canadensis L. Resources. 2024;13(3):1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.3390/resources13030043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/resources13030043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonti M, Nebel S, Rivera D, Heinrich M. Wild gathered food plants in the European Mediterranean: a comparative analysis. Economic Botany. 2006;60(2):130&#x2013;142. doi: 10.1663/0013-0001(2006)60[130:WGFPIT]2.0.CO;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1663/0013-0001(2006)60[130:WGFPIT]2.0.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Ma Z, van der Kuijp TJ, Yuan Z, Huang L. A review of soil heavy metal pollution from mines in China: pollution and health risk assessment. Science of the Total Environment. 2014;468&#x2013;469:843&#x2013;853. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2013.08.090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2013.08.090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24076505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B, Huang Q, Cai H, Guo X, Wang T, Gui M. Study of heavy metal concentrations in wild edible mushrooms in Yunnan province, China. Food Chemistry. 2015;188:294&#x2013;300. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2015.05.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2015.05.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26041195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loganathan P. Port Harcourt, Nigeria: African Regional Aquaculture Centre (ARAC)Soil quality considerations in the selection of sites for aquaculture. ARAC/87/WP/12. (FAO/UNDP&#x2013;NIOMR Project RAF/82/009) 1987</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loska K, Wiechu&#x142;a D, Pelczar J. Application of enrichment factor to assessment of zinc enrichment/depletion in farming soils. Communications in Soil Science and Plant Analysis. 2005;36(9&#x2013;10):1117&#x2013;1128. doi: 10.1081/CSS-200056880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1081/CSS-200056880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik RN, Husain SZ, Nazir I. Heavy metal contamination and accumulation in soil and wild plant species from industrial area of Islamabad, Pakistan. Pakistan Journal of Botany. 2010;42(1):291&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansi K, Tabaza Y, Aburjai T. The iron chelating activity of Gundelia tournefortii in iron overloaded experimental rats. Journal of Ethnopharmacology. 2020;263(February):113114. doi: 10.1016/j.jep.2020.113114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2020.113114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32736049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mente&#x15f;e &#x15e;. Yakak&#xf6;y flint bed. Journal of Izmir Studies. 2022;8(17):1&#x2013;14. [In Turkish]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mic&#xf3; C, Recatal&#xe1; L, Peris M, S&#xe1;nchez J. Assessing heavy metal sources in agricultural soils of an European Mediterranean area by multivariate analysis. Chemosphere. 2006;65(5):863&#x2013;872. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2006.03.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2006.03.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16635506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moameri M, Jafri M, Tavili A, Motasharezadeh B, Zare MA. Potential for phytoremediation of contaminated soils with lead, zinc, cadmium and nickel (case study: Rangelands around National Lead &amp; Zinc Factory, Zanjan, Iran) Journal of Rangeland Science. 2017;7(2):160&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohsenzadeh F, Rad AC. Bioremediation of heavy metal pollution by nano-particles of Noaea Mucronata. International Journal of Bioscience, Biochemistry and Bioinformatics. 2012;2(2):85&#x2013;89. doi: 10.7763/IJBBB.2012.V2.77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7763/IJBBB.2012.V2.77</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montgomery DR, Bikl&#xe9; A, Archuleta R, Brown P, Jordan J. Soil health and nutrient density : preliminary comparison of regenerative and conventional farming. PeerJ. 2022;10:1&#x2013;20. doi: 10.7717/peerj.12848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.12848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8801175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35127297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muminov MA, Guo L, Song Y, Gu X, Cen Y, Meng J, Jiang G. Comparisons of weed community, soil health and economic performance between wheat-maize and garlic-soybean rotation systems under different weed managements. PeerJ. 2018;2018(5):e4799. doi: 10.7717/peerj.4799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.4799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5984582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29868258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natural Gas  Subscriber Center Opened in Kemalpasa&#x327;. 2022.  [05 November 2024].  
https://www.dogalgaz.com.tr/yayin/323/kemalpasaa-ya-abone-merkezi-acildi_30561.html. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nefis  Local food recipes. 2014.  [18 October 2024]. https://www.nefisyemektarifleri.com/yoresel-yemek-kenger/ https://www.nefisyemektarifleri.com/yoresel-yemek-kenger/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neina D. The role of soil pH in plant nutrition and soil remediation. Applied and Environmental Soil Science. 2019;2019(3):1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1155/2019/5794869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/5794869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>OEHHA  Nickel refinery dust. 2009.  [22 May 2024]. https://oehha.ca.gov/chemicals/nickel-refinery-dust https://oehha.ca.gov/chemicals/nickel-refinery-dust</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrovi&#x107; M, Meduni&#x107; G, Fiket &#x17d;. Essential role of multi-element data in interpreting elevated element concentrations in areas impacted by both natural and anthropogenic influences. PeerJ. 2023;11:e15904. doi: 10.7717/peerj.15904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.15904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10512964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37744221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinela J, Carvalho AM, Ferreira ICFR. Wild edible plants: nutritional and toxicological characteristics, retrieval strategies and importance for today&#x2019;s society. Food and Chemical Toxicology. 2017;110(October):165&#x2013;188. doi: 10.1016/j.fct.2017.10.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fct.2017.10.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29042290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proshad R, Idris AM. Evaluation of heavy metals contamination in cereals, vegetables and fruits with probabilistic health hazard in a highly polluted megacity. Environmental Science and Pollution Research. 2023;30(32):79525&#x2013;79550. doi: 10.1007/s11356-023-27977-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-023-27977-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37289387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai PK, Lee SS, Zhang M, YF Tsang, Kim KH. Heavy metals in food crops: health risks, fate, mechanisms, and management. Environment International. 2019;125(2018):365&#x2013;385. doi: 10.1016/j.envint.2019.01.067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envint.2019.01.067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30743144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranfa A, Maurizi A, Romano B, Bodesmo M. The importance of traditional uses and nutraceutical aspects of some edible wild plants in human nutrition: the case of Umbria (central Italy) Plant Biosystems. 2014;148(2):297&#x2013;306. doi: 10.1080/11263504.2013.770805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/11263504.2013.770805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashid A, Schutte BJ, Ulery A, Deyholos MK, Sanogo S, Lehnhoff EA, Beck L. Heavy metal contamination in agricultural soil: environmental pollutants affecting crop health. Agronomy. 2023;13(6):1&#x2013;30. doi: 10.3390/agronomy13061521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy13061521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray A, Ray R, Sreevidya EA. How many wild edible plants do we eat&#x2014;their diversity, use, and implications for sustainable food system: an exploratory analysis in India. Frontiers in Sustainable Food Systems. 2020;4:56. doi: 10.3389/fsufs.2020.00056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsufs.2020.00056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rengel Z, Robinson DL. Competitive Al3+ inhibition of Net Mg2+ uptake by intact lolium multiflorum roots: I. Kinetics. Plant Physiology. 1989;91(4):1407&#x2013;1413. doi: 10.1104/pp.91.4.1407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.91.4.1407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1062198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16667193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rom&#xe1;n-Ochoa Y, Choque Delgado GT, Tejada TR, Yucra HR, Durand AE, Hamaker BR. Heavy metal contamination and health risk assessment in grains and grain-based processed food in Arequipa region of Peru. Chemosphere. 2021;274:129792. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2021.129792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2021.129792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33556663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadee BA. Determination of elements in indigenous vegetables using ICP-MS. Cihan University-Erbil Scientific Journal. 2022;6(1):26&#x2013;31. doi: 10.24086/cuesj.v6n1y2022.pp26-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24086/cuesj.v6n1y2022.pp26-31</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkar D, Walker-Swaney J, Shetty K. Food diversity and indigenous food systems to combat diet-linked chronic diseases. Current Developments in Nutrition. 2020;4:3&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1093/CDN/NZZ099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/CDN/NZZ099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7101483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32258994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathiyamoorthy P, Van Damme P, Oven M, Golan-Goldhirsh A. Heavy metals in medicinal and fodder plants of the negev desert. Journal of Environmental Science and Health - Part A Toxic/Hazardous Substances and Environmental Engineering. 1997;32(8):2111&#x2013;2123. doi: 10.1080/10934529709376671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10934529709376671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen N, Irfan NM, Khan IN, Islam S, Islam MS, Ahmed MK. Presence of heavy metals in fruits and vegetables: health risk implications in Bangladesh. Chemosphere. 2016;152:431&#x2013;438. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2016.02.060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2016.02.060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27003365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma RK, Agrawal M, Marshall FM. Heavy metals in vegetables collected from production and market sites of a tropical urban area of India. Food and Chemical Toxicology. 2009;47(3):583&#x2013;591. doi: 10.1016/j.fct.2008.12.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fct.2008.12.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19138719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sponza D, Karao&#x1e7;lu N. Environmental geochemistry and pollution studies of Alia&#x1e7;a metal industry district. Environment International. 2002;27(7):541&#x2013;553. doi: 10.1016/S0160-4120(01)00108-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0160-4120(01)00108-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11868663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutherland RA. Bed sediment-associated trace metals in an urban stream, Oahu, Hawaii. Environmental Geology. 2000;39(6):611&#x2013;627. doi: 10.1007/s002540050473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s002540050473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarcan G, Ak&#x131;nc&#x131; G, Dan&#x131;&#x15f;man MA. Assessment of the pollution from tannery effluents upon waters and soils in and around Kula vicinity, Turkey. Water, Air, and Soil Pollution. 2010;213(1&#x2013;4):199&#x2013;210. doi: 10.1007/s11270-010-0378-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11270-010-0378-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarhan A, Firat M, Topal G. Comprehensive study of all Gundelia L. taxa exists in the globe: an insight on LC-MS/MS based phytochemical investigation and bioactivity potential of 22 species. Biochemical Systematics and Ecology. 2023;109(May):104672. doi: 10.1016/j.bse.2023.104672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bse.2023.104672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry  Turkish standard for contaminants and toxins in food and feed (32360) 2023.  [14 October 2024]. https://www.resmigazete.gov.tr/eskiler/2023/11/20231105-1.htm https://www.resmigazete.gov.tr/eskiler/2023/11/20231105-1.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tun&#xe7;t&#xfc;rk M, Sekeroglu N, &#xd6;zg&#xf6;k&#xe7;e F, Tuncturk M, Ozgokce F. Chemical composition of some edible wild plants grown in Eastern Anatolia. American Journal of Essential Oils and Natural Products. 2015;2(3):31&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turan M, Kordali S, Zengin H, Dursun A, Sezen Y. Macro and micro mineral content of some wild edible leaves consumed in Eastern Anatolia. Acta Agriculturae Scandinavica Section B: Soil and Plant Science. 2003;53(3):129&#x2013;137. doi: 10.1080/090647103100095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/090647103100095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turkish Standards Institute . TS ISO 11465-Soil quality; determination of dry matter and water content on a mass basis; gravimetric method. Ankara, Turkey: Turkish Standards Institute (TSE); 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>TurkStat  Weight averages by age group and gender, 2008-2022. 2023. https://data.tuik.gov.tr/Kategori/GetKategori?p=Saglik-ve-Sosyal-Koruma-101.  [18 October 2024]. https://data.tuik.gov.tr/Kategori/GetKategori?p=Saglik-ve-Sosyal-Koruma-101</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>TurkStat  Population of Izmir Districts. 2024. https://biruni.tuik.gov.tr/medas/?kn=95&amp;locale=tr.  [05 August 2024]. https://biruni.tuik.gov.tr/medas/?kn=95&amp;locale=tr</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner NJ, Luczaj LJ, Migliorini P, Pieroni A, Dreon AL, Sacchetti LE, Paoletti MG. Edible and tended wild plants, traditional ecological knowledge and Agroecology. Critical Reviews in Plant Sciences. 2011;30(1&#x2013;2):198&#x2013;225. doi: 10.1080/07352689.2011.554492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07352689.2011.554492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) Soil taxonomy a basic system of soil classification for making and interpreting soil surveys (Issue 436) 436 Washington, DC: Natural Resources Conservation Service, USDA; 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Nutrition Board Institute of Medicine . Dietary reference intakes. National Academy Press; Washington, DC: 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA Washington, DC: U.S. Environmental Protection AgencySupplemental guidance for developing soil screening OSWER 9355.4-24. 2002;106 (Issue December, 106)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA . Provisional peer reviewed toxicity values for iron and compounds (CASRN 7439-89-6) derivation of subchronic and chronic oral RfDs. Washington, DC: U.S. Environmental Protection Agency; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA . IRIS toxicological review of hexavalent chromium [Cr(VI)] CASRN 18540-29-9. Washington, DC: U.S. Environmental Protection Agency; 2024a. (Issue August)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39869745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA  IRIS assessments. 2024b. https://iris.epa.gov/AtoZ/?list_type=alpha.  [19 August 2025]. https://iris.epa.gov/AtoZ/?list_type=alpha</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA  Regional Screening Levels (RSLs) 2024c.  [19 August 2025]. https://www.epa.gov/risk/regional-screening-levels-rsls https://www.epa.gov/risk/regional-screening-levels-rsls</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veerman CP. Activity update of the Mission Board of European Union on soil health and food. Soil and Environmental Health. 2023;1(2):100018. doi: 10.1016/j.seh.2023.100018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seh.2023.100018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wairich A, De Conti L, Lamb TI, Keil R, Neves LO, Brunetto G, Sperotto RA, Ricachenevsky FK. Throwing copper around: how plants control uptake, distribution, and accumulation of copper. Agronomy. 2022;12(5):994. doi: 10.3390/agronomy12050994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy12050994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei J, Cen K. Contamination and health risk assessment of heavy metals in cereals, legumes, and their products: a case study based on the dietary structure of the residents of Beijing, China. Journal of Cleaner Production. 2020;260:121001. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.121001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.121001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler K, Fuchs R, Rounsevell M, Herold M. Global land use changes are four times greater than previously estimated. Nature Communications. 2021;12:2501. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-22702-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-22702-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8113269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33976120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wuana RA, Okieimen FE. Heavy metals in contaminated soils: a review of sources, chemistry, risks and best available strategies for remediation. ISRN Ecology. 2011;2011:1&#x2013;20. doi: 10.5402/2011/402647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5402/2011/402647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaylali-Abanuz G. Heavy metal contamination of surface soil around Gebze industrial area, Turkey. Microchemical Journal. 2011;99(1):82&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1016/j.microc.2011.04.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.microc.2011.04.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo C, Xiao H, Zhong QW, Weng Q. Unequal impacts of urban industrial land expansion on economic growth and carbon dioxide emissions. Communications Earth and Environment. 2024;5:203. doi: 10.1038/s43247-024-01375-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43247-024-01375-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng X, Kong S, Zhang Q, Ren H, Liu J, Feng Y, Yan Q, Qin S, Zheng S, Yao L, Fan Z, Zhang Y, Liu X, Yan Y, Zhu K, Ding F, Liu W, Liu D, Qi S, Fu P. Source profiles and emission factors of organic and inorganic species in fine particles emitted from the ultra-low emission power plant and typical industries. Science of the Total Environment. 2021;789:147966. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.147966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.147966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34058574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Liu F, Yu X, Jiang X, Cui Y, Li M. Risk assessment and ecotoxicological diagnosis of soil from a chemical industry park in Nanjing, China. Ecotoxicology. 2021;30(7):1303&#x2013;1314. doi: 10.1007/s10646-020-02320-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10646-020-02320-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33405002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Sun X, Du B, Yin S, Liu C. Multielement stoichiometry in Quercus variabilis under natural phosphorus variation in subtropical China. Scientific Reports. 2015;5(January):7839. doi: 10.1038/srep07839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep07839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4296308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25592849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>further reading</Title><Reference><Citation>Aktaruzzaman M, Zakir HM, Quadir QF, Rashid MH, Mallick S, Biswas P, Nayeem SMMR. Toxic heavy metals content in different agrochemicals available in markets of Bangladesh and their loads to the agricultural lands. Environmental Monitoring and Assessment. 2024;196(11):1053. doi: 10.1007/s10661-024-13212-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10661-024-13212-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39404921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allaway WH. Agronomic controls over the environmental cycling of trace elements. Advances in Agronomy. 1968;20(C):235&#x2013;274. doi: 10.1016/S0065-2113(08)60858-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0065-2113(08)60858-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alloway BJ. Heavy metals in soils. In: Alloway BJ, Trevors JT, editors. Encyclopedia of toxicology. 4th edn. Volume 1-9 (Third, Vol. 9) Springer; Dordrecht: 2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-12-824315-2.00658-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelova V, Ivanova R, Ivanov K. Heavy metal accumulation and distribution in oil crops. Communications in Soil Science and Plant Analysis. 2004;35(17&#x2013;18):2551&#x2013;2566. doi: 10.1081/LCSS-200030368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1081/LCSS-200030368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai QL, Bi XH, Wu JH, Zhang YF, Wang J, Xu H, Yao L, Jiao L, Feng YC. Characterization and source identification of heavy metals in ambient PM10 and PM2.5 in an integrated Iron and Steel industry zone compared with a background site. Aerosol and Air Quality Research. 2015;15(3):875&#x2013;887. doi: 10.4209/aaqr.2014.09.0226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4209/aaqr.2014.09.0226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dionne J, Walker TR. Air pollution impacts from a pulp and paper mill facility located in adjacent communities, Edmundston, New Brunswick, Canada and Madawaska, Maine, United States. Environmental Challenges. 2021;5(August):100245. doi: 10.1016/j.envc.2021.100245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envc.2021.100245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekin &#x130;. Mineral and heavy metal concentration of nutritionally and therapeutically valued wild plants: insights into health effects. &#x130;stanbul Journal of Pharmacy. 2022;52(2):179&#x2013;186. doi: 10.26650/istanbuljpharm.2022.1066377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26650/istanbuljpharm.2022.1066377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedlova M. The influence of heavy metals on soil biological and chemical properties. Soil and Water Research. 2010;5(1):21&#x2013;27. doi: 10.17221/11/2009-swr.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17221/11/2009-swr</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautam PK, Gautam RK, Banerjee S, Chattopadhyaya MC, Pandey JD. Heavy metals in the environment: fate, transport, toxicity and remediation technologies. In: Pathania D, editor. Heavy metals: sources, toxicity and remediation techniques. Issue February. Hauppauge, NY: Nava Science Publishers; 2016. pp. 101&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gimeno-Garc&#xed;a E, Andreu V, Boluda R. Heavy metals incidence in the application of inorganic fertilizers and pesticides to rice farming soils. Environmental Pollution. 1996;92(1):19&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1016/0269-7491(95)00090-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0269-7491(95)00090-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15091407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govil PK, Reddy GLN, Krishna AK. Contamination of soil due to heavy metals in the Patancheru industrial development area, Andhra Pradesh, India. Environmental Geology. 2001;41(3&#x2013;4):461&#x2013;469. doi: 10.1007/s002540100415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s002540100415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaworska H, Matuszczak K, R&#xf3;za&#x144;ski S. Impact of pulp and paper industry on the content of selected elements in soils and plants. Catena. 2020;193:104579. doi: 10.1016/j.catena.2020.104579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.catena.2020.104579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> National Atmospheric Emissions Inventory (NAEI)  Heavy metal emission estimates. 1999. https://uk-air.defra.gov.uk/assets/documents/reports/empire/naei/annreport/annrep98/chap6_3.html.  [10 July 2024]. https://uk-air.defra.gov.uk/assets/documents/reports/empire/naei/annreport/annrep98/chap6_3.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osma E, Ozyigit II, Demir G, Yasar U. Assesment of some heavy metals in wild type and cultivated purslane (Portulaca oleracea L.) and soils in Istanbul, Turkey. Fresenius Environmental Bulletin. 2014;23(9):2181&#x2013;2189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passant NR, Peirce M, Rudd HJ, Scott DW, Marlowe I, Watterson JD.  UK particulate and heavy metal emissions from industrial processes AEAT-6270 (Issue 2) Culham, Abingdon, Oxfordshire, UK: AEA Technology plc; 2002.  [10 July 2024].  .&#xa0;https://uk-air.defra.gov.uk/assets/documents/reports/empire/AEAT6270Issue2finaldraft_v2.pdf. 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peris M, Mic&#xf3; C, Recatal&#xe1; L, S&#xe1;nchez R, S&#xe1;nchez J. Heavy metal contents in horticultural crops of a representative area of the European Mediterranean region. Science of the Total Environment. 2007;378(1&#x2013;2):42&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2007.01.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2007.01.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17306337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perusic M, Vasiljevi&#x107; L, Pelemis SS. The main sources of heavy metals in the soil and pathways intake safety od children&#x2019;s toys view project. International congress &#x201c;Engineering, Environment and Materials in Processing Industry&#x201d;; 2019. pp. 453&#x2013;465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renna M, Cocozza C, Gonnella M, Abdelrahman H, Santamaria P. Elemental characterization of wild edible plants from countryside and urban areas. Food Chemistry. 2015;177:29&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2014.12.069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2014.12.069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25660854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semreen MH, Aboul-Enein HY. Determination of heavy metal content in wild-edible mushroom from Jordan. Analytical Letters. 2011;44(5):932&#x2013;941. doi: 10.1080/00032711003790072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00032711003790072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Zacharias M, Kalpana S, Mishra S. Heavy metals accumulation and distribution pattern in different vegetable crops. Journal of Environmental Chemistry and Ecotoxicology. 2012;4(4):75&#x2013;81. doi: 10.5897/jece11.076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/jece11.076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Duan X, Wang L. Spatial distribution and source analysis of heavy metals in soils influenced by industrial enterprise distribution: case study in Jiangsu Province. Science of the Total Environment. 2020;710:134953. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2019.134953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2019.134953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31923652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarcinas BA, Ishak CF, McLaughlin MJ, Cozens G. Heavy metals in soils and crops in Southeast Asia, 1. Peninsular Malaysia. Environmental Geochemistry and Health. 2004b;26(3):343&#x2013;357. doi: 10.1007/s10653-005-4669-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10653-005-4669-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15719158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarcinas BA, Pongsakul P, McLaughlin MJ, Cozens G. Heavy metals in soils and crops in Southeast Asia. 2. Thailand. Environmental Geochemistry and Health. 2004a;26(3):359&#x2013;371. doi: 10.1007/s10653-005-4670-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10653-005-4670-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15719159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, Qiang C, Liu J. Spatial distribution characteristics of heavy metals in the soil of coal chemical industrial areas. Journal of Soils and Sediments. 2018;18(5):2044&#x2013;2052. doi: 10.1007/s11368-018-1972-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11368-018-1972-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Yang H, Sun R, Cui M, Sun N, Zhang S. Evaluation and analysis of heavy metals in iron and steel industrial area. Environment, Development and Sustainability. 2022;24(9):10997&#x2013;11010. doi: 10.1007/s10668-021-01893-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10668-021-01893-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang P, Zou B, Li NY, Li ZA. Heavy metal contamination in soils and food crops around Dabaoshan mine in Guangdong, China: implication for human health. Environmental Geochemistry and Health. 2009;31(6):707&#x2013;715. doi: 10.1007/s10653-009-9248-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10653-009-9248-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19214759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoffoli HJO, Do Amaral-Sobrinho NMB, Zonta E, Luisi MV, Marcon G, Tol&#xf3;n-Becerra A. Inputs of heavy metals due to agrochemical use in tobacco fields in Brazil&#x2019;s Southern Region. Environmental Monitoring and Assessment. 2013;185(3):2423&#x2013;2437. doi: 10.1007/s10661-012-2721-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10661-012-2721-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22729828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>