<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41497238</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2288-176X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of exercise rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exerc Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of kinesiology taping leggings on exercise performance and physiological responses during CrossFit training in women aged 20-30 years.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>300</StartPage><EndPage>306</EndPage><MedlinePgn>300-306</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12965/jer.2550742.371</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study examined the effects of kinesiology taping leggings on exercise performance and physiological responses during CrossFit training in women aged 20-30 years. A randomized crossover design was employed with 42 healthy participants. Each participant completed two 3-week training periods wearing either taping leggings or regular leggings, separated by a 2-week washout period. Sixteen variables, including strength, endurance, power, agility, balance, proprioception, functional movement, heart-rate variability, exercise satisfaction, and lower-limb circumference, were measured. Significant improvements were observed in isokinetic strength (148.25&#xb1;12.45 to 151.78&#xb1;12.38 N&#xb7;m), joint-position sense (2.18&#xb0;&#xb1;0.65&#xb0; to 1.95&#xb0;&#xb1;0.62&#xb0;), exercise satisfaction (6.85&#xb1;1.42 to 7.34&#xb1;1.28), and edema reduction (31.5% decrease). Most other fitness variables showed improvement trends but were not statistically significant. Taping leggings provided selective but meaningful benefits in enhancing proprioception, improving subjective satisfaction, and reducing edema during CrossFit training.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Korean Society of Exercise Rehabilitation.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Joon-Hee</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Counseling Rehabilitation, KwangWoon University, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Um</LastName><ForeName>Sung-Heum</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>FORTIUM Lab, Korea University, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jae-Suk</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-8804-7511</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, CHA University, Pocheon, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>J Exerc Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101615171</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2288-176X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Compression garments</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CrossFit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kinesiology taping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Women</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>CONFLICT OF INTEREST No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41497238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12765890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.2550742.371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jer-21-6-300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bosco C, Luhtanen P, Komi PV. A simple method for measurement of mechanical power in jumping. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1983;50:273&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6681758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg GA. Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1982;14:377&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7154893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bringard A, Perrey S, Belluye N. Aerobic energy cost and sensation responses during submaximal running exercise--positive effects of wearing compression tights. Int J Sports Med. 2006;27:373&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16729379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook G, Burton L, Hoogenboom B. Pre-participation screening: the use of fundamental movements as an assessment of function - part 2. N Am J Sports Phys Ther. 2006;1:132&#x2013;139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2953359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21522225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies V, Thompson KG, Cooper SM. The effects of compression garments on recovery. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:1786&#x2013;1794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19675482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doan BK, Kwon YH, Newton RU, Shim J, Popper EM, Rogers RA, Bolt LR, Robertson M, Kraemer WJ. Evaluation of a lower-body compression garment. J Sports Sci. 2003;21:601&#x2013;610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12875311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drouin JM, Valovich-mcLeod TC, Shultz SJ, Gansneder BM, Perrin DH. Reliability and validity of the Biodex System 3 Pro isokinetic dynamometer velocity, torque and position measurements. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2004;91:22&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14508689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilleard W, McConnell J, Parsons D. The effect of patellar taping on the onset of vastus medialis obliquus and vastus lateralis muscle activity in persons with patellofemoral pain. Phys Ther. 1998;78:25&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9442193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinrich KM, Patel PM, O&#x2019;Neal JL, Heinrich BS. High-intensity compared to moderate-intensity training for exercise initiation, enjoyment, adherence, and intentions: an intervention study. BMC Public Health. 2014;14:789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4129110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25086646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang CY, Hsieh TH, Lu SC, Su FC. Effect of the Kinesio tape to muscle activity and vertical jump performance in healthy inactive people. Biomed Eng Online. 2011;10:70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3174125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21831321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakeman JR, Byrne C, Eston RG. Lower limb compression garment improves recovery from exercise-induced muscle damage in young, active females. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;109:1137&#x2013;1144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20376479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowall MG, Kolk G, Nuber GW, Cassisi JE, Stern SH. Patellar taping in the treatment of patellofemoral pain. A prospective randomized study. Am J Sports Med. 1996;24:61&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8638755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Flanagan SD, Comstock BA, Fragala MS, Earp JE, Dunn-Lewis C, Ho JY, Thomas GA, Solomon-Hill G, Penwell ZR, Powell MD, Wolf MR, Volek JS, Denegar CR, Maresh CM. Effects of a whole body compression garment on markers of recovery after a heavy resistance workout in men and women. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:804&#x2013;814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20195085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamberts RP, Swart J, Capostagno B, Noakes TD, Lambert MI. Heart rate recovery as a guide to monitor fatigue and predict changes in performance parameters. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20:449&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19558377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leanderson J, Eriksson E, Nilsson C, Wykman A. Proprioception in classical ballet dancers. A prospective study of the influence of an ankle sprain on proprioception in the ankle joint. Am J Sports Med. 1996;24:370&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8734890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Su H, Du L, Li G, Lv Y, Liu X, Feng L, Yu L. Effects of compression garments on muscle strength and power recovery post-exercise: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Life (Basel) 2025;15:438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11944185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40141783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacRae BA, Cotter JD, Laing RM. Compression garments and exercise: garment considerations, physiology and performance. Sports Med. 2011;41:815&#x2013;843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21923201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathiowetz V, Weber K, Volland G, Kashman N. Reliability and validity of grip and pinch strength evaluations. J Hand Surg Am. 1984;9:222&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6715829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murawska-Cialowicz E, Wojna J, Zuwala-Jagiello J. Crossfit training changes brain-derived neurotrophic factor and irisin levels at rest, after Wingate and progressive tests, and improves aerobic capacity and body composition of young physically active men and women. J Physiol Pharmacol. 2015;66:811&#x2013;821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26769830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plisky PJ, Rauh MJ, Kaminski TW, Underwood FB. Star excursion balance test as a predictor of lower extremity injury in high school basketball players. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2006;36:911&#x2013;919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17193868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salimi Z, Ferguson-Pell MW. Investigating the test-retest reliability of Illinois Agility Test for wheelchair users. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0241412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7595385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33119654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith MM, Sommer AJ, Starkoff BE, Devor ST. Crossfit-based high-intensity power training improves maximal aerobic fitness and body composition. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27:3159&#x2013;3172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23439334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teques P, Calmeiro L, Silva C, Borrego C. Validation and adaptation of the Physical Activity Enjoyment Scale (PACES) in fitness group exercisers. J Sport Health Sci. 2020;9:352&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7411091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32768128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>