<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41125254</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1423-0410</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>121</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Vox sanguinis</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Vox Sang</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A scoping review of grey zone use for transfusion-transmitted infection screening among blood donors.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>102</StartPage><EndPage>113</EndPage><MedlinePgn>102-113</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/vox.70137</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Screening for transfusion-transmitted infections (TTIs) among blood donors is done using qualitative screening assays. Screening values that are close to cut-off values lie in the uncertainty zone, often denoted as the grey zone (GZ). This scoping review evaluated studies that have assessed the GZ reactivity by supplementary tests and its consequences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Studies evaluating GZ or indeterminate or inconclusive results for TTI screening among blood donors were searched using PubMed, Scopus and Google Scholar databases. Full text for the included articles was reviewed and analysed for study characteristics, TTI screening and GZ reactivity. This included GZ range, repeat or confirmatory testing, follow-up of such donors, effect on donor deferral and collected blood units.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 16 studies were included. GZ was evaluated for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B virus (HBV), hepatitis C virus (HCV), syphilis, Chagas disease and human T-lymphotropic virus (HTLV). GZ values ranged from 0.5 to 1.2 times sample to cut-off (S/CO) values in different studies. The protocol for repeat/confirmatory testing was also heterogeneous. During repeat testing, many donors were found to be reactive or repeat GZ reactive. In confirmatory assays, the majority were negative, but many were positive or indeterminate. The protocol for donor follow-up and deferral protocols also varied significantly among different centres.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">GZ evaluation showed a small yet significant risk of TTI from samples identified within the GZ range. There is further need for follow-up studies to establish TTI risk from repeat reactive or indeterminate samples, which will help in establishing uniform protocols for GZ samples.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 International Society of Blood Transfusion.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaurasia</LastName><ForeName>Rahul</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9228-3594</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Transfusion Medicine, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sil</LastName><ForeName>Suhasini</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Transfusion Medicine, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khiamniungan</LastName><ForeName>Chanchi</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Transfusion Medicine, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patidar</LastName><ForeName>Gopal Kumar</ForeName><Initials>GK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9681-3898</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Transfusion Medicine, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pandey</LastName><ForeName>Hem Chandra</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Transfusion Medicine, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000098583">Scoping Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Vox Sang</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0413606</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0042-9007</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001782" MajorTopicYN="Y">Blood Donors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065227" MajorTopicYN="Y">Transfusion Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086982" MajorTopicYN="Y">Blood-Borne Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D046148" MajorTopicYN="Y">Donor Selection</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008403" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mass Screening</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood donors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">donor deferral</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">grey zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transfusion&#x2010;transmitted infection</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41125254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/vox.70137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>He J, Parker S. Chapter 2.7 &#x2013; qualitative immunoassay&#x2014;features and design. In: Wild D, editor. The immunoassay handbook. Fourth ed. Oxford: Elsevier; 2013. p. 139&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiely P, Hoad VC, Wood EM. False positive viral marker results in blood donors and their unintended consequences. Vox Sang. 2018;113:530&#x2013;539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleinman S, Wang B, Wu Y, Glynn SA, Williams A, Nass C, et al. The donor notification process from the donor's perspective. Transfusion. 2004;44:658&#x2013;666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tynell E, Norda R, Ekermo B, Sanner M, Andersson S, Bj&#xf6;rkman A. False&#x2010;reactive microbiologic screening test results in Swedish blood donors&#x2010;how big is the problem? a survey among blood centers and deferred donors. Transfusion. 2007;47:80&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busch MP, Watanabe KK, Smith JW, Hermansen SW, Thomson RA. False&#x2010;negative testing errors in routine viral marker screening of blood donors. For the Retrovirus Epidemiology Donor Study. Transfusion. 2000;40:585&#x2013;589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acar A, Kemahli S, Altunay H, Kosan E, Oncul O, Gorenek L, et al. HBV, HCV and HIV seroprevalence among blood donors in Istanbul, Turkey: how effective are the changes in the national blood transfusion policies? Braz J Infect Dis. 2010;14:41&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabino EC, Salles NA, de Almeida&#x2010;Neto C, Barreto AM, Basques F, Barros EA, et al. Performance of parallel screening of Brazilian blood donors with two human immunodeficiency virus immunoassays: implications for sequential immunoassay testing algorithms in other countries. Transfusion. 2011;51:175&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malhotra S, Marwaha N, Saluja K. Seroprevalence of human immunodeficiency virus in north Indian blood donors using third and fourth generation enzyme linked immunosorbent assay. Asian J Transfus Sci. 2013;7:125&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommese L, Iannone C, Cacciatore F, De Iorio G, Napoli C. Comparison between screening and confirmatory serological assays in blood donors in a region of South Italy. J Clin Lab Anal. 2014;28:198&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng P, Liu J, Wang J, Dong X, Li J, Bi X, et al. Parallel enzyme&#x2010;linked immunosorbent assay screening for human immunodeficiency virus among blood donors in five Chinese blood centres: a retrospective analysis. Transfus Med. 2015;25:259&#x2013;264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solanki A, Singh A, Chaudhary R. Impact of grey zone sample testing by enzyme&#x2010;linked immunosorbent assay in enhancing blood safety: experience at a tertiary care hospital in North India. Asian J Transfus Sci. 2016;10:71&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moya&#x2010;Salazar J, Ubidia&#x2010;Incio R, Incio&#x2010;Grande M, Blejer JL, Gonzalez CA. Seroprevalence, cost per donation and reduction in blood supply due to positive and indeterminate results for infectious markers in a blood bank in Lima, Peru. Rev Bras Hematol Hemoter. 2017;39:102&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anitha M, Babu K, Praveen M, Sriranjitha T. Effect of grey zone sample testing of transfusion transmissible infectious diseases on safety of blood&#x2010;experience of a tertiary care referral teaching hospital blood bank from South India. Int J Res Med Sci. 2017;5:5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh OG, Devi KM, Surjit K. Reassessment of initial grey zone samples in enzyme&#x2010;linked immunosorbant assay by repeat test for blood donor screening of HIV, HBV and HCV at a teaching hospital, in the north eastern India. IOSR&#x2010;JDMS. 2019;18:21&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M&#x2010;Y, Devare S, Liu J&#x2010;F, Lv X&#x2010;T, Yin P, Guo N, et al. Comparison of three immunoassay systems for screening of HIV infection in blood donation in China. Ann Blood. 2019;4:13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad CR, Sahoo B. Effect of grey zone sample testing of transfusion transmissible infectious diseases by enzyme linked immunosorbent assay in blood safety &#x2013; experience at a tertiary care hospital blood bank from Western Odisha. Sch J App Med Sci. 2018;6:4701&#x2013;4703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhardwaj G, Tiwari AK, Arora D, Aggarwal G, Pabbi S, Setya D. Utility of grey zone testing strategy in transfusion transmissible infection testing in blood bank is of limited value! Indian J Pathol Microbiol. 2020;63:255&#x2013;257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dogra A, Gosai D, Jasani J. Effect of grey zone samples testing by enzyme immunoassay and its impact on enhancing blood safety: experience from tertiary care hospital based blood Bank in Central Gujarat. Indian J Forensic Med Toxicol. 2021;15:93&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel K, Ranapurwala M, Patel A, Mansuri N. Utility of grey zone sample testing strategy for transfusion transmittable infections to improve blood safety of a tertiary care center. Int J Clin Diagn Pathol. 2021;4:103&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandukuri M, Vujhini SK, Bonagiri S, Bogi MK. Gray zone sample testing in enhancing blood safety. Global J Transfus Med. 2021;6:72&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz LJN, Amaral CEM. Correlation of serological and molecular markers in the screening for hepatitis B virus in blood bank in northern Brazil. Hematol Transfus Cell Ther. 2023;45:428&#x2013;434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson K, Atkinson KM, Fergusson DA, Brown A, Forster A, Murphy MSQ, et al. Problems with precaution: the transfusion medicine experience. J Risk Res. 2019;22:137&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira P, Westgard J, Encarna&#xe7;&#xe3;o P, Seghatchian J, de Sousa G. The role of uncertainty in results of screening immunoassays in blood establishments. Transfus Apher Sci. 2015;52:252&#x2013;255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira P, Westgard JO, Encarna&#xe7;&#xe3;o P, Seghatchian J. Analytical model for calculating indeterminate results interval of screening tests, the effect on seroconversion window period: a brief evaluation of the impact of uncertain results on the blood establishment budget. Transfus Apher Sci. 2014;51:126&#x2013;131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira P. Computation of the &#x201c;gray zone&#x201d; based on experimental data and its effect on the trueness in HIV results in the blood, cells and tissues banks. Mathews J Case Rep. 2017;2:1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>