<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41572995</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2222-3959</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of ophthalmology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Ophthalmol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Chronic alcohol consumption on retinal microcirculation in healthy subjects: an optic coherence tomography angiography study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>326</StartPage><EndPage>332</EndPage><MedlinePgn>326-332</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.18240/ijo.2026.02.15</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the effects of chronic alcohol consumption on retinal microcirculation by comparing different alcohol-consuming groups using optical coherence tomography (OCT) and OCT angiography (OCTA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This observational clinical study utilized a cross-sectional and prospective design, focusing on chronic alcohol consumers alongside a non-consuming control group. OCT/OCTA imaging parameters including central retinal subfield thickness (CST), subfoveal choroidal thickness (SCT), foveal avascular zone (FAZ) and vessel density (VD) in the superficial and deep capillary plexuses in both the macular and optic disc (OD) regions were recorded. Data were analyzed using SPSS 15.0; descriptive statistics were reported, group comparisons were performed with Chi-square, Kruskal-Wallis, and Bonferroni-corrected Mann-Whitney <i>U</i> tests, and relationships were assessed using Spearman correlation, with statistical significance set at <i>P</i>&lt;0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 160 eyes of 160 participants (110 females and 50 males with mean age 38.7&#xb1;9.9y) who don't smoke were divided into five groups: never, occasional, monthly, weekly and daily drinkers. The mean CST was 216.6&#xb1;14.2 &#xb5;m and the mean SCT was 358.9&#xb1;84.5 &#xb5;m. There was no statistically significantly difference in CST and SCT among the groups (<i>P</i>=0.890, 0.799). Foveal superficial capillary plexuses (SCPs) VD was higher in monthly drinkers compared to occasional drinkers (<i>P</i>=0.015). Foveal VD in deep capillary plexus was also higher in monthly drinkers than in never and occasional drinkers (<i>P</i>=0.004, 0.006). Nasal SCPs VD at the OD was higher in monthly drinkers compared to never drinkers (<i>P</i>=0.005). There was no significant difference FAZ area among the groups (<i>P</i>=0.071).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Both superficial and deep microvascular structures in the inferior quadrants of macula are positively correlated with frequency of alcohol use. Also in our study results is that the monthly drinker group has uniquely higher VDs in both macula and OD. This leads us to consider moderate alcohol consumption may also have protective effects on retinal microcirculation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>International Journal of Ophthalmology Press.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yildiz</LastName><ForeName>Dilan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Prof. Dr. Cemil Tascioglu City Hospital, Istanbul 34384, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uzundede</LastName><ForeName>Tahsin</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Prof. Dr. Cemil Tascioglu City Hospital, Istanbul 34384, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cakir</LastName><ForeName>Akin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Prof. Dr. Cemil Tascioglu City Hospital, Istanbul 34384, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karatas</LastName><ForeName>Gamze</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Prof. Dr. Cemil Tascioglu City Hospital, Istanbul 34384, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coban</LastName><ForeName>Busra</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Viransehir Public Hospital, Sanliurfa 63700, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Ophthalmol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101553860</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2222-3959</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">alcohol consumption</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">foveal avascular zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">optical coherence tomography angiography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">retinal microcirculation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vessel density</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: Yildiz D, None; Uzundede T, None; Cakir A, None; Karatas G, None; Coban B, None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41572995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12820616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18240/ijo.2026.02.15</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijo-19-02-326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Manthey J, Shield KD, Rylett M, et al. Global alcohol exposure between 1990 and 2017 and forecasts until 2030: a modelling study. Lancet. 2019;393(10190):2493&#x2013;2502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31076174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armas Rojas NB, Lacey B, Simadibrata DM, et al. Alcohol consumption and cause-specific mortality in Cuba: prospective study of 120 623 adults. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;33:100692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7980059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33768200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Heide FCT, Eussen SJPM, Houben AJHM, et al. Alcohol consumption and microvascular dysfunction: a J-shaped association: the maastricht study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2023;22(1):67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10039613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36964536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang X, He G, Zeng Y, et al. Quantitative evaluation of choroidal and retinal microvasculature post-alcohol consumption: a pilot study. Microvasc Res. 2024;152:104629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37984565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S, Wu S, Feng H, et al. An optimized segmentation and quantification approach in microvascular imaging for OCTA-based neovascular regression monitoring. BMC Med Imaging. 2021;21(1):13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7825210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33482750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng F, Deng XF, Zhang Q, et al. Advances in swept-source optical coherence tomography and optical coherence tomography angiography. Adv Ophthalmol Pract Res. 2023;3(2):67&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10577875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37846376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray BC, Dziak JJ, Lanza ST. Age trends in alcohol use behavior patterns among U.S. adults ages 18-65. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2019;205:107689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6957076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31707270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoudinezhad G, Nishida T, Weinreb RN, et al. Associations of smoking and alcohol consumption with the development of open angle glaucoma: a retrospective cohort study. BMJ Open. 2023;13(10):e072163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10551939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37793935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leske MC, Warheit-Roberts L, Wu SY. Open-angle glaucoma and ocular hypertension: the Long Island Glaucoma Case-control Study. Ophthalmic Epidemiol. 1996;3(2):85&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8841060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Franco R, M&#xe9;ndez-Mar&#xed;n D, Garc&#xed;a-Roa M, et al. Central macular thickness in a healthy Mexican population using huvitz optical coherence tomography. Clin Ophthalmol. 2020;14:3931&#x2013;3940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7680185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33235432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najeeb S, Ganne P, Damagatla M, et al. Mapping the thickness of retinal layers using Spectralis spectral domain optical coherence tomography in Indian eyes. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2022;70(8):2990&#x2013;2997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9672761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35918959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashmani N, Hashmani S, Murad A, et al. Macular vascular density at the superficial capillary plexus using the optical coherence tomography angiography. Clin Ophthalmol. 2019;13:295&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6371924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30799915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhasmana D, Herbert L, Patel V, et al. The effect of acute ethanol consumption on the human retinal circulation: a study in diabetic and non-diabetic subjects. Eur J Ophthalmol. 1994;4(3):144&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7819729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luksch A, Resch H, Weigert G, et al. Acute effects of intravenously administered ethanol on retinal vessel diameters and flicker induced vasodilatation in healthy volunteers. Microvasc Res. 2009;78(2):224&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19523476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahlaee A, Samara WA, Hsu J, et al. In vivo assessment of macular vascular density in healthy human eyes using optical coherence tomography angiography. Am J Ophthalmol. 2016;165:39&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26921803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim CW, Cheng J, Tay ELT, et al. Optical coherence tomography angiography of the macula and optic nerve head: microvascular density and test-retest repeatability in normal subjects. BMC Ophthalmol. 2018;18(1):315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6288920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30526537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aboud SA, Hammouda LM, Saif MYS, et al. Effect of smoking on the macula and optic nerve integrity using optical coherence tomography angiography. Eur J Ophthalmol. 2022;32(1):436&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33567885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;ilo&#x11f;lu E, Unal F, Sukgen EA, et al. Evaluation of foveal avascular zone and capillary plexus in smokers using optical coherence tomography angiography. J Curr Ophthalmol. 2020;32(1):53&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7265278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32510014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafarizadeh A, Homaie M, Abdollahi M, et al. Time course study of optical coherence tomography angiography in patients with methanol induced optic neuropathy. BMC Ophthalmol. 2023;23(1):178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10126549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37098467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kojima S, Sugiyama T, Kojima M, et al. Effect of the consumption of ethanol on the microcirculation of the human optic nerve head in the acute phase. Jpn J Ophthalmol. 2000;44(3):318&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10913661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;ahin T, Karadere ME, Y&#x131;ld&#x131;z V, et al. Evaluation of the retinal nerve fiber layer with optic coherence tomography in patients with alcohol use disorder. J Fr Ophtalmol. 2021;44(5):665&#x2013;669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33840492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krittanawong C, Isath A, Rosenson RS, et al. Alcohol consumption and cardiovascular health. Am J Med. 2022;135(10):1213&#x2013;1230.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9529807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35580715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson SC, Burgess S, Mason AM, et al. Alcohol consumption and cardiovascular disease: a mendelian randomization study. Circ Genom Precis Med. 2020;13(3):e002814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7299220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32367730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millwood IY, Walters RG, Mei XW, et al. Conventional and genetic evidence on alcohol and vascular disease aetiology: a prospective study of 500000 men and women in China. Lancet. 2019;393(10183):1831&#x2013;1842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6497989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30955975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiva-Blanch G, Arranz S, Lamuela-Raventos RM, et al. Effects of wine, alcohol and polyphenols on cardiovascular disease risk factors: evidences from human studies. Alcohol Alcohol. 2013;48(3):270&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23408240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hindy G, Engstr&#xf6;m G, Larsson SC, et al. Role of blood lipids in the development of ischemic stroke and its subtypes: a mendelian randomization study. Stroke. 2018;49(4):820&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5895121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29535274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant A, Roy-Gagnon MH, Bastasic J, et al. Alcohol consumption, genetic risk, and intraocular pressure and glaucoma: the Canadian longitudinal study on aging. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2023;64(10):3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10327959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37405759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health (US); Biological Sciences Curriculum Study. NIH Curriculum Supplement Series. Bethesda (MD): National Institutes of Health (US); 2007.  Information about Alcohol.  https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK20360/.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>