<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41913829</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of Outdated Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute (CLSI) Breakpoint Implementation on Antimicrobial Susceptibility Interpretation: A Retrospective Analytical Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e104338</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e104338</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e104338</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.104338</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Introduction Using outdated breakpoints can lead to a considerable overestimation of susceptibility, which can result in ineffective treatments; therefore, it's crucial to adopt current standards to improve patient outcomes. Methods This retrospective analytical&#xa0;study analyzed 9,279 bacterial isolates. Reporting errors in antimicrobial susceptibility testing (AST) by the Kirby-Bauer disk diffusion method&#xa0;due to the use of outdated breakpoints was assessed by comparing the revised cutoff breakpoints of specific antibiotics with previous Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute (CLSI) guidelines. Chi-square testing and McNemar's test were used to evaluate paired interpretive shifts between the older and updated CLSI breakpoints. Results Among <i>Enterobacterales</i>, analysis of 2,262 aminoglycoside zone diameters revealed significant misclassification when outdated CLSI breakpoints were applied. Gentamicin also showed a significant shift in susceptibility distribution (&#x3c7;&#xb2; = 95.27, p &lt; 0.0001), with paired analysis confirming correction of susceptible isolates to the intermediate category using updated breakpoints (McNemar &#x3c7;&#xb2; = 36.0, p &lt; 0.0001). Amikacin demonstrated a borderline overall shift (&#x3c7;&#xb2; = 6.00, p = 0.0499) but substantial paired misclassification (McNemar &#x3c7;&#xb2; = 36.0, p &lt; 0.0001). In&#xa0;<i>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</i>, piperacillin-tazobactam (&#x3c7;&#xb2; = 6.62, p = 0.0366) and tobramycin (&#x3c7;&#xb2; = 77.94, p &lt; 0.0001) demonstrated a significant redistribution of susceptibility categories, with older criteria overestimating susceptibility. Among&#xa0;<i>Staphylococcus aureus</i>, implementation of revised 34th-edition CLSI linezolid breakpoints introduced an intermediate category and resulted in significant reclassification from susceptible to intermediate (&#x3c7;&#xb2; = 17.45, p = 0.00016; McNemar &#x3c7;&#xb2; = 17.0, p &lt; 0.0001). Conclusion Unregulated and delayed implementation of updated CLSI breakpoints results in significant misclassification of antimicrobial susceptibility, leading to overestimation of susceptibility and masking emerging resistance. Standardized and timely adoption of revised breakpoints, along with supportive laboratory systems, is essential to ensure accurate susceptibility interpretation, effective antimicrobial stewardship, and reliable antimicrobial resistance surveillance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Goyal et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goyal</LastName><ForeName>Nisha</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Microbiology, University College of Medical Sciences, Delhi, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gangar</LastName><ForeName>Seema</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Microbiology, Maharishi Markandeshwar Institute of Medical Sciences &amp; Research, Mullana, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramakrishnan</LastName><ForeName>Bhavya</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Microbiology, University College of Medical Sciences, Delhi, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goma</LastName><ForeName>Monika</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Microbiology, University College of Medical Sciences, Delhi, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sj</LastName><ForeName>Gayathri</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Microbiology, University College of Medical Sciences, Delhi, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Das</LastName><ForeName>Shukla</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Microbiology, University College of Medical Sciences, Delhi, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amr</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">breakpoints</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clsi</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance underreporting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">revised ast cutoff</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">update guidelines</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve human participants or tissue. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41913829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13033102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.104338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Time to switch from CLSI to EUCAST? A Southeast Asian perspective. Cusack TP, Ashley EA, Ling CL, Roberts T, Turner P, Wangrangsimakul T, Dance DA. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmi.2019.03.016. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2019;25:782&#x2013;785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6587905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30922928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wayne PA. USA: Clinical and Laporatory Standards Institute; 2023. Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute (CLSI). Performance Standards for Antimicrobial Susceptibility Testing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The European Committee on Antimicrobial Susceptibility Testing. Breakpoint tables for interpretation of MICs and zone diameters. Version 13.0,2023.  [
Dec;
2024 
]. 2023. http://www.eucast.org http://www.eucast.org</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Implementation of the World Health Organization global antimicrobial resistance surveillance system in Uganda, 2015-2020: mixed-methods study using national surveillance data. Nabadda S, Kakooza F, Kiggundu R, et al. JMIR Public Health Surveill. 2021;7:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8569544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34673531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Setting interpretive breakpoints for antimicrobial susceptibility testing using disk diffusion. Kronvall G, Giske CG, Kahlmeter G. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2011.04.006. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2011;38:281&#x2013;290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21640560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Establishing antimicrobial resistance surveillance &amp; research network in India: journey so far. Walia K, Madhumathi J, Veeraraghavan B, et al. Indian J Med Res. 2019;149:164&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6563732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31219080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Understanding and addressing CLSI breakpoint revisions: a primer for clinical laboratories. Humphries RM, Abbott AN, Hindler JA. https://doi.org/10.1128/jcm.00203-19 J Clin Microbiol. 2019;57</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6535595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30971460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aminoglycosides: an overview. Krause KM, Serio AW, Kane TR, Connolly LE. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2016;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4888811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27252397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparing clinical outcomes of piperacillin-tazobactam administration and dosage strategies in critically ill adult patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Fawaz S, Barton S, Nabhani-Gebara S. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12879-020-05149-6. BMC Infect Dis. 2020;20:430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7305614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32563242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Time above the MIC of piperacillin-tazobactam as a predictor of outcome in Pseudomonas aeruginosa bacteremia. Tannous E, Lipman S, Tonna A, Hector E, Hussein Z, Stein M, Reisfeld S. https://doi.org/10.1128/aac.02571-19 Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2020;64</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7526819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32482679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The oxazolidinone linezolid inhibits initiation of protein synthesis in bacteria. Swaney SM, Aoki H, Ganoza MC, Shinabarger DL. https://doi.org/10.1128/aac.42.12.3251 . Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 1998;42:3251&#x2013;3255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC106030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9835522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The pharmacologic and bacteriologic properties of oxazolidinones, a new class of synthetic antimicrobials. Dresser LD, Rybak MJ.  https://doi.org/10.1002/j.1875-9114.1998.tb03109.x. Pharmacotherapy. 1998;18:456&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9620097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedaquiline-pretomanid-linezolid regimens for drug-resistant tuberculosis. Conradie F, Bagdasaryan TR, Borisov S, et al. N Engl J Med. 2022;387:810&#x2013;823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9490302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36053506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antibiotic consumption in India: geographical variations and temporal changes between 2011 and 2019. Koya SF, Ganesh S, Selvaraj S, Wirtz VJ, Galea S, Rockers PC. https://doi.org/10.1093/jacamr/dlac112 JAC Antimicrob Resist. 2022;4:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9596537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36320447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drug utilization, rationality, and cost analysis of antimicrobial medicines in a tertiary care teaching hospital of Northern India: a prospective, observational study. Bimba HV, Roy V, Batta A, Daga MK. Indian J Pharmacol. 2020;52:179&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7446674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32874000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>What's new from the CLSI subcommittee on antimicrobial susceptibility testing M100. Abbey TC, Deak E. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinmicnews.2019.11.002 Clinical Microbiol Newslett. 2019;41:203&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stelling J, O'Brien TF. Molecular Microbiology: Diagnostic Principles and Practice. 2016. WHONET: software for surveillance of infecting microbes and their resistance to antimicrobial agents.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overview of changes to the clinical and laboratory standards institute performance standards for antimicrobial susceptibility testing, M100. Humphries R, Bobenchik AM, Hindler JA, Schuetz AN. https://doi.org/10.1128/jcm.00213-21 J Clin Microbiol. 2021;59:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8601225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34550809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of antibiotic susceptibility test results: how guilty a laboratory could be? Nassar MS, Hazzah WA, Bakr WM. https://doi.org/10.1186/s42506-018-0006-1. J Egypt Public Health Assoc. 2019;94:4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6329728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30686832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wayne PA. 2024. Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute. Performance Standards for Antimicrobial Susceptibility Testing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wayne PA. 2022. Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute. Performance Standards for Antimicrobial Susceptibility Testing. 2022CLSI M100-S32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of ciprofloxacin and levofloxacin disk diffusion and Etest using the 2019 Enterobacteriaceae CLSI breakpoints. Humphries RM, Hindler JA, Shaffer K, Campeau SA. https://doi.org/10.1128/jcm.01797-18 J Clin Microbiol. 2019;57</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6425192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30567744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breakpoint beware: reliance on historical breakpoints for Enterobacteriaceae leads to discrepancies in interpretation of susceptibility testing for carbapenems and cephalosporins and gaps in detection of carbapenem-resistant organisms. Yarbrough ML, Wallace MA, Potter RF, D'Souza AW, Dantas G, Burnham CD. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10096-019-03711-y. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2020;39:187&#x2013;195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31679102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of the recent clinical and laboratory standards institute breakpoint changes on the antimicrobial spectrum of aminoglycosides and the activity of plazomicin against multidrug-resistant and carbapenem-resistant Enterobacterales from United States Medical Centers. Sader HS, Mendes RE, Kimbrough JH, Kantro V, Castanheira M. https://doi.org/10.1093/ofid/ofad058 Open Forum Infect Dis. 2023;10:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9969732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36861086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2813. Impact of a recent change in tobramycin breakpoints (CLSI) on the proportion of Pseudomonas aeruginosa clinical isolates that are multidrug-resistant: CANWARD, 2016 to 2021. Walkty A, Adam H, Baxter M, Lagace-Wiens P, Karlowsky J, Zhanel G. https://doi.org/10.1093/ofid/ofad500.2424 Open Forum Infect Dis. 2023;10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A-280 Impact of 2022 CLSI revised piperacillin/tazobactam clinical breakpoints on Enterobacterales isolates identified at a tertiary medical center in southern Taiwan. Kuo S. https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvad097.247 Clin Chem. 2023;69:97&#x2013;247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CLSI methods development and standardization working group best practices for evaluation of antimicrobial susceptibility tests. Humphries RM, Ambler J, Mitchell SL, et al.  https://doi.org/10.1128/jcm.01934-17 J Clin Microbiol. 2018;56</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5869819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29367292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>