<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41935286</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1475-2875</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Malaria journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Malar J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Malarial pneumonopathy in Malawian children with cerebral malaria.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12936-026-05882-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Respiratory distress is a well-recognized clinical presentation in pediatric malaria and is associated with increased mortality. Traditionally described as "acidotic breathing," this phenomenon has been attributed to compensatory hyperventilation secondary to metabolic acidosis. However, this explanation may not adequately capture causative mechanisms. We sought to quantify the prevalence of respiratory distress in children with cerebral malaria (CM) and to evaluate underlying pathophysiologic contributors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this prospective, observational study, 97 Malawian children aged 6&#xa0;months to 12&#xa0;years meeting the World Health Organization (WHO) criteria for CM were enrolled. Vitals were recorded, including oxygen saturation and oxygen supplementation when present. Clinical signs of respiratory distress were documented on admission using WHO definitions. Admission lactate levels and blood gas analyses were obtained to characterize acid-base status. A standardized 12-zone point-of-care lung ultrasound was performed to assess pulmonary aeration patterns.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-seven participants (28%) met WHO-defined criteria for respiratory distress. Despite elevated lactate levels (median 7.0&#xa0;mmol/L [4.2, 13.3]), median pH remained 7.41. Metabolic acidosis was the sole disturbance in only 12 children (12%). A primary respiratory alkalosis was observed in 33% of the cohort, and lung ultrasound revealed subcentimeter consolidations in 88% of all participants. Larger consolidations (&#x2265;&#x2009;1&#xa0;cm) consistent with pneumonia were less common. Absence of diffuse edema on lung ultrasound made cardiac or renal failure an unlikely primary cause of respiratory distress. No child met criteria for pediatric acute respiratory distress syndrome. Respiratory distress was not associated with increased mortality in this cohort.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings challenge the longstanding attribution of respiratory distress in CM to metabolic acidosis alone. The frequent occurrence of a primary respiratory alkalosis, together with the near-universal presence of subpleural consolidations on lung ultrasound, suggests that alternative mechanisms-including pulmonary microvascular obstruction, interstitial inflammation, and dysregulation of the central respiratory drive-are likely contributing to the observed respiratory patterns. We propose the terminology malarial pneumonopathy to describe this broader spectrum of lung involvement. Reframing the traditional concept of "acidotic breathing" as malarial pneumonopathy may better reflect the spectrum of respiratory dysfunction in CM, improve diagnostic accuracy, and guide future research, clinical guidelines, and interventions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wynkoop</LastName><ForeName>Hunter J</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Critical Care Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, Nationwide Children's Hospital, The Ohio State University, 700 Children's Drive, Columbus, OH, 43205, USA. hunter.wynkoop@nationwidechildrens.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lintner-Rivera</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Critical Care Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, Ryan White Center for Pediatric Infectious Diseases and Global Health, Indiana University School of Medicine, Indianapolis, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Terrie</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Osteopathic Medical Specialties, College of Osteopathic Medicine, Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Blantyre Malaria Project, Kamuzu University of Health Sciences, Blantyre, Malawi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seydel</LastName><ForeName>Karl B</ForeName><Initials>KB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Osteopathic Medical Specialties, College of Osteopathic Medicine, Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Blantyre Malaria Project, Kamuzu University of Health Sciences, Blantyre, Malawi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pensulo</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Blantyre Malaria Project, Kamuzu University of Health Sciences, Blantyre, Malawi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayamie</LastName><ForeName>Mubarack</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics and Child Health, Kamuzu University of Health Sciences, Blantyre, Malawi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chetcuti</LastName><ForeName>Karen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Radiology, Department of Paediatrics and Child Health, Kamuzu University of Health Sciences, Blantyre, Malawi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vidal</LastName><ForeName>Lorenna L Moreira</ForeName><Initials>LLM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, Perelman School of Medicine at the University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Brien</LastName><ForeName>Nicole F</ForeName><Initials>NF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Critical Care Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, Nationwide Children's Hospital, The Ohio State University, 700 Children's Drive, Columbus, OH, 43205, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>5U01AI126610-02</GrantID><Agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Malar J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101139802</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1475-2875</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebral malaria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory alkalosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory distress</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This was an ancillary study to Treating Brain Swelling in Pediatric Cerebral Malaria, which was approved by the IRB at Michigan State University (IRB18-01261) and the University of Malawi College of Medicine Research Ethics Committee (COMREC) (P.09/16/2024). Following the conclusion of the clinical trial, approval was received from the IRB at Nationwide Children&#x2019;s Hospital (Study #00003593) and again by COMREC (P.07/23-0169). Competing of Interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41935286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12936-026-05882-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12936-026-05882-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Organization Wh. World Malaria Report 2023. Geneva: World Health Organization. 2023(2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsh K, Forster D, Waruiru C, Mwangi I, Winstanley M, Marsh V, et al. Indicators of life-threatening malaria In African children. N Engl J Med. 1995;332(21):1399&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jallow M, Casals-Pascual C, Ackerman H, Walther B, Walther M, Pinder M, et al. Clinical features of severe malaria associated with death: a 13-year observational study in the Gambia. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(9):E45645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitran C, Opoka R, Conroy A, Namasopo S, Kain K, Hawkes M. Pediatric malaria with respiratory distress: prognostic significance of point-of-care lactate. Microorganisms. 2023;11(4):923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awandare GA, Goka B, Boeuf P, Tetteh JKA, Kurtzhals JAL, Behr C, et al. Increased levels of inflammatory mediators in children with severe plasmodium falciparum malaria with respiratory distress. J Infect Dis. 2006;194(10):1438&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lackritz E, Campbell C, Ruebush T, Hightower A, Wakube W, Were J. Effect of blood transfusion on survival among children in a Kenyan hospital. Lancet. 1992;340(8818):524&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bojang K, Van Hensbroek M, Palmer A, Banya W, Jaffar S, Greenwood B. Predictors of mortality in Gambian children with severe malaria anaemia. Ann Trop Paediatr. 1997;17(4):355&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>English M, Sauerwein R, Waruiru C, Mosobo M, Obiero J, Lowe B, et al. Acidosis in severe childhood malaria. Qjm Monthly J Assoc Phys. 1997;90(4):263&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization W. Who guidelines for malaria. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malaria Ws. Tropical medicine &amp; international health. 19. Tm &amp; Ih. 2014:7&#x2013;131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anstey N, Jacups S, Cain T, Pearson T, Ziesing P, Fisher D, et al. Pulmonary manifestations of uncomplicated falciparum and vivax malaria: cough, small airways obstruction, impaired gas transfer, and increased pulmonary phagocytic activity. J Infect Dis. 2002;185(9):1326&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milner D Jr, Factor R, Whitten R, Ra C, Kamiza S, Pinkus G, et al. Pulmonary pathology in pediatric cerebral malaria. Human Pathol. 2013;44(12):2719&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor W, Hanson J, Turner G, White N, Dondorp A. Respiratory manifestations of malaria. Chest. 2012;142(2):492&#x2013;505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dzeing-Ella A, Pc NO, Tchoua R, Planche T, Mboza B, Mbounja M, et al. Severe falciparum malaria in Gabonese children: clinical and laboratory features. Malar J. 2005;4:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mockenhaupt FP, Ehrhardt S, Burkhardt J, Bosomtwe SY, Laryea S, Anemana S, et al. Manifestation and outcome of severe malaria in children in Northern Ghana. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2004;71(2):167&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dondorp AM, Fanello CI, Hendriksen IC, Gomes E, Seni A, Chhaganlal KD, et al. Artesunate versus quinine in the treatment of severe falciparum malaria in African children (Aquamat): an open-label, Randomised Trial. Lancet. 2010;376(9753):1647&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vercesi V, Pisani L, Van Tongeren P, Lagrand W, Leopold S, Huson M, et al. External confirmation and exploration of the Kigali modification for diagnosing moderate or severe Ards. Intens Care Med. 2018;44(4):523&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khemani R, Thomas N, Venkatachalam V, Scimeme J, Berutti T, Schneider J, et al. Comparison of Spo2 to Pao2 based markers of lung disease severity for children with acute lung injury. Crit Care Med. 2012;40(4):1309&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albert M, Dell R, Winters R. Quantitative displacement of acid-base equilibrium in metabolic acidosis. Ann Intern Med. 1967;66(2):312&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mojoli F, Bouhemad B, Mongodi S, Lichtenstein D. Lung ultrasound for critically ill patients. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2019;199(6):701&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seydel K, Kampondeni S, Valim C, Potchen M, Milner D, Muwalo F, et al. Brain swelling and death in children with cerebral malaria. N Engl J Med. 2015;372(12):1126&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Severe falciparum malaria. World Health Organization, communicable diseases cluster. Trans Royal Soc Trop Med Hygiene. 2000;94(Suppl. 1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adrogu&#xe9; H, Madias N. Secondary responses to altered acid-base status: The rules of engagement. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2010;21(6):920&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo De Moraes A, Surani S. Effects of diabetic ketoacidosis in the respiratory system. World J Diabetes. 2019;10(1):16&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Seidlein L, Olaosebikan R, Hendriksen I, Lee S, Adedoyin O, Agbenyega T, et al. Predicting the clinical outcome of severe falciparum malaria in African children: findings from a large randomized trial. Clin Infect Dis. 2012;54(8):1080&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adrogu&#xe9; HJ, Madias Ne. Respiratory acidosis, respiratory alkalosis, and mixed disorders. Compr Clin Nephrol E-Book. 2014;169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer B, Clegg D. Respiratory acidosis and respiratory alkalosis: Core curriculum 2023. Am J Kidney Dis. 2023;82(3):347&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madan A. Correlation between the levels of Spo(2) and Pao(2). Lung India. 2017;34(3):307&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khemani R, Patel N, Bart R 3rd, Newth C. Comparison of the pulse oximetric saturation/fraction of inspired oxygen ratio and the Pao2/fraction of inspired oxygen ratio in children. Chest. 2009;135(3):662&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conroy Al, Datta D, Opoka Ro, Batte A, Bangirana P, Gopinadhan A, Et al. cerebrospinal fluid biomarkers provide evidence for kidney-brain axis involvement in cerebral malaria pathogenesis. Frontiers Human Neurosci. 2023;17:2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conroy A, Opoka R, Bangirana P, Idro R, Ssenkusu J, Datta D, et al. Acute Kidney Injury is associated with impaired cognition and Chronic Kidney Disease in a prospective cohort of children with Severe Malaria. BMC Med. 2019;17(1):98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wynkoop HJ, Bevan A, Galeano X, Raees M, Haque Mr, Taylor T, Et al. Multiple organ dysfunction syndrome in Malawian children with cerebral malaria. Am J Trop Med Hygiene. 2024:Tpmd240303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ewart S. Control of ventilation. In: Cunningham&#x2019;s textbook of veterinary physiology. Elsevier; 2020. p. 560&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paintal A. Mechanism of stimulation of type J pulmonary receptors. J Physiol. 1969;203(3):511&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paintal A, Damodaran V, Guz A. Mechanism of excitation of type J receptors. Acta Neurobiol Exp (Wars). 1973;33(1):15&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tembo D, Harawa V, Tran T, Afran L, Molyneux M, Taylor T, et al. The ability of Interleukin-10 to negate Haemozoin-related pro-inflammatory effects has the potential to restore impaired macrophage function associated with Malaria infection. Malar J. 2023;22(1):125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark I, Alleva L, Budd A, Cowden W. Understanding the role of inflammatory cytokines in malaria and related diseases. Travel Med Infect Dis. 2008;6(1&#x2013;2):67&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdman L, Finney C, Liles W, Kain K. Inflammatory pathways in malaria infection: TLRs share the stage with other components of innate immunity. Mol Biochem Parasitol. 2008;162(2):105&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carannante N, Scarica S, Disarno R, Langella G, Di Micco P, Fiorentino G. Lung damages of malaria: a differential diagnosis and treatment in emergency room of a rare case. Italian J Med. 2023;17(3).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray STJ, Fuller CE, Ahmadu A, Kafoteka E, Muiruri-Liomba A, Malenga A, et al. Aetiologies, neuroradiological features, and risk factors for mortality and long-term neurosequelae of febrile coma in Malawian children: a prospective cohort study. Lancet Glob Health. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gravel C, Neuman M, Monuteaux M, Neal J, Miller A, Bachur R. Significance of sonographic subcentimeter, subpleural consolidations in pediatric patients evaluated for pneumonia. J Pediatr. 2022;243:193-9.E2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereda M, Chavez M, Hooper-Miele C, Gilman R, Steinhoff M, Ellington L, et al. Lung ultrasound for the diagnosis of pneumonia in children: a meta-analysis. Pediatrics. 2015;135(4):714&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soldati G, Giannasi G, Smargiassi A, Inchingolo R, Demi L. Contrast-enhanced ultrasound in patients with COVID-19: Pneumonia, acute respiratory distress syndrome, or something else? J Ultrasound Med. 2020;39(12):2483&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusuf G, Wong A, Rao D, Tee A, Fang C, Sidhu P. The use of contrast-enhanced ultrasound in Covid-19 lung imaging. J Ultrasound. 2022;25(2):319&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zotzmann V, Lang C, Bamberg F, Bode C, Staudacher D. Are subpleural consolidations indicators for segmental pulmonary embolism in Covid-19? Intensive Care Med. 2020;46(6):1109&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinkman Je, Toro F, Sharma S. Physiology, respiratory drive. Statpearls [Internet]: Statpearls Publishing; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potchen M, Kampondeni S, Seydel K, Haacke E, Sinyangwe S, Mwenechanya M, et al. 1.5 tesla magnetic resonance imaging to investigate potential etiologies of brain swelling in pediatric cerebral malaria. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2018;98(2):497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mj P, Kampondeni S, Kb S, Gl B, Ca H, Wg B, et al. Acute brain Mri findings in 120 Malawian children with cerebral malaria: new insights into an ancient disease. Ajnr Am J Neuroradiol. 2012;33(9):1740&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khonsary S. Guyton and Hall: textbook of medical physiology. Surg Neurol Int. 2017. https://doi.org/10.4103/sni.sni.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>