<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41322042</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2325-9671</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Orthopaedic journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Orthop J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Immediate Weightbearing After Augmented Modified Brostr&#xf6;m Reconstruction: A Retrospective Review of an Accelerated Rehabilitation Protocol.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23259671251389196</StartPage><MedlinePgn>23259671251389196</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23259671251389196</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/23259671251389196</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">An anatomic modified Brostr&#xf6;m reconstruction has replaced traditional nonanatomic procedures as the standard of care for chronic lateral ankle instability. This technique typically involves repair of both the anterior talofibular ligament and the calcaneofibular ligament. However, this reconstruction is often limited by damage to native tissue and prolonged healing time, which restricts early weightbearing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="HYPOTHESIS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The suture tape-augmented Brostr&#xf6;m procedure would allow for early weightbearing without increasing the risk of early reconstruction failure, while allowing a satisfactory return to sport.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Case series; Level of evidence, 4.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A retrospective chart review was conducted on patients who underwent a suture tape-augmented Brostr&#xf6;m reconstruction between August 2020 and January 2023. All patients followed a standardized accelerated rehabilitation protocol that included immediate postoperative weightbearing as tolerated. Primary outcomes included the ability to perform a single-leg hop and heel rise at 6 weeks postoperatively. Secondary outcomes included visual analog scale (VAS) scores, postoperative complications (eg, deep vein thrombosis [DVT], infection, return to operative suite, or failure), patient satisfaction, and return to sport.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 133 patients were screened for inclusion in this retrospective review. A total of 119 patients met the inclusion criteria, with a mean follow-up duration of 16.7 &#xb1; 8.2 months (range, 6-52 months). A total of 27 patients had cartilage injuries requiring marrow stimulation; 20 of these were located in zone 6 of the talar dome. At 6 weeks postoperatively, 90% of patients were able to perform a single-leg heel raise and 81% could complete a single-leg hop. The mean VAS score at final follow-up (mean, 16.7 &#xb1; 8.2 months postoperatively) was 1.0 &#xb1; 1.9 (range, 0-8). At 1-year postoperative follow-up, 99% of patients reported satisfaction and 95% had returned to sport. Male patients were significantly more likely to complete the single-leg hop test at 6 weeks (<i>P</i> = .04). No instances of reconstruction failure, revision surgery, DVT, or postoperative infection were reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Suture tape-augmented modified Brostr&#xf6;m reconstruction enabled immediate postoperative weightbearing without evidence of reconstruction failure. Most patients achieved excellent functional outcomes by 6 weeks, with minimal complications, high satisfaction, and return to sport before 1 year.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martin</LastName><ForeName>Kevin D</ForeName><Initials>KD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anand</LastName><ForeName>Srihan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rust</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chinnasamy</LastName><ForeName>Harish</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Curatolo</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Orthop J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101620522</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2325-9671</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ankle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomechanics of ligament</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic lateral ankle instability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ligaments</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical therapy/rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>One or more of the authors has declared the following potential conflict of interest or source of funding: K.M. is a paid consultant for Arthrex, iWalk, Trition Inc, ConMed, and the United States Army. AOSSM checks author disclosures against the Open Payments Database (OPD). AOSSM has not conducted an independent investigation on the OPD and disclaims any liability or responsibility relating thereto.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41322042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12663060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671251389196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_23259671251389196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Coetzee JC, Ellington JK, Ronan JA, Stone RM. Functional results of open Brostr&#xf6;m ankle ligament repair augmented with a suture tape. Foot Ankle Int. 2018;39(3):304-310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29420055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirose K, Murakami G, Minowa T, Kura H, Yamashita T. Lateral ligament injury of the ankle and associated articular cartilage degeneration in the talocrural joint: anatomic study using elderly cadavers. J Orthop Sci. 2004;9(1):37-43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14767703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlson J, Eriksson B, Bergsten T, Rudholm O, Sward L. Comparison of two anatomic reconstructions for chronic lateral instability of the ankle joint. Am J Sports Med. 1997;25(1):48-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9006691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk KL, Campbell JT, Guyton GP, Parks BG, Schon LC. ATFL elongation after Brostrom procedure: a biomechanical investigation. Foot Ankle Int. 2008;29(11):1126-1130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19026207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulwin R, Watson TS, Rigby R, Coetzee JC, Vora A. Traditional modified Brostr&#xf6;m vs suture tape ligament augmentation. Foot Ankle Int. 2021;42(5):554-561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33491480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundeen GA, Diefenbach C, Moles LH, White LL, Barousse P. Immediate unrestricted weightbearing with simple stirrup brace following single anchor lateral ankle ligament stabilization. Foot Ankle Spec. 2022;15(5):456-463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33215526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luthfi A, Nakasa T, Ikuta Y, et al. Risk factors for the recurrence of instability after lateral ankle ligament repair. Foot Ankle Int. 2023;44(7):617-628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37162133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffulli N, Del Buono A, Maffulli GD, et al. Isolated anterior talofibular ligament Brostr&#xf6;m repair for chronic lateral ankle instability: 9-year follow-up. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41(4):858-864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23388673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin KD, Andres NN, Robinson WH. Suture tape augmented Brostr&#xf6;m procedure and early accelerated rehabilitation. Foot Ankle Int. 2021;42(2):145-150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33019806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valderrabano V, Hintermann B, Horisberger M, Fung TS. Ligamentous posttraumatic ankle osteoarthritis. Am J Sports Med. 2006;34(4):612-620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16303875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vopat ML, Tarakemeh A, Morris B, et al. Early versus delayed mobilization postoperative protocols for lateral ankle ligament repair: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Orthop J Sports Med. 2020;8(6):2325967120925256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7309402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32613020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldrop NE, 3rd, Wijdicks CA, Jansson KS, LaPrade RF, Clanton TO. Anatomic suture anchor versus the Brostr&#xf6;m technique for anterior talofibular ligament repair: a biomechanical comparison. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40(11):2590-2596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22962291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang AH, Su T, Jiang YF, et al. Arthroscopic modified Brostr&#xf6;m procedure achieved similar favorable short term outcomes to open procedure for chronic lateral ankle instability cases with generalized joint laxity. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(9):4043-4051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37162539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>