<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41496884</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2468-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of vascular surgery cases and innovative techniques</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Vasc Surg Cases Innov Tech</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fenestrated endovascular aortic repair for complex abdominal aortic aneurysms using in situ laser fenestrations.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>102054</StartPage><MedlinePgn>102054</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">102054</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jvscit.2025.102054</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In situ fenestration (ISF) is a technique for fenestrated endovascular aortic repair (FEVAR) that can be used for urgent repairs of abdominal aortic aneurysms (AAAs) when there is an inadequate infrarenal landing zone for use of a conventional aortic endograft. It involves deliberate endograft coverage of indispensable branch vessels with ISF of the endograft fabric followed by a bridging covered stent. The aim of this series was to review the indications, early clinical outcomes, and technical feasibility of ISF technique for FEVAR of complex AAAs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This single-center retrospective case series included all patients with complex aortic aneurysms involving visceral branch vessels requiring urgent repair who were selected for FEVAR using the ISF technique. Briefly, the minimum length of proximal landing zone was determined for each patient. The branch vessels in this segment were prestented as radiographic markers. A polyester-based endograft was fully deployed. Using a steerable sheath, fenestrations were created using a CVX-300 excimer laser and covered, balloon-expandable stents were used to restore perfusion to the target vessels.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">From February 2023 to December 2024, 12 patients underwent ISF-FEVAR with 33 intended target vessels. Technical success per Society for Vascular Surgery reporting standards was 91% (30/33). Perioperative complications included 30-day mortality (n = 2), failure to create a fenestration (n = 1), target vessel dissection (n = 2), transient acute kidney injury (n = 1), spinal cord ischemia (n = 1), and femoral artery pseudoaneurysm (n = 1). There were one type II (n = 1) and one type IIIb endoleak at 1 month, and three secondary interventions performed during the follow-up period. There was no aneurysm growth and one patient experienced sac shrinkage.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">ISF of aortic stent grafts is a feasible and useful technique for urgent FEVAR of complex AAAs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mattson</LastName><ForeName>Aslyn E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Vascular Surgery, Charles E. Schmidt College of Medicine, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Motta</LastName><ForeName>John C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Vascular Surgery, Boca Raton Regional Hospital at Baptist Health South Florida, Boca Raton, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Grandis</LastName><ForeName>Eileen</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Vascular Surgery, Boca Raton Regional Hospital at Baptist Health South Florida, Boca Raton, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>W Anthony</ForeName><Initials>WA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Vascular Surgery, Boca Raton Regional Hospital at Baptist Health South Florida, Boca Raton, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Vasc Surg Cases Innov Tech</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101701125</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2468-4287</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Abdominal aortic aneurysm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fenestrated endovascular aortic repair</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Laser fenestration</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41496884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12767861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jvscit.2025.102054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2468-4287(25)00336-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Varkevisser R.R.B., O'Donnell T.F.X., Swerdlow N.J., et al. Fenestrated endovascular aneurysm repair is associated with lower perioperative morbidity and mortality compared with open repair for complex abdominal aortic aneurysms. J Vasc Surg. 2019;69:1670&#x2013;1678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30553730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farber M.A., Matsumura J.S., Han S., et al. Early outcomes from the pivotal trial of a four-branch off-the shelf solution to treat complex abdominal and type IV thoracoabdominal aortic aneurysms. J Vasc Surg. 2024;80:1326&#x2013;1335.e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38904579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conrad M.F., Cambria R.P. Contemporary management of descending thoracic and thoracoabdominal aortic aneurysms: endovascular versus open. Circulation. 2008;117:841&#x2013;852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18268161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal G., Hamady M. Complex abdominal aortic aneurysms: a review of radiological and clinical assessment, endovascular interventions, and current evidence of management outcomes. BJR Open. 2024;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11392563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39267950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouveia E., Melo R., Fern&#xe1;ndez Prendes C., et al. Systematic review and meta-analysis of physician modified endografts for treatment of thoraco-abdominal and complex abdominal aortic aneurysms. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2022;64:188&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35483575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkins A.D., Atkins M.D. Branched and fenestrated aortic endovascular grafts. Methodist Debakey Cardiovasc J. 2023;19:15&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10000330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36910555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prapassaro T., Teraa M., Chinsakchai K., et al. Mid-term outcomes of chimney endovascular aortic aneurysm repair: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Vasc Surg. 2022;79:359&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34666145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doonan R.J., Girsowicz E., Dubois L., Gill H.L. A systematic review and meta-analysis of endovascular juxtarenal aortic aneurysm repair demonstrates lower perioperative mortality compared with open repair. J Vasc Surg. 2019;70:2054&#x2013;2064.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31327612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy E.H., Dimaio J.M., Dean W., Jessen M.E., Arko F.R. Endovascular repair of acute traumatic thoracic aortic transection with laser-assisted in-situ fenestration of a stent-graft covering the left subclavian artery. J Endovasc Ther. 2009;16:457&#x2013;463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19702349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redlinger R.E., Jr., Ahanchi S.S., Panneton J.M. In situ laser fenestration during emergent thoracic endovascular aortic repair is an effective method for left subclavian artery revascularization. J Vasc Surg. 2013;58:1171&#x2013;1177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23746832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Hou&#xe9;rou T., Fabre D., Alonso C.G., et al. In situ antegrade laser fenestrations during endovascular aortic repair. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2018;56:356&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30196815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyun A.J., Potter H.A., Magee G.A., et al. Comparative early results of in situ fenestrated endovascular aortic repair and other emergent complex endovascular aortic repair techniques for ruptured suprarenal and thoracoabdominal aortic aneurysms at a regional aortic center. J Vasc Surg. 2022;76:875&#x2013;883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35697311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oderich G.S., Forbes T.L., Chaer R., et al. Reporting standards for endovascular aortic repair of aneurysms involving the renal-mesenteric arteries. J Vasc Surg. 2021;73:4S&#x2013;52S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32615285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fillinger M.F., Greenberg R.K., McKinsey J.F., Chaikof E.L., Society for Vascular Surgery Ad Hoc Committee on TEVAR Reporting Standards Reporting standards for thoracic endovascular aortic repair (TEVAR) J Vasc Surg. 2010;52:1022&#x2013;1033.e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20888533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean A., Wanhainen A., Mani K., et al. In situ laser fenestrations of aortic endografts for emergent aortic disease. Ann Vasc Surg. 2023;93:329&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36646250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman P.F., Gupta J.D., Barleben A. Laser fenestration for complex aortic repair: versatile option in difficult anatomy, emergencies and bailouts. Ann Vasc Surg. 2025;111:39&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39427981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Hou&#xe9;rou T., &#xc1;lvarez-Marcos F., Gaudin A., et al. Midterm outcomes of antegrade in situ laser fenestration of polyester endografts for urgent treatment of aortic pathologies involving the visceral and renal arteries. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2023;65:720&#x2013;727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36731765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf3;nsson G.G., Zielinski A.H., Berczeli M., et al. In situ laser fenestration of visceral endografts (InLoVE): midterm outcomes from a multicentre study. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2025;69:715&#x2013;722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39746568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe9;n&#xe9;maud J., Fadel G., Touma J., et al. Initial results of antegrade laser fenestrations using image fusion guidance and company manufactured stent grafts in complex aortic aneurysm repair. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2021;62:204&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33994306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzur M., Magee G.A., Ziegler K.R., Weaver F.A., Rowe V.L., Han S.M. Caudally directed in situ fenestrated endografting for emergent thoracoabdominal aortic aneurysm repair. J Vasc Surg Cases Innov Tech. 2021;7:553&#x2013;557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8358128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34401624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shehab M., J&#xf3;nsson G.G., Kuzniar M., Mani K., Lindstr&#xf6;m D., Wanhainen A. A novel off-the-shelf single-fenestrated stent graft for emergent complex aortic aneurysm repair. J Vasc Surg Cases Innov Tech. 2023;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10700847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38078281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stern J.R., Tran K., Dossabhoy S.S., Sorondo S.M., Lee J.T. A fenestrated, double-barrel technique for proximal reintervention after open or endovascular abdominal aortic aneurysm repair. J Vasc Surg Cases Innov Tech. 2022;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9898739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36747609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touma J., Kobeiter H., Majewski M., Tacher V., Desgranges P. Triple in situ antegrade laser fenestration of aortic stent-graft extension using fusion imaging for urgent treatment of symptomatic abdominal aneurysm with type 1 endoleak. Cardiovasc Intervent Radiol. 2018;41:513&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29230497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z.W., Qiao Z.T., Li M.X., Bai H.L., Liu Y.F., Bai T. Antegrade in situ laser fenestration of aortic stent graft during endovascular aortic repair: a case report. World J Clin Cases. 2022;10:1401&#x2013;1409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8855181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35211576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastracci T.M., Greenberg R.K., Eagleton M.J., Hernandez A.V. Durability of branches in branched and fenestrated endografts. J Vasc Surg. 2013;57:926&#x2013;933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23433817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiBartolomeo A.D., Han S.M. Techniques of antegrade in situ laser fenestration for endovascular aortic repair of complex abdominal and thoracoabdominal aortic aneurysms. J Vasc Surg Cases Innov Tech. 2022;8:787&#x2013;793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9729918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36507085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pini R., Faggioli G., Gallitto E., et al. The different effect of branches and fenestrations on early and long-term visceral vessel patency in complex aortic endovascular repair. J Vasc Surg. 2020;71:1128&#x2013;1134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31635962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsilimparis N., Gouveia E Melo R., Tenorio E.R., et al. Multicenter study on physician-modified endografts for thoracoabdominal and complex abdominal aortic aneurysm repair. Circulation. 2024;150:1327&#x2013;1342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38989565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finnesgard E.J., Jones D.W., Beck A.W., et al. Trends and outcomes over time with fenestrated and branched endovascular aortic repair in the United States aortic research consortium. J Vasc Surg. 2025;81:1235&#x2013;1243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39914755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grima M.J., Wanhainen A., Lindstr&#xf6;m D. In situ laser fenestration technique: bench-testing of aortic endograft to guide clinical practice. J Endovasc Ther. 2024;31:126&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10773159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36000361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glorion M., Coscas R., McWilliams R.G., Javerliat I., Go&#xeb;au-Brissonniere O., Coggia M. A comprehensive review of in situ fenestration of aortic endografts. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2016;52:787&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27843111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Q., Zhou X., He Y., et al. Experimental analysis of in situ fenestration of endovascular stent-grafts: comparison between needle and laser puncture. Ann Vasc Surg. 2021;77:280&#x2013;287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34411679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayet J., Heim F., Coggia M., Chakfe N., Coscas R. An experimental study of laser in situ fenestration of current aortic endografts. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2018;56:68&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29706260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crawford S.A., Sanford R.M., Forbes T.L., Amon C.H., Doyle M.G. Clinical outcomes and material properties of in situ fenestration of endovascular stent grafts. J Vasc Surg. 2016;64:244&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27183859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayet J., Canonge J., Heim F., Coggia M., Chakf&#xe9; N., Coscas R. Mechanical comparison between fenestrated endograft and physician-made fenestrations. J Clin Med. 2023;12:4911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10420147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37568314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowdall J.F., Greenberg R.K., West K., et al. Separation of components in fenestrated and branched endovascular grafting--branch protection or a potentially new mode of failure? Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2008;36:2&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18440249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darvish C.J., Lagerman N.P., Virag O., et al. Development of a method to achieve antegrade in situ fenestration of endovascular stent grafts in abdominal aortic aneurysms. J Vasc Surg Cases Innov Tech. 2024;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11653130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39697799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>