<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41141794</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>41</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biological and Therapeutic Applications of Gallic Acid Produced by <i>Aspergillus terreus</i> PQ344456 Using Submerged Fermentation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>48488</StartPage><EndPage>48499</EndPage><MedlinePgn>48488-48499</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.5c05913</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In this research, <i>Aspergillus terreus</i> PQ344456 fungi was utilized to produce gallic acid through techniques, such as submerged fermentation, that showed a maximum production rate of 188.58 &#xb1; 0.27 mg/mL at 96 h. <i>Aspergillus terreus</i> PQ344456 isolates were identified through visualization of phenotypic and genotypic characteristics through procedures that involved the implementation of 18S rRNA sequencing and investigation of the most optimal fermentation conditions through testing the impact of tannic acid levels, pH, and temperature on production rate, in which their values tended to be found optimal at 1.5%, 5, and 30 &#xb0;C, respectively. Moreover, the 2,2-diphenyl-1-picrylhydrazyl (DPPH) assay was employed to assess gallic acid's antioxidant activity, displaying a half-maximal inhibitory concentration (IC<sub>50</sub>) value of 54.96 &#x3bc;g/mL. In addition, antibacterial effectiveness was evaluated against various pathogenic strains. The minimum inhibitory concentration (MIC) value appeared to range from 0.0625 to 8 mg/mL and inhibition zone diameters from 29 &#xb1; 3.71 mm to 41 &#xb1; 1.00 mm. Antifungal activity was also assessed, with inhibition zones ranging from 12 &#xb1; 3.21 mm and MIC values from 0.125 to 8 mg/mL. Summarizing the research findings, <i>Aspergillus terreus</i> PQ344456 showed efficacy when used to produce gallic acid that was found to offer considerable potential to be used as an antioxidant, antibacterial, and antifungal agent concurrently with providing features like safety, accompanied by the fact that gallic acid is of natural origin.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alhazmi</LastName><ForeName>Nuha M</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7294-1510</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, College of Science, University of Jeddah, Jeddah 21589, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">441424</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41141794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12547566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c05913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lekshmi R., Arif Nisha S., Tirumalai Vasan P., Kaleeswaran B.. A comprehensive review on tannase: Microbes associated production of tannase exploiting tannin rich agro-industrial wastes with special reference to its potential environmental and industrial applications. Environ. Res. 2021;201:111625. doi: 10.1016/j.envres.2021.111625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2021.111625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34224709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshime L. T., Melo I. L. P. D., Sattler J. A. G., Torres R. P., Mancini-Filho J.. Bioactive compounds and the antioxidant capacities of seed oils from pomegranate (Punica granatum L.) and bitter gourd (Momordica charantia L.) Food Sci. Technol. 2019;39:571. doi: 10.1590/fst.23218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/fst.23218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ch&#xe1;vez-Gonz&#xe1;lez M. L., Rodr&#xed;guez-Duran L. V., Buenrostro-Figueroa J. J., Sep&#xfa;lveda-Torre L., Ascacio-Vald&#xe9;s J. A., Rodr&#xed;guez-Herrera R., Aguilar C. N.. Tannin degrading enzymes: catalytic properties and technological perspectives. Enzymes Food Technol. 2018:125&#x2013;141. doi: 10.1007/978-981-13-1933-4_7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-13-1933-4_7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilar-Z&#xe1;rate P., Cruz-Hern&#xe1;ndez M. A., Montanez J. C., Belmares-Cerda R. E., Aguilar C. N.. Bacterial tannases: production, properties and applications. Rev. Mex. Ing. Quim. 2014;13(1):63&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed A. I., Abou-Taleb Kh.A.. Implementation of different fermentation techniques for induction of tannase and gallic acid using agro-residues substrates. Egypt. J. Microbiol. 2019;54:39&#x2013;54. doi: 10.21608/ejm.2019.13840.1103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/ejm.2019.13840.1103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd-elmotey S., Nassar F. R., Nasr S. A., Abou-Taleb K. A.. Tannase and gallic acid production by Aspergillus niger SWP33 and Penicillium griseoroseum T11 using agricultural wastes under submerged and solid-state fermentation and its application. Egypt. J. Chem. 2022;65:21&#x2013;35. doi: 10.21608/ejchem.2022.108040.4948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/ejchem.2022.108040.4948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arshad R., Mohyuddin A., Saeed S., Ul Hassan A.. Optimized production of tannase and gallic acid from fruit seeds by solid state fermentation using Aspergillus oryzae . Trop. J. Pharm. Res. 2021;18:911. doi: 10.4314/tjpr.v18i5.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/tjpr.v18i5.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava A., Kar R.. Production of gallic acid by immobilized Aspergillus niger using polyurethane foam as solid support. Int. J. Food Eng. 2011;7(6):1. doi: 10.2202/1556-3758.1684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2202/1556-3758.1684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Tanash A. B., Abdel-Dayem S., Alshaymaa N.. Optimization of the hydrolysis process of tannic acid for gallic acid production by tannase of Aspergillus awamori using response surface methodology. Innovative Rom. Food Biotechnol. 2012;10:9&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M., Sun W., Wang J., He Y., Zhang J., Li F., Qi C., Zhu H., Xue Y., Hu Z., Zhang Y.. Bioactive secondary metabolites from the marine-associated fungus Aspergillus terreus. Bioorg. Chem. 2018;80:525&#x2013;530. doi: 10.1016/j.bioorg.2018.06.029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bioorg.2018.06.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30014920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amr K., Ibrahim N., Elissawy A. M., Singab A. N. B.. Unearthing the fungal endophyte Aspergillus terreus for chemodiversity and medicinal prospects: a comprehensive review. Fungal Biol. Biotechnol. 2023;10(1):6. doi: 10.1186/s40694-023-00153-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40694-023-00153-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10040139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36966331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atlas, R. M. Handbook of microbiological media, 4 th ed.; CRC Press, Inc., 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee D., Mondal K. C., Pati B. R.. Production and characterization of extracellular and intracellular tannase from newly isolated Aspergillus aculeatus DBF 9. J. Basic Microbiol. 2001;41:313&#x2013;318. doi: 10.1002/1521-4028(200112)41:6&lt;313::AID-JOBM313&gt;3.0.CO;2-W.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1521-4028(200112)41:6&lt;313::AID-JOBM313&gt;3.0.CO;2-W</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11802541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller J. H., Hinton J.. A Protein-Free Medium for Primary Isolation of the Gonococcus and Meningococcus . Proc. Soc. Exp. Biol. Med. 1941;48:330. doi: 10.3181/00379727-48-13311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3181/00379727-48-13311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atlas R. M., Synder J. W.. Reagents, stains, and media: Bacteriology. Man. Clin. Microbiol. 2011:272. doi: 10.1128/9781555816728.ch17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/9781555816728.ch17</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S. How Cells Grow. Bioprocess engineering kinetics, sustainability, and reactor design, 2nd ed.; Elsevier: Amsterdam, 2013; pp 629&#x2013;697, Chapter 11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leboffe, M. J. ; Pierce, B. E. . Microbiology: Laboratory Theory and Application; Essentials. Morton Publishing Company: Englewood, 2019. 925 W. Kenyon Avenue, Unit 12 Englewood, CO 80110.; pp 35&#x2013;48</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batra A., Saxena R. K.. Potential tannase producers from the genera Aspergillus and Penicillium. Process Biochem. 2005;40(5):1553&#x2013;1557. doi: 10.1016/j.procbio.2004.03.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procbio.2004.03.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitt, J. I. ; Hocking, A. D. . Fungi and food spoilage, 3rd ed.; Springer: Dordrecht Heidelberg London New York, 2009; pp 1&#x2013;519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell, C. K. ; Johnson, E. M. ; Warnock, D. W. . Identification of pathogenic fungi, 2nd ed.; Blackwell Publishing Ltd., 2013; p 352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White, T. J. ; Bruns, T. ; Lee, S. ; Taylor, J. . Amplification and direct sequencing of fungal ribosomal RNA genes for phylogenetics. In PCR protocols: A guide to methods and applications; Innis, M. A. , Gelfand, D. H. , Sninsky, J. J. , White, T. J. , Eds.; Academic Press: San Diego, CA, 1990; pp 315&#x2013;322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimnoi P., Pongsilp N., Lumyong S.. Endophytic actinomycetes isolated from Aquilaria crassna Pierre ex Lec and screening of plant growth promoters production. World J. Microbiol. Biotechnol. 2010;26(2):193&#x2013;203. doi: 10.1007/s11274-009-0159-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11274-009-0159-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claverie, J. M. ; Noterdame, C. , Bioinformatics for dummies. Bioinformatics &amp; Computational Biology, 2 nd ed.: New York, United States, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maier, R. M. ; Pepper, I. L. . Bacterial growth, 3rd ed.; Environ. Microbiol. Academic Press, 2015; pp 37&#x2013;56, Chapter 3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirt, S. J. Principles of cell and microbe and cell cultivation; Blackwell Scientific: Oxford, 1975; pp 4&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawford H. G., Roseau J. D.. Mannose fermentation by ethanologenic recombinants of Escherichia coli and Kinetical aspects. Biotechnol. Lett. 1993;15:615&#x2013;620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajpai B., Patil S.. A new approach to microbial production of gallic acid. Braz. J. Microbiol. 2008;39(4):708&#x2013;711. doi: 10.1590/S1517-83822008000400021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1517-83822008000400021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3768451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24031294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh M. P., Gupta A., Sisodia S. S.. Qualitative Analysis of Gallic Acid by HPLC Method In Different Extracts of Terminalia Bellerica Roxb Fruit FABAD . J. Pharm. Sci. 2019;44(2):101&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S., Sandhir R., Ojha S.. Evaluation of antioxidant activity and total phenol in different varieties of Lantana camara leaves. BMC Res. Notes. 2014;7:560. doi: 10.1186/1756-0500-7-560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1756-0500-7-560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4156633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25145266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antara S., Batra A.. Evaluation of Antimicrobial Activity of Different Solvent Extracts of Medicinal Plant: Melia azedarach L. Int. J. Curr. Pharm. Res. 2012;4:67&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singariya P., Mourya K. K., Kumar P.. Antimicrobial Activity of the Crude Extracts of Withania somnifera and Cenchrus setigerus In-vitro. Pharmacogn. J. 2012;4(27):60&#x2013;65. doi: 10.5530/pj.2012.27.10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5530/pj.2012.27.10</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3574538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23439788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binutu O. A., Cordell G. A.. Gallic Acid Derivatives from Mezoneuron benthamianum Leaves. Pharm. Biol. 2000;38:284&#x2013;286. doi: 10.1076/1388-0209(200009)3841-AFT284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1076/1388-0209(200009)3841-AFT284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21214477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute . Performance Standards for Antimicrobial Susceptibility Testing; 25th Informational Supplement. CLSI Document M100-S25; Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute: Wayne, PA, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryman, A. ; Cramer, D. . Quantitative data analysis with IBM SPSS 17, 18 &amp; 19: A Guide for Social Scientists. 1st ed.; Routledge: London, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vassileva M., Malus&#xe1; E., Eichler-L&#xf6;bermann B., Vassilev N.. Aspegillus terreus: From Soil to Industry and Back. Microorganisms. 2020;8:1655. doi: 10.3390/microorganisms8111655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms8111655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7692665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33113865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadumane, V. K. ; Venkatachalam, P. ; Gajaraj, B. . Aspergillus Applications in Cancer Research. In New and Future Developments in Microbial Biotechnology and Bioengineering: Aspergillus System Properties and Applications; Gupta, V. , Ed.; Elsevier B.V.: Amsterdam, The Netherlands, 2016; pp 243&#x2013;252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kathuria A., Singhal P., Singh N.. Tannin Biodegradation by Tannase Produced from Aspergillus terreus ITCC 8413.11 and its Culture conditions. Bull. Environ., Pharmacol. Life Sci. 2018;8(1):39&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd El Taw A. M., Murad H., Khattab M., Azzaz H.. Optimizing production of Tannase and in vitro evaluation on ruminal fermentation, degradability and gas production. Int. J. Dairy Sci. 2019;14(2):53&#x2013;60. doi: 10.3923/ijds.2019.53.60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3923/ijds.2019.53.60</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis B., Waikhom S. D., Roy P., Bhardwaj P. K., Singh M. W., Chandradev S. K., Talukdar N. C.. Invasion of Solanum tuberosum L. by Aspergillus terreus: a microscopic and proteomics insight on pathogenicity. BMC Res. Notes. 2014;7:350. doi: 10.1186/1756-0500-7-350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1756-0500-7-350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4065392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24917207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moglad E., Saeed S., Saeed H., Ahmed H., Salih K., Altayb H., Elhag W.. Molecular characterization and antifungal susceptibility of Aspergillus spp. among patients with underlying lung diseases. Trop. Med. Infect. Dis. 2022;7(10):274. doi: 10.3390/tropicalmed7100274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/tropicalmed7100274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9612272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36288015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>abd-elmotey S., Nasar F., Nasar S., Abou-Taleb K.. Tannase and gallic acid production by Aspergillus niger SWP33 and Penicillium griseoroseum T11 using agricultural wastes under submerged and solid-state fermentation and its application. Egypt. J. Chem. 2022;65(0):21&#x2013;35. doi: 10.21608/ejchem.2022.108040.4948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/ejchem.2022.108040.4948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Malek N., Rizk S., Ahmed A.. Advances in submerged liquid fermentation and formulation of entomopathogenic fungi. Appl. Microbiol. Biotechnol. 2024;108:451. doi: 10.1007/s00253-024-13287-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00253-024-13287-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11364594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39212719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narayanamurthy G., Ramachandra Y. L., Padmalatha R. S., Sujan Ganapathy P. S., Kavitha B. T., Manohara Y. N.. Comparative studies on submerged, liquid surface and solid state fermentation for citric acid production by Aspergillus niger RCNM 17. Asian Journal of Microbiology. Biotechnol. Environ. Sci. 2008;10(2):361&#x2013;364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy M. N., Reddy N. L. N.. Production of tannase by isolated Aspergillus terreus under submerged fermentation. Int. J. Sci. Technol. 2015;4(2):102&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao C., Li R., Wan Z., Liu W., Wang X., Qiao J., Wang D., Bulmer G., Calderone R.. The effects of temperature, pH, and salinity on the growth and dimorphism of Penicillium marneffei. Med. Mycol. 2007;45(5):401&#x2013;407. doi: 10.1080/13693780701358600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13693780701358600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17654266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arafat A. B. E.-T., Abdel-Dayem A. A., Alshaymaa N.. Optimization the hydrolysis process of tannic acid for gallic acid production by tannase of Aspergillus awamori using response surface methodology. Innovative Rom. Food Biotechnol. 2012;(10):9&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S., Yu Y., Jo Y., Han J. H., Xue Y., Cho M., Bae S. J., Ryu D., Park W., Ha K. T., Zhuang S.. Impact of extraction techniques on phytochemical composition and bioactivity of natural product mixtures. Front. Pharmacol. 2025;16:1615338. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2025.1615338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2025.1615338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12343529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40808686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olszowy M., Dawidowicz A. L., J&#xf3;zwik-Dol eba M.. Are mutual interactions between antioxidants the only factors responsible for antagonistic antioxidant effect of their mixtures? Additive and antagonistic antioxidant effects in mixtures of gallic, ferulic and caffeic acids. Eur. Food Res. Technol. 2019;245:1473&#x2013;1485. doi: 10.1007/s00217-019-03255-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00217-019-03255-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olszowy M.. What is responsible for antioxidant properties of polyphenolic compounds from plants? Plant Physiol. Biochem. 2019;144:135&#x2013;143. doi: 10.1016/j.plaphy.2019.09.039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.plaphy.2019.09.039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31563754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafiee S. A., Farhoosh R., Sharif A.. Antioxidant Activity of Gallic Acid as Affected by an Extra Carboxyl Group than Pyrogallol in Various Oxidative Environments. Eur. J. Lipid Sci. Technol. 2019;120:1800319. doi: 10.1002/ejlt.201800319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejlt.201800319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khorsandi K., Kianmehr Z., Hosseinmardi Z., Hosseinzadeh R.. Anti-cancer effect of gallic acid in presence of low level laser irradiation: ROS production and induction of apoptosis and ferroptosis. Cancer Cell Int. 2020;20:18. doi: 10.1186/s12935-020-1100-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12935-020-1100-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6958578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31956296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James J., Girija K.. Antioxidant Effectiveness and Phytochemical Composition of Ipomoea muricata (I. turbinata): A Focus on Phenolic and Flavonoids for Pharmaceutical Prospects. J. Pharm. BioAllied Sci. 2025;17(Suppl 1):S516&#x2013;S518. doi: 10.4103/jpbs.jpbs_580_25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jpbs.jpbs_580_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12156509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40510963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandhya Rani S., Vedavijaya T., Sree P. K., Shanmugasundaram J., Deepalatha C., Raju M. G., Babu Sayana S.. A Comprehensive Analysis of Phytochemical Composition, Acute Toxicity Assessment, and Antioxidant Potential of Ethanolic Extract of Carica Papaya Seeds. Cureus. 2023;15(11):e49686. doi: 10.7759/cureus.49686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.49686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10757050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38161939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh D. P., Verma S., Prabha R.. Investigations on Antioxidant Potential of Phenolic Acids and Flavonoids: The Common Phytochemical Ingredients in Plants. J. Plant Biochem. Physiol. 2018;6:219. doi: 10.4172/2329-9029.1000219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2329-9029.1000219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borges A., Ferreira C., Saavedra M. J., Sim&#xf5;es M.. Antibacterial Activity and Mode of Action of Ferulic and Gallic Acids Against Pathogenic Bacteria. Microb. Drug Resist. 2013;19(4):256&#x2013;265. doi: 10.1089/mdr.2012.0244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/mdr.2012.0244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23480526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sang H., Jin H., Song P., Xu W., Wang F.. Gallic acid exerts antibiofilm activity by inhibiting methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus adhesion. Sci. Rep. 2024;14(1):17220. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-68279-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-68279-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11282228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39060363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorrentino E., Succi M., Tipaldi L., Pannella G., Maiuro L., Sturchio M., Coppola R., Tremonte P.. Antimicrobial activity of gallic acid against food-related Pseudomonas strains and its use as biocontrol tool to improve the shelf life of fresh black truffles. Int. J. Food Microbiol. 2018;266:183&#x2013;189. doi: 10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2017.11.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2017.11.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29227905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z. J., Liu M., Dawuti G., Dou Q., Ma Y., Liu H. G., Aibai S.. Antifungal Activity of Gallic Acid In Vitro and In Vivo. Phytother. Res. 2017;31(7):1039&#x2013;1045. doi: 10.1002/ptr.5823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.5823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28524381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen D. M., Seo D. J., Lee H. B., Kim I. S., Kim K. Y., Park R. D., Jung W. J.. Antifungal activity of gallic acid purified from Terminalia nigrovenulosa bark against Fusarium solani. Microb. Pathog. 2013;56:8&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1016/j.micpath.2013.01.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.micpath.2013.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23333407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jadimurthy R., Jagadish S., Nayak S. C., Kumar S., Mohan C. D., Rangappa K. S.. Phytochemicals as Invaluable Sources of Potent Antimicrobial Agents to Combat Antibiotic Resistance. Life. 2023;13(4):948. doi: 10.3390/life13040948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/life13040948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10145550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37109477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>