<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41254624</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2458</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nonlinear and lagged effects of climate variability on dengue incidence in an urban megacity: a distributed lag non-linear model (DLNM) based study in Bangkok, Thailand.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4024</StartPage><MedlinePgn>4024</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4024</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12889-025-25420-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Dengue fever represents a significant and escalating public health challenge in tropical megacities such as Bangkok, Thailand. This study aims to examine the associations between temperature, humidity, rainfall, and wind speed with dengue incidence across multiple lag periods and to explore spatial heterogeneity in these climate-dengue relationships across Bangkok&#x2019;s urban zones.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY">Analysis of 105,890 confirmed dengue cases reported in Bangkok between 2015 and 2024, stratified across six urban zones. Distributed Lag Non-Linear Models (DLNM) were employed to quantify the effects of four key meteorological variables: temperature, humidity, rainfall, and wind speed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Significant non-linear relationships and heterogeneity in climate-driven dengue risk were found across both space and time. Spatially, the effects were most pronounced for humidity and wind speed. For instance, over a 0&#x2013;2 months lag, higher humidity was associated with a substantial increase in risk in North Krung Thon (RR=1.477, 95% CI: 1.290&#x2013;1.690) but a significant protective effect in South and Middle Bangkok. Similarly, wind speed was associated with a significant risk increase in South Bangkok (RR=1.405, 95% CI: 1.293&#x2013;1.526) but a protective effect in East Bangkok (RR=0.749, 95% CI: 0.710&#x2013;0.789). Elevated minimum temperature also exhibited a spatially varied impact, peaking in Middle Bangkok (RR=1.350, 95% CI: 1.288&#x2013;1.414). The analysis confirmed distinct patterns over time, with climate impacts manifesting as immediate risks in some zones and as pronounced delayed risks (8&#x2013;12 months) in others.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The associations between climatic variables and dengue incidence in Bangkok are highly complex, non-linear, and characterized by significant spatial and temporal heterogeneity. The varied timing of climate impacts, from immediate to delayed, suggests that public health responses must be adapted to the unique temporal risk structures of each urban zone, providing a framework for more precise interventions in complex urban environments.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12889-025-25420-2.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Polrob</LastName><ForeName>Warunya</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mahidol University, Nakhonsawan Campus, Nakhonsawan, 60130, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>La-Up</LastName><ForeName>Aroon</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mahidol University, Nakhonsawan Campus, Nakhonsawan, 60130, Thailand. aroon.lau@mahidol.ac.th.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968562</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2458</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bangkok-Thailand</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Climate variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dengue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lagged effects</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nonlinear effects</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by Mahidol University Central Institutional Review Board (MU-CIRB). The approval number was MU-CIRB 2024/439.0111. This study was conducted in full accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki and relevant national guidelines. The requirement for informed consent was formally waived by the MU-CIRB as the research was based on a retrospective analysis of anonymized and aggregated secondary data with no personal identifiers. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41254624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12625335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-025-25420-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12889-025-25420-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bhatt S, Gething PW, Brady OJ, Messina JP, Farlow AW, Moyes CL, et al. The global distribution and burden of dengue. Nature. 2013;496(7446):504&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature12060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3651993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23563266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Carreras B, Yang B, Grabowski MK, Sheppard LW, Huang AT, Salje H, et al. Periodic synchronisation of dengue epidemics in Thailand over the last 5 decades driven by temperature and immunity. PLoS Biol. 2022;20(3):e3001160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pbio.3001160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8967062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35302985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez LJ, Yamaguchi J, Weiss S, Carlos C, Meyer TV, Rodgers MA, et al. Climate, inter-serotype competition and arboviral interactions shape dengue dynamics in Thailand. Commun Biology. 2025;8(1):601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42003-025-07999-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11992266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40216923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polwiang S. The time series seasonal patterns of dengue fever and associated weather variables in Bangkok (2003&#x2013;2017). BMC Infect Dis. 2020;20(1):208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-020-4902-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7068876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32164548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Zhang Q, Li L, He J, Guo J, Wang Z, et al. The effect of temperature on dengue virus transmission by Aedes mosquitoes. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2023;13:1242173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcimb.2023.1242173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10552155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37808907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Q, Jing Q, Collender PA, Head JR, Li Q, Yu H, et al. Prior water availability modifies the effect of heavy rainfall on dengue transmission: a time series analysis of passive surveillance data from Southern China. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1287678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10722414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38106890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell KM, Lin CD, Iamsirithaworn S, Scott TW. The complex relationship between weather and dengue virus transmission in Thailand. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2013;89(6):1066&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.13-0321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3854883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23958906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang K, Chen C-D, Shih C-M, Lee T-C, Wu M-T, Wu D-C, et al. Time-Lagging interplay effect and excess risk of Meteorological/Mosquito parameters and petrochemical gas explosion on dengue incidence. Sci Rep. 2016;6(1):35028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep35028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5062066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27733774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez MS, G&#xf3;mez AA, M&#xfc;ller GV, Walker E, Robert MA, Estallo EL. Relationship between climate variables and dengue incidence in Argentina. Environ Health Perspect. 2023;131(5):57008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1289/EHP11616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10208431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37224070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnin L, Tran A, Herbreteau V, Marcombe S, Boyer S, Mangeas M, et al. Predicting the effects of climate change on dengue vector densities in Southeast Asia through Process-Based modeling. Environ Health Perspect. 2022;130(12):127002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1289/EHP11068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9726451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36473499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasparrini A, Armstrong B, Kenward MG. Distributed lag non-linear models. Stat Med. 2010;29(21):2224&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.3940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2998707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20812303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaskaran K, Gasparrini A, Hajat S, Smeeth L, Armstrong B. Time series regression studies in environmental epidemiology. Int J Epidemiol. 2013;42(4):1187&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/dyt092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3780998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23760528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasparrini A, Guo Y, Hashizume M, Lavigne E, Zanobetti A, Schwartz J, et al. Mortality risk attributable to high and low ambient temperature: a multicountry observational study. Lancet. 2015;386(9991):369&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(14)62114-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4521077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26003380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song B, Zhang H, Jiao L, Jing Z, Li H, Wu S. Effect of high-level fine particulate matter and its interaction with meteorological factors on AECOPD in Shijiazhuang, China. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):8711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-12791-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9130147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35610290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thisyakorn U, Saokaew S, Gallagher E, Kastner R, Sruamsiri R, Oliver L, et al. Epidemiology and costs of dengue in thailand: A systematic literature review. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2022;16(12):e0010966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0010966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9810168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36534668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumharn W, Piwngam W, Pilahome O, Ninssawan W, Jankondee Y, Chaochaikong S. Effects of meteorological factors on dengue incidence in Bangkok city: a model for dengue prediction. Model Earth Syst Environ. 2023;9(1):1215&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40808-022-01557-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugeno M, Kawazu EC, Kim H, Banouvong V, Pehlivan N, Gilfillan D, et al. Association between environmental factors and dengue incidence in Lao people&#x2019;s Democratic republic: a nationwide time-series study. BMC Public Health. 2023;23(1):2348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-023-17277-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10683213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38012549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasparrini A. Distributed lag linear and Non-Linear models in R: the package Dlnm. J Stat Softw. 2011;43(8):1&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v043.i08</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3191524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22003319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefebvre B, Karki R, Misslin R, Nakhapakorn K, Daud&#xe9; E, Paul RE. Importance of public transport networks for reconciling the spatial distribution of dengue and the association of socio-economic factors with dengue risk in Bangkok, Thailand. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:10123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9408777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36011755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibb R, Col&#xf3;n-Gonz&#xe1;lez FJ, Lan PT, Huong PT, Nam VS, Duoc VT, et al. Interactions between climate change, urban infrastructure and mobility are driving dengue emergence in Vietnam. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):8179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-43954-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10713571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38081831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdock CC, Evans MV, McClanahan TD, Miazgowicz KL, Tesla B. Fine-scale variation in microclimate across an urban landscape shapes variation in mosquito population dynamics and the potential of Aedes albopictus to transmit arboviral disease. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2017;11(5):e0005640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0005640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5466343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28558030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa E, Santos E, Correia J, Albuquerque C. Impact of small variations in temperature and humidity on the reproductive activity and survival of Aedes aegypti (Diptera, Culicidae). Revista Brasileira De Entomol. 2010;54:488&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0085-56262010000300021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamau WW, Sang R, Rotich G, Agha SB, Menza N, Torto B, et al. Patterns of Aedes aegypti abundance, survival, human-blood feeding and relationship with dengue risk, Kenya. Front Trop Dis. 2023;4:1113531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wai KT, Arunachalam N, Tana S, Espino F, Kittayapong P, Abeyewickreme W, et al. Estimating dengue vector abundance in the wet and dry season: implications for targeted vector control in urban and peri-urban Asia. Pathog Glob Health. 2012;106(8):436&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1179/2047773212Y.0000000063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3541889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23318235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiwat H, Doerdjan K, Kerpens M, Samjhawan A, Sardjoe P, Soekhoe T. Importance of domestic water containers as Aedes aegypti breeding sites in Suriname; implications for dengue control. Acad J Suriname. 2013;4(1):403&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getachew D, Tekie H, Gebre-Michael T, Balkew M, Mesfin A. Breeding sites of Aedes aegypti: potential dengue vectors in dire Dawa, East Ethiopia. Interdisciplinary Perspect Infect Dis. 2015;2015(1):706276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4576013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26435712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waewwab P, Sungvornyothin S, Potiwat R, Okanurak K. Impact of dengue-preventive behaviors on Aedes immature production in Bang Kachao, Samut Prakan Province, thailand: a cross-sectional study. BMC Public Health. 2020;20(1):905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-020-8394-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7291577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32527239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdonschot PFM, Besse-Lototskaya AA. Flight distance of mosquitoes (Culicidae): A metadata analysis to support the management of barrier zones around rewetted and newly constructed wetlands. Limnologica. 2014;45:69&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.limno.2013.11.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javed N, L&#xf3;pez-Denman AJ, Paradkar PN, Bhatti A. Flight traits of dengue-infected Aedes aegypti mosquitoes. Comput Biol Med. 2024;171:108178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2024.108178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38394802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeleke ED, Shittu RA, Beierkuhnlein C, Thomas SM. High wind speed prevents the establishment of the disease vector mosquito Aedes albopictus in its climatic niche in Europe. Front Environ Sci. 2022;10:846243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiang MV, Santillana M, Chen JT, Onnela J-P, Krieger N, Eng&#xf8;-Monsen K, et al. Incorporating human mobility data improves forecasts of dengue fever in Thailand. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-79438-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7806770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33441598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pakarnseree R, Chunkao K, Bualert S. Physical characteristics of Bangkok and its urban heat Island phenomenon. Build Environ. 2018;143:561&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.buildenv.2018.07.042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phanitchat T, Zhao B, Haque U, Pientong C, Ekalaksananan T, Aromseree S, et al. Spatial and Temporal patterns of dengue incidence in Northeastern Thailand 2006&#x2013;2016. BMC Infect Dis. 2019;19(1):743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-019-4379-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6708185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31443630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wongkoon S, Jaroensutasinee M, Jaroensutasinee K. Spatio-temporal climate-based model of dengue infection in Southern, Thailand. Trop Biomed. 2016;33:55&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33579141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koyadun S, Butraporn P, Kittayapong P. Ecologic and sociodemographic risk determinants for dengue transmission in urban areas in Thailand. Interdiscip Perspect Infect Dis. 2012;2012:907494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2012/907494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3463950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23056042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marti R, Li Z, Catry T, Roux E, Mangeas M, Handschumacher P, et al. A mapping review on urban landscape factors of dengue retrieved from Earth observation Data, GIS Techniques, and survey questionnaires. Remote Sens. 2020;12(6):932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs12060932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z, Liu T, Li X, Wang J, Lin H, Chen L, et al. Individual and interactive effects of socio-ecological factors on dengue fever at fine Spatial scale: a geographical detector-based analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2017;14:795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5551233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28714925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu Y, Shi X, Wang Y, Li R, Lu L, Liu Q. Effects of socio-economic and environmental factors on the Spatial heterogeneity of dengue fever investigated at a fine scale. Geospat Health. 2018;13:682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30451470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>