<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41194230</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1746-4269</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of ethnobiology and ethnomedicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Ethnobiol Ethnomed</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ethnobotanical assessment of wild edible plants and associated threats in Guraferda district, Bench-Sheko Zone, Southwest Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>77</StartPage><MedlinePgn>77</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">77</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13002-025-00827-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Wild edible plants (WEPs) play a vital role in food security, nutrition, and cultural heritage in Ethiopia. In the Guraferda district, communities depend on WEPs, but systematic documentation of their diversity, uses, and associated traditional knowledge is limited. This study aimed to document WEPs diversity, utilization patterns, ethnobotanical knowledge, and conservation status.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Data were collected from 96 informants across eight purposively selected kebeles between June 2023 and May 2024 using semi-structured interviews, guided field walks, focus group discussions, and market surveys. Species identification followed standard herbarium procedures. Ethnobotanical significance and threats were assessed through preference, direct matrix and threats ranking. Quantitative analyses, including the Botanical Ethnoknowledge Index (BEI), t tests, ANOVA, and correlation analyses, were conducted in R software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 64 WEP species belonging to 47 genera and 25 families were recorded, with Moraceae (7 species) most represented. Fruits (42.2%), leave (29.7%), and tubers (10.9%) were the most consumed parts, and herbs were the dominant life form. Forests were the primary habitat, with peak availability in spring. Common harvesting methods included picking (53.2%), plucking (32.8%), and digging (14%). Ethnobotanical knowledge varied significantly among demographic groups (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), and Jaccard's similarity index showed both shared and unique patterns. Culturally and nutritionally important species included Colocasia esculenta (L.) Schott and Coccinia abyssinica (Lam.) Cogn. Major threats were deforestation and overharvesting, while traditional practices such as sacred groves and home gardens supported conservation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">WEPs are crucial for dietary diversity, nutrition, and income in Guraferda but face growing human-induced threats. Sustainable management, community-based conservation, and preservation of traditional knowledge are essential, alongside nutritional assessments of key species to strengthen their role in local food systems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Awoke</LastName><ForeName>Ashebir</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, Mizan-Tepi University, Tepi, Ethiopia. ashebir@mtu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tigab</LastName><ForeName>Temesgen</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ethiopian Biodiversity Institute, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dessie</LastName><ForeName>Yitayih</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, Injibara University, Injbara, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bitew</LastName><ForeName>Gizachew</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, Mizan-Tepi University, Tepi, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Ethnobiol Ethnomed</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101245794</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1746-4269</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010945" MajorTopicYN="Y">Plants, Edible</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019448" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ethnobotany</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019359" MajorTopicYN="N">Knowledge</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003247" MajorTopicYN="N">Conservation of Natural Resources</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Conservation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethnobotanical knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Food security</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Guraferda</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wild edible plants</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Before collecting data, authorization letters were obtained from the Guraferda District Administration Offices. Informants provided verbal consent prior to participating in interviews and group discussions, and their information was recorded with their approval. Additionally, consent was secured from the informants for the publication of the data collected from them. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors state that they do not have any competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41194230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12587692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-025-00827-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13002-025-00827-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Botha MS, Cowling RM, Esler KJ, De Vynck J, Potts AJ. Have humans living within the Greater Cape Floristic Region used the same plant species through time? S Afr J Bot. 2019;1(122):11&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sajb.2019.01.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamathaba MP. Botanical Efforts for a Comprehensive Assessment of Vascular Plant Diversity in South Africa. University of Johannesburg (South Africa); 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faraji L, Karimi M. Botanical gardens as valuable resources in plant sciences. Biodivers Conserv. 2022;31(12):2905&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10531-019-01926-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzo S, Lulekal E, Nemomissa S. Ethnobotanical study of underutilized wild edible plants and threats to their long-term existence in Midakegn district, West Shewa zone, Central Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2023;19(1):30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-023-00601-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10347739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37452368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray A, Ray R. The culture has not faded: reliance on diverse wild edible plants in prehistory, history, and modern times. In: Wild food plants for zero hunger and resilient agriculture. Singapore: Springer Nature; 2023. p. 43&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh RP, Chintagunta AD, Agarwal DK, Kureel RS, Kumar SJ. Varietal replacement rate: prospects and challenges for global food security. Glob Food Sec. 2020;1(25):100324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gfs.2019.100324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duguma HT. Wild edible plant nutritional contribution and consumer perception in Ethiopia. Int J Food Sci. 2020;2020(1):2958623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7487116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32953878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutie FM, Rono PC, Kathambi V, Hu GW, Wang QF. Conservation of wild food plants and their potential for combatting food insecurity in Kenya as exemplified by the drylands of Kitui County. Plants. 2020;9(8):1017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants9081017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7464302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32806636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olowo SF, Aremu AO. Utilisation pattern and economic potential of indigenous fruits and vegetables among rural communities in Akure, Nigeria.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulian T, Diazgranados M, Pironon S, Padulosi S, Liu U, Davies L, et al. Unlocking plant resources to support food security and promote sustainable agriculture. Plants People Planet. 2020;2(5):421&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ppp3.10145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dejene T, Agamy MS, Ag&#xfa;ndez D, Martin-Pinto P. Ethnobotanical survey of wild edible fruit tree species in lowland areas of Ethiopia. Forests. 2020;11(2):177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f11020177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding XY, Zhang Y, Wang L, Zhuang HF, Chen WY, Wang YH. Collection calendar: the diversity and local knowledge of wild edible plants used by Chenthang Sherpa people to treat seasonal food shortages in Tibet, China. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2021;17(1):40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-021-00464-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8190990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34112198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Q, Cheng Z, Zhang R, Luo B, Long C. Wild edible plants of the Yao people in Jianghua, China: plant-associated traditional knowledge and practice vital for food security and ecosystem service. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2024;20(1):80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-024-00724-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11360554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39198831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beleta KG, Jiru DB, Tolera KD. Assessment of edible woody plants&#x2019; diversity, their threats, and local people&#x2019;s perception in Borecha Woreda of Buno Bedele Zone, Southwestern Ethiopia. Int J Forestry Res. 2024;2024(1):7269154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yimer A, Forsido SF, Addis G, Ayelign A. Potential and prospects of utilization, development, and conservation of wild edible plants of the meinit ethnic community in Bench-Maji Zone, Southwestern Ethiopia. East African Journal of Sciences. 2023;17(2):199&#x2013;214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awoke A, Gudesho G, Akmel F, Shanmugasundaram P. Traditionally used medicinal plants for human ailments and their threats in Guraferda District, Benchi-Sheko zone, Southwest Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2024;20(1):82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-024-00709-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11367917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39223653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awoke A, Gudesho G, Akmel F, Tessema ZK, Tilahun W, Abdu AA, et al. Medicinal plants used for treatment of domestic animal diseases and their threats in Guraferda district, Bench-Sheko Zone, South West Ethiopia. Ethnobot Res Appl. 2024;8(29):1&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidane B, Van der Maesen LJ, van Andel T, Asfaw Z, Sosef MS. Ethnobotany of wild and semi-wild edible fruit species used by Maale and Ari ethnic communities in southern Ethiopia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giday M, Teklehaymanot T. Use of wild edible and nutraceutical plants in Raya-Azebo District of Tigray Region, northern Ethiopia. Tropic Med Health. 2023;51(1):58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41182-023-00550-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10594744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37872596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekele M, Woldeyes F, Lulekal E, Bekele T, Demissew S. Ethnobotanical investigation of medicinal plants in Buska Mountain range, Hamar district, Southwestern Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2022;18(1):1&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-022-00558-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9484237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36123732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassa Z, Asfaw Z, Demissew S. Ethno-ecological study of medicinal and wild edible plants in Sheka Zone, Southern Nations, Nationalities and Peoples Regional State, Ethiopia. Trop Plant Res. 2020;7(1):65&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22271/tpr.2020.v7.i1.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7003439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32024539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotton CM. Ethnobotany: principles and applications. 1996 Oct 4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hankiso M, Warkineh B, Asfaw Z, Debella A. Ethnobotany of wild edible plants in Soro District of Hadiya Zone, southern Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2023;19(1):21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-023-00588-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10236777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37269005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;ft M, Barik SK, Lykke AM. Quantitative ethnobotany: Application of multivariate and statistical analysis in ethnobotany. People and Plants working paper. 1999;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dulal K, Chaudhary S, Uprety Y, Shrestha N, Shakya S, Munankarmi N. Ethnomedicinal plants used by the local people of Changunarayan Municipality, Bhaktapur. Nepal Ethnobot Res Appl. 2022;22(23):1&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulaiman N. Botanical ethnoknowledge index: a new quantitative assessment method for cross-cultural analysis. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2025;21(1):20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-025-00772-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11927197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40114209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse D, Masresha G, Lulekal E, Alemu A. Ethnobotanical study of wild edible plants in Metema and Quara districts, Northwestern Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2025;21(1):7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-025-00761-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11804023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39920808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin GJ. Ethnobotany: a methods manual. Routledge; 2010 Sep 23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mengesha BK. Ethnobotany of wild and semi-wild edible and medicinal plants used by Maale and Ari ethnic groups in southern Ethiopia (Doctoral dissertation, Wageningen University and Research).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalmuanpuii R, Zodinpuii B, Bohia B, Zothanpuia LJ, Singh PK. Wild edible vegetables of ethnic communities of Mizoram (Northeast India): an ethnobotanical study in thrust of marketing potential. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2024;20(1):58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-024-00680-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11135011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38807182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yiblet Y, Adamu E. An ethnobotanical study of wild edible plants in Tach Gayint district, South Gondar zone, Amhara region, Northwestern Ethiopia. Evidence-Based Complement Alternat Med. 2023;2023(1):7837615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/7837615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10319463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37408582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdella M, Cheneke B, Ketama M. Assessment of wild edible plant species in East Hararghe Zone, Oromia, Ethiopia. Int J Sci Technol Soc/Rev Int Ci&#xca;ncias, Tecnol Soc. 2023; 11(3).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyakoojo C, Tugume P. Traditional use of wild edible plants in the communities adjacent Mabira Central Forest Reserve. Uganda Ethnobot Res Appl. 2020;31(20):1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anbessa B, Lulekal E, Debella A, Hymete A. Ethnobotanical study of medicinal plants in Dibatie district, Metekel zone, Benishangul Gumuz Regional State, western Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2024;20(1):85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-024-00723-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11404030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39278939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin M, Aziz MA, Pieroni A, Nazir A, Al-Ghamdi AA, Kangal A, et al. Edible wild plant species used by different linguistic groups of Kohistan Upper Khyber Pakhtunkhwa (KP), Pakistan. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2023;19(1):6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-023-00577-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9923922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36782205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemu M, Asfaw Z, Lulekal E, Warkineh B, Debella A, Sisay B, et al. Ethnobotanical study of traditional medicinal plants used by the local people in Habru District, North Wollo Zone, Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2024;20(1):4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-023-00644-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10768247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38178202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masresha G, Melkamu Y, Walle GC. Ethnobotanical study on wild edible plants in Metema district, Amhara regional state, Ethiopia. Int J Forestry Res. 2023;2023(1):9243343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birhanu A. Study on wild edible plant used by Shinasha ethnic community at Metekel Zone, Northwest Ethiopia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lungphi P, Wangpan T, Tangjang S. Wild edible plants and their additional uses by the Tangsa community living in the Changlang district of Arunachal Pradesh, India. Pleione. 2018;12(2):151&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26679/Pleione.12.2.2018.151-164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tebkew M, Gebremariam Y, Mucheye T, Alemu A, Abich A, Fikir D. Uses of wild edible plants in Quara district, northwest Ethiopia: implication for forest management. Agric Food Secur. 2018;7(1):1&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40066-018-0163-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balemie K, Kebebew F. Ethnobotanical study of wild edible plants in Derashe and Kucha Districts, South Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2006;2(1):53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1746-4269-2-53</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1769355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17184523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassen A. Diversity and potential contribution of wild edible plants to sustainable food security in North Wollo, Ethiopia. Biodiv J Biol Div. 2021; 22(6).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemneh D. Ethnobotany of wild edible plants in Yilmana Densa and Quarit Districts of West Gojjam zone, Amhara region, Ethiopia. Ethnobot Res Appl. 2020;20(47):2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7910050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33681356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghorbani A, Langenberger G, Sauerborn J. A comparison of the wild food plant use knowledge of ethnic minorities in Naban River Watershed National Nature Reserve, Yunnan, SW China. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2012;8(1):17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1746-4269-8-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3485152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22559280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khakurel D, Uprety Y, &#x141;uczaj &#x141;, Rajbhandary S. Foods from the wild: local knowledge, use pattern and distribution in Western Nepal. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(10):e0258905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0258905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8530312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34673823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meitei LR, De A, Mao AA. An ethnobotanical study on the wild edible plants used by forest dwellers in Yangoupokpi Lokchao Wildlife Sanctuary, Manipur, India. Ethnobot Res Appl. 2022;23(15):1&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Fatimi M. Wild edible plants traditionally collected and used in southern Yemen. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2021;17(1):49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-021-00475-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8351113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34372859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalali M, Abedi M, Memariani F, Ghorbani A. Ethnobotanical study of wild edible plants in the mountainous regions of Semnan Province, Iran. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2024;20(1):93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-024-00732-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11451187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39367458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oduor FO, Kaindi DW, Abong GO, Thuita F, Termote C. Diversity and utilization of indigenous wild edible plants and their contribution to food security in Turkana County, Kenya. Front Sustain Food Syst. 2023;4(7):1113771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsufs.2023.1113771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahir M, Abrahim A, Beyene T, Dinsa G, Guluma T, Alemneh Y, et al. The traditional use of wild edible plants in pastoral and agro-pastoral communities of Mieso District, eastern Ethiopia. Tropic Med Health. 2023;51(1):10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41182-023-00505-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9948460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36814353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woldemedhin AA, Lulekal E, Bekele T, Debella A, Debebe E, Tessema S. Ethnobotanical study of edible wild plants in Ensaro district, Amhara regional state, Ethiopia. Review. 2021;19:3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biri S, Ayenew B, Dida G, Sebsibe A, Gurmessa F, Woldeab B, et al. Ethnobotanical study of wild edible plants in Arsi Robe district of East Arsi Zone, Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2024;20(1):70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-024-00703-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11289975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39080759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aryal KP, Poudel S, Chaudhary RP, Chettri N, Chaudhary P, Ning W, et al. Diversity and use of wild and non-cultivated edible plants in the Western Himalaya. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2018;14(1):10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-018-0211-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5789610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29378614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashagre M, Asfaw Z, Kelbessa E. Ethnobotanical study of wild edible plants in Burji District, Segan area zone of southern nations, nationalities and peoples region (SNNPR), Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2016;12(1):32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-016-0103-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4971624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27485265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emire A, Demise S, Giri T, Tadele W. Ethnobotanical study of wild edible plants in Liben and Wadera Districts of Guji Zone, Southern Ethiopia. Glob J Agric Res. 2022;10(3):47&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tewelde F. Marketable medicinal, edible and spice plants in Endasilase-Shire District Tigray Regional State. Ethiopia Res J Med Sci. 2018;13(13):1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse D, Masresha G, Lulekal E, Wondafrash M. A systematic review exploring the diversity and food security potential of wild edible plants in Ethiopia. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):17821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-67421-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11294628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39090093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awoke A, Siyum Y, Gudesho G, Akmel F, Abate KS. Ethnobotanical study of wild and semi-wild edible plants in Yeki district, Sheka Zone, Southwest Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2025;21(1):54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-025-00810-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12335779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40783529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meragiaw M, Fekadu M, Senbeta F, Demissew S. Ethnobotanical survey of multipurpose, medicinal and wild edible plants in the upper Gibe watershed landscapes, West Shewa zone, Ethiopia. Plant Biosyst- Int J Deal Asp Plant Biol. 2024;158(5):1149&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addis G, Asfaw Z, Woldu Z. The role of wild and semi-wild edible plants to household food sovereignty in Hamar and Konso Communities. South Ethiopia Ethnobot Res Appl. 2013;28(11):251&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosissa D, Abraha B. Tuber wild plants of Shinasha people as food and medicine in Bullen District. Northw Ethiopia Biodivers Int J. 2018;2:53&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emire A, Demise S, Giri T. Ethnobotanical Study of Wild Edible Fruit Tree and Shrub Species in Adola Rede and Odo Shakiso Midland Districts of Guji Zone, Southern Ethiopia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wassie KB, Tsegay BA. Nutrient composition and phytochemical screening of selected wild edible plants in the Sedie Muja District, South Gondar Zone, Ethiopia. Discov Appl Sci. 2025;7(9):1017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42452-025-07570-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fassil A, Mazengia E, Gebreamanuel B, Dessie Y, Kumera B, Atnkut B, et al. Harvesting nature&#x2019;s bounty: exploring the ethnobotanical landscape of wild edible plants in the Awi Ag&#xe4;w community, Northwestern Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2024;20(1):59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-024-00696-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11140977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38816853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidane L, Kejela A. Food security and environment conservation through sustainable use of wild and semi-wild edible plants: a case study in Berek Natural Forest, Oromia special zone, Ethiopia. Agric Food Secur. 2021;10(1):29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40066-021-00308-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tebkew M, Asfaw Z, Zewudie S. Underutilized wild edible plants in the Chilga District, northwestern Ethiopia: focus on wild woody plants. Agri Food Sec. 2014;3(1):12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2048-7010-3-12</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meragiaw M, Asfaw Z, Argaw M. Indigenous knowledge (IK) of wild edible plants (WEPs) and impacts of resettlement in Delanta, Northern Ethiopia. Res Rev J Herb Sci. 2015;4(3):8&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sina B, Degu HD. Knowledge and use of wild edible plants in the Hula District of the Sidama Zone. Int J Bio-Resour Stress Manag. 2015;6(3):352&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5958/0976-4038.2015.00052.4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teklehaymanot T, Giday M. Ethnobotanical study of wild edible plants of Kara and Kwego semi-pastoralist people in Lower Omo River Valley, Debub Omo Zone, SNNPR, Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2010;6(1):23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1746-4269-6-23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2933608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20712910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teklehaymanot T. An ethnobotanical survey of medicinal and edible plants of Yalo Woreda in Afar regional state, Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2017;13(1):40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-017-0166-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5499056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28679438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awoke A, Siyum Y, Awoke D, Gebremedhin H, Tadesse A. Ethnobotanical study of medicinal plants and their threats in Yeki district, Southwestern Ethiopia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2024;20(1):107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-024-00748-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11663343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39709441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yangdon P, Araki T, Rahayu YY, Norbu K. Ethnobotanical study of wild edible fruits in eastern Bhutan. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2022;18(1):27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-022-00526-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8966357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35354474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortolotto IM, Amorozo MC, Neto GG, Oldeland J, Damasceno-Junior GA. Knowledge and use of wild edible plants in rural communities along Paraguay River, Pantanal, Brazil. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2015;11(1):46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-015-0026-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4469002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26025294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang Y, &#x141;uczaj &#x141;, Kang J, Zhang S. Wild food plants and wild edible fungi in two valleys of the Qinling Mountains (Shaanxi, central China). J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2013;9(1):26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1746-4269-9-26</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3686673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23587149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jigme J, Yangchen K. Ethnobotanical study of the wild edible plants used by the indigenous people of Merak in Bhutan. Asian J Ethnobiol. 2023;6(1):31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13057/asianjethnobiol/y060101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobezie S, Mersha W. Ethnobotanical survey of some wild edible plants among the Mursi, Bodi and Bacha communities in lower Omo valley of south Omo zone, southern Ethiopia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phumthum M, Balslev H, Barfod AS. Important medicinal plant families in Thailand. Front Pharmacol. 2019;25(10):1125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2019.01125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6774001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31607932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>