<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41250730</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pervasiveness and Frequency of Retinopathy of Prematurity in a Tertiary Care Centre and Its Correlation With Birth Weight and Gestational Age: A Retrospective Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e94804</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e94804</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e94804</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.94804</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Introduction Retinopathy of prematurity (ROP) is a vasoproliferative retinal disorder affecting incompletely vascularized retina of preterm infants. It remains one of the leading preventable causes of childhood blindness worldwide. The incidence and severity of ROP vary with neonatal care standards, oxygen regulation, and demographic factors. Birth weight (BW) and gestational age (GA) are the most important predictors of disease, though other perinatal and systemic factors may contribute. In India, wide variation in reported prevalence underlines the importance of centre-specific data to guide screening protocols. Aim To determine the prevalence and severity of ROP in a tertiary-level hospital and to analyse its association with BW, GA, and retinal vascularization patterns. Methods&#xa0; This retrospective observational study was conducted at a tertiary hospital in South India from January 2022 to December 2024. Infants with GA &#x2264;32 weeks and/or BW &lt;2000 g, and those with GA 32-36 weeks with additional risk factors, were screened as per national guidelines. Data on maternal history, GA, BW, oxygen therapy, laboratory findings, retinal zone at first examination, and ROP stage were collected. Statistical analysis was performed using Microsoft Excel (Microsoft Corp., Redmond, WA) and IBM SPSS v29 (IBM Corp., Armonk, NY). Descriptive statistics and Pearson chi-square tests were applied, with p &lt; 0.05 considered significant. Results&#xa0; A total of 375 infants were screened. A total of 50 infants (13.3%) had extremely low birth weight (ELBW), 171 (45.6%) had very low birth weight (VLBW), and 154 (41.1%) had low birth weight (LBW). Regarding gestational age (GA), 43 (11.5%) were extremely preterm, 156 (41.6%) were very preterm, and 176 (46.9%) were late preterm. A total of 12 (3.2%) had immature retinal vascularization in Zone I, 154 (41.1%) in Zone II, and 182 (48.5%) in Zone III, while 27 (7.2%) had a mature retina. ROP was present in 19 infants (5.1%): Stage I in 11 (2.9%), Stage II in 8 (2.1%); plus disease was seen in one infant (0.3%). Retinal immaturity was significantly associated with lower BW (&#x3c7;&#xb2; = 104.387, df = 6, <i>p</i> = 0.0005) and earlier GA (&#x3c7;&#xb2; = 132.535, df = 6, <i>p</i> = 0.0005). Conclusion&#xa0; Prevalence of ROP in this tertiary hospital was 5.1%, with lower BW and earlier GA strongly associated with immature retinal vascularization. These findings underscore the importance of targeted screening and meticulous neonatal care to prevent sight-threatening ROP.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Kumaresan et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumaresan</LastName><ForeName>Supreetha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Sri Ramachandra Institute of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meera Devasena</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Sri Ramachandra Institute of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Annamalai</LastName><ForeName>Radha</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Sri Ramachandra Institute of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tellakula</LastName><ForeName>Adithya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Adithya Eye Clinic, Chennai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhimanadham</LastName><ForeName>Venkat Meghana</ForeName><Initials>VM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Sri Ramachandra Institute of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muthayya</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Sri Ramachandra Institute of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">birth weight</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gestational age</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neonatal screening</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevalence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">retinopathy of prematurity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Institutional Research Ethics Committee issued approval CSP-MED/25/FEB/113/27. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41250730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12619968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.94804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Extreme prematurity and fibroblastic overgrowth of persistent vascular sheath behind each crystalline lens: I. preliminary report. Terry TL. Am J Ophthalmol. 2018;192:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30055814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization; International Agency for the Prevention of Blindness. Vision 2020: The right to sight - global initiative for the elimination of avoidable nlindness.  [
Oct;
2025 
]. 2007. https://iris.who.int/bitstream/handle/10665/43754/9789241595889_eng.pdf https://iris.who.int/bitstream/handle/10665/43754/9789241595889_eng.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retinopathy of prematurity in middle-income countries. Gilbert C, Rahi J, Eckstein M, O'Sullivan J, Foster A. Lancet. 1997;350:12&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9217713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preterm-associated visual impairment and estimates of retinopathy of prematurity at regional and global levels for 2010. Blencowe H, Lawn JE, Vazquez T, Fielder A, Gilbert C. Pediatr Res. 2013;74 Suppl 1:35&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3873709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24366462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The incidence and course of retinopathy of prematurity: findings from the early treatment for retinopathy of prematurity study. Good WV, Hardy RJ, Dobson V, Palmer EA, Phelps DL, Quintos M, Tung B. Pediatrics. 2005;116:15&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15995025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retinopathy of prematurity. Chen J, Smith LE. Angiogenesis. 2007;10:133&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17332988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retinopathy of prematurity-incidence today. Zin A, Gole GA. Clin Perinatol. 2013;40:185&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23719304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggressive posterior retinopathy of prematurity in infants &#x2265; 1500 g birth weight. Sanghi G, Dogra MR, Katoch D, Gupta A. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2014;62:254&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4005248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24618495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retinopathy of prematurity. Hellstr&#xf6;m A, Smith LE, Dammann O. Lancet. 2013;382:1445&#x2013;1457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4389630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23782686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A cohort study of transcutaneous oxygen tension and the incidence and severity of retinopathy of prematurity. Flynn JT, Bancalari E, Snyder ES, et al. N Engl J Med. 1992;326:1050&#x2013;1054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1549150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High or low oxygen saturation and severe retinopathy of prematurity: a meta-analysis. Chen ML, Guo L, Smith LE, Dammann CE, Dammann O. Pediatrics. 2010;125:0&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4016714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20498174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The International Classification of Retinopathy of Prematurity revisited. Arch Ophthalmol. 2005;123:991&#x2013;999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16009843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retinopathy of prematurity in India - what can we learn from the polio legacy? Athikarisamy SE, Vinekar A, Patole S. Lancet Reg Health Southeast Asia. 2023;14:100210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10363497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37492414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An update on retinopathy of prematurity (ROP) Dogra MR, Katoch D, Dogra M. Indian J Pediatr. 2017;84:930&#x2013;936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28674824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retinopathy of prematurity. Chawla D, Agarwal R, Deorari A, Paul VK, Chandra P, Azad RV. Indian J Pediatr. 2012;79:501&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20978871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retinopathy of prematurity in a tertiary care center--incidence, risk factors and outcome. Chaudhari S, Patwardhan V, Vaidya U, Kadam S, Kamat A. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19179740/ Indian Pediatr. 2009;46:219&#x2013;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19179740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retinopathy of prematurity as a major cause of severe visual impairment and blindness in children in schools for the blind in Guadalajara city, Mexico. Zepeda-Romero LC, Barrera-de-Leon JC, Camacho-Choza C, et al. Br J Ophthalmol. 2011;95:1502&#x2013;1505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21653214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retinopathy of prematurity in Asian Indian babies weighing greater than 1250 grams at birth: ten year data from a tertiary care center in a developing country. Vinekar A, Dogra MR, Sangtam T, Narang A, Gupta A. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17699940/ Indian J Ophthalmol. 2007;55:331&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2636032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17699940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk factors of threshold retinopathy of prematurity. Dutta S, Narang S, Narang A, Dogra M, Gupta A. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15297681/ Indian Pediatr. 2004;41:665&#x2013;671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15297681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of expansion of telemedicine screening for retinopathy of prematurity in India. Vinekar A, Mangalesh S, Jayadev C, Gilbert C, Dogra M, Shetty B. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2017;65:390&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5565892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28573995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathogenesis of retinopathy of prematurity. Smith LE. Semin Neonatol. 2003;8:469&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15001119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>