<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41771949</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Functional training versus conventional physiotherapy for postpartum pelvic girdle pain: a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-41258-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to evaluate the efficacy of functional training in alleviating postpartum pelvic girdle pain (PGP). A total of 40 patients diagnosed with postpartum PGP who received outpatient rehabilitation treatment in our department between July 2023 and June 2024 were enrolled. Participants were randomly assigned to either the experimental group or the control group (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;20 in each group) using a random number table. The control group received routine pelvic floor physical therapy, while the experimental group received additional functional training based on the standard treatment protocol. The two groups were compared in terms of Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) scores, Pelvic Girdle Questionnaire (PGQ) scores, surface electromyographic (sEMG) values of the pelvic floor muscles based on the Glazer protocol-specifically the mean and root mean square (RMS) values across five phases (pre-resting, phasic contraction, tonic contraction, endurance contraction, post-resting), and the angle difference in the Active Straight Leg Raise (ASLR) test. All 40 patients completed the study. There were no statistically significant differences between the two groups in baseline characteristics, including age, height, weight, BMI, parity, and neonatal birth weight (P&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). The experimental group showed a significant decrease in the pre-resting and post-resting phases and a substantial increase in phasic contraction, tonic contraction, or endurance contraction phases of the Glazer's sEMG assessment (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). In contrast, the control group showed a significant decrease only in the pre-resting and post-resting phases (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), with no substantial increase in phasic contraction, tonic contraction, or endurance contraction phases (P&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). Before treatment, the control group had significantly higher values in phasic contraction, tonic contraction, and endurance contraction phases compared to the experimental group; however, no significant differences were found between groups after treatment (P&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). The experimental group demonstrated significant improvements in PGQ, VAS, and ASLR angle after treatment (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), with greater efficacy than the control group (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). No significant differences were observed between groups in PGQ and VAS scores prior to treatment, but the experimental group performed better after treatment (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). No significant between-group differences were found in ASLR angle before or after treatment (P&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). Functional training can significantly improve postpartum pelvic girdle pain and enhance pelvic floor muscle function.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Kuannv</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sir Run Run Shaw Hospital, Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pelvic Floor Disease Diagnosis, Treatment, and Rehabilitation Center of SRRSH, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Jinna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sir Run Run Shaw Hospital, Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pelvic Floor Disease Diagnosis, Treatment, and Rehabilitation Center of SRRSH, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jingyi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sir Run Run Shaw Hospital, Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pelvic Floor Disease Diagnosis, Treatment, and Rehabilitation Center of SRRSH, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xihui</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sir Run Run Shaw Hospital, Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pelvic Floor Disease Diagnosis, Treatment, and Rehabilitation Center of SRRSH, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoqi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sir Run Run Shaw Hospital, Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pelvic Floor Disease Diagnosis, Treatment, and Rehabilitation Center of SRRSH, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yangzheng</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sir Run Run Shaw Hospital, Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Zhejiang, China. yangzheng.li@zju.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pelvic Floor Disease Diagnosis, Treatment, and Rehabilitation Center of SRRSH, Hangzhou, China. yangzheng.li@zju.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sir Run Run Shaw Hospital, No. 3, Qingchun East Road, Shangcheng District, Hangzhou, Zhejiang Province, China. yangzheng.li@zju.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic girdle pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postpartum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surface electromyography (sEMG)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41771949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-41258-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-41258-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bergstr&#xf6;m, C., Persson, M. &amp; Mogren, I. Pregnancy-related low back pain and pelvic girdle pain approximately 14 months after pregnancy &#x2013; pain status, self-rated health and family situation. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 14, 48 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uddin, J., Shumi, S. S. &amp; Flatt, J. D. Prevalence and predictors of musculoskeletal pain among pregnant women: A cross-sectional study. Healthcare 13, 2524 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elden, H., Gutke, A., Kjellby-Wendt, G., Fagevik-Olsen, M. &amp; Ostgaard, H.-C. Predictors and consequences of long-term pregnancy-related pelvic girdle pain: A longitudinal follow-up study. BMC Musculoskelet. Disord. 17, 276 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoseph, E. T. et al. Pregnancy-related spinal biomechanics: A review of low back pain and degenerative spine disease. Bioengineering 12, 858 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsson, C. &amp; Nilsson-Wikmar, L. Health-related quality of life and physical ability among pregnant women with and without back pain in late pregnancy. Acta Obstet. Gynecol. Scand. 83, 351&#x2013;357 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quaghebeur, J., Petros, P., Wyndaele, J.-J. &amp; De Wachter, S. Pelvic-floor function, dysfunction, and treatment. Eur. J. Obstet. Gynecol. Reprod. Biol. 265, 143&#x2013;149 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceprnja, D., Chipchase, L., Liamputtong, P. &amp; Gupta, A. This is hard to cope with&#x201d;: The lived experience and coping strategies adopted amongst Australian women with pelvic girdle pain in pregnancy. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth 22, 96 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arab, A. M., Shanbehzadeh, S., Rasouli, O., Amiri, M. &amp; Ehsani, F. Automatic activity of deep and superficial abdominal muscles during stable and unstable sitting positions in individuals with chronic low back pain. J. Bodyw. Mov. Ther. 22, 627&#x2013;631 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman, D. P. &amp; Soto, A. T. Sacroiliac joint dysfunction: Diagnosis and treatment. Am. Fam. Physician 105, 239&#x2013;245 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung, C. J., Tao, F., Senter, C., Ramirez, F. D. &amp; Wong, S. E. Pregnancy-related hip and pelvis musculoskeletal conditions, risk factors, and prevention. Curr. Rev. Musculoskelet. Med. 18, 585&#x2013;598 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson, C. A. et al. The relation between the transversus abdominis muscles, sacroiliac joint mechanics, and low back pain. Spine 27, 399&#x2013;405 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mens, J. M. A. &amp; Pool-Goudzwaard, A. The transverse abdominal muscle is excessively active during active straight leg raising in pregnancy-related posterior pelvic girdle pain: An observational study. BMC Musculoskelet. Disord. 18, 372 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen, L. K., Backhausen, M., Hegaard, H. K. &amp; Juhl, M. Physical exercise and pelvic girdle pain in pregnancy: A nested case&#x2013;control study within the danish national birth cohort. Sexual &amp; Reproductive Healthcare 6, 198&#x2013;203 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenport, M. H. et al. Exercise for the prevention and treatment of low back, pelvic girdle and lumbopelvic pain during pregnancy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Br. J. Sports Med. 53, 90&#x2013;98 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldabe, D. et al. Management of women with pregnancy-related pelvic girdle pain: An international delphi study. Physiotherapy 115, 66&#x2013;84 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ElDeeb, A. M., Abd-Ghafar, K. S., Ayad, W. A. &amp; Sabbour, A. A. Effect of segmental stabilizing exercises augmented by pelvic floor muscles training on women with postpartum pelvic girdle pain: A randomized controlled trial. J. Back Musculoskelet. Rehabil. 32, 693&#x2013;700 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majchrzycki, M. et al. Application of osteopathic manipulative technique in the treatment of back pain during pregnancy. Ginekol. Pol. 86, 224&#x2013;228 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teymuri, Z., Hosseinifar, M. &amp; Sirousi, M. The effect of stabilization exercises on pain, disability, and pelvic floor muscle function in postpartum lumbopelvic pain: A randomized controlled trial. Am. J. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 97, 885&#x2013;891 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puri, S. N., Fating, T. &amp; Dhage, P. P. The impact of functional stability exercises on alleviating pelvic girdle pain in pregnancy: A review. Cureus 15, e48769 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehsani, F., Sahebi, N., Shanbehzadeh, S., Arab, A. M. &amp; ShahAli, S. Stabilization exercise affects function of transverse abdominis and pelvic floor muscles in women with postpartum lumbo-pelvic pain: A double-blinded randomized clinical trial study. Int. Urogynecol. J. 31, 197&#x2013;204 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetanat, S., ShahAli, S., Dadgoo, M., Noorizadeh Dehkordi, S. &amp; Naghian Fesharaki, M. Effect of motor control training and breathing exercises on pain, disability and core muscle activity in women with postpartum lumbopelvic pain: A study protocol for randomised controlled trial study. BMJ Open 15, e093691 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostgaard, H. C., Zetherstr&#xf6;m, G., Roos-Hansson, E. &amp; Svanberg, B. Reduction of back and posterior pelvic pain in pregnancy. Spine 19, 894&#x2013;900 (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cong, H. et al. Cross-cultural adaptation, reliability, and validity of a Chinese version of the pelvic girdle questionnaire. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth 21, 470 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glazer, H. I., Romanzi, L. J. &amp; Polaneczky, M. Pelvic floor muscle surface electromyography. Reliability and clinical predictive validity.. J. Reprod. Med. 44(9), 779&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.3109/01674829909075592 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagevik Ols&#xe9;n, M. et al. Validation of self-administered tests for screening for chronic pregnancy-related pelvic girdle pain. BMC Musculoskelet. Disord. 22, 237 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermani, E., Mittal, R. &amp; Weeks, A. Pelvic girdle pain and low back pain in pregnancy: A review. Pain Pract.&#x202f;: Off. J. World Inst. Pain 10, 60&#x2013;71 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addula, S. R., Khan, Z., Ramaswamy, Y. &amp; Veeramachaneni, P. Blockchain-enabled healthcare optimization: enhancing security and decision-making using the mother optimization algorithm. 0&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos, F. F. et al. Prevention of low back and pelvic girdle pain during pregnancy: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials with GRADE recommendations. Physiotherapy 118, 1&#x2013;11 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vesting, S., Gutke, A. &amp; de Baets, L. Educating women to prevent and treat low back and pelvic girdle pain during and after pregnancy: A systematized narrative review. Ann. Med. 57, 2476046 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Sullivan, P. B. &amp; Beales, D. J. Diagnosis and classification of pelvic girdle pain disorders, part 2: Illustration of the utility of a classification system via case studies. Man. Ther. 12, e1-12 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okanishi, N., Kito, N., Akiyama, M. &amp; Yamamoto, M. Spinal curvature and characteristics of postural change in pregnant women. Acta Obstet. Gynecol. Scand. 91, 856&#x2013;861 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro Lira, S. O., de Soares Sousa, V. P. &amp; Viana, E. Therapeutic exercise versus other modalities for prevention and treatment of low back, pelvic girdle, and lumbopelvic pain during pregnancy: A review protocol. PLoS One 17, e0274471 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heo, M.-Y., Kim, K., Hur, B.-Y. &amp; Nam, C.-W. The effect of lumbar stabilization exercises and thoracic mobilization and exercises on chronic low back pain patients. J. Phys. Ther. Sci. 27, 3843&#x2013;3846 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodges, P. W., Sapsford, R. &amp; Pengel, L. H. M. Postural and respiratory functions of the pelvic floor muscles. Neurourol. Urodyn. 26, 362&#x2013;371 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oleksy, &#x141; et al. The reliability of pelvic floor muscle bioelectrical activity (sEMG) assessment using a multi-activity measurement protocol in young women. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 18, 765 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, S. et al. Effects of functional magnetic stimulation combined with pelvic floor muscle training on cerebral hemodynamics and brain functional connectivity in women with postpartum pelvic floor dysfunction: A randomized controlled trial. Int. J. Womens Health 17, 4631&#x2013;4647 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiri, R., Coggon, D. &amp; Falah-Hassani, K. Exercise for the prevention of low back and pelvic girdle pain in pregnancy: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Eur. J. Pain (lond Engl) 22, 19&#x2013;27 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son, M. S. et al. Effects of dynamic neuromuscular stabilization on diaphragm movement, postural control, balance and gait performance in cerebral palsy. Neurorehabilitation 41, 739&#x2013;746 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher, D. et al. CONSORT 2010 explanation and elaboration: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. Int. J. Surg. (Lond Engl). 10, 28&#x2013;55 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copay, A. G., Subach, B. R., Glassman, S. D., Polly, D. W. &amp; Schuler, T. C. Understanding the minimum clinically important difference: A review of concepts and methods. Spine J. 7, 541&#x2013;546 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly, A. M. The minimum clinically significant difference in visual analogue scale pain score does not differ with severity of pain. Emerg. Med. J. 18, 205&#x2013;207 (2001).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>