<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41487186</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>51</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Petrogenesis of Late Permian Mafic Rocks in the Western Guangxi Area, SW China: Implications for the Emeishan Mantle Plume Magmatism.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>63179</StartPage><EndPage>63188</EndPage><MedlinePgn>63179-63188</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.5c09264</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Mafic rocks in western Guangxi exhibit pronounced spatiotemporal correlation with the Emeishan Large Igneous Province (ELIP), providing critical constraints on its magmatic distribution, petrogenetic mechanisms, and evolutionary history. This study presents zircon U-Pb geochronology, whole-rock geochemistry, and Sr-Nd isotopic data for Tianlin mafic rocks from the outer zone of the ELIP. These rocks yield a concordant zircon U-Pb age of 258.3 Ma, contemporaneous with the main eruptive phase of the ELIP. Geochemically, they comprise a high-Ti series (TiO<sub>2</sub> = 2.79-4.74 wt %; Ti/Y = 507-1229), exhibiting ocean-island basalt (OIB)-like chondrite-normalized REE patterns but subtle negative Nb-Ta-Zr-Hf anomalies on primitive mantle-normalized diagrams. Moderately enriched Sr-Nd isotopic signatures [(<sup>87</sup>Sr/<sup>86</sup>Sr)<sub>i</sub> = 0.705522-0.705891; &#x3b5;Nd-(t) = +0.43 to +0.81] indicate derivation from an enriched mantle source. Integrating regional geology with these data, we propose that interaction between the Late Permian Emeishan mantle plume and Neoproterozoic oceanic slab generated the ELIP's compositional diversity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2810-2987</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangxi Laboratory on the Study of Coral Reefs in the South China Sea &amp; School of Marine Sciences, Guangxi University, Nanning 530004, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12664</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zhenhao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangxi Laboratory on the Study of Coral Reefs in the South China Sea &amp; School of Marine Sciences, Guangxi University, Nanning 530004, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12664</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Yaqi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangxi Laboratory on the Study of Coral Reefs in the South China Sea &amp; School of Marine Sciences, Guangxi University, Nanning 530004, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12664</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41487186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12756774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c09264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ernst R. E., Youbi N.. How Large Igneous Provinces affect global climate, sometimes cause mass extinctions, and represent natural markers in the geological record. Palaeogeogr., Palaeoclimatol., Palaeoecol. 2017;478:30&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1016/j.palaeo.2017.03.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.palaeo.2017.03.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H. B., Zhang Z. C., Santosh M., L&#xfc; L. S., Han L., Liu W.. Late Permian basalts in the Yanghe area, eastern Sichuan Province, SW China: Implications for the geodynamics of the Emeishan flood basalt province and Permian global mass extinction. J. Asian Earth Sci. 2017;134:293&#x2013;308. doi: 10.1016/j.jseaes.2016.11.029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jseaes.2016.11.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y. G., Chung S. L., Jahn B. M., Wu G. Y.. Petrologic and geochemical constraints on the petrogenesis of Permian-Triassic Emeishan flood basalts in southwestern China. Lithos. 2001;58(3&#x2013;4):145&#x2013;168. doi: 10.1016/S0024-4937(01)00055-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0024-4937(01)00055-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He B., Xu Y. G., Chung S. L., Xiao L., Wang Y.. Sedimentary evidence for a rapid, kilometer-scale crustal doming prior to the eruption of the Emeishan flood basalts. Earth Planet. Sci. Lett. 2003;213(3&#x2013;4):391&#x2013;405. doi: 10.1016/S0012-821X(03)00323-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0012-821X(03)00323-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung S. L., Jahn B. M. J. G.. Plume-lithosphere interaction in generation of the Emeishan flood basalts at the Permian-Triassic boundary. Geology. 1995;23(10):889&#x2013;892. doi: 10.1130/0091-7613(1995)023&lt;0889:PLIIGO&gt;2.3.CO;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1130/0091-7613(1995)023&lt;0889:PLIIGO&gt;2.3.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou M. F., Malpas J., Song X. Y., Robinson P. T., Sun M., Kennedy A. K., Lesher C. M., Keays R. R.. A temporal link between the Emeishan large igneous province (SW China) and the end-Guadalupian mass extinction. Earth Planet. Sci. Lett. 2002;196(3&#x2013;4):113&#x2013;122. doi: 10.1016/S0012-821X(01)00608-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0012-821X(01)00608-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He B., Xu Y. G., Huang X. L., Luo Z. Y., Shi Y. R., Yang Q. J., Yu S. Y.. Age and duration of the Emeishan flood volcanism, SW China: Geochemistry and SHRIMP zircon U-Pb dating of silicic ignimbrites, post-volcanic Xuanwei Formation and clay tuff at the Chaotian section. Earth Planet. Sci. Lett. 2007;255(3&#x2013;4):306&#x2013;323. doi: 10.1016/j.epsl.2006.12.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsl.2006.12.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y. N., Xue S. C., Klemd R., Yang L., Zhao F., Wang Q. F.. Late Permian plume and Neoproterozoic subduction-modified mantle interaction: Insights from geochronology and Sr-Nd-O isotopes of mafic dikes of the western Emeishan large igneous province. Am. J. Sci. 2022;322(8):993&#x2013;1018. doi: 10.2475/08.2022.02.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2475/08.2022.02</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu S. Y., Song X. Y., Chen L. M.. Interaction between mantle plume and subduction-modified lithospheric mantle: Geochemical evidence from the picritic lavas from the Emeishan large igneous province. Chem. Geol. 2024;648:121964. doi: 10.1016/j.chemgeo.2024.121964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemgeo.2024.121964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Zhang Z. C., Zhang R. X., Zhu J., Cheng Z. G., Santosh M.. Role of slab-derived fluids in the Emeishan Large Province. Geol. Soc. Am. Bull. 2025;137:4161&#x2013;4170. doi: 10.1130/B38200.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1130/B38200.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q. J., Ren Z. Y., Xia X. P., Zhang L., Yang Q., Yuan C.. Water Content and Hydrogen Isotopes of Olivine-Hosted Melt Inclusions in the Dali Picrites, SW China: Reassessing the Role of Water in the Formation of the Emeishan Large Igneous Province. J. Geophys. Res.: Solid Earth. 2023;128(11):e2023JB027547. doi: 10.1029/2023JB027547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2023JB027547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin H., Wu X. K., Qin H. F., Li C. M., Li Y. K., Su H. M., Holwell D. A., Zhang D. Y.. Contribution from ancient subducted slab to the Emeishan Large Igneous Province: Constraints from the petrogenesis of mafic intrusions in the western Guangxi area, South China. Lithos. 2023;446&#x2013;447:107131. doi: 10.1016/j.lithos.2023.107131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lithos.2023.107131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Z. J., Zhong H., Zhu W. G., Hu W. J.. Mantle plume-subducted oceanic slab interaction contributes to geochemical heterogeneity of the Emeishan large igneous province. Chem. Geol. 2022;611:121117. doi: 10.1016/j.chemgeo.2022.121117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemgeo.2022.121117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu L. S., Cawood P. A., Du Y. S., Zhu D. C., Lai Z. Q., Wang Q., Yang J.. OIB-type mafic-ultramafic rocks in South Guangxi, South China: A record of interaction between Paleo-Tethys subduction and Emeishan large Igneous Province. Lithos. 2024;468-469:107497. doi: 10.1016/j.lithos.2024.107497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lithos.2024.107497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng F. C., Tian Y. L., Kerr A. C., Wang W., Wu Z. P., Xu Q., Du Q., Zhou Y. Q., Liu J. Q.. Geochemistry and petrogenesis of Late Permian basalts from the Sichuan Basin, SW China: Implications for the geodynamics of the Emeishan mantle plume. J. Asian Earth Sci. 2023;241:105477. doi: 10.1016/j.jseaes.2022.105477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jseaes.2022.105477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X. J., Liang Q. D., Li Z. L., Castillo P. R., Shi Y., Xu J. F., Huang X. L., Liao S., Huang W. L., Wu W. N.. Origin of Permian extremely high Ti/Y mafic lavas and dykes from Western Guangxi, SW China: Implications for the Emeishan mantle plume magmatism. J. Asian Earth Sci. 2017;141:97&#x2013;111. doi: 10.1016/j.jseaes.2016.09.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jseaes.2016.09.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai S. C., Qin J. F., Li Y. F., Li S. Z., Santosh M.. Permian high Ti/Y basalts from the eastern part of the Emeishan Large Igneous Province, southwestern China: Petrogenesis and tectonic implications. J. Asian Earth Sci. 2012;47:216&#x2013;230. doi: 10.1016/j.jseaes.2011.07.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jseaes.2011.07.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia W. J., Yan Q. R., Xiang Z. J., Xia L., Jiang W., Li X. J., Zhou B., Deng L.. Baddeleyite and zircon U-Pb dating of Badu diabase in the Nanpanjiang Basin and its tectonic significance. Acta Geosci. Sin. 2019;40(2):265&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y. S., Gao S., Hu Z. C., Gao C. G., Zong K. Q., Wang D. B.. Continental and Oceanic Crust Recycling-induced Melt-Peridotite Interactions in the Trans-North China Orogen: U-Pb Dating, Hf Isotopes and Trace Elements in Zircons from Mantle Xenoliths. J. Petrol. 2010;51(1&#x2013;2):537&#x2013;571. doi: 10.1093/petrology/egp082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/petrology/egp082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludwig, K. R. ISOPLOT 3.00: A Geochronological Toolkit for Microsoft Excel.; Berkeley Geochronology Center: California, Berkeley, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J., Liu Y. S., Yang Y. H., Hu Z. C.. Calibration and correction of LA-ICP-MS and LA-MC-ICP-MS analyses for element contents and isotopic ratios. Solid Earth Sci. 2016;1(1):5&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1016/j.sesci.2016.04.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sesci.2016.04.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thirlwall M. F.. Long-term reproducibility of multicollector Sr and Nd isotope ratio analysis. Chem. Geol. 1991;94(2):85&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1016/S0009-2541(10)80021-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0009-2541(10)80021-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C. F., Li X. H., Li Q. L., Guo J. H., Li X. H., Yang Y. H.. Rapid and precise determination of Sr and Nd isotopic ratios in geological samples from the same filament loading by thermal ionization mass spectrometry employing a single-step separation scheme. Anal. Chim. Acta. 2012;727:54&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1016/j.aca.2012.03.040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aca.2012.03.040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22541823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Tang S. H., Zhu X. K., Pan C. X.. Production and Certification of the Reference Material GSB 04&#x2013;3258&#x2013;2015 as a 143Nd/144Nd Isotope Ratio Reference. Geostand. Geoanal. Res. 2017;41(2):255&#x2013;262. doi: 10.1111/ggr.12151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ggr.12151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winchester J., Floyd P.. Geochemical discrimination of different magma series and their differentiation products using immobile element. Chem. Geol. 1977;20:325&#x2013;343. doi: 10.1016/0009-2541(77)90057-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0009-2541(77)90057-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou M. F., Zhao J. H., Qi L., Su W. C., Hu R. Z.. Zircon U-Pb geochronology and elemental and Sr-Nd isotope geochemistry of Permian mafic rocks in the Funing area, SW China. Contrib. Mineral. Petrol. 2006;151(1):1&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1007/s00410-005-0030-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00410-005-0030-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, S. S. ; McDonough, W. F. . Chemical and Isotopic Systematics of Oceanic Basalt: Implications for Mantle Composition and Processes; Geological Society of London Special Publications, 1989; Vol. 42, pp 313&#x2013;345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polat A., Frei R., Deng H., Yang X. M., Sotiriou P.. Anatomy of a Neoarchean continental arc-backarc system in the Cross Lake-Pipestone Lake region, northwestern Superior Province, Canada. Precambrian Res. 2022;370:106556. doi: 10.1016/j.precamres.2021.106556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.precamres.2021.106556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudnick, R. L. ; Gao, S. . Composition of the Continental Crust. In Treatise on Geochemistry; Elsevier, 2003; Vol. 3, pp 1&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson J. F. G., Maitre R. W. L.. Upper mantle amphiboles and micas and TiO2, K2O, and P2O5 abundances and 100 Mg/(Mg + Fe2+) ratios of common basalts andandesites: implications for modal mantle metasomatism and undepleted mantle compositions. J. Petrol. 1987;28:37&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1093/petrology/28.1.37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/petrology/28.1.37</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu D. C., Mo X. X., Wang L. Q., Zhao Z. D., Liao Z. L.. Hotspot-ridge interaction for the evolution of Neo-Tethys: insights from the Late Jurassic-Early Cretaceous magmatism in southern Tibet. Acta Petrol. Sin. 2008;24(2):225&#x2013;237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearce J. A.. Geochemical fingerprinting of oceanic basalts with applications to ophiolite classification and the search for Archean oceanic crust. Lithos. 2008;100(1&#x2013;4):14&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1016/j.lithos.2007.06.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lithos.2007.06.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearce, J. A. Trace Element Characteristics of Lavas from Destructive Plate Boundaries. In Orogenic Andesites and Related Rocks; Thorpe, R. S. , Ed.; Wiley: Chichester, U.K., 1982; pp 528&#x2013;548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao L., Xu Y. G., Mei H. J., Zheng Y. F., He B., Pirajno F.. Distinct mantle sources of low-Ti and high-Ti basalts from the western Emeishan large igneous province, SW China: implications for plume-lithosphere interaction. Earth Planet. Sci. Lett. 2004;228(3&#x2013;4):525&#x2013;546. doi: 10.1016/j.epsl.2004.10.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsl.2004.10.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie D., O&#x2019;Nions R. K.. The source regions of ocean island basalts. J. Petrol. 1995;36:133&#x2013;159. doi: 10.1093/petrology/36.1.133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/petrology/36.1.133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobolev A. V., Hofmann A. W., Kuzmin D. V., Yaxley G. M., Arndt N. T., Chung S. L., Danyushevsky L. V., Elliott T., Frey F. A., Garcia M. O., Gurenko A. A., Kamenetsky V. S., Kerr A. C., Krivolutskaya N. A., Matvienkov V. V., Nikogosian I. K., Rocholl A., Sigurdsson I. A., Sushchevskaya N. M., Teklay M.. The amount of recycled crust in sources of mantle-derived melts. Science. 2007;316(5823):412&#x2013;417. doi: 10.1126/science.1138113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1138113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17395795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson M. G., Hart S. R., Koppers A. A. P., Staudigel H., Konter J., Blusztajn J., Kurz M., Russell J. A.. The return of subducted continental crust in Samoan lavas. Nature. 2007;448(7154):684&#x2013;687. doi: 10.1038/nature06048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature06048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17687322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kepezhinskas P., McDermott F., Defant M. J., Hochstaedter A., Drummond M. S., Hawkesworth C. J., Koloskov A., Maury R. C., Bellon H.. Trace element and Sr&#x2013;Nd&#x2013;Pb isotopic constraints on a three&#x2013;component model of Kamchatka Arc petrogenesis. Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta. 1997;61(3):577&#x2013;600. doi: 10.1016/S0016-7037(96)00349-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0016-7037(96)00349-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson K. T. M.. Experimental determination of partition coefficients for rare earth and high-field-strength elements between clinopyroxene, garnet, and basaltic melt at high pressures. Contrib. Mineral. Petrol. 1998;133(1&#x2013;2):60&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1007/s004100050437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004100050437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green N. L.. Influence of slab thermal structure on basalt source regions and melting conditions: REE and HFSE constraints from the Garibaldi volcanic belt, northern Cascadia subduction system. Lithos. 2006;87(1&#x2013;2):23&#x2013;49. doi: 10.1016/j.lithos.2005.05.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lithos.2005.05.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z. C., Mao J. W., Cai J. H., Kusky T. M., Zhou G., Yan S. H., Zhao L.. Geochemistry of picrites and associated lavas of a Devonian island arc in the northern Junggar terrane, Xinjiang (NW China): Implications for petrogenesis, arc mantle sources and tectonic setting. Lithos. 2008;105(3&#x2013;4):379&#x2013;395. doi: 10.1016/j.lithos.2008.05.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lithos.2008.05.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldanmaz E., Pearce J. A., Thirlwall M. F., Mitchell J. G.. Petrogenetic evolution of late Cenozoic, post-collision volcanism in western Anatolia, Turkey. J. Volcanol. Geotherm. Res. 2000;102(1&#x2013;2):67&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1016/S0377-0273(00)00182-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0377-0273(00)00182-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J. H., Sun J. F., Chen F., Wilde S. A., Wu F. Y.. Sources and petrogenesis of late triassic dolerite dikes in the liaodong peninsula: Implications for post-collisional lithosphere thinning of the eastern North China Craton. J. Petrol. 2007;48(10):1973&#x2013;1997. doi: 10.1093/petrology/egm046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/petrology/egm046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y. N., Wang Q. F., Xue S. C., Santosh M., Wang T. Y., Chai H.. Permian-Triassic tectonic evolution of the Ailaoshan orogenic belt in SW China: insights from magmatic records. Int. Geol. Rev. 2024;66(4):833&#x2013;854. doi: 10.1080/00206814.2023.2212275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00206814.2023.2212275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J., Xia X. P., Lai C. K., Zhou M. L., Ma P. F.. First Identification of Late Permian Nb-Enriched Basalts in Ailaoshan Region (SW Yunnan, China): Contribution From Emeishan Plume to Subduction of Eastern Paleotethys. Geophys. Res. Lett. 2019;46(5):2511&#x2013;2523. doi: 10.1029/2018GL081687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2018GL081687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J., Xia X. P., Wang Q., Spencer C. J., He B., Lai C. K.. Low-&#x3b4;18O A-type granites in SW China: Evidence for the interaction between the subducted Paleotethyan slab and the Emeishan mantle plume. GSA Bull. 2022;134(1&#x2013;2):81&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1130/B35929.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1130/B35929.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y. N., Wang Q. F., Deng J., Xue S. C., Li C. S., Ripley E. M.. Late Permian-Early Triassic mafic dikes in the southwestern margin of the South China block: Evidence for Paleo-Pacific subduction. Lithos. 2021;384&#x2013;385:105994. doi: 10.1016/j.lithos.2021.105994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lithos.2021.105994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Lin W., Faure M., Nguyen V. V., Meng L. T., Chu Y., Wei W., Thu H. L. T., Lepvrier C., Vu T. V., Li Q. L., Wang H., Chen Z. C., Wu L., Wang F.. Correlation among the Ailaoshan-Song Ma-Song Chay orogenic belts and implications for the evolution of the eastern Paleo-Tethys Ocean. Tectonophysics. 2022;843:229618. doi: 10.1016/j.tecto.2022.229618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tecto.2022.229618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin W., Wang Y., Liu F., Meng L. T., Wu Q. Y., Guo Z., Wei W., Chu Y., Li J. Y., Wang Q. C., Faure M., Nguyen V. V.. Indochina orogenic belt and related geodynamics. Sci. China Earth Sci. 2025;68(6):1691&#x2013;1715. doi: 10.1007/s11430-024-1499-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11430-024-1499-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cawood P. A., Wang W., Zhao T. Y., Xu Y. J., Mulder J. A., Pisarevsky S. A., Zhang L. M., Gan C. S., He H. Y., Liu H. C., Qi L., Wang Y. J., Yao J. L., Zhao G. C., Zhou M. F., Zi J. W.. Deconstructing South China and consequences for reconstructing Nuna and Rodinia. Earth-Sci. Rev. 2020;204:103169. doi: 10.1016/j.earscirev.2020.103169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.earscirev.2020.103169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Y., Zheng H., He Z. Y., De Grave J., Li H., Tang Z. Y., Lash G. G., Kang P. X.. Reassessing early to mid-Neoproterozoic (&#x223c;885&#x2013;720 Ma) tectonic evolution of the southwestern Jiangnan Orogen: A detrital zircon perspective. Precambrian Res. 2024;410:107482. doi: 10.1016/j.precamres.2024.107482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.precamres.2024.107482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>