<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41640819</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2589-5141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of hand surgery global online</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hand Surg Glob Online</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Current Gaps and Future Directions in Brachial Plexus, Upper-Extremity and Lower-Extremity Nerve Injuries (Nerve SPACE 2025).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100935</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100935</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100935</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jhsg.2025.100935</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Treatment of peripheral nerve injury remains one of the most challenging aspects of reconstructive surgery. Functional outcomes remain inconsistent, high-quality evidence is limited, and major knowledge gaps persist.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="WHERE ARE WE NOW?" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">When evaluating patients for peripheral nerve injury, the treating physician must ascertain several critical factors to help inform decision-making, including the timing, mechanism, localization, and severity of the injury. Current algorithms rely on history, physical examination, electrodiagnostic studies, imaging, and occasionally operative exploration to establish a diagnosis. The surgeon must decide if the injury will recover spontaneously or if further operative intervention is indicated to achieve the best possible functional outcome. Accurate prognostication remains challenging secondary to the difficulty grouping patients into homogenous cohorts based on patient and injury characteristics, as well as heterogenous outcome measures. Intraoperatively, determining both the severity and zone of injury remains challenging. Surgical treatment strategies include neurolysis, primary repair, nerve grafting, nerve transfer, or tendon transfers. Functional outcomes assessment is currently performed using Medical Research Council muscle grading, range of motion measures, and various sensory measures, which remain subjective with inconsistent intraobserver and interobserver reliability. Nerve-specific patient reported outcomes measures remain limited.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="WHERE DO WE NEED TO GO?" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Diagnostic improvements are needed to more quickly and accurately define injury severity and determine which patients will benefit from surgical intervention. Intraoperatively, accurate determination of both the zone of injury and the functional status of the proximal nerve is also needed. Reproducible outcome measures that can be easily adopted across multiple institutions are needed to facilitate high-quality evidence that can help guide treatment decisions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="HOW DO WE GET THERE?" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Multicenter collaborative efforts are needed to focus clinical research priorities using reproducible diagnostic criteria to accurately define injury severity, establish consistency in surgical techniques and treatment algorithms, and accurately and reproducibly measure outcomes. Further translational efforts in imaging, biomaterials, and basic science research are also needed. By aligning research priorities with patient-centered outcomes, the field can begin to close the gap between surgical innovation and functional recovery.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blum</LastName><ForeName>Ethan</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Washington University in St. Louis School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wright</LastName><ForeName>David J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, University of California, Irvine School of Medicine, Irvine, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yusha Katie</ForeName><Initials>YK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, University of Washington, Seattle, WA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dy</LastName><ForeName>Christopher J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, University of Washington, Seattle, WA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Hand Surg Glob Online</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101759126</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2589-5141</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brachial plexus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lower extremity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nerve surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Peripheral nerve injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Upper extremity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Research reported in this publication was supported by the National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases of the National Institutes of Health under Award Number R13AR085496. The content is solely the responsibility of the authors and does not necessarily represent the official views of the National Institutes of Health. Dr Dy declares research support from the National Institutes of Health, Orthopaedic Research and Education Foundation, American Foundation for Surgery of the Hand, and Checkpoint Surgical. Dr Dy receives fees for speaking engagements from Johnson &amp; Johnson/DePuy Synthes and Checkpoint Surgical and is on the medical advisory board for OrthoCell. The other authors have no other relevant conflicts to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41640819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12865621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhsg.2025.100935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2589-5141(25)00255-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Padovano W.M., Dengler J., Patterson M.M., et al. Incidence of nerve injury after extremity trauma in the United States. Hand (N Y) 2022;17(4):615&#x2013;623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9274890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33084377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill J.R., Lanier S.T., Brogan D.M., Dy C.J. Management of adult brachial plexus injuries. J Hand Surg Am. 2021;46(9):778&#x2013;788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34158206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seiler J.G., III, Desai M.J., Payne S.H. Tendon transfers for radial, median, and ulnar nerve palsy. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2013;21(11):675&#x2013;684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24187037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith B.W., Sakamuri S., Spain D.A., Joseph J.R., Yang L.J., Wilson T.J. An update on the management of adult traumatic nerve injuries-replacing old paradigms: a review. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2019;86(2):299&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30278019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright DJ. Current gaps in evidence and knowledge: upper extremity nerve injury&#x2013;what questions need to be asked? Paper presented at: Nerve SPACE Conference. Nerve SPACE Conference. May 9-10, 2025 St. Louis, MO.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He B., Zhu Z., Zhu Q., et al. Factors predicting sensory and motor recovery after the repair of upper limb peripheral nerve injuries. Neural Regen Res. 2014;9(6):661&#x2013;672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4146230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25206870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon T. The physiology of neural injury and regeneration: the role of neurotrophic factors. J Commun Disord. 2010;43(4):265&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20451212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felici N., Alban A. Timing of surgery in peripheral nerve injury of the upper extremity. J Hand Surg Eur Vol. 2024;49(6):712&#x2013;720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38641934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray K.M., Burkat A.J., Arney L.A., Peterman N.J., Mandala S.R., Capito A.E. Timing and predictors of upper extremity peripheral nerve reconstruction. JPRAS Open. 2025;44:308&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12018019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40271482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKay B.J., Cox C.T., Valerio I.L., et al. Evidence-based approach to timing of nerve surgery: a review. Ann Plast Surg. 2021;87(3):e1&#x2013;e21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8560160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33833177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox I.K., Mackinnon S.E. Adult peripheral nerve disorders: nerve entrapment, repair, transfer, and brachial plexus disorders. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2011;127(5):105e&#x2013;118e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3864586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21532404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malessy M.J., van Duinen S.G., Feirabend H.K., Thomeer R.T. Correlation between histopathological findings in C-5 and C-6 nerve stumps and motor recovery following nerve grafting for repair of brachial plexus injury. J Neurosurg. 1999;91(4):636&#x2013;644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10507386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberle J.W., Antoniadis G., Rath S.A., Richter H.P. Value of nerve action potentials in the surgical management of traumatic nerve lesions. Neurosurgery. 1997;41(6):1337&#x2013;1342. discussion 1342&#x2013;1344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9402585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dy C.J., Garg R., Lee S.K., Tow P., Mancuso C.A., Wolfe S.W. A systematic review of outcomes reporting for brachial plexus reconstruction. J Hand Surg Am. 2015;40(2):308&#x2013;313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7079817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25510158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carey-Ewend A.G., Goldfarb J.H., Randall Z.D., Brogan D.M., Dy C.J. The current state of outcome measurements after peripheral nerve injury: a systematic review. J Hand Surg Glob Online. 2025;7(2):192&#x2013;195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11962904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40182860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu KY. Current gaps in evidence and knowledge: lower extremity nerve injury. Paper presented at: Nerve SPACE Conference. Paper presented at: Nerve SPACE Conference. May 9-10, 2025 St. Louis, MO.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon T. Peripheral nerve regeneration and muscle reinnervation. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(22):8652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7697710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33212795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieber R.L., Frid&#xe9;n J. Functional and clinical significance of skeletal muscle architecture. Muscle Nerve. 2000;23(11):1647&#x2013;1666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11054744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackay M.J., Ayres J.M., Harmon I.P., Tarakemeh A., Brubacher J., Vopat B.G. Traumatic peroneal nerve injuries: a systematic review. JBJS Rev. 2022;10(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35020680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols D.S., Fenton J., Cox E., et al. Surgical interventions for lumbosacral plexus injuries: a systematic review. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2022;10(8)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9400934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36032367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg S.P., Hassan A.M., Patel A.A., et al. Outcomes of tibial nerve repair and transfer: a structured evidence-based systematic review and meta-analysis. J Foot Ankle Surg. 2021;60(6):1280&#x2013;1289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34366221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Head L.K., M&#xe9;dor M.C., Karir A., Wolff G., Boyd K.U. Impact of body mass index and comorbidities on outcomes in upper extremity nerve transfers. J Reconstr Microsurg. 2021;37(9):713&#x2013;719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33984870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karir A., Head L.K., M&#xe9;dor M.C., Wolff G., Boyd K.U. Elevated body mass index negatively impacts recovery of shoulder abduction strength in triceps motor branch to axillary nerve transfers. Hand (N Y) 2023;18(1_suppl):36S&#x2013;42S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9896274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35236161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Socolovsky M., Di Masi G., Bonilla G., Malessy M. Spinal to accessory nerve transfer in traumatic brachial plexus palsy: is body mass index a predictor of outcome ? Acta Neurochir (Wien) 2014;156(1):159&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24146182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klifto K.M., Azoury S.C., Gurno C.F., Card E.B., Levin L.S., Kovach S.J. Treatment approach to isolated common peroneal nerve palsy by mechanism of injury: systematic review and meta-analysis of individual participants' data. J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg. 2022;75(2):683&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34801427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore A.M., Bettlach C.R., Tung T.T., West J.M., Russo S.A. Lower extremity nerve transfers in acute flaccid myelitis patients: a case series. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2021;9(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8376396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34422521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubelski D., Pennington Z., Tuffaha S., Moore A., Belzberg A.J. Sciatic-to-femoral nerve end-to-end coaptation for proximal lower extremity function in patients with acute flaccid myelitis: technical note and review of the literature. Oper Neurosurg. 2021;21(1):20&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33733670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doi K., Hattori Y., Maruyama A., et al. Acute flaccid myelitis: mid-term clinical course of knee extension paralysis and outcomes of nerve transfer. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2024;106(20):1876&#x2013;1887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38815052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferris S., Maciburko S.J. Partial tibial nerve transfer to tibialis anterior for traumatic peroneal nerve palsy. Microsurgery. 2017;37(6):596&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28449390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seruya M. Anatomical and technical considerations in fascicular nerve transfers for foot drop. J Reconstr Microsurg. 2025;41(1):19&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38485168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathieu L., Addas B.M.J., Irimura S.C., Oberlin C., Belkheyar Z. Management of sciatic nerve defects: lessons learned and proposal for a new strategy. Ann Plast Surg. 2020;84(5):559&#x2013;564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31855866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dy CJ. Adult brachial plexus injury: current gaps in evidence and knowledge. Paper presented at: Nerve SPACE Conference. May 9-10, 2025 St. Louis, MO.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dy C.J., Brogan D.M., Loeffler B.J., et al. Pain interference prior to and 1 year after surgery for adult traumatic brachial plexus injury. J Hand Surg Am. 2024;49(12):1196&#x2013;1202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39297827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancuso C.A., Lee S.K., Saltzman E.B., et al. Development of a questionnaire to measure impact and outcomes of brachial plexus injury. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2018;100(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29406348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dy C.J., Baty J., Saeed M.J., Olsen M.A., Osei D.A. A population-based analysis of time to surgery and travel distances for brachial plexus surgery. J Hand Surg Am. 2016;41(9):903&#x2013;909.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5004775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27570225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris M.T., Daluiski A., Dy C.J. A thematic analysis of online discussion boards for brachial plexus injury. J Hand Surg Am. 2016;41(8):813&#x2013;818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27311862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christy M.N., Dy C.J., Gaston R.G., et al. Variation in recommended treatment strategies among American surgeons for actual adult traumatic brachial plexus injury cases. J Hand Surg Am. 2025;50(9):1131.e1&#x2013;1131.e9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39570220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>