<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41275015</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-2959</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>197</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental monitoring and assessment</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Monit Assess</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Carbon stock dynamics in juniper woodlands are jointly influenced by socio-ecological and environmental variables in the monsoon-shadow zone of the eastern Hindu Kush: insights for climate change mitigation strategies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1364</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1364</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10661-025-14787-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In the eastern Hindu Kush, juniper woodlands play a vital role in sustaining montane dryland ecosystems, thereby acting as significant carbon sinks. We investigated the spatial dynamics of both aboveground carbon stock (AGCS) and soil organic carbon (SOC) in relation to environmental variables and disturbance regimes. Cluster analysis identified three distinct woodland types, each exhibiting significant structural diversity, with low to moderate stem densities (318-492 stems ha<sup>-1</sup>) and basal area (12-20.2&#x202f;m<sup>2</sup>&#xa0;ha<sup>-1</sup>) (ANOVA, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.03). The overall AGCS was low, ranging from 8&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2 to 14.2&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1&#xa0;Mg C ha<sup>-1</sup>, with significant variation among the woodland types (ANOVA, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.03), while SOC stock ranged from 19 to 25&#xa0;Mg C ha<sup>-1</sup>. In total, the amount of CO<sub>2</sub> sequestered by the woodlands was estimated at 105-134&#xa0;Mg CO&#x2082; ha<sup>-1</sup>. Structural attributes, soil silt, phosphorus, and water availability were identified as the primary drivers explaining a substantial portion of AGCS. In contrast, temperature, precipitation, and soil CaCO<sub>3</sub> had a secondary influence, followed by negative impacts of soil pH, sand percentage, topography, and geographic coordinates. Similarly, soil electrical conductivity, phosphorus, and potassium were positive determinants of the SOC stock, whereas humidity was negatively correlated. Notably, AGCS was highest in the least disturbed communities and exhibited a robust negative relationship with disturbance intensity (R<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.25, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.005). This study highlights the interconnectedness of socio-ecological and environmental factors in determining carbon density. It also emphasizes the importance of protecting degraded ecosystems through afforestation, woodland conservation, and community-based management to reduce the impacts of climate change.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Din</LastName><ForeName>Nasir Ud</ForeName><Initials>NU</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-7981-7736</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Botany, University of Malakand, Dir Lower, PO Box 18800, Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Nasrullah</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0592-0255</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Botany, University of Malakand, Dir Lower, PO Box 18800, Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Pakistan. nasrullah.uom@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Monit Assess</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8508350</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0167-6369</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012987">Soil</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7440-44-0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002244">Carbon</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057231" MajorTopicYN="Y">Climate Change</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018653" MajorTopicYN="Y">Juniperus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004784" MajorTopicYN="Y">Environmental Monitoring</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012987" MajorTopicYN="N">Soil</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002244" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carbon</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065928" MajorTopicYN="Y">Forests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057965" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carbon Sequestration</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007194" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">India</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017753" MajorTopicYN="N">Ecosystem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aboveground carbon stock</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eastern Hindu Kush</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Juniper woodlands</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Socio-ecological drivers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Soil organic carbon</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval: All authors have read, understood, and have complied as applicable with the statement on &#x201c;Ethical responsibilities of Authors&#x2019; as found in the Instructions for Authors&#x201d;. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41275015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10661-025-14787-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10661-025-14787-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, S., Jia, H., Chen, Z., Li, Q., Yin, D., Israr, M., Hayat, W., Bilal, H., Ahmed, R., &amp; Ashraf, A. (2021). Effects of climate and land use changes on stream flow of Chitral River basin of northern highland Hindu-Kush region of Pakistan. Journal of Hydro-Environment Research, 38, 53&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jher.2021.08.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jher.2021.08.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akay, A. O., Akg&#xfc;l, M., Esin, A. I., Demir, M., &#x15e;ent&#xfc;rk, N., &amp; &#xd6;zt&#xfc;rk, T. (2021). Evaluation of occupational accidents in forestry in Europe and Turkey by k-means clustering analysis. Turkish Journal of Agriculture and Forestry, 45(4), 495&#x2013;509. https://doi.org/10.3906/tar-2010-55</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3906/tar-2010-55</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, S., Khan, S. M., Ahmad, Z., Siddiq, Z., Ullah, A., Yoo, S., Han, H., &amp; Raposo, A. (2023). Carbon sequestration potential of different forest types in Pakistan and its role in regulating services for public health. Frontiers in Public Health, 10, Article 1064586. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2022.1064586</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2022.1064586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amir, M., Liu, X., Ahmad, A., Saeed, S., Mannan, A., &amp; Muneer, M. A. (2018). Patterns of biomass and carbon allocation across chronosequence of chir pine (Pinus roxburghii) Forest in Pakistan: Inventory-based estimate. Advances in Meteorology, 2018(1), 3095891. https://doi.org/10.1155/2018/3095891</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/3095891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artaxo, P., Hansson, H. C., Andreae, M. O., B&#xe4;ck, J., Alves, E. G., Barbosa, H. M., Bender, F., Bourtsoukidis, E., Carbone, S., Chi, J., &amp; Decesari, S. (2022). Tropical and boreal forest atmosphere interactions: A review. Tellus. Series B, Chemical and Physical Meteorology, 74, 24&#x2013;163. https://doi.org/10.16993/tellusb.34</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16993/tellusb.34</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai, J., Chen, X., Dobermann, A., Yang, H., Cassman, K. G., &amp; Zhang, F. (2010). Evaluation of NASA satellite- and model-derived weather data for simulation of maize yield potential in China. Agronomy Journal, 102(1), 9&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.2134/agronj2009.0085</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2134/agronj2009.0085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baskent, E. Z. (2020). A framework for characterizing and regulating ecosystem services in a management planning context. Forests, 11(1), Article 102. https://doi.org/10.3390/f11010102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f11010102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batool, F., Bahadur, S., &amp; Long, W. (2024). Soil nutrients determine leaf traits and above-ground biomass in the tropical cloud forest of Hainan Island. Frontiers in Forests and Global Change, 7, Article 1342135. https://doi.org/10.3389/ffgc.2024.1342135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/ffgc.2024.1342135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behera, S. K., Sahu, N., Mishra, A. K., Bargali, S. S., Behera, M. D., &amp; Tuli, R. (2017). Aboveground biomass and carbon stock assessment in Indian tropical deciduous forest and relationship with stand structural attributes. Ecological Engineering, 99, 513&#x2013;524. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoleng.2016.11.046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoleng.2016.11.046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellard, C., Bertelsmeier, C., Leadley, P., Thuiller, W., &amp; Courchamp, F. (2012). Impacts of climate change on the future of biodiversity. Ecology Letters, 15(4), 365&#x2013;377. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1461-0248.2011.01736.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1461-0248.2011.01736.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beretta, A. N., Silbermann, A. V., Paladino, L., Torres, D., Kassahun, D., Musselli, R., &amp; Lamohte, A. G. (2014). Soil texture analyses using a hydrometer: Modification of the Bouyoucos method. Ciencia e Investigaci&#xf3;n Agraria: Revista Latinoamericana De Ciencias De La Agricultura, 41(2), 263&#x2013;271. https://doi.org/10.4067/s0718-16202014000200013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Case, M. J., Johnson, B. G., Bartowitz, K. J., &amp; Hudiburg, T. W. (2021). Forests of the future: Climate change impacts and implications for carbon storage in the Pacific Northwest, USA. Forest Ecology and Management, 482, Article 118886. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foreco.2020.118886</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foreco.2020.118886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatzistathis, T., &amp; Therios, I. (2013). How soil nutrient availability influences plant biomass and how biomass stimulation alleviates heavy metal toxicity in soils: The cases of nutrient use efficient genotypes and phytoremediators, respectively. In Biomass now-cultivation and utilization. IntechOpen. https://doi.org/10.5772/53594</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chisholm, P. J., &amp; Gray, A. N. (2024). Forest carbon sequestration on the west coast, USA: Role of species, productivity, and stockability. PLoS ONE, 19(5), Article e0302823. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0302823</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0302823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark, A. III, Saucier, J. R., &amp; McNab, W. H. (1986). Total-tree weight, stem weight, and volume tables for hardwood species in the southeast.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowther, T. W., Thomas, S. M., Maynard, D. S., Baldrian, P., Covey, K., Frey, S. D., van Diepen, L. T., &amp; Bradford, M. A. (2015). Biotic interactions mediate soil microbial feedbacks to climate change. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 112(22), 7033&#x2013;7038. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1502956112</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1502956112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daget, P., Ahdali, L., &amp; David, P. (1988). Mediterranean bioclimate and its variation in the Palaearctic region. In Mediterranean-type Ecosystems (pp. 139&#x2013;148). Springer Netherlands. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-94-009-3099-5_6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, A., &amp; Zhao, T. B. (2017). Uncertainties in historical changes and future projections of drought. Part I: Estimates of historical drought changes. Climate Change, 144, 519&#x2013;533. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10584-016-1705-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10584-016-1705-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damptey, F. G., Birkhofer, K., Nsiah, P. K., &amp; de la Riva, E. G. (2020). Soil properties and biomass attributes in a former gravel mine area after two decades of forest restoration. Land, 9(6), Article 209. https://doi.org/10.3390/land9060209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/land9060209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Andrade Wagner, M., Bogoni, J. A., &amp; Fiaschi, P. (2022). Myrtaceae richness and distribution across the Atlantic Forest Domain are constrained by geoclimatic variables. Plant Ecology, 223(9), 1079&#x2013;1092. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11258-022-01258-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11258-022-01258-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Frenne, P., Graae, B. J., Rodr&#xed;guez-S&#xe1;nchez, F., Kolb, A., Chabrerie, O., Decocq, G., De Kort, H., De Schrijver, A., Diekmann, M., Eriksson, O., &amp; Gruwez, R. (2013). Latitudinal gradients as natural laboratories to infer species&#x2019; responses to temperature. Journal of Ecology, 101(3), 784&#x2013;795. https://doi.org/10.1111/1365-2745.12074</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1365-2745.12074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeWald, S. J. (2005). Heating with wood: Producing, harvesting and processing firewood. Cooperative Extension, Institute of Agriculture and Natural Resources, University of Nebraska&#x2013;Lincoln.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din, N. U. (2018). Assessment of diversity and conservation-related issues of Juniperus species in District Chitral, Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Pakistan (Unpublished M.Phil. thesis). Department of Botany, Hazara University, Mansehra, Pakistan.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din, N. U., Khan, N., Ullah, R., Okla, M. K., Abdel-Maksoud, M. A., Saleh, I. A., Abu-Harirah, H. A., &amp; AlRamadneh, T. N. (2025). Does pruning affect the structural and ecological productivity of Juniper woodlands in the eastern Hindu Kush? PeerJ, 13, Article e19184. https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.19184</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.19184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dlugokencky, E., Tans, P., Trends in atmospheric carbon dioxide. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, Global Monitoring Laboratory (NOAA/GML). http://www.gml.noaa.gov/gmd/ccgg/trends/global.html . Last accessed: 09 May 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, J., Kaufmann, R. K., Myneni, R. B., Tucker, C. J., Kauppi, P. E., Liski, J., Buermann, W., Alexeyev, V., &amp; Hughes, M. K. (2003). Remote sensing estimates of boreal and temperate forest woody biomass: Carbon pools, sources, and sinks. Remote Sensing of Environment, 84(3), 393&#x2013;410. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0034-4257(02)00130-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0034-4257(02)00130-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ensslin, A., Rutten, G., Pommer, U., Zimmermann, R., Hemp, A., &amp; Fischer, M. (2015). Effects of elevation and land use on the biomass of trees, shrubs and herbs at Mount Kilimanjaro. Ecosphere, 6, 1&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1890/ES14-00492.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1890/ES14-00492.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, Y., Zhou, G., Shi, Y., Du, H., Zhou, Y., &amp; Xu, X. (2013). Effects of terrain on stand structure and vegetation carbon storage of Phyllostachys edulis forest. Science Silvae Sinicae, 49, 177&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, J. Y., Chen, A. P., Peng, C. H., &amp; Zhao, S. Q. (2001). Changes in forest biomass carbon storage in China between 1949 and 1998. Science, 292, 2320&#x2013;2322. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1058629</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1058629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, L., Cong-Qiang, L., Shi-lu, W., &amp; Zheng-jie, Z. (2012). Soil temperature and moisture controls on surface fluxes and profile concentrations of greenhouse gases in karst area in central part of Guizhou Province, Southwest China. Environmental Earth Sciences, 67(5), 1431&#x2013;1439. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12665-012-1588-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-012-1588-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO. (2022). The state of the world&#x2019;s forests 2022. Forest pathways for green recovery and building inclusive, resilient and sustainable economies. FAO. https://doi.org/10.4060/cb9360en</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedlingstein, P., O&#x2019;sullivan, M., Jones, M. W., Andrew, R. M., Hauck, J., Olsen, A., Peters, G. P., Peters, W., Pongratz, J., Sitch, S., &amp; Le Qu&#xe9;r&#xe9;, C. (2020). Global carbon budget 2020. Earth System Science Data Discussions, 1-3. https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-12-3269-2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gartley, K. L. (2011). Recommended methods for measuring soluble salts in soils. In: Recommended Soil Testing Procedures for the Northeastern United States. Northeast Regional Publication, 493, 1864&#x2013;1862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebeyehu, G., Soromessa, T., Bekele, T., &amp; Teketay, D. (2019). Carbon stocks and factors affecting their storage in dry Afromontane forests of Awi Zone, Northwestern Ethiopia. Journal of Ecology and Environment, 43, 1&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10.1186/s41610-019-0105-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41610-019-0105-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghafoor, G. Z., Shahid, M. G., Ali, M., &amp; Ghafoor, N. (2023). Ecosystem services in the changing climate: Calling attention for the conservation of tropical and subtropical forests. In Tropical Forests-Ecology, Diversity and Conservation Status. IntechOpen. https://doi.org/10.5772/intechopen.109800</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbs, H. K., Brown, S., Niles, J. O., &amp; Foley, J. A. (2007). Monitoring and estimating tropical forest carbon stocks: Making REDD a reality. Environmental Research Letters, 2, Article 045023. https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/2/4/045023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-9326/2/4/045023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grieco, E., Vangi, E., Chiti, T., &amp; Collalti, A. (2024). Impacts of deforestation and land use/land cover change on carbon stock dynamics in Jomoro District, Ghana. Journal of Environmental Management, 367, Article 121993. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121993</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gul, J., Muhammad, S., Liu, S. Y., Ullah, S., Ahmad, S., Hayat, H., &amp; Tahir, A. A. (2020). Spatio-temporal changes in the six major glaciers of the Chitral River basin (Hindukush Region of Pakistan) between 2001 and 2018. Journal of Mountain Science, 17(3), 572&#x2013;587. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11629-019-5728-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11629-019-5728-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris, N. L., Gibbs, D. A., Baccini, A., Birdsey, R. A., De Bruin, S., Farina, M., Fatoyinbo, L., Hansen, M. C., Herold, M., Houghton, R. A., &amp; Potapov, P. V. (2021). Global maps of twenty-first century forest carbon fluxes. Nature Climate Change, 11(3), 234&#x2013;240. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41558-020-00976-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41558-020-00976-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heger, A., Becker, J. N., Navas, L. K. V., &amp; Eschenbach, A. (2021). Factors controlling soil organic carbon stocks in hardwood floodplain forests of the lower middle Elbe River. Geoderma, 404, 115389. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geoderma.2021.115389</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoderma.2021.115389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim, T., Tesfay, F., &amp; Geremew, B. (2021). Diversity of woody species and biomass carbon stock in response to exclosure age in central dry lowlands of Ethiopia. The Open Environmental Research Journal, 14, 1&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.2174/2590277602114010001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/2590277602114010001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IEA. (2017). Energy access outlook 2017. International Energy Agency, World Energy Outlook Special Report. https://www.iea.org/reports/energy-access-outlook-2017 . Accessed 09 May 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jhariya, M. K., Bargali, S. S., Swamy, S. L., Kittur, B., Bargali, K., &amp; Pawar, G. V. (2014). Impact of forest fire on biomass and carbon storage pattern of tropical deciduous forests in Bhoramdeo Wildlife Sanctuary, Chhattisgarh. International Journal of Ecology and Environmental Sciences, 40(1), 57&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent, M. (2011). Vegetation description and data analysis: A practical approach. John Wiley &amp; Sons. https://doi.org/10.2307/3451427</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/3451427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, I., Hayat, U., Lushuang, G., Khan, F., Xinyi, H., &amp; Shufan, W. (2024). Association of carbon pool with vegetation composition along the elevation gradients in subtropical forests in Pakistan. Forests, 15(8), Article 1395. https://doi.org/10.3390/f15081395</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f15081395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, I. A., Khan, W. R., Anwar, A., &amp; Nazre, M. (2021). Assessment of above-ground biomass in Pakistan forest ecosystem&#x2019;s carbon pool: A review. Forests, 12(5), 586. https://doi.org/10.3390/f12050586</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f12050586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, N., Ahmed, M., Ahmed, A. J. A. Z., Shaukat, S. S., Wahab, M., Ajaib, M., Siddiqui, M. F., &amp; Nasir, M. (2011). Important medicinal plants of Chitral Gol National Park (CGNP) Pakistan. Pakistan Journal of Botany, 43(2), 797&#x2013;809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, N., Shaukat, S. S., Ahmed, M., &amp; Siddiqui, M. F. (2013). Vegetation&#x2013;environment relationships in the forests of Chitral District, Hindukush range of Pakistan. Journal of Forestry Research, 24(2), 205&#x2013;216. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11676-013-0346-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11676-013-0346-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, N., Nguyen, H. T., Galelli, S., &amp; Cherubini, P. (2022). Increasing drought risks over the past four centuries amidst projected flood intensification in the Kabul River Basin (Afghanistan and Pakistan)&#x2014;Evidence from tree rings. Geophysical Research Letters, 49(24), Article e2022GL100703. https://doi.org/10.1029/2022gl100703</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2022gl100703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H. N., &amp; Park, J. H. (2024). Monitoring of soil EC for the prediction of soil nutrient regime under different soil water and organic matter contents. Applied Biological Chemistry, 67(1), 1. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13765-023-00849-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13765-023-00849-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kindermann, G., Obersteiner, M., Sohngen, B., Sathaye, J., Andrasko, K., Rametsteiner, E., Schlamadinger, B., Wunder, S., &amp; Beach, R. (2008). Global cost estimates of reducing carbon emissions through avoided deforestation. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 105(30), 10302&#x2013;10307. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0710616105</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0710616105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, P., Kumar, A., Patil, M., Hussain, S., &amp; Singh, A. N. (2024). Factors influencing tree biomass and carbon stock in the Western Himalayas, India. Frontiers in Forests and Global Change, 6, Article 1328694. https://doi.org/10.3389/ffgc.2023.1328694</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/ffgc.2023.1328694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Qu&#xe9;r&#xe9;, C., Andrew, R. M., Friedlingstein, P., Sitch, S., Hauck, J., Pongratz, J., Pickers, P. A., Korsbakken, J. I., Peters, G. P., Canadell, J. G., &amp; Arneth, A. (2018). Global carbon budget 2018. Earth System Science Data, 10(4), 2141&#x2013;2194. https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-10-2141-2018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/essd-10-2141-2018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H., Wang, S., Gao, L., &amp; Yu, G. (2007). The carbon storage of the subtropical forest vegetation in central Jiangxi province. Acta Ecologica Sinica, 27, 693&#x2013;704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H., Hu, Y., Liu, G., Sheng, J., Zhang, W., Zhao, H., Kang, H., &amp; Zhou, X. (2023). Responses of biomass accumulation and nutrient utilization along a phosphorus supply gradient in Leymus chinensis. Scientific Reports, 13(1), 5660. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-31402-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-31402-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J., Nie, M., Powell, J. R., Bissett, A., &amp; Pendall, E. (2020). Soil physico-chemical properties are critical for predicting carbon storage and nutrient availability across Australia. Environmental Research Letters, 15(9), Article 094088. https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ab9f7e</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-9326/ab9f7e</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, M., Hong, L., Ye, W., Wang, Z., &amp; Shen, H. (2022a). Phyllosphere bacterial and fungal communities vary with host species identity, plant traits and seasonality in a subtropical forest. Environmental Microbiome, 17(1), 29. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40793-022-00423-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, T., Zou, Y., Liu, Y., Luo, P., Xiong, Q., Lu, H., Lai, C., &amp; Axmacher, J. C. (2022b). Mountain forest biomass dynamics and its drivers in southwestern China between 1979 and 2017. Ecological Indicators, 142, Article 109289. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecolind.2022.109289</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Brando, P. M., Morton, D. C., Lawrence, D. M., Yang, H., &amp; Randerson, J. T. (2022c). Deforestation-induced climate change reduces carbon storage in remaining tropical forests. Nature Communications, 13(1), 1964. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-022-29601-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, J., Crowther, T. W., Picard, N., Wiser, S., Zhou, M., Alberti, G., Schulze, E. D., McGuire, A. D., Bozzato, F., Pretzsch, H., &amp; De-Miguel, S. (2016). Positive biodiversity-productivity relationship predominant in global forests. Science, 354(6309), Article aaf8957. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aaf8957</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aaf8957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lie, Z., Xue, L., &amp; Jacobs, D. F. (2018). Allocation of forest biomass across broad precipitation gradients in China&#x2019;s forests. Scientific Reports, 8(1), 10536. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-28899-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-28899-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyu, G., Wang, X., Huang, X., Xu, J., Li, S., Cui, G., &amp; Huang, H. (2024). Toward a more robust estimation of forest biomass carbon stock and carbon sink in mountainous region: A case study in Tibet, China. Remote Sensing, 16(9), 1481. https://doi.org/10.3390/rs16091481</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs16091481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markesteijn, L., Poorter, L., Bongers, F., Paz, H., &amp; Sack, L. (2011). Hydraulics and life history of tropical dry forest tree species: Coordination of species&#x2019; drought and shade tolerance. New Phytologist, 191(2), 480&#x2013;495. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-8137.2011.03708.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8137.2011.03708.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEwan, R. W., Lin, Y. C., Sun, I. F., Hsieh, C. F., Su, S. H., Chang, L. W., Song, G. Z. M., Wang, H. H., Hwong, J. L., Lin, K. C., &amp; Yang, K. C. (2011). Topographic and biotic regulation of aboveground carbon storage in subtropical broad-leaved forests of Taiwan. Forest Ecology and Management, 262(9), 1817&#x2013;1825. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foreco.2011.07.028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foreco.2011.07.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meena, A., Bidalia, A., Hanief, M., Dinakaran, J., &amp; Rao, K. S. (2019). Assessment of above-and belowground carbon pools in a semi-arid forest ecosystem of Delhi, India. Ecological Processes, 8(1), Article 8. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13717-019-0163-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13717-019-0163-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moser, G., Hertel, D., &amp; Leuschner, C. (2007). Altitudinal change in LAI and stand leaf biomass in tropical montane forests: A transect study in Ecuador and a pan-tropical meta-analysis. Ecosystems, 10, 924&#x2013;935. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10021-007-9063-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10021-007-9063-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhati, G. L., Olago, D., &amp; Olaka, L. (2018). Quantification of carbon stocks in Mount Marsabit Forest Reserve, a sub-humid montane forest in northern Kenya under anthropogenic disturbance. Global Ecology and Conservation, 14, Article e00383. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gecco.2018.e00383</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gecco.2018.e00383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mwakisunga, B., &amp; Majule, A. E. (2012). The influence of altitude and management on carbon stock quantities in Rungwe Forest, southern highland of Tanzania. Open Journal of Ecology. https://doi.org/10.4236/oje.2012.24025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/oje.2012.24025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naeem, U. A., Hashmi, H. N., &amp; Shakir, A. S. (2013). Flow trends in river Chitral due to different scenarios of glaciated extent. KSCE Journal of Civil Engineering, 17(1), 244&#x2013;251. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12205-013-1978-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12205-013-1978-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasrullah, K., Fayaz, A., Kishwar, A., &amp; Shahid, S. (2015). Composition, structure and regeneration dynamics of Olea ferruginea royle forests from Hindukush range of Pakistan. Journal of Mountain Science, 12(3), 647&#x2013;658. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11629-013-2831-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11629-013-2831-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson, D. W., &amp; Sommers, L. E. (1996). Total carbon, organic carbon, and organic matter. In Methods of Soil Analysis: Part 3 Chemical Methods, 5, 961&#x2013;1010. https://doi.org/10.2136/sssabookser5.3.c34</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfc;sser, M., &amp; Dickore, W. B. (2002). A tangle in the triangle: Vegetation map of the eastern Hindukush (Chitral, Northern Pakistan). Erdkunde. https://doi.org/10.3112/erdkunde.2002.01.03</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3112/erdkunde.2002.01.03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nzabarinda, V., Bao, A., Tie, L., Uwamahoro, S., Kayiranga, A., Ochege, F. U., et al. (2025). Expanding forest carbon sinks to mitigate climate change in Africa. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 207, Article 114849. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2024.114849</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2024.114849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pachauri, R. K., Allen, M. R., Barros, V. R., Broome, J., Cramer, W., Christ, R., Church, J. A., Clarke, L., Dahe, Q., Dasgupta, P., Dubash, N. K., Edenhofer, O., Elgizouli, I., Field, C. B., Forster, P., Friedlingstein, P., Fuglestvedt, J., G&#xf3;mez-Echeverri, L., Hallegatte, S., &#x2026; van Ypserle, J. P. (2014). Climate change 2014: Synthesis report. In R. K. Pachauri &amp; L. A. Meyer (Eds.), Contribution of Working Groups I, II and III to the Fifth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change. Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pakistan Bureau of Statistics. (2023). Population and Housing Census 2023. Government of Pakistan. Available at: http://census.pbs.gov.pk . Accessed May 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson, T. R., Brown, S. L., &amp; Birdsey, R. A. (2007). Measurement guidelines for the sequestration of forest carbon. In: General Technical Report NRS-18. US Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Northern Research Station, Newtown Square, 27&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.2737/nrs-gtr-18</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto, E., Cuesta, F., Bernardi, A., Llerena-Zambrano, M., P&#xe9;rez, &#xc1;. J., van der Sande, M. T., Gosling, W. D., &amp; Burgess, K. S. (2023). Determinants of above-ground carbon stocks and productivity in secondary forests along a 3000-m elevation gradient in the Ecuadorian Andes. Plant Ecology &amp; Diversity, 16(3&#x2013;4), 127&#x2013;146. https://doi.org/10.1080/17550874.2023.2274844</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17550874.2023.2274844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qasim, M., &amp; Csaplovics, E. (2023). Comparative study of forest biomass and carbon stocks of Margalla Hills National Park, Pakistan. Forest Science and Technology, 19(3), 139&#x2013;154. https://doi.org/10.1080/21580103.2023.2208141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21580103.2023.2208141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qasim, M., Khan, M., &amp; Rashid, W. (2023). Spatial and temporal analyses of land use changes with special focus on seasonal variation in snow cover in district Chitral; A Hindu Kush mountain region of Pakistan. Remote Sensing Applications: Society and Environment, 29, Article 100902. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rsase.2022.100902</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rsase.2022.100902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, Y., Chin, M. Y., Hoy, Z. X., Lee, C. T., Khan, M., &amp; Woon, K. S. (2023). Pearson correlation analysis between carbon dioxide emissions and socioeconomic factors across nations&#x2019; income groups. Chemical Engineering Transactions, 106, 181&#x2013;186. https://doi.org/10.3303/CET23106031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3303/CET23106031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman, G., Rahman, A. U., Anwar, M. M., Dawood, M., &amp; Miandad, M. (2022). Spatio-temporal analysis of climatic variability, trend detection, and drought assessment in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Pakistan. Arabian Journal of Geosciences, 15(1), Article 81. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12517-021-09382-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-021-09382-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randers, J., &amp; Goluke, U. (2020). An earth system model shows self-sustained thawing of permafrost even if all man-made GHG emissions stop in 2020. Scientific Reports, 10(1), 18456. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-75481-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-75481-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riestra, D., Noellemeyer, E., &amp; Quiroga, A. (2012). Soil texture and forest species condition the effect of afforestation on soil quality parameters. Soil Science, 177, 279&#x2013;287. https://doi.org/10.1097/ss.0b013e318245d0fe</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ss.0b013e318245d0fe</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagar, R., Raghubanshi, A. S., &amp; Singh, J. S. (2003). Tree species composition, dispersion and diversity along a disturbance gradient in a dry tropical forest region of India. Forest Ecology and Management, 186(1&#x2013;3), 61&#x2013;71. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0378-1127(03)00235-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0378-1127(03)00235-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selmants, P. C., Litton, C. M., Giardina, C. P., &amp; Asner, G. P. (2014). Ecosystem carbon storage does not vary with mean annual temperature in Hawaiian tropical montane wet forests. Global Change Biology, 20(9), 2927&#x2013;2937. https://doi.org/10.1111/gcb.12636</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gcb.12636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, C. M., Gairola, S., Baduni, N. P., Ghildiyal, S. K., &amp; Suyal, S. (2011). Variation in carbon stocks on different slope aspects in seven major forest types of temperate region of Garhwal Himalaya, India. Journal of Biosciences, 36(4), 701&#x2013;708. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12038-011-9103-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12038-011-9103-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheshnitsan, S., Odnoralov, G., Tikhonova, E., Gorbunova, N., Sheshnitsan, T., Murariu, O. C., &amp; Caruso, G. (2024). Influence of soil texture on carbon stocks in deciduous and coniferous forest biomass in the forest-steppe zone of Oka-Don Plain. Soil Systems, 8(4), Article 118. https://doi.org/10.3390/soilsystems8040118</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/soilsystems8040118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simegn, T. Y., &amp; Soromessa, T. (2015). Carbon stock variations along altitudinal and slope gradient in the forest belt of Simen Mountains National Park, Ethiopia. American Journal of Environmental Protection, 4, 199. https://doi.org/10.11648/j.ajep.20150404.15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11648/j.ajep.20150404.15</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slik, J. F., Paoli, G., McGuire, K., Amaral, I., Barroso, J., Bastian, M., Blanc, L., Bongers, F., Boundja, P., Clark, C., &amp; Collins, M. (2013). Large trees drive forest aboveground biomass variation in moist lowland forests across the tropics. Global Ecology and Biogeography, 22(12), 1261&#x2013;1271. https://doi.org/10.1111/geb.12092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/geb.12092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, R., Han, X., Yang, Q., Zheng, Z., &amp; Xi, D. (2022). Effects of understory vegetation heterogeneity on soil organic carbon components in Cunninghamia lanceolata plantation. Land, 11(12), Article 2300. https://doi.org/10.3390/land11122300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/land11122300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Z., Shi, P., Li, P., Li, Z., Niu, H., Zu, P., Cao, M., &amp; Jia, Y. (2024). Effects of forest type on carbon storage in the hilly region of Loess Plateau, China. Frontiers in Forests and Global Change, 7, Article 1349047. https://doi.org/10.3389/ffgc.2024.1349047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/ffgc.2024.1349047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart, R. R., Nasir, E., &amp; Ali, S. I. (1972). Flora of West Pakistan: An annotated catalogue of the vascular plants of West Pakistan and Kashmir. Fakhri Printing Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swamy, S. L., Dutt, C. B. S., Murthy, M. S. R., Mishra, A., &amp; Bargali, S. S. (2010). Floristics and dry matter dynamics of tropical wet evergreen forests of Western Ghats, India. Current Science, 99(3), 353&#x2013;364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syed, Z., Ahmad, S., Dahri, Z. H., Azmat, M., Shoaib, M., Inam, A., Qamar, M. U., Hussain, S. Z., &amp; Ahmad, S. (2022). Hydroclimatology of the Chitral River in the Indus Basin under changing climate. Atmosphere, 13(2), Article 295. https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos13020295</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/atmos13020295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toochi, E. C. (2018). Carbon sequestration: How much can forestry sequester CO2? Forest Research and Engineering: International Journal, 2(3), 148&#x2013;150. https://doi.org/10.15406/freij.2018.02.00040</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15406/freij.2018.02.00040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker, C., Brandt, M., Hiernaux, P., Kariryaa, A., Rasmussen, K., Small, J., Igel, C., Reiner, F., Melocik, K., Meyer, J., &amp; Sinno, S. (2023). Sub-continental-scale carbon stocks of individual trees in African drylands. Nature, 615(7950), 80&#x2013;86. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-022-05653-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-022-05653-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sande, M. T., Pe&#xf1;a-Claros, M., Ascarrunz, N., Arets, E. J., Licona, J. C., Toledo, M., &amp; Poorter, L. (2017). Abiotic and biotic drivers of biomass change in a neotropical forest. Journal of Ecology, 105(5), 1223&#x2013;1234. https://doi.org/10.1111/1365-2745.12756</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1365-2745.12756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Schmalz, K. E., Ruz, E. J. H., de Souza, D. A., de Oliveira Jr, A. P., Alvarez, W. D. P., &amp; Salm, R. (2025). Palm community structure association with topography, hydrography and forest density in a remote site in the Iriri river valley, Eastern Amazon. ARPHA Preprints, 6, e148043. https://doi.org/10.3897/arphapreprints.e148043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3897/arphapreprints.e148043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weil, R. R., &amp; Brady, N. C. (2008). The nature and properties of soils (5th ed.). Pearson.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright, I. J., Reich, P. B., Westoby, M., Ackerly, D. D., Baruch, Z., Bongers, F., Cavender-Bares, J., Chapin, T., Cornelissen, J. H., Diemer, M., &amp; Flexas, J. (2004). The worldwide leaf economics spectrum. Nature, 428(6985), 821&#x2013;827. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature02403</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature02403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, L., Yu, G., He, N., Wang, Q., Gao, Y., Wen, D., Li, S., Niu, S., &amp; Ge, J. (2018). Carbon storage in China&#x2019;s terrestrial ecosystems: A synthesis. Scientific Reports, 8, 2806. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-20764-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-20764-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, X., Cheng, P., Zhang, Q., Li, X., He, J., Yan, X., Zhao, W., &amp; Wang, L. (2022). Comparisons of climate change characteristics in typical arid regions of the Northern Hemisphere. Frontiers in Environmental Science, 10, Article 1033326. https://doi.org/10.3389/fenvs.2022.1033326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenvs.2022.1033326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X., Li, T., &amp; Shao, M. A. (2022). Factors controlling deep-profile soil organic carbon and water storage following Robinia pseudoacacia afforestation of the Loess Plateau in China. Forest Ecosystems, 9, Article 100079. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fecs.2022.100079</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fecs.2022.100079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zegeye, H. (2013). Global climate change: causes, impacts and solutions. In S. Workeneh, N. Dechassa, M. Ketema, &amp; A. Belayneh (Eds.), Proceedings of the International Conference on Biodiversity Conservation and Ecosystem Services for Climate Change Mitigation and Sustainable Development (pp. 2&#x2013;15). Haramaya University and United Nations Development Programme.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, R., Wei, Y., Huang, J., Chen, X., &amp; Cai, C. (2021). Soil organic carbon stock and fractional distribution across central-south China. International Soil and Water Conservation Research, 9(4), 620&#x2013;630. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.iswcr.2021.04.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.iswcr.2021.04.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C., Deng, Q., Liu, A., Liu, C., &amp; Xie, G. (2021). Effects of stand structure and topography on forest vegetation carbon density in Jiangxi province. Forests, 12(11), Article 1483. https://doi.org/10.3390/f12111483</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f12111483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L., Luo, T., Liu, X., &amp; Kong, G. (2010). Altitudinal variations in seedling and sapling density and age structure of timberline tree species in the Sergyemla Mountains, Southeast Tibet. Acta Ecologica Sinica, 30(2), 76&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chnaes.2010.03.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chnaes.2010.03.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M., Wang, K., Deng, Z., Liu, H., &amp; Duang, Y. (2014). Factors influencing the spatial distribution of vegetation carbon density in karst landscapes of Northwest Guangxi: A case study based on radial basis function network model. Acta Ecologica Sinica, 34, 3472&#x2013;3479. https://doi.org/10.5846/stxb201308062035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5846/stxb201308062035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X. K., Qi, L. I., Liang, W. J., Zhang, M., Xue-Lian, B. A. O., &amp; Zu-Bin, X. I. E. (2013). Soil nematode response to biochar addition in a Chinese wheat field. Pedosphere, 23(1), 98&#x2013;103. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1002-0160(12)60084-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1002-0160(12)60084-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, H., Chen, Y., Zhu, C., Chen, Y., Yang, Y., Li, W., &amp; Chen, S. (2021). Warming increases the carbon sequestration capacity of Picea schrenkiana in the Tianshan Mountains, China. Forests, 12(8), Article 1066. https://doi.org/10.3390/f12081066</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f12081066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zobayed, S. M. A., Afreen, F., &amp; Kozai, T. (2005). Temperature stress can alter the photosynthetic efficiency and secondary metabolite concentrations in St. John&#x2019;s wort. Plant Physiology and Biochemistry, 43(10&#x2013;11), 977&#x2013;984. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plaphy.2005.07.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.plaphy.2005.07.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>