<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41069932</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2624-8212</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in artificial intelligence</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Artif Intell</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Deep learning for causal inference using low birth weight in midwife-led continuity care intervention in north Shoa zone, Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1484299</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1484299</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1484299</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/frai.2025.1484299</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Low birth weight (LBW), under 2,500&#x202f;g, poses health risks, though not always requiring treatment. Early detection of high-risk pregnancies enables preventive care, improving outcomes for mother and baby. This study aimed to establish cause-and-effect relationships using Causal Deep Learning (CDL) models that reduce bias and estimate heterogeneous treatment effects on LBW in the Midwife-Led Continuity Care (MLCC) intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study used a quasi-experimental study design (August 2019-September 2020) in North Shoa, Ethiopia, and enrolled 1,166 women divided into two groups: one receiving MLCC and the other receiving other professional groups for comprehensive antenatal/postnatal care. The dataset and code are provided in data availability section. Our model combines counterfactual convolutional neural networks to analyze time-based patterns and Bayesian Ridge regression to reduce bias in propensity scores. We use Counterfactual Regression with Wasserstein Distance (CFR-WASS) and Counterfactual Regression with Maximum Mean Discrepancy (CFR-MMD) to balance patient characteristics and improve counterfactual estimates of treatment effects. This approach strengthens causal insights into how MLCC interventions affect LBW outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The Deep neural networks (DNN) model showed strong predictive accuracy for LBW, with 81.3% training and 81.4% testing performance, an area under the curve (AUC) of 0.88, enabling the reliable early identification of high-risk pregnancies. The study found a strong link between meconium aspiration syndrome (MAS) and LBW (<i>p</i>&#x202f;=&#x202f;0.002), but this does not mean MAS directly causes LBW. MAS likely results from fetal distress or other pregnancy complications that may independently affect LBW. While statistical associations exist, clinical causation remains unproven; therefore, the counterfactual analysis showed MLCC could help reduce LBW risk. CFR-WASS achieved high accuracy (84%) while the precision in heterogeneous treatment effect (PEHE&#x202f;=&#x202f;1.006) and the average treatment effect (ATE&#x202f;=&#x202f;0.24), and CFR-MMD PEHE of 1.02, ATE of 0.45, demonstrating potential for tailored treatment strategies. DNN and multilayer perceptrons uniquely identified key neural weights and biases favoring normal birth weight while suppressing LBW predictions, offering interpretable insights for clinical risk assessment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The CFR-WASS/CFR-MMD model strengthens LBW prediction by identifying crucial factors like MAS and healthcare access, while accurate PEHE and ATE estimates support data-driven prenatal care and targeted interventions for healthier outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Moges, Tegegne, Mitku, Tesfahun and Hailemeskel.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moges</LastName><ForeName>Wudneh Ketema</ForeName><Initials>WK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics, College of Science, Bahir Dar University, Bahir Dar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics, College of Science, Debre Berhan University, Debre Berhan, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Data Science, College of Computing, Debre Berhan University, Debre Berhan, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tegegne</LastName><ForeName>Awoke Seyoum</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics, College of Science, Bahir Dar University, Bahir Dar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mitku</LastName><ForeName>Aweke A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics, College of Science, Bahir Dar University, Bahir Dar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Change Institute (GCI), Faculty of Science, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tesfahun</LastName><ForeName>Esubalew</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, College of Health Science, Debre Berhan University, Debre Berhan, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hailemeskel</LastName><ForeName>Solomon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Midwifery, College of Health Science, Debre Berhan University, Debre Berhan, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Artif Intell</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101770551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2624-8212</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">average treatment effect</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">causal deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low birth weight</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">midwife-led continuity care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">precision in estimating heterogeneous treatment effects</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41069932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12504305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frai.2025.1484299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adugna M., Asmare K., Wondim A. (2025). Meconium aspiration syndrome and associated factors among neonates admitted at the neonatal intensive care unit at Northwest Ethiopia comprehensive specialized hospitals, Northwest Ethiopia 2023. BMC Pediatr. 25:167. doi: 10.1186/s12887-024-05181-4, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12887-024-05181-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11881333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40038672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alabbad D. A., Ajibi S. Y., Alotaibi R. B., Alsqer N. K., Alqahtani R. A., Felemban N. M., et al. (2024). Birthweight range prediction and classification: a machine learning-based sustainable approach. Mach. Learn. Knowledge Extract. 6, 770&#x2013;788. doi: 10.3390/make6020036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/make6020036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam M.A., Zaman Sajib M. R. U., Rahman F., Ether S., Hanson M., Sayeed A., et al. (2023). Implication of big data analytics, artificial intelligence, machine learning and deep learning in the public health sector of Bangladesh: a scoping review protocol Open Science Framework.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzubaidi L., Zhang J., Humaidi AJ., Al-Dujaili A., Duan Y., Al-Shamma O., et al. (2021). Review of deep learning: concepts, CNN architectures, challenges, applications, future directions. J. Big Data 8, 1&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1186/s40537-021-00444-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40537-021-00444-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8010506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33816053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arayeshgari M., Najafi-Ghobadi S., Tarhsaz H., Parami S., Tapak L. (2023). Machine learning-based classifiers for the prediction of low birth weight. Healthcare Inform. Res. 29, 54&#x2013;63. doi: 10.4258/hir.2023.29.1.54, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4258/hir.2023.29.1.54</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9932310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36792101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athey S., Imbens G. (2016). Recursive partitioning for heterogeneous causal effects. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 113, 7353&#x2013;7360. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1510489113, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1510489113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4941430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27382149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basile Ibrahim B., Interrante J. D., Fritz A. H., Tuttle M. S., Kozhimannil K. B. (2022). Inequities in availability of evidence-based birth supports to improve perinatal health for socially vulnerable rural residents. Children 9:1077. doi: 10.3390/children9071077, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/children9071077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9324486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35884061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berrevoets J., Kacprzyk K., Qian Z., van der Schaar M. (2024). Causal deep learning: encouraging impact on real-world problems through causality. Foundations and trends&#xae;. Signal Process. 18, 200&#x2013;309. doi: 10.1561/2000000123</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1561/2000000123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bland C., Tonello L., Biganzoli E., Snowdon D., Antuono P., Lanza M., et al. (2020). Advances in artificial neural networks. Adv. Artif. Neural Netw. 2020:119. doi: 10.1136/bmj.m2922</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m2922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos Trujillo O., Perez-Gonzalez J., Medina-Ba&#xf1;uelos V.. (2020). &#x201c;Early prediction of weight at birth using support vector regression&#x201d;. In VIII Latin American conference on biomedical engineering and XLII National Conference on biomedical engineering: proceedings of CLAIB-CNIB 2019, October 2-5, 2019, Canc&#xfa;n, M&#xe9;xico. Springer,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Li G., Ruan Y., Zou L., Wang X., Zhang W. (2013). An epidemiological survey on low birth weight infants in China and analysis of outcomes of full-term low birth weight infants. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth 13, 1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1186/1471-2393-13-242, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2393-13-242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3877972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24370213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curth A., Peck R. W., McKinney E., Weatherall J., van der Schaar M. (2024). Using machine learning to individualize treatment effect estimation: challenges and opportunities. Clin. Pharmacol. Therap. 115, 710&#x2013;719. doi: 10.1002/cpt.3159, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cpt.3159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38124482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Hollander C. J., McCredie V. A., Uleryk E. M., Kucab M., le R. M., Hayosh O., et al. (2025). Breastfeeding support provided by lactation consultants: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA. Pediatrics 179, 508&#x2013;520. doi: 10.1001/jamapediatrics.2024.6810, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2024.6810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11877411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40029627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dandona R., Majumder M., Akbar M., Bhattacharya D., Nanda P., Kumar G. A., et al. (2022). Assessment of quality of antenatal care services in public sector facilities in India. BMJ Open 12:e065200. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2022-065200, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2022-065200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9716787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36456027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson L., Boland M. R. (2021). Towards deep phenotyping pregnancy: a systematic review on artificial intelligence and machine learning methods to improve pregnancy outcomes. Brief. Bioinform. 22:bbaa369. doi: 10.1093/bib/bbaa369, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bib/bbaa369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8424395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33406530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desta M. (2019). &#x201c;Low birth weight and adverse perinatal outcomes,&#x201d; in Childbirth (Alphen aan den Rijn, The Netherlands: IntechOpen; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endalamaw A., Engeda E. H., Ekubagewargies D. T., Belay G. M., Tefera M. A. (2018). Low birth weight and its associated factors in Ethiopia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ital. J. Pediatr. 44, 1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1186/s13052-018-0586-6, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13052-018-0586-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6258299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30477557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engdaw G. T., Tesfaye A. H., Feleke M., Negash A., Yeshiwas A., Addis W., et al. (2023). Effect of antenatal care on low birth weight: a systematic review and meta-analysis in Africa, 2022. Front. Public Health 11:1158809. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2023.1158809, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2023.1158809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10335749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37441651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Z., Kernan K. F., Sriram A., Benos P. V., Canna S. W., Carcillo J. A., et al. (2023). Deep neural networks with knockoff features identify nonlinear causal relations and estimate effect sizes in complex biological systems. GigaScience 12:giad044. doi: 10.1093/gigascience/giad044, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gigascience/giad044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10316696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37395630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez Turienzo C., Rayment-Jones H., Roe Y., Silverio S. A., Coxon K., Shennan A. H., et al. (2021). A realist review to explore how midwifery continuity of care may influence preterm birth in pregnant women. Birth 48, 375&#x2013;388. doi: 10.1111/birt.12547, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/birt.12547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33749001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fikre R., Gubbels J., Teklesilasie W., Gerards S. (2023). Effectiveness of midwifery-led care on pregnancy outcomes in low-and middle-income countries: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth 23:386. doi: 10.1186/s12884-023-05664-9, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-023-05664-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10214693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37237358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebregzabiherher Y., Haftu A., Weldemariam S., Gebrehiwet H. (2017). The prevalence and risk factors for low birth weight among term newborns in Adwa general hospital, northern Ethiopia. Obstet. Gynecol. Int. 2017, 1&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1155/2017/2149156, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2017/2149156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5514323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28744313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh I., Sanyal M. K., Jana R. (2018). &#x201c;An integrated approach incorporating nonlinear dynamics and machine learning for predictive analytics and delving into causal interaction&#x201d; in Intelligent engineering informatics: Proceedings of the 6th international conference on FICTA. ed. Sheng Z. (Boca Raton, FL, USA: Springer; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez-Lumbreras A., Vilaplana-Carnerero C., Lest&#xf3;n V&#xe1;zquez M., Vedia C., Morros R., Giner-Soriano M. (2024). Treatment of hypertension during pregnancy: a cohort of pregnancy episodes from the SIDIAP database, Catalonia, Spain. Front. Pharmacol. 15:1346357. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2024.1346357, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2024.1346357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11215181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38953107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodfellow I., Bengio Y., Courville A. (2016). Deep learning 1. Cambridge: MIT Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopalkrishnan R. (2020). Advances in deep generative modeling for clinical data. Basel, Switzerland: Massachusetts Institute of Technology.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hailemeskel S., Alemu K., Christensson K., Tesfahun E., Lindgren H. (2022). Midwife-led continuity of care improved maternal and neonatal health outcomes in north Shoa zone, Amhara regional state, Ethiopia: a quasi-experimental study. Women Birth 35, 340&#x2013;348. doi: 10.1016/j.wombi.2021.08.008, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wombi.2021.08.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34489211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hailu L. D., Kebede D. L. (2018). Determinants of low birth weight among deliveries at a referral Hospital in Northern Ethiopia. Biomed. Res. Int. 2018, 1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1155/2018/8169615, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/8169615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5937567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29850570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe5;kansson S., Lindblom V., Gottesman O., Johansson FD. (2020). Learning to search efficiently for causally near-optimal treatments. Adv. Neural Inf. Proces. Syst. 33, 1333&#x2013;1344. doi: 10.1111/aogs.14039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aogs.14039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassoun M. H. (1995). Fundamentals of artificial neural networks. Stuttgart, Germany: MIT press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y. (2022). &#x201c;Robust causal learning for the estimation of average treatment effects.&#x201d; In the 2022 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN). IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter P. J., Muthiani Y., N&#xe4;s&#xe4;nen-Gilmore P. K., Koivu A. M., P&#xf6;rtfors P., Bastola K., et al. (2023). A modular systematic review of antenatal interventions to address undernutrition during pregnancy in the prevention of low birth weight. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 117, S134&#x2013;S147. doi: 10.1016/j.ajcnut.2023.01.024, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajcnut.2023.01.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37331760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain H. I., Kamarudin F., Thaker H. M. T., Salem M. A. (2019). Artificial neural network to model managerial timing decision: non-linear evidence of deviation from target leverage. Int. J. Comput. Intell. Syst. 12, 1282&#x2013;1294. doi: 10.2991/ijcis.d.191101.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2991/ijcis.d.191101.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain K., Kothari R. B., Mhaske S. N., Misal G. B. (2020). To study the complications of meconium aspiration syndrome &amp; their outcome about Gestational age &amp; Birth Weight in tertiary health care Centre. VIMS Health Sci. J. 7, 47&#x2013;49. doi: 10.46858/vimshjs.7203</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46858/vimshjs.7203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao L., Wang Y., Liu X., Li L., Liu F., Ma W., et al. (2024). Causal inference meets deep learning: a comprehensive survey. Research 7:0467. doi: 10.34133/research.0467, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34133/research.0467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11384545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39257419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson J. (2022). Maternal micronutrient status as a risk factor for perinatal mortality in a Tanzanian randomized controlled trial. Afr. J. Reprod. Health 26, 38&#x2013;48. doi: 10.29063/ajrh2022/v26i7.5, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29063/ajrh2022/v26i7.5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37585146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kallus N. (2020). Deepmatch: balancing deep covariate representations for causal inference using adversarial training. In international conference on machine learning. PMLR.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassaw A., Kassie Y. T., Kefale D., Azmeraw M., Arage G., Asferi W. N., et al. (2023). Pooled prevalence and its determinants of stunting among children during their critical period in Ethiopia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One 18:e0294689. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0294689, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0294689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10686443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38019780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katiso N. A., Kassa G. M., Fekadu G. A., Kidanemariam Berhe A., Muche A. A. (2020). Prevalence and determinants of low birth weight in Ethiopia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Adv. Public Health 2020, 1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1155/2020/7589483, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/7589483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keles E., Bagci U. (2023). The past, current, and future of neonatal intensive care units with artificial intelligence: a systematic review. NPJ Digit. Med. 6:220. doi: 10.1038/s41746-023-00941-5, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-023-00941-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10682088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38012349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent D. M., Steyerberg E., Van Klaveren D. (2018). Personalized evidence based medicine: predictive approaches to heterogeneous treatment effects. BMJ:k4245. doi: 10.1136/bmj.k4245, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.k4245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6889830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30530757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan W., Zaki N., Masud M. M., Ahmad A., Ali L., Ali N., et al. (2022). Infant birth weight estimation and low birth weight classification in United Arab Emirates using machine learning algorithms. Sci. Rep. 12:12110. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-14393-6, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-14393-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9287292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35840605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiriakidou N., Diou C. (2022). &#x201c;An evaluation framework for comparing causal inference models.&#x201d; In Proceedings of the 12th Hellenic Conference on Artificial Intelligence.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch B. J., Park D. E., Hungate B. A., Liu C. M., Johnson J. R., Price L. B. (2024). Predicting sepsis mortality in an era of pandrug-resistant E. coli through modeling. Commun. Med. 4:278. doi: 10.1038/s43856-024-00693-7, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43856-024-00693-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11671531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39725703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch B. J., Sainburg T., Geraldo Bast&#xed;as P., Jiang S., Sun Y., Foster J. G. (2025). A primer on deep learning for causal inference. Sociol. Methods Res. 54, 397&#x2013;447. doi: 10.1177/00491241241234866</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00491241241234866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koivu A. M., N&#xe4;s&#xe4;nen-Gilmore P. K., Hunter P. J., Muthiani Y., Isoj&#xe4;rvi J., Heimonen O., et al. (2023). Antenatal interventions to address harmful behaviors and psychosocial risk factors in the prevention of low birth weight. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 117, S148&#x2013;S159. doi: 10.1016/j.ajcnut.2022.11.028, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajcnut.2022.11.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37331761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong W., Qiu M., Li M., Xuanyu J. (2022). &#x201c;Causal graph convolutional neural network for emotion recognition.&#x201d; in IEEE Transactions on Cognitive and Developmental Systems.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin A., Lu J., Xuan J., Zhu F., Zhang G. (2020). A causal Dirichlet mixture model for causal inference from observational data. ACM Trans. Intellig. Syst. Technol. 11, 1&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1145/3379500</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3379500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L., Sperrin M., Jenkins D. A., Martin G. P., Peek N. (2021). A scoping review of causal methods enabling predictions under hypothetical interventions. Diagn. Progn. Res. 5, 1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1186/s41512-021-00092-9, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41512-021-00092-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7860039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33536082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling Y., Upadhyaya P., Chen L., Jiang X., Kim Y. (2023). Emulate randomized clinical trials using heterogeneous treatment effect estimation for personalized treatments: methodology review and benchmark. J. Biomed. Inform. 137:104256. doi: 10.1016/j.jbi.2022.104256, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbi.2022.104256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9845190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36455806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y., Zhang X., Fu X., Chen F., Wong K. K. L. (2019). Ensemble machine learning for estimating fetal weight at varying gestational age. Proc. AAAI Conf. Artif. Intell. 33, 9522&#x2013;9527. doi: 10.1609/aaai.v33i01.33019522, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1609/aaai.v33i01.33019522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayberry L. J., Avery M. D., Budin W., Perry S. (2017). Improving maternal and infant outcomes by promoting normal physiologic birth on hospital birthing units. Nurs. Outlook 65, 240&#x2013;241. doi: 10.1016/j.outlook.2017.02.007, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.outlook.2017.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28363309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mbogu H.M., (2023). Improving outcomes in machine learning and data-driven learning systems using structural causal models.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinshausen N. (2018). Causality from a distributional robustness point of view. In the 2018 IEEE data science workshop (DSW). IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moges W. K., Tegegne A. S., Mitku A. A., Tesfahun E., Hailemeskel S. (2025). Causal machine learning models for predicting low birth weight in midwife-led continuity care intervention in north Shoa zone, Ethiopia. BMC Med. Inform. Decis. Mak. 25:64. doi: 10.1186/s12911-025-02917-9, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12911-025-02917-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11806756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39920662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montesinos L&#xf3;pez O. A., Montesinos L&#xf3;pez A., Crossa J. (2022). &#x201c;Fundamentals of artificial neural networks and deep learning&#x201d; in Multivariate statistical machine learning methods for genomic prediction. ed Abdulqader J. (Cham, Switzerland: Springer; ), 379&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36103587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira M.W. L., Rodrigues J., Furtado V., Mavromoustaki C., Kumar N., Woungang I., et al. (2019). Fetal birth weight estimation in high-risk pregnancies through machine learning techniques. In ICC 2019&#x2013;2019 IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC). 2019. IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mose A., Fikadu Y., Zewdie A., Haile K., Shitu S., Wasie Kasahun A., et al. (2023). Pregnant women&#x2019;s perception of midwifery-led continuity care model in Ethiopia: a qualitative study. BMC Womens Health 23:304. doi: 10.1186/s12905-023-02456-3, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-023-02456-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10251613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37291592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahatkar S., et al. (2025). &#x201c;Collating random forest classifier and artificial neural networks for the risk detection of maternal health.&#x201d; In the 2025 International Conference on Computational, Communication and Information Technology (ICCCIT). IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neupane S., Scott S., Piwoz E., Kim S. S., Menon P., Nguyen P. H. (2023). More is not enough: high quantity and high quality antenatal care are both needed to prevent low birthweight in South Asia. PLoS Glob. Public Health 3:e0001991. doi: 10.1371/journal.pgph.0001991, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0001991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10249805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37289728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang B., Nijkamp E., Wu Y. N. (2020). Deep learning with tensorflow: a review. J. Educ. Behav. Stat. 45, 227&#x2013;248. doi: 10.3102/1076998619872761</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/1076998619872761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J. J. H., Harari O., Siden E., Zoratti M., Dron L., Zannat N. E., et al. (2020). Interventions to improve birth outcomes of pregnant women living in low-and middle-income countries: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Gates Open Res. 3:1657. doi: 10.12688/gatesopenres.13081.2, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/gatesopenres.13081.2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7520556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33134854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pattanayak S., Pattanayak J. S., John S. (2017). Pro deep learning with tensorflow. Washington, DC, USA: Springer.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramachandra V. (1803). Deep learning for causal inference. ArXiv preprint 149:2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Y., Wu D., Tong Y., L&#xf3;pez-DeFede A., Gareau S. (2023). Issue of data imbalance on low birthweight baby outcomes prediction and associated risk factors identification: establishment of benchmarking key machine learning models with data rebalancing strategies. J. Med. Internet Res. 25:e44081. doi: 10.2196/44081, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/44081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10267797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37256674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reza T. B., Salma N. (2024). Prediction and feature selection of low birth weight using machine learning algorithms. J. Health Popul. Nutr. 43:157. doi: 10.1186/s41043-024-00647-8, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41043-024-00647-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11471022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39396025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roslina E. (2020). Relationship between antenatal care and low birth weight (LBW) incidence in Indonesia: secondary data analysis of IDHS 2017. Indian J. Public Health Res. Dev. 11:1179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samek W., Montavon G., Lapuschkin S., Anders C. J., Muller K. R. (2021). Explaining deep neural networks and beyond: a review of methods and applications. Proc. IEEE 109, 247&#x2013;278. doi: 10.1109/JPROC.2021.3060483</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JPROC.2021.3060483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandall J., Soltani H., Gates S., Shennan A., Devane D., Cochrane Pregnancy and Childbirth Group (2016). Midwife-led continuity models versus other models of care for childbearing women. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2016:4667. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD004667, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD004667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8663203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27121907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandall J., Fernandez C., Turienzo, Devan D., Soltani H., Gillespie P., et al. (2024). Midwife continuity of care models versus other models of care for childbearing women. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2024:CD004667. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD004667.pub6, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD004667.pub6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11005019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38597126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shalit U., Johansson F. D., Sontag D. (2017). Estimating individual treatment effect: generalization bounds and algorithms. in the international conference on machine learning. PMLR.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi C., Blei D., Veitch V. (2019). Adapting neural networks for the estimation of treatment effects. Adv. Neural Inf. Proces. Syst. 32, 1&#x2013;44. doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1905.12741</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1905.12741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmelink R., Neppelenbroek E., Pouwels A., van der Lee N., Pajkrt E., Ziesemer K. A., et al. (2025). Understanding how midwife-led continuity of care can be implemented and under what circumstances: a realist review. BMJ Open 15:e091968. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2024-091968, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2024-091968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11842984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39979052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunarni N., Noviati E., Kurniawan R., Mulyati N.&#x2019;. (2018). Kelengkapan Antenatal Care (ANC) Dengan Kejadian BBLR. Jurnal Kesehatan STIKES Muhammadiyah Ciamis 5, 42&#x2013;51. doi: 10.52221/jurkes.v5i2.35</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52221/jurkes.v5i2.35</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao J., Yuan Z., Sun L., Yu K., Zhang Z. (2021). Fetal birthweight prediction with measured data by a temporal machine learning method. BMC Med. Inform. Decis. Mak. 21, 1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1186/s12911-021-01388-y, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12911-021-01388-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33494752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taye M. M. (2023). Understanding of machine learning with deep learning: architectures, workflow, applications and future directions. Computers 12:91. doi: 10.3390/computers12050091</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/computers12050091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tekeba B., Techane M. A., Workneh B. S., Zegeye A. F., Gonete A. T., Ahmed M. A., et al. (2024). Determinants of preterm birth among reproductive age women in sub-Saharan Africa: evidence from the most recent demographic and health survey data-2019-2022. PLoS One 19:e0305810. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0305810, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0305810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11198911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38917208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uauy R., Corvalan C., Casanello P., Kuzanovic J. (2013). &#x201c;Intervention strategies for preventing low birthweight in developing countries: Importance of considering multiple interactive factors&#x201d; in Maternal and child nutrition: The first 1,000 days (Washington, DC, USA: Karger Publishers; ), 31&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23887102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uniyal P., Kalra B., Wasim S. (2021). A study of profile of meconium aspiration syndrome in relation with birth weight and gestational age of newborns and their immediate outcome. Int. J. Contemp. Pediatr. 8, 1021&#x2013;1026. doi: 10.18203/2349-3291.ijcp20212041, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18203/2349-3291.ijcp20212041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voon S. T., Lay J. T. S., San W. T. W., Shorey S., Lin S. K. S. (2017). Comparison of midwife-led care and obstetrician-led care on maternal and neonatal outcomes in Singapore: a retrospective cohort study. Midwifery 53, 71&#x2013;79. doi: 10.1016/j.midw.2017.07.010, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.midw.2017.07.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28778037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wachamo T. M., Bililign Yimer N., Bizuneh A. D. (2019). Risk factors for low birth weight in hospitals of north Wello zone, Ethiopia: a case-control study. PLoS One 14:e0213054. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0213054, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0213054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6426181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30893344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whata A., Chimedza C. (2022). Evaluating uses of deep learning methods for causal inference. IEEE Access 10, 2813&#x2013;2827. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3140189</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3140189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widiyaningrum A. N., Pamungkasari E. P., Murti B. (2020). Meta-analysis: amniotic meconium and low birth weight as predictors of asphyxia in newborns. J. Matern. Child Health 5, 590&#x2013;600. doi: 10.26911/thejmch.2020.05.05.12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26911/thejmch.2020.05.05.12.</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2021). WHO antenatal care recommendations for a positive pregnancy experience. Nutritional interventions update: Zinc supplements during pregnancy. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34432398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Wang W., Mao B., Qiu J., Guo H., Yi B., et al. (2022). Maternal folic acid supplementation, dietary folate intake, and low birth weight: a birth cohort study. Front. Public Health 10:844150. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2022.844150, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2022.844150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9218084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35757618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu M. H., Kang D. R. (2019). Improving causal inference in observational studies: propensity score matching. Cardiovasc. Prevent. Pharmacotherapy 1, 57&#x2013;62. doi: 10.36011/cpp.2019.1.e6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36011/cpp.2019.1.e6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zawadzki R. S., Grill J. D., Gillen D. L., and for the Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease Neuroimaging Initiative (2023). Frameworks for estimating causal effects in observational settings: comparing confounder adjustment and instrumental variables. BMC Med. Res. Methodol. 23:122. doi: 10.1186/s12874-023-01936-2, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-023-01936-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10201752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37217854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zenebe A., Tegegne K. T., Bifato B., Assefa A. A. (2021). Association between iron and folic acid supplementation and birth weight in Ethiopia: systemic review and Meta-analysis. Bull. Natl. Res. Cent. 45:135. doi: 10.1186/s42269-021-00595-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42269-021-00595-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y.-F., Zhang H., Lipton Z. C., Li L. E., Xing E. P. (2022). Exploring transformer backbones for heterogeneous treatment effect estimation. ArXiv preprint 2202. doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2202.01336</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2202.01336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>