<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41915980</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-7103</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>717</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of colloid and interface science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Colloid Interface Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Machine learning-guided design of cellulose-based hydrogels for predictive swelling and impact resistance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>140401</StartPage><MedlinePgn>140401</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jcis.2026.140401</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0021-9797(26)00578-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Robust hydrogel composites were fabricated through a one-step chemical gelation route using carboxymethyl cellulose, acrylamide, and a fixed gold nanoparticle-containing formulation platform to obtain impact-resistant materials with composition-dependent swelling and mechanical responses. Increasing cellulose content progressively reinforced the network, raising tensile strength from 3.68 to 10.79&#xa0;MPa, increasing compressive strength by 3.3&#xa0;MPa, and enabling complete resilience recovery of 100%, while dynamic mechanical analysis showed concurrent increases in storage modulus and loss modulus, consistent with improved energy storage and dissipation. Wettability and swelling were likewise governed by network density, with cellulose-rich formulations showing lower equilibrium water uptake and higher water contact angles, whereas swelling remained stimulus-responsive, decreasing at 65&#xa0;&#xb0;C relative to 25&#xa0;&#xb0;C and increasing markedly at pH&#xa0;13. Swelling kinetics were well described by Higuchi and Korsmeyer-Peppas behavior, indicating coupled diffusion and network relaxation during water uptake. To predict swelling ratio, a machine learning workflow was implemented using grouped cross-validation that held out complete formulation, pH, and temperature condition groups, with formulation percentage, pH, temperature, and time as inputs. Under this conservative protocol, the random forest model delivered the best mean fold performance, with a mean R<sup>2</sup> of 0.652&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.257, while the aggregated held-out prediction series reached an R<sup>2</sup> of 0.842. The CEL<sub>4</sub> composite also protected glass from shattering in bottle, ball, and hammer impact demonstrations, highlighting strong cushioning behavior. These results establish cellulose-tuned p(CEL/AAm)/Au hydrogel composites as promising protective layers with predictable swelling behavior, while Au nanoparticle-specific contributions remain to be isolated by future control studies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ejeromedoghene</LastName><ForeName>Onome</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State and Local Joint Engineering Laboratory for Novel Functional Polymeric Materials, College of Chemistry, Chemical Engineering and Materials Science, Soochow University, 215123 Suzhou, Jiangsu Province, PR China. Electronic address: oejeromedoghene@suda.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akor</LastName><ForeName>Ephraim</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Sciences, Faculty of Natural Sciences, Redeemer's University P.M.B 230 Ede, Osun State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Huaguang</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State and Local Joint Engineering Laboratory for Novel Functional Polymeric Materials, College of Chemistry, Chemical Engineering and Materials Science, Soochow University, 215123 Suzhou, Jiangsu Province, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oderinde</LastName><ForeName>Olayinka</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Nile University of Nigeria, Plot 681, Cadastral Zone C-OO, Research &amp; Institution Area, Jabi Airport Bypass, Abuja, FCT, 900001, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hussain</LastName><ForeName>Muzammal</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Southeast University, Jiangning District, Nanjing, Jiangsu Province 211189, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zexin</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State and Local Joint Engineering Laboratory for Novel Functional Polymeric Materials, College of Chemistry, Chemical Engineering and Materials Science, Soochow University, 215123 Suzhou, Jiangsu Province, PR China. Electronic address: zhangzx@suda.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Colloid Interface Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0043125</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0021-9797</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chemical gelation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrogel composites</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Impact resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Swelling kinetics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41915980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2026.140401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0021-9797(26)00578-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>