<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41741469</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Wetland water quality status and suitability for human intended uses in Angolelana Tara District, North Shewa Zone, Central Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">11063</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-35485-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Recognizing the relationship between human well-being and water chemistry is central to identify and manage sources of human stress in multifunctional wetlands to set proper management implications. Despite the paramount services provided by wetlands, these ecosystems in Ethiopia remain marginalized due to anthropogenic activities. The studied wetlands are also threatened by human activities, but little is known in science concerning the water quality and its suitability status. Hence, the main purpose of this study was to examine the Hilsenoff family biotic index (H-FBI) and analyze the water physicochemical parameters to determine the water quality and associated suitability status of Burana Natural Wetland (BNW) and Totosie Semi-Artificial Wetland (TSAW) for irrigation, fishery, and domestic uses. For this study, a total of 56 quadrates were mapped to collect water and other environmental data. The data was analyzed using CANOCO and SPSS software. Accordingly, the average values of water and air temperature, pH, DO, and EC were taken from BNW and found to be 20.43 <sup>0</sup>C, 18.92 <sup>0</sup>C, 8.25, 7.64 mgL<sup>-1</sup>, and 110.80 &#x3bc;Scm<sup>-1</sup>, respectively. These parameters were also done for the TSAW and qualified low records, and hence relatively better water quality. Likewise, the Cl<sup>-</sup>, Na<sup>+</sup>, K<sup>+</sup>, NH<sub>4</sub>-N and TN concentrations were 0.84 meqL<sup>-1</sup>, 0.37 meqL<sup>-1</sup>, 0.12 meqL<sup>-1</sup>, 2.02 mgL<sup>-1</sup>, and 0.02%, respectively in BNW. As compared to the BNW, these parameters were relatively low in TSAW. The NO<sub>3</sub>-N and SRP concentrations in both wetlands were measured and exceeding the standards set for freshwater bodies. The H-FBI values for TSAW and BNW were 5.44 and 7.57, respectively showing their good and poor water quality status. Although robust studies about habitat suitability need to be conducted, the present study roughly revealed the suitability of wetlands&#x2019; water for irrigation, fishery, and domestic uses, except for drinking as verified based on international standards. However, still the two wetlands demand restoration for sustainability.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moges</LastName><ForeName>Admasu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, Debre Beran University, P. O. Box. 445, Debra Berhan, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eyayu</LastName><ForeName>Alamrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1029-5191</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, Debre Tabor University, P. O. Box. 272, Debre Tabor, Ethiopia. azeleke242@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>IFS 12-A-6667</GrantID><Agency>International Foundation for Sciences (IFS)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fishery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Irrigation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Water parameters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Water suitability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wetland ecosystem</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41741469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13044270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-35485-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-35485-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wondie, A. Ecological conditions and ecosystem services of wetlands in the Lake Tana area. <i>Ethiopia. Ecohydrology and Hydrobiology</i><b>18</b>(2), 231&#x2013;244. 10.1016/j.ecohyd.2018.02.002 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecohyd.2018.02.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moges, A. &amp; Mebrate, T. Ecological conditions and ecosystem services of artificial wetlands in semiarid Ethiopian highlands. <i>Inter. J. Ecol.</i><b>2022</b>, 7667611. 10.1155/2022/766761 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/766761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moges, A. &amp; Eyayu, A. Analyzing ecological health, plant diversity and indicator species of wetlands in Ethiopia: Implications for conservation. <i>Wetlands</i><b>45</b>, 91. 10.1007/s13157-025-01977-x (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13157-025-01977-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mereta, S. T., Boets, P., De Meester, L. &amp; Goethals, P. L. M. Development of a multimetric Index based on benthic macroinvertebrates for the assessment of natural wetlands in Southwest Ethiopia. <i>Ecological Indicator</i><b>29</b>, 510&#x2013;521 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2013.01.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moges, A., Beyene, A., Triest, L., Ambelu, A. &amp; Kelbessa, E. Imbalance of ecosystem services of wetlands and the perception of the local community towards their restoration and management in Jimma Highlands, Southwestern Ethiopia. <i>Wetlands</i><b>38</b>, 1087&#x2013;1095. 10.1007/s13157-016-0743-x (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13157-016-0743-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moges, A. &amp; Dibaba, A. Plant biodiversity, wetland indicators, and ecosystem analysis of Human-Made wetlands in central Ethiopia. <i>Inter. J. Ecol.</i><b>2024</b>, 6520568 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/ijec/6520568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raburu, P.O., Okeyo-Owuor, J.B., Kwena, F . Community based approach to the management of Nyando wetland, Lake Victoria basin, Kenya. Kenya Disaster Concern, VIRED, UNDP: Nairobi. 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banderi, A. Water Quality Assessment of Amir Kabir Sugarcane Agro-industry with Respect to Agricultural and Drinking Views. <i>Journal of Environment and Ecology.</i><b>3</b>, 11&#x2013;28 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5296/jee.v3i1.2353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Water Management Institute (IWMI). Wetlands and people. Colombo, SriLanka: International Water Management Institute (IWMI). 32p. 10.5337/2014.202. (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayers R.S., Westcot D.W.Water Quality for Agriculture: <b>Review 1</b>. FAO Irrigation and Drainage Paper 29. Rome, https://www.scribd.com/doc/215866301/Water-Quality-for-Agriculture.(FAO 1985)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Guidelines for Drinking-Water Quality 3<sup>rd</sup> Edition Incorporating the First and Second Addenda. Vol. 1- Recommendations, World Health Organization, Geneva, https://www.academia.edu/23644264/Guidelines_for_Drinking_water_Quality.(2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35417116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DBARC (Debre Berhan Agricultural Research Center). Monthly Rainfall (Mm), Monthly Minimum and Maximum Temperature (<sup>0</sup>C) recorded from 2007&#x2013;2016. Debre Berhan, Ethiopia. (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US EPA. Methods for evaluating wetland condition: using vegetation to assess environmental conditions in wetlands. Office of Water United State Environment Protection Agent, Washington DC (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American People Health Association (APHA). Standard methods of water and wastewater, 21st eds. American People Health Association, Washington DC. (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degefu, F., Lakew, A., Tigabu, Y. &amp; Teshome, K. The water quality degradation of upper Awash River, Ethiopia. <i>EthiopianJ Environ. Stud. Manage.</i><b>6</b> (1), 58&#x2013;66. 10.4314/ejesm.v6i1.7 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ejesm.v6i1.7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abebe, W. B. et al. Ecological Status as the Basis for the Holistic Environmental Flow Assessment of a Tropical Highland River in Ethiopia. <i>Water</i><b>13</b>, 1913. 10.3390/w13141913 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w13141913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriel, W., Lock, K., De Pauw, N. &amp; Goethals, P. L. M. Multimetric macroinvertebrate Index Flanders (MMIF) for biological assessment of rivers and lakes in Flanders (Belgium). <i>Limnologica</i><b>39</b>(40), 199&#x2013;207 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.limno.2009.10.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suarez, D. L. Relationship between pHc and SAR and alternative method for estimating SAR of soil or drainage water. <i>Soil Sci Soc Amer J.</i><b>45</b>(3), 469&#x2013;475 (1981).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2136/sssaj1981.03615995004500030005x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerber, A., Gabriel, M.J.M. Aquatic invertebrates of South Africa Rivers. Institute of Water Quality Study, South Africa. (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard, R. W. Jr. <i>Guide to aquatic maro-invertebrates of the Upper Midwest</i> (University of Minnesota, St. Paul, 2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baye Sitotaw . Assessment of Benthic- Macroinvertebrate structures in relation to Environmental degradation in some Ethiopian Rivers. MSc. Thesis, School of Graduate Studies, Addis Ababa, and University (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilsenhoff, W. L. Rapid field assessment of organic pollution with a family-level biotic index. <i>J. N Am. Benthol Soc.</i><b>7</b>, 65&#x2013;68 (1988).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/1467832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilsenhoff, W. L. Rapid field assessment of organic pollution with a family-level biotic index. <i>J. N. Am. Benthol. Soc.</i><b>7</b>(1), 65&#x2013;68 (1988).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/1467832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leps, J. &amp; Smilauer, P. <i>Multivariate analysis of ecological data using CANOCO</i> (Cambridge University Press, 2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakure, B. Z., Fikadu, S. &amp; Malu, A. Analysis of physicochemical water quality parameters for streams under agricultural, urban and forest land-use types: in the case of gilgel Gibe catchment. <i>Southwest Ethiopia. Applied Water Science</i><b>10</b>, 2034. 10.1007/s13201-020-01318-9 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13201-020-01318-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corry F. Wetland health and importance research program: Development of a tool for assessment of the environmental condition of wetlands using macrophytes. Water Research Commission, ISBN 978&#x2013;1&#x2013;77005&#x2013;936&#x2013;8, Republic of South Africa. (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tampo, L. et al. Benthic Macroinvertebrates as Ecological Indicators: Their Sensitivity to Water Quality and Human Disturbances in a Tropical River. <i>Front. Water</i><b>3</b>, 662765. 10.3389/frwa.2021.662765 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frwa.2021.662765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tekile, A. K. Suitability Assessment of Surface Water Quality for Irrigation: A Case Study of Modjo River. <i>Ethiopia. J. of Environ. Public Health.</i><b>2023</b>, 1482229 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9897910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36742370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsubih, M. et al. Assessing Surface Water Quality for Irrigation Purposes in Some Dams of Asir Region, Saudi Arabia Using Multi-Statistical Modeling Approaches. <i>Water</i><b>14</b>, 1439. 10.3390/w14091439 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w14091439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moges, A. Flora and fauna composition and development of plant-based monitoring tool for the improvement of ecosystem services and ecological state of wetlands of Jimma Highlands, Ethiopia, PhD thesis, Jimma University, Ethiopia. (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sert, B. E. &amp; S&#xf6;&#x11f;&#xfc;t, Z. Assessment of wetlands and water plants within the scope of ecosystem services. CambridgeScholars Publishing, Editors: Efe, R. and &#xd6;zt&#xfc;rk, M. ISBN: ISBN (10): 1-4438-7283-0 ISBN (13): 978-1-4438-7283-6. (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phocailes . Handbook on Pressurized Irrigation Techniques Second Edition, FAO, New Delhi. India.2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Australian and New Zealand Environment and Conservation Council (ANZECC). National water quality management strategy in Australian water quality guidelines for fresh and marine waters. <i>Australia and New Zealand Environment and Conservation Council</i>, Canberra. (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodier J,. Legube B., Merlet N. L&#x2019;Analyse de l&#x2019;eau, 9e &#xe9;dition enti&#xe8;rement mise &#xe0; jour. 2009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eidson, J. P. Water quality. In: (ed Marshall, W. D.) Assessing change in the Edisto River basin: an ecological characterization. Columbia, SC: South Carolina Water Resources Commission; (1993). Report No.: 177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinesly, R. L. &amp; Jones, T. D. Phosphorus in waters from sewage sludge amended lysimeters. <i>Environ. Pollut.</i><b>65</b>, 293&#x2013;309 (1990).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0269-7491(90)90122-S</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15092254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mengiste, W., Tsegaye, D., Dagalo, S. &amp; Yitbareke, T. Spatial and temporal analysis of irrigation water and soil quality in the Achewa small-scale irrigation area. <i>Southwestern Ethiopia. Discover Sustainability</i><b>6</b>, 908. 10.1007/s43621-025-01825-2 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43621-025-01825-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gbolagade, A. A., Muhammed, D. Timothy. &amp; AO.,. Assessment of the suitability of water quality for irrigation in Ogbomoso, Oyo State. <i>GSC Biological and Pharmaceutical Sciences.</i><b>09</b>, 021&#x2013;031 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30574/gscbps.2019.9.2.0191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aregahegn, Z. &amp; Zerihun, M. Study on Irrigation Water Quality in the Rift Valley Areas of Awash River Basin. <i>Ethiopia Appl. Environ. Soil. Sci.</i><b>8844745</b>, 1&#x2013;20. 10.1155/2021/8844745 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/8844745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandaville, S. M. &amp; Dartmouth Benthic macroinvertebrates in freshwaters-taxa tolerance values, metrics, and protocols. NS:Soil &amp; Water Conservation Society of Metro Halifax. (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CSA. Agricultural Sample Survey: Report on Area and Production of Major Crops (Private Peasant Holdings, MeherSeason), 2016/2017. Volume I, Statistical Bulletin 584. Central Statistical Agency (CSA), Addis Ababa (2017). (2009) E.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Guidelines for Drinking Water Quality Recommendation. Vol. 1, World Health Organization, Geneva. http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/dwq /gdwq2v1/ en/index. html. (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayers R.S., Westcot D.W. Water Quality for Agriculture. FAO Irrigation and Drainage Paper 29. Rome, https://www.scribd.com/doc/215866301/Water-Quality-for-Agriculture(FAO 1976):</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. <i>Guideline for drinking-water quality: fourth edition incorporating the first addendum</i> (World Health Organization, 2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28759192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Guidelines for Drinking Water Quality.&#xa0;4th Edition World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland. https://www.paho.org/en/documents/guidelines-drinking-water-quality-4o-ed-2011 .(2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enawgaw, Y. &amp; Lemma, B. Ecological Conditions and Benthic acroinvertebrates of Lake Tinishu Ababya, Ethiopia. <i>Oceanography &amp; Fisheries Open Access Journal</i><b>10</b>(2), 32&#x2013;45. 10.19080/OFOAJ.2019.10.555782 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19080/OFOAJ.2019.10.555782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebresllasse, H. Wetland degradation in Ethiopia: causes, consequences and remedies. <i>J. Environ. Earth Sci.</i><b>4</b>(11), 40&#x2013;48 (2014).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>