<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41245402</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-861X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Urolithin A supplementation on performance and antioxidant status in academy soccer players during preseason: a pilot randomised controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1674446</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1674446</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1674446</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fnut.2025.1674446</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Polyphenol-derived compounds, such as Urolithin A (UA), may exert beneficial effects to performance adaptations during periods of high training stress through several pathways including a reduction in an oxidative stress and improved mitochondrial function. At present, the benefits of UA supplementation have been observed predominantly in clinical and preclinical models. This pilot study aimed to investigate the effects of UA supplementation on performance outcomes, antioxidant status, and intervention feasibility and acceptability during a six-week preseason period in academy soccer players.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Twenty male academy soccer players (age: 17.5&#x202f;&#xb1;&#x202f;1.0&#x202f;years) were randomly assigned 1:1 to receive 1,000&#x202f;mg/day of UA or an isocaloric taste-matched placebo which was given post-training over the course of a six-week training intervention in a single-blinded, parallel-group design. The intervention was delivered alongside the team's preseason training from November to December 2024. Primary outcome was aerobic endurance (Yo-Yo Intermittent Recovery Test Level 1), with secondary outcomes including lower-limb strength and power metrics (Countermovement Jump), maximal sprinting speed, and salivary antioxidant capacity using the RoXsta&#x2122; System. Each of the primary and secondary outcomes were assessed pre and post the intervention. Feasibility and acceptability of the intervention along with dietary intake was assessed via individual questionnaire, pre and post intervention, while subjective stress-recovery status was assessed via questionnaire administered weekly over the duration of the intervention. Primary and secondary data were analysed using linear mixed effects models, with group (UA/placebo)&#x202f;&#xd7;&#x202f;time (pre/post) interactions interpreted using estimated marginal means.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">UA supplementation led to significantly greater improvements in Yo-Yo IRT1 performance compared to placebo (&#x394;&#x202f;=&#x202f;+239&#x202f;m, 95% CI [20, 454&#x202f;m], <i>p</i>&#x202f;=&#x202f;0.048). For secondary outcomes, countermovement jump height also improved in the UA group relative to placebo (&#x394;&#x202f;=&#x202f;+3.33&#x202f;cm, [0.88, 5.95&#x202f;cm], <i>p</i>&#x202f;=&#x202f;0.020). No group x time differences were observed in sprint speed, jump power, impulse, or eccentric duration, or saliva antioxidant assays. Antioxidant activity declined significantly over time in the placebo group but did not so in the UA group. Feasibility and acceptability questionnaire responses indicated the intervention as it was delivered was rated with high feasibility and acceptability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Six weeks of UA supplementation during preseason improved aerobic endurance and some measures of jump performance in elite academy soccer players, while preserving aspects of antioxidant status. Confidence limits on the primary and secondary findings were broad. These findings potentially support UA as a feasible and well-tolerated intervention in athletic populations, warranting further research in larger and well powered confirmatory trials (Clinical Trial No. ACTRN12624000959572).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Monsalve Acevedo, Sanctuary, Aitken, Wilkins, Harrison and Naughton.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monsalve Acevedo</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences and Pharmacy, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanctuary</LastName><ForeName>Colin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences and Pharmacy, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Sports Science and Exercise Testing Laboratory, University of Newcastle, Ourimbah, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aitken</LastName><ForeName>Robert John</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Reproductive Science, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunter Medical Research Institute, New Lambton Heights, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilkins</LastName><ForeName>Alex</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Reproductive Science, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harrison</LastName><ForeName>Natasha</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Reproductive Science, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naughton</LastName><ForeName>Mitchell</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences and Pharmacy, University of Newcastle, Callaghan, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Sports Science and Exercise Testing Laboratory, University of Newcastle, Ourimbah, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101642264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-861X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aerobic capacity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anaerobic exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">countermovement jump</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polyphenols</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">supplement</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>MN declares that Timeline Nutrition provided reimbursement for travel and accommodation expenses associated to attend American College of Sports Medicine Annual Meeting 2025, during which the data from this study were presented. The company had no role in the design, execution, analysis, or interpretation of the study. RA has received renumeration from Memphasys as a consultant and Scientific Director. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41245402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12611738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2025.1674446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Reilly T. Energetics of high-intensity exercise (soccer) with particular reference to fatigue. J Sports Sci. (1997) 15:257&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1080/026404197367263, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/026404197367263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9232551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Krustrup P, Bangsbo J. Match performance of high-standard soccer players with special reference to development of fatigue. J Sports Sci. (2003) 21:519&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1080/0264041031000071182, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0264041031000071182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12848386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xf8;len T, Chamari K, Castagna C, Wisl&#xf8;ff U. Physiology of soccer: an update. Sports Med. (2005) 35:501&#x2013;36. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200535060-00004, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200535060-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15974635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley PS, Noakes TD. Match running performance fluctuations in elite soccer: indicative of fatigue, pacing or situational influences? J Sports Sci. (2013) 31:1627&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2013.796062, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2013.796062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23808376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong T-S, Reilly T, Morton J, Bae S-W, Drust B. Quantification of the physiological loading of one week of &#x201c;pre-season&#x201d; and one week of &#x201c;in-season&#x201d; training in professional soccer players. J Sports Sci. (2011) 29:1161&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2011.583671, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2011.583671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21777053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva JR, Brito J, Akenhead R, Nassis GP. The transition period in soccer: a window of opportunity. Sports Med. (2016) 46:305&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1007/s40279-015-0419-3, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0419-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26530720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R, Duclos M, Foster C, Fry A, Gleeson M, Nieman D, et al. Prevention, diagnosis and treatment of the overtraining syndrome: joint consensus statement of the European College of Sport Science (ECSS) and the American College of Sports Medicine (ACSM). Eur J Sport Sci. (2013) 13:1&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1249/mss.0b013e318279a10a</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0b013e318279a10a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23247672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McArdle F, Pattwell DM, Vasilaki A, McArdle A, Jackson MJ. Intracellular generation of reactive oxygen species by contracting skeletal muscle cells. Free Radic Biol Med. (2005) 39:651&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2005.04.010, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2005.04.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16085183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers SK, Ji LL, Kavazis AN, Jackson MJ. Reactive oxygen species: impact on skeletal muscle. Compr Physiol. (2011) 1:941&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1002/j.2040-4603.2011.tb00348.x, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/j.2040-4603.2011.tb00348.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3893116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23737208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellmann M, Bertollo M, Bosquet L, Brink M, Coutts AJ, Duffield R, et al. Recovery and performance in sport: consensus statement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. (2018) 13:240&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2017-0759</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2017-0759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29345524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray B, Rosenbloom C. Fundamentals of glycogen metabolism for coaches and athletes. Nutr Rev. (2018) 76:243&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1093/nutrit/nuy001, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nutrit/nuy001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6019055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29444266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinlan R, Hill JA. The efficacy of tart cherry juice in aiding recovery after intermittent exercise. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. (2020) 15:368&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2019-0101, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2019-0101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31614329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale KC, Hueglin S, Broad E. Tart cherry juice in athletes: a literature review and commentary. Curr Sports Med Rep. (2017) 16:230&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1249/JSR.0000000000000385, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0000000000000385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28696985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyakayiru J, Jonvik KL, Trommelen J, Pinckaers PJ, Senden JM, Van Loon LJ, et al. Beetroot juice supplementation improves high-intensity intermittent type exercise performance in trained soccer players. Nutrients. (2017) 9:314. doi: 10.3390/nu9030314, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu9030314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5372977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28327503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreux PA, Blanco-Bose W, Ryu D, Burdet F, Ibberson M, Aebischer P, et al. The mitophagy activator urolithin A is safe and induces a molecular signature of improved mitochondrial and cellular health in humans. Nat Metab. (2019) 1:595&#x2013;603. doi: 10.1038/s42255-019-0073-4, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42255-019-0073-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32694802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A, D&#x2019;Amico D, Andreux PA, Fouassier AM, Blanco-Bose W, Evans M, et al. Urolithin A improves muscle strength, exercise performance, and biomarkers of mitochondrial health in a randomized trial in middle-aged adults. Cell Rep Med. (2022) 3:100633. doi: 10.1016/j.xcrm.2022.100633, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xcrm.2022.100633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9133463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35584623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Song G, Zhu H, Qian H, Pan X, Song X, et al. Pharmacological effects of urolithin A and its role in muscle health and performance: current knowledge and prospects. Nutrients. (2023) 15:4441. doi: 10.3390/nu15204441, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15204441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10609777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37892516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selma MV, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Sarr&#xed;as A, Salas-Salvad&#xf3; J, Andr&#xe9;s-Lacueva C, Alasalvar C, &#xd6;rem A, et al. The gut microbiota metabolism of pomegranate or walnut ellagitannins yields two urolithin-metabotypes that correlate with cardiometabolic risk biomarkers: comparison between normoweight, overweight-obesity and metabolic syndrome. Clin Nutr. (2018) 37:897&#x2013;905. doi: 10.1016/j.clnu.2017.03.012, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2017.03.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28347564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Amico D, Andreux PA, Vald&#xe9;s P, Singh A, Rinsch C, Auwerx J. Impact of the natural compound urolithin A on health, disease, and aging. Trends Mol Med. (2021) 27:687&#x2013;99. doi: 10.1016/j.molmed.2021.04.009, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molmed.2021.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34030963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryu D, Mouchiroud L, Andreux PA, Katsyuba E, Moullan N, Nicolet-dit-F&#xe9;lix AA, et al. Urolithin A induces mitophagy and prolongs lifespan in C. elegans and increases muscle function in rodents. Nat Med. (2016) 22:879&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1038/nm.4132, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm.4132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27400265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, D&#x2019;Amico D, Shankland E, Bhayana S, Garcia JM, Aebischer P, et al. Effect of urolithin A supplementation on muscle endurance and mitochondrial health in older adults: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Netw Open. (2022) 5:e2144279. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.44279, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.44279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8777576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35050355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Zhu H, Yun H, Liu J, Song G, Teng J, et al. Assessment of Urolithin A effects on muscle endurance, strength, inflammation, oxidative stress, and protein metabolism in male athletes with resistance training: an 8-week randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2024) 21:2419388. doi: 10.1080/15502783.2024.2419388, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2024.2419388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11536656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39487653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira JE, Leal M, Ferraz R, Ribeiro J, Cachada JM, Barbosa TM, et al. Effects of match location, quality of opposition and match outcome on match running performance in a Portuguese professional football team. Entropy. (2021) 23:973. doi: 10.3390/e23080973, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/e23080973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8391710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34441113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellmann M, K&#xf6;lling S. Recovery and stress in sport: a manual for testing and assessment. London: Routledge; (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;lling S, Schaffran P, Bibbey A, Drew M, Raysmith B, N&#xe4;ssi A, et al. Validation of the acute recovery and stress scale (ARSS) and the short recovery and stress scale (SRSS) in three English-speaking regions. J Sports Sci. (2020) 38:130&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2019.1684790, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2019.1684790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31696778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekhon M, Cartwright M, Francis JJ. Development of a theory-informed questionnaire to assess the acceptability of healthcare interventions. BMC Health Serv Res. (2022) 22:279. doi: 10.1186/s12913-022-07577-3, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-022-07577-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8887649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35232455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangsbo J, Iaia FM, Krustrup P. The yo-yo intermittent recovery test: a useful tool for evaluation of physical performance in intermittent sports. Sports Med. (2008) 38:37&#x2013;51. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200838010-00004, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200838010-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18081366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan Z, Castagna C, Krustrup P, Wong DP, P&#xf3;voas S, Boullosa D, et al. Exploring the use of 5 different Yo-Yo tests in evaluating V &#x2d9; O 2 max &#x2d9; V O _ 2max and fitness profile in team sports: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. (2025) 35:e70054. doi: 10.1111/sms.70054, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.70054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40356566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collings TJ, Lima YL, Dutaillis B, Bourne MN. Concurrent validity and test&#x2013;retest reliability of VALD ForceDecks' strength, balance, and movement assessment tests. J Sci Med Sport. (2024) 27:572&#x2013;80. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2024.04.014, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2024.04.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38777737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aitken RJ, Wilkins A, Harrison N, Kobarfard K, Lambourne S. Towards the development of novel, point-of-care assays for monitoring different forms of antioxidant activity: the RoXsta(TM) system. Antioxidants (Basel). (2024) 13:1379. doi: 10.3390/antiox13111379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox13111379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11591381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39594521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates D, M&#xe4;chler M, Bolker BM, Walker SC. Fitting linear mixed-effects models using lme4. J Stat Softw. (2015) 67:1&#x2013;48. doi: 10.18637/jss.v067.i01</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v067.i01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuznetsova A, Brockhoff PB, Christensen RHB. lmerTest package: tests in linear mixed effects models. J Stat Softw. (2017) 82:1&#x2013;26. doi: 10.18637/jss.v082.i13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v082.i13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weissgerber TL, Garovic VD, Savic M, Winham SJ, Milic NM. From static to interactive: transforming data visualization to improve transparency. PLoS Biol. (2016) 14. doi: 10.1371/journal.pbio.1002484</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pbio.1002484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4917243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27332507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borm GF, Fransen J, Lemmens WA. A simple sample size formula for analysis of covariance in randomized clinical trials. J Clin Epidemiol. (2007) 60:1234&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2007.02.006, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2007.02.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17998077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deprez D, Fransen J, Lenoir M, Philippaerts RM, Vaeyens R. The Yo-Yo intermittent recovery test level 1 is reliable in young high-level soccer players. Biol Sport. (2015) 32:65&#x2013;70. doi: 10.5604/20831862.1127284, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5604/20831862.1127284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4314606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25729152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Springham M, Singh N, Stewart P, Matthews J, Jones I, Norton-Sherwood C, et al. Countermovement jump and isometric strength test-retest reliability in English premier league academy football players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. (2024) 19:1444&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2023-0473, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2023-0473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39353577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Yu L. Emerging evidence of Urolithin A in sports nutrition: bridging preclinical findings to athletic applications. Front Nutr. (2025) 12:1585922. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2025.1585922, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2025.1585922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12122305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40453722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aedo-Mu&#xf1;oz E, P&#xe9;rez-Contreras J, Bustamante-Garrido A, Arriagada-Tarife&#xf1;o D, Cancino-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Retamal-Espinoza M, et al. Is countermovement jump an indirect marker of neuromuscular mechanism? Relationship with isometric knee extension test. J Funct Morphol Kin. (2024) 9:242. doi: 10.3390/jfmk9040242</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk9040242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11587026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39584895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormack SJ, Newton RU, McGuigan MR, Doyle TLA. Reliability of measures obtained during single and repeated countermovement jumps. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. (2008) 3:131&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.3.2.131, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.3.2.131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19208922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Djedjibegovic J, Marjanovic A, Panieri E, Saso L. Ellagic acid-derived Urolithins as modulators of oxidative stress. Oxidative Med Cell Longev. (2020) 2020:1&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1155/2020/5194508, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/5194508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7407063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32774676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson MJ. Control of reactive oxygen species production in contracting skeletal muscle. Antioxid Redox Signal. (2011) 15:2477&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1089/ars.2011.3976, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/ars.2011.3976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3176346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21699411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santiba&#xf1;ez-Gutierrez A, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Landa J, Busto N, Todorovic N, Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Mielgo-Ayuso J. Supplementation on sport performance, biomarkers of intestinal damage, and oxidative stress in recreational athletes. J Funct Morphol Kin. (2025) 10:131. doi: 10.3390/jfmk10020131</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk10020131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12015827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40566427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Torres I, Guarner-Lans V, Rubio-Ruiz ME. Reductive stress in inflammation-associated diseases and the pro-oxidant effect of antioxidant agents. Int J Mol Sci. (2017) 18:2098. doi: 10.3390/ijms18102098, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms18102098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5666780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28981461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senn S. Seven myths of randomisation in clinical trials. Stat Med. (2013) 32:1439&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1002/sim.5713, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.5713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23255195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopewell S, Chan A-W, Collins GS, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Moher D, Schulz KF, et al. CONSORT 2025 explanation and elaboration: updated guideline for reporting randomised trials. BMJ. (2025) 389. doi: 10.1136/bmj-2024-081124</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2024-081124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11995452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40228832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato M, Coratella G, Stiff A, Iacono AD. The validity and between-unit variability of GNSS units (STATSports Apex 10 and 18 Hz) for measuring distance and peak speed in team sports. Frontiers in physiology. (2018) 9:1288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6161633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30298015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham H, Averick M, Bryan J, Chang W, McGowan LDA, Fran&#xe7;ois R, et al. Welcome to the Tidyverse. Journal of open source software, (2019) 4:1686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenth R, Singmann H, Love J, Buerkner P, Herve M. Emmeans: Estimated marginal means, aka least-squares means (R package version 1.5. 1.)[Computer software]. The Comprehensive R Archive Network, (2021).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>