<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41390866</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mechanical analysis and application of floor failure mechanism under repeated mining in close-distance coal seams.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2728</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2728</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2728</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-32535-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The stress state of primary rocks is redistributed during coal mining, which leads to deformation and failure of the floor strata. Coal seam floor experiences repeated additional stress from the mining of two overlying seams in close-distance mining. An assessment of floor stability is required in the presence of a confined aquifer within the floor strata. The failure characteristics of floor rock strata are crucial for analyzing water inrush from floor. This mechanical response of floor deformation and failure becomes particularly pronounced when the roof is treated using the full caving method. Floor strata were analyzed for the 220,105 working face at Xinji 2<sup>#</sup> Coal Mine, with an elastic half&#x2011;plane theory established. The stress distribution characteristics of the floor were investigated using software MATLAB. The width of the plastic zone and the maximum failure depth of floor were determined based on the slip line field theory of floor rock mass. A reference was provided for water damage control during repeated mining of the 1<sup>#</sup> coal seam. Continuous field observation of floor failure was performed through drilling combined with the network parallel electrical method. Apparent resistivity at the depth of 19.6&#xa0;m below floor was approximately twice the background resistivity of the corresponding stratum. The apparent resistivity of rock strata below 19.6&#xa0;m remained constant, indicating a protective zone. These results confirm the reliability of the theoretical analysis and provide a technical foundation for safe mining in the working face.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yingfu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mining Engineering, Anhui University of Science and Technology, Huainan, 232001, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Safe Mining of Deep Coal Resources and Environment Protection, Huainan, 232000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mining Engineering, Anhui University of Science and Technology, Huainan, 232001, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Tongtong</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mining Engineering, Anhui University of Science and Technology, Huainan, 232001, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Fangang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mining Engineering, Anhui University of Science and Technology, Huainan, 232001, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Guanfeng</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanics and Optoelectronic Physics, Anhui University of Science and Technology, Huainan, 232001, Anhui, China. guanfeng_chang@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Safe Mining of Deep Coal Resources and Environment Protection, Huainan, 232000, China. guanfeng_chang@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Close coal seams</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Failure mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Floor stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanical analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parallel electrical method</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Repeated mining</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Consent to publish: All authors of this article consent to publish. All participants of the work provided consent to publish.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41390866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12824316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-32535-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-32535-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. et al. The evolution of coal&#x2019;s energy status and green low-carbon development under the dual carbon goals. <i>J. Coal Sci.</i><b>48</b> (07), 2599&#x2013;2612 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, G. et al. Strengthening the safety of the coal industry to Lay the foundation for energy security. <i>China Coal</i>. <b>48</b> (07), 1&#x2013;9 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan, H., Chen, D. &amp; Mao, D. Analysis of deep mining status and disaster prevention in china&#x2019;s coal mines. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>44</b> (01), 39&#x2013;46 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Q. et al. Classification and analysis of mine water hazard types and their main characteristics. <i>J. Coal</i>. <b>38</b> (04), 561&#x2013;565 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, S. et al. Mechanisms and prevention technologies for new type old Kong bottom plate ore geothermal water. <i>Coalf. Geol. Explor.</i><b>51</b> (07), 103&#x2013;112 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, Y. et al. Characteristics, causes and prevention strategies of coal mine water hazards in China. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>51</b> (07), 1&#x2013;14 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rui, G. et al. Influential factors and control of water inrush in a coal seam as the main aquifer. <i>Int. J. Min. Sci. Technol.</i><b>28</b> (02):187&#x2013;193 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. et al. Failure characteristics of coal seam floor and risk assessment of water inrush caused by underground coal mining. <i>Energy Explor. Exploit.</i><b>41</b> (2), 677&#x2013;695 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/01445987221144332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, Q. &amp; Li, S. A review of fracture development in engineering boundaries of deep rock masses. <i>J. Rock. Mech. Eng.</i><b>6</b>, 1278&#x2013;1284 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, F., Shen, B. &amp; Kang, Y. Mechanism analysis of coal seam floor failure and calculation of maximum damage depth. <i>Min. Saf. Environ. Prot.</i><b>42</b> (03), 58&#x2013;61 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, X. et al. Physical modeling of floor heave for the deep-buried roadway excavated in ten degree inclined strata using infrared thermal imaging technology. <i>Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol.</i><b>63</b>, 228&#x2013;243 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2016.12.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. et al. Research on the characteristics and control of soft rock tunnel floor failure. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>51</b> (03), 21&#x2013;28 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, X. et al. Stress distribution and failure mechanism of coal mining face floor. <i>J. Coal Sci.</i><b>35</b> (11), 1832&#x2013;1836 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, H. Stress distribution characteristics in deep coal mines and rock mass control technology for roadways. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>41</b> (09), 12&#x2013;17 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, H. et al. Elastomechanical analysis of mining-induced damage depth in coal seam floor under hydraulic pressure. <i>J. Min. Saf. Eng.</i><b>34</b> (03), 452&#x2013;458 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, Z. Z., Song, W. C. &amp; Liu, W. T. Theoretical models for simulating the failure range and stability of inclined floor strata induced by mining and hydraulic pressure. <i>Int. J. Rock. Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>132</b>, 104382 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2020.104382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. Application of parallel network electromagnetics in coal seam overlying rock damage monitoring. <i>Coalf. Geol. Explor.</i><b>02</b>, 61&#x2013;64 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Z. et al. Kinematic analysis and key theories of bedrock control with engineering applications. <i>J. Coal Sci.</i><b>49</b> (01), 16&#x2013;35 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Z. <i>A Concise Tutorial on Elasticity</i> (Higher Education Press, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, M. <i>Ground Pressure and Strata Control</i> (China University of Mining and Technology, 2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. et al. Analysis of in-situ mining floor fracture characteristics along the working face trend in aquifer pressure mining areas. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>50</b> (12), 206&#x2013;214 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. <i>Study on Floor Failure Characteristics and Water Inrush Mechanism in the Mining Area of Weibei Aohui Pressure Water</i> (Xi&#x2019;an University of Science and Technology, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, C. &amp; Dang, Y. Analysis of the formation mechanism of geological structures in the second mine area of Xinji. <i>Energy Technol. Manage.</i><b>47</b> (04), 182&#x2013;186 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, L. <i>Study on the Disintegration Law of Underplate in Pressure-Oriented Gypsum Filling Mining in Zhucun Mine</i> (China University of Mining and Technology, 2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, S. et al. Simulation study on floor damage characteristics in close-range double-layer mining of thin coal seams. <i>Energy Environ. Prot.</i><b>47</b> (06), 261&#x2013;266 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. <i>Simulation Study on the Law of Floor Damage in Pressurized Mining Faces</i> (Taiyuan University of Technology, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, Q. <i>Study on the Distribution Patterns of Rupture Zones in the Bottom Plate of the First Mining Face of Limin Mine 16 Coal</i> (Liaoning Technical University, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, M. <i>Developmental Characteristics of Floor Disintegration Zones and Water Inrush Assessment in Mining Faces Under 24m Mining Height Conditions</i> (China University of Mining and Technology, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cha, C. et al. Numerical analysis of floor damage depth in slowly inclined coal seam mining. <i>China Min.</i><b>33</b> (08), 169&#x2013;175 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, G. Application of network parallel electric method in height measurement of two belts in high-caregging comprehensive mining face. <i>Shaanxi Coal Ind.</i><b>44</b> (08), 140&#x2013;143 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, F. Study on the floor failure patterns of working face 1311 in Hudi coal mine, Jincheng mining area. <i>Coal Mine Modernization</i>. <b>32</b> (05), 38&#x2013;41 (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>