<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41815684</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2250-0685</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of orthopaedic case reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Orthop Case Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of Spine Hip Relation and its Correlation as a Guide to Total Hip Arthroplasty.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>299</StartPage><EndPage>306</EndPage><MedlinePgn>299-306</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.13107/jocr.2026.v16.i03.6976</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS AND BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Dislocation remains one of the most common complications following total hip arthroplasty (THA). Although the classical "Lewinnek's safe zone" for acetabular cup positioning has long guided surgeons, a considerable number of dislocations still occur even within this zone. Recent evidence emphasizes the importance of the dynamic spinopelvic relationship, specifically variations in pelvic tilt and functional anteversion, which directly influence acetabular orientation and joint stability. This study aims to analyze the spinopelvic relationship and its effect on acetabular cup anteversion and femoral head coverage in THA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 30 patients aged between 20 and 70 years undergoing primary THA were included in the study. Pre-operative assessment involved X-rays of the lumbar spine and pelvis in both supine and standing positions to determine changes in pelvic tilt. Acetabular anteversion was modified accordingly. Postoperatively, acetabular cup positioning and femoral head coverage were evaluated radiographically using the Woo and Morrey method for anteversion and the lateral center edge angle (LCEA) of Wiberg. Statistical analysis was performed using the Statistical Package for the Social Sciences version 23.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The mean pelvic tilt in supine and standing positions was -3.30&#xb0; and -5.77&#xb0;, respectively, with a mean change of -2.44&#xb0;. The mean target anteversion was 13.32&#xb0;, and the mean achieved anteversion was 14.65&#xb0;. The mean LCEA was 50.51&#xb0;. A weak negative correlation was found between anteversion achieved and LCEA (&#x3c1; = -0.27, P = 0.141). The LCEA was highest when acetabular anteversion was within 5&#xb0;-25&#xb0;, suggesting optimal femoral head coverage within this range.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The study highlights that a fixed "safe zone" for acetabular cup placement is insufficient. Individualized cup orientation based on spinopelvic parameters enhances joint stability and femoral head coverage. Functional assessment of pelvic tilt and anteversion should be integrated into pre-operative planning to reduce the risk of impingement and dislocation in THA.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; Indian Orthopaedic Research Group.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mittal</LastName><ForeName>Deepanshu</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Adesh Institute of Medical Sciences and Research, Bathinda, Punjab, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bindal</LastName><ForeName>Shikhar</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Dayanand Medical College and Hospital, Ludhiana, Punjab, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maingi</LastName><ForeName>Sajal</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Dayanand Medical College and Hospital, Ludhiana, Punjab, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paruthi</LastName><ForeName>Pallavi</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia, ESIC Medical College and Hospital, Ludhiana, Punjab, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bery</LastName><ForeName>Mannat</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dayanand Medical College and Hospital, Ludhiana, Punjab, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Orthop Case Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101641392</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2250-0685</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spinopelvic relationship</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acetabular anteversion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">femoral head coverage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lateral center edge angle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pelvic tilt</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">total hip arthroplasty</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest: Nil</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41815684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12972993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13107/jocr.2026.v16.i03.6976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JOCR-16-3-299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Delaunay C, Hamadouche M, Girard J, Duhamel A, SoFCOT Group. What are the causes for failures of primary hip arthroplasties in France? Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2013;471:3863&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3825891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23529633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hailer NP, Weiss RJ, Stark A, K&#xe4;rrholm J. The risk of revision due to dislocation after total hip arthroplasty depends on surgical approach, femoral head size, sex, and primary diagnosis. An analysis of 78,098 operations in the Swedish Hip Arthroplasty Register. Acta Orthop. 2012;83:442&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3488169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23039167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney CR, Pellicci PM. Complications in primary total hip arthroplasty: Avoidance and management of dislocations. Instr Course Lect. 2003;52:247&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12690852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sariali E, Lazennec JY, Khiami F, Catonn&#xe9; Y. Mathematical evaluation of jumping distance in total hip arthroplasty: Influence of abduction angle, femoral head offset, and head diameter. Acta Orthop. 2009;80:277&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2823207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19421906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miki H, Kyo T, Kuroda Y, Nakahara I, Sugano N. Risk of edge-loading and prosthesis impingement due to posterior pelvic tilting after total hip arthroplasty. Clin Biomech (Bristol) 2014;29:607&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24933660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewinnek GE, Lewis JL, Tarr R, Compere CL, Zimmerman JR. Dislocations after total hip-replacement arthroplasties. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1978;60:217&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">641088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazennec JY, Boyer P, Gorin M, Catonn&#xe9; Y, Rousseau MA. Acetabular anteversion with CT in supine, simulated standing, and sitting positions in a THA patient population. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2011;469:1103&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3048248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21161739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanawade V, Dorr LD, Wan Z. Predictability of acetabular component angular change with postural shift from standing to sitting position. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2014;96:978&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24951732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrack RL. Dislocation after total hip arthroplasty: Implant design and orientation. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2003;11:89&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12670135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wixson RL. Computer-assisted total hip navigation. Instr Course Lect. 2008;57:707&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18399618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito CI, Gladnick BP, Lee YY, Lyman S, Wright TM, Mayman DJ, et al. Cup position alone does not predict risk of dislocation after hip arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty. 2015;30:109&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4270833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lafage V, Schwab F, Patel A, Hawkinson N, Farcy JP. Pelvic tilt and truncal inclination: Two key radiographic parameters in the setting of adults with spinal deformity. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2009;34:E599&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19644319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lembeck B, Mueller O, Reize P, Wuelker N. Pelvic tilt makes acetabular cup navigation inaccurate. Acta Orthop. 2005;76:517&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16195068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellon SJ, Grammatopoulos G, Andersen MS, Pandit HG, Gill HS, Murray DW. Optimal acetabular component orientation estimated using edge-loading and impingement risk in patients with metal-on-metal hip resurfacing arthroplasty. J Biomech. 2015;48:318&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25482661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy TF, Alipit V, Nevelos J, Elmallah RK, Mont MA. Acetabular cup anteversion and inclination in hip range of motion to impingement. J Arthroplasty. 2016;31:264&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27067753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laffargue P, Pinoit Y, Tabutin J, Giraud F, Puget J, Migaud H. Computer-assisted positioning of the acetabular cup for total hip arthroplasty based on joint kinematics without prior imaging: Preliminary results with computed tomographic assessment. Rev Chir Orthop Reparatrice Appar Mot. 2006;92:316&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16948458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clohisy JC, Carlisle JC, Beaul&#xe9; PE, Kim YJ, Trousdale RT, Sierra RJ, et al. A systematic approach to the plain radiographic evaluation of the young adult hip. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2008;90(Suppl 4):47&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2682767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18984718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo RY, Morrey BF. Dislocations after total hip arthroplasty. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1982;64:1295&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7142237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eilander W, Harris SJ, Henkus HE, Cobb JP, Hogervorst T. Functional acetabular component position with supine total hip replacement. Bone Joint J. 2013;95-B:1326&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24078527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel MP, von Roth P, Jennings MT, Hanssen AD, Pagnano MW. What safe zone? The vast majority of dislocated THAs are within the lewinnek safe zone for acetabular component position. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2016;474:386&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4709312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26150264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inaba Y, Kobayashi N, Suzuki H, Ike H, Kubota S, Saito T. Preoperative planning for implant placement with consideration of pelvic tilt in total hip arthroplasty: Postoperative efficacy evaluation. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2016;17:280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4944317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27412447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiberi JV, Pulos N, Kertzner M, Schmalzried TP. A more reliable method to assess acetabular component position. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2012;470:471&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3254767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21822569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>