<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41808976</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2193-6331</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>87</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neurological surgery. Part B, Skull base</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neurol Surg B Skull Base</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mini-invasive Anterior Petrosal Intertentorial Approach for Trigeminal Neuralgia: Rationale and Limits of the Technique.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>144</StartPage><EndPage>150</EndPage><MedlinePgn>144-150</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/a-2587-6267</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The retrosigmoid approach (RSA) is considered the standard surgical choice to address a neurovascular conflict involving the trigeminal nerve. The subtemporal transtentorial approach (STA) represents the main alternative. We describe here the mini-invasive anterior petrosal intertentorial approach with a view to reduce complications associated with the standard STA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Mini-invasive anterior petrosal intertentorial approach (M-APIA) was described for a case of refractory trigeminal neuralgia. This approach includes a very limited amount of drilling of the petrous ridge to expose the posterior fossa dura and the superior petrosal sinus to facilitate the subsequent tentorial peeling. Tentorial peeling enables to develop an intertentorial plane between the temporal tentorial leaf (TTL) and the posterior fossa tentorial leaf (PFTL). A linear incision over the posterior fossa dura and the PFTL offers a wide exposure of the neurovascular conflict.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">M-APIA enables to expose the root entry zone (REZ) of the trigeminal nerve without exposing the temporal lobe or the cerebellum.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">M-APIA can be considered as a safe alternative to the RSA or STA for trigeminal microvascular decompression (MVD), especially for select cases. Additional studies are needed for a better understanding of its advantages and disadvantages.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Thieme. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giammattei</LastName><ForeName>L</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departement of Neurosurgery, Lausanne University Hospital, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Squair</LastName><ForeName>J W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departement of Neurosurgery, Lausanne University Hospital, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peters</LastName><ForeName>D</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0908-7128</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fava</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Neuromed, Pozzilli, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mellal</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departement of Neurosurgery, Lausanne University Hospital, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aureli</LastName><ForeName>V</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departement of Neurosurgery, Lausanne University Hospital, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pistocchi</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Radiology, Service of Diagnostic and Interventional Radiology, Neuroradiology Unit, Lausanne University Hospital, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Starnoni</LastName><ForeName>D</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departement of Neurosurgery, Lausanne University Hospital, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daniel</LastName><ForeName>R T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departement of Neurosurgery, Lausanne University Hospital, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>J Neurol Surg B Skull Base</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101580780</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2193-634X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior petrosal intertentorial approach</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microvascular decompression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tentorial peeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">trigeminal neuralgia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest All authors certify that they have no affiliations with or involvement in any organization or entity with any financial interest (such as honoraria; educational grants; participation in speakers' bureaus; membership, employment, consultancies, stock ownership, or other equity interest; and expert testimony or patent-licensing arrangements), or non-financial interest (such as personal or professional relationships, affiliations, knowledge, or beliefs) in the subject matter or materials discussed in this manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41808976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12971241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2587-6267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JNLS-B-24-Nov-0191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kundu B, Rolston J D. Nationwide shift from percutaneous rhizotomy to microvascular decompression for treatment of trigeminal and other cranial nerve neuralgias. Headache. 2018;58(10):1675&#x2013;1679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30334252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogiwara T, Goto T, Kusano Y et al. Subtemporal transtentorial approach for recurrent trigeminal neuralgia after microvascular decompression via the lateral suboccipital approach: case report. J Neurosurg. 2015;122(06):1429&#x2013;1432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25423272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starnoni D, Peters D, Giammattei L et al. Anterior petrosectomy with intertentorial approach. Oper Neurosurg (Hagerstown) 2024;26(03):301&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10857660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37878474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Carlo D T, Benedetto N, Perrini P. Clinical outcome after microvascular decompression for trigeminal neuralgia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurosurg Rev. 2022;46(01):8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36481917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herta J, Schmied T, Loidl T B et al. Microvascular decompression in trigeminal neuralgia: predictors of pain relief, complication avoidance, and lessons learned. Acta Neurochir (Wien) 2021;163(12):3321&#x2013;3336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8599248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34674027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dziedzic T A, Abhinav K, Fernandez-Miranda J C. Subtemporal approach and its infratentorial extension: review and a comparative analysis of different techniques. J Neurol Surg B Skull Base. 2022;84(01):89&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9897897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36743711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaughlin N, Ma Q, Emerson J, Malkasian D R, Martin N A. The extended subtemporal transtentorial approach: the impact of trochlear nerve dissection and tentorial incision. J Clin Neurosci. 2013;20(08):1139&#x2013;1143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23743353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jittapiromsak P, Wu A, Nakaji P, Spetzler R F, Preul M C. The challenge of access to the pontomesencephalic junction: an anatomical study of lateral approach and exposure. Skull Base. 2010;20(05):311&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3023326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21358994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goehre F, Lehecka M, Jahromi B R et al. Subtemporal approach to posterior cerebral artery aneurysms. World Neurosurg. 2015;83(05):842&#x2013;851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25683130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D, Zeng M, Yao Y, Zhang N, Yang T, Xia C. Retractorless surgery for petroclival meningiomas via the subtemporal approach: a try to reduce brain retraction injury. Comput Math Methods Med. 2022;2022:6.436542E6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9303107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35872953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabatino G, Rigante L, Marchese E et al. Anterior subtemporal approach for posterolateral brainstem cavernomas: report of ten cases. Acta Neurochir (Wien) 2012;154(11):2009&#x2013;2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22961242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith E R, Chapman P H, Ogilvy C S.Far posterior subtemporal approach to the dorsolateral brainstem and tentorial ring: technique and clinical experience Neurosurgery 20035202364&#x2013;368., discussion 368&#x2013;369</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12535365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ste&#x148;o J, B&#xed;zik I, Ste&#x148;ov&#xe1; J, Tim&#xe1;rov&#xe1; G.Subtemporal transtentorial resection of cavernous malformations involving the pyramidal tract in the upper pons and mesencephalon Acta Neurochir (Wien) 2011153101955&#x2013;1962., discussion 1962</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21845370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zieli&#x144;ski G, Sajjad E A, Robak &#x141;, Koziarski A. Subtemporal approach for gross total resection of retrochiasmatic craniopharyngiomas: our experience on 30 cases. World Neurosurg. 2018;109:e265&#x2013;e273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28987834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann A M, Price A V. A history of the Jannetta procedure. J Neurosurg. 2019;132(02):639&#x2013;646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30717044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Shang Y, Zhang Y, Zhao Y. Endoscopic microvascular decompression versus microscopic microvascular decompression for trigeminal neuralgia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Neurosci. 2023;117:73&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37776679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teo C, Nakaji P, Mobbs R J.Endoscope-assisted microvascular decompression for trigeminal neuralgia: technical case report Neurosurgery 200659(4, Suppl 2):ONSE489-90, discussion ONSE490</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17041524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giammattei L, Passeri T, Abbritti R et al. Surgical morbidity of the extradural anterior petrosal approach: the Lariboisi&#xe8;re experience. J Neurosurg. 2022;138(01):276&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35561692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang S W, Wu A, Gore Pet al. Quantitative comparison of Kawase's approach versus the retrosigmoid approach: implications for tumors involving both middle and posterior fossae Neurosurgery 200964(3, Suppl):ons44&#x2013;ons51., discussion ons51&#x2013;ons52</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19240572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomio R, Horiguchi T, Borghei-Razavi H, Tamura R, Yoshida K, Kawase T. Anterior transpetrosal approach: experiences in 274 cases over 33 years. Technical variations, operated patients, and approach-related complications. J Neurosurg. 2021;136(02):413&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34388716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibao S, Toda M, Orii M, Fujiwara H, Yoshida K. Various patterns of the middle cerebral vein and preservation of venous drainage during the anterior transpetrosal approach. J Neurosurg. 2016;124(02):432&#x2013;439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26314997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibao S, Yoshida K. Simplified anterior transpetrosal approach without superior petrosal sinus and tentorial incision for lesions centered in Meckel's cave. Acta Neurochir (Wien) 2023;165(07):1833&#x2013;1839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37099067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutierrez S, Iwanaga J, Dumont A S, Tubbs R S. Direct drainage of the basal vein of Rosenthal into the superior petrosal sinus: a literature review. Anat Cell Biol. 2020;53(04):379&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7769095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33148874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Przepiorka L, W&#xf3;jtowicz K, Camlet K et al. Postoperative cerebral venous sinus thrombosis following a retrosigmoid craniotomy&#x2014;a clinical and radiological analysis. Brain Sci. 2023;13(07):1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10377583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37508971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sattari S A, Shahbandi A, Xu R et al. Sacrifice or preserve the superior petrosal vein in microvascular decompression surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurosurg. 2022;138(02):390&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35901727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng L. Complications after obliteration of the superior petrosal vein: are they rare or just underreported? J Clin Neurosci. 2016;31:1&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27178112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia L, Liu M-X, Zhong J et al. Fatal complications following microvascular decompression: could it be avoided and salvaged? Neurosurg Rev. 2017;40(03):389&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27734209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartindale M, Mohamed A, Bell J et al. Neurotologic complications following microvascular decompression: a retrospective study. J Neurol Surg B Skull Base. 2020;81(01):37&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6997002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32021748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>