<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41647504</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2005-4408</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinics in orthopedic surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Orthop Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Red-White Zone Involvement and Medial Meniscal Tears Are Associated with Poorer Prognosis after Arthroscopic Repair of Bucket-Handle Tears.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>40</StartPage><EndPage>51</EndPage><MedlinePgn>40-51</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4055/cios25106</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Arthroscopic repair of bucket-handle meniscal tears (BHMTs) is technically challenging owing to the complexity of the tear patterns. Compared to simpler meniscal tears, BHMTs are associated with a higher failure rate and often require subsequent meniscectomy. This study aimed to assess clinical outcomes, failure rates, and risk factors for failure following primary arthroscopic repair of BHMTs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Seventy-four patients (mean age, 27.2 &#xb1; 11.2 years) who underwent arthroscopic BHMT repair were included (mean follow-up period, 60.2 &#xb1; 36.0 months). Analyzed risk factors included age, sex, body mass index, chronicity, laterality, tear zone, and concomitant anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Clinical failure was defined as the presence of clinical symptoms consistent with a meniscus tear and the need for subsequent surgery. The Kaplan-Meier method and log-rank test were performed to compare groups classified by postoperative meniscal healing status on magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) at a mean follow-up period of 7.30 &#xb1; 1.80 months. Clinical outcomes were assessed using the Tegner activity score, Lysholm knee score, and Hospital for Special Surgery (HSS) knee score.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The clinical failure rate was 14.9% (11 / 74). Six patients underwent subtotal meniscectomy, and 5 patients underwent partial meniscectomy. Red-white zone involvement was a significant risk factor for clinical failure (odds ratio, 6.182; 95% CI, 1.093-34.950; <i>p</i> = 0.039). Survival analysis based on postoperative MRI findings revealed a significant difference among 3 groups (<i>p</i> = 0.008): the completely healed group showed a 100% survival rate (20 / 20); the partially healed group, 80% (32 / 40); and the unhealed group, 0% (0 / 5). Patients with lateral BHMTs had a significantly higher rate of complete healing than those with medial BHMTs (46.4% vs. 18.9%; <i>p</i> = 0.014). At the final follow-up, the non-failure group demonstrated significantly higher Tegner activity (5.1 &#xb1; 1.2 vs. 4.4 &#xb1; 0.5; <i>p</i> = 0.038), Lysholm knee (87.7 &#xb1; 6.2 vs. 83.2 &#xb1; 3.1; <i>p</i> = 0.029), and HSS knee (93.9 &#xb1; 4.7 vs. 89.6 &#xb1; 3.0; <i>p</i> = 0.007) scores than the failure group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">BHMTs involving the red-white zone or located in the medial meniscus-particularly those showing inferior early postoperative MRI healing-should be closely monitored after surgery.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by The Korean Orthopaedic Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bae</LastName><ForeName>Bo Seung</ForeName><Initials>BS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7673-8541</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Graduate School, Kyung Hee University, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Jung Suk</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1186-271X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Graduate School, Kyung Hee University, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Sang Hak</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6711-6361</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Center for Joint Diseases and Rheumatism, Kyung Hee University Hospital at Gangdong, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Orthop Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101505087</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2005-291X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000070600" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tibial Meniscus Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001182" MajorTopicYN="Y">Arthroscopy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008592" MajorTopicYN="N">Menisci, Tibial</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anterior cruciate ligament</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bucket&#x2013;handle tear</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meniscal tears</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Menisci</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>CONFLICT OF INTEREST: No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41647504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12868098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4055/cios25106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nepple JJ, Dunn WR, Wright RW. Meniscal repair outcomes at greater than five years: a systematic literature review and meta-analysis. J Bone Jt Surg-Am Vol. 2012;94(24):2222&#x2013;2227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3528023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23318612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardizzone CA, Houck DA, McCartney DW, Vidal AF, Frank RM. All-inside repair of bucket-handle meniscal tears: clinical outcomes and prognostic factors. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48(13):3386&#x2013;3393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32195594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uzun E, Misir A, Kizkapan TB, Ozcamdalli M, Akkurt S, Guney A. Evaluation of midterm clinical and radiographic outcomes of arthroscopically repaired vertical longitudinal and bucket-handle lateral meniscal tears. Orthop J Sports Med. 2019;7(5):232596711984320</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6512156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31157282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hupperich A, Salzmann GM, Niemeyer P, et al. What are the factors to affect outcome and healing of meniscus bucket handle tears? Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2018;138(10):1365&#x2013;1373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29959519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moatshe G, Cinque ME, Godin JA, Vap AR, Chahla J, LaPrade RF. Comparable outcomes after bucket-handle meniscal repair and vertical meniscal repair can be achieved at a minimum 2 years&#x2019; follow-up. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45(13):3104&#x2013;3110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28806092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saltzman BM, Cotter EJ, Wang KC, et al. Arthroscopically repaired bucket-handle meniscus tears: patient demographics, postoperative outcomes, and a comparison of success and failure cases. CARTILAGE. 2020;11(1):77&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6921958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29957019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaunat M, Fournier G, O&#x2019;Loughlin P, et al. Clinical outcome and failure analysis of medial meniscus bucket-handle tear repair: a series of 96 patients with a minimum 2 year follow-up. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2020;140(11):1649&#x2013;1654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31993744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shakespeare DT, Rigby HS. The bucket-handle tear of the meniscus. A clinical and arthrographic study. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 1983;65:383&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6874707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubman MH, Noyes FR, Barber-Westin SD. Arthroscopic repair of meniscal tears that extend into the avascular zone. Am J Sports Med. 1998;26(1):87&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9474408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn JH, Kim KI, Wang JH, Kyung BS, Seo MC, Lee SH. Arthroscopic repair of bucket-handle tears of the lateral meniscus. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2015;23(1):205&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24213736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding DY, Tucker LY, Vieira AL, Freshman RD. Surgical outcomes after bucket-handle meniscal repairs: analysis of a large contained cohort. Am J Sports Med. 2022;50(9):2390&#x2013;2396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35647901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logan CA, Aman ZS, Kemler BR, Storaci HW, Dornan GJ, LaPrade RF. Influence of medial meniscus bucket-handle repair in setting of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction on tibiofemoral contact mechanics: a biomechanical study. Arthrosc J Arthrosc Relat Surg. 2019;35(8):2412&#x2013;2420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31395180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espejo-Reina A, Serrano-Fern&#xe1;ndez JM, Mart&#xed;n-Castilla B, Estades-Rubio FJ, Briggs KK, Espejo-Baena A. Outcomes after repair of chronic bucket-handle tears of medial meniscus. Arthrosc J Arthrosc Relat Surg. 2014;30(4):492&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24680309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa GG, Grassi A, Zocco G, et al. What is the failure rate after arthroscopic repair of bucket-handle meniscal tears? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2022;50(6):1742&#x2013;1752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34161741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalifis G, Raoulis V, Panteliadou F, Liantsis A, D&#x2019;Ambrosi R, Hantes M. Long-term follow-up of bucket-handle meniscal repairs: chondroprotective effect outweighs high failure risk. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2022;30(7):2209&#x2013;2214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34741626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer DE, Kalish LA, Martin DJ, et al. Outcomes after the operative treatment of bucket-handle meniscal tears in children and adolescents. Orthop J Sports Med. 2019;7(1):232596711882030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6350150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30729144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawashima I, Tsukahara T, Sakai T, et al. Delayed anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction increases the incidence of medial meniscal bucket handle tears and medial compartment chondral injuries in patients aged 40 years and older. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2021;141(6):971&#x2013;975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33426607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn JH, Lee SH, Kim KI, Nam J. Arthroscopic meniscus repair for recurrent subluxation of the lateral meniscus. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2018;26(3):787&#x2013;792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28258328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett G. Clinical results of meniscus repair in patients 40 years and older. Arthrosc J Arthrosc Relat Surg. 1998;14(8):824&#x2013;829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9848593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson AF, Irrgang JJ, Dunn W, et al. Interobserver reliability of the International Society of Arthroscopy, Knee Surgery and Orthopaedic Sports Medicine (ISAKOS) classification of meniscal tears. Am J Sports Med. 2011;39(5):926&#x2013;932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21411745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi NH, Kim BY, Hwang Bo BH, Victoroff BN. Suture versus FasT-Fix all-inside meniscus repair at time of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Arthrosc J Arthrosc Relat Surg. 2014;30(10):1280&#x2013;1286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25085047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon KH, Park JY, Kwon YB, Lee YJ, Kim EJ, Kim SG. Inside-out repair of the meniscus in concomitant anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: absorbable versus nonabsorbable sutures. Arthrosc J Arthrosc Relat Surg. 2020;36(4):1074&#x2013;1082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31948720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerritsen LM, van der Lelij TJ, van Schie P, et al. Higher healing rate after meniscal repair with concomitant ACL reconstruction for tears located in vascular zone 1 compared to zone 2: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2022;30(6):1976&#x2013;1989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9165248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35072757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chahla J, Alexander B, Robert &#x15a;. Evidence-based management of complex knee injuries: restoring the anatomy to achieve best outcomes. 1st ed. St. Louis: Elsevier; 2021. pp. 157&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent RH, Pope CF, Lynch JK, Jokl P. Magnetic resonance imaging of the surgically repaired meniscus: six-month follow-up. Magn Reson Imaging. 1991;9(3):335&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1881251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Bin SI, Kim JM, et al. Effect of high body mass index on survivorship after lateral meniscal allograft transplantation: a propensity score matching analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2023;51(8):2127&#x2013;2132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37249132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins AT, Kulvaranon M, Spritzer CE, McNulty AL, De-Frate LE. The influence of obesity and meniscal coverage on in vivo tibial cartilage thickness and strain. Orthop J Sports Med. 2020;8(12):2325967120964468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7720327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33330731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller RE, O&#x2019;Donnell EA, Medina GI, et al. Biological augmentation of meniscal repair: a systematic review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2022;30(6):1915&#x2013;1926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35258647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cong T, Reddy RP, Hall AJ, Ernazarov A, Gladstone J. Current practices for rehabilitation after meniscus repair: a survey of members of the American Orthopaedic Society for Sports Medicine. Orthop J Sports Med. 2024;12(2):23259671231226134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11025434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38639001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamura M, Furumatsu T, Kitayama T, et al. The preoperative flexion tear gap affects postoperative meniscus stability after pullout repair for medial meniscus posterior root tear. Knee Surg Relat Res. 2025;37(1):16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11969855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40181486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>