<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41530691</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2318</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC geriatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Geriatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acceptability and effectiveness of stationary bike intervention on health outcomes among older adults: a systematic review of intervention studies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>130</StartPage><MedlinePgn>130</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">130</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12877-025-06757-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Promoting physical activity (PA) among older adults is challenging due to physical limitations and varying levels of motivation. Stationary biking is a safe, non-weight-bearing form of exercise that is well-suited to this population. Although several studies have investigated stationary bike (SB) interventions, there is limited synthesis regarding their focus, effectiveness, and acceptability. This study aims to identify the primary focus areas of published SB interventions and evaluate their acceptability and impact on health outcomes in older adults.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Following PRISMA guidelines, a comprehensive search of seven databases was conducted up to June 18th, 2023, without restrictions on publication year. After duplicate records were removed, two independent reviewers screened studies in a two-phase process. Eligible studies included original intervention research reporting both baseline and post-intervention outcomes, in which stationary biking was employed either as a health assessment tool or as an intervention modality among individuals aged 60 years or older.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Out of 8,022 studies, 47 English-language articles were included: 28 Randomized Controlled Trials (RCTs) and 19 (40.43%) Non-RCTs, including Pretest-post-test and Quasi-Experimental studies. The most common focus points of the included studies were Cognitive function, Motor and Balance, Physiological and Psychological changes, Cardiovascular, and Executive function. The most common study populations had neurological problems (15/47, 31.91% studies). Among the 47 included studies, the highest participants&#x2019; acceptance rate was 38% (18/47 studies), while the retention rate was 15% (07/47 studies), the adherence rate was 6% (3/47 studies), and the lowest dropout rate was 13% (06/47 studies). Significant health outcomes after SB intervention included Aerobic capacity (VO<sub>2</sub> max), Cycling efficiency, Cognition, Executive function, Quality of life (QOL), and Mobility (Timed up and Go test), mentioned in at least 5 studies. About 25% (12/47) of all included studies used virtual aid (VA)-assisted SB intervention and among them 9 RCTs showed better improvement in cycling efficiency, cognition, and executive function compared to non-VA groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">A review of 47 studies found that stationary biking shows moderate acceptability (38%) and yields significant benefits in VO<sub>2</sub> max, cycling efficiency, cognition, executive function, quality of life, and mobility (Timed Up and Go test) in adults aged&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;60. Stationary biking especially when combined with VA, shows promise as a low-risk intervention to enhance physical and cognitive health in older adults, warranting further high-quality randomized trials to optimize its prescription.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12877-025-06757-0.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akter</LastName><ForeName>Taiyeba</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science and Sport, University of Erlangen- Nuremberg, Erlangen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical and Translational Biology, Ume&#xe5; University, Ume&#xe5;, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moneruzzaman</LastName><ForeName>Md</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Rehabilitation Medicine, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Rehabilitation Research Center, Beijing Bo'ai Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maduray</LastName><ForeName>Kellina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Qilu Hospital of Shandong University, Jinan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kader</LastName><ForeName>Manzur</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Science, School of Health and Welfare, Dalarna University, Falun, 791 88, Sweden. manzur.kader@outlook.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Geriatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968548</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2318</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acceptability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Effectiveness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Older adults</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">QOL</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stationary bike</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VA</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41530691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12857070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-025-06757-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12877-025-06757-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ageing. and health. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/ageing-and-health. Accessed 5 Apr 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarck S, Busse N, Ziegler G, Glanz W, Becke A, D&#xfc;zel E. Heart rate variability during physical exercise is associated with improved cognitive performance in alzheimer&#x2019;s dementia Patients&#x2014;A longitudinal feasibility study. Front Sports Act Living. 2021;3:684089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2021.684089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8319237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34337405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global recommendations on physical activity for health. https://www.who.int/publications-detail-redirect/9789241599979. Accessed 5 Apr 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogel T, Lepr&#xea;tre P-M, Brechat P-H, Lonsdorfer E, Benetos A, Kaltenbach G, et al. Effects of a short-term personalized intermittent work exercise program (IWEP) on maximal cardio-respiratory function and endurance parameters among healthy young and older seniors. J Nutr Health Aging. 2011;15:905&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12603-011-0087-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22159781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng SP, Yang CY, Tang FI, Chen IJ. Training effects of a 12-week walking program on Parkinson disease patients and community-dwelling older adults. NeuroRehabilitation. 2013;32:967&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/NRE-130920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23867422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh-Park M, Holtzer R, Mahoney J, Wang C, Verghese J. Effect of treadmill training on specific gait parameters in older adults with frailty: case series. J Geriatr Phys Ther. 2011;34:184&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JPT.0b013e3182193165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3226950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22124418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanderson B, Askew C, Stewart I, Walker P, Gibbs H, Green S. Short-term effects of cycle and treadmill training on exercise tolerance in peripheral arterial disease. J Vasc Surg. 2006;44:119&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jvs.2006.03.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16828435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauman AE, Rissel C. Cycling and health: an opportunity for positive change? Med J Aust. 2009;190:347&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5694/j.1326-5377.2009.tb02443.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19351304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C-W, Cho G-H. Effect of stationary cycle exercise on gait and balance of elderly women. J Phys Ther Sci. 2014;26:431&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.26.431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3976019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24707100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plante TG, Cacciatore TW. Might virtual reality promote the mood benefits of exercise? J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2003;25(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyness JM, Caine ED, King DA, Cox C, Yoediono Z. Psychiatric disorders in older primary care patients. J Gen Intern Med. 1999;14:249&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1525-1497.1999.00326.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1496563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10203638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzuto D, Orsini N, Qiu C, Wang HX, Fratiglioni L. Lifestyle, social factors, and survival after age 75: population based study. BMJ. 2012;345:e5568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.e5568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3431442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22936786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaesser G, Tucker WJ, Sawyer BJ, Bhammar DM, Angadi S. Cycling efficiency and energy cost of walking in young and older adults. J Appl Physiol. 2018;124:414&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00789.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29146688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu F. Improving recruitment, retention, and adherence to 6-month cycling in alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Geriatr Nurs. 2013;34:181&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gerinurse.2012.12.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5679113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23414638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher CG, Sherrington C, Herbert RD, Moseley AM, Elkins M. Reliability of the PEDro scale for rating quality of randomized controlled trials. Phys Ther. 2003;83:713&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/83.8.713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12882612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stang A. Critical evaluation of the Newcastle-Ottawa scale for the assessment of the quality of nonrandomized studies in meta-analyses. Eur J Epidemiol. 2010;25:603&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10654-010-9491-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20652370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antunes HK, De Mello MT, Santos-Galdur&#xf3;z RF, Galdur&#xf3;z JCF, Aquino Lemos V, Tufik S, et al. Effects of a physical fitness program on memory and blood viscosity in sedentary elderly men. Braz J Med Biol Res. 2015;48:805&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1414-431x20154529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4568808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26222648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha RM, Arsa G, Oliveira-Silva I, Ferreira Rocha I, Machado Lehnen A. Acute blood pressure effects in older adults with hypertension after different modalities of exercise: an experimental study. J Aging Phys Act. 2021;29:952&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33863853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emery CF. Effect of age on physiological and psychological functioning among COPD patients in an exercise program. J Agining Health. 1994;6:3&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/089826439400600101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11890183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari M, Vangelista A, Vedovi E, Falso M, Segattini C, Brotto E, et al. Minimally supervised home rehabilitation improves exercise capacity and health status in patients with COPD. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2004;83:337&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.PHM.0000124437.92263.BA</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15100621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraz DD, Trippo KV, Duarte GP, Neto MG, Bernardes Santos KO, Filho JO. The effects of functional Training, bicycle Exercise, and exergaming on walking capacity of elderly patients with Parkinson disease: A pilot randomized controlled Single-blinded trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2018;99:826&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2017.12.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29337023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou H-Y, Chen J, Hai L, Wang P, Zhang J-X, Li H-J. Effects of exergame and bicycle exercise intervention on blood pressure and executive function in older adults with hypertension: A three-group randomized controlled study. Exp Gerontol. 2023;173:112099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2023.112099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36681131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyce J, Smyth PJ, Donnelly AE, DaVAanche K. The Simon task and aging: does acute moderate exercise influence cognitive control? Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46:630&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3182a77980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23924921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katyal S, Freeman M, Miller JA, Thomas SG. Short-term aerobic training and circulatory function in women: age and hormone- replacement therapy. 2003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12605585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebeau JC, Mason J, Roque N, Tenenbaum G. The effects of acute exercise on driving and executive functions in healthy older adults. Int J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2022;20:283&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1612197X.2020.1849353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8992970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35401070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Garc&#xed;a J, Colado JC, Guzm&#xe1;n JF. Acute effects of aerobic exercise and active videogames on cognitive Flexibility, reaction Time, and perceived exertion in older adults. Games Health J. 2019;8:371&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/g4h.2018.0143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31199694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madden KM, Lockhart C, Cuff D, Potter TF, Meneilly GS. Short-term aerobic exercise reduces arterial stiffness in older adults with type 2 diabetes, hypertension, and hypercholesterolemia. Diabetes Care. 2009;32:1531&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc09-0149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2713633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19509011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morita N, Okita K. Is gender a factor in the reduction of cardiovascular risks with exercise training? Circ J. 2013;77:646&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1253/circj.CJ-12-0607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23220798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nocera JR, Mammino K, Kommula Y, Wharton W, Crosson B, McGregor KM. Effects of combined aerobic exercise and cognitive training on verbal fluency in older adults. Gerontol Geriatr Med. 2020;6:2333721419896884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2333721419896884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6950538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31950073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezasoltani Z, Sanati E, Kazempour Mofrad R, Azizi S, Dadarkhah A, Najafi S. Randomized controlled trial of aquatic cycling for treatment of knee osteoarthritis in elderly people. Top Geriatric Rehabilitation. 2020;36:103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TGR.0000000000000264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9467329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36343293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toll&#xe1;r J, Nagy F, T&#xf3;th BE, T&#xf6;r&#xf6;k K, Szita K, Csutor&#xe1;s B, et al. Exercise effects on multiple sclerosis quality of life and Clinical-Motor symptoms. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52:1007&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31876670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Cunha NM, Isbel ST, Frost J, Fearon A, McKune AJ, Naumovski N, et al. Effects of a virtual group cycling experience on people living with dementia: A mixed method pilot study. Dement (London). 2021;20:1518&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1471301220951328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32820955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwan RYC, Liu JYW, Fong KNK, Qin J, Leung PK-Y, Sin OSK, et al. Feasibility and effects of virtual reality Motor-Cognitive training in Community-Dwelling older people with cognitive frailty: pilot randomized controlled trial. JMIR Serious Games. 2021;9:e28400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/28400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8380584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34383662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Roie E, Martien S, Hurkmans E, Pelssers J, Seghers J, Boen F, et al. Ergometer-cycling with strict versus minimal contact supervision among the oldest adults: A cluster-randomised controlled trial. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2017;70:112&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.archger.2017.01.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28131050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S, Ji H, Won J, Jo E-A, Kim Y-S, Park J-J. The effects of exergaming on executive and physical functions in older adults with dementia: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2023;25:e39993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/39993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10031442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36881445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu F, Savik K, Wyman JF, Bronas UG. Maintaining physical fitness and function in alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: a pilot study. Am J Alzheimers Dis Other Demen. 2011;26:406&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1533317511414861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5679098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21750046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbas RL, Saab IM, Al-Sharif HK, Naja N, El-Khatib A. Effect of adding motorized cycle ergometer over exercise training on balance in older adults with dementia: A randomized controlled trial. Exp Aging Res. 2023;49:100&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0361073X.2022.2046947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35301911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson-Hanley C, Arciero PJ, Brickman AM, Nimon JP, Okuma N, Westen SC, et al. Exergaming and older adult cognition: a cluster randomized clinical trial. Am J Prev Med. 2012;42:109&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2011.10.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22261206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson-Hanley C, Arciero PJ, Westen SC, Nimon J, Zimmerman E. Neuropsychological benefits of stationary bike exercise and a cybercycle exergame for older adults with diabetes: an exploratory analysis. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2012;6:849&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/193229681200600416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3440156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22920811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson-Hanley C, Arciero P. Snyder. Social facilitation in virtual reality-enhanced exercise: competitiveness moderates exercise effort of older adults. CIA. 2011;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3212419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22087067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson-Hanley C, Barcelos NM, Zimmerman EA, Gillen RW, Dunnam M, Cohen BD, et al. The aerobic and cognitive exercise study (ACES) for Community-Dwelling older adults with or At-Risk for mild cognitive impairment (MCI): Neuropsychological, Neurobiological and neuroimaging outcomes of a randomized clinical trial. Front Aging Neurosci. 2018;10:76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2018.00076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5945889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29780318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barcelos N, Shah N, Cohen K, Hogan MJ, Mulkerrin E, Arciero PJ, et al. Aerobic and cognitive exercise (ACE) pilot study for older adults: executive function improves with cognitive challenge while exergaming. J Int Neuropsychol Soc. 2015;21:768&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1355617715001083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26581789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellumori M, Uygur M, Knight CA. High-Speed cycling intervention improves Rate-Dependent mobility in older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49:106&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5161700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27501360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buccola VA, Stone WJ. Effects of jogging and cycling programs on physiological and personality variables in aged men. Res Q. 1975;46:134&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1056059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brisswalter J, Wu SSX, Sultana F, Bernard T, Abbiss CR. Age difference in efficiency of locomotion and maximal power output in well-trained triathletes. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114:2579&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-014-2977-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25118840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callow DD, Pena GS, Stark CEL, Smith JC. Effects of acute aerobic exercise on mnemonic discrimination performance in older adults. J Int Neuropsychol Soc. 2023;29:519&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1355617722000492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10538177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35968853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cicek A, Ozdincler AR, Tarakci E. Interactive video game-based approaches improve mobility and mood in older adults: A nonrandomized, controlled tri&#x307;al. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2020;24:252&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2020.01.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32825997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombo V, Mondellini M, Fumagalli A, Aliverti A, Sacco M. A virtual reality-based endurance training program for COPD patients: acceptability and user experience. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. 2023:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37272556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitlin LN, Lawton MP, Windsor-landsberg lisa A, Kleban MH, Sands laura P, Posner J. In search of psychological benefits exercise in healthy older adults. J Agining Health. 1992;4:174&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/089826439200400202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill MW, Oxford SW, Duncan MJ, Price MJ. The effects of arm crank ergometry, cycle ergometry and treadmill walking on postural sway in healthy older females. Gait Posture. 2015;41:252&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2014.10.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25455437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loggia G, Gauthier A, Lemiere F, Drigny J, Desvergee A, Leconte P, et al. Cycle more with virtual reality: a proof of concept study in an institutionalised able-bodied geriatric population. Age Ageing. 2021;50:1422&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afab040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33677476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahajan A, Mahajan S, Tilekar S. A pilot randomized controlled trial of interval training and sleep hygiene for improving sleep in older adults. J Aging Phys Act. 2021;29:993&#x2013;1002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33837158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miki E, Kataoka T, Okamura H. Feasibility and efficacy of speed-feedback therapy with a bicycle ergometer on cognitive function in elderly cancer patients in Japan. Psychooncology. 2014;23:906&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.3501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24532471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauwels C, Roren A, Gautier A, Lini&#xe8;res J, Rannou F, Poiraudeau S, et al. Home-based cycling program tailored to older people with lumbar spinal stenosis: barriers and facilitators. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2018;61:144&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rehab.2018.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29499383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Posner JD, Gorman KM, Windsor-Landsberg L, Larsen J, Bleiman M, Shaw C, et al. Low to moderate intensity endurance training in healthy older adults: physiological responses after four months. J Am Geriatr Soc. 1992;40:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.1992.tb01820.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1727835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridgel AL, Ault DL. High-Cadence cycling promotes sustained improvement in Bradykinesia, Rigidity, and mobility in individuals with Mild-Moderate parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease. 2019;2019:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/4076862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6421744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30944720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salisbury D, Mathiason MA, Yu F. Exercise dose and aerobic fitness response in alzheimer&#x2019;s dementia: findings from the FIT-AD trial. Int J Sports Med. 2022;43:850&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1639-2307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34492709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarck S, Busse N, Ziegler G, Glanz W, Becke A, D&#xfc;zel E. Heart rate variability during physical exercise is associated with improved cognitive performance in alzheimer&#x2019;s dementia Patients-A longitudinal feasibility study. Front Sports Act Living. 2021;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8319237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34337405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willenheimer R, Erhardt L, Cline C, Rydberg E, Israelsson B. Exercise training in heart failure improves quality of life and exercise capacity. Eur Heart J. 1998;19:774&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/euhj.1997.0853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9717012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu F, Vock DM, Zhang L, Salisbury D, Nelson NW, Chow LS, et al. Cognitive effects of aerobic exercise in alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: A pilot randomized controlled trial. J Alzheimers Dis. 2021;80:233&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-201100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8075384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33523004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogel T, Brechat P-H, Lepr&#xea;tre P-M, Kaltenbach G, Berthel M, Lonsdorfer J. Health benefits of physical activity in older patients: a review. Int J Clin Pract. 2009;63:303&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1742-1241.2008.01957.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19196369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graves JM, Iyer KR, Willis MM, Ebel BE, Rivara FP, Vavilala MS. Emergency department-reported injuries associated with mechanical home exercise equipment in the USA. Inj Prev. 2014;20:281&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/injuryprev-2013-040833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4306571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24061163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Yu null. Guiding research and practice: a conceptual model for aerobic exercise training in alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Am J Alzheimers Dis Other Demen. 2011;26:184&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1533317511402317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5898238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21429955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toll&#xe1;r J, Nagy F, Moizs M, T&#xf3;th BE, Sanders LMJ, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T. Diverse exercises similarly reduce older adults&#x2019; mobility limitations. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51:1809&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30973482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JPT, Rothstein HR. Introduction to meta-analysis. Wiley; 2009. 10.1002/9780470743386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang MYC, Eng JJ, Dawson AS, Gylfad&#xf3;ttir S. The use of aerobic exercise training in improving aerobic capacity in individuals with stroke: a meta-analysis. Clin Rehabil. 2006;20:97&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/0269215506cr926oa</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3167867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16541930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>