<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41606012</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integration of &#x3b2;-VAE, DWT, and GMM for Sentinel-2-based mapping of hydrothermal alteration and iron speciation in the Zafarghand area, Iran.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6470</StartPage><MedlinePgn>6470</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">6470</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-36349-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Remote sensing (RS) technologies have emerged as efficient and cost-effective tools for the rapid identification of hydrothermal alteration zones, thereby supporting mineral exploration. The Zafarghand area in northeastern Isfahan Province, situated within the Central Iran structural zone of the Urmia&#x2013;Dokhtar magmatic arc, hosts a porphyry system with multiple alteration types, including phyllic, propylitic, argillic, potassic, and silicic zones. This study aimed to develop an unsupervised and data-driven framework for mapping hydrothermal alteration using high-resolution satellite imagery. To achieve this, Sentinel-2 data were processed through a &#x3b2;-Variational Autoencoder (&#x3b2;-VAE) Deep Learning (DL) model, enriched by Discrete Wavelet Transform (DWT), and subsequently clustered with a Gaussian Mixture Model (GMM). The proposed approach successfully identified alteration zones and iron-bearing minerals (Fe&#xb2;&#x207a;, Fe&#xb3;&#x207a;, and iron oxides) at a 20-m spatial resolution. Validation using geochemical data showed classification accuracies of 94.74% and 95.74% for the phyllic and propylitic zones, respectively. In addition, buffered pixel-based validation using confusion matrices yielded overall accuracies of 94.5% and 86.9% for the phyllic and propylitic maps, confirming the statistical robustness of the proposed framework. Due to the limited distribution of argillic and silicic alteration, the depth of the potassic zone, and the lack of sufficient geochemical data for their validation, this study mainly focused on identifying phyllic and propylitic alteration along with iron oxides.These findings demonstrate that integrating DL, wavelet analysis, and probabilistic clustering with Sentinel-2 imagery provides a robust framework for detecting hydrothermal alteration zones. While the current study primarily focused on phyllic, propylitic, and iron-oxide zones due to limitations in data availability, the framework is transferable to other porphyry systems, provided that suitable reference data exist for validation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41598-026-36349-w.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalkhoran</LastName><ForeName>Samane Esmaelzade</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mining Engineering, Amirkabir University of Technology (Tehran Polytechnic), Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghannadpour</LastName><ForeName>Seyyed Saeed</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mining Engineering, Amirkabir University of Technology (Tehran Polytechnic), Tehran, Iran. s.ghannadpour@aut.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Discrete wavelet transform (DWT)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gaussian mixture model (GMM)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrothermal alteration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Iron oxide mapping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sentinel-2 image</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">&#x392;-variational autoencoder (&#x3b2;-VAE)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41606012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12910021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-36349-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-36349-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Okada, K. Breakthrough technologies for mineral exploration. <i>Min. Econ.</i><b>35</b>, 429. 10.1007/s13563-022-00317-3 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13563-022-00317-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirmard, H., Farahbakhsh, E., M&#xfc;ller, R. D. &amp; Chandra, R. A review of machine learning in processing remote sensing data for mineral exploration. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>268</b>, 112750 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2021.112750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajesh, H. M. Application of remote sensing and GIS in mineral resource mapping&#x2014;An overview. <i>J. Mineral. Petrol. Sci.</i><b>99</b>, 83&#x2013;103. 10.2465/jmps.99.83 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2465/jmps.99.83</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent, R. K. <i>Fundamentals of Geological and Environmental Remote Sensing</i> (Prentice Hall, 1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, R. P. <i>Remote Sensing Geology</i> 2nd edn (Springer, 2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prost, G. L. <i>Remote Sensing for Geoscientists&#x2014;Image Analysis and Integration</i> 3rd edn (CRC, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manuel, R., Brito, M. D. G., Chichorro, M. &amp; Rosa, C. Remote sensing for mineral exploration in central Portugal. <i>Minerals</i><b>7</b>, 184. 10.3390/min7100184 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min7100184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sillitoe, R. H. Porphyry copper systems. <i>Econ. Geol.</i><b>105</b>, 3&#x2013;41. 10.2113/gsecongeo.105.1.3 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2113/gsecongeo.105.1.3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, Y., Cheng, Q., Jing, L., Ye, B. &amp; Fu, H. Mineral prospectivity mapping of porphyry copper deposits based on remote sensing imagery and geochemical data in the Duolong ore district, Tibet. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>15</b>, 439 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs15020439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdellatif, M. et al. Revealing porphyry mineralization Cu-Au signatures via analyzing aeromagnetic and remote sensing data of Dara-Monqul, area Egypt. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 26903. 10.1038/s41598-025-09809-y (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-09809-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12290052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40707507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallaha, M., Jamali, H., Alaminia, Z. &amp; Pour, A. B. ASTER remote sensing data for detecting porphyry copper type alteration patterns in West Zafarghand Cu&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;Mo deposit, Iran. <i>Int. J. Image Data Fusion</i> (in press). 10.1080/19479832.2024.2429589</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain, R., Bhu, H., Pandey, A. K. &amp; Pour, A. B. Base-metal exploration by using remote sensing, geology, geophysical, and geochemical datasets with clues from ancient mining: A comprehensive review on Aravalli&#x2013;Delhi fold Belt, Rajasthan, India. <i>Adv. Space Res.</i><b>75</b>, 277&#x2013;315. 10.1016/j.asr.2024.09.038 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asr.2024.09.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmani, N. et al. Evaluation of support vector machine classifiers for lithological mapping using PRISMA hyperspectral remote sensing data: Sahand&#x2013;Bazman magmatic arc, central Iran. <i>Remote Sens. Appl. Soc. Environ.</i><b>37</b>, 101449. 10.1016/j.rsase.2025.101449 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rsase.2025.101449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arian, H. et al. Mapping potential zones of Lithium-bearing pegmatites using ASTER and Sentinel-2 remote sensing imagery in the Tagablor Pegmatite Field, Central Afghanistan. <i>Remote Sens. Appl. Soc. Environ.</i> , 101625 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, L., Fan, H. &amp; Ulrich, T. Editorial for special issue critical metals in hydrothermal ores: resources, recovery, and challenges. <i>Minerals</i><b>11</b>, 299. 10.3390/books978-3-0365-1921-0 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/books978-3-0365-1921-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habashi, J., Jamshid Moghadam, H., Mohammady Oskouei, M., Pour, A. B. &amp; Hashim, M. PRISMA hyperspectral remote sensing data for mapping alteration minerals in Sar-e-Ch&#xe2;h-e-Shur region, Birjand, Iran. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>16</b>, 1277. 10.3390/rs16071277 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs16071277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habashi, J. et al. Revealing critical mineralogical insights in extreme environments using deep learning technique on hyperspectral PRISMA satellite imagery: dry Valleys, South Victoria Land, Antarctica. <i>ISPRS J. Photogramm Remote Sens.</i><b>228</b>, 83&#x2013;121. 10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2025.07.005 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2025.07.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, C. et al. Deep learning-based geological map generation using geological routes. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>309</b>, 114214. 10.1016/j.rse.2024.114214 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2024.114214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeCun, Y., Bengio, Y. &amp; Hinton, G. Deep learning. <i>Nature</i><b>521</b>, 436&#x2013;444. 10.1038/nature14539 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature14539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26017442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bengio, Y. Learning deep architectures for AI. <i>Found. Trends Mach. Learn.</i><b>2</b>, 1&#x2013;127. 10.1561/2200000006 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1561/2200000006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo, R., Luo, Z., Xiong, Y. &amp; Yin, B. A geologically constrained variational autoencoder for mineral prospectivity mapping. <i>Nat. Resour. Res.</i><b>31</b>, 1121&#x2013;1133. 10.1007/s11053-021-09994-9 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11053-021-09994-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohandoss, T., Kulkarni, A., Northrup, D., Mwebaze, E. &amp; Alemohammad, H. Generating synthetic multispectral satellite imagery from Sentinel-2. <i>ArXiv Preprint arXiv:2012 03108</i>. 10.48550/arXiv.2012.03108 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2012.03108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, B., Xu, Y., Wan, B., Wu, X. &amp; Yi, G. Hydrothermally altered mineral mapping using synthetic application of Sentinel-2A MSI, ASTER and Hyperion data in the Duolong area, Tibetan Plateau, China. <i>Ore Geol. Rev.</i><b>101</b>, 384&#x2013;397 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2018.07.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge, W. et al. Assessment of the capability of Sentinel-2 imagery for iron-bearing minerals mapping: A case study in the Cuprite area, Nevada. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>12</b>, 3028. 10.3390/rs12183028 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs12183028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Q. et al. Interpretation of hydrothermal alteration and structural framework of the Huize Pb&#x2013;Zn deposit, SW China, using Sentinel-2, ASTER, and Gaofen-5 satellite data: implications for Pb&#x2013;Zn exploration. <i>Ore Geol. Rev.</i><b>150</b>, 105154. 10.1016/j.oregeorev.2022.105154 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2022.105154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aminroayaei Yamini, M., Tutti, F., Aminoroayaei Yamini, M. R., Ahmadian, J. &amp; Wan, B. Examination of chloritization of biotite as a tool for reconstructing the physicochemical parameters of mineralization and associated alteration in the Zafarghand porphyry copper system, Ardestan, central iran: Mineral-chemistry and stable isotope analyses. <i>Mineral. Petrol.</i><b>111</b>, 747&#x2013;759 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00710-016-0486-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmaelzadeh Kalkhoran, S., Ghannadpour, S. S., Moeini Rad, A. &amp; Jalili, H. Comparing the performance of ASTER and LANDSAT 8 satellite images in identifying iron oxide and porphyry copper alterations in Zafarghand region of Isfahan Province. <i>J. Mineral. Res. Eng.</i><b>9</b>, 41&#x2013;65. 10.30479/jmre.2023.19459.1669 (2024a).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30479/jmre.2023.19459.1669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghannadpour, S. S., Hasiri, M., Shahrabi, H. S. &amp; Jalili, H. Mapping alteration zones associated with Cu mineralization: an approach based on image processing using the singularity method and fuzzy gamma operator. <i>Kharazmi J. Earth Sci.</i><b>10</b>, 91&#x2013;122 (2024b).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalkhoran, S. E., Ghannadpour, S. S. &amp; Pour, A. B. Optimized hydrothermal alteration mapping in porphyry copper systems using a hybrid DWT-2D/MAD algorithm on ASTER satellite remote sensing imagery. <i>Minerals</i><b>15</b>, 626. 10.3390/min15060626 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min15060626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghorbani, M. An introduction to the economic geology of Iran. Publ. Natl. Geosci. Database Country (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geological and Mineral Exploration Organization of Iran. Report on systematic geochemical exploration on a 1:100,000 scale in Ardestan. (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radfar, J. <i>Geological Map of Ardestan, Scale 1:100,000. Geol</i> (Surv, 1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alaminia, Z., Bagheri, H. &amp; Salehi, M. Geochemical and geophysical investigations and fluid inclusion studies in the exploration area of Zafarghand (northeast Isfahan, Iran). <i>J. Econ. Geol.</i><b>9</b>, 295&#x2013;312. 10.22067/econg.v9i2.56334 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22067/econg.v9i2.56334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi, M. H. <i>An Introduction To the Geology of Iran</i> (Geological Organization of Iran, 1976).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghian, M. &amp; Ghaffary, M. The petrogenesis of Zafarghand granitoid Pluton (SE of Ardestan). <i>Petrol. J.</i><b>2</b>, 47&#x2013;70 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aminoroayaei Yamini, M., Tutti, F., Haschke, M., Ahmadian, J. &amp; Murata, M. Synorogenic copper mineralization during the Alpine&#x2013;Himalayan orogeny in the Zafarghand copper exploration district, central iran: Petrography, geochemistry, and alteration thermometry. <i>Geol. J.</i><b>52</b>, 263&#x2013;281. 10.1002/gj.2755 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/gj.2755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aminoroayaei Yamini, M., Tutti, F. &amp; Ahmadian, J. Hydrothermal alteration of porphyry copper deposit in the Southwest of Zafarghand with emphasis on mineralogical and geochemical changes in the area. <i>J. Earth Sci. Res.</i><b>7</b>, 75&#x2013;90 (2016). https://dorl.net/dor/20.1001.1.20088299.1395.7.1.6.7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghannadpour, S. S. &amp; Kalkhoran, S. E. Spatial analysis of Zafarghand porphyry copper system alterations using a combination of singularity and U-Statistics methods. <i>Iran. J. Sci.</i> 1&#x2013;17. 10.1007/s40995-025-01828-8 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madani, A. &amp; Harbi, H. Spectroscopy of the mineralized tonalite&#x2013;diorite intrusions, Bulghah gold mine area, Saudi arabia: effects of opaques and alteration products on fieldspec data. <i>Ore Geol. Rev.</i><b>44</b>, 148&#x2013;157 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2011.09.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunt, G. R. Spectral signatures of particulate minerals in the visible and near infrared. <i>Geophysics</i><b>42</b>, 501&#x2013;513 (1977).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1190/1.1440721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi, S., Nadimi, A. R. &amp; Aalaminia, Z. Investigating the relationship between mineralization and alteration zones with tectonic structures using remote sensing studies in the Southern Ardestan region (northeast of Isfahan). <i>Geophysics</i><b>7</b>, 29&#x2013;47 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghafari, M. Petrology and geochemistry of the granitoid massif of southern Zafarghand (Ardestan). MSc thesis, Faculty of Earth Sciences, Shahrood Univ. Technol., Semnan, Iran (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavanji, N. Investigation of the replacement mechanism of the granitoid mass in southern Zafarghand (Ardestan) using the AMS method. MSc thesis, Faculty of Science, Dept. of Geology, Shahrood Univ. Technol. (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu, H. Y. et al. Zircon U&#x2013;Pb age constraints from Iran on the magmatic evolution related to neotethyan subduction and Zagros orogeny. <i>Lithos</i><b>162&#x2013;163</b>, 70&#x2013;87. 10.1016/j.lithos.2012.12.010 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lithos.2012.12.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aminoroayaei Yamini, M., Touti, F., Ahmadian, J. &amp; Aminoroayaei Yamini, M. R. Magmatic mixing as the main factor in the accumulation of copper in the Zafarghand porphyry copper deposit. Proc. 7th Conf. Iranian Econ. Geol. Soc., Damghan Univ., Iran (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radoux, J. et al. Sentinel-2&#x2019;s potential for sub-pixel landscape feature detection. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>8</b>, 488. 10.3390/rs8060488 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs8060488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pahlevan, N., Sarkar, S., Franz, B. A., Balasubramanian, S. V. &amp; He, J. Sentinel-2 multispectral instrument (MSI) data processing for aquatic science applications: demonstrations and validations. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>201</b>, 47&#x2013;56. 10.1016/j.rse.2017.08.033 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2017.08.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boumahdi, M., Garc&#xed;a-Pedrero, A., Lillo-Saavedra, M. &amp; Gonzalo-Martin, C. A new benchmark for Spatiotemporal fusion of Sentinel-2 and Sentinel-3 OLCI images. <i>Earth Sci. Inf.</i><b>18</b>, 349. 10.1007/s12145-025-01855-4 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12145-025-01855-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanaras, C., Bioucas-Dias, J., Galliani, S., Baltsavias, E. &amp; Schindler, K. Super-resolution of Sentinel-2 images: learning a globally applicable deep neural network. <i>ISPRS J. Photogramm Remote Sens.</i><b>146</b>, 305&#x2013;319. 10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2018.09.018 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2018.09.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pahlevan, N., Chittimalli, S. K., Balasubramanian, S. V. &amp; Vellucci, V. Sentinel-2/Landsat-8 product consistency and implications for monitoring aquatic systems. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>220</b>, 19&#x2013;29. 10.1016/j.rse.2018.10.027 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2018.10.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loughlin, W. P. Principal component analysis for alteration mapping. <i>Photogramm Eng. Remote Sens.</i><b>57</b>, 1163&#x2013;1169 (1991).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis, J. et al. IEEE,. Sentinel-2 global surface reflectance level-2A product generated with Sen2Cor. In <i>Proc. IEEE Int. Geosci. Remote Sens. Symp. (IGARSS)</i> 8522&#x2013;8525 (2019). 10.1109/IGARSS.2019.8898540</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju, J. et al. The harmonized Landsat and Sentinel-2 version 2.0 surface reflectance dataset. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>324</b>, 114723. 10.1016/j.rse.2025.114723 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2025.114723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claverie, M., Masek, J. G., Ju, J. &amp; Dungan, J. L. <i>Harmonized Landsat-8 Sentinel-2 (HLS) Product User&#x2019;s Guide</i> (NASA, 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabbaghi, H., Moradzadeh, A. &amp; Asadi Haron, H. ASTER spectral analysis for host rock associated with porphyry copper-molybdenum mineralization. <i>Geologica Macedonica</i>. <b>31</b> (1), 49&#x2013;65 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghojogh, B., Ghodsi, A., Karray, F. &amp; Crowley, M. Factor analysis, probabilistic principal component analysis, variational inference, and variational autoencoder: tutorial and survey. <i>ArXiv</i> ArXiv:2101.00734 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milano, N., Casella, M., Esposito, R. &amp; Marocco, D. Exploring the potential of variational autoencoders for modeling nonlinear relationships in psychological data. <i>Behav. Sci.</i><b>14</b>, 527. 10.3390/bs14070527 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bs14070527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11273997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39062350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai, J., Kong, S. &amp; Gomes, C. P. PMLR,. Gaussian mixture variational autoencoder with contrastive learning for multi-label classification. In <i>Proc. Int. Conf. Mach. Learn.</i> 1383&#x2013;1398 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, I. et al. beta-VAE: Learning basic visual concepts with a constrained variational framework. In <i>Proc. Int. Conf. Learn. Represent.</i> (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess, C. P. et al. Understanding disentangling in &#x3b2;-VAE. <i>ArXiv</i>10.48550/ArXiv.1804.03599 (2018). ArXiv:1804.03599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1804.03599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingma, D. P. &amp; Welling, M. Auto-encoding variational Bayes. <i>ArXiv arXiv</i> :13126114 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farge, M. Wavelet transforms and their applications to turbulence. <i>Annu. Rev. Fluid Mech.</i><b>24</b>, 395&#x2013;458 (1991).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.fl.24.010192.002143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrus, C. S., Gopinath, R. A. &amp; Guo, H. <i>Wavelets and Wavelet Transforms</i> (Rice University, 1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Fleet, P. J. <i>Discrete Wavelet Transformations: an Elementary Approach with Applications</i> (Wiley, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Percival, D. B. <i>Wavelet Methods for time Series Analysis</i> (Cambridge University Press, 2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demirel, H. &amp; Anbarjafari, G. Discrete wavelet transform-based satellite image resolution enhancement. <i>IEEE Trans. Geosci. Remote Sens.</i><b>49</b>, 1997&#x2013;2004. 10.1109/TGRS.2010.2100401 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TGRS.2010.2100401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallat, S. G. A theory for multiresolution signal decomposition: the wavelet representation. <i>IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell.</i><b>11</b>, 674&#x2013;693. 10.1109/34.192463 (1989).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/34.192463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds, D. A. Gaussian mixture models. In <i>Encyclopedia of Biometrics</i> (ed. Li, S. Z.) 827&#x2013;832Springer, (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viroli, C. &amp; McLachlan, G. J. Deep Gaussian mixture models. <i>Stat. Comput.</i><b>29</b>, 43&#x2013;51. 10.1007/s11222-017-9793-z (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11222-017-9793-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzaii, M., Bagheri, H. &amp; Ayati, F. Determination and mapping of hydrothermal alteration zones in exploration Marbin area (North of Zefreh) by remote sensing, field observations and petrology investigations. <i>Petrological J.</i><b>10</b> (3), 1&#x2013;24 (2019).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>