<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41527186</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-445X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>111</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of live-high, train-low strategy induced by chronic low-dose carbon monoxide exposure on haematological parameters and performance in trained individuals.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1891</StartPage><EndPage>1903</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1891-1903</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/EP093005</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Altitude training enhances haematological adaptations and endurance at sea level, typically requiring exposure to &#x223c;2500&#xa0;m altitude for 3-4&#xa0;weeks. Emerging evidence suggests that low-dose carbon monoxide (CO) inhalation might mimic hypoxia and might be used by elite athletes. In this study, we examine whether periodic low-dose CO exposure can replicate the live-high, train-low model in well-trained individuals, focusing primarily on haematological and performance effects of CO exposure, with haematological markers commonly used to interpret haemoglobin mass changes discussed as exploratory. Eight well-trained individuals (four males and four females) participated in a randomized crossover study. They completed two training blocks of 4&#xa0;weeks at sea level: one with CO inhalation (INCO) to simulate live-high, train-low and one with ambient air as a control (AIR), separated by a 6&#xa0;month washout. Haematological variables, in vivo muscle oxidative capacity and performance metrics were assessed before and after each intervention. After INCO, haemoglobin mass (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.018; +53.6&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;10.8 g. vs. +0.8&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;11.8&#xa0;g), red blood cell volume (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.032; +156.6&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;66.7 mL vs. -65.1&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;50.7 mL) and blood volume (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.036; +240.4&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;120.5 mL vs. -208.3&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;167.5 mL) increased significantly compared with AIR. INCO significantly reduced immature reticulocytes (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.04), but muscle oxidative capacity and performance metrics remained unchanged. These findings suggest that daily low-dose CO exposure at sea level over 4 weeks enhanced haematological adaptations more than standard training but did not affect muscle oxidative capacity or performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Experimental Physiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Villanova</LastName><ForeName>Simone</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement, Human and Health Sciences, University of Rome 'Foro Italico', Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Porcelli</LastName><ForeName>Simone</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9494-0858</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine, University of Pavia, Pavia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ekstr&#xf6;m</LastName><ForeName>Lena</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine, Division of Clinical Pharmacology, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cardinale</LastName><ForeName>Daniele A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8607-550X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Nutrition and Biomechanics, The Swedish School of Sport and Health Sciences GIH, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Pharmacology, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P2022-0019</GrantID><Agency>The Swedish National Centre for Research in Sports</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>D2020-0010</GrantID><Agency>The Swedish National Centre for Research in Sports</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9002940</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0958-0670</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7U1EE4V452</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002248">Carbon Monoxide</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006454">Hemoglobins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002248" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carbon Monoxide</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000531" MajorTopicYN="N">Altitude</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006454" MajorTopicYN="N">Hemoglobins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010101" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen Consumption</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elite athlete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endurance performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">erythropoiesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">haemoglobin mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypoxia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mitochondria</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41527186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP093005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Adami, A., Cao, R., Porszasz, J., Casaburi, R., &amp; Rossiter, H. B. (2017). Reproducibility of NIRS assessment of muscle oxidative capacity in smokers with and without COPD. Respiratory Physiology &amp; Neurobiology, 235, 18&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astridge, D. J., McKenna, M., Campbell, A., &amp; Turner, A. P. (2024). Haemoglobin mass responses and performance outcomes among high&#x2010;performance swimmers following a 3&#x2010;week live&#x2010;high, train&#x2010;high camp at 2320 m. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 124(8), 2389&#x2013;2399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal, S., Liu, D., Mao, Q., Bauer, N., &amp; Wang, B. (2024). Carbon monoxide as a potential therapeutic agent: A molecular analysis of its safety profiles. Journal of Medicinal Chemistry, 67(12), 9789&#x2013;9815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barstow, T. J. (2019). Understanding near infrared spectroscopy and its application to skeletal muscle research. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md.: 1985), 126(5), 1360&#x2013;1376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonetti, D. L., &amp; Hopkins, W. G. (2009). Sea&#x2010;level exercise performance following adaptation to hypoxia: A meta&#x2010;analysis. Sports Medicine (Auckland, N.Z.), 39(2), 107&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;ning, D., Maassen, N., Thomas, A., &amp; Steinacker, J. M. (2001). Extracellular pH defense against lactic acid in normoxia and hypoxia before and after a Himalayan expedition. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 84(1&#x2010;2), 78&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonne, T. C., Lundby, C., Lundby, A. K., Sander, M., Bejder, J., &amp; Nordsborg, N. B. (2015). Altitude training causes haematological fluctuations with relevance for the athlete biological passport. Drug Testing and Analysis, 7(8), 655&#x2013;662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boone, J., Barstow, T. J., Celie, B., Prieur, F., &amp; Bourgois, J. (2016). The interrelationship between muscle oxygenation, muscle activation, and pulmonary oxygen uptake to incremental ramp exercise: Influence of aerobic fitness. Applied Physiology, Nutrition, and Metabolism, 41(1), 55&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breenfeldt Andersen, A., Bonne, T. C., Hansen, J., Oturai, P., &amp; Lundby, C. (2023). Validation of a clinically applicable device for fast and accurate quantification of blood volume. Journal of Clinical Laboratory Analysis, 37(9&#x2010;10), e24928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burge, C. M., &amp; Skinner, S. L. (1995). Determination of hemoglobin mass and blood volume with CO: Evaluation and application of a method. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md. : 1985), 79(2), 623&#x2013;631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chance, B., Erecinska, M., &amp; Wagner, M. (1970). Mitochondrial responses to carbon monoxide toxicity. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 174(1), 193&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman, R. F., Stray&#x2010;Gundersen, J., &amp; Levine, B. D. (1998). Individual variation in response to altitude training. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md.: 1985), 85(4), 1448&#x2013;1456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constantini, K., Wilhite, D. P., &amp; Chapman, R. F. (2017). A clinician guide to altitude training for optimal endurance exercise performance at sea level. High Altitude Medicine &amp; Biology, 18(2), 93&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas, C. G., Haldane, J. S., &amp; Haldane, J. B. (1912). The laws of combination of haemoglobin with carbon monoxide and oxygen. The Journal of Physiology, 44(4), 275&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durante, W., Johnson, F. K., &amp; Johnson, R. A. (2006). Role of carbon monoxide in cardiovascular function. Journal of Cellular and Molecular Medicine, 10(3), 672&#x2013;686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekblom, B., &amp; Huot, R. (1972). Response to submaximal and maximal exercise at different levels of carboxyhemoglobin. Acta Physiologica Scandinavica, 86(4), 474&#x2013;482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eklund, E., Andersson, A., Ekstrom, L., &amp; Hirschberg, A. L. (2021). Urinary steroid profile in elite female athletes in relation to serum androgens and in comparison with untrained controls. Frontiers in Physiology, 12, 702305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faiss, R., &amp; Krumm, B. (2024). Carbon monoxide rebreathing as a doping method &#x2013; A toxic debate. Drug Testing and Analysis, 17(7), 942&#x2013;943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faude, O., Kindermann, W., &amp; Meyer, T. (2009). Lactate threshold concepts: How valid are they? Sports Medicine (Auckland, N.Z.), 39(6), 469&#x2013;490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari, M., Muthalib, M., &amp; Quaresima, V. (2011). The use of near&#x2010;infrared spectroscopy in understanding skeletal muscle physiology: Recent developments. Philosophical Transactions. Series A, Mathematical, Physical, and Engineering Sciences, 369(1955), 4577&#x2013;4590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foresti, R., Bani&#x2010;Hani, M. G., &amp; Motterlini, R. (2008). Use of carbon monoxide as a therapeutic agent: Promises and challenges. Intensive Care Medicine, 34(4), 649&#x2013;658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvican, L. A., Pottgiesser, T., Martin, D. T., Schumacher, Y. O., Barras, M., &amp; Gore, C. J. (2011). The contribution of haemoglobin mass to increases in cycling performance induced by simulated LHTL. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 111(6), 1089&#x2013;1101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvican&#x2010;Lewis, L. A., Sharpe, K., &amp; Gore, C. J. (2016). Time for a new metric for hypoxic dose? Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md.: 1985), 121(1), 352&#x2013;355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard, O., Brocherie, F., Goods, P. S. R., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2020). An updated panorama of "Living Low&#x2010;Training High" altitude/hypoxic methods. Frontiers in Sports and Active Living, 2, 26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard, O., Levine, B. D., Chapman, R. F., &amp; Wilber, R. (2023). Living High&#x2010;Training Low" for Olympic Medal Performance: What Have We Learned 25 Years After Implementation? International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 18(6), 563&#x2013;572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gore, C. J., Hahn, A. G., Aughey, R. J., Martin, D. T., Ashenden, M. J., Clark, S. A., Garnham, A. P., Roberts, A. D., Slater, G. J., &amp; McKenna, M. J. (2001). Live high: Train low increases muscle buffer capacity and submaximal cycling efficiency. Acta Physiologica Scandinavica, 173(3), 275&#x2013;286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gore, C. J., Sharpe, K., Garvican&#x2010;Lewis, L. A., Saunders, P. U., Humberstone, C. E., Robertson, E. Y., Wachsmuth, N. B., Clark, S. A., McLean, B. D., Friedmann&#x2010;Bette, B., Neya, M., Pottgiesser, T., Schumacher, Y. O., &amp; Schmidt, W. F. (2013). Altitude training and haemoglobin mass from the optimised carbon monoxide rebreathing method determined by a meta&#x2010;analysis. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 47 Suppl 1(Suppl 1), i31&#x2013;i39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gough, C. E., Saunders, P. U., Fowlie, J., Savage, B., Pyne, D. B., Anson, J. M., Wachsmuth, N., Prommer, N., &amp; Gore, C. J. (2012). Influence of altitude training modality on performance and total haemoglobin mass in elite swimmers. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 112(9), 3275&#x2013;3285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govus, A. D., Garvican&#x2010;Lewis, L. A., Abbiss, C. R., Peeling, P., &amp; Gore, C. J. (2015). Pre&#x2010;altitude serum ferritin levels and daily oral iron supplement dose mediate iron parameter and hemoglobin mass responses to altitude exposure. PLoS ONE, 10(8), e0135120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grenet, G., Blanc, C., Bardel, C., Gueyffier, F., &amp; Roy, P. (2020). Comparison of crossover and parallel&#x2010;group designs for the identification of a binary predictive biomarker of the treatment effect. Basic &amp; Clinical Pharmacology &amp; Toxicology, 126(1), 59&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haldane, J. B. S. (1912). The dissociation of oxyhemoglobin in human blood during partial CO poisoning. The Journal of Physiology, 45, 1912&#x2013;1913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanada, A., Sander, M., &amp; Gonzalez&#x2010;Alonso, J. (2003). Human skeletal muscle sympathetic nerve activity, heart rate and limb haemodynamics with reduced blood oxygenation and exercise. The Journal of Physiology, 551(Pt 2), 635&#x2013;647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogan, M. C., Bebout, D. E., Gray, A. T., Wagner, P. D., West, J. B., &amp; Haab, P. E. (1990). Muscle maximal O2 uptake at constant O2 delivery with and without CO in the blood. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md.: 1985), 69(3), 830&#x2013;836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs, R. A., Boushel, R., Wright&#x2010;Paradis, C., Calbet, J. A., Robach, P., Gnaiger, E., &amp; Lundby, C. (2013). Mitochondrial function in human skeletal muscle following high&#x2010;altitude exposure. Experimental Physiology, 98(1), 245&#x2013;255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs, R. A., Rasmussen, P., Siebenmann, C., Diaz, V., Gassmann, M., Pesta, D., Gnaiger, E., Nordsborg, N. B., Robach, P., &amp; Lundby, C. (2011). Determinants of time trial performance and maximal incremental exercise in highly trained endurance athletes. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md.: 1985), 111(5), 1422&#x2013;1430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krumm, B., Lundby, C., Hansen, J., Bejder, J., Sorensen, H., Equey, T., Saugy, J., Botre, F., &amp; Faiss, R. (2024). Yearly intrasubject variability of hematological biomarkers in elite athletes for the Athlete Biological Passport. Drug Testing and Analysis, 16(11), 1285&#x2013;1294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine, B. D., &amp; Stray&#x2010;Gundersen, J. (1997). Living high&#x2010;training low: Effect of moderate&#x2010;altitude acclimatization with low&#x2010;altitude training on performance. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md.: 1985), 83(1), 102&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mairbaurl, H. (2013). Red blood cells in sports: Effects of exercise and training on oxygen supply by red blood cells. Frontiers in Physiology, 4, 332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet, G. P., &amp; Brocherie, F. (2020). Hypoxic training is beneficial in elite athletes. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 52(2), 515&#x2013;518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet, G. P., Chapman, R. F., Girard, O., &amp; Brocherie, F. (2019). Is live high&#x2010;train low altitude training relevant for elite athletes? Flawed analysis from inaccurate data. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 53(15), 923&#x2013;925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet, G. P., Roels, B., Schmitt, L., Woorons, X., &amp; Richalet, J. P. (2010). Combining hypoxic methods for peak performance. Sports Medicine (Auckland, N.Z.), 40(1), 1&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minson, C. T., &amp; Joyner, M. J. (2024). Carbon monoxide inhalation for performance: Dancing with the devil? Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md.: 1985), 137(6), 1563&#x2013;1565.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero, D., &amp; Lundby, C. (2019). Arterial oxygen content regulates plasma erythropoietin independent of arterial oxygen tension: A blinded crossover study. Kidney International, 95(1), 173&#x2013;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika, I., Bourdillon, N., Zelenkova, I., Vergnoux, F., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2024). Hematological and performance adaptations to altitude training (2,320m) in elite middle&#x2010;distance and distance swimmers. Frontiers in Physiology, 15, 1474479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika, I., Sharma, A. P., &amp; Stellingwerff, T. (2019). Contemporary Periodization of Altitude Training for Elite Endurance Athletes: A Narrative Review. Sports Medicine (Auckland, N.Z.), 49(11), 1651&#x2013;1669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullen, J., Baekken, L. V., Tormakangas, T., Ekstrom, L., Ericsson, M., Hullstein, I. R., &amp; Schulze, J. J. (2020). Inter&#x2010;individual variation of the urinary steroid profiles in Swedish and Norwegian athletes. Drug Testing and Analysis, 12(6), 720&#x2013;730.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okazaki, K., Stray&#x2010;Gundersen, J., Chapman, R. F., &amp; Levine, B. D. (2019). Iron insufficiency diminishes the erythropoietic response to moderate altitude exposure. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md.: 1985), 127(6), 1569&#x2013;1578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olbrecht, J., Mader, A., Heck, H., &amp; Hollmann, W. (1992). Importance of a calculation scheme to support the interpretation of lactate tests. In Biomechanics and medicine in swimming. swimming science VI, ed. Maclaren TRaLH. (pp. 243&#x2013;251). E &amp; FN Spon.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pecorella, S. R., Potter, J. V., Cherry, A. D., Peacher, D. F., Welty&#x2010;Wolf, K. E., Moon, R. E., Piantadosi, C. A., &amp; Suliman, H. B. (2015). The HO&#x2010;1/CO system regulates mitochondrial&#x2010;capillary density relationships in human skeletal muscle. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Lung Cellular and Molecular Physiology, 309(8), L857&#x2013;871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilotto, A. M., Adami, A., Mazzolari, R., Brocca, L., Crea, E., Zuccarelli, L., Pellegrino, M. A., Bottinelli, R., Grassi, B., Rossiter, H. B., &amp; Porcelli, S. (2022). Near&#x2010;infrared spectroscopy estimation of combined skeletal muscle oxidative capacity and O2 diffusion capacity in humans. The Journal of Physiology, 600(18), 4153&#x2013;4168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porcelli, S., Grassi, B., Poole, D. C., &amp; Marzorati, M. (2019). Exercise intolerance in patients with mitochondrial myopathies: Perfusive and diffusive limitations in the O2 pathway. Current Opinion in Physiology, 10, 202&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhodes, M. A., Carraway, M. S., Piantadosi, C. A., Reynolds, C. M., Cherry, A. D., Wester, T. E., Natoli, M. J., Massey, E. W., Moon, R. E., &amp; Suliman, H. B. (2009). Carbon monoxide, skeletal muscle oxidative stress, and mitochondrial biogenesis in humans. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 297(1), H392&#x2013;H399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson, R. S., Noyszewski, E. A., Saltin, B., &amp; Gonzalez&#x2010;Alonso, J. (2002). Effect of mild carboxy&#x2010;hemoglobin on exercising skeletal muscle: Intravascular and intracellular evidence. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 283(5), R1131&#x2013;R1139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robach, P., Bonne, T., Fluck, D., Burgi, S., Toigo, M., Jacobs, R. A., &amp; Lundby, C. (2014). Hypoxic training: Effect on mitochondrial function and aerobic performance in hypoxia. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 46(10), 1936&#x2013;1945.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenthal, L. D. (2006). Carbon monoxide poisoning. Immediate diagnosis and treatment are crucial to avoid complications. American Journal of Nursing, 106(3), 40&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan, T. E., Brophy, P., Lin, C. T., Hickner, R. C., &amp; Neufer, P. D. (2014). Assessment of in vivo skeletal muscle mitochondrial respiratory capacity in humans by near&#x2010;infrared spectroscopy: A comparison with in situ measurements. The Journal of Physiology, 592(15), 3231&#x2013;3241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders, P. U., Ahlgrim, C., Vallance, B., Green, D. J., Robertson, E. Y., Clark, S. A., Schumacher, Y. O., &amp; Gore, C. J. (2010). An attempt to quantify the placebo effect from a three&#x2010;week simulated altitude training camp in elite race walkers. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 5(4), 521&#x2013;534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, W., &amp; Prommer, N. (2005). The optimised CO&#x2010;rebreathing method: A new tool to determine total haemoglobin mass routinely. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 95(5&#x2010;6), 486&#x2013;495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, W., &amp; Prommer, N. (2010). Impact of alterations in total hemoglobin mass on VO 2max. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews, 38(2), 68&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, W. F. J., Hoffmeister, T., Haupt, S., Schwenke, D., Wachsmuth, N. B., &amp; Byrnes, W. C. (2020). Chronic Exposure to Low&#x2010;Dose Carbon Monoxide Alters Hemoglobin Mass and V O2max. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 52(9), 1879&#x2013;1887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semenza, G. L. (2000). HIF&#x2010;1: Mediator of physiological and pathophysiological responses to hypoxia. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md.: 1985), 88(4), 1474&#x2013;1480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sen, S., Peltz, C., Beard, J., &amp; Zeno, B. (2010). Recurrent carbon monoxide poisoning from cigarette smoking. American Journal of the Medical Sciences, 340(5), 427&#x2013;428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siebenmann, C., &amp; Dempsey, J. A. (2020). Hypoxic training is not beneficial in elite athletes. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 52(2), 519&#x2013;522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siebenmann, C., Keiser, S., Robach, P., &amp; Lundby, C. (2017). CORP: The assessment of total hemoglobin mass by carbon monoxide rebreathing. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md.: 1985), 123(3), 645&#x2013;654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siebenmann, C., Robach, P., Jacobs, R. A., Rasmussen, P., Nordsborg, N., Diaz, V., Christ, A., Olsen, N. V., Maggiorini, M., &amp; Lundby, C. (2012). Live high&#x2010;train low using normobaric hypoxia: A double&#x2010;blinded, placebo&#x2010;controlled study. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md. : 1985), 112(1), 106&#x2013;117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siebenmann, C., Roche, J., Schlittler, M., Simpson, L. L., &amp; Stembridge, M. (2024). Regulation of haemoglobin concentration at high altitude. The Journal of Physiology, 602(21), 5587&#x2013;5600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sottas, P. E., Robinson, N., Rabin, O., &amp; Saugy, M. (2011). The athlete biological passport. Clinical Chemistry, 57(7), 969&#x2013;976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suliman, H. B., Carraway, M. S., Tatro, L. G., &amp; Piantadosi, C. A. (2007). A new activating role for CO in cardiac mitochondrial biogenesis. Journal of Cell Science, 120(Pt 2), 299&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UCI. (2025). The UCI bans repeated inhalation of carbon monoxide, and introduces measures to ensure participation of best teams in top&#x2010;tier road events.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urianstad, T., Villanova, S., Odden, I., Hansen, J., Molmen, K. S., Porcelli, S., Ronnestad, B. R., &amp; Cardinale, D. A. (2024). Carbon monoxide supplementation: Evaluating its potential to enhance altitude training effects and cycling performance in elite athletes. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md.: 1985), 137(5), 1092&#x2013;1105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villanova, S., Pastorio, E., Pilotto, A. M., Marciano, A., Quaresima, V., Adami, A., Rossiter, H. B., Cardinale, D. A., &amp; Porcelli, S. (2025). Oxidative and O(2) diffusive function in triceps brachii of recreational to world class swimmers. Experimental Physiology, 110(11), 1721&#x2013;1731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wachsmuth, N. B., Volzke, C., Prommer, N., Schmidt&#x2010;Trucksass, A., Frese, F., Spahl, O., Eastwood, A., Stray&#x2010;Gundersen, J., &amp; Schmidt, W. (2013). The effects of classic altitude training on hemoglobin mass in swimmers. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 113(5), 1199&#x2013;1211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WADA. (2025). 2026 List of Prohibited Substances and Methods. ed. Wada, https://www.wada&#x2010;ama.org/en/resources/2026&#x2010;prohibited&#x2010;list</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Ji, Y., Zhou, L., Xiang, Y., Heinonen, I., &amp; Zhang, P. (2019). A new method to improve running economy and maximal aerobic power in athletes: Endurance training with periodic carbon monoxide inhalation. Frontiers in Physiology, 10, 701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wehrlin, J. P., &amp; Hallen, J. (2006). Linear decrease in .VO2max and performance with increasing altitude in endurance athletes. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 96(4), 404&#x2013;412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO guidelines approved by the guidelines review committee. In WHO guidelines for indoor air quality: selected pollutants. World Health Organization Copyright &#xa9; 2010, World Health Organization.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuckerbraun, B. S., Chin, B. Y., Bilban, M., d'Avila, J. C., Rao, J., Billiar, T. R., &amp; Otterbein, L. E. (2007). Carbon monoxide signals via inhibition of cytochrome c oxidase and generation of mitochondrial reactive oxygen species. Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology Journal, 21(4), 1099&#x2013;1106.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>