<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41695728</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2218-5836</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of orthopedics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Orthop</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does surgeon handedness affect the outcomes after primary total knee arthroplasty? A retrospective cohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>113696</StartPage><MedlinePgn>113696</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">113696</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5312/wjo.v17.i2.113696</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Various factors affecting the outcomes after primary total knee arthroplasty (TKA) have been investigated in the literature; however, the effect of surgeon handedness on outcomes has rarely been addressed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To assess whether the radiological and functional outcomes differ between right and left primary TKA when operated by right-handed surgeons.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective evaluation of 370 TKAs performed by right-handed surgeons [47.8% right TKAs, dominant side (Group D), and 52.2% left TKAs, non-dominant side (Group N)]. The radiological outcomes were the overall alignment measured as the hip-knee-ankle (HKA) angle, and the tibial and femoral component alignment in the coronal plane measured as the medial tibial proximal angle (MPTA) and mechanical lateral distal femoral angle (mLDFA). The percentage of each alignment outside the accepted safe zone values (outliers) were calculated. The functional outcome at the last follow up was evaluated per the Knee Society Score (KSS) System for 206 knees only.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">There were no difference in patients' basic characteristics or in postoperative radiological or functional outcomes between Group D and Group N as follows: HKA, 177.96&#xb0; &#xb1; 3.13&#xb0; <i>vs</i> 178.55&#xb0; &#xb1; 3.38&#xb0; (<i>P</i> = 0.082), MPTA, 88.90&#xb0; &#xb1; 2.61&#xb0; <i>vs</i> 89.43&#xb0; &#xb1; 2.71&#xb0; (<i>P</i> = 0.056), mLDFA, 90.16&#xb0; &#xb1; 2.54&#xb0; <i>vs</i> 89.76&#xb0; &#xb1; 2.53&#xb0; (<i>P</i> = 0.140), and KSS, 80.59 &#xb1; 14.73 <i>vs</i> 79.56 &#xb1; 15.64 (<i>P</i> = 0.628). There was no significant difference in the percentage of outliers in the HKA and mLDFA between groups. For the MPTA, Group D had significantly more implants within the safe zone than Group N, 53.7% <i>vs</i> 41.4% (<i>P</i> = 0.022). There was no difference regarding using intramedullary (IM) <i>vs</i> extramedullary (EM) alignment for the tibial cut between both groups (<i>P</i> = 0.687). In Group D, there was no significant difference in mean MPTA between IM (88.86&#xb0; &#xb1; 3.26&#xb0;) and EM (88.93&#xb0; &#xb1; 1.76&#xb0;) methods (<i>P</i> = 0.862); however, EM resulted in significantly fewer outliers compared to IM (29.2% <i>vs</i> 63.6% respectively; <i>P</i> &lt; 0.001). In Group N, the EM method produced a significantly more valgus alignment than IM (90.38&#xb0; &#xb1; 1.99&#xb0; <i>vs</i> 88.56&#xb0; &#xb1; 3.00&#xb0;, <i>P</i> &lt; 0.001), but this did not translate into a significant reduction in outliers (<i>P</i> = 0.650).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The overall radiological and functional outcomes after primary TKA were unaffected by the surgeon's handedness; however, the placement of the tibial component was significantly more precise on the dominant side with fewer outliers.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2026. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khalifa</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic, Qena Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital, South Valley University, Qena 83523, Qina, Egypt. ahmed_adel0391@med.svu.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdelaal</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery and Traumatology, Assiut University Hospital, Assiut 71515, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moustafa</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed Ma</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery and Traumatology, Assiut University Hospital, Assiut 71515, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Orthop</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576349</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2218-5836</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional laterality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychomotor performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Radiological outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surgeon handedness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Total knee arthroplasty</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The authors declare no conflict of interest concerning this manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41695728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12898334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5312/wjo.v17.i2.113696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>DeFrance MJ, Scuderi GR. Are 20% of Patients Actually Dissatisfied Following Total Knee Arthroplasty? A Systematic Review of the Literature. J Arthroplasty. 2023;38:594&#x2013;599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36252743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halawi MJ, Jongbloed W, Baron S, Savoy L, Williams VJ, Cote MP. Patient Dissatisfaction After Primary Total Joint Arthroplasty: The Patient Perspective. J Arthroplasty. 2019;34:1093&#x2013;1096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30799270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muertizha M, Cai X, Ji B, Aimaiti A, Cao L. Factors contributing to 1-year dissatisfaction after total knee arthroplasty: a nomogram prediction model. J Orthop Surg Res. 2022;17:367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9330701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35902950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inui H, Yamagami R, Kono K, Kawaguchi K. What are the causes of failure after total knee arthroplasty? J Joint Surg Res. 2023;1:32&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datta S, Sanka SK, Tahir M, Shing MS, Omaonu VM, Pierce TP. Why Are Primary Total Knee Arthroplasties Failing? A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Arthroplasty. 2025;40:2219&#x2013;2225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40349863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao K, Chen Y. Comprehensive evaluation of risk factors for aseptic loosening in cemented total knee arthroplasty: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Exp Orthop. 2024;11:e12095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11260281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39035847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Esposito CI, Koch CN, Lee YY, Padgett DE, Wright TM. Polyethylene Damage Increases With Varus Implant Alignment in Posterior-stabilized and Constrained Condylar Knee Arthroplasty. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2017;475:2981&#x2013;2991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5670063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28822068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hamersveld KT, Marang-van de Mheen PJ, Nelissen RGHH. The Effect of Coronal Alignment on Tibial Component Migration Following Total Knee Arthroplasty: A Cohort Study with Long-Term Radiostereometric Analysis Results. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2019;101:1203&#x2013;1212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31274722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel MP, Oussedik S, Parratte S, Lustig S, Haddad FS. Coronal alignment in total knee replacement: historical review, contemporary analysis, and future direction. Bone Joint J. 2014;96-B:857&#x2013;862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24986936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhanushali A, Holder C, McAuliffe MJ, Martin D, Smitham PJ. Revision Rates After Total Knee Arthroplasty Among Surgeons of Varying Experience: An Australian Orthopaedic Association National Joint Replacement Study. J Arthroplasty. 2025:S0883&#x2013;5403(25)00755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40541847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz FH, Lange J. Factors That Affect Outcome Following Total Joint Arthroplasty: a Review of the Recent Literature. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2017;10:346&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5577422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28664450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang NF, Dowsey MM, Ee E, Stoney JD, Babazadeh S, Choong PF. Coronal alignment correlates with outcome after total knee arthroplasty: five-year follow-up of a randomized controlled trial. J Arthroplasty. 2012;27:1737&#x2013;1741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22868073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Victor J. Optimising position and stability in total knee arthroplasty. EFORT Open Rev. 2017;2:215&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5467672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28630758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermue H, Andriollo L, Servien E, Batailler C, Lustig S. Functional knee positioning in total knee arthroplasty: Rationale and current evidence. J Joint Surg Res. 2025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karasavvidis T, Pagan Moldenhauer CA, Lustig S, Vigdorchik JM, Hirschmann MT. Definitions and consequences of current alignment techniques and phenotypes in total knee arthroplasty (TKA) - there is no winner yet. J Exp Orthop. 2023;10:120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10665290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37991599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matassi F, Pettinari F, Frascon&#xe0; F, Innocenti M, Civinini R. Coronal alignment in total knee arthroplasty: a review. J Orthop Traumatol. 2023;24:24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10203068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37217767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luan Y, Zhang M, Ran T, Wang H, Fang C, Nie M, Wang M, Cheng CK. Correlation between component alignment and short-term clinical outcomes after total knee arthroplasty. Front Surg. 2022;9:991476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9606652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36311927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimnoch J, Syr&#xf3;wka P, Tarnacka B. Advancements in Total Knee Arthroplasty over the Last Two Decades. J Clin Med. 2025;14:5375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12347839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40806996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segura-Nuez J Sr, Mart&#xed;n-Hern&#xe1;ndez C Sr, Segura-Nuez JC Sr, Segura-Mata JC Sr. Methods of alignment in total knee arthroplasty, systematic review. Orthop Rev (Pavia) 2024;16:117769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11142931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38827414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson-Tranum AK, Ford MC, Hou N, Powell DW, Guyton JL, Crockarell JR, Holland CT, Mihalko WM. Kinematic Alignment Compared With Mechanical Alignment Techniques Results in Greater Peak Three-Dimensional Knee Joint Moments During Stair Negotiation. J Arthroplasty. 2025;40:S347&#x2013;S353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39863062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamali AA, Shekhar A, Dungy D, Stewart SL. Kinematic versus mechanical alignment: A systematic review of systematic reviews and meta-analyses of randomised controlled trials. J Exp Orthop. 2024;11:e70044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11522918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39478687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennington N, Redmond A, Stewart T, Stone M. The impact of surgeon handedness in total hip replacement. Ann R Coll Surg Engl. 2014;96:437&#x2013;441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4474195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25198975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song X, Ni M, Li H, Li X, Li X, Fu J, Chen J. Is the cup orientation different in bilateral total hip arthroplasty with right-handed surgeons using posterolateral approach? J Orthop Surg Res. 2018;13:123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5967059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29792206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong X, Yang M, Li X, Ni M, Zhang G, Chen J, Chai W. Impact of surgeon handedness in manual and robot-assisted total hip arthroplasty. J Orthop Surg Res. 2020;15:159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7171772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32316973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong X, Yang M, Ong A, Guo R, Chen J, Wang Y, Chai W. A Surgeon's handedness in direct anterior approach-hip replacement. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2020;21:516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7397678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32746833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalifa AA, Hassan AA. Surgeon handedness affects the acetabular cup positioning during primary total hip arthroplasty regardless of the surgical approach. a systematic review and metanalysis. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2024;25:792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11460204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39375663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta S, Lotke PA. Impact of surgeon handedness and laterality on outcomes of total knee arthroplasties: should right-handed surgeons do only right TKAs? Am J Orthop (Belle Mead NJ) 2007;36:530&#x2013;533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18033564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Zhao F, Zha G, Zheng X, Yang G, Xu S. [Effect of surgeon's handedness on distribution of prosthesis during primary total knee arthroplasty] Zhongguo Xiu Fu Chong Jian Wai Ke Za Zhi. 2020;34:696&#x2013;701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8171536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32538558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z, Liu Y, Yang M, Zhang Z, Kong X, Chai W. Effects of Surgeon Handedness on the Outcomes of Unicompartmental Knee Arthroplasty: A Single Center's Experience. Orthop Surg. 2022;14:3293&#x2013;3299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9732585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36281639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaglarz D, Kowalczewski J, Dudek P, Pankowski R, Marczak D, Grzelecki D. The influence of the surgeon's handedness and standing position at the operating table on the radiological outcomes in primary total knee arthroplasty. Knee. 2024;50:147&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39178723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, Pocock SJ, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Vandenbroucke JP STROBE Initiative. The Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. J Clin Epidemiol. 2008;61:344&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18313558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullaji AB, Khalifa AA, Shetty G, Thakur H. Comparison with Navigation of a Novel Three-Step Technique for Improving Accuracy of the Distal Femoral Resection during Conventional TKA: A Case-Control Study. J Knee Surg. 2023;36:195&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34237781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daines BK, Dennis DA. Gap balancing vs. measured resection technique in total knee arthroplasty. Clin Orthop Surg. 2014;6:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3942594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24605183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahran MA, Khalifa AA, Ahmed MA, Bakr HM, Khalifa YE. Evaluating distal femoral torsion and posterior condylar line reliability for adjusting femoral component rotation in TKA, Egyptian population radiographic study. J Clin Orthop Trauma. 2021;13:99&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7920017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33717884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng HB, Ying XZ, Chen GJ, Yang XQ, Lin DD, Li ZJ, Liu HX. Extramedullary versus intramedullary tibial alignment technique in total knee arthroplasty: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Clinics (Sao Paulo) 2015;70:714&#x2013;719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4602384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26598086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalifa AA, Fayez M, Elkady H, Abdelaal AM, Elassal MA. The Outcome of Posterior-Stabilized, Rotating Platform Total Knee Arthroplasty at a Minimum Ten-Year Follow-Up, a Middle East Institution Experience. J Knee Surg. 2022;35:718&#x2013;724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33126282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalifa AA, Mullaji AB, Mostafa AM, Farouk OA. A Protocol to Systematic Radiographic Assessment of Primary Total Knee Arthroplasty. Orthop Res Rev. 2021;13:95&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8294812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34305412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longstaff LM, Sloan K, Stamp N, Scaddan M, Beaver R. Good alignment after total knee arthroplasty leads to faster rehabilitation and better function. J Arthroplasty. 2009;24:570&#x2013;578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18534396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen MM, Pagnano MW. Neutral mechanical alignment: Is it Necessary? Bone Joint J. 2016;98-B:81&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26733648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berend ME, Ritter MA, Meding JB, Faris PM, Keating EM, Redelman R, Faris GW, Davis KE. Tibial component failure mechanisms in total knee arthroplasty. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2004:26&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15534515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullaji AB, Shetty GM, Kanna R, Vadapalli RC. The influence of preoperative deformity on valgus correction angle: an analysis of 503 total knee arthroplasties. J Arthroplasty. 2013;28:20&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22677145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park A, Stambough JB, Nunley RM, Barrack RL, Nam D. The Inadequacy of Short Knee Radiographs in Evaluating Coronal Alignment After Total Knee Arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty. 2016;31:878&#x2013;882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26410551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Insall JN, Dorr LD, Scott RD, Scott WN. Rationale of the Knee Society clinical rating system. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1989:13&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2805470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feeley I, Hegarty A, Hickey A, Glynn A. Impact of Use of Intramedullary and Extramedullary Guides on Tibial Component Geometry in Total Knee Replacements: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Knee Surg. 2016;29:487&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26540653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva JD, Nunes B, Duarte F, Raposo F, Valente L, Antunes A, Oliveira P, Sousa A. Effect of tibial alignment in early failure in total knee arthroplasties. Rev Chi Orthop Traumatol. 2016;102:S80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suh DS, Kang KT, Son J, Kwon OR, Baek C, Koh YG. Computational study on the effect of malalignment of the tibial component on the biomechanics of total knee arthroplasty: A Finite Element Analysis. Bone Joint Res. 2017;6:623&#x2013;630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5717075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29162607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazarian GS, Haddad FS, Donaldson MJ, Wignadasan W, Nunley RM, Barrack RL. Implant Malalignment may be a Risk Factor for Poor Patient-Reported Outcomes Measures (PROMs) Following Total Knee Arthroplasty (TKA) J Arthroplasty. 2022;37:S129&#x2013;S133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35248754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabharwal S, MacKenzie JS, Sterling RS, Ficke JR, LaPorte DM. Left-Handedness Among Orthopaedic Surgeons and Trainees. JB JS Open Access. 2020;5:e20.00019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7418909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32832824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks NE, Lipman JM, French JC. The Right Way to Teach Lefties - Exploring the Experiences of Left-Handed Trainees and Surgeons. J Surg Educ. 2023;80:1552&#x2013;1566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37563001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagaraj MB, AbdelFattah KR, Farr DE. Laparoscopic Ambidexterity in Left-Handed Trainees. J Surg Res. 2022;275:203&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35305486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savetsky IL, Cammarata MJ, Kantar RS, Diaz-Siso JR, Avashia YJ, Rohrich RJ, Saadeh PB. The Left-handed Plastic Surgery Trainee: Perspectives and Recommendations. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2020;8:e2686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7572112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33133882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcsp ICB, Dipcot JA. A Comparison of Dominant and Non-dominant Hand Function in both Right- and Left-Handed Individuals using the Southampton Hand Assessment Procedure (SHAP) Br J Hand Ther. 2003;8:4&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Lee SG, Park SK, Lee SM, Kim -K, Choi JH, Kim SH. Comparison of Grip and Pinch Strength between Dominant and Non-dominant Hand according to Type of Handedness of Female College Students. J Int Acad Phys Ther Res. 2011;2:201&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jee H, Park J. Comparative Analyses of the Dominant and Non-Dominant Upper Limbs during the Abduction and Adduction Motions. Iran J Public Health. 2019;48:1768&#x2013;1776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6908899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31850253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGrath TM, Waddington G, Scarvell JM, Ball NB, Creer R, Woods K, Smith D. The effect of limb dominance on lower limb functional performance--a systematic review. J Sports Sci. 2016;34:289&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26055387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanna GB, Drew T, Clinch P, Shimi S, Dunkley P, Hau C, Cuschieri A. Psychomotor skills for endoscopic manipulations: differing abilities between right and left-handed individuals. Ann Surg. 1997;225:333&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1190685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9060591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Robles M, D&#xed;az-Mart&#xed;nez FJ, Le&#xf3;n-Mu&#xf1;oz VJ, Mar&#xed;n-Mart&#xed;nez C, Murcia-Asensio A, Moreno-Cascales M, Lajara-Marco F. Ergonomic Evaluation of Different Surgeon Positions for Total Knee Arthroplasty Surgery. Appl Sci. 2023;13:11842.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>