<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41426968</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2309-995X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sovremennye tekhnologii v meditsine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sovrem Tekhnologii Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Use of High-Concentration Collagen-Based Composition and Gelatin Granules as Bioinks for Extrusion 3D Bioprinting of Porous-Structured Hydrogel Constructs.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>33</StartPage><EndPage>46</EndPage><MedlinePgn>33-46</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.17691/stm2025.17.5.02</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED"><b>The aim of the study</b> was to analyze the composition feasibility of the bioinks based on high-concentration collagen (40 mg/ml) and gelatin granules (6.25 mg/ml) for bioprinting of porous-structured hydrogel constructs using an extrusion 3D bioprinter.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Bioprinting was performed on a 3D Invivo bioprinter (Rokit, South Korea). We assessed the filament continuity during extrusion, the changes in its thickness after test printing and incubation, as well as the biodegradation of prepared scaffolds. The hydrogel cytocompatibility was studied by the proliferation of adipose-derived stem cells (ADSCs) incorporated into the scaffolds. Flow cytometry was performed to determine the immunophenotype of ADSCs. Cell proliferation in the scaffold structure was studied <i>in vitro</i> during 28 days spectrophotometrically after adding PrestoBlue reagent. The expression of target genes was analyzed by quantitative reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) on day 21 of cultivation. We used the primers for mRNA encoding the synthesis of chondrogenic factors and metabolites (<i>ACAN</i>, <i>SOX9</i>, <i>COL1A1</i>, <i>COL2A1</i>), surface markers (<i>CD29</i>, <i>CD44</i>, <i>CD73</i>, <i>CD90</i>, <i>CD105</i>), as well as hypoxia (<i>HIF1A</i>), proliferation (<i>PCNA</i>), and apoptosis (<i>BCL2</i>, <i>BAX</i>) factors. The morphology of the scaffolds was studied on day 28 of culturing by light microscopy after fixing and staining the histological sections.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The extrusion of the high concentration collagen-based hydrogel composition (40 mg/ml) and gelatin granules (6.25 mg/ml) during printing was stable, there was no filament breakage. When incubated in phosphate-buffered saline, the filament thickness of the hydrogel was statistically significantly higher than the scaffold thickness after printing. The degradation of the scaffolds from the hydrogel and gelatin in the solution of type I collagenase started earlier than the collagen scaffolds. The incubation in phosphate-buffered saline for 14 days resulted in less mass loss when drying the collagen scaffolds with gelatin granules. The cells isolated from human adipose tissue expressed surface markers characteristic of ADSCs. ADSCs proliferation and differentiation in chondrogenic direction were observed in both groups compared. The differences were in the spatial arrangement of the cells. In the collagen scaffolds the most cells were on the surface, while in the scaffolds from collagen and gelatin the cells were distributed throughout the whole volume. The 2<sup>-&#x394;&#x394;Ct</sup> quantitative reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction results showed the increased expression of the transcription factor <i>SOX9</i> by the cells in the collagen and gelatin scaffolds, as well as the decreased expression of the anti-apoptotic gene <i>BCL2</i> relative to the collagen scaffolds.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The present study suggested the bioink composition based on high concentration collagen (40 mg/ml) and gelatin granules (6.25 mg/ml) for bioprinting of porous-structured hydrogel constructs. The study showed hydrogel to be appropriate for printing and exhibited the properties of a porous material. The hydrogel provided the uniform distribution of ADSCs in the scaffold volume, contributing to their differentiation in the chondrogenic direction. Thus, the suggested bioink composition appears to be a promising material to be used in tissue engineering.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kisel</LastName><ForeName>A A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Researcher, Laboratory of Tissue Engineering; The A. Tsyb Medical Radiological Research Centre - the Branch of National Medical Research Radiological Centre of the Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, 10 Zhukov St., Obninsk, 249036, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Isaeva</LastName><ForeName>E V</ForeName><Initials>EV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD, Senior Researcher, Laboratory of Tissue Engineering; The A. Tsyb Medical Radiological Research Centre - the Branch of National Medical Research Radiological Centre of the Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, 10 Zhukov St., Obninsk, 249036, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beketov</LastName><ForeName>E E</ForeName><Initials>EE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD, Director of Development Center; Mabscale LLC, 5A Highway No.4, Special Industrial and Production Economic Zone, Tolyatti, 445043, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arguchinskaya</LastName><ForeName>N V</ForeName><Initials>NV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Junior Researcher, Laboratory of Tissue Engineering; The A. Tsyb Medical Radiological Research Centre - the Branch of National Medical Research Radiological Centre of the Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, 10 Zhukov St., Obninsk, 249036, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gusarova</LastName><ForeName>V R</ForeName><Initials>VR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biologist, Laboratory of Post-Radiation Recovery, Department of Radiation Biochemistry; The A. Tsyb Medical Radiological Research Centre - the Branch of National Medical Research Radiological Centre of the Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, 10 Zhukov St., Obninsk, 249036, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yakimova</LastName><ForeName>A O</ForeName><Initials>AO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD, Head of the Laboratory of Molecular and Cellular Radiobiology; The A. Tsyb Medical Radiological Research Centre - the Branch of National Medical Research Radiological Centre of the Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, 10 Zhukov St., Obninsk, 249036, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demyashkin</LastName><ForeName>G A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MD, DSc, Head of the Pathomorphology Department; The A. Tsyb Medical Radiological Research Centre - the Branch of National Medical Research Radiological Centre of the Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, 10 Zhukov St., Obninsk, 249036, Russia; Head of Histology and Immunohistochemistry Department, Institute of Translational Medicine and Biotechnology; First Moscow State Medical University named after I.M. Sechenov (Sechenov University), 8/2 Trubetskaya St., Moscow, 119991, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lagoda</LastName><ForeName>T S</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD, Research Laboratory Assistant, Laboratory of Tissue Engineering; The A. Tsyb Medical Radiological Research Centre - the Branch of National Medical Research Radiological Centre of the Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, 10 Zhukov St., Obninsk, 249036, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baranovsky</LastName><ForeName>D S</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MD, PhD, Head of the Biotechnology Research and Production Complex; The A. Tsyb Medical Radiological Research Centre - the Branch of National Medical Research Radiological Centre of the Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, 10 Zhukov St., Obninsk, 249036, Russia; Deputy Head of the Center for Collective Use of Scientific Equipment "Radiological and Cellular Technologies"; National Medical Research Radiology Centre of the Ministry of the Russian Federation, 4 Korolev St., Obninsk, 249036, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klabukov</LastName><ForeName>I D</ForeName><Initials>ID</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD, Associate Professor; Obninsk Institute for Nuclear Power Engineering - the Branch of National Research Nuclear University MEPHI, 1 Campus Territory, Obninsk, 249034, Russia; Researcher; Peoples' Friendship University of Russia named after Patrice Lumumba, 6 Miklukho-Maklaya St., Moscow, 117198, Russia; Head of Regenerative Medicine Department; National Medical Research Radiology Centre of the Ministry of the Russian Federation, 4 Korolev St., Obninsk, 249036, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ivanov</LastName><ForeName>S A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MD, DSc, Corresponding Member of the Russian Academy of Sciences, Director; The A. Tsyb Medical Radiological Research Centre - the Branch of National Medical Research Radiological Centre of the Ministry of Health of the Russian Federation, 10 Zhukov St., Obninsk, 249036, Russia; Professor of the Department of Oncology and X-ray Radiology named after V.P. Kharchenko, Medical Institute; Peoples' Friendship University of Russia named after Patrice Lumumba, 6 Miklukho-Maklaya St., Moscow, 117198, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shegay</LastName><ForeName>P V</ForeName><Initials>PV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MD, PhD, Head of the Center for Innovative Radiological and Regenerative Technologies; National Medical Research Radiology Centre of the Ministry of the Russian Federation, 4 Korolev St., Obninsk, 249036, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaprin</LastName><ForeName>A D</ForeName><Initials>AD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MD, DSc, Professor, Academician of the Russian Academy of Sciences, General Director; National Medical Research Radiology Centre of the Ministry of the Russian Federation, 4 Korolev St., Obninsk, 249036, Russia; Head of the Department of Urology and Operative Nephrology with a Course of Oncourology, Medical Institute; Peoples' Friendship University of Russia named after Patrice Lumumba, 6 Miklukho-Maklaya St., Moscow, 117198, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Russia (Federation)</Country><MedlineTA>Sovrem Tekhnologii Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101604515</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2076-4243</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9000-70-8</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005780">Gelatin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D020100">Hydrogels</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9007-34-5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003094">Collagen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005780" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gelatin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066330" MajorTopicYN="Y">Printing, Three-Dimensional</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020100" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hydrogels</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062028" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bioprinting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003094" MajorTopicYN="Y">Collagen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054457" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tissue Scaffolds</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016062" MajorTopicYN="N">Porosity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000273" MajorTopicYN="N">Adipose Tissue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="N">cytology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D023822" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tissue Engineering</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013234" MajorTopicYN="N">Stem Cells</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="N">cytology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049109" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Proliferation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002478" MajorTopicYN="N">Cells, Cultured</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">3D bioprinting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ADSCs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bioinks</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scaffold</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tissue engineering</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest. The authors declare no conflicts related to the present study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41426968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12715487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17691/stm2025.17.5.02</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lories R.J., Luyten F.P. The bone-cartilage unit in osteoarthritis. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2011;7(1):43&#x2013;49. doi: 10.1038/nrrheum.2010.197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrrheum.2010.197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21135881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matai I., Kaur G., Seyedsalehi A., McClinton A., Laurencin C.T. Progress in 3D bioprinting technology for tissue/ organ regenerative engineering. Biomaterials. 2020;226:119536. doi: 10.1016/j.biomaterials.2019.119536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biomaterials.2019.119536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31648135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le H., Xu W., Zhuang X., Chang F., Wang Y., Ding J. Mesenchymal stem cells for cartilage regeneration. J Tissue Eng. 2020;11:2041731420943839. doi: 10.1177/2041731420943839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2041731420943839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7457700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32922718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang X., Daneshmandi L., Awale G., Nair L.S., Laurencin C.T. Skeletal muscle regenerative engineering. Regen Eng Transl Med. 2019;5(3):233&#x2013;251. doi: 10.1007/s40883-019-00102-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40883-019-00102-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7992466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33778155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury D., Anand S., Naing M.W. The arrival of commercial bioprinters &#x2014; towards 3D bioprinting revolution! Int J Bioprint. 2018;4(2):139. doi: 10.18063/IJB.v4i2.139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18063/IJB.v4i2.139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7582003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33102917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atala A., Yoo J.J. Essentials of 3D biofabrication and translation. 1st. Academic Press; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malda J., Visser J., Melchels F.P., J&#xfc;ngst T., Hennink W.E., Dhert W.J., Groll J., Hutmacher D.W. 25th anniversary article: engineering hydrogels for biofabrication. Adv Mater. 2013;25(36):5011&#x2013;5028. doi: 10.1002/adma.201302042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.201302042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24038336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn S.H., Lee J., Park S.A., Kim W.D. Threedimensional bio-printing equipment technologies for tissue engineering and regenerative medicine. Tissue Eng Regen Med. 2016;13(6):663&#x2013;676. doi: 10.1007/s13770-016-0148-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13770-016-0148-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6170866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30603447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaeva E.V., Kisel A.A., Beketov E.E., Demyashkin G.A., Yakovleva N.D., Lagoda T.S., Arguchinskaya N.V., Baranovsky D.S., Ivanov S.A., Shegay P.V., Kaprin A.D. Effect of collagen and GelMA on preservation of the costal chondrocytes&#x2019; phenotype in a scaffold in vivo. Sovremennye tehnologii v medicine. 2023;15(2):5. doi: 10.17691/stm2023.15.2.01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17691/stm2023.15.2.01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosset M., Berenbaum F., Thirion S., Jacques C. Primary culture and phenotyping of murine chondrocytes. Nat Protoc. 2008;3(8):1253&#x2013;1260. doi: 10.1038/nprot.2008.95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nprot.2008.95</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18714293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbruggen G., Wang J., Wang L., Elewaut D., Veys E.M. Analysis of chondrocyte functional markers and pericellular matrix components by flow cytometry. Methods Mol Med. 2004;100:183&#x2013;208. doi: 10.1385/1-59259-810-2:183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1385/1-59259-810-2:183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15280596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mumme M., Barbero A., Miot S., Wixmerten A., Feliciano S., Wolf F., Asnaghi A.M., Baumhoer D., Bieri O., Kretzschmar M., Pagenstert G., Haug M., Schaefer D.J., Martin I., Jakob M. Nasal chondrocyte-based engineered autologous cartilage tissue for repair of articular cartilage defects: an observational first-in-human trial. Lancet. 2016;388(10055):1985&#x2013;1994. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(16)31658-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(16)31658-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27789021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellingman C.A., Verwiel E.T., Slagt I., Koevoet W., Poublon R.M., Nolst-Trenit&#xe9; G.J., Baatenburg de Jong R.J., Jahr H., van Osch G.J. Differences in cartilage-forming capacity of expanded human chondrocytes from ear and nose and their gene expression profiles. Cell Transplant. 2011;20(6):925&#x2013;940. doi: 10.3727/096368910X539119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3727/096368910X539119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21054934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aisenstadt A.A., Enukashvili N.I., Zolina T.L., Alexandrov L.V., Smoljaninov A.B. Comparison of proliferation and immunophenotype of MSC, obtained from bone marrow, adipose tissue and umbilical cord. Vestnik Severo-Zapadnogo gosudarstvennogo meditsinskogo universiteta im. I.I. Mechnikova. 2015;7(2):14&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logovskaya L.V., Bukharova T.B., Volkov A.V., Vikhrova E.B., Makhnach O.V., Goldshtein D.V. Induction of osteogenic differentiation of multipotent mesenchymal stromal cells from human adipose tissue. Bull Exp Biol Med. 2013;155(1):145&#x2013;150. doi: 10.1007/s10517-013-2100-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10517-013-2100-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23667893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hospodiuk M., Dey M., Sosnoski D., Ozbolat I.T. The bioink: a comprehensive review on bioprintable materials. Biotechnol Adv. 2017;35(2):217&#x2013;239. doi: 10.1016/j.biotechadv.2016.12.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biotechadv.2016.12.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28057483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osidak E.O., Karalkin P.A., Osidak M.S., Parfenov V.A., Sivogrivov D.E., Pereira F.D.A.S., Gryadunova A.A., Koudan E.V., Khesuani Y.D., &#x41a;asyanov V.A., Belousov S.I., Krasheninnikov S.V., Grigoriev T.E., Chvalun S.N., Bulanova E.A., Mironov V.A., Domogatsky S.P. Viscoll collagen solution as a novel bioink for direct 3D bioprinting. J Mater Sci Mater Med. 2019;30(3):31. doi: 10.1007/s10856-019-6233-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10856-019-6233-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30830351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaeva E.V., Beketov E.E., Demyashkin G.A., Yakovleva N.D., Arguchinskaya N.V., Kisel A.A., Lagoda T.S., Malakhov E.P., Smirnova A.N., Petriev V.M., Eremin P.S., Osidak E.O., Domogatsky S.P., Ivanov S.A., Shegay P.V., Kaprin A.D. Cartilage formation in vivo using high concentration collagen-based Bioink with MSC and decellularized ECM granules. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(5):2703. doi: 10.3390/ijms23052703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23052703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8910854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35269850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arguchinskaya N.V., Beketov E.E., Isaeva E.V., Kisel A.A., Eremin P.S., Ivanov S.A., Shegay P.V., Kaprin A.D. Riboflavin-induced photocrosslinking of highly concentrated collagen: printing accuracy, degradation time, and cytocompatibility. Appl Biochem Microbiol. 2023;59(8):1062&#x2013;1070. doi: 10.1134/s0003683823080033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1134/s0003683823080033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Primer-BLAST. A tool for finding specific primers.  URL:  https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/tools/primer-blast/index.cgi
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie F., Xiao P., Chen D., Xu L., Zhang B. miRDeepFinder: a miRNA analysis tool for deep sequencing of plant small RNAs. Plant Mol Biol. 2012;80(1):75&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1007/s11103-012-9885-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11103-012-9885-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radisic M., Deen W., Langer R., Vunjak-Novakovic G. Mathematical model of oxygen distribution in engineered cardiac tissue with parallel channel array perfused with culture medium containing oxygen carriers. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2005;288(3):H1278&#x2013;H1289. doi: 10.1152/ajpheart.00787.2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.00787.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15539422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin S., Chimene D., Garza J.E., Gaharwar A.K., Alge D.L. Clickable PEG hydrogel microspheres as building blocks for 3D bioprinting. Biomater Sci. 2019;7(3):1179&#x2013;1187. doi: 10.1039/c8bm01286e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c8bm01286e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9179007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30656307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying G.L., Jiang N., Maharjan S., Yin Y.X., Chai R.R., Cao X., Yang J.Z., Miri A.K., Hassan S., Zhang Y.S. Aqueous two-phase emulsion Bioink-enabled 3D bioprinting of porous hydrogels. Adv Mater. 2018;30(50):e1805460. doi: 10.1002/adma.201805460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.201805460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6402588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30345555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao J., Zhu S., Zhou N., Wang Y., Wan H., Zhang L., Tang Y., Pan Y., Yang Y., Zhang J., Liu R. Nanoparticle-stabilized emulsion Bioink for digital light processing based 3D bioprinting of porous tissue constructs. Adv Healthc Mater. 2022;11(12):e2102810. doi: 10.1002/adhm.202102810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adhm.202102810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35194975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M.K., Jeong W., Lee S.M., Kim J.B., Jin S., Kang H.W. Decellularized extracellular matrix-based bio-ink with enhanced 3D printability and mechanical properties. Biofabrication. 2020;12(2):025003. doi: 10.1088/1758-5090/ab5d80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1758-5090/ab5d80</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31783385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H.W., Su W.T., Liu C.Y., Huang C.C. Highly organized porous gelatin-based scaffold by microfluidic 3D-foaming technology and dynamic culture for cartilage tissue engineering. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(15):8449. doi: 10.3390/ijms23158449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23158449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9369316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35955581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaeva E.V., Beketov E.E., Yuzhakov V.V., Arguchinskaya N.V., Kisel A.A., Malakhov E.P., Lagoda T.S., Yakovleva N.D., Shegay P.V., Ivanov S.A., Kaprin A.D. The use of collagen with high concentration in cartilage tissue engineering by means of 3D-bioprinting. Cell and Tissue Biology. 2021;15(5):493&#x2013;502. doi: 10.1134/s1990519x21050059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1134/s1990519x21050059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabatabaei F., Moharamzadeh K., Tayebi L. Fibroblast encapsulation in gelatin methacryloyl (GelMA) versus collagen hydrogel as substrates for oral mucosa tissue engineering. J Oral Biol Craniofac Res. 2020;10(4):573&#x2013;577. doi: 10.1016/j.jobcr.2020.08.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobcr.2020.08.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7479286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32939336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krouwels A., Melchels F.P.W., van Rijen M.H.P., &#xd6;ner F.C., Dhert W.J.A., Tryfonidou M.A., Creemers L.B. Comparing hydrogels for human nucleus pulposus regeneration: role of osmolarity during expansion. Tissue Eng Part C Methods. 2018;24(4):222&#x2013;232. doi: 10.1089/ten.TEC.2017.0226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/ten.TEC.2017.0226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29457534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X., Yu C., Wang P., Xu W., Wan X., Lai C.S.E., Liu J., Koroleva-Maharajh A., Chen S. Rapid 3D bioprinting of decellularized extracellular matrix with regionally varied mechanical properties and biomimetic microarchitecture. Biomaterials. 2018;185:310&#x2013;321. doi: 10.1016/j.biomaterials.2018.09.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biomaterials.2018.09.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6186504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30265900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirasawa S., Sekiya I., Sakaguchi Y., Yagishita K., Ichinose S., Muneta T. In vitro chondrogenesis of human synovium-derived mesenchymal stem cells: optimal condition and comparison with bone marrow-derived cells. J Cell Biochem. 2006;97(1):84&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1002/jcb.20546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcb.20546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16088956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdan V.G., Zafranskaya M.M., Gain Y.M., Demidchik Y.E. Adipose tissue-derived mesenchymal stem cells of and fibroblast&#x2019;s cultures &#x2014; choice of biological transplants cellular component. Geny i kletki. 2012;7(4):48&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichinose S., Tagami M., Muneta T., Sekiya I. Morphological examination during in vitro cartilage formation by human mesenchymal stem cells. Cell Tissue Res. 2005;322(2):217&#x2013;226. doi: 10.1007/s00441-005-1140-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00441-005-1140-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16091918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrell M.J., Shin J.I., Smith L.J., Mauck R.L. Functional consequences of glucose and oxygen deprivation on engineered mesenchymal stem cell-based cartilage constructs. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2015;23(1):134&#x2013;142. doi: 10.1016/j.joca.2014.09.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2014.09.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4275365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25241241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirasawa S., Sekiya I., Sakaguchi Y., Yagishita K., Ichinose S., Muneta T. In vitro chondrogenesis of human synovium-derived mesenchymal stem cells: optimal condition and comparison with bone marrow-derived cells. J Cell Biochem. 2006;97(1):84&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1002/jcb.20546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcb.20546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16088956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J.H., Kim W.K., Sung Y.K., Kwack M.H., Song S.Y., Choi J.S., Park S.G., Yi T., Lee H.J., Kim D.D., Seo H.M., Song S.U., Sung J.H. The molecular mechanism underlying the proliferating and preconditioning effect of vitamin C on adipose-derived stem cells. Stem Cells Dev. 2014;23(12):1364&#x2013;1376. doi: 10.1089/scd.2013.0460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/scd.2013.0460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4046194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24524758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barlian A., Judawisastra H., Alfarafisa N.M., Wibowo U.A., Rosadi I. Chondrogenic differentiation of adipose-derived mesenchymal stem cells induced by L-ascorbic acid and platelet rich plasma on silk fibroin scaffold. PeerJ. 2018;6:e5809. doi: 10.7717/peerj.5809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.5809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6250097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30488014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown D.A., MacLellan W.R., Laks H., Dunn J.C., Wu B.M., Beygui R.E. Analysis of oxygen transport in a diffusion-limited model of engineered heart tissue. Biotechnol Bioeng. 2007;97(4):962&#x2013;975. doi: 10.1002/bit.21295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bit.21295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17195988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussey G.S., Dziki J.L., Badylak S.F. Extracellular matrix-based materials for regenerative medicine. Nat Rev Mater. 2018;3(7):159&#x2013;173. doi: 10.1038/s41578-018-0023-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41578-018-0023-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibragimova S.I., Medvedeva E.V., Romanova I.A., Istranov L.P., Istranova E.V., Lychagin A.V., Nedorubov A.A., Timashev P.S., Telpukhov V.I., Chagin A.S. Implantation of various cell-free matrixes does not contribute to the restoration of hyaline cartilage within full-thickness focal defects. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;23(1):292. doi: 10.3390/ijms23010292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23010292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8745283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35008719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dionigi B., Ahmed A., Pennington E.C., Zurakowski D., Fauza D.O. A comparative analysis of human mesenchymal stem cell response to hypoxia in vitro: implications to translational strategies. J Pediatr Surg. 2014;49(6):915&#x2013;918. doi: 10.1016/j.jpedsurg.2014.01.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpedsurg.2014.01.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24888834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon B.G., Kwack D.O., Rho G.J. Variation of telomerase activity and morphology in porcine mesenchymal stem cells and fibroblasts during prolonged in vitro culture. Anim Biotechnol. 2011;22(4):197&#x2013;210. doi: 10.1080/10495398.2011.624651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10495398.2011.624651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22132813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dmitrieva R.I., Minullina I.R., Bilibina A.A., Tarasova O.V., Anisimov S.V., Zaritskey A.Y. Bone marrow-and subcutaneous adipose tissue-derived mesenchymal stem cells: differences and similarities. Cell Cycle. 2012;11(2):377&#x2013;383. doi: 10.4161/cc.11.2.18858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4161/cc.11.2.18858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22189711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell A.L., Lefavor R., Durand N., Glover L., Zubair A.C. Modifiers of mesenchymal stem cell quantity and quality. Transfusion. 2018;58(6):1434&#x2013;1440. doi: 10.1111/trf.14597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/trf.14597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29582436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Romero J., Gaillard J.P., Grogan S.P., Nesic D., Trub T., Mainil-Varlet P. Immunophenotypic analysis of human articular chondrocytes: changes in surface markers associated with cell expansion in monolayer culture. J Cell Physiol. 2005;202(3):731&#x2013;742. doi: 10.1002/jcp.20164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcp.20164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15389573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albrecht C., Schlegel W., Bartko P., Eckl P., Jagersberger T., V&#xe9;csei V., Marlovits S. Changes in the endogenous BMP expression during redifferentiation of chondrocytes in 3D cultures. Int J Mol Med. 2010;26(3):317&#x2013;323. doi: 10.3892/ijmm_00000468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ijmm_00000468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20664946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maldonado V.V., Patel N.H., Smith E.E., Barnes C.L., Gustafson M.P., Rao R.R., Samsonraj R.M. Clinical utility of mesenchymal stem/stromal cells in regenerative medicine and cellular therapy. J Biol Eng. 2023;17(1):44. doi: 10.1186/s13036-023-00361-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13036-023-00361-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10334654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37434264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cicione C., D&#xed;az-Prado S., Mui&#xf1;os-L&#xf3;pez E., Hermida-G&#xf3;mez T., Blanco F.J. Molecular profile and cellular characterization of human bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells: donor influence on chondrogenesis. Differentiation. 2010;80(2&#x2013;3):155&#x2013;165. doi: 10.1016/j.diff.2010.06.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diff.2010.06.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20619527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes T.L., Kimura H.A., Pinheiro C.C.G., Shimomura K., Nakamura N., Ferreira J.R., Gomoll A.H., Hernandez A.J., Bueno D.F. Human synovial mesenchymal stem cells good manufacturing practices for articular cartilage regeneration. Tissue Eng Part C Methods. 2018;24(12):709&#x2013;716. doi: 10.1089/ten.TEC.2018.0219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/ten.TEC.2018.0219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6306653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30412046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C.B., Han S.A., Kim E.M., Lee S., Seong S.C., Lee M.C. Chondrogenic potentials of human synovium-derived cells sorted by specific surface markers. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2013;21(1):190&#x2013;199. doi: 10.1016/j.joca.2012.10.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2012.10.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23069852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raftery R.M., Gonzalez Vazquez A.G., Chen G., O&#x2019;Brien F.J. Activation of the SOX-5, SOX-6, and SOX-9 trio of transcription factors using a gene-activated scaffold stimulates mesenchymal stromal cell chondrogenesis and inhibits endochondral ossification. Adv Healthc Mater. 2020;9(10):e1901827. doi: 10.1002/adhm.201901827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adhm.201901827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32329217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefebvre V., Angelozzi M., Haseeb A. SOX9 in cartilage development and disease. Curr Opin Cell Biol. 2019;61:39&#x2013;47. doi: 10.1016/j.ceb.2019.07.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceb.2019.07.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6956855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31382142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song H., Park K.H. Regulation and function of SOX9 during cartilage development and regeneration. Semin Cancer Biol. 2020;67(Pt 1):12&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1016/j.semcancer.2020.04.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semcancer.2020.04.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32380234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King L.E., Hohorst L., Garc&#xed;a-S&#xe1;ez A.J. Expanding roles of BCL-2 proteins in apoptosis execution and beyond. J Cell Sci. 2023;136(22):jcs260790. doi: 10.1242/jcs.260790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/jcs.260790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37994778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q., Zhang L., Yuan X., Ou Y., Zhu X., Cheng Z., Zhang P., Wu X., Meng Y., Zhang L. The relationship between the Bcl-2/Bax proteins and the mitochondria-mediated apoptosis pathway in the differentiation of adipose-derived stromal cells into neurons. PLoS One. 2016;11(10):e0163327. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0163327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0163327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5051896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27706181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan X., Zhang L., Wang S., Ou Y., Wang Q., Peng W., Luo H., Cheng Z., Zhu X. Mitochondrial apoptosis and autophagy in the process of adipose-derived stromal cell differentiation into astrocytes. Cell Biol Int. 2016;40(2):156&#x2013;165. doi: 10.1002/cbin.10548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cbin.10548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26399453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>