<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41073914</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2334</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC infectious diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence and associated risk factors of pulmonary tuberculosis among suspected patients in Sawla General Hospital, Gofa Zone, Southern Ethiopia: a hospital-based cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1268</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1268</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1268</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12879-025-11728-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">TB is a chronic infectious disease caused by the rod-shaped bacillus Mycobacterium tuberculosis. Ethiopia is ranked 12th among the 30 countries with a high TB burden. The aim of this study was to assess the prevalence and associated risk factors for pulmonary tuberculosis (PTB) among suspected patients in Sawla General Hospital, Gofa Zone, Southern Ethiopia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A hospital-based cross-sectional study was carried out on 253 suspected tuberculosis (TB) patients who visited Sawla General Hospital between September 21 and October 24, 2023. The data were collected using a structured questionnaire. Sputum samples were examined using the GeneXpert MTB/RIF assay. The data were analyzed using SPSS version 27. Descriptive statistics are presented as frequencies and percentages. Logistic regression was used to identify the factors associated with tuberculosis. A p value&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 indicated statistical significance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The age range of the study participants was 18 to 89 years, with a mean age of 38.9 years and a standard deviation of 12.0 years. Among 253 suspected TB patients, 27 (10.7%) were identified as having PTB. A relatively higher proportion of PTB cases 18.4% (7/38) was observed among individuals aged 45-54 years, 11.8% (13/110) of females, 16.2% (11/68) of urban residents, 33.3% (2/6) of widowed individuals, and 22.2% (2/9) of students. According to the current study, smoking status and khat chewing status were significantly associated with PTB, with AORs of 3.547 (1.084, 11.605; 95% CI) and 2.852 (1.029, 7.904; 95% CI), respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Cigarette smoking and khat chewing were found to be associated with PTB. These findings suggest that targeted health education and behavioral interventions may be beneficial.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zigale</LastName><ForeName>Abreham</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, College of Natural and Computational Sciences, Arba Minch University, P.O. Box 21, Arba Minch, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wedajo</LastName><ForeName>Bikila</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, College of Natural and Computational Sciences, Arba Minch University, P.O. Box 21, Arba Minch, Ethiopia. bikilawedajo@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2334</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014397" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tuberculosis, Pulmonary</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006769" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitals, General</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009169" MajorTopicYN="N">Mycobacterium tuberculosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013183" MajorTopicYN="N">Sputum</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary tuberculosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk factor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sawla General Hospital</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The current study was adhered to the declaration of Helsinki as the research was involved human participants. Thus, this study was reviewed by the ethical review board of Arba Minch University (IRB/1509/2023). Permission from relevant bodies in the study area was obtained. Informed consent was also obtained from the study participants. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41073914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12512924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-025-11728-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12879-025-11728-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kizilta&#x15f; &#x15e;, Babalik A, Tuberculosis. An Overview. Airway diseases. 2023:635&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Wang T, Du J, Sun L, Wang G, Ni R, An Y, Fan X, Li Y, Guo R, Mao L. Decoding the WHO global tuberculosis report 2024: a critical analysis of global and Chinese key data. Zoonoses. 2025;5(1):999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15212/ZOONOSES-2024-0061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Meeting report of the WHO expert consultation on the definition of extensively drug-resistant tuberculosis, 27&#x2013;29 October 2020. World Health Organization, 2021. Accessed: 29 Oct. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daley CL. The global fight against tuberculosis. Torac Surg Clin. 2019;29(1):19&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demissie TA, Belayneh D. Magnitude of Mycobacterium tuberculosis infection and its resistance to rifampicin using Xpert-MTB/RIF assay among presumptive tuberculosis patients at Motta general Hospital, Northwest Ethiopia. Infect Drug Resist. 2021;14:1335&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IDR.S300585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8039012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33854346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abay GK, Abraha BH. Trends of Mycobacterium tuberculosis and rifampicin resistance in adigrat general Hospital, Eastern zone of Tigrai, North Ethiopia. Trop Dis Travel Med Vaccines. 2020;6(1):14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duressa TA, Mersha MA, Assefa D, Klinkenberg E. Prevalence and associated risk factors of pulmonary tuberculosis among prisoners in Benishangul Gumuz Region, Ethiopia. Am J Nurs Health Sci. 2022;3(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hordofa MW, Adela TB. Prevalence of Refampcin mono resistant Mycobacterium tuberculosis among suspected cases attending at Yirgalem hospital. Clin Med Res. 2015;4(3):75&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11648/j.cmr.20150403.13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naing L, Winn TB, Rusli BN. Practical issues in calculating the sample size for prevalence studies. Archives Orofac Sci. 2006;1:9&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihiretie H, Getacher D, Araya Y, Gemechu D, Taye E, Seyoum B. Prevalence of smear positive pulmonary tuberculosis (PTB) and associated factors among PTB suspects attending Harar tuberculosis control center, Harar, Ethiopia. J Med Lab Diagnosis. 2018;9(1):1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/JMLD2015.0111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinnick TM, Starks AM, Alexander HL, Castro KG. Evaluation of the cepheid Xpert MTB/RIF assay. Expert Rev Mol Diagn. 2015;15(1):9&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1586/14737159.2015.976556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5875728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25373876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diriba K, Awulachew E. Associated risk factor of tuberculosis infection among adult patients in Gedeo Zone, Southern Ethiopia. SAGE Open Med. 2022;10:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20503121221086725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moges B, Amare B, Asfaw F, Tesfaye W, Tiruneh M, Belyhun Y, Mulu A, Kassu A. Prevalence of smear positive pulmonary tuberculosis among prisoners in North Gondar zone Prison, Northwest Ethiopia. BMC Infect Dis. 2012;12(1):352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2334-12-352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3531261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23241368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temesgen E, Belete Y, Haile K, Ali S. Prevalence of active tuberculosis and associated factors among people with chronic psychotic disorders at St. Amanuel mental specialized hospital and Gergesenon mental rehabilitation center, addis Ababa, Ethiopia. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21(1):1100. 10.1186/s12879-021-06807-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-021-06807-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8547023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34702208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali H, Zeynudin A, Mekonnen A, Abera S, Ali S. Smear positive pulmonary tuberculosis (PTB) prevalence amongst patients at Agaro teaching health center, South West Ethiopia. Ethiop J Health Sci. 2012;22(1):71&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3437982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22984333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaganath D, Zalwango S, Okware B, Nsereko M, Kisingo H, Malone L, Lancioni C, Okwera A, Joloba M, Mayanja-Kizza H, Boom WH. Contact investigation for active tuberculosis among child contacts in Uganda. Clin Infect Dis. 2013;57(12):1685&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/cit645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3840405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24077055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chipinduro M, Mateveke K, Makamure B, Ferrand RA, Gomo E. Stool Xpert<sup>&#xae;</sup> MTB/RIF test for the diagnosis of childhood pulmonary tuberculosis at primary clinics in Zimbabwe. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2017;21(2):161&#x2013;6.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5588/ijtld.16.0357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5234433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28234079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little KM, Msandiwa R, Martinson N, Golub J, Chaisson R, Dowdy D. Yield of household contact tracing for tuberculosis in rural South Africa. BMC Infect Dis. 2018;18(1):299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-018-3193-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6030742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29973140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baloch S, Devrajani BR, Rahman AA. The prevalence of smear positive pulmonary tuberculosis in Hyderabad, Sindh, Pakistan. Elixir Hum Physio. 2013;60:16447&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayles H, Schaap A, Nota A, Sismanidis C, Tembwe R, De Haas P, Muyoyeta M, Beyers N, Peter Godfrey-Faussett1 for the ZAMSTAR Study Team. Prevalence of tuberculosis, HIV and respiratory symptoms in two Zambian communities: implications for tuberculosis control in the era of HIV. PLoS ONE. 2009;4(5):e5602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0005602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2680044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19440346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boakye-Appiah JK, Steinmetz AR, Pupulampu P, Ofori-Yirenkyi S, Tetteh I, Frimpong M, Oppong P, Opare-Sem O, Norman BR, Stienstra Y, Van Der Werf TS. High prevalence of multidrug-resistant tuberculosis among patients with rifampicin resistance using GeneXpert Mycobacterium tuberculosis/rifampicin in Ghana. Int J Mycobacteriology. 2016;5(2):226&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmyco.2016.02.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliyo A, Abdisa Y, Robale G, Tilahun D, Aman L, Ibrahim A. Pulmonary tuberculosis prevalence and associated factors among adult patients visiting Finchwa health Center, West Guji Zone, Southern Ethiopia. SVOA Microbiol. 2023;4(3):71&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.58624/SVOAMB.2023.04.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebretsadik D, Ahmed N, Kebede E, Mohammed M, Belete MA. Prevalence of tuberculosis by automated GeneXpert rifampicin assay and associated risk factors among presumptive pulmonary tuberculosis patients at Ataye district Hospital, North East Ethiopia. Infect Drug Resist. 2020;13:1507&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IDR.S248059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7247715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32547120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfaye DJ, Tirore LD, Beshir WG, Shimelis T. Smear positivity and associated risk factors among pulmonary tuberculosis suspects at Nigist Eleni Mohammed memorial Hospital, Hossana, South Ethiopia. Open Access Libr J. 2015;2(3):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemayehu M, Tigabu A, Yunkura S, Hagos F, Tegene B. Prevalence of smear positive pulmonary tuberculosis and associated risk factors among pulmonary tuberculosis suspected patients at private health institutions in Gondar Town, Northwest ethiopia: A cross-sectional study. Am J Infect Dis Microbiol. 2017;5(1):61&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derbie A, Mekonnen D. Prevalence of smear positive pulmonary tuberculosis among patients visiting Bahir Dar health center, Northwest Ethiopia. Int J Public Health Epidemiol. 2015;4(6):179&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amare H, Gelaw A, Anagaw B, Gelaw B. Smear positive pulmonary tuberculosis among diabetic patients at the Dessie referral hospital, Northeast Ethiopia. Infect Dis Poverty. 2013;2(1):6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2049-9957-2-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3707095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24499664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayu B, Mekiso AB, Legesse T. Prevalence of pulmonary tuberculosis and associated factors among prisoners in Wolaita Zone, Southern ethiopia: crosssectional study. Am J Public Health Res. 2016;4(4):142&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eliso E, Medhin G, Belay M. Prevalence of smear positive pulmonary tuberculosis among outpatients presenting with cough of any duration in Shashogo Woreda, Southern Ethiopia. BMC Public Health. 2015;15(1):112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-015-1411-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4339008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25879547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adane K, Ameni G, Bekele S, Abebe M, Aseffa A. Prevalence and drug resistance profile of Mycobacterium tuberculosis isolated from pulmonary tuberculosis patients attending two public hospitals in East Gojjam zone, Northwest Ethiopia. BMC Public Health. 2015;15(1):572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-015-1933-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4473837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26092570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yohanes A, Abera S, Ali S. Smear positive pulmonary tuberculosis among suspected patients attending Metehara sugar factory hospital; Eastern Ethiopia. Afr Health Sci. 2012;12(3):325&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3557681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23382747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wondawek TM, Ali MM. Delay in treatment seeking and associated factors among suspected pulmonary tuberculosis patients in public health facilities of Adama town, Eastern Ethiopia. BMC Public Health. 2019;19(1):1527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-019-7886-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6857315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31727034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jemal M, Tarekegne D, Atanaw T, Ebabu A, Endris M, Tessema B, Moges F, Deressa T. Treatment outcomes of tuberculosis patients in Metema hospital, Northwest ethiopia: a four years retrospective study. Mycobact Dis. 2015;5(4):10&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zenebe T, Tefera E. Tuberculosis treatment outcome and associated factors among smear-positive pulmonary tuberculosis patients in Afar, Eastern ethiopia: a retrospective study. Brazilian J Infect Dis. 2016;20(6):635&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bjid.2016.07.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andarge DB, Anticho TL, Jara GM, Ali MM. Prevalence of Mycobacterium tuberculosis infection and rifampicin resistance among presumptive tuberculosis cases visiting tuberculosis clinic of Adare general Hospital, Southern Ethiopia. SAGE Open Med. 2021;9:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20503121211045541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berhe G, Enqueselassie F, Hailu E, Mekonnen W, Teklu T, Gebretsadik A, Berhe R, Haile T, Aseffa A. Population-based prevalence survey of tuberculosis in the Tigray region of Ethiopia. BMC Infect Dis. 2013;13(1):448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2334-13-448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3849763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24073793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tulu B, Dida N, Kassa Y, Taye B. Smear positive pulmonary tuberculosis and its risk factors among tuberculosis suspect in South East Ethiopia; a hospital based cross-sectional study. BMC Res Notes. 2014;7(1):285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1756-0500-7-285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4023165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24884870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ejeta E, Legesse M, Ameni G. Preliminary study on the epidemiology of tuberculosis in Nekemte and its surroundings-Western Ethiopia. Sci Technol Arts Res J. 2012;1(1):18&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/star.v1i1.98770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigwan EI, Ohaeri MC, David E, Wakjissa FD, Sheyin Z. Some risk factors associated with Acid-alcohol-fast bacilli in patients with suspected pulmonary tuberculosis in jos, central Nigeria. Afr J Infect Dis. 2014;8(2):27&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ajid.v8i2.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4325356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25729533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebede AH, Mamo H. Multidrug-resistant tuberculosis treatment outcomes and associated factors at Yirgalem general Hospital, Sidama Region, South ethiopia: a retrospective cohort study. BMC Pulm Med. 2024;24(1):527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-024-03350-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11498962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39438829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altet MN, Alcaide J, Plans P, Taberner JL, Salto E, Folguera L, Salleras L. Passive smoking and risk of pulmonary tuberculosis in children immediately following infection. A case-control study. Tuber Lung Dis. 1996;77(6):537&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimeles E, Enquselassie F, Aseffa A, Tilahun M, Mekonen A, Wondimagegn G, Hailu T. Risk factors for tuberculosis: A case&#x2013;control study in addis Ababa, Ethiopia. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(4):e0214235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0214235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6445425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30939169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvi A, Rizwan M, Sunosi RA, Jerah AB. Does Khat chewing increases the risk of Mycobacterium tuberculosis infection by macrophage immune modulation? Med Hypotheses. 2014;82(6):667&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mehy.2014.02.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24661941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>