<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41361367</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2334</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC infectious diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Predictors of nutritional recovery among undernourished adults on antiretroviral therapy treated with ready-to-use therapeutic food at public health facilities in Southeast Ethiopia: a retrospective cohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1696</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1696</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1696</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12879-025-12149-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Undernutrition remains a significant public health challenge among people living with HIV in Ethiopia. To address this issue, the country has implemented programs providing ready-to-use therapeutic foods (RUTF) to improve the nutritional status of this vulnerable population. However, empirical evidence on recovery rates and associated factors for individuals undergoing antiretroviral therapy (ART) remains limited. We investigated the nutritional recovery rate and its predictors among undernourished adult individuals receiving ART and RUTF at public health facilities in the Borena Zone, southeastern Ethiopia, in 2023.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A multicenter, institution-based retrospective cohort study was conducted among all 483 undernourished adults treated with RUTF at health facilities in the Borena Zone from January 2017 to December 2022. The study population comprised all undernourished adults living with HIV who received treatment with a ready-to-use therapeutic food. Socio-demographic, clinical, and nutrition-related data were extracted from medical records using an open data kit platform. Bivariable and multivariable Cox regression models were employed to identify predictors of nutritional recovery at 5% significance level.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The study found the overall recovery rate was 55.5% [95% CI: 51&#x2013;60%], with an incidence rate of 14.2 per 100 person-months of observations. The median recovery time was 4 months (95% CI: 3.56, 5.03 months). Attending formal education (AHR: 1.51 [95%CI: 1.13,2.00]), presence of opportunistic infections (AHR: 0.58 [95%CI: 0.43,0.77]), WHO clinical stage I and II (AHR: 1.76 [95%CI: 1.28, 2.41]), severe acute malnutrition (AHR: 0.27 [95% CI:0.19,0.39]) and newly enrolled to ART (AHR:0.59 [95%CI: 0.39, 0.89]) were independent predictors of nutritional recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The study demonstrated that the nutritional recovery rate was 55.5%, which fell short of the 75% target. To enhance recovery outcomes, caregivers should prioritize individuals with severe malnutrition and highly compromised immune systems. Implementing routine screening for malnutrition and providing timely treatment for opportunistic infections are crucial strategies to improve recovery among these vulnerable groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL NUMBER">Not applicable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12879-025-12149-x.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wengelu</LastName><ForeName>Dawit</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Borena Zone Health Department, Borena Zone, Yabello, Oromia, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Assele</LastName><ForeName>Desalegn Dawit</ForeName><Initials>DD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2006-6368</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Hawassa University, Hawassa, Ethiopia. desalegndawit96@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Letta</LastName><ForeName>Shiferaw</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0648-4662</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, College of Health and Medical Sciences, Haramaya University, Harar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abera</LastName><ForeName>Admas</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7577-7576</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, College of Health and Medical Sciences, Haramaya University, Harar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2334</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HIV/AIDS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Undernutrition</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval: Ethical clearance was obtained from the Institutional Health Research Ethics Review Committee of Haramaya University College of Health and Medical Sciences and conducted according to the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Permission was obtained from the head of health facilities, and at each health facility, before starting the data collection, HIV focal persons were to use secondary data for this study, as the study was conducted through a review of patient records, and no consent was obtained from the patients. The personal informant was kept anonymous throughout the investigation, and information concerning particular personal identifiers, like patient names, was not collected. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41361367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12683861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-025-12149-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12879-025-12149-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO. HIV and AIDS:https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/hiv-aids. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNAIDS. Undernutrition in People Living with HIV (PLHIV):https://indicatorregistry.unaids.org/indicator/undernutrition-people-living-hiv-plhiv. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNAIDS. Fact Sheet:Global HIV statistics. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebru TH, Mekonen HH, Kiros KG. Undernutrition and associated factors among adult HIV/AIDS patients receiving antiretroviral therapy in Eastern zone of Tigray, Northern ethiopia: a cross-sectional study. Archives Public Health. 2020;78(1):100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13690-020-00486-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7559062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33072319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulu H, Hamza L, Alemseged F. Prevalence of malnutrition and associated factors among hospitalized patients with acquired immunodeficiency syndrome in Jimma university specialized Hospital, Ethiopia. Ethiop J Health Sci. 2016;26(3):217&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ejhs.v26i3.4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4913189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27358542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahan LK, Raymond JL. Krause&#x2019;s food &amp; the nutrition care process-e-book. Elsevier Health Sciences; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sashindran VK, Thakur R. In: Dumais N, editor. Malnutrition in HIV/AIDS: aetiopathogenesis. Nutrition and HIV/AIDS - Implication for Treatment, Prevention and Cure; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benzekri NA, Sambou JF, Ndong S, Diallo MB, Tamba IT, Faye D, et al. The impact of food insecurity on HIV outcomes in Senegal, West africa: a prospective longitudinal study. BMC Public Health. 2021;21(1):451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-021-10444-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7936446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33676463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussen S, Belachew T, Hussien N. Nutritional status and its effect on treatment outcome among HIV infected clients receiving HAART in ethiopia: a cohort study. AIDS Res Ther. 2016;13:32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12981-016-0116-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5034514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27688793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thimmapuram R, Lanka S, Esswein A, Dall L. Correlation of nutrition with immune status in human immunodeficiency virus outpatients. Mo Med. 2019;116:336&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6699812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31527985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minwagaw MT, Akenie BB, Tewabe DS, Tegegne AS, Beyene TB. Predictors of poor adherence to CART and treatment failure at Second-Line regimens among adults in public hospitals of Amhara Region, North-Western ethiopia: A retrospective cohort study. Patient Prefer Adherence. 2021;15:2855&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/PPA.S339108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8713999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34992354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alebel A, Sibbritt D, Petrucka P, Demant D. Undernutrition increased the risk of loss to follow-up among adults living with HIV on ART in Northwest ethiopia: a retrospective cohort study. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):22556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-27077-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9800382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36581708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alebel A, Demant D, Petrucka P, Sibbritt D. Effects of undernutrition on opportunistic infections among adults living with HIV on ART in Northwest ethiopia: using inverse-probability weighting. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(3):e0264843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0264843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8901070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35255109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khatri S, Amatya A, Shrestha B. Nutritional status and the associated factors among people living with HIV: an evidence from cross-sectional survey in hospital based antiretroviral therapy site in Kathmandu, Nepal. BMC Nutr. 2020;6(1):22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40795-020-00346-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7294605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32549993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC. HIV and Nutrition and Food Safety https://www.hivinfo.nih.gov/understanding-hiv/fact-sheets/hiv-and-nutrition-and-food-safety. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebremichael DY, Hadush KT, Kebede EM, Zegeye RT, Food, Insecurity. Nutritional Status, and factors associated with malnutrition among people living with HIV/AIDS attending antiretroviral therapy at public health facilities in West Shewa Zone, central Ethiopia. Biomed Res Int. 2018;2018:1913534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/1913534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5960526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29854730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bontrager E, Sadler K. Early stages of a &#x2018;Food by prescription&#x2019; programme for HIV infected adults; 2011 01/02/2011 00:00:00. 82 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunguya BF, Ulenga NK, Siril H, Puryear S, Aris E, Mtisi E, et al. High magnitude of under nutrition among HIV infected adults who have not started ART in Tanzania&#x2013;a call to include nutrition care and treatment in the test and treat model. BMC Nutr. 2017;3(1):58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40795-017-0180-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7050693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32153838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussien S. Ready-to-Use therapeutic food for management of wasting in HIV infected adults: A qualitative investigation of views and experiences of patients in Ethiopia. Int J Nutr Food Sci. 2015;4(5):518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallewa J, Szubert AJ, Mugyenyi P, Chidziva E, Thomason MJ, Chepkorir P, et al. Effect of ready-to-use supplementary food on mortality in severely immunocompromised HIV-infected individuals in Africa initiating antiretroviral therapy (REALITY): an open-label, parallel-group, randomised controlled trial. Lancet HIV. 2018;5(5):e231&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2352-3018(18)30038-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5932190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29653915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfay FH, Javanparast S, Gesesew H, Mwanri L, Ziersch A. Characteristics and impacts ofsystematic review nutritional programmes to address undernutrition of adults living with HIV in sub-Saharan africa: a systematic review of evidence. BMJ Open. 2022;12(1):e047205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-047205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8734022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34987036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhagavathula AS, Tegegn HG, Dawson A, Elnour AA, Shehab A. Retention and treatment outcomes of an undernutrition program for HIV patients involving Ready-to-Use therapeutic food at Gondar university Hospital, ethiopia: A Cross-Sectional study. J Clin Diagn Res. 2016;10(8):LC01&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5028486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27656469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diress G, Moges NA. Nutritional recovery and its predictors among adult HIV patients on The rapeutic Feeding Programat Finote-Selam General Hospital, Northwest Ethiopia: a retrospective cohort study. AIDS research and treatment; 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7794040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33489367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sphere Association. The Sphere Handbook: Humanitarian Charter and Minimum Standards in Humanitarian Response, fourth edition, Geneva, Switzerland. www.spherestandards.org/handbook2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO. Rapid drought assessment report for Borena and Dawa zones:https://reliefweb.int/report/ethiopia/rapid-drought-assessment-report-borena-and-dawa-zones. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin KF, Noble MD, Berndt VK. Drying climates and gendered suffering: links between Drought, food Insecurity, and women&#x2019;s HIV in Less-Developed countries. Soc Indic Res. 2021;154(1):313&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11205-020-02562-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7685297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33250551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemu S, Zenu S, Tsegaye D. Time to nutritional recovery and its predictors among undernourished adult patients living with human immune deficiency virus attending Anti-Retroviral therapy at public health facilities in Southwest Ethiopia. A multicenter study. HIV AIDS (Auckl). 2022;14:285&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9206438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35726321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FMoH. National consolidated guidelines for comprehensive HIV prevention, care and treatment. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse H, Toma A. Nutritional treatment outcomes of therapeutic feeding program and its predictors among HIV patients at Hawassa university comprehensive specialized Hospital, Hawassa City, Sidama, Southern ethiopia: A retrospective cohort study. HIV AIDS (Auckl). 2023;15:83&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10008424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36919023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woldie H, Ketema D, Ayana M, Alebe A. Predictors of recovery rate among undernourished HIV-positive adults treated with ready-to-use therapeutic food at Debre Markos comprehensive specialized hospital: a retrospective cohort study. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(8).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8336829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34347849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadler K, Bontrager E, Rogers B, Coates J, Ghosh S, Kidane Y, et al. Food by prescription: measuring the impact and cost-effectiveness of prescribed food on recovery from malnutrition and HIV disease progression among HIV&#x2009;+&#x2009;adult clients in Ethiopia. Boston, USA: Feinstein International Center, Friedman School of Nutrition Science and Policy, Tufts University; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfay F, Ziersch A, Mwanri L, Javanparast S. Contextual and individual level factors influencing nutritional program effectiveness in HIV care setting in Tigray region, Northern ethiopia: mixed methods study. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(4):e0231859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0231859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7185904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32339181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata JM, Cohen CR, Young SL, Wamuyu C, Armes MN, Otieno BO, et al. Descriptive characteristics and health outcomes of the food by prescription nutrition supplementation program for adults living with HIV in Nyanza Province, Kenya. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(3):e91403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0091403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3960130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24646586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girum T, Yasin F, Wasie A, Shumbej T, Bekele F, Zeleke B. The effect of universal test and treat program on HIV treatment outcomes and patient survival among a cohort of adults taking antiretroviral treatment (ART) in low income settings of gurage zone, South Ethiopia. AIDS Res Therapy. 2020;17(1):19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12981-020-00274-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32423457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, McGoogan JM, Wu Z. The benefits of immediate ART. J Int Association Providers AIDS Care (JIAPAC). 2019;18:2325958219831714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325958219831714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6748486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30832530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biniyam DK, Ribka DG, Tesfalem TT. The level of adherence to food by prescription (FBP) program among adults living with HIV/AIDS in addis Ababa City, ethiopia: A facility-based cross-sectional study. Int J Nutr Metabolism. 2020;12(1):8&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/IJNAM2019.0263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maldey B, Ashenafi S, Fisaha H. outcome-of-ready-to-use-food-therapy-among-patients-on-hivaids-care-in-mekelle-hospital-Northern-Ethiopia-retrospective-cohort-study-2155-6113.1000268. J AIDS Clin Res 2014;5(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner CT, Brown J, Shaw E, Uddin I, Tsaliki E, Roe JK, et al. Persistent T cell repertoire perturbation and T cell activation in HIV after long term treatment. Front Immunol. 2021;12:634489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.634489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7959740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33732256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belay GM, Wubneh CA. Childhood tuberculosis treatment outcome and its association with HIV co-infection in ethiopia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Trop Med Health. 2020;48:7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41182-020-00195-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7027074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32099521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodd PJ, Prendergast AJ, Beecroft C, Kampmann B, Seddon JA. The impact of HIV and antiretroviral therapy on TB risk in children: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Thorax. 2017;72(6):559&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2016-209421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5520282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28115682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geremew D, Melku M, Endalamaw A, Woldu B, Fasil A, Negash M, et al. Tuberculosis and its association with CD4(+) T cell count among adult HIV positive patients in Ethiopian settings: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Infect Dis. 2020;20(1):325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-020-05040-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7204319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32380957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Justiz VA, Naik R. HIV-1&#x2013;Associated opportunistic infections. [Updated 2023 Jan 27]. In: StatPearls [Internet]. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2023 Jan-. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK539787/. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abebaw N, Endeshaw M, Ayenew M. Severe acute malnutrition as a major predictor for poor nutritional outcome among adult HIV patients treated with FPB program: a case-control study. Universa Med. 2019;38(2):121&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18051/UnivMed.2019.v38.121-130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>