<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41307488</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1757-9988</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The journal of adhesive dentistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Adhes Dent</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Functional Monomer Type Determines the Interfacial Properties of Experimental Self-Adhesive Composites Bonded to Dentin.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>251</StartPage><EndPage>260</EndPage><MedlinePgn>251-260</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3290/j.jad.c_2378</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the influence of functional monomer type and powder-to-liquid ratio on the interfacial properties and degree of conversion of experimental self-adhesive flowable resin composites (SAFRCs) bonded to dentin.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Nine experimental SAFRC formulations were developed by varying the powder-to-liquid ratio (1.9, 2.2, 2.5) and the functional monomers included (10-MDP, GPDM, HEMA). Human molars (n = 27) were restored using each formulation and analyzed using a rheometer to assess viscosity, Raman micro-spectroscopy for inter-diffusion zone (IDZ) width, and degree of conversion at the interface (DC%). Two-way ANOVA and post-hoc tests were performed for statistical analysis (&#x3b1; = 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Rheological testing revealed, as expected, non-Newtonian flow behavior in all composites, with significant effects of both powder-to-liquid ratio (P 0.001) and monomer type (P 0.001) on viscosity. 10-MDP composites exhibited optimal viscosity (1.12-2.86 mPa&#xb7;s) across all ratios, significantly lower than GPDM and HEMA. Raman mapping showed a distinct IDZ with hybrid characteristics for 10-MDP formulations, contrasting with abrupt transitions or gaps in GPDM and HEMA groups. IDZ width was significantly greater in 10-MDP formulations (P 0.0001). The DC% at the interface was highest for 10-MDP and HEMA formulations, exceeding 68%, while GPDM composites showed lower values (P 0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Functional monomer type critically affects the interfacial bonding performance and conversion rate of SAFRCs, with 10-MDP outperforming GPDM and HEMA in interdiffusion and adhesive quality. Variations in powder-to-liquid ratio influenced viscosity but had a limited impact on interfacial performance. Optimized formulations with 10-MDP may enhance the clinical efficacy of SAFRCs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL RELEVANCE STATEMENT" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Refining acidic-monomer chemistry and viscosity in SAFRCs could improve their bonding predictability.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andrade</LastName><ForeName>Rita</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaves</LastName><ForeName>Carolina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva</LastName><ForeName>Diana C</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Serro</LastName><ForeName>Ana Paula</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azul</LastName><ForeName>Ana Mano</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc1;guas</LastName><ForeName>Hugo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Delgado</LastName><ForeName>Ant&#xf3;nio H S</ForeName><Initials>AHS</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>J Adhes Dent</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100888552</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1461-5185</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003188">Composite Resins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008689">Methacrylates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017220">Dentin-Bonding Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011208">Powders</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>85590-00-7</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C069749">methacryloyloxydecyl dihydrogen phosphate</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003188" MajorTopicYN="Y">Composite Resins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014783" MajorTopicYN="N">Viscosity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013059" MajorTopicYN="N">Spectrum Analysis, Raman</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003804" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dentin</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008422" MajorTopicYN="N">Materials Testing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001840" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dental Bonding</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008689" MajorTopicYN="N">Methacrylates</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013499" MajorTopicYN="N">Surface Properties</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012212" MajorTopicYN="N">Rheology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017220" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dentin-Bonding Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011208" MajorTopicYN="N">Powders</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Raman spectroscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adhesion to dentin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adhesive materials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-adhesive resins</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41307488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12666403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3290/j.jad.c_2378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">6707210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alghauli MA, Alqutaibi AY, Wille S, Kern M. Clinical reliability of self-adhesive luting resins compared to other adhesive procedures: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Dent. 2023;129:104394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36566829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beun S, Bailly C, Dabin A, Vreven J, Devaux J, Leloup G. Rheological properties of experimental Bis-GMA/TEGDMA flowable resin composites with various macrofiller/microfiller ratio. Dent Mater. 2009;25:198&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18620747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brkanovi&#x107; S, Sever EK, Vukelja J, Ivica A, Mileti&#x107; I, Krmek SJ. Comparison of different universal adhesive systems on dentin bond strength. Materials (Basel) 2023;16:1530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9963205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36837160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brueckner C, Schneider H, Haak R. Shear bond strength and tooth-composite interaction with self-adhering flowable composites. Oper Dent. 2017;42:90&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27802122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadenaro M, Maravic T, Comba A, Mazzoni A, Fanfoni L, Hilton T, Ferracane J, Breschi L. The role of polymerization in adhesive dentistry. Dent Mater 2019;35:e1&#x2013;e22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30554830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charton C, Falk V, Marchal P, Pla F, Colon P. Influence of Tg, viscosity and chemical structure of monomers on shrinkage stress in light-cured dimethacrylate-based dental resins. Dent Mater. 2007;23:1447&#x2013;1459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17719627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Feng S, Jin Y, Hou Y, Zhu S. Comparison of bond strength of universal adhesives using different etching modes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Dent Mater J. 2022;41:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34471040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>David C, Cardoso de Cardoso G, Isolan CP, Piva E, Moraes RR, Cuevas-Suarez CE. Bond strength of self-adhesive flowable composite resins to dental tissues: a systematic review and meta-analysis of in vitro studies. J Prosthet Dent. 2021;128:876&#x2013;885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33838916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado A, Belmar Da Costa M, Polido MC, Mano Azul A, Sauro S. Collagen-depletion strategies in dentin as alternatives to the hybrid layer concept and their effect on bond strength: a systematic review. Sci Rep. 2022;12:13028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9338246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35906302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado AH. Characterization of dental bonding systems and commercial versus novel self-adhesive restoratives. Doctoral thesis (Ph.D), UCL (University College London), 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado AHS, Almuusa A, Eshmawi Y, Xia W, Ashley P, Young AM. Novel self-bonding composites: resin-dentin interfacial chemistry. Ann Med. 2019;51:97&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado AHS, Owji N, Ashley P, Young AM. Varying 10-methacryloyloxydecyl dihydrogen phosphate (10-MDP) level improves polymerisation kinetics and flexural strength in self-adhesive, remineralising composites. Dent Mater. 2021;37:1366&#x2013;1376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34144796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado AHS, Young AM. Modelling ATR-FTIR spectra of dental bonding systems to investigate composition and polymerisation kinetics. Materials. 2021;14:1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7915020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33562837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feitosa VP, Sauro S, Ogliari FA, Ogliari AO, Yoshihara K, Zanchi CH, et al. Impact of hydrophilicity and length of spacer chains on the bonding of functional monomers. Dent Mater 2014;30:e317&#x2013;e323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24993808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira MN, Neves M, Santos D, Fernandes I, Marto CM, Laranjo M, et al. Effect of varying functional monomers in experimental self-adhesive composites: polymerization kinetics, cell metabolism influence and sealing ability. Biomed Mater. 2023;18:065014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37738988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu J, Kakuda S, Pan F, Hoshika S, Ting S, Fukuoka A, et al. Bonding performance of a newly developed step-less all-in-one system on dentin. Dent Mater J. 2013;32:203&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23538754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita (Nakajima) K, Nikaido T, Francis Burrow M, Iwasaki T, Tanimoto Y, Hirayama S, Nishiyama N. Effect of the demineralisation efficacy of MDP utilized on the bonding performance of MDP-based all-in-one adhesives. J Dent. 2018;77:59&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30031056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingl&#xea;s M, Vasconcelos E Cruz J, Mano Azul A, Polido M, Delgado AHS. Comparative assessment of different pre-treatment bonding strategies to improve the adhesion of self-adhesive composites to dentin. Polymers. 2022;14:3945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9570807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36235894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin X, Han F, Wang Q, Yuan X, Zhou Q, Xie H, et al. The roles of 10-methacryloyloxydecyl dihydrogen phosphate and its calcium salt in preserving the adhesive-dentin hybrid layer. Dent Mater. 2022;38:1194&#x2013;1205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35715248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josic U, Teti G, Ionescu A, Maravic T, Mazzitelli C, Cokic S, et al. Cytotoxicity and microbiological behavior of universal resin composite cements. Dent Mater. 2024;40:1515&#x2013;1523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39054113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latta MA, Radniecki SM. Bond strength of self-adhesive restorative materials affected by smear layer thickness but not dentin desiccation. J Adhes Dent. 2020;22:79&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32030378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee IB, Min SH, Kim SY, Ferracane J. Slumping tendency and rheological properties of flowable composites. Dent Mater. 2010;26:443&#x2013;448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20170946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee IB, Son HH, Um CM. Rheologic properties of flowable, conventional hybrid, and condensable composite resins. Dent Mater. 2003;19:298&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12686294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leinfelder KF, Radz GM, Nash RW. A report on a new condensable composite resin. Compendium of continuing education in dentistry (Jamesburg, NJ : 1995) 1998;19:230&#x2013;232, 234, 236&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9590947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miletic V. Dental Composite Materials for Direct Restorations [Internet]. Miletic V (ed). Cham: Springer International Publishing, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mine A, De Munck J, Van Ende A, Poitevin A, Matsumoto M, Yoshida Y, et al. Limited interaction of a self-adhesive flowable composite with dentin/enamel characterized by TEM. Dent Mater. 2017;33:209&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28007394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteiro AA, Salgado VE, Vitti RP, Loureiro Bertolo MV, Cavalcante LM, Schneider LFJ. Effect of adhesive-monomers and photoinitiator on C=C conversion and color stability of model self-adhesive flowable composites. Int J Adhes Adhes. 2018;87:119&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monticelli F, Osorio R, Mazzitelli C, Ferrari M, Toledano M. Limited decalcification/diffusion of self-adhesive cements into dentin. J Dent Res. 2008;87:974&#x2013;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18809754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moszner N, Salz U. New developments of polymeric dental composites. Prog Polymer Sci. 2001;26:535&#x2013;576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira Ferraz LC, Ubaldini ALM, de Oliveira BMB, Neto AM, Sato F, Baesso ML, Pascotto RC. Analytical method to estimate resin cement diffusion into dentin. J Biomed Opt. 2016;21:055003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27232592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perdig&#xe3;o J. Current perspectives on dental adhesion: (1) Dentin adhesion &#x2013; not there yet. Jpn Dent Sci Rev. 2020;56:190&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8216299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34188727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson J, Rizk M, Hoch M, Wiegand A. Bonding performance of self-adhesive flowable composites to enamel, dentin and a nano-hybrid composite. Odontology. 2018;106:171&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29243187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pimentel De Oliveira R, De Paula BL, Ribeiro ME, Alves E, Costi HT, Silva C. Evaluation of the bond strength of self-etching adhesive systems containing HEMA and 10-MDP monomers: bond strength of adhesives containing HEMA and 10-MDP. Int J Dent. 2022;2022:5756649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9205737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35722040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poitevin A, De Munck J, Van Ende A, Suyama Y, Mine A, Peumans M, Van Meerbeek B. Bonding effectiveness of self-adhesive composites to dentin and enamel. Dent Mater. 2013;29:221&#x2013;230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23107191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakano W, Nakajima M, Prasansuttiporn T, Foxton RM, Tagami J. Polymerization behavior within adhesive layer of one- and two-step self-etch adhesives: a micro-Raman spectroscopic study. Dent Mater. 2013;32:992&#x2013;998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24240894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salz U, M&#xfc;cke A, Zimmermann J, Tay FR, Pashley DH. pKa value and buffering capacity of acidic monomers commonly used in self-etching primers. J Adhes Dent. 2006;8:143&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16830660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauro S, Osorio R, Watson TF, Toledano M. Assessment of the quality of resin-dentin bonded interfaces: An AFM nano-indentation, &#x3bc;tBS and confocal ultramorphology study. Dent Mater. 2012;28:622&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22425481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scholz KJ, Bittner A, Cieplik F, Hiller K-A, Schmalz G, Buchalla W, Federlin M. Micromorphology of the adhesive interface of self-adhesive resin cements to enamel and dentin. Materials (Basel) 2021;14:492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7864341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33498588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengar EV, Mulay S, Beri L, Gupta A, Almohareb T, Binalrimal S, et al. Comparative evaluation of microleakage of flowable composite resin using etch and rinse, self-etch adhesive systems, and self-adhesive flowable composite resin in class v cavities: confocal laser microscopic study. Materials. 2022;15:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9319247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35888429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer P, Wang Y. Adhesive phase separation at the dentin interface under wet bonding conditions. J Biomed Mater Res. 2002;62:447&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12209931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer P, Ye Q, Park J, Topp EM, Misra A, Marangos O, et al. Adhesive/dentin interface: The weak link in the composite restoration. Ann Biomed Eng. 2010;38:1989&#x2013;2003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2871971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20195761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian F, Zhou L, Zhang Z, Niu L, Zhang L, Chen C, et al. Paucity of nanolayering in resin-dentin interfaces of MDP-based adhesives. J Dent Re. 2016;95:380&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4802780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26701351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Meerbeek B, Yoshihara K, Van Landuyt K, Yoshida Y, Peumans M. From buonocore&#x2019;s pioneering acid-etch technique to self-adhering restoratives. A status perspective of rapidly advancing dental adhesive technology. J Adhes Dent. 2020;22:7&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32030373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vichi A, Margvelashvili M, Goracci C, Papacchini F, Ferrari M. Bonding and sealing ability of a new self-adhering flowable composite resin in class I restorations. Clin Oral Investig. 2013;17:1497&#x2013;1506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23086332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walters NJ, Xia W, Salih V, Ashley PF, Young AM. Poly(propylene glycol) and urethane dimethacrylates improve conversion of dental composites and reveal complexity of cytocompatibility testing. Dent Mater. 2016;32:264&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26764174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Spencer P. Quantifying adhesive penetration in adhesive/dentin interface using confocal Raman microspectroscopy. J Biomed Mater Res. 2002;59:46&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11745536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao C, Ahmed MH, Okazaki Y, Van Landuyt KL, Huang C, Van Meerbeek B. Bonding Efficacy of a new self-adhesive restorative onto flat dentin vs class-i cavity-bottom dentin. J Adhes Dent. 2020;22:65&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32030377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao C, Ahmed MH, Zhang F, Mercelis B, van Landuyt KL, Huang C, van Meerbeek B. Structural/chemical characterization and bond strength of a new self-adhesive bulk-fill restorative. J Adhes Dent. 2020;22:85&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32030379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshihara K, Hayakawa S, Nagaoka N, Okihara T, Yoshida Y, Van Meerbeek B. Etching efficacy of self-etching functional monomers. J Dent Res. 2018;97:1010&#x2013;1016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29554434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshihara K, Nagaoka N, Hayakawa S, Okihara T, Yoshida Y, Van Meerbeek B. Chemical interaction of glycero-phosphate dimethacrylate (GPDM) with hydroxyapatite and dentin. Dent Mater. 2018;34:1072&#x2013;1081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29716740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshihara K, Nagaoka N, Nakamura A, Hara T, Yoshida Y, Van Meerbeek B. Nano-layering adds strength to the adhesive interface. J Dent Res. 2021;100:515&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33345712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshihara K, Nagaoka N, Yoshida Y, Van Meerbeek B, Hayakawa S. Atomic level observation and structural analysis of phosphoric-acid ester interaction at dentin. Acta Biomater. 2019;97:544&#x2013;556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31425891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshioka M, Yoshida Y, Inoue S, Lambrechts P, Vanherle G, Nomura Y, et al. Adhesion/decalcification mechanisms of acid interactions with human hard tissues. J Biomed Mater Res. 2002;59:56&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11745537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>