<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41686829</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Study on the influence of periodic roof fracturing on the mechanical disturbance characteristics of coal and gas outburst behavior in the mining face.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0337026</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0337026</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0337026</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0337026</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To elucidate the stress evolution characteristics of coal and the gas-dynamic response mechanism during periodic roof fracturing in longwall mining, the 3DEC numerical simulation software was employed to investigate the distribution characteristics of the abutment pressure at the instant of roof fracturing and elastic rebound. Based on the coupling relationship between abutment pressure and gas pressure, the gas occurrence characteristics in the mining face were further analyzed. The results indicate that, with increasing mining advance, the stress distribution after roof fracturing-affected by the roof suspension length and elastic rebound behavior-differs significantly from conventional patterns. As the mining face advances, the length of the overlying hard roof increases, and the elastic rebound behavior at the moment of roof failure reduces the vertical stress on the coal seam, thereby forming a stress-relief zone (Zone II) ahead of the working face. Using the COMSOL Multiphysics software for simulation, it was concluded that the elastic rebound at the moment of roof failure, in conjunction with the cyclic pressurization process, jointly determines the timing characteristics of coal energy release, which has a direct dynamic control effect on the initiation and eruption of gas outbursts. The stress perturbations caused by roof elastic rebound not only alter the mechanical structure and fracture evolution of the coal body, but also influence the occurrence and flow state of gas, thereby controlling the conditions and dynamic intensity of coal and gas outbursts. It provides a new theoretical basis for the prevention and control of gas outbursts and roof-related disasters.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Zhang et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Chunhua</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety Science and Engineering, Liaoning Technical University, Fuxin, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Mine Thermodynamic Disasters and Control of Ministry of Education(Liaoning Technical University), Huludao, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Ziyue</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-5231-5239</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety Science and Engineering, Liaoning Technical University, Fuxin, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Mine Thermodynamic Disasters and Control of Ministry of Education(Liaoning Technical University), Huludao, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety Science and Engineering, Liaoning Technical University, Fuxin, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Mine Thermodynamic Disasters and Control of Ministry of Education(Liaoning Technical University), Huludao, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Jingyu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety Science and Engineering, Liaoning Technical University, Fuxin, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Mine Thermodynamic Disasters and Control of Ministry of Education(Liaoning Technical University), Huludao, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jinquan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety Science and Engineering, Liaoning Technical University, Fuxin, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Mine Thermodynamic Disasters and Control of Ministry of Education(Liaoning Technical University), Huludao, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003031">Coal</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003031" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003032" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coal Mining</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013314" MajorTopicYN="N">Stress, Mechanical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003198" MajorTopicYN="N">Computer Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41686829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12904452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0337026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-58783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dou LM, He J, Cao AY. Principle of dynamic-static load superposition of rock burst in coal mines and its prevention. J China Coal Soc. 2015;40(7):1469&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu YP, Song XM, Xing PW. Stability analysis of key blocks in large-mining-height working face roof fracture. J China Coal Soc. 2009;34(8):1027&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi JJ, Ma NJ, Bai ZS. Analysis of roof fracture position and support technology for gob-side entry retaining. Coal Sci Technol. 2013;41(7).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang H, Gao F, Xu G, Ren H. Mechanical behaviors of coal measures and ground control technologies for China&#x2019;s deep coal mines &#x2013; A review. J Rock Mech Geotech Eng. 2023;15(1):37&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1016/j.jrmge.2022.11.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jrmge.2022.11.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Rui Q, Yang Y. Roof movement and instability fracture characteristics in shallow-buried thin coal seam conventional mining faces. Geomech Geophys Geo-Energy Geo-Resourc. 2024;10(1):27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong F, Yin H, Ren H, Cheng W, Tai S, Miao T, et al. Trapezoidal Failure Behavior and Fracture Evolution Mechanism of Overburden in Extra-thick Coal Mining in Weakly Cemented Strata. Rock Mech Rock Eng. 2024;57(12):11239&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1007/s00603-024-04147-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-024-04147-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao R, Xu B, Bai D, Feng G, Li M. Influence of fracturing spacing on rock mass fracturing and energy evolution in overlying strata. Theor Appl Fract Mech. 2025;140:105174. doi: 10.1016/j.tafmec.2025.105174</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tafmec.2025.105174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie H, Gao M, Zhang R, et al. Study on the Mechanical Properties and Mechanical Response of Coal Mining at 1000 m or Deeper. Rock Mech Rock Eng 2019;52:1475&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao M, Jin W, Dai Z, Xie J. Relevance between abutment pressure and fractal dimension of crack network induced by mining. International J Min Scie Technol. 2013;23(6):925&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmst.2013.11.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmst.2013.11.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He MC, Miao JL, Feng JL. Rock burst process of limestone and its acoustic emission characteristics under true-triaxial unloading conditions. Int J Rock Mech Min Sci. 2010;47(2):286&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmms.2009.09.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2009.09.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua A-Z, You M-Q. Rock failure due to energy release during unloading and application to underground rock burst control. Tunnell Undergr Space Technol. 2001;16(3):241&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/s0886-7798(01)00046-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0886-7798(01)00046-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam MdR, Hayashi D, Kamruzzaman ABM. Finite element modeling of stress distributions and problems for multi-slice longwall mining in Bangladesh, with special reference to the Barapukuria coal mine. Int J Coal Geol. 2009;78(2):91&#x2013;109. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2008.10.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2008.10.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Q, Yang J, Song H, Wu X, Liu Y, Wei X. Study on the Method of Pressure Relief and Energy Absorption for Protecting Roadway Under Thick and Hard Roof. Rock Mech Rock Eng. 2023;56(10):7177&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1007/s00603-023-03447-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-023-03447-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang J, Mu Z, Ma&#x142;kowski P, Cai W, Gong S, Cao A, et al. The role of advance rate in mining-induced stress and microseismic behavior during longwall face advance. Geomat Natl Hazards Risk. 2025;16(1). doi: 10.1080/19475705.2025.2515536</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19475705.2025.2515536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Liu J, Jiang B, Jiang Z, Deng Y, Xu C. Synergistic reinforcement using pressure releasing and energy absorbing method under hard roof: Physical model test. J Rock Mech Geotech Eng. 2025;17(9):5845&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1016/j.jrmge.2025.01.056</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jrmge.2025.01.056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng G, Xu W, Shi B, Wu J, Sun B, Zhu H. Experimental study on the deformation and failure mechanism of overburden rock during coal mining using a comprehensive intelligent sensing method. J Rock Mech Geotech Eng. 2022;14(5):1626&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1016/j.jrmge.2022.07.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jrmge.2022.07.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, Wang Y, Yang J, Zhang X, He M. Meso- and macroeffects of roof split blasting on the stability of gateroad surroundings in an innovative nonpillar mining method. Tunnell Underground Space Technol. 2019;90:99&#x2013;118. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2019.04.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2019.04.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, He B, Hou X, Li J, Liu L. Stress&#x2013;Energy Mechanism for Rock Failure Evolution Based on Damage Mechanics in Hard Rock. Rock Mech Rock Eng. 2019;53(3):1021&#x2013;37. doi: 10.1007/s00603-019-01953-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-019-01953-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M, Xueqiu H, Dazhao S, Xianghui T, Li Z, Yarong X, et al. Extracting and Predicting Rock Mechanical Behavior Based on Microseismic Spatio-temporal Response in an Ultra-thick Coal Seam Mine. Rock Mech Rock Eng. 2023;56(5):3725&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1007/s00603-023-03247-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-023-03247-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng X, Zhao G, Li Y, Meng X, Tu Q, Huang S, et al. Mining&#x2010;Induced Pressure&#x2010;Relief Mechanism of Coal&#x2010;Rock Mass for Different Protective Layer Mining Modes. Adv Mater Sci Eng. 2021;2021(1). doi: 10.1155/2021/3598541</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/3598541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu Y, Wang E, Li Z, Gao F, Zhang Z, Li B, et al. Identification of Coal and Gas Outburst-Hazardous Zones by Electric Potential Inversion During Mining Process in Deep Coal Seam. Rock Mech Rock Eng. 2022;55(6):3439&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1007/s00603-022-02804-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-022-02804-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong X, Li S, Wang E, Wang X, Zhou Y, Ji P, et al. Experimental and numerical investigations on dynamic mechanical responses and failure process of gas-bearing coal under impact load. Soil Dyn Earthquake Eng. 2021;142:106579. doi: 10.1016/j.soildyn.2021.106579</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soildyn.2021.106579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B, Wang E, Shang Z, Liu X, Li Z, Li B, et al. Optimize the early warning time of coal and gas outburst by multi-source information fusion method during the tunneling process. Process Saf Environ Prot. 2021;149:839&#x2013;49. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2021.03.029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2021.03.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng X, Qi L, Wang Z, Zhou X, Hua C. Study on Overburden Movement Deformation and Roof Breakage Law of Under-Protective Steeply Inclined Coal Seam Mining. Sustainability. 2022;14(16):10068. doi: 10.3390/su141610068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su141610068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Zhang Y, Du W. An analytical approach to estimate the mechanical state of roof strata in underground longwall mining. Geomech Eng. 2021;27(1):55&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boothukuri VR, Bhattacharjee RM, Panigrahi DC, Benerjee G. Impact of geo technical factors on strata behavior in longwall panels of Godavari Valley coal field-a case study. Int J Min Sci Technol. 2019;29(2):335&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmst.2018.06.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmst.2018.06.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji S, He H, Karlov&#x161;ek J. Application of superposition method to study the mechanical behaviour of overlying strata in longwall mining. Int J Rock Mech Min Sci. 2021;146:104874. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmms.2021.104874</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2021.104874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie SR, Chen DD, Zeng JC. Spatiotemporal relationship between the initial fracture of the main roof structure and overall rebound. J China Coal Soc. 2019;(9).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An F, Yuan Y, Chen X, Li Z, Li L. Expansion energy of coal gas for the initiation of coal and gas outbursts. Fuel. 2019;235:551&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2018.07.132</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2018.07.132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>