<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41841083</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Uterine Smooth Muscle Tumor of Uncertain Malignant Potential (STUMP): A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103536</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103536</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103536</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103536</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Uterine smooth muscle tumors of uncertain malignant potential (STUMP) are rare mesenchymal neoplasms that occupy a diagnostic gray zone between benign leiomyomas and malignant leiomyosarcomas. Owing to their low incidence and overlapping clinical, radiological, and histopathological features, STUMPs pose significant diagnostic and therapeutic challenges and are frequently identified only after surgical intervention for presumed benign disease. We report the case of a 39-year-old Mexican woman with a two-year history of abnormal uterine bleeding (AUB) and severe dysmenorrhea. Preoperative imaging findings were consistent with an intramural uterine mass and diffuse adenomyosis. The patient underwent a total abdominal hysterectomy with bilateral salpingectomy. Histopathological examination revealed a smooth muscle tumor characterized by focal nuclear atypia, a low mitotic index of up to 2 mitoses per 10 high-power fields, and absence of coagulative tumor cell necrosis (CTCN), findings consistent with a diagnosis of STUMP. The postoperative course was uneventful, and the patient was referred for long-term clinical surveillance. This report constitutes the first indexed case of STUMP in a Mexican patient and underscores the importance of thorough histopathological evaluation for accurate diagnosis, as well as the relevance of structured long-term follow-up given the potential for delayed recurrence.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Interian-Alvarez et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Interian-Alvarez</LastName><ForeName>Fernando J</ForeName><Initials>FJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecology and Obstetrics, Hospital Regional "Elvia Carrillo Puerto" Institute for Social Security and Services for State Workers (ISSSTE), M&#xe9;rida, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Universidad Aut&#xf3;noma de Yucat&#xe1;n, M&#xe9;rida, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pumares-Campos</LastName><ForeName>Jocelyn</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecology and Obstetrics, Hospital Regional "Elvia Carrillo Puerto" Institute for Social Security and Services for State Workers (ISSSTE), M&#xe9;rida, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reyes-Cabrera</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Hospital Regional "Elvia Carrillo Puerto" Institute for Social Security and Services for State Workers (ISSSTE), M&#xe9;rida, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ortiz-Villanueva</LastName><ForeName>Brayan J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, La Salle University, Mexico City, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecological Endoscopic Surgery, Hospital Regional Adolfo L&#xf3;pez Mateos, Institute for Social Security and Services for State Workers (ISSSTE), Mexico City, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mendoza-Arcique</LastName><ForeName>Diana L</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecology and Obstetrics, Hospital Regional "Elvia Carrillo Puerto" Institute for Social Security and Services for State Workers (ISSSTE), M&#xe9;rida, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">abnormal uterine bleeding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">case report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">histopathological diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hysterectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-term surveillance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recurrence risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stump</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">uterine mesenchymal tumor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">uterine smooth muscle tumor of uncertain malignant potential</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41841083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12989177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abd Almohsen N. Gynecologic Pathology. Encyclopedia of Pathology. Cham: Springer; 2023. WHO classification of tumors of the uterine corpus, pathology of the uterine corpus.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uterine smooth muscle tumors of uncertain malignant potential: a retrospective evaluation of clinical pathology and immunohistochemistry features. Akbarzadeh-Jahromi M, Todarbary N, Aslani FS, Najib F, Zare M, Amirmoezi F. Surg Exp Pathol. 2024;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uterine smooth muscle tumor of uncertain malignant potential (STUMP): case report and literature review (Article in Spanish) Serrano Ortiz OF, Hern&#xe1;ndez G&#xf3;mez JA, Santana DJ, Bonilla Gonzalez CF, Garc&#xed;a Burgos A, Luna J. Rev Colomb Cancerol. 2023;27:114&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smooth muscle tumor of uncertain malignant potential (STUMP): a comprehensive multidisciplinary update. Tinelli A, D'Oria O, Civino E, et al. Medicina (Kaunas) 2023;59</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10456637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37629661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The SCARE 2023 guideline: updating consensus Surgical CAse REport (SCARE) guidelines. Sohrabi C, Mathew G, Maria N, Kerwan A, Franchi T, Agha RA. Int J Surg. 2023;109:1136&#x2013;1140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10389401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37013953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The FIGO classification of causes of abnormal uterine bleeding in the reproductive years. Munro MG, Critchley HO, Fraser IS. Fertil Steril. 2011;95:2204&#x2013;2208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21496802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Problematic uterine smooth muscle neoplasms. A clinicopathologic study of 213 cases. Bell SW, Kempson RL, Hendrickson MR. http://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8179071/ Am J Surg Pathol. 1994;18:535&#x2013;558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8179071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recurrence of uterine smooth muscle tumor of uncertain malignant potential: a systematic review of the literature. Di Giuseppe J, Grelloni C, Giuliani L, Delli Carpini G, Giannella L, Ciavattini A. Cancers (Basel) 2022;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9104240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35565452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>p53, p16 and ki67 as immunohistochemical prognostic markers in uterine smooth muscle tumors of uncertain malignant potential (STUMP) Travaglino A, Raffone A, Gencarelli A, et al. Pathol Res Pract. 2021;226:153592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34481212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turashvili G. Smooth muscle tumors of uncertain malignant potential. 2021. https://www.pathologyoutlines.com/topic/uterusstump.html https://www.pathologyoutlines.com/topic/uterusstump.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smooth muscle tumor of uncertain malignant potential (STUMP): a systematic review of the literature in the last 20 years. Bucuri CE, Ciortea R, Malutan AM, et al. Curr Oncol. 2024;31:5242&#x2013;5254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11430651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39330016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardighieri L, Ayhan A, Strickland AL. Adenomatoid tumor. 2024. http://www.pathologyoutlines.com/topic/uterusadenomatoid.html http://www.pathologyoutlines.com/topic/uterusadenomatoid.html</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>