<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41400588</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-8649</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of fish biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Fish Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of population dynamics parameters estimated for 34 bony fishes in oligotrophic Mediterranean shelf/break waters.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jfb.70302</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Understanding the life-history patterns of fish species is crucial for effective fisheries management across temporal and spatial scales. This study investigates the population dynamics of fish inhabiting the shelf and break zone of the Gulf of Antalya, a highly oligotrophic region of the Mediterranean Sea that serves as a major spawning ground for various species, including fast-growing deep-sea fishes that reach maturity within 1-2&#x2009;years. Population parameters, such as asymptotic length and growth rate, were estimated from length-frequency distributions using ELEFAN I in the FISAT programme. Multi-species analyses, particularly of dominant taxa, were performed to evaluate their interactions within the study area, while seasonality and environmental variability were also considered. A total of 165 demersal and some pelagic fish species were recorded throughout the year, of which 34 bony fish species were examined in detail. The results showed that population parameters varied significantly with both fish size and bottom depth. Along the shelf (10-75&#x2009;m), asymptotic length (L<sub>&#x221e;</sub>) and growth rate (K) decreased with depth. At the shelf edge (200&#x2009;m), L<sub>&#x221e;</sub> remained high and K declined, whereas at the shelf break (300&#x2009;m), L<sub>&#x221e;</sub> decreased and K increased. Mortality rates [total mortality (Z) and natural mortality (M)] declined with increasing fish size, with medium-sized fishes exhibiting the highest Z values. The relationship between maximum age (tmax) and natural mortality (M) showed a significant correlation, particularly across size classes rather than depth strata. A comparative analysis with data from 524 publications indicated that population parameters are strongly influenced by geographical location within the Mediterranean, temporal variation (e.g., pre-2000s, 1990s-2000s, post-2000s) and west-east spatial gradients. This study also provides the first comprehensive population characteristics for four species - Epinephelus aeneus, Glossanodon leioglossus, Macroramphosus scolopax and Pagrus caeruleostictus - with important ecological and management implications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Fisheries Society of the British Isles.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mutlu</LastName><ForeName>Erhan</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6825-3587</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Basic Sciences, Fisheries Faculty, Akdeniz University, Antalya, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miglietta</LastName><ForeName>Claudia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Independent Researcher, Cellino San Marco, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Meo</LastName><ForeName>Ilaria</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Basic Sciences, EcoFishUS Research, Seville, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deval</LastName><ForeName>Mehmet Cengiz</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Fisheries and Processing of Aquatic Products, Fisheries Faculty, Akdeniz University, Antalya, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2014.01.0111.001</GrantID><Agency>Akdeniz &#xdc;niversitesi</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2014.01.0111.001</GrantID><Agency>Scientific Research 714 Coordination Unit of Akdeniz University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Fish Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0214055</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-1112</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Levantine Sea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bony fish</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multi&#x2010;species analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oligotrophic waters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">population dynamics</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41400588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jfb.70302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Abaunza, P., Gordo, L. S., Garc'&#x131;a Santamar'&#x131;a, M. T., Iversen, S. A., Murta, A. G., &amp; Gallo, E. (2008). Life history parameters as basis for the initial recognition of stock management units in horse mackerel (Trachurus trachurus). Fisheries Research, 89, 167&#x2013;180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ailane, F., Kassar, A., &amp; Hemida, F. (2021). Growth and mortality of Serranus cabrilla (Linnaeus, 1758) (Actinopterygii: Perciformes: Serranidae) from Bou Ismail Bay, off Algeria, south&#x2010;western Mediterranean. Indian Journal of Fishery, 68(2), 1&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.21077/ijf.2021.68.2.100525-01</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alekseev, F. E. (1983). Hermaphroditism in porgies (Perciforme: Sparidae). II. Sexual structure of populations, mechanism of its formation and evolution in scups, Pagrus pagrus, P. Orphus, P. ehrenbergi and P. auriga. Journal of Ichthyology, 23, 61&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allam, S. (2003). Growth, mortality and yield per recruit of Bogue, Boops boops (L.), from the Egyptian Mediterranean waters off Alexandria. Mediterranean Marine Science, 4(1), 87&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.12681/mms.244</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al&#xf3;s, J., Palmer, M., Alonso&#x2010;Fern&#xe1;ndez, A., &amp; Morales&#x2010;Nin, B. (2010). Individual variability and sex&#x2010;related differences in the growth of Diplodus annularis (Linnaeus, 1758). Fisheries Research, 101(1&#x2013;2), 60&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves, D. C., Vasconcelos, L. P., &amp; Agostinho, A. A. (2018). Age composition and growth without age data: A likelihood&#x2010;based model. Fisheries Research, 204, 361&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasopoulou, A., Yiannopoulos, C., Megalofonou, P., &amp; Papaconstantinou, C. (2006). Distribution and population structure of the Chlorophthalmus agassizi (Bonaparte, 1840) on an unexploited fishing ground in the Greek Ionian Sea. Journal of Applied Ichthyology, 22, 521&#x2013;529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appeldoorn, R. (1987). Modification of a seasonally oscillating growth function for use with mark&#x2010;recapture data. ICES Journal of Marine Science, 43, 194&#x2013;198. https://doi.org/10.1093/icesjms/43.3.194</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagenal, T. B., &amp; Tesch, F. W. (1978). Age and growth. In T. B. Bagenal (Ed.), Methods for assessment of fish production in fresh waters. IBP Handbook, 3 (pp. 101&#x2013;136). Blackwell Scientific Publications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba&#x15f;usta, A., Ba&#x15f;usta, N., Ozcan, E. I., &amp; Girgin, H. (2020). Age and growth of the Lessepsian migrant Lagocephalus spadiceus (Actinopterygii: Tetraodontiformes: Tetraodontidae) from the Gulf of Iskenderun, north&#x2010;eastern Mediterranean, Turkey. Acta Ichthyologica et Piscatoria, 50(3), 325&#x2013;332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba&#x15f;usta, A., Ozcan, E. I., &amp; Ba&#x15f;usta, N. (2020). Age and growth of the phaeton dragonet, Synchiropus phaeton (Actinopterygii: Perciformes: Callionymidae), from the Gulf of Iskenderun, north&#x2010;eastern Mediterranean, Turkey. Ichthyologica Piscatoria, 50(1), 63&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauchot, R., Ridet, J. M., &amp; Bauchot, M.&#x2010;L. (1989). The brain organization of butterflyfishes. Environmental Biology of Fishes, 25(1/3), 205&#x2013;219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beverton, R. J. H. (1954). Maturation, growth and mortality of clupeid and Engraulid stocks in relation to fishing. Rapports et Proc&#xe8;s&#x2010;Verbaux des R&#xe9;unions, 154, 44&#x2013;67. https://doi.org/10.17895/ices.pub.19274888</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beverton, R. J. (1987). Longevity in fish: Some ecological and evolutionary considerations. Basic Life Sciences, 42, 161&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharya, C. G. (1967). A simple method of resolution of a distribution into Gaussian components. Biometrics, 23, 115&#x2013;135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bianchini, M., &amp; Ragonese, S. (2011). Establishing length&#x2010;at&#x2010;age references in the red mullet, Mullus barbatus L. 1758 (Pisces, Mullidae), a case study for growth assessments in the Mediterranean geographical sub&#x2010;areas (GSA). Mediterranean Marine Science, 12(2), 316&#x2013;332. https://doi.org/10.12681/mms.35</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilecenoglu, M. (2009). Growth and feeding habits of the brown comber, Serranus hepatus (Linnaeus, 1758) in Izmir Bay, Aegean Sea. Acta Adriatica, 50(1), 105&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bingel, F. (2002). Bal&#x131;k Populasyonlar&#x131;n&#x131;n &#x130;ncelenmesi. Baki Kulu Kitabevi.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bingel, F., Gucu, A. C., &amp; Mutlu, E. (1990). Bal&#x131;kc&#x131;l&#x131;k biyolojisi bilgisayar paket program&#x131;, BALIKIST (A Package computer programs for fisheries biology, FISHSTAT). Techical Report and Manual, Middle East Technical University&#x2010;Institute of Marine Sciences, Erdemli, Mersin, Turkey, pp. 105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bingel, F., G&#xfc;c&#xfc;, A. C., &amp; Mutlu, E. (1994). Computation programs for some applications in fisheries biology (written in Basic), FISHSTAT. Technical Report and Manual, IPB University (Institut Pertanian Bogor), IPB, Bogor, Indonesia, pp. 35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottari, T., Dimech, M., Nardone, G., Rinelli, P., &amp; Ragonese, S. (2010). Distribution and biological features of the African armoured searobin, Peristedion cataphractum L. 1758 (Teleostei, Peristediidae) off the southern coasts of Sicily (Mediterranean Sea). Acta Ichthyologica et Piscatoria, 40(2), 113&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottari, T., Nardone, G., Rinelli, P., &amp; Ragonese, S. (2011). Is the African armoured searobin (Peristedion cataphractum, Peristediidae) stock off the south Sicily and north African coasts a &#x201c;unit stock&#x201d;? Cybium, 35(2), 91&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouain, A. (1983). Croissance lineaire des serrans des cotes sud&#x2010;est de la Tunisie. Rapport De La Commission Internationale De La Mer M&#xe9;diterran&#xe9;e, 28(5), 87&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbonara, P., Zupa, W., Anastasopoulou, A., Bellodi, A., Bittetto, I., Charilaou, C., Chatzispirou, A., Elleboode, R., Esteban, A., Follesa, M. C., Isajlovic, I., Jadaud, A., Garcia&#x2010;Ruiz, C., Giannakaki, A., Guijarro, B., Kiparissis, S. E., Ligas, A., Mah&#xe9;, K., Massaro, A., &#x2026; Sion, L. (2019). Explorative analysis on red mullet (Mullus barbatus) ageing data variability in the Mediterranean. Scientia Marina, 83, 271&#x2013;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charnov, E. (1993). Life history invariants. In Oxford Series in Ecology and Evolution. Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charnov, E. L., Gislason, H., &amp; Pope, J. G. (2012). Evolutionary assembly rules for fish life histories. Fish and Fisheries, 14(2), 213&#x2013;224. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-2979.2012.00467.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilari, A., George, P., &amp; Evaggelos, T. (2006). Aspects of the biology of blackspot seabream (Pagellus bogaraveo) in the Ionian Sea, Greece. Fisheries Research, 77, 84&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cicek, E., &amp; Avsar, D. (2011). Growth, mortality and spatial distribution of brushtooth lizardfish, Saurida undosquamis (Richardson, 1848), inhabiting the Karatas coasts (Iskenderun Bay, northeastern Mediterranean). Acta Zoologica Bulgarica, 63, 97&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coll, M., Piroddi, C., Steenbeek, J., Kaschner, K., Ben Rais Lasram, F., Aguzzi, J., Ballesteros, E., Bianchi, C. N., Corbera, J., Dailianis, T., Danovaro, R., Estrada, M., Froglia, C., Galil, B. S., Gasol, J. M., Gertwagen, R., Gil, J., Guilhaumon, F., Kesner&#x2010;Reyes, K., &#x2026; Voultsiadou, E. (2010). The biodiversity of the Mediterranean Sea: Estimates, patterns, and threats. PLoS One, 5(8), e11842. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0011842</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colloca, F., Cardinale, M., &amp; Ardizzone, G. D. (1997). Biology, spatial distribution and population dynamics of Lepidotrigla cavillone [Pisces: Triglidae] in the Central Tyrrhenian Sea. Fisheries Research, 32, 21&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Meo, I., Miglietta, C., Mutlu, E., Deval, M. C., Balaban, C., &amp; Olguner, T. M. (2018). Ecological distribution of demersal fish species in space and time on the shelf of Antalya gulf, Turkey. Marine Biodiversity, 48, 2105&#x2013;2118. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12526-017-0739-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Mitcheson, Y. S., &amp; Liu, M. (2008). Functional hermaphroditism in teleosts. Fish and Fisheries, 9, 1&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deval, M. C., Kebap&#xe7;&#x131;o&#x11f;lu, T., G&#xfc;ven, O., &amp; Olguner, M. T. (2018). Population pattern and dynamics of the Bluemouth Helicolenus dactylopterus (Delaroche, 1809) in the eastern Mediterranean Sea. Journal of Applied Ichthyology, 34, 568&#x2013;580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deval, M. C., &amp; Mutlu, E. (2024). Spatio&#x2010;temporal density of the demersal Chondrichthyes assemblage in an upper bathyal of the eastern Mediterranean Sea. Marine Biodiversity, 54(2), 31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Onghia, G., Sion, L., Maiorano, P., Mytilineou, C., Dalessandro, S., Carlucci, R., &amp; Desantis, S. (2006). Population biology and life strategies of Chlorophthalmus agassizii Bonaparte, 1840 (Pisces: Osteichthyes) in the Mediterranean Sea. Marine Biology, 14, 435&#x2013;446. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00227-005-0231-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dulcic, J., Kraljevic, M., &amp; Cetinic, G. P. (2000). Age, growth and mortality of blotched picarel Spicara maena L. (Pisces: Centracanthidae) in the eastern central Adriatic. Fisheries Research, 48, 69&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dulcic, J., Pallaoro, A., Cetinic, P., Kraljevic, M., Soldo, A., &amp; Jardas, I. (2003). Age, growth and mortality of picarel, Spicara smaris L. (Pisces: Centracanthidae), from the eastern Adriatic (Croatian coast). Journal of Applied Ichthyology, 19, 10&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferri, J., Br&#x10d;i&#x107;, J., &#x160;keljo, F., Sr&#x161;en, L., &amp; Uvodi&#x107;, A. (2017). A preliminary study on the age and growth of the Argentine, Argentina sphyraena (Actinopterygii: Osmeriformes: Argentinidae) from the eastern Adriatic Sea. Acta Ichthyologica et Piscatoria, 47(4), 365&#x2013;369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filiz, H., Bilge, G., Irmak, E., Togugla, M., Uckun, D., &amp; Akalin, S. (2006). Age and growth of hollowsnout grenadier, Caelorinchus caelorhincus (Risso, 1810), in the Aegean Sea. Journal of Applied Ichthyology, 22, 285&#x2013;287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Froese, R. &amp; Pauly, D. (2024). FishBase. World wide web electronic publication. www.fishbase.org, version (02/2024)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamito, S. (1998). Growth models and their use in ecological modelling: An application to a fish populatio. Ecological Modelling, 113, 83&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gayanilo, F. C., &amp; Pauly, D. (2001). FAO&#x2010;ICLARM fish stock assessment tools (FISAT II ver. 0.4.1). FAO.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordo, L. S., Neves, A., Vieira, A. R., Paiva, R. B., &amp; Sequeira, V. (2016). Age, growth and mortality of the comber Serranus cabrilla (Linnaeus, 1758) in the eastern Atlantic. Marine Biology Research, 12, 656&#x2013;662. https://doi.org/10.1080/17451000.2016.1169295</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gul, G., Ismen, A., &amp; Arslan, M. (2014). Age, growth, and reproduction of Dentex maroccanus (Actinopterygii: Perciformes: Sparidae) in the Saros Bay (north Aegean Sea). Acta Ichthyologica et Piscatoria, 44(4), 295&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handjar, H., Guendouzi, Y., Niar, A., Kara, H., &amp; Benhalima, M. (2022). Stock status of the bogue Boops boops (Walbaum, 1792) in Algerian west coast (Southwestern Mediterranean Sea). Regional Studies in Marine Science, 56, 102727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris, P. J., &amp; McGovern, J. C. (1997). Changes in the life history of red porgy, Pagrus pagrus, from the southeastern United States, 1972&#x2010;1994*. Fishery Bulletin, 95(4), 732&#x2013;747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heral, O., &amp; Bayhan, B. (2020). Age and growth of Morocco Dentex dentex maroccanus Valenciennes, 1830 (Actinopterygii: Sparidae) in Izmir Bay,Central Aegean Sea, Turkey. Acta Zoologica Bulgarica, 72(1), 149&#x2013;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewitt, D. A., &amp; Hoenig, J. M. (2005). Comparison of two approaches for estimating natural mortality based on longevity. Fishery Bulletin, 103, 433&#x2013;437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoenig, J. M. (1983). Empirical use of longevity data to estimate mortality rates. Fishery bulletin, 81, 898&#x2013;903. Hoenig, J.M. (1983). Empirical use of longevity data to estimate mortality rates. Fishery Bulletin, 81, 898&#x2013;903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holden, M. J., &amp; Raitt, D. F. S. (1975). Manual de Ciencia pesquera. parte 2. M&#xe9;todos para investigar los recursos y su aplicaci&#xf3;n. Doc Tec FAO Pesca, 115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hordyk, A., Loneragan, N. R., &amp; Prince, J. D. (2015). An evaluation of an iterative harvest strategy for data&#x2010;poor fisheries using the length&#x2010;based spawning potential ratio assessment methodology. Fisheries Research, 171, 20&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fishres.2014.12.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hordyk, A., Ono, K., Sainsbury, K., Loneragan, N., &amp; Prince, J. (2015). Some explorations of the life history ratios to describe length composition, spawning&#x2010;per&#x2010;recruit, and the spawning potential ratio. ICES Journal of Marine Science, 72, 204&#x2013;216. https://doi.org/10.1093/icesjms/fst235</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismen, A. (1995). Growth, mortality and yield per recruit model ofpicarel (Spicara smaris L.) on the eastern Turkish Black Sea coast. Fisheries Research, 22, 299&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismen, A. (2006). Growth and reproduction of Por's goatfish (Upeneus pori Ben&#x2010;Tuvia &amp; Golani, 1989) in &#x130;skenderun bay, the eastern Mediterranean. Turkish Journal of Zoology, 30(1), 91&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x130;&#x15f;men, A. (2005). Age, growth and reproduction of the goldband goatfish, Upeneus moluccensis (Bleeker, 1855), in &#x130;skenderun bay, the eastern Mediterranean. Turkish Journal of Zoology, 29, 301&#x2013;309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen, A. L. (1995). Beverton and Holt life history invariants result from optimal trade&#x2010;off of reproduction and survival. Canadian Journal of Fisheries and Aquatic Sciences, 53, 820&#x2013;822.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalhoro, M. A., Liu, Q., Waryani, B., Panhwar, S. K., &amp; Memon, K. H. (2014). Growth and mortality of Brushtooth lizardfish, Saurida undosquamis,from Pakistani waters. Pakistan Journal of Zoology, 46(1), 139&#x2013;151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kara, A., &amp; Bayhan, B. (2015). Age and growth of Boops boops (Linnaeus, 1758) in Izmir Bay, Aegean Sea, Turkey. Journal of Applied Ichthyology, 31(4), 620&#x2013;626. https://doi.org/10.1111/jai.12680</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karachle, P. K., &amp; Stergiou, K. I. (2014). Diet and feeding habits of Spicara maena and S. Smaris (Pisces, Osteichthyes, Centracanthidae) in the North Aegean Sea. Acta Adriatica, 55(1), 75&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaya, M., Benli, H. A., Katagan, T., &amp; Ozaydin, O. (1999). Age, growth, sex&#x2010;ratio, spawning season and food of golden banded goat&#xae;sh, Upeneus moluccensis Bleeker (1855) from the Mediterranean and south Aegean Sea coasts of Turkey. Fisheries Research, 41, 317&#x2013;328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaldi, A., Chater, I., Elleboode, R., Mah&#xe9;, K., &amp; Chakroun&#x2010;Marzouk, N. (2021). Age, growth and mortality of the striped seabream Lithognathus mormyrus (Linnaeus, 1758) in the Gulf of Tunis (Central Mediterranean Sea). Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom, 101, 159&#x2013;167. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0025315420001307</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khemiri, S., Gaamour, A., Zylberberg, L., Meunier, F., &amp; Romdahane, M. S. (2005). Age and growth of bogue, Boops boops, in Tunisian waters. Acta Adriatica, 46, 159&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koca, H. U. (2023). Age, growth, and mortality of Bogue (Boops boops, Linnaeus, 1758) from the Antalya Bay (Northwest Mediterranean Sea, T&#xfc;rkiye). Israeli Journal of Aquaculture &#x2013; Bamidgeh, 75(2), 1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.46989/001c.84080</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraljevic, M., Dulcic, J., Cetinic, P., &amp; Pallaoro, A. (1996). Age, growth and mortality of the striped sea bream, Lithognathus mormyrus L. in the northern Adriatic. Fishery Research, 28(4), 361&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labropoulou, M., &amp; Papaconstantinou, C. (2000). Comparison of otolith growth and somatic growth in two macrourid fishes. Fisheries Research, 46, 177&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labropoulou, M., Tserpes, G., &amp; Tsimenides, N. (1998). Age, growth and feeding habits of the Brown comber Serranus hepatus (Linnaeus, 1758) on the Cretan shelf. Estuarine, Coastal and Shelf Science, 46, 723&#x2013;732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurec, A., &amp; Mesnil, B. (1987). Analytical investigations of errors in mortality rates estimated from length distributions of catches. In D. Pauly &amp; G. R. Morgan (Eds.), Length&#x2010;based methods in fisheries research. ICLARM Conference Proceedings 13 (pp. 239&#x2013;281). International Center for Living Aquatic Resources Management, Manila, Philippines, and Kuwait Institute for Scientific Research.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macpherson, E. (1979). Relations trophiques des poissons dans la M&#xe9;diterran&#xe9;e occidentale. Rapp. Comm. Int. Explor. Sci. Mer M&#xe9;diterr., 25(26), 49&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacPherson, E., &amp; Duarte, C. M. (1991). Bathymetric trends in demersal fish size: Is there a general relationship? Marine Ecology Progress Series, 71, 103&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez&#x2010;Ba&#xf1;os, P., Ram&#xed;rez, J. G., Demestre, M., &amp; Maynou, F. (2018). European hake (Merluccius merluccius) assessment based on size frequencies and basic biological parameters in the SW Mediterranean. Fisheries Research, 205, 35&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massuti, &#xc2;. E., Morales&#x2010;Nin, B., &amp; Stefanescu, C. (1995). Distribution and biology of five grenadier fish (Pisces: Macrouridae) from the upper and middle slope of the north&#x2010;western Mediterranean. Deep Sea Research, Part I: Oceanographic Research Papers, 42, 307&#x2013;330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massut&#xed;, E., Morales&#x2010;Nin, B., &amp; Moranta, J. (2000). Age and growth of blue&#x2010;mouth, Helicolenus dactylopterus (Osteichthyes: Scorpaenidae), in the western Mediterranean. Fisheries Research, 46, 165&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathews, C. P. (1974). An account of some methods of overcoming errors in ageing tropical and subtropical fish populations when hard tissue growth marking are unreliable and the data sparse. In T. B. Bagenal (Ed.), Ageing of fish (pp. 158&#x2013;166). Unwin Brothers.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathews, C. P. (1987). Fisheries management in a developing country: The most appropriate balance of size&#x2010; and age&#x2010;related methods for practical assessments. In D. Pauly &amp; G. R. Morgan (Eds.), Length&#x2010;based methods in fisheries research. ICLARM Conference Proceedings (Vol. 13, pp. 321&#x2013;334). International Center for Living Aquatic Resources Management, Manila, Philippines, and Kuwait Institute for Scientific Research.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald, J. F., &amp; Palanacki, D. (1989). Interval estimation of the size of a small population from a mark&#x2010;recapture experiment. Biometrics, 45(4), 1223&#x2013;1231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehanna, S. F. (2018). Population dynamics of two Lessepsian migrant goatfish species; Upeneus pori and Upeneus moluccensis from the southeastern Mediterranean, Port Said region, Egypt. In A. Kallel, et al. (Eds.), Recent advances in environmental science from the Euro&#x2010;Mediterranean and surrounding regions, advances in science, Technology &amp; Innovation, Springer Cham (pp. 1659&#x2013;1661).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehanna, S. F. (2022). Population parameters and reproductive biology of the streaked gurnard, Chelidonichthys lastoviza (Bonnaterre, 1788) in the Egyptian Mediterranean waters (GFCM&#x2010;GSA 26). Iranian Journal of Ichthyology, 9(4), 233&#x2013;243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellon&#x2010;Duval, C., de Pontual, H., M&#xe9;tral, L., &amp; Quemener, L. (2010). Growth of European hake (Merluccius merluccius) in the Gulf of lions based on conventional tagging. ICES Journal of Marine Science, 67, 62&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.1093/icesjms/fsp215</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metin, G., &#x130;lkyaz, A. T., Soykan, O., &amp; Kinacigil, H. T. (2011). Biological characteristics of the common pandora, Pagellus erythrinus (Linnaeus, 1758), in the central Aegean Sea. Turkish Journal of Zoology, 35(3), 2. https://doi.org/10.3906/zoo-0904-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohdeb, R., &amp; Kara, M. H. (2014). Age, growth and reproduction of the Morocco dentex Dentex maroccanus of the eastern coast of Algeria. Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom, 95(6), 1261&#x2013;1270. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0025315414001945</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteiro, P., Bentes, L., Coelho, R., Correia, C., Erzini, K., Lino, P. G., Ribeiro, J., &amp; Gon&#xe7;alves, J. M. S. (2010). Age and growth, mortality and reproduction of the striped sea bream Lithogonathus mormyrus Linnaeus, 1758, from the south coast of Portugal (Algarve). Marine Biology Research, 6, 53&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales&#x2010;Nin, B. (2001). Mediterranean deep&#x2010;water fish age determination and age validation: The state of the art. Fisheries Research, 51, 377&#x2013;383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moranta, J., Stefanescu, C., Massut&#xf5;&#xc2;, E., Morales&#x2010;Nin, B., &amp; Lloris, D. (1998). Fish community structure and depth&#x2010;related trends on the continental slope of the Balearic Islands (Algerian basin, western Mediterranean). Marine Ecology Progress Series, 171, 247&#x2013;259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morato, T., Afonso, P., Carvalho, N., Lourinho, P., Santos, R. S., Krug, H. M., &amp; Nash, R. D. M. (2007). Growth, reproduction and recruitment patterns of the wide&#x2010;eyed flounder, Bothus podas Delaroche (Pisces: Bothidae), from the Azores. Marine Biology Research, 3(6), 403&#x2013;411. https://doi.org/10.1080/17451000701712331</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moulleca, F. N., Velez, L., Verley, P., Barrier, N., Ulses, C., Carbonara, P., Esteban, A., Follesa, C., Gristina, M., &amp; Jadaud, A. (2019). Capturing the big picture of Mediterranean marine biodiversity with an endto&#x2010;end model of climate and fishing impacts. Progress in Oceanography, 178, 102179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutlu, E. (2013). Morphometry and areal growth cohorts of common epifaunal species on a sand bottom of the Cilician shelf (Turkey), Mediterranean Sea. Journal of Applied Biological Sciences, 7(2), 42&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutlu, E., de Meo, I., &amp; Miglietta, C. (2021). Spatio&#x2010;temporal distribution of pufferfish (Tetraodontidae) along the Turkish coast of the Mediterranean Sea. Mediterranean Marine Science, 22(1), 1&#x2013;19. https://doi.org/10.12681/mms.23481</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutlu, E., Deval, M. C., De Meo, I., Saygu, &#x130;., &amp; Miglietta, C. (2022). Spatiotemporal density and ecology of batoids (Elasmobranchii) along a Turkish shelf&#x2010;upper slope of the Mediterranean Sea during years 2009&#x2013;2015. Thalassas: An International Journal of Marine Sciences, 38(1), 57&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutlu, E., K&#x131;dey&#x15f;, A. E., &#x15e;ahin, F., Erik, G., Aksu, H., Erdem, E., Karay&#xfc;cel, S., &amp; Bat, L. (2022). Population dynamics and ecology of the invasive veined rapa whelk, Rapana venosa in the southern Black Sea. Estuarine, Coastal and Shelf Science, 268, 107807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutlu, E., Meo, I. D., Miglietta, C., &amp; Deval, M. C. (2023). Ecological indicative stressors of native vs. non&#x2010;native fish in an ultra&#x2010;oligotrophic region of the Mediterranean Sea. Sustainability, 15(3), 2726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutlu, E., Migletta, C., De Meo, I., &amp; Deval, M. C. (2022). Spatiotemporal and bioecological distribution of four commercial mullid species in an ultra&#x2010;oligotrophic Mediterranean gulf. Turkish Journal of Zoology, 46(6), 484&#x2013;499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutlu, E., Miglietta, C., De Meo, I., &amp; Deval, M. C. (2022). Length&#x2010;weight relationships of 107 osseous and 9 cartilaginous fish species on a shelf&#x2010;break zone of the eastern Mediterranean Sea. Cahiers de Biologie Marine, 63(1), 19&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutlu, E., Olguner, C., G&#xf6;ko&#x11f;lu, M., &amp; &#xd6;zvarol, Y. (2022a). Population dynamics and ecology of Caulerpa prolifera vs Caulerpa taxifolia var. distichophylla within a Levantine gulf. Thalassas: An International Journal of Marine Sciences, 38(2), 1311&#x2013;1325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutlu, E., Olguner, C., G&#xf6;ko&#x11f;lu, M., &amp; &#xd6;zvarol, Y. (2022b). Seasonal growth dynamics of Posidonia oceanica in a pristine Mediterranean gulf. Ocean Science Journal, 57(3), 381&#x2013;397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutlu, E., Olguner, C., &#xd6;zvarol, Y., &amp; G&#xf6;ko&#x11f;lu, M. (2022). Spatiotemporal biometrics of Cymodocea nodosa in a western Turkish Mediterranean coast. Biologia, 77(3), 649&#x2013;670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadon, M. O., &amp; Ault, J. S. (2016). A stepwise stochastic simulation approach to estimate life history parameters for data&#x2010;poor fisheries. Canadian Journal of Fisheries and Aquatic Sciences, 73, 1&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.1139/cjfas-2015-0303</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nash, R. D. M., &amp; Geffen, A. J. (2005). Age and growth. In R. N. Gibson (Ed.), Flatfishes. Biology and exploitation. Fish and Aquatic Resources Series 9 (pp. 138&#x2013;153). Blackwell Science.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikiforidou, V., Gkikas, E., Mytilineou, C., Haralabous, J., Koutsoubas, D., &amp; Anastasopoulou, A. (2023). Age, growth and otolith morphometrics of Serranus hepatus (L., 1758) in two areas of the eastern Mediterranean. Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom, 103, e59. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0025315423000474</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pajuelo, G., &amp; Lorenzo, J. M. (1998). Population biology of the common pandora Pagellus erythrinus (Pisces: Sparidae) off the Canary Islands. Fisheries Research, 36, 75&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pajuelo, J. G., &amp; Lorenzo, J. M. (1996). Life history of the red porgy Pagrus pagrus (Teleostei: Sparidae) off the Canary Islands, central east Atlantic. Fisheries Research, 28, 163&#x2013;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pajuelo, J. G., &amp; Lorenzo, J. M. (2002). Edad y crecimiento del raspall&#xf3;n, Diplodus annularis (Pisces: Sparidae), en el archipi&#xe9;lago Canario (Atl&#xe1;ntico centro&#x2010;oriental). Ciencias Marinas, 28(1), 1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pajuelo, J'e. G., Mart&#x131;nez, I., Gonzalez, J. A., Lorenzo, J. M., Garc&#x131;a&#x2010;Mederos, A., Dom&#x131;nguez&#x2010;Seoane, R., &amp; Hernandez&#x2010;Cruz, C. M. (2006). Growth pattern and age estimation of the coastal sparid fish Pagrus auriga on the Canary Islands shelf. Fisheries Research, 82, 7&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papaconstantinon, C., Mytilineou, C., &amp; Panos, T. (1988). Aspects of the life of red pandora, Pagellus erythrinus (Sparidae) off western Greece. Cybium, 12, 267&#x2013;280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauly, D. (1980). On the interrelationships between natural mortality, growth parameters and mean environmental temperature in 175 fish stocks. Journal du Conseil, CIEM, 39(3), 175&#x2013;192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauly, D. (1983). Some simple methods for the the assessment of tropical fish stock. Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauly, D. (1984a). Fish population dynamics in tropical waters: A manual for use with programmable calculators. ICLARM Studies and Review, 8, 325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauly, D. (1984b). Length&#x2010;converted catch curves: A powerful tool for fisheries research in the tropics (part II). ICLARM Fishbyte, 2(1), 17&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauly, D. (1987). A review of the ELEFAN system for analysis of length&#x2010;frequency data in fish and aquatic invertebrates. In D. Pauly &amp; G. R. Morgan (Eds.), Length&#x2010;based methods in fisheries research. ICLARM Conference Proceedings (Vol. 13, p. 468). International Center for Living Aquatic Resources Management, Manila, Philippines, and Kuwait Institute for Scientific Research.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauly, D. (1990). Length&#x2010;converted catch curves and the seasonal growth of fishes. ICLARM Fishbyte, 8(3), 33&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauly, D., &amp; Morgan, G. R. (1987). Length&#x2010;based methods in fisheries research. In ICLARM conference proceedings (Vol. 13, p. 468). International Center for Living Aquatic Resources Management, Manila, Philippines, and Kuwait Institute for Scientific Research.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philips, A. E. (2014). Age composition of the European hake Merluccius merluccius, Linnaeus, 1758 from the Egyptian Mediterranean waters off Alexandria. Egyptian Journal of Aquatic Research, 40, 163&#x2013;169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pineiro, C., &amp; Sainza, M. (2003). Age estimation, growth and maturity of the European hake (Merluccius merluccius (Linnaeus, 1758)) from Iberian Atlantic waters. ICES Journal of Marine Science, 60, 1086&#x2013;1102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirrera, L., Bottari, T., Busalacchi, B., Giordano, D., Modica, L., Perdichizzi, A., Perdichizzi, F., Profeta, A., &amp; Rinelli, P. (2009). Distribution and population structure of the fish Helicolenus dactylopterus dactylopterus (Delaroche, 1809) in the Central Mediterranean (southern Tyrrhenian Sea). Marine Ecology, 30, 161&#x2013;174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell, D. G. (1979). Estimation of mortality and growth parameters from the length&#x2010;frequency in the catch. Rapports et Proc&#xe8;s&#x2010;Verbaux des R&#xe9;unions, CIEM, 175, 167&#x2013;169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafail, S. Z. (1971). A new growth model for fishes and the estimation of optimum age of fish populations. Marine Biology, 10, 3&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragonese, S., Vitale, S., Mazzola, S., Pagliarino, E., &amp; Bianchini, M. L. (2012). Behavior of some growth performance indexes for exploited Mediterranean hake. Acta Adriatica, 53(1), 105&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricker, W. E. (1975). Computation and interpretation of biological statistics of fish populations. Bulletin/Fisheries Research Board of Canada, 191, 382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rochet, M. J. (1998). Short&#x2010;term effects of fishing on life history traits of fishes. ICES Journal of Marine Science, 55, 371&#x2013;391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez&#x2010;Castaneda, J. C., Ventero, A., Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;Marquez, M. G., &amp; Iglesias, M. (2022). Spatial and temporal analysis (2009&#x2013;2020) of the biological parameters, abundance and distribution of Trachurus mediterraneus (Steindachner, 1868) in the Western Mediterranean. Fisheries Research, 256, 106483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabry, S. E.&#x2010;S., El&#x2010;Gammal, F. I., Mehanna, S. F., Abdel&#x2010;Hameid, N.&#x2010;A. H., &amp; Farrag, E. F. E. (2015). Age, growth and mortality of streaked gurnard (Trigloporus lastoviza, Bonnaterre, 1788) in the Egyptian Mediterranean waters off Alexandria. International Journal of Fisheries and Aqu Atic Studies, 3(1), 75&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayg&#x131;l&#x131;, B., &#x130;&#x15f;men, A., &amp; Arslan &#x130;hsano&#x11f;lu, M. (2016). Age and growth of blotched picarel (Spicara maena Linnaeus, 1758) in the sea of Marmara and northern Aegean Sea. Ege Journal of Fisheries and Aquatic Sciences, 33(2), 143&#x2013;149. https://doi.org/10.12714/egejfas.2016.33.2.08</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schintu, P., Passariello, M., Belluscio, A., &amp; Ardizzone, G. D. (1994). Growth and diet of Bothus podas (Pisces: Bothidae) in the Central Mediterranean Sea. Scientia Marina, 58, 359&#x2013;361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepherd, J. G. (1987a). Towards a method for short&#x2010;term forecasting of catch rates based on length compositions. In D. Pauly &amp; G. R. Morgan (Eds.), Length&#x2010;based methods in fisheries research. ICLARM conference proceedings (Vol. 13, pp. 167&#x2013;176). International Center for Living Aquatic Resources Management, Manila, Philippines, and Kuwait Institute for Scientific Research.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepherd, J. G. (1987b). A weakly parametric method for estimating growth parameters from length composition data. In D. Pauly &amp; G. R. Morgan (Eds.), Length&#x2010;based methods in fisheries research. ICLARM Conf. Proc. 13, Manilla : ICLARM (pp. 113&#x2013;119).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimazaki, H., &amp; Shinomoto, S. (2007). A method forselecting the bin size of a time histogram. Neural Computation, 19, 1503&#x2013;1527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sisma&#x2010;Ventura, G., Bialik, O. M., Yam, R., Herut, B., &amp; Silverman, J. (2017). pCO2 variability in the surface waters of the ultra&#x2010;oligotrophic Levantine Sea: Exploring the air&#x2013;sea CO2 fluxes in a fast warming region. Marine Chemistry, 196, 13&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somarakis, S., &amp; Machias, A. (2002). Age, growth and batymetric distribution of red pandora (Pagellus erytrinus) on the Cretan shelf (eastern Mediterranean). Journal of Marine Biological Association in UK, 82, 149&#x2013;160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonin, O., Spanier, E., Levi, D., Patti, B., Rizzo, P., &amp; Andreoli, M. G. (2007). Nanism (dwarfism) in fish: A comparison between red mullet Mullus barbatus from the southeastern and the central Mediterranean. Marine Ecological Progres Series, 343, 221&#x2013;228. https://doi.org/10.3354/meps06917</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparre, P. (1987). Method for the estimation of growth, mortality and gear selection/recruitment parameters from length&#x2010;frequency samples weighted by catch per effort, 75&#x2010;102. In D. Pauly &amp; G. R. Morgan (Eds.), Length&#x2010;based methods in fisheries research. Length&#x2010;based methods in fisheries research. ICLARM Conference Proceedings 13 (p. 468). International Center for Living Aquatic Resources Management, Manila, Philippines, and Kuwait Institute for Scientific Research.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparre, R. (1989). What is the optimum interval class size for length&#x2010;frequency analysis? Fishbyte, 7(2), 23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stergiou, K. I. (2000). Life&#x2010;history patterns of fishes in the Hellenic seas. Web Ecology, 1, 1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stergiou, K. I., &amp; Karpouzi, V. S. (2002). Feeding habits and trophic levels of Mediterranean fish. Reviews in Fish Biology and Fisheries, 11(3), 217&#x2013;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, C. C. (1958). Cod growth and temperature. ICES Journal of Marine Science, 23, 366&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira, C. M., Batista, M. I., &amp; Cabral, H. N. (2010). Diet, growth and reproduction of four flatfishes on the Portuguese coast. Scientia Marina, 74(2), 223&#x2013;233. https://doi.org/10.3989/scimar.2010.74n2223</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Then, A. Y., Hoenig, J. M., Hall, N. G., &amp; Hewitt, D. A. (2014). Evaluating the predictive performance of empirical of predatory fish communities. Nature, 423, 280&#x2013;283. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature01610</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Then, A. Y., Hoenig, J. M., Hall, N. G., &amp; Hewitt, D. A. (2015). Evaluating the predictive performance of empirical estimators of natural mortality rate using information on over 200 fish species. ICES Journal of Marine Science, 72, 82&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsangridis, A., &amp; Filippousis, N. (1988). Length&#x2010;based approach to the estimation of growth and mortality parameters of Spicara smaris (L.) in the Saronikos gulf, Greece, and remarks on the application of the Beverton and Holt relative yield per recruit model. FAO Fishery Report, 412, 94&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsangridis, A., &amp; Filippousis, N. (1991). Use of length&#x2010;frequency data in the estimation of growth parameters of three Mediterranean fish species: Bogue (Boops boops L.), picarel (Spicara smaris L.) and horse mackerel (Trachurus trachurus L.). Fisheries Research, 12, 283&#x2013;297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsangridis, A., &amp; Filippousis, N. (1992). Growth pattern of picarel, S. smaris (L.) (Centacanthidae), a protogynous species. Cybium, 16(3), 233&#x2013;243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tserpesa, G., &amp; Tsimenides, N. (2001). Age, growth and mortality of Serranus cabrilla (Linnaeus, 1758) on the Cretan shelf. Fisheries Research, 51, 27&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turley, C. M., Bianchi, M., Christaki, U., Conan, P., Harris, J. R. W., Psarra, S., Ruddy, G., Stutt, E. D., Tselepides, A., &amp; Van Wambeke, F. (2000). The relationship between primary producers and bacteria in an oligotrophic sea &#x2010; the Mediterranean and biogeochemical implications. Marine Ecology Progress Series, 193, 11&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10.3354/meps193011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyler, P. A. (1988). Seasonality in deep sea. Oceanography and Marine Biology, 26, 227&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulut&#xfc;rk, E., Akal&#x131;n, S., Tunka&#x2010;Eronat, E. G., &#xd6;zayd&#x131;n, O., &amp; Tosuno&#x11f;lu, Z. (2016). Some biological aspects of spotted flounder Citharus linguatula (Linnaeus, 1758) in Izmir Bay (Aegean Sea). Ege Journal of Fisheries and Aquatic Sciences, 33(1), 1&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.12714/egejfas.2016.33.1.01</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vassilopoulou, V., &amp; Papaconstantinou, C. (1994). Age, growth and mortality of the spotted flounder (Citharus linguatula Linnaeus, 1758) in the Aegean Sea. Scientia Marina, 58(3), 261&#x2013;267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velasco, E. M., Jim&#xe9;nez Tenorio, N., Del Arbol, J., Bruz&#xf3;n, M. A., Baro, J., &amp; Sobrino, I. (2011). Age, growth and reproduction of the axillary seabream, Pagellus acarne, in the Atlantic and Mediterranean waters off southern Spain. Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom, 91(6), 1243&#x2013;1253. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0025315410000305</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vidalis, K., &amp; Tsimenidis, N. (1996). Age determination and growth of picarel (Spicara smaris) from the Cretan continental shelf (Greece). Fisheries Research, 28, 395&#x2013;421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wague, A., &amp; Papaconstantinou, C. (1997). Age, growth and mortality of the brown comber Serranus hepatus (L. 1758) (Pisces, Serranidae) in the Thermaikos gulf (Aegean Sea, Greece). Marine Life, 1/2, 39&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walpole, R. E. (1992). Pengantar Statistika [statistics Introduction] (2nd ed.). PT Gramedia Pustaka Utama.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, K., Zhang, C., Xu, B., Xue, Y., &amp; Ren, Y. (2020). Selecting optimal bin size to account for growth variability in electronic LEngth frequency ANalysis (ELEFAN). Fisheries Research, 225, 105474. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fishres.2019.105474</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wetherall, J. A. (1986). A new method for estimating growth and mortality parameters from length&#x2010;frequency data. ICLARM Fishbyte, 4(1), 12&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolff, M. (1989). A proposed method for standardization of the selection of class intervals for length frequency analysis. Fishbyte, 7(1), 5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wootton, R. J. (1992). Fish ecology (p. 203). Blackwell.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>