<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41738054</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-462X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in plant science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Plant Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Geographical variability in morphology and nutritional composition of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> seeds: a meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1720005</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1720005</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1720005</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fpls.2026.1720005</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The miracle tree, <i>M. oleifera</i>, is valued for its nutritional composition, climate adaptability, industrial and environmental usefulness. Despite well-known benefits, nutritional composition varies with the geographical location. The seeds of Moringa are rich in high-quality oil and protein and are also a source of carbohydrates, but their relative quantities vary among geographical locations. A meta-regression analysis was carried out using PRISMA guidelines, to explore the variability, and deciding factors in Moringa seeds. A systematic search of Scopus and google Scholar identified reports that mentioned morphological or nutritional or both traits was carried out. After removing duplicates and reviews, total 31 original research articles were included in the study. Two independent datasets, morphological and nutritional, were prepared by extracting numerical data of mature seeds. Statistical framework included Pearson's correlation to quantify trait relationship and ANCOVA to assess covariate effects on nutritional components. Datasets were analyzed using R software. Random effect meta regression model was employed to assess the heterogeneity in nutrient composition across climatic zones. The crude fat, total carbohydrates and crude protein were highly variable (&#x3c3; = 14.56, 14.54 and 12.08 respectively). The variabilities in ash and moisture were low (&#x3c3; =1.41 and 2.48 respectively) while crude fiber showed intermediate variability (&#x3c3; = 2.87). Although, there was a trend in nutritional composition of <i>M. oleifera</i> seeds along the latitude and climatic zones, statistical model fitting was non-significant for these variables. Pearson's correlation among nutritional components was pronounced and significant, supported by carbon-nitrogen metabolism. This study did not find any trend in the highly variable morphological components (CV 38.52% and 43.12% for length and width respectively) of Moringa seeds with geographical location.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Sharma, Tokas, Bhuker, Kamboj, Malik, McGill and Bhardwaj.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Preeti</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Chaudhary Charan Singh (CCS) Haryana Agricultural University, Hisar, Haryana,&#xa0;India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Indian Council of Agriculture Research (ICAR)- Central Soil Salinity Research Institute, Karnal, Haryana,&#xa0;India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tokas</LastName><ForeName>Jayanti</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Chaudhary Charan Singh (CCS) Haryana Agricultural University, Hisar, Haryana,&#xa0;India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhuker</LastName><ForeName>Axay</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Seed Science &amp; Technology, Chaudhary Charan Singh (CCS) Haryana Agricultural University, Hisar, Haryana,&#xa0;India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamboj</LastName><ForeName>Baldev Raj</ForeName><Initials>BR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agronomy, Chaudhary Charan Singh (CCS) Haryana Agricultural University, Hisar, Haryana,&#xa0;India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malik</LastName><ForeName>Anurag</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Research and Innovation, Uttaranchal University, Dehradun, Uttarakhand,&#xa0;India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McGill</LastName><ForeName>Craig Robert</ForeName><Initials>CR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Agriculture and the Environment, Massey University, Palmerston North,&#xa0;New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhardwaj</LastName><ForeName>Ajay Kumar</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Indian Council of Agriculture Research (ICAR)- Central Soil Salinity Research Institute, Karnal, Haryana,&#xa0;India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Plant Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101568200</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-462X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carbon-nitrogen metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">climatic zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">crude protein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">moringa seed</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">morphological variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutritional composition</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41738054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12926359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2026.1720005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>
Abdalla H. A., Ali M., Amar M. H., Chen L., Wang Q. F. (2022). 
Characterization of Phytochemical and Nutrient Compounds from the Leaves and Seeds of <i>M. oleifera oleifera</i> and <i>Moringa peregrina</i>. Horticulturae
8, 1081. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/horticulturae8111081
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/horticulturae8111081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Abdulkadir A. R., Zawawi D. D., Jahan M. S. (2016). 
Proximate and phytochemical screening of different parts of <i>Moringa oleifera</i>. Russian Agric. Sci.
42, 34&#x2013;36. doi:&#xa0; 10.3103/S106836741601002X
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3103/S106836741601002X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abiodun O. A., Adegbite J. A., Omolola A. O. (2012). Chemical and physicochemical properties of Moringa flours and oil. Global J. Sci. Frontier Res. Biol. Sci. 12, 1&#x2013;7. doi:&#xa0; 10.53555/nnas.v2i7.677</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.53555/nnas.v2i7.677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen D. K., Young J. D. (2013). Carbon and nitrogen provisions alter the metabolic flux in developing soybean embryos. Plant Physiol. 161, 1458&#x2013;1475. doi:&#xa0; 10.1104/pp.112.203299, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.112.203299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3585609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23314943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Annongu A., Karim O. R., Toye A. A., Sola-Ojo F. E., Kayode R. M. O., Badmos A. H. A., et al. (2014). 
Geo-Assessment of chemical composition and nutritional Evaluation of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> seeds in nutrition of Broilers. J. Agric. Sci.
6, 119. doi:&#xa0; 10.5539/jas.v6n4p119
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5539/jas.v6n4p119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Anwar F., Rashid U. (2007). 
Physico-chemical characteristics of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> seeds and seed oil from a wild provenance of Pakistan. Pak. J. Bot.
39 (5), 1443&#x2013;1453.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azam S. M., Farhatullah F., Adnan Nasim A. N., Sikandar Shah S. S., Sidra Iqbal S. I. (2013). Correlation studies for some agronomic and quality traits in Brassica napus L. Sarhad Journal of Agriculture 29 (4).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babatunde O., Ogunwale O. P., Ajayi O. O., Ajayi I. A. (2022). Correlation between oil, protein and carbohydrate content of plant seeds, skin and fruit pulp. J. Chem. Soc. Nigeria 47. doi:&#xa0; 10.46602/jcsn.v47i1.713</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46602/jcsn.v47i1.713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Banerji R., Bajpai A. (2009). 
Oil and fatty acid diversity in genetically variable clones of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> from India. J. Oleo Sci.
58, 9&#x2013;16. doi:&#xa0; 10.5650/jos.58.9, PMID: 

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5650/jos.58.9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19075502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck H. E., McVicar T. R., Vergopolan N., Berg A., Lutsko N. J., Dufour A., et al. (2023). High-resolution (1 km) K&#xf6;ppen-Geiger maps for 1901&#x2013;2099 based on constrained CMIP6 projections. Sci. Data 10, 724. doi:&#xa0; 10.1038/s41597-023-025496, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41597-023-025496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10593765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37872197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellaloui N., Hu Y., Mengistu A., Abbas H. K., Kassem M. A., Tigabu M. (2016). Elevated atmospheric carbon dioxide and temperature affect seed composition, mineral nutrition, and 15N and 13C dynamics in soybean genotypes under controlled environments. Atlas J. Plant Biol., 56&#x2013;65. doi:&#xa0; 10.5147/AJPB.V0I0.114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5147/AJPB.V0I0.114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cambon J., Hernang&#xf3;mez D., Belanger C., Possenriede D. (2021). tidygeocoder: An R package for geocoding. J. Open Source Software 6, 3544. doi:&#xa0; 10.21105/joss.03544</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21105/joss.03544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Champigny M. L. (1995). Integration of photosynthetic carbon and nitrogen metabolism in higher plants. Photosynthesis Res. 46, 117&#x2013;127. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/BF00020422, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00020422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24301574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Chatepa L. E. C., Mbewe E. C. (2018). 
Proximate, physical and chemical composition of leaves and seeds of Moringa (<i>Moringa oleifera</i>) from Central Malawi: A potential for increasing animal food supply in the 21st century. Afr. J. Agric. Res.
13, 2872&#x2013;2880. doi:&#xa0; 10.5897/AJAR2018.13535
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/AJAR2018.13535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Chelliah R., Ramakrishnan S., Antony U. (2017). 
Nutritional quality of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> for its bioactivity and antibacterial properties. Int. Food Res. J.
24, 825.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Coello K. E., Frias J., Mart&#xed;nez-Villaluenga C., Cartea M. E., Abilleira R., Pe&#xf1;as E. (2020). 
Potential of germination in selected conditions to improve the nutritional and bioactive properties of moringa (<i>Moringa oleifera</i> L.). Foods
9, 1639. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/foods9111639, PMID: 

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/foods9111639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7696275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33182814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das R., Biswas S. (2022). &#x201c; Influence of abiotic stresses on seed production and quality,&#x201d; in Seed biology updates. Ed. C. Jimenez-Lopez J. (London, UNITED KINGDOM: IntechOpen; ). doi:&#xa0; 10.5772/intechopen.106045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5772/intechopen.106045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Dhakad A. K., Singh M., Singh S., Kapoor R., Walia G. S., Dhillon G. P. (2023). 
Phenological and floral variations in ecotypes of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> for reproductive adaptations in subtropical conditions. Indian J. Ecol.
50, 1701&#x2013;1711. doi:&#xa0; 10.55362/IJE/2023/4121
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55362/IJE/2023/4121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ebeid H. M., Kholif A. E., Chrenkova M., Anele U. Y. (2020). 
Ruminal fermentation kinetics of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> leaf and seed as protein feeds in dairy cow diets: in sacco degradability and protein and fiber fractions assessed by the CNCPS method. Agroforestry Syst.
94, 905&#x2013;915. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s10457-019-00456-7
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10457-019-00456-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Fagwalawa L., Yahaya S., Umar D. (2014). 
A comparative proximate analysis of bark, leaves and seeds of <i>Moringa oleifera</i>. Int. J. Basic Appl. Chem. Sci.
5, 56&#x2013;62.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filho M. M., Destro D., Miranda L. A., Spinosa W. A., Carr&#xe3;o-Panizzi M. C., Montalv&#xe1;n R. (2001). Relationships among oil content, protein content and seed size in soybeans. Braz. Arch. Biol. Technol. 44, 23&#x2013;32. doi:&#xa0; 10.1590/S1516-89132001000100004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1516-89132001000100004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Gandji K., Tovissod&#xe9; F. C., Azihou A. F., Akpona J. D. T., Assogbadjo A. E., Kaka&#xef; R. L. G. (2020). 
Morphological diversity of the agroforestry species <i>Moringa oleifera</i> Lam. as related to ecological conditions and farmers&#x2019; management practices in Benin (West Africa). South Afr. J. Bot.
129, 412&#x2013;422. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.sajb.2019.10.004
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sajb.2019.10.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Gopalakrishnan L., Doriya K., Kumar D. S. (2016). 
<i>Moringa oleifera</i>: A review on nutritive importance and its medicinal application. Food Sci. Hum. wellness
5, 49&#x2013;56. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.fshw.2016.04.001
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fshw.2016.04.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Gupta N., Chinnappa M., Singh P. M., Kumar R., Sagar V. (2022). 
Determination of the physio-biochemical changes occurring during seed development, maturation, and desiccation tolerance in <i>Moringa oleifera</i> Lam. South Afr. J. Bot.
144, 430&#x2013;436. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.sajb.2021.09.010
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sajb.2021.09.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Guzm&#xe1;n-Maldonado S. H., L&#xf3;pez-Manzano M. J., Madera-Santana T. J., N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez-Col&#xed;n C. A., Grijalva-Verdugo C. P., Villa-Lerma A. G., et al. (2020). 
Caracterizaci&#xf3;n nutricional de hojas, semillas, c&#xe1;scara y flores de <i>Moringa oleifera</i> de dos regiones de M&#xe9;xico. Agronom&#xed;a Colombiana. 38, 287-297. doi:&#xa0; 10.15446/agron.colomb.v38n2.82644
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15446/agron.colomb.v38n2.82644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamada F. A., Sabah S. S., Mahdy E., El-Raouf H. S. A., El-Taher A. M., El-Leel O. F., et al. (2024). Genetic, phytochemical and morphological identification and genetic diversity of selected Moringa species. Sci. Rep. 14, 1&#x2013;18. doi:&#xa0; 10.1038/s41598-024-79148-x, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-79148-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11649686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39681573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Romero &#xc1;.H., Perroni Y., S&#xe1;nchez Vel&#xe1;squez L. R., Mart&#xed;nez-Hern&#xe1;ndez S., &#xc1;vila-Bello C. H., Xu X., et al. (2024). Soil C: N: P stoichiometric signatures of grasslands differ between tropical and warm temperate climatic zones. Biogeochemistry 167, 909&#x2013;926. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s10533-024-01143-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10533-024-01143-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain Z., Johnson E. N., Wang L., Blackshaw R. E., Gan Y. (2019). Comparative analysis of oil and protein content and seed yield of five Brassicaceae oilseeds on the Canadian prairie. Ind. Crops Products 136, 77&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huntley B. J. (2023). &#x201c; Solar energy, temperature and rainfall,&#x201d; in Ecology of Angola: terrestrial biomes and ecoregions ( Springer International Publishing, Cham: ), 95&#x2013;125. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/978-3-031-18923-4_5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-031-18923-4_5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hymowitz T., Collins F. I., Panczner J., Walker W. M. (1972). Relationship between the content of oil, protein, and sugar in soybean seed 1. Agron. J. 64, 613&#x2013;616. doi:&#xa0; 10.2134/agronj1972.00021962006400050019x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2134/agronj1972.00021962006400050019x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Illingworth K. A., Lee Y. Y., Siow L. F. (2022). 
The effect of isolation techniques on the physicochemical properties of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> protein isolates. Food Chem. Adv.
1, 100029. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.focha.2022.100029
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.focha.2022.100029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilyas M., Arshad M. U., Saeed F., Iqbal M. (2015). Antioxidant potential and nutritional comparison of moringa leaf and seed powders and their tea infusions. J. Anim. Plant Sci. 25, 226&#x2013;233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Iqbal S., Bhanger M. I. (2006). 
Effect of season and production location on antioxidant activity of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> leaves grown in Pakistan. J. Food Composition Anal.
19, 544&#x2013;551. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.jfca.2005.05.001
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfca.2005.05.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur M., Tak Y., Bhatia S., Asthir B., Lorenzo J. M., Amarowicz R. (2021). Crosstalk during the carbon&#x2013;nitrogen cycle that interlinks the biosynthesis, mobilization and accumulation of seed storage reserves. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 22, 12032. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/ijms222112032, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms222112032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8585027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34769462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimbonguila A., Nzikou J. M., Matos L., Loumouamou B., Ndangui C. B., Pambou-Tobi N. P. G., et al. (2010). Proximate composition of selected Congo oil seeds and physicochemical properties of the oil extracts. Res. J. Appl. Sciences Eng. Technol. 2, 60&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kubis S. E., Pike M. J., Everett C. J., Hill L. M., Rawsthorne S. (2004). 
The import of phosphoenolpyruvate by plastids from developing embryos of oilseed rape, <i>Brassica napus</i> (L.), and its potential as a substrate for fatty acid synthesis. J. Exp. Bot.
55, 1455&#x2013;1462. doi:&#xa0; 10.1093/jxb/erh157, PMID: 

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jxb/erh157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15208349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Labbassi S., Tahiri A., Mimouni A., Chabbi N., Telmoudi M., Afi C., et al. (2024). 
Argo-morphological and genetic diversity of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> grown in Morocco under a semi-arid climate. Genet. Resour. Crop Evol., 1&#x2013;17. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s10722-024-02047-7
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10722-024-02047-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemenkova P. (2020). Using R Packages' tmap', 'raster' and' ggmap' for Dartographic Visualization: An Example of Dem-Based Terrain Modelling of Italy, Apennine Peninsula. Zbornik radova-Geografski fakultet Univerziteta u Beogradu 68, 99&#x2013;116. doi:&#xa0; 10.5937/zrgfub2068099L</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5937/zrgfub2068099L</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Liang L., Wang C., Li S., Chu X., Sun K. (2019). 
Nutritional compositions of Indian <i>Moringa oleifera</i> seed and antioxidant activity of its polypeptides. Food Sci. Nutr.
7, 1754&#x2013;1760. doi:&#xa0; 10.1002/fsn3.1015, PMID: 

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/fsn3.1015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6526633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31139388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestri D. M., Guzm&#xe1;n G. A., Giorda L. M. (1998). Correlation between seed size, protein and oil contents, and fatty acid composition in soybean genotypes. Grasas y Aceites 49, 450&#x2013;453. doi:&#xa0; 10.3989/gya.1998.v49.i5-6.757</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3989/gya.1998.v49.i5-6.757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Melo A. S., Benitez L. C., Barbosa V. S. (2020). 
Environmental seasonality influences on reproductive attributes of <i>Moringa oleifera</i>. Pesquisa Florestal Bras.
40. doi:&#xa0; 10.4336/2020.pfb.40e201801745
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4336/2020.pfb.40e201801745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Mgbemena N. M., Obodo G. A. (2016). 
Comparative Analysis of Proximate and mineral composition of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> root, leave and seed obtained in Okigwe Imo State, Nigeria. J. Mol. Stud. Med. Res.
1, 57&#x2013;62. doi:&#xa0; 10.18801/jmsmr.010216.07
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18801/jmsmr.010216.07</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulugeta G., Fekadu A. (2014). Industrial and agricultural potentials of Moringa. Carbon 45, 1&#x2013;08.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Musa J., Njidda A. A. (2021). 
Chemical composition, anti-nutritive substances, amino acid profile and mineral composition of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> seeds subjected to different boiling duration. Nigerian J. Anim. Sci. Technol. (NJAST)
4, 43&#x2013;52.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Noronha B. G., Pereira M. D., Flores A. V., Demartelaere A. C. F., De Medeiros A. D. (2018). 
Morphometry and physiological quality of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> seeds in the function of their fruit position. J. Exp. Agric. Int.
25, 1&#x2013;10. doi:&#xa0; 10.9734/jeai/2018/43375
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/jeai/2018/43375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ogunsina B. S., Olumakaiye M. F., Chinma C. E., Akomolafe O. P. (2015). 
Effect of hydrothermal processing on the proximate composition and organoleptic characteristics of dehulled <i>Moringa oleifera</i> seeds. Nutr. Food Sci.
45, 944&#x2013;953. doi:&#xa0; 10.1108/NFS-04-2015-0036
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/NFS-04-2015-0036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Olagbemide P. T., Philip C. N. A. (2014). 
Proximate analysis and chemical composition of raw and defatted <i>Moringa oleifera</i> kernel. Adv. Life Sci. Technol.
24, 92&#x2013;99.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palenchar P. M., Kouranov A., Lejay L. V., Coruzzi G. M. (2004). Genome-wide patterns of carbon and nitrogen regulation of gene expression validate the combined carbon and nitrogen (CN)-signaling hypothesis in plants. Genome Biol. 5, R91. doi:&#xa0; 10.1186/gb-2004-5-11-r91, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/gb-2004-5-11-r91</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC545782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15535867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Pandey V. N., Chauhan V., Pandey V. S., Upadhyaya P. P., Kopp O. R. (2019). 
<i>Moringa oleifera</i> Lam.: a biofunctional edible plant from India, phytochemistry and medicinal properties. J. Plant Stud.
8, 10. doi:&#xa0; 10.5539/jps.v8n1p10
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5539/jps.v8n1p10</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qaderi M. M., Martel A. B., Strugnell C. A. (2023). Environmental factors regulate plant secondary metabolites. Plants 12, 447. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/plants12030447, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants12030447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9920071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36771531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai S. K., Pal A. K., Pandey J., Dayal A. (2023). Moringa: A bioactive elixir for nutrition, ecology and prosperity. Indian Farming 73, 21&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Rafael R. H., Martha H. R., Cruz Monterrosa Rosy G., Mayra D. R., Judith J. G., Le&#xf3;n-Espinosa Erika B., et al. (2021). 
Morphological characterization of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> seeds from different crops of Mexico. Agro Productividad. doi:&#xa0; 10.32854/agrop.v14i11.2175
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32854/agrop.v14i11.2175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajendran C., Kirtana S., Rashmi V., Yadav P., Anilakumar K. R. (2020). Nutritional and anti-oxidant potential of commonly growing planfoods from southern India. Defence Life Sci. J. 5. doi:&#xa0; 10.14429/dlsj.5.13959</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14429/dlsj.5.13959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ramos L. M., Costa R. S., M&#xf4;ro F. V., Silva R. C. (2010). 
Morfologia de frutos e sementes e morfofun&#xe7;&#xe3;o de pl&#xe2;ntulas de Moringa (<i>Moringa oleifera</i> Lam.). Comunicata Scientiae
1, 156&#x2013;156. doi:&#xa0; 10.9734/JEAI/2018/43375
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/JEAI/2018/43375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rani B., Devi T., Kumari N., Rani P., Duhan J., Lavisha (2025). A comprehensive overview of nutritional and bioactive compounds of Moringa oleifera seeds. Int. J. Advanced Biochem. Res. 9, 315&#x2013;323. doi:&#xa0; 10.33545/26174693.2025.v9.i8e.5172</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33545/26174693.2025.v9.i8e.5172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Rivas R., Oliveira M. T., Santos M. G. (2013). 
Three cycles of water deficit from seed to young plants of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> woody species improves stress tolerance. Plant Physiol. Biochem.
63, 200&#x2013;208. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.plaphy.2012.11.026, PMID: 

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.plaphy.2012.11.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23274248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ruiz-Hern&#xe1;ndez R., Hern&#xe1;ndez-Rodr&#xed;guez M., Cruz-Monterrosa R. G., D&#xed;az-Ram&#xed;rez M., Jim&#xe9;nez-Guzm&#xe1;n J., Le&#xf3;n-Espinosa E. B., et al. (2021). 
Morphological characterization of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> seeds from different crops of Mexico. Agro Productividad. doi:&#xa0; 10.32854/agrop.v14i11.2175
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32854/agrop.v14i11.2175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Saa R. W., Fombang Nig E., Radha C., Ndjantou E. B., Njintang Yanou N. (2022). 
Effect of soaking, germination, and roasting on the proximate composition, antinutrient content, and some physicochemical properties of defatted <i>Moringa oleifera</i> seed flour. J. Food Process. Preservation
46, e16329. doi:&#xa0; 10.1111/jfpp.16329
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jfpp.16329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Saheed I. A., Aliyu N., Muhammed M., Oluwasegun A. N. (2019). 
Evaluation of proximate content and vitamin profile of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> seed hull. Int. J. Livestock Production
10, 188&#x2013;191. doi:&#xa0; 10.5897/IJLP2018.0512
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/IJLP2018.0512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Sodamade A., Owonikoko A. D., Owoyemi D. S. (2017). 
Nutrient contents and mineral composition of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> Seed. Int. J. Communication Syst.
5, 205&#x2013;207.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stadtlander T., Becker K. (2017). Proximate composition, amino and fatty acid profiles and element compositions of four different Moringa species. J. Agric. Sci. 9, 46&#x2013;57. doi:&#xa0; 10.5539/jas.v9n7p46</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5539/jas.v9n7p46</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang M., Zhang Y., Liu Y., Tong C., Cheng X., Zhu W., et al. (2019). Mapping loci controlling fatty acid profiles, oil and protein content by genome-wide association study in Brassica napus. Crop J. 7, 217&#x2013;226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Umerah N. N., Asouzu A. I., Okoye J. I. (2019). 
Effect of processing on the nutritional composition of <i>Moringa olifera</i> Leaves and Seeds. Eur. J. Nutr. Food Saf.
11, 124&#x2013;135. doi:&#xa0; 10.9734/ejnfs/2019/v11i330155
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/ejnfs/2019/v11i330155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Buuren S., Groothuis-Oudshoorn K. (2011). mice: multivariate imputation by chained equations in R. J. Stat. Software 45, 1&#x2013;67. doi:&#xa0; 10.18637/jss.v045.i03</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v045.i03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weigelt K., K&#xfc;ster H., Radchuk R., M&#xfc;ller M., Weichert H., Fait A., et al. (2008). Increasing amino acid supply in pea embryos reveals specific interactions of N and C metabolism, and highlights the importance of mitochondrial metabolism. Plant J. 55, 909&#x2013;926., PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18494854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Wiltshire F. M. S., de Fran&#xe7;a Santos A., Silva L. K. B., de Almeida L. C., dos Santos Freitas L., Lima A. S., et al. (2022). 
Influence of seasonality on the physicochemical properties of <i>Moringa oleifera</i> Lam. Seed oil and their oleochemical potential. Food Chemistry: Mol. Sci.
4, 100068. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.fochms.2021.100068, PMID: 

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fochms.2021.100068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8991620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35415675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue W. T., Gianinetti A., Wang R., Zhan Z. J., Yan J., Jiang Y., et al. (2016). Characterizing barley seed macro-and micro-nutrients under multiple environmental conditions. Cereal Res. Commun. 44, 639&#x2013;649. doi:&#xa0; 10.1556/0806.44.2016.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1556/0806.44.2016.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Zhigila D. A., Mohammed S., Oladele F. A., Sawa F. B. (2015). 
Numerical analyses of leaf and fruit external morphology in <i>Moringa oleifera</i> Lam. Jurnal Teknologi
77. doi:&#xa0; 10.11113/jt.v77.6368
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11113/jt.v77.6368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>