<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41489784</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2731-9229</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Discover nano</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Discov Nano</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Green synthesis of silver nanoparticles from Elaeagnus angustifolia extract: characterization and evaluation of antibacterial and cytotoxic properties.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s11671-025-04423-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Current medical problems are complex and require a new approach. Nanomaterials can address these complications. Silver nanoparticles (AgNPs), in particular green-synthetized particles, because of their unique properties have attract the attention of scientist. The objective of this work deals with using Elaeagnus angustifolia (EA) leaf extract as a reducing agent for biofabrication of AgNPs and investigation of its antibacterial and anti-cancer properties.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">UV-Visible spectroscopy (UV-Vis), X-ray diffraction (XRD), Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR), field emission scanning electron microscopy (FESEM), transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM), Scanning-Transmission Electron Microscope (STEM) and atomic force microscopy (AFM) techniques were used for characterization of the biosynthesized AgNPs. Antimicrobial efficacy was measured through disk diffusion and minimum inhibitory concentration (MIC) methods, while cytotoxic effects on PC-3 cancer cells were evaluated using the MTT assay.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The biosynthesized AgNPs exhibited a strong surface plasmon resonance peak at approximately 441&#xa0;nm, confirming successful synthesis. XRD analysis indicated a face-centered cubic structure, with crystallite sizes 27.04&#xa0;nm. Antibacterial tests revealed significant activity against E. coli and K. pneumoniae, with AgNPs demonstrating comparable efficacy to standard antibiotics. In particular, AgNPs demonstrated successful activity on E. coli with an MIC value of 113.24&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;14.36 and an inhibition zone of 24.32&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.25&#xa0;mm, comparable to standard antibiotics Furthermore, the AgNPs displayed notable cytotoxic effects on PC-3 cells, with an IC<sub>50</sub> value of 58.77&#xa0;&#xb5;g/mL.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results explore the potential of leaf extract of Elaeagnus angustifolia as an effective agent for the green synthesis of AgNPs that have significant antibacterial properties. This study supports the application of green synthesis in medical therapies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baran</LastName><ForeName>Ayse</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Field Crops, K&#x131;z&#x131;ltepe Faculty of Agricultural Sciences and Technologies, , Mardin Artuklu University, Mardin, 47200, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghorbanzadeh</LastName><ForeName>Vajihe</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurophysiology Research Center, Cellular and Molecular Medicine Research Institute, Urmia University of Medical Sciences, Urmia, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Do&#x11f;an</LastName><ForeName>Yusuf</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Field Crops, K&#x131;z&#x131;ltepe Faculty of Agricultural Sciences and Technologies, , Mardin Artuklu University, Mardin, 47200, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmadian</LastName><ForeName>Elham</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nephrology and Kidney Transplantation Research Center, Clinical Research Institute, Urmia University of Medical Sciences, Urmia, Iran. ahmadian.elham@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kidney Research Center, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran. ahmadian.elham@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zulfugarova</LastName><ForeName>Parvin</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Normal Physiology, Azerbaijan Medical University, Baku, AZ1022, Azerbaijan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohamed</LastName><ForeName>Ali Jimale</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, Faculty of Medicine, Somali National University, Mogadishu, 801, Somalia. alijimamohamed@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Discov Nano</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918540788706676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2731-9229</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cytotoxicity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Green nanoparticles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nanotechnology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: There is no need for any ethics or permission for the plant used in this study. This plant is a plant that is commonly found everywhere. Also, it is not an endemic species. There is no need for a permit for its use. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41489784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12770042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s11671-025-04423-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s11671-025-04423-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Singh N, Kumar B, Usman UL, Susan MABH. Nano revolution: exploring the frontiers of nanomaterials in science, technology, and society. Nano-Structures &amp; Nano-Objects. 2024;39:101299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akg&#xf6;l S, Ulucan-Karnak F, Kuru CI, Ku&#x15f;at K. The usage of composite nanomaterials in biomedical engineering applications. Biotechnol Bioeng. 2021;118(8):2906&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bit.27843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34050923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ovais M, Khalil AT, Islam NU, Ahmad I, Ayaz M, Saravanan M, et al. Role of plant phytochemicals and microbial enzymes in biosynthesis of metallic nanoparticles. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol. 2018;102:6799&#x2013;814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00253-018-9146-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29882162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alasgarova N, Synthesis of plant-derived selenium nanoparticles from lankaran-astara tea. (<i>Camellia sinensis</i> L.) Plant and evaluation of their activities on different enzymes. Adv Biology Earth Sci. 2025;10(2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shashiraj KN, Nayaka S, Kumar RS, Kantli GB, Basavarajappa DS, Gunagambhire PV, et al. Rotheca Serrata flower bud extract mediated bio-friendly preparation of silver nanoparticles: their characterizations, anticancer, and apoptosis inducing ability against pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma cell line. Processes. 2023;11(3):893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr11030893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Wang Y-Y, Huang J, Chen C-Y, Wang Z-X, Xie H. Silver nanoparticles: synthesis, medical applications and biosafety. Theranostics. 2020;10(20):8996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/thno.45413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7415816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32802176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelghany TM, Al-Rajhi AM, Almuhayawi MS, Abada E, Al Abboud MA, Moawad H, et al. Green fabrication of nanocomposite doped with selenium nanoparticle&#x2013;based starch and glycogen with its therapeutic activity: antimicrobial, antioxidant, and anti-inflammatory in vitro. Biomass Convers Biorefinery. 2023;13(1):431&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13399-022-03257-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Rajhi AMH, Yahya R, Bakri MM, Yahya R, Abdelghany TM. In situ green synthesis of Cu-doped ZnO based polymers nanocomposite with studying antimicrobial, antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activities. Appl Biol Chem. 2022;65(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13765-022-00702-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suppiah DD, Julkapli NM, Sagadevan S, Johan MR. Eco-friendly green synthesis approach and evaluation of environmental and biological applications of iron oxide nanoparticles. Inorg Chem Commun. 2023;152:110700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inoche.2023.110700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganbarov K, Aliyeva N, Naghiyev F, Mamedov I. (2025). Antimicrobial activity of hydropyridine derivatives against gram-positive and gram-negative pathogenic bacteria. Adv Biology Earth Sci, 10(2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaman U, Evaluation of cytotoxic and antimicrobial activities of methanolic extracts from <i>Cystoseira foeniculacea</i> and <i>Sargassum vulgare</i>. Adv Biology Earth Sci. 2025;10(2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahim M, Shahzaib A, Nishat N, Jahan A, Bhat TA, Inam A. Green synthesis of silver nanoparticles: a comprehensive review of methods, influencing factors, and applications. JCIS Open. 2024:100125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alharbi NS, Alsubhi NS, Felimban AI. Green synthesis of silver nanoparticles using medicinal plants: characterization and application. J Radiation Res Appl Sci. 2022;15(3):109&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tehranizadeh ZA, Baratian A, Hosseinzadeh H. Russian Olive (Elaeagnus angustifolia) as a herbal healer. BioImpacts: BI. 2016;6(3):155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15171/bi.2016.22</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5108988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27853679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamidpour R, Hamidpour S, Hamidpour M, Shahlari M, Sohraby M, Shahlari N, et al. Russian Olive (E. angustifolia.): from a variety of traditional medicinal applications to its novel roles as active antioxidant, anti-inflammatory, anti-mutagenic and analgesic agent. J Traditional Complement Med. 2017;7(1):24&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtcme.2015.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farzaei MH, Bahramsoltani R, Abbasabadi Z, Rahimi R. A comprehensive review on phytochemical and pharmacological aspects of E. angustifolia. J Pharm Pharmacol. 2015;67(11):1467&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jphp.12442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26076872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duman H, Eker F, Akda&#x15f;&#xe7;i E, Witkowska AM, Bechelany M, Karav S. Silver nanoparticles: a comprehensive review of synthesis methods and chemical and physical properties. Nanomaterials. 2024;14(18):1527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nano14181527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11434896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39330683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halimi M, Nasrabadi M, Soleamani N, Rouhani N. Green synthesis of nanosilver particles from extract of dracocephalum Lindbergii. Asian J Nanosci Mater. 2018;1(1):19&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zakaria ZZ, Ahen Y, Ahmed NH, Sokary S, Bawadi H, Al-Asmakh M. Exploring <i>Elaeagnus Angustifolia</i>: a comprehensive review of its potential in cancer treatment and management. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Rajhi AMH, Abdelghany TM, Almuhayawi MS, et al. The green approach of chitosan/Fe2O3/ZnO-nanocomposite synthesis with an evaluation of its biological activities. Appl Biol Chem. 2024;67:75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13765-024-00926-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghonaim MI, Alsalamah SA, Bazaid AS, et al. Biosynthesis of CuO@Au NPs and its formulated into biopolymers carboxymethyl cellulose and chitosan: Characterizations, Antimicrobial, anticancer and antioxidant properties. Waste Biomass Valoriz. 2024;15:5191&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12649-024-02469-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mortazavi-Derazkola S, Yousefinia A, Naghizadeh A, Lashkari S, Hosseinzadeh M. Green synthesis and characterization of silver nanoparticles using <i>elaeagnus angustifolia</i> bark extract and study of its antibacterial effect. J Polym Environ. 2021:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdo&#x11f;an &#xd6;, Pa&#x15f;a S, Cevik O. Green synthesis and characterization of anticancer effected silver nanoparticles with silverberry (<i>Elaeagnus angustifolia</i>) fruit aqueous extract. Int J Pure Appl Sci. 2021;7(3):391&#x2013;400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dua TK, Giri S, Nandi G, Sahu R, Shaw TK, Paul P. Green synthesis of silver nanoparticles using eupatorium adenophorum leaf extract: characterizations, antioxidant, antibacterial and photocatalytic activities. Chem Pap. 2023;77(6):2947&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11696-023-02676-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vishwasrao C, Momin B, Ananthanarayan L. Green synthesis of silver nanoparticles using Sapota fruit waste and evaluation of their antimicrobial activity. Waste Biomass Valoriz. 2019;10:2353&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12649-018-0230-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huong VTL, Nguyen NT. Green synthesis, characterization and antibacterial activity of silver nanoparticles using<i> Sapindus mukorossi</i> fruit pericarp extract. Materials Today: Proceedings. 2021;42:88&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad S, Munir S, Zeb N, Ullah A, Khan B, Ali J et al. Green nanotechnology: a review on green synthesis of silver nanoparticles&#x2014;An ecofriendly approach. Int J Nanomed. 2019:5087&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debnath B, Das R. Controlled synthesis of saponin-capped silver nanotriangles and their optical properties. Plasmonics. 2019;14(6):1365&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11468-019-00923-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qing Ya, Cheng L, Li R, Liu G, Zhang Y, Tang X et al. Potential antibacterial mechanism of silver nanoparticles and the optimization of orthopedic implants by advanced modification technologies. Int J Nanomed. 2018:3311&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kummara S, Patil MB, Uriah T. Synthesis, characterization, biocompatible and anticancer activity of green and chemically synthesized silver nanoparticles&#x2013;a comparative study. Biomed Pharmacother. 2016;84:10&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2016.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27621034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Y, Du Z, Ma S et al. Biosynthesis, Antibacterial Activity and Anticancer Effects Against Prostate Cancer (PC-3) Cells of Silver Nanoparticles Using Dimocarpus Longan Lour. Peel Extract. Nanoscale Res Lett 2016;11:300. 10.1186/s11671-016-1511-9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>