<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41681262</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Lap Joint Configuration and Seam Strategy in Green-Laser Welding on Multi-Layer Cu Foil Stacks to Lead-Tab Joints for Pouch Cell Application.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">573</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma19030573</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study examines the joining characteristics of Cu foil stacks to lead tabs using green-laser welding in the main-welding step of a sequential welding process for lithium-ion pouch cells. The influence of lap configuration, line and wobble seam strategies, and process parameters was systematically investigated in terms of bead morphology, mechanical performance, metallurgical characteristics, and electrical resistance. Under the present line-welding parameter window (2.0 kW, 100-200 mm/s), humping, pinholes, and porosity were observed, particularly in the upper lead-tab configuration, which is attributed to melt-pool/keyhole instability under the applied conditions. Wobble welding effectively suppressed these defects in the foil-stack configuration by promoting stable melt flow and efficient bubble expulsion. Mechanical tests revealed that the wobble-based seam strategy achieved a maximum tensile-shear load of approximately 1.28 kN at a wobble amplitude of 0.8 mm. Fracture analysis confirmed a transition from seam-type interfacial failure in line welding to ductile tearing in the heat-affected zone with wobble welding. In electrical performance, wobble welding reduced resistance to as low as 45 &#xb5;&#x3a9; at a wobble amplitude of 1.2 mm, while line welding yielded higher and scattered values. These results should be interpreted as the combined outcome of the wobble-based seam strategy (beam oscillation together with overlapped stitch welding at a lower travel speed) under the present processing windows. A strictly matched A/B comparison at identical linear energy density and seam layout will be investigated in future work to isolate the effect of oscillation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hong</LastName><ForeName>Seong Min</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6754-1210</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Joining and Welding Research Institute, The University of Osaka, Osaka 567-0047, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Go</LastName><ForeName>Bum-Su</ForeName><Initials>BS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute, Korea Welding and Joining Engineering Association, Gwangju 61012, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bang</LastName><ForeName>Hee-Seon</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Welding and Joining Science Engineering, Chosun University, Gwangju 61452, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">beam oscillation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">copper foil stack</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electrical resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">green-laser welding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lead-tab joining</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lithium-ion pouch cells</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>We confirm that this work is original, has not been published previously, and is not under consideration elsewhere, in whole or in part. All authors have approved the manuscript and agree with its submission (no conflict of interest) and data availability. Overall, all the authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41681262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12897689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma19030573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma19030573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zwicker M.F.R., Moghadam M., Zhang W., Nielsen C.V. Automotive battery pack manufacturing&#x2014;A review of battery to tab joining. J. Adv. Join. Process. 2020;1:100017. doi: 10.1016/j.jajp.2020.100017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jajp.2020.100017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin S., Nam S., Yu J., Park J., Kim D. Ultrasonic metal welding of multilayered copper foils to nickel-plated copper sheet in lithium-ion battery cell. Metals. 2021;11:1195. doi: 10.3390/met11081195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met11081195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arimoto K., Sasaki T., Doi Y., Kim T. Ultrasonic bonding of multi-layered foil using a cylindrical surface tool. Metals. 2019;9:505. doi: 10.3390/met9050505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met9050505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao D., Ren D., Zhao K., Sun P., Guo X., Liu L. Ultrasonic welding of magnesium&#x2013;titanium dissimilar metals: A study on thermo-mechanical analyses of welding process by experimentation and finite element method. Chin. J. Mech. Eng. 2019;32:97. doi: 10.1186/s10033-019-0409-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s10033-019-0409-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joo S.M., Bang H.S., Han J.U., Kim K.H., Ahn B.H. Laser stitch welding technology for the fabrication of automotive parts. J. Weld. Join. 2013;31:1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.5781/KWJS.2013.31.4.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5781/KWJS.2013.31.4.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimatteo V., Ascari A., Fortunato A. Continuous laser welding with spatial beam oscillation of dissimilar thin sheet materials (Al&#x2013;Cu and Cu&#x2013;Al): Process optimization and characterization. J. Manuf. Process. 2019;44:158&#x2013;165. doi: 10.1016/j.jmapro.2019.06.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2019.06.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y., Jeong S.J., Yun S.M., Lee J.I. Study on Laser Welding of Dissimilar Materials between Aluminum and Copper (I)&#x2014;Research Trend in Laser Welding Technology and Materials Testing Methods. J. Weld. Join. 2022;40:416&#x2013;437. doi: 10.5781/JWJ.2022.40.5.7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5781/JWJ.2022.40.5.7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Q., Zhang P., Lu Q.H., Yan H.-W., Shi H. Application and development of blue and green laser in industrial manufacturing: A review. Opt. Laser Technol. 2023;158:108202. doi: 10.1016/j.optlastec.2023.110202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optlastec.2023.110202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M., Zhang Y., Mao C., Hu Y., Chen G., Bi Z. Experiments on formation mechanism of root humping in high-power laser autogenous welding of thick plates with stainless steels. Opt. Laser Technol. 2019;111:11&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1016/j.optlastec.2018.09.029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optlastec.2018.09.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., Mi G., Wang C. A study on laser beam oscillating welding characteristics for the 5083 aluminum alloy: Morphology, microstructure and mechanical properties. J. Manuf. Process. 2020;53:12&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1016/j.jmapro.2020.01.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2020.01.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar N., Pamarthi V.V., Das A. Investigating laser and ultrasonic welding of pouch cell multi-foil current collectors for electric vehicle battery fabrication. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2024;134:2497&#x2013;2511. doi: 10.1007/s00170-024-14281-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-024-14281-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon H.S., Bang H.S. The effect of wobbling on the welding characteristics in Al/Cu fiber laser welded joints. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2023;127:5343&#x2013;5352. doi: 10.1007/s00170-023-11653-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-023-11653-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo H.J., Kim M.J., Kang H.S. A study on the green laser weldability of copper-aluminum battery materials. Korean J. Met. Mater. 2024;62:757&#x2013;766. doi: 10.3365/KJMM.2024.62.10.757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3365/KJMM.2024.62.10.757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grabmann S., Kriegler J., Harst F., G&#xfc;nter F.J., Zaeh M.F. Laser welding of current collector foil stacks in battery production&#x2013;mechanical properties of joints welded with a green high-power disk laser. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2022;118:2571&#x2013;2586. doi: 10.1007/s00170-021-07839-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-021-07839-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann F., Roth S., Schmidt M. Tailored laser beam shapes for welding of copper using green laser radiation. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2024;131:3827&#x2013;3838. doi: 10.1007/s00170-024-13180-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-024-13180-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia X., Lupo G., Leparoux M., Turlo V., Hoffmann P. Energy-efficient microwelding of copper by continuous-wave green laser: Insights into nanoparticle-assisted absorptivity enhancement. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2024;675:160940. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamat S., Ramesh K., Rao S. Green laser welding of copper foils to tabs for LIB applications: Experiments and simulations. J. Manuf. Process. 2022;75:91&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H., White D.R., DebRoy T. Current issues and problems in laser welding of automotive aluminium alloys. Int. Mater. Rev. 1999;44:238&#x2013;266. doi: 10.1179/095066099101528298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1179/095066099101528298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackburn J. Welding and Joining of Aerospace Materials. Woodhead Publishing; Sawston, UK: 2012. Laser welding of metals for aerospace and other applications; pp. 75&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>