<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41189240</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>104</Volume><Issue>42</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence and determinants of erectile dysfunction among diabetic patients attending to selected governmental hospitals, Gurage Zone, Central Ethiopia Region, Ethiopia: A prospective cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e45120</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e45120</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e45120</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000045120</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diabetic men have been reported to have a 3-fold increased risk of developing erectile dysfunction (ED). However, no studies have been conducted in our study area to assess the prevalence and determinants of ED among diabetic patients. Therefore, this study was aimed to determine the prevalence and determinants of ED among diabetic patients attending selected governmental hospitals in Gurage Zone, Central Ethiopia Region. A hospital-based cross-sectional study was conducted involving 320 diabetic patients who attended follow-up visits between September 1 to December 30, 2020. Data on socio-demographic, clinical, and lifestyle characteristics were collected using a structured questionnaire. Anthropometric measurements and blood pressure were obtained in accordance with standard guidelines. Erectile function was assessed using the International Index of Erectile Function-5. Fasting blood glucose and lipid profiles were analyzed using the A25 BioSystems clinical chemistry analyzer. Data entry and analysis were performed using the Statistical Package for the Social Sciences (SPSS) version 20. Multivariable logistic regression analysis was used to identify independent predictors of ED. Of the 320 diabetic patients included in the study, 233 (72.8%; 95% confidence interval [CI]: 67.5-77.8) were found to have ED. Multivariable logistic regression analysis identified several factors significantly associated with ED: being in the age group of 40 to 49 years (adjusted odds ratios [AOR]&#x2005;=&#x2005;5.91; 95% CI: 2.09-16.76), alcohol consumption (AOR&#x2005;=&#x2005;3.79; 95% CI: 1.88-7.60), khat chewing (AOR&#x2005;=&#x2005;2.44; 95% CI: 1.28-4.64), use of antihypertensive medication (AOR&#x2005;=&#x2005;5.72; 95% CI: 1.57-20.86), low high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (AOR&#x2005;=&#x2005;2.37; 95% CI: 1.23-4.57), elevated total cholesterol (AOR&#x2005;=&#x2005;2.97; 95% CI: 1.33-6.65), and poor glycemic control (AOR&#x2005;=&#x2005;2.68; 95% CI: 1.41-5.10). This study revealed a high prevalence of ED among male diabetic patients. The identified determinant factors should be carefully considered in the prevention, early detection, and management of ED in this population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abrar</LastName><ForeName>Seid</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory Sciences, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Wolkite University, Gubrei, Central Ethiopia Region, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Woyesa</LastName><ForeName>Shiferaw Bekele</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical Laboratory Science, Faculty of Health Sciences, Institute of Health, Jimma University, Jimma, Oromia Region, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nida</LastName><ForeName>Abdulsemed Worku</ForeName><Initials>AW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, School of Medicine, College of Health Sciences, Wolkite University, Wolkite, Central Ethiopia Region, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asres</LastName><ForeName>Yaregal</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory Science, College of Medicine and Health Science, Bahir Dar University, Bahir Dar, Amhara Region, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mamo</LastName><ForeName>Aklilu Getachew</ForeName><Initials>AG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8939-8534</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical Laboratory Science, Faculty of Health Sciences, Institute of Health, Jimma University, Jimma, Oromia Region, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001786">Blood Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007172" MajorTopicYN="Y">Erectile Dysfunction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006779" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitals, Public</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003920" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001786" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Glucose</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gurage Zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetes mellitus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">erectile dysfunction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41189240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12537073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000045120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202510170-00117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zeru MA, Tesfa E, Mitiku AA, Seyoum A, Bokoro TA. Prevalence and risk factors of type-2 diabetes mellitus in Ethiopia: systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2021;11:1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8571297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34741064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain MJ, Al-Mamun M, Islam MR. Diabetes mellitus, the fastest growing global public health concern: early detection should be focused. Heal Sci Rep. 2024;7:5&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10958528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38524769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seid A, Gerensea H, Tarko S, Zenebe Y, Mezemir R. Prevalence and determinants of erectile dysfunction among diabetic patients attending in hospitals of central and northwestern zone of Tigray, northern Ethiopia: a cross-sectional study. BMC Endocr Disord. 2017;17:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5353861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28298205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eid JF, Nehra A, Andersson KE, et al. First international conference on the management of erectile dysfunction; overview consensus statment. 2000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11035379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nisahan B, Kumanan T, Rajeshkannan N, Peranantharajah T, Aravinthan M. Erectile dysfunction and associated factors among men with diabetes mellitus from a tertiary diabetic center in Northern Sri Lanka. BMC Res Notes. 2019;12:4&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6451292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30953562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah P, Trivedi N. A meta-analysis on efficacy and tolerability of sildenafil for erectile dysfunction in patients with diabetes mellitus. Indian J Sex Transm Dis AIDS. 2018;39:61&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6111643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30187018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walle B, Lebeta KR, Fita YD, Abdissa HG. Prevalence of erectile dysfunction and associated factors among diabetic men attending the diabetic clinic at Felege Hiwot Referral Hospital, Bahir Dar, North West Ethiopia, 2016. BMC Res Notes. 2018;11:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5815197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29448969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Defeudis G, Mazzilli R, Tenuta M, et al. Erectile dysfunction and diabetes: a melting pot of circumstances and treatments. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2022;38:1&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9286480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34514697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penson FD, Wallace LK, Latini MD, Henning MJ, Lubeck PD, Lue FT. More severe erectile dysfunction and worse quality of life than the general population of impotent patients? Health Care (Don Mills). 2003;26:1093&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12663579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldwin K, Ginsberg P, Harkaway RC. Under-reporting of erectile dysfunction among men with unrelated urologic conditions. Int J Impot Res. 2003;15:87&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12789385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binmoammar TA, Hassounah S, Alsaad S, Rawaf S, Majeed A. The impact of poor glycaemic control on the prevalence of erectile dysfunction in men with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review. JRSM Open. 2016;7:205427041562260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4776250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26981254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazi AA, Blonde L. Classification of Diabetes Mellitus. Vol. 21, Clinics in Laboratory Medicine. 2001; 1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11321930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd-Jones DM, Morris PB, Ballantyne CM, et al. 2017 focused update of the 2016 ACC expert consensus decision pathway on the role of non-statin therapies for LDL-cholesterol lowering in the management of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease risk: a report of the american college of cardiology task fo. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2017;70:1785&#x2013;822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28886926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen RC, Riley A, Wagner G, Osterloh IH, Kirkpatrick J, Mishra A. The international index of erectile function (IIEF): a multidimensional scale for assessment of erectile dysfunction. Urology. 1997;49:822&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9187685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lexington Medical Center; Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine. SPECIMEN COLLECTION, HANDLING, and TRANSPORT. 2011:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azad AK, Setunge S, Selim S, et al. Dyslipidaemia as a risk factor for erectile dysfunction in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients. Diabetes Metabol Syndrome. 2019;13:748&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30641801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bin Nordin R, Soni T, Kaur A, Loh KP, Miranda S. Prevalence and predictors of erectile dysfunction in adult male outpatient clinic attendees in Johor, Malaysia. Singapore Med J. 2019;60:40&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6351699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29774359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutagaywa RK, Lutale J, Muhsin A, Kamala BA. Prevalence of erectile dysfunction and associated factors among diabetic men attending diabetic clinic at muhimbili national hospital in Dar-es-Salaam, Tanzania. Pan Afr Med J. 2014;17:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4145282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25170371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrini MG, Gonzalez-Cadavid NF, Rajfer J. Aging related erectile dysfunction-potential mechanism to halt or delay its onset. Transl Androl Urol. 2017;6:20&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5313305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28217447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tridiantari DK, Saraswati LD, Udiyono A. Epidemiology of erectile dysfunction in men with diabetes mellitus: a study in a primary health care center in Indonesia. Med J Indones. 2020;29:82&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ugwu T, Ezeani I, Onung S, Kolawole B, Ikem R. Predictors of erectile dysfunction in men with type 2 diabetes mellitus referred to a tertiary healthcare centre. Adv Endocrinol. 2016;2016:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JC, Bennett M. Aging and atherosclerosis: Mechanisms, functional consequences, and potential therapeutics for cellular senescence. Circ Res. 2012;111:245&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22773427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon RM, Howard L, Zapata D, Frank J, Freedland SJ, Vidal AC. The association of exercise with both erectile and sexual function in black and white men. J Sex Med. 2015;12:1202&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25801073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langer R, Sharma E, Langer B, Gupta RK, Kumari R, Majeed M. Erectile dysfunction: prevalence and determinants among T2DM men attending a tertiary care hospital in northern India. Int Surg J. 2019;6:1115&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimani ST, Nyongesa AW. Effects of single daily khat (<i>Catha edulis</i>) extract on spatial learning and memory in CBA mice.
Behav Brain Res. 2008;195:192&#x2013;7.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18588917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckerleg S. East African discourses on khat and sex. J Ethnopharmacol. 2010;132:600&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20832464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asefa A, Nigussie T, Henok A, Mamo Y. Prevalence of sexual dysfunction and related factors among diabetes mellitus patients in Southwest Ethiopia. BMC Endocr Disord. 2019;19:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6921479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31852461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassar OH, Aklan HM. Yemenlilerde erektil disfonksiyon: Khat &#xe7;i&#x1e7;neme bir rol oynuyor mu? Eurasian J Med. 2014;46:69&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4261453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25610301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang K, Yin S, Xiao Y, et al. Sexual dysfunction in patients with diabetes: association between remnant cholesterol and erectile dysfunction. Lipids Health Dis. 2024;23:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10882869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38388371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machingura PI. Erectile dysfunction among diabetic patients at parirenyatwa group of hospitals in Zimbabwe. Texila Int J Public Health. 2018;6:69&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangiorgi G, Cereda A, Benedetto D, et al. Anatomy, pathophysiology, molecular mechanisms, and clinical management of erectile dysfunction in patients affected by coronary artery disease: a review. Biomedicines. 2021;9:432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8074129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33923709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foresta C, Caretta N, Corona G, et al. Clinical and metabolic evaluation of subjects with erectile dysfunction: a review with a proposal flowchart. Int J Androl. 2009;32:198&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19076256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weldesenbet AB, Kebede SA, Tusa BS. Prevalence of erectile dysfunction and its associated factors among patients with diabetes in Ethiopia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Int Med Res. 2021;49:300060521993318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7890740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33583238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunfowokan O, Ezemenahi SI, Alabi AN, Adesuwa Q, Aigbokhaode BAO. Erectile dysfunction predictors in hypertensives at a primary care clinic in Southern Nigeria. Afr J Prim Health Care Fam Med. 2022;14:e1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9257715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35792631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett GI. Erectile dysfunction, diabetes and cardiovascular risk. Br J Diabetes Vasc Dis. 2016;16:52&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezeude CM, Ezeude AM, Young EE, Oguejiofor OC, Bakari AG. Correlates of erectile dysfunction in Nigerian men with type 2 diabetes mellitus: experience from a tertiary health center. J Diabetes Mellitus. 2020;10:182&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malavige LS, Jayaratne SD, Kathriarachchi ST, Sivayogan S, Fernando DJ, Levy JC. Erectile dysfunction among men with diabetes is strongly associated with premature ejaculation and reduced libido. J Sex Med. 2008;5:2125&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18624974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardahanli I, Celik M. Can myocardial performance index predict early cardiac risks in erectile dysfunction? Aging Male. 2021;23:1355&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32429725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardahanli I, Yilmaz AH, Akg&#xfc;n O, Gurbanov R. Evaluation of ventricular repolarization parameters in erectile dysfunction: a predictor of cardiac diseases. J Mens health. 2022;18:78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karakurt D, Ede H, Turan Y, G&#xfc;rel A, Ardahanli I, Sarak T. Yeni tani konmus hipertansiyonu olan hastalarda erektil disfonksiyon ile epikardiyal yag dokusu kalinligi ve karotis intima-media kalinligi arasindaki iliskinin degerlendirilmesi. Turk Kardiyol Dern Ars. 2020;48:746&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33257608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>