<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41743754</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0974-5963</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>23</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>CytoJournal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cytojournal</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Usefulness of fine needle aspiration cytology in diagnosis of soft tissue tumors and its correlation with histopathological features.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.25259/Cytojournal_263_2024</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Fine needle aspiration cytology (FNAC) is a standard diagnostic tool and has several advantages which are specific to soft tissue tumors (STT). STT arises from non-epithelial and extra-skeletal tissue of the body, excluding the reticuloendothelial system, glia, and supporting tissues of organs. Primary STTs are very rare and encompass a wide range of different tumor types; therefore, the classification and diagnosis remain complex. If the tumor is diagnosed as benign, surgery may not be necessary. However, in the case of malignancy, a cytological diagnosis allows for the initiation of palliative treatment. This study was conducted to evaluate the role of FNAC in the diagnosis of STT by sub classifying them based on their cytology features and finally correlating their FNAC findings with histopathological results with special reference to immunohistochemistry (IHC) in diagnostic challenging cases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIAL AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">It was a hospital-based retrospective study conducted in a tertiary care center, over a period of 2 years, i.e., from July 2016 to May 2018. After obtaining approval from the ethics committee of the institution, the study was carried out. All STT cases subjected to FNAC followed by incisional, excisional, or core needle biopsy or complete resection for histopathological examination were studied. The slides of these patients were retrieved and reviewed to establish a proper diagnosis. IHC was carried out in most cases whenever there was a diagnostic dilemma.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In our study, among 50 patients who presented with STT, 40 were benign, and 10 were malignant. The median age of incidence was 41, and male-to-female ratio was 0.85:1. The most common site was the trunk. There were four discordant cases, and the final evaluation of all results showed sensitivity, specificity, positive predictive value of tests, and negative predictive value of tests of FNAC as 100%, 76.92%, 92.5%, and 100%, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In STT, most were benign tumors, with lipomas being the most common among them. While benign and malignant were easy to diagnose, intermediate spindle cell tumors were often missed on cytology. These intermediate tumors represent the diagnostic "grey zone." With increasing experience, STT can be diagnosed more accurately. FNAC is therefore a standard pre-operative diagnostic tool and a reliable alternative to open biopsy for diagnosing STT.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Scientific Scholar.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dindalkoppa</LastName><ForeName>Madhuri</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4829-6838</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Symbiosis Medical College for Women and Symbiosis University Hospital and Research Centre, Symbiosis International (Deemed University), Pune, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shetty</LastName><ForeName>Prajna K</ForeName><Initials>PK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9156-9969</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, KLE Jagadguru Gangadhar Mahaswamigalu Moorusavirmath Medical College and Hospital, Hubli, KLE academy of Higher Education and Research, Deemed to be university, Belgavi, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dinesh</LastName><ForeName>U S</ForeName><Initials>US</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, SDM College of Medical Sciences and Hospital, Shri Dharmasthala Manjunatheshwara University, Dharwad, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vimal</LastName><ForeName>Shruti</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Symbiosis Medical College for Women and Symbiosis University Hospital and Research Centre, Symbiosis International (Deemed University), Pune, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Javalgi</LastName><ForeName>Anita P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pathology Discipline Department of Biomedical Science College of Medicine Gulf Medical University Ajman UAE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cytojournal</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101231642</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1742-6413</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fine needle aspiration cytology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immunohistochemistry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Negative predictive value of tests</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Positive predictive value of tests</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Soft tissue tumors</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41743754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12931189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25259/Cytojournal_263_2024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.25259/Cytojournal_263_2024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rekhi B, Gorad BD, Kakade AC, Chinoy R. Scope of FNAC in the diagnosis of soft tissue tumors--a study from a tertiary cancer referral center in India. Cytojournal. 2007;4:20. doi: 10.1186/1742-6413-4-20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1742-6413-4-20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2164954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17973999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enzinger Franz M, Weiss SW. 6th ed. Philadelphia, PA: Elsevier Saunders; 2014. Enzinger and Weiss's soft tissue tumors.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demay R. 2nd ed. Chicago: ASCP Press; 2012. The art and science of cytopathology; pp. 636&#x2013;749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association World medical association declaration of Helsinki: Ethical principles for medical research involving human participants. JAMA. 2024;333:71&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1001/jama.2024.21972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2024.21972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39425955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatura KR, Katyal A, Hiremath SS. Fine-needle aspiration cytology in soft tissue tumors: How far did we go?? 2015;2:107&#x2013;11. doi: 10.15713/ins.jcri.56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15713/ins.jcri.56</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogun GO. Fine needle Aspiration Biopsy (FNAB) in the initial evaluation and diagnosis of palpable soft tissue lesions and with histologic correlation. Pan Afr Med J. 2015;20:44. doi: 10.11604/pamj.2015.20.44.4271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11604/pamj.2015.20.44.4271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4449991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26090002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez Campora R, Munoz-Arias G, Otal-Salaverri C, Jorda-Heras M, Garcia-Alvarez E, Gomez-Pascual A, et al. Fine needle aspiration cytology of primary soft tissue tumors. Morphologic analysis of the most frequent types. Acta Cytol. 1992;36:905&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1449029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tailor HJ, Bhagat VM, Kaptan KB, Italiya SL, Balar HR, Agarwal MP. Diagnostic accuracy of fine needle aspiration cytology in soft tissue tumors: Our institutional experience. Int J Res Med Sci. 2013;1:443&#x2013;7. doi: 10.5455/2320-6012.ijrms20131126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5455/2320-6012.ijrms20131126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy S, Manna AK, Pathak S, Guha D. Evaluation of fine needle aspiration cytology and its correlation with histopathological findings in soft tissue tumours. J Cytol. 2007;24:37&#x2013;40. doi: 10.4103/0970-9371.42089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0970-9371.42089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beg S, Vasenwala SM, Haider N, Ahamad SS, Maheshwari V, Khan M. A comparison of cytological and histopathological findings and role of immunostains in the diagnosis of soft tissue tumors. J Cytol. 2012;29:125&#x2013;30. doi: 10.4103/0970-9371.97154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0970-9371.97154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3391793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22787293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akerman M, Domanski HA. The cytology of soft tissue tumours. Monogr Clin Cytol. 2003;16(IX-X):1&#x2013;112. doi: 10.1159/isbn.978-3-318-00986-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/isbn.978-3-318-00986-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14518076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arul P, Masilamani S. Fine needle aspiration cytology of soft tissue tumors with its histopathological correlation in a rural hospital of South India: A retrospective study. Clin Cancer Investig J. 2016;5:146&#x2013;50. doi: 10.4103/2278-0513.178066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/2278-0513.178066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop JA. Soft tissue pseudosarcomas. Surg Pathol Clin. 2011;4:699&#x2013;719. doi: 10.1016/j.path.2011.08.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.path.2011.08.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26837644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surbhi Metgud R, Naik S, Patel S. Spindle cell lesions: A review on immunohistochemical markers. J Can Res Ther. 2017;13:412&#x2013;8. doi: 10.4103/0973-1482.176178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0973-1482.176178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28862201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilpatrick SE, Ward WG, Cappellari JO, Bos GD. Fine-needle aspiration biopsy of soft tissue sarcomas. A cytomorphologic analysis with emphasis on histologic subtyping, grading, and therapeutic significance. Am J Clin Pathol. 1999;112:179&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1093/ajcp/112.2.179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcp/112.2.179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10439797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa MJ, Campman SC, Davis RL, Howell LP. Fine-needle aspiration cytology of sarcoma: Retrospective review of diagnostic utility and specificity. Diagn Cytopathol. 1994;15:23&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1002/(SICI)1097-0339(199607)15:1&lt;23::AID-DC6&gt;3.0.CO;2-R.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1097-0339(199607)15:1&lt;23::AID-DC6&gt;3.0.CO;2-R</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8807248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers CN, Berardo MD, Frable WJ. Fine-needle aspiration biopsy: Pitfalls in the diagnosis of spindle-cell lesions. Diagn Cytopathol. 1993;10:232&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1002/dc.2840100309. discussion 241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dc.2840100309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8050331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ers&#xf6;z C, Zorludemir U, Tanyeli A, G&#xfc;m&#xfc;rd&#xfc;l&#xfc; D, Celiktas M. Fine needle aspiration cytology of hepatoblastoma. A report of two cases. Acta Cytol. 1998;42:799&#x2013;802. doi: 10.1159/000331851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000331851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9622712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Maghraby HQ, Khalbuss WE, Rao UN, Cieply K, Dacic S, Monaco SE. Fine needle aspiration biopsy diagnosis of dedifferentiated liposarcoma: Cytomorphology and MDM2 amplification by FISH. Cytojournal. 2010;7:5. doi: 10.4103/1742-6413.62257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1742-6413.62257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2861822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20436789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Rohil M, Ylagan LR, Bhalla S. Fine needle aspiration cytology of a dedifferentiated liposarcoma: report of a case with histologic and immunohistochemical follow-up. Acta Cytol. 2001;45(4):641&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1159/000327880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000327880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11480734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aleixo PB, Hartmann AA, Menezes IC, Meurer RT, Oliveira AM. Can MDM2 and CDK4 make the diagnosis of well differentiated/dedifferentiated liposarcoma? An immunohistochemical study on 129 soft tissue tumours. J Clin Pathol. 2009;62(12):1127&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1136/jcp.2009.070201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jcp.2009.070201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19946100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaithanya K, Dinesh CU. Utility of fine needle aspiration cytology in diagnosing soft tissue tumors-experience in our institution. IP J Diagn Pathol Oncol. 2017;2:76&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalbuss WE, Teot LA, Monaco SE. Diagnostic accuracy and limitations of fine-needle aspiration cytology of bone and soft tissue lesions. Cancer Cytopathol. 2010;118:24&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1002/cncy.20058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncy.20058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20091838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakely PE, Jr, Kneisl JS. Soft tissue aspiration cytopathology. Cancer. 2000;90:292&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1002/1097-0142(20001025)90:5&lt;292::AID-CNCR5&gt;3.0.CO;2-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1097-0142(20001025)90:5&lt;292::AID-CNCR5&gt;3.0.CO;2-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11038426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akerman M, Idvall I, Rydholm A. Cytodiagnosis of soft tissue tumors and tumor-like conditions by means of fine needle aspiration biopsy. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg (1978) 1980;96:61&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1007/BF01246145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01246145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7377928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parajuli S, Lakhey M. Efficacy of fine needle aspiration cytology in diagnosing soft tissue tumors. J Pathol Nepal. 2012;2:305&#x2013;8. doi: 10.3126/jpn.v2i4.6884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/jpn.v2i4.6884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakheja G, Handa U, Punia RS, Attri AK. Fine-needle aspiration cytology in soft tissue tumors-5-year institutional experience. Diagn Cytopathol. 2022;50:463&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1002/dc.25017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dc.25017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35869962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey G, Jalaly F. Fine needle aspiration cytology of soft tissue lesion: Our institutional experience. IOSR J Dent Med Sci. 2021;20:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>