<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41120900</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2229</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC plant biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Plant Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Bio-integration of rhizobacteria and biogenic silver nanoparticles against Pseudomonas syringae pv. syringae causing plum bacterial canker.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1412</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1412</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1412</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12870-025-07466-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Plum is a nutritionally and medicinally valuable fruit with high economic value; however, in temperate regions, its yield continuously suffers from bacterial canker caused by Pseudomonas syringae pathovars.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">To bridge the research gap, a study was conducted to optimize the use of rhizobacteria and biogenic silver nanoparticles (AgNPs) for controlling bacterial canker in plums. Rhizobacteria were isolated from plum orchards and identified (through 16&#xa0;S rRNA gene sequencing, phylogenetic analysis using MEGA) and further evaluated for plant growth-promoting characteristics (siderophore production, production of hydrogen cyanide, solubilization of phosphate, and biofilm formation). The results revealed that 7 isolates out of 19 rhizobacterial isolates produced biofilm, of which Rw-1, Rw-6, Rw-7, and Hj-2 were Pseudomonas fluorescens, while Rw-12 and Hj-5 were identified as Bacillus subtilis. Besides, biogenic AgNPs were prepared in different concentrations (0.2%, 0.4%, and 0.6%) by using Cannabis sativa plant extract. X-ray diffraction (indicated the size of crystalline green silver nanoparticles of ~&#x2009;20&#xa0;nm), Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy (confirmed the presence of alkyne molecules, polyphenols, and carbonyl compounds on the AgNPs surface), and scanning electron microscopy (SEM) were used for characterization of the nanoparticles. Additionally, the antibacterial activity of AgNPs was determined by the disk diffusion assay with 18-hour cultures of P. syringae. In vitro experiments showed that the highest inhibition zone (24.32&#xa0;mm) was caused by the 0.6% AgNPs concentration, proving the strongest antibacterial activity. The subsequent glasshouse tests confirmed that a consortium of two strains of Bacillus with 0.6% AgNPs allowed the lowest disease incidence (18.13%), proving efficient disease suppression. Combination of Bacillus and Pseudomonas strains with 0.6% AgNPs recorded significantly higher disease incidence, with the probable reason being incompatibility among these bacterial genera.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The research findings emphasize the potential of applying compatible rhizobacterial consortia and biogenic (C. sativa) silver nanoparticles as a potent substitute for synthetic pesticides in controlling plum bacterial canker.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Kanwal</LastName><ForeName>Misbah</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plant Pathology, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Poonch Rawalakot, Rawalakot, 12350, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Raees</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plant Pathology, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Poonch Rawalakot, Rawalakot, 12350, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hanif</LastName><ForeName>Asma</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Botany, University of Karachi, Karachi, 75270, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehmood</LastName><ForeName>Umair</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plant Pathology, PMAS-Arid Agriculture University, Rawalpindi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alqahtani</LastName><ForeName>Mashael Daghash</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, College of Science, Princess Nourah bint Abdulrahman University, P.O. Box 84428, Riyadh , 11671, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iqbal</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Aamir</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agronomy, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Poonch Rawalakot, Rawalakot, 12350, Pakistan. muhammadaamir@upr.edu.pk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>PNURSP2025R355</GrantID><Agency>Princess Nourah Bint Abdulrahman University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Plant Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967807</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2229</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3M4G523W1G</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012834">Silver</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000900">Anti-Bacterial Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012834" MajorTopicYN="Y">Silver</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044224" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pseudomonas syringae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053768" MajorTopicYN="Y">Metal Nanoparticles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010935" MajorTopicYN="Y">Plant Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068242" MajorTopicYN="Y">Prunus domestica</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018441" MajorTopicYN="N">Biofilms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001412" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bacillus subtilis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011551" MajorTopicYN="N">Pseudomonas fluorescens</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010802" MajorTopicYN="N">Phylogeny</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000900" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Bacterial Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bacterial canker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biological control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nanoparticles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rhizobacteria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">X-ray diffraction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This article does not contain any studies with human participants or animals. The collection of plant materials complies with the relevant institutional, national, and international guidelines and legislation. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41120900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12539026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12870-025-07466-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12870-025-07466-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ertekin C, Gozlekci S, Kabas O, Sonmez S, Akinci I. Some physical, pomological and nutritional properties of two plum (<i>Prunus domestica</i> L.) cultivars. J Food Eng. 2006;75(4):508&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfoodeng.2005.04.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afanador&#x2013;Barajas LN, Wilches AV, Macana YAM, Medina&#x2013;P&#xe9;rez G. History, distribution, production and taxonomic classification of Plum. In: Handbook of Plum fruit. Boca Raton: CRC; 2022. p. 1&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wangchu L, Angami T, Mandal D. Plum. In: Temperate fruits. Oakville: Apple Academic; 2021. p. 297&#x2013;331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO). Statistic division. Rome: FAO; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAOSTAT. Statistics division. Rome: Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alibekov RS, Gabrilyants EA, Tursynbai LM, Konakbay A. Antioxidant properties and nutritional value of plum. In: <i>Industrial Technologies and Engineering Conference Proceedings</i>; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Liu H, Mazhar MS, Quddus S, Agar OT, Suleria HAR. Australian native plum: a review of the phytochemical and health effects. Food Rev Int. 2024;40(1):504&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/87559129.2023.2172428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faria AF, Marques MC, Mercadante AZ. Identification of bioactive compounds from jambol&#xe3;o (<i>Syzygium cumini</i>) and antioxidant capacity evaluation in different pH conditions. Food Chem. 2011;126(4):1571&#x2013;8.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2010.12.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25213929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowri S, Almeida L, Amorim T, Carneiro N, Souto AP, Esteves MF. Polymer nanocomposites for multifunctional finishing of textiles: a review. Text Res J. 2010;80(13):1290&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0040517509357652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penrose LJ. Disease control in stone fruits in Australia. Pestic Outlook. 1998;9(2):13&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seethapathy P, Gothandaraman R, Gurudevan T, Malik IA. Diseases, pests, and disorders in plum: diagnosis and management. In: Handbook of Plum fruit. Boca Raton: CRC; 2022. p. 133&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron HR. Diseases of deciduous fruit trees incited by <i>Pseudomonas syringae</i> Van hall: A review of the literature with additional data. Corvallis: Agricultural Experiment Station, Oregon State University; 1962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi M, Ghasemi A, Rahimian H. Phenotypic characterization of Iranian strains of <i>Pseudomonas syringae</i> pv. <i>syringae</i> Van Hall, the causal agent of bacterial canker disease of stone fruit trees. J Agric Sci Technol. 2001;3(1):51&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed R, Inam&#x2013;ul&#x2013;Haq M, Shahzad U, Hyder S, Shahzaman S, Gondal AS. First report of bacterial canker caused by <i>Pseudomonas syringae</i> pv. <i>morsprunorum</i> on Peach from Khyber Pakhtunkhwa Province of Pakistan. Plant Dis. 2018;102(10):2027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1094/PDIS-10-17-1618-PDN</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fei Z, Joung JG, Tang X, Zheng Y, Huang M, Lee JM, et al. Tomato functional genomics database: A comprehensive resource and analysis package for tomato functional genomics. Nucleic Acids Res. 2010;39(1):1156&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3013811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20965973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong K, Rhodes C. Gardening bacterial canker of stone fruits. Int J Phytopathol. 2022;11(1):43&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marroni MV, Casonato S, Pitman AR, Visnovsky SB, Beresford RM, Jones EE. Review of <i>Pseudomonas</i> species causing bacterial canker of <i>Prunus</i> species with emphasis on sweet cherry (<i>Prunus avium</i>) in new Zealand. Eur J Plant Pathol. 2024;168(2):297&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10658-023-02755-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lownsbery B, English H, Noel G, Schick F. Influence of Nemaguard and Lovell rootstocks and <i>Macroposthonia Xenoplax</i> on bacterial canker of Peach. J Nematol. 1977;9(3):221&#x2013;4.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2620238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19305599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennelly MM, Cazorla FM, de Vicente A, Ramos C, Sundin GW. <i>Pseudomonas syringae</i> diseases of fruit trees: progress toward understanding and control. Plant Dis. 2007;91(1):4&#x2013;17.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1094/PD-91-0004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30781059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bibi S, Inam&#x2013;Ul&#x2013;Haq M, Riaz A, Malik SI, Tahir MI, Ahmed R. Screening and characterization of rhizobacteria antagonistic to <i>Pseudomonas syringae</i> causing bacterial canker of stone fruits in Punjab and KPK. Int J Biosci. 2017;10(5):405&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fantozzi S, Giovanardi A, Magalh&#xe3;es FA, Di Michele R, Cortesi M, Gatta G. Assessment of three&#x2013;dimensional joint kinematics of the upper limb during simulated swimming using wearable inertial&#x2013;magnetic measurement units. J Sports Sci. 2016;34(11):1073&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2015.1088659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26367468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos MG, Nunes da Silva M, Vasconcelos MW, Carvalho SM. Scientific and technological advances in the development of sustainable disease management tools: A case study on Kiwifruit bacterial canker. Front Plant Sci. 2024;14:1306420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2023.1306420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10808555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38273947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batsmanova LM, Gonchar LM, Taran NY, Okanenko AA. Using a colloidal solution of metal nanoparticles as micronutrient fertiliser for cereals. Sumy: Sumy State University; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vishnu M, Kannan M, Soundararajan R, Suganthi A, Subramanian A, Senthilkumar M, et al. Nano&#x2013;bioformulations: emerging trends and potential applications in next generation crop protection. Environ Sci Nano. 2024;11(7):2831&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D4EN00263F</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kannan M, Mohan M, Elango K, Govindaraju K, Mani M. Principles and application of nanotechnology in pest management. In: Trends in horticultural entomology. Singapore: Springer Nature; 2022. p. 49&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y, Zhao W, Zhu G, Tan Z, Huang L, Zhang P, et al. Nano&#x2013;pesticides and fertilizers: solutions for global food security. Nanomaterials. 2023;14(1):90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nano14010090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10780761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38202545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azarakhsh M, Gerivani M. Antibacterial activity of chitosan/thyme essential oil/Copper nano&#x2013;complexes against <i>Pseudomonas syringae</i> pv. <i>syringae</i>. Plant Protect. 2025;48(2):1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samrot AV, Saigeetha S, Shobana N, Chandrasekaran K. Green&#x2013;synthesized nanoparticle&#x2013;based polymer nanocomposites: Synthesis, characterizations, and applications. In: Biodegradable and biocompatible polymer nanocomposites. Amsterdam: Elsevier; 2023. p. 241&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamaoka&#x2013;Yano D, Amorim E, Valarini P, de Melo I. Characterization of rhizobacteria from citrus rhizosphere to control <i>Phytophthora nicotinae</i> var. <i>parasitica</i> and <i>P. citrophthora</i>. In: <i>World Congress of Soil Science</i>; 2019. Montpellier, France.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manik U, Nande A, Raut S, Dhoble S. Green synthesis of silver nanoparticles using plant leaf extraction of <i>Artocarpus heterophyllus</i> and <i>Azadirachta indica</i>. Results Mater. 2020;6:100086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rinma.2020.100086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vivek M, Kumar PS, Steffi S, Sudha S. Biogenic silver nanoparticles by <i>Gelidiella Acerosa</i> extract and their antifungal effects. Avicenna J Med Biotechnol. 2011;3(3):143&#x2013;52.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3558184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23408653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbeshehy EK, Elazzazy AM, Aggelis G. Silver nanoparticles synthesis mediated by new isolates of <i>Bacillus</i> spp., nanoparticle characterization and their activity against bean yellow mosaic virus and human pathogens. Front Microbiol. 2015;6:453.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2015.00453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4429621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26029190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vicente JG, Roberts S. Screening wild Cherry micropropagated plantlets for resistance to bacterial canker. Pseudomonas syringae and related pathogens: biology and genetics. Dordrecht: Springer; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malleswari D, Bagyanarayan G. In vitro screening of rhizobacteria isolated from the rhizosphere of medicinal and aromatic plants for multiple plant growth&#x2013;promoting activities. J Microbiol Biotechnol. 2013;3:84&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teintze M, Hossain M, Barnes C, Leong J, Van der Helm D. Structure of ferric pseudobactin: A siderophore from a plant growth promoting <i>Pseudomonas</i>. Biochemistry. 1981;20(22):6446&#x2013;57.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/bi00525a025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7306518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deshwal VK, Kumar P. Effect of salinity on growth and PGPR activity of pseudomonads. J Acad Ind Res. 2013;2(6):353&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadakis M, Carre F, Kervio G, Rawlins J, Panoulas VF, Chandra N, et al. The prevalence, distribution, and clinical outcomes of electrocardiographic repolarization patterns in male athletes of African/Afro&#x2013;Caribbean origin. Eur Heart J. 2011;32(18):2304&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehr140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21613263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qurashi AW, Sabri AN. Bacterial exopolysaccharide and biofilm formation stimulate chickpea growth and soil aggregation under salt stress. Braz J Microbiol. 2012;43:1183&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1517-83822012000300046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3768896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24031943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujishige NA, Kapadia NN, De Hoff PL, Hirsch AM. Investigations of <i>Rhizobium</i> biofilm formation. FEMS Microbiol Ecol. 2006;56(2):195&#x2013;206.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1574-6941.2005.00044.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16629750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagar A, Rai S, Sharma S, Perveen K, Bukhari NA, Sayyed R, et al. Molecular characterization reveals biodiversity and biopotential of rhizobacterial isolates of <i>Bacillus</i> spp. Microb Ecol. 2024;87(1):83.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00248-024-02397-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11189325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38888737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A, Gupta M, Rathod L, Verma S, Parashar S. Molecular characterization of plant growth promoting rhizobacteria isolated from nodules of <i>Cicer arietinum</i> plant. Biochem Cell Arch. 2025;25(1):1443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daphedar A, Taranath TC. Green synthesis of zinc nanoparticles using leaf extract of <i>Albizia saman</i> (Jacq.) Merr. and their effect on root meristems of <i>Drimia indica</i> (Roxb.) Jessop. Caryologia. 2018;71(2):93&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00087114.2018.1437980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamdagni P, Khatri P, Rana JS. Green synthesis of zinc oxide nanoparticles using flower extract of <i>Nyctanthes arbor&#x2013;tristis</i> and their antifungal activity. J King Saud Univ. 2018;30(2):168&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jksus.2016.10.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asif M, Yasmin R, Asif R, Ambreen A, Mustafa M, Umbreen S. Green synthesis of silver nanoparticles (AgNPs), structural characterization, and their antibacterial potential. Dose Response. 2022;20(2):15593258221088709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15593258221088709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9112420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35592270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasieczna&#x2013;Patkowska S, Cichy M, Flieger J. Application of fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy in characterization of green synthesized nanoparticles. Molecules. 2025;30(3):684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules30030684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11821210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39942788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varympopi A, Dimopoulou A, Papafotis D, Avramidis P, Sarris I, Karamanidou T, et al. Antibacterial activity of copper nanoparticles against <i>Xanthomonas Campestris</i> pv. <i>vesicatoria</i> in tomato plants. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(8):4080.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23084080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9032352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35456899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abel S, Tesfaye JL, Shanmugam R, Dwarampudi LP, Lamessa G, Nagaprasad N, et al. Green synthesis and characterizations of zinc oxide (ZnO) nanoparticles using aqueous leaf extracts of coffee (<i>Coffea arabica</i>) and its application in environmental toxicity reduction. J Nanomater. 2021;2021(1):3413350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradian F, Ghorbani R, Biparva P. Assessment of different antibacterial effects of Fe and Cu nanoparticles on <i>Xanthomonas campestris</i> growth and expression of its pathogenic gene <i>HrpE</i>. J Agric Sci Technol. 2018;20(5):1059&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>