<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41413470</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2393</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC pregnancy and childbirth</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Determinants of Birth Asphyxia Among Neonates in Selected Hospitals of Ethiopia: A Multi-site Unmatched Case-Control Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1309</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1309</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1309</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12884-025-08284-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Birth asphyxia is a significant cause of most perinatal mortality and morbidity worldwide. In Ethiopia, maternal medical conditions, such as pregnancy-induced hypertension and diabetes, have significantly contributed to the increase in neonatal morbidity and adverse birth outcomes. The study aimed to identify the determinants of birth asphyxia among neonates delivered in Southwest Shoa Zone public hospitals, Ethiopia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A retrospective unmatched case-control study design was used among neonates delivered at a selected hospital in Southwest Shoa Zone, Ethiopia, between 20 August 2022 and 19 November 2022. Cases and controls were enrolled in a ratio of 1:2. The cases were newborns with birth asphyxia, Apgar score (Appearance, Pulse, Grimaces, Activity, and Respiration)&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;7 within the first five minutes at birth. Newborns without birth asphyxia with Apgar score&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;7 within the first five minutes at birth were selected as controls. For each enrolled case of birth asphyxia, two unmatched control newborns who delivered without birth asphyxia were enrolled in selected hospitals during the study period. Data were collected using structured questionnaires and medical records. The collected data were cleaned, coded and entered into Epi Info version 7, then exported to Statistical Package for Social Sciences version 26 for analysis. Multivariate logistic regression analysis was used to identify the determinants of birth asphyxia, with the level of significance set at p-value&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The study revealed that the mean age of the case mothers was 27 years (SD&#x2009;=&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;7.3) and that of control mothers was 27.1 years (SD&#x2009;=&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;5.4). Meconium-stained amniotic fluid [AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.9; 95% CI (1.02&#x2013;3.6)], pregnancy-induced hypertension [AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;5.8; 95% CI (2.65&#x2013;13.63), instrumental delivery [AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;5.71; 95% CI (1.56 &#x2212;&#x2009;28.2)], post term [AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;9.68 95% CI (1.87&#x2013;26.87)], induction/augmentation of labor [AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;5.09; 95% CI (1.06&#x2013;24.36)] and non-cephalic presentation [AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.68; 95%CI (0.24&#x2013;7.55)] were significantly associated with birth asphyxia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Birth asphyxia was significantly associated with maternal and obstetric factors, including meconium-stained amniotic fluid, pregnancy-induced hypertension, instrumental delivery, post-term, induction of labor and non-cephalic presentation. These findings highlight the importance of comprehensive maternal and newborn care, including strengthening antenatal care to identify and manage pregnancy-related complications, promoting maternal recognition of danger signs during pregnancy, and ensuring timely access to skilled intrapartum and emergency obstetric care to reduce the incidence of birth asphyxia.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Girma</LastName><ForeName>Ketema</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Ambo University, Ambo, Oromia Region, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tefera</LastName><ForeName>Eden Girmaye</ForeName><Initials>EG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Midwifery, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Ambo University, Ambo, Oromia Region, Ethiopia. edengirmaye@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdissa</LastName><ForeName>Bayisa</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Ambo University, Ambo, Oromia Region, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967799</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2393</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Asphyxias</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Birth complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Case-control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Determinants</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neonate</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study complies the ethical issues in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki [29]. The study was reviewed and approved by Ambo University College of Medicine and Health Sciences Ethical Review Board (ERB) (Ref.No.AU/CMHS-RCS/27/2022). The study participants were informed about purpose the study, risks and benefits of the study. In this study, participation was thoroughly voluntary. The participant&#x2019;s right to privacy and confidentiality was rigorously upheld. The study does not reveal any information that could be used to identify a participant. Moreover, written informed consent was obtained from all participants before the study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41413470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12715957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-025-08284-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12884-025-08284-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aziz K, Lee HC, Escobedo MB, Hoover AV, Kamath-Rayne BD, Kapadia VS, et al. Part 5: Neonatal resuscitation: 2020 American heart association guidelines for cardiopulmonary resuscitation and emergency cardiovascular care. Circulation. 2020;142(16):S524&#x2013;50. Available from: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33081528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Cuevas I, Parra-Llorca A, S&#xe1;nchez-Illana A, Nu&#xf1;ez-Ramiro A, Kuligowski J, Ch&#xe1;fer-Peric&#xe1;s C, et al. Oxygen and oxidative stress in the perinatal period. Redox Biol. 2017;12:674&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.redox.2017.03.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5388914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28395175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyckoff MH, Singletary EM, Soar J, Olasveengen TM, Greif R, Liley HG, et al. International Consensus on Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation and Emergency Cardiovascular Care Science With Treatment Recommendations: Summary From the Basic Life Support; Advanced Life Support; Neonatal Life Support; Education, Implementation, and Teams. Circulation. 2022;145(9):e645&#x2013;721. Available from: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000001017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34813356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Mental Health, Brain Health and Substance Use. 2019. Available from: https://www.who.int/teams/mental-health-and-substance-use/promotion-prevention/maternal-mental-health. [cited 2023 Feb 3].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Inter-agency group for child mortality estimation. Monitoring the situation of children and women. 2021. Available from: https://data.unicef.org/topic/child-survival/under-five-mortality/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). World Health Organization. The United Nations Inter-agency Group for Child survival and the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). 2022. Available from: https://data.unicef.org/topic/child-survival/child-survival-sdgs/. [cited 2022 Dec 24].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethiopian Public Health Institute (EPHI) Inner City Fund International (ICF). Ethiopia Mini Demographic and Health Survey. Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, and Rockville, Maryland, USA: CSA and ICF; 2019. Available from: https://dhsprogram.com/pubs/pdf/FR363/FR363.pdf. [cited 2022 Jan 13].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdo RA, Halil HM, Kebede BA, Anshebo AA, Gejo NG. Prevalence and contributing factors of birth asphyxia among the neonates delivered at Nigist Eleni Mohammed memorial teaching hospital, Southern Ethiopia: a cross-sectional study. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2019;19(1):536. Available from: 10.1186/s12884-019-2696-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-019-2696-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6937931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31888542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Central Statistical Agency (CSA) [Ethiopia]. Population Projections for Ethiopia, 2007&#x2013;2037. Addis Ababa, Ethiopia: Central Statistical Agency; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wosenu L, Worku AG, Teshome DF, Gelagay AA. Determinants of birth asphyxia among live birth newborns in university of Gondar referral hospital, Northwest ethiopia: A case-control study. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(9):e0203763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0203763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6128623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30192884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). WHO Recommendations for Care of the Preterm or Low-Birth-Weight Infant. Gesundheitswesen. 2022;86:289&#x2013;293. Available from: https://iris.who.int/bitstream/handle/10665/363697/9789240058262-eng.pdf.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36449655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steven G, Gabbe, Niebyl JR, Simpson JL, London MB, Obstetrics. Normal and problem pregnancies. Volume 4, 6th ed. Philadelphia: Elsevier; 2012. pp. 1&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, Gao J, Liu J, Tang Y, Zhong M, He J, et al. Perinatal maternal characteristics predict a high risk of neonatal asphyxia: A multi-center retrospective cohort study in China. Front Med. 2022;9:944272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2022.944272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9393324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36004371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayebare E, Hanson C, Nankunda J, Hjelmstedt A, Nantanda R, Jonas W, et al. Factors associated with birth asphyxia among term singleton births at two referral hospitals in Northern Uganda: a cross sectional study. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2022;22(1):767. Available from: http://0-search.ebscohost.com.oasis.unisa.ac.za/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;db=cmedm&amp;AN=36224532&amp;site=ehost-live&amp;scope=site.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9559004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36224532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tun&#xe7; &#x15e;, O&#x11f;lak SC, Gedik &#xd6;zk&#xf6;se Z, &#xd6;lmez F. The evaluation of the antepartum and intrapartum risk factors in predicting the risk of birth asphyxia. J Obstet Gynaecol Res. 2022;48(6):1370&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jog.15214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35315167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fain JA. Reading,Understanding and applying nursing research. 2nd ed. Philadelphia: Davis Company; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosmer DW, Lemeshow S, Sturdivant RX. Applied Logistic Regression. 3rd ed. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palsdottir K, Dagbjartsson A, Thorkelsson T, Hardardottir H. Birth asphyxia and hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy, incidence and obstetric risk factors. Laeknabladid. 2007;93(9):595&#x2013;601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17823499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadeem G, Rehman A, Bashir H. Risk factors associated with birth asphyxia in term newborns at a tertiary care hospital of Multan, Pakistan. Cureus. 2021;13(10):e18759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8590025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34796056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nangia S, Thukral A, Chawla D. Tracheal suction at birth in non-vigorous neonates born through meconium-stained amniotic fluid. Cochrane database Syst Rev. 2021;6:CD012671. Available from: http://0-search.ebscohost.com.oasis.unisa.ac.za/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;db=cmedm&amp;AN=34133025&amp;site=ehost-live&amp;scope=site.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8207961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34133025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Msisiri Laidi S, Kibusi Stephen M, Kimaro Franisca D. Risk Factors for Birth Asphyxia in Hospital-Delivered Newborns in Dodoma, Tanzania: A Case-Control Study. SAGE Open Nurs. 2024;10:23779608241246870. Available from: 10.1177/23779608241246874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23779608241246874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11044786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38665876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He XG, Li JF, Xu FD, Xie HQ, Huang TL. [Clinical features of severe meconium aspiration syndrome (MAS) and early predicting factors for severe MAS in neonates with meconium-stained amniotic fluid]. Zhongguo Dang Dai Er Ke Za Zhi. 2022;24(6):662&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9250403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35762433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghnia A, Mohammadpoor S. The investigation of rate of birth asphyxia and its relationship with delivery mode at shahid beheshti hospital of Isfahan during 2013, 2014, and 2015. Int J Prev Med. 2019;10(1):23. Available from: https://www.ijpvmjournal.net/article.asp?issn=2008-7802.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijpvm.IJPVM_383_16</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6390421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30820310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunny AK, Paudel P, Tiwari J, Bagale BB, Kukka A, Hong Z, et al. A multicenter study of incidence, risk factors and outcomes of babies with birth asphyxia in Nepal. BMC Pediatr. 2021;21(1):394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12887-021-02858-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8431921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34507527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vayssi&#xe8;re C, Haumonte JB, Chantry A, Coatleven F, Debord MP, Gomez C, et al. Prolonged and post-term pregnancies: guidelines for clinical practice from the French college of gynecologists and obstetricians (CNGOF). Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2013;169(1):10&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejogrb.2013.01.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23434325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitriana Y, M AI, Mallongi A, Mappajanci M, Seweng A, Hidayanty H, et al. Risk factors for asphyxia neonatorum in public health centres of Nosarara and pantoloan, palu City. Gac Sanit. 2021;35(Suppl 2):S131&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaceta.2021.07.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34929795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igboanugo S, Chen A, Mielke JG. Maternal risk factors for birth asphyxia in low-resource communities. A systematic review of the literature. J Obstet Gynaecol (Lahore). 2020;40(8):1039&#x2013;55. Available from: 10.1080/01443615.2019.1679737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01443615.2019.1679737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31825270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garba B, Sakajiki M, Musa A, Kolawole T, Adeniji A, Adelakun MB. Prevalence and Risk Factors for Perinatal Asphyxia as Seen at a Specialist Hospital in Gusau, Nigeria. Sub-Saharan African Journal of Medicine. 2018;5(1):12&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki. Ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. J Am Coll Dent. 2014;81(3):14&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25951678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>