<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41431562</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Indications and Outcomes of Colon Resection in a Conflict Zone: A Single-Center Experience From a Military Hospital in Yemen.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e97456</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e97456</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e97456</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.97456</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">&#xa0;Although colon resection is a common procedure, data on its indications and outcomes in conflict-affected regions are limited. These environments present unique surgical challenges, driven by the dual burden of acute trauma and advanced-stage chronic diseases. This study aimed to analyze the experience of colon resection to identify key risk factors and inform surgical practices in austere settings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">&#xa0;A single-center prospective observational study was conducted on 89 patients who underwent colon resection at a military hospital in Sana'a, Yemen, between September 2022 and April 2024. Data on patient demographics, indications, surgical procedures, and postoperative outcomes were collected and analyzed. The primary endpoint was the incidence of adverse outcomes, defined as a composite of significant morbidity and in-hospital mortality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">&#xa0;A total of 89 patients were included (mean age 36.9 years; n=81, 91.0% male). The predominant indication was penetrating trauma (n=70, 78.7%). The overall adverse outcome rate was 19.1% (n=17), comprising a&#xa0;significant morbidity rate of 7.9% (n=7) and an in-hospital mortality rate of 11.2% (n=10). Significant morbidity included events such as&#xa0;anastomotic leak requiring re-operation. Patients presenting with shock on admission had a higher adverse outcome rate than stable patients (34.6% vs. 12.7%); this represented a&#xa0;strong clinical trend that approached statistical significance&#xa0;(OR 3.47, 95%CI 0.95-12.69; P=0.066).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">&#xa0;In this conflict-zone hospital, the patient's initial physiological state, particularly the presence of shock, was the most critical determinant of the postoperative outcomes. Despite the austere conditions, the observed anastomotic leak rate suggests that primary anastomosis is a viable option for carefully selected, hemodynamically stable patients. These findings underscore the need for context-specific guidelines that prioritize physiological risk stratification to guide surgical decision-making.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Albrashi et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Albrashi</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, General Military Hospital, Sana'a, YEM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Obadiel</LastName><ForeName>Yasser A</ForeName><Initials>YA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Faculty of Medicine and Health Science, Sana'a University, Sana'a, YEM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aldomini</LastName><ForeName>Hussam A</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, General Military Hospital, Sana'a, YEM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jowah</LastName><ForeName>Haitham M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Faculty of Medicine and Health Science, Sana'a University, Sana'a, YEM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">austere environment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">colectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">colon resection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">penetrating trauma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgical outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">war surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">yemen</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Institutional Review Board of the Yemeni Board for Medical Specialization issued approval IRB/YBMS/2022/031. This study was conducted in accordance with the ethical principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Additionally, administrative approval was obtained from the Military General Hospital in Sana'a, where the study was conducted. Written informed consent was obtained from all participants or their legally authorized representatives prior to their inclusion in the study. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41431562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12718625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.97456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Stein DE. Medscape: Colon resection.  [
Jul;
2025 
]. 2023. https://emedicine.medscape.com/article/1891505-overview https://emedicine.medscape.com/article/1891505-overview</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of penetrating intraperitoneal colon injuries: a meta-analysis and practice management guideline from the Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma. Cullinane DC, Jawa RS, Como JJ, et al. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2019;86:505&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30789470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addressing abdominal trauma from conflict and warfare in under-resourced regions: a critical narrative review. Awuah WA, Tan JK, Shah MH, et al. Health Sci Rep. 2024;7:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11497492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39444729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Indications and outcomes of endoscopic resection for non-pedunculated colorectal lesions: a narrative review. Shahini E, Lib&#xe2;nio D, Lo Secco G, Pisani A, Arezzo A. World J Gastrointest Endosc. 2021;13:275&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8394186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34512876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Factors influencing surgical management and outcomes of colonic trauma: a prospective observational study at three hospitals in Sana'a City, Yemen. Al-Amy AL, Al-Ajaly MY, Jowah HM. BMC Surg. 2025;25:406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12403608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40898172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes of nonoperative management of penetrating abdominal trauma injury: a retrospective study. Obadiel YA, Albrashi A, Allahabi N, Sharafaddeen M, Ahmed F. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11102771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38765339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colorectal carcinoma at Al-Gamhouria Teaching Hospital, Aden, Yemen. Hamid GA, Saeed NM, Ba-Ashen Y, Ba-Kubirah R. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22227540/ Gulf J Oncolog. 2012:16&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22227540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The damage control sequence and underlying logic. Rotondo MF, Zonies DH. Surg Clin North Am. 1997;77:761&#x2013;777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9291979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damage control resuscitation in patients with severe traumatic hemorrhage: a practice management guideline from the Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma. Cannon JW, Khan MA, Raja AS, et al. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2017;82:605&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28225743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evolution of the operative management of colon trauma. Sharpe JP, Magnotti LJ, Fabian TC, Croce MA. Trauma Surg Acute Care Open. 2017;2:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5877907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29766094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penetrating colon injuries requiring resection: diversion or primary anastomosis? An AAST prospective multicenter study. Demetriades D, Murray JA, Chan L, et al. J Trauma. 2001;50:765&#x2013;775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11371831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intestinal obstruction: predictor of poor prognosis in colorectal carcinoma? Mohd Suan MA, Tan WL, Soelar SA, Ismail I, Abu Hassan MR. Epidemiol Health. 2015;37:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4459110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25868638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The impact of colon injuries on the outcome of gunshot wounds to the abdomen. Singh Y, Motilall S, Khulu BL, Jackson BS. Langenbecks Arch Surg. 2023;408:328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10447282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37612518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>