<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41776224</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sleep quality prediction in basketball athletes using a deep learning framework with an attention mechanism based on multimodal data.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-42147-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>It is difficult for traditional prediction methods to comprehensively evaluate the sleep quality problems of college basketball players, which is a key research problem in the field of physical education in colleges and universities. This study aims to develop an applied multimodal tabular-learning framework with feature-level attention for sleep-quality screening among university basketball athletes. Empirical data were collected from student-athletes at a university, including physical fitness indicators (e.g., BMI, strength, endurance), psychological characteristics (anxiety and stress), and sociodemographic variables (gender, grade, and years of training). Sleep quality was assessed using the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI). After data preprocessing, including cleaning, standardization, and one-hot encoding, four predictive models-Logistic Regression, Random Forest, XGBoost, and Attention-based Multilayer Perceptron (Attention-MLP)-were constructed and compared. The Attention-MLP model outperformed other models in accuracy (0.732) and F1 value (0.630), showing the advantage of modeling complex feature interaction, while BMI and anxiety were identified as the most influential predictors. However, discrimination for the moderate sleep-quality class was poor (Class 2 AUC&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.40), indicating that the current model is more suitable for screening-oriented stratification rather than definitive classification. The results show that the Attention-MLP achieved statistically significant but moderate gains over classic baselines under the current sample size, supporting screening-oriented risk stratification rather than definitive diagnosis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Liping</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Department, Dalian Maritime University, Dalian, 116001, China. 20141005@dlmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miao</LastName><ForeName>Jialiang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Department, Dalian Maritime University, Dalian, 116001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Attention mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multimodal physical fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychological characteristics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep quality prediction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethics declaration: This study was approved by the Ethics Committee of Dalian Maritime University (approval no. DMU-202518). We certify that the study was performed in accordance with the 1964 Declaration of Helsinki and later amendments. This study was obtained informed consent from all the participants.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41776224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-42147-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-42147-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec, M., Halson, S., Abaidia, A. E., Ahmaidi, S. &amp; Dupont, G. Stress, sleep and recovery in elite soccer: A critical review of the literature. Sports Med. 45, 1387&#x2013;1400. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-015-0358-z (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baranwal, N., Phoebe, K. Y. &amp; Siegel, N. S. Sleep physiology, pathophysiology, and sleep hygiene. Prog. Cardiovasc. Dis. 77, 59&#x2013;69. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pcad.2023.03.006 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrosielski, D. A., Sweeney, L. &amp; Lisman, P. J. The association between poor sleep and the incidence of sport and physical training-related injuries in adult athletic populations: A systematic review. Sports Med. 51, 777&#x2013;793. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-020-01376-1 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kullik, L., Isenmann, E., Schalla, J. &amp; Kellmann, M. The impact of menstrual cycle phase and symptoms on sleep, recovery, and stress in elite female basketball athletes: A longitudinal study. Front. Physiol. 12, 1663657. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2025.1663657 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dridi, N., Souissi, M. A., Dridi, R., Ceylan, H. &#x130;. &amp; Bragazzi, N. Evening smartphone exposure impairs sleep quality and next-day performance in elite soccer players: A randomized controlled trial. Biol. Sport. 43 (2), 145&#x2013;154. https://doi.org/10.5114/biolsport.2026.56337 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y., Iwao, K. &amp; Shimamoto, H. The relationship between subjective sleep, mental health, and life skills acquisition among university student-athletes: A study on gender differences. Asian J. Sport Exerc. Psychol. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajsep.2025.100014 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wannell, B. R., Brunner, F. M. J. &amp; Lovibond, Z. N. &amp; colleagues. The influence of partial sleep restriction on repeated sprint ability and reaction time in university athletes. Front. Sports Active Liv. 7, 1519987. https://doi.org/10.3389/fspor.2025.1519987 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, J., Yu, Z. &amp; Yang, J. Multimodal attention-based deep learning for automatic modulation classification. Front. Energy Res. 10, 1041862. https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2022.1041862 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao, Z., Yu, L. &amp; Ye, L. Research on theories and practices of occupational physical fitness training. Res. Sports Sci. 38 (1), 1&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.15877/j.cnki.nsic.20240409.005 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diao, Y. &amp; Zhang, L. Correlation analysis of influencing factors of depression and anxiety in patients undergoing coronary intervention surgery. China Med. Pharm. 14 (13), 160&#x2013;163. https://doi.org/10.20116/j.issn2095-0616.2024.13.38 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graves, B. S., Hall, M. E., Dias-Karch, C., Haischer, M. H. &amp; Apter, C. Gender differences in perceived stress and coping among college students. PLoS One. 16 (8), e0255634. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0255634 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, W. &amp; Chen, Y. Social appearance pressure and body image: Chain mediation effect of self-awareness and perceived stress. Chin. J. Clin. Psychol. 32 (4), 744&#x2013;749. https://doi.org/10.16128/j.cnki.1005-3611.2024.04.005 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Q., Liu, M., Chen, X. Y. &amp; Yao, J. N. Rumination and sleep quality in college students: The role of negative emotions and sleep procrastination. Chin. J. Clin. Psychol. 32 (1), 203&#x2013;206. https://doi.org/10.16128/j.cnki.1005-3611.2024.01.037 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, A. et al. An innovative IoT and edge intelligence framework for monitoring elderly people using anomaly detection on data from non-wearable sensors. Sensors 25 (6), 1735. https://doi.org/10.3390/s25061735 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cvetkov-Iliev, A., Allauzen, A. &amp; Varoquaux, G. Analytics on non-normalized data sources: More learning, rather than more cleaning. IEEE Access. 10, 42420&#x2013;42431. https://doi.org/10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3169500 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieskovsk&#xe1;, E., Jakubec, M., Jarina, R. &amp; Chmul&#xed;k, M. A review on speech emotion recognition using deep learning and attention mechanism. Electronics 10 (10), 1163. https://doi.org/10.3390/electronics10101163 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tirumanadham, N. S. K. M. K. &amp; Thaiyalnayaki, S. Enhancing student performance prediction in e-learning environments: Advanced ensemble techniques and robust feature selection. Int. J. Mod. Educ. Comput. Sci. 17 (2), 67&#x2013;86. https://doi.org/10.5815/ijmecs.2025.02.03 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang, K. M., Seow, E. K., Fam, P. S. &amp; Cheng, L. H. Classification of edible bird&#x2019;s nest samples using a logistic regression model through the mineral ratio approach. Food Control. 137, 108921. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodcont.2022.108921 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, W., Tu, J., Xu, N. &amp; Liu, Z. Predicting daily heating energy consumption in residential buildings through integration of random forest model and meta-heuristic algorithms. Energy 301, 131726. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2023.131726 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, Y. C., Chang, K. H. &amp; Wu, G. J. Application of extreme gradient boosting trees in the construction of credit risk assessment models for financial institutions. Appl. Soft Comput. 73, 914&#x2013;920. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asoc.2018.09.029 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauer, J., Mariani, V. C., dos Santos Coelho, L., Ribeiro, M. H. D. M. &amp; Rampazzo, M. Extreme gradient boosting model based on improved Jaya optimizer applied to forecasting energy consumption in residential buildings. Evol. Syst. 1&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12530-022-09430-7 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brauwers, G. &amp; Frasincar, F. A general survey on attention mechanisms in deep learning. IEEE Trans. Knowl. Data Eng. 35 (4), 3279&#x2013;3298. https://doi.org/10.1109/TKDE.2021.3059197 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostafaei, S. H., Tanha, J. &amp; Sharafkhaneh, A. A novel deep learning model based on transformer and cross modality attention for classification of sleep stages. J. Biomed. Inform. 157, 104689. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbi.2024.104689 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. An interpretable deep learning model for sleep quality prediction using multimodal data. IEEE J. Biomed. Health Inf. 26 (2), 653&#x2013;662 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, L., Zhang, Z. &amp; Liu, J. Circadian rhythm and sleep: A deep learning approach to integrate temporal and behavioral features. Sleep. Health. 9 (1), 50&#x2013;59 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, M. &amp; Lee, H. Predicting sleep disorders using deep learning with psychological and lifestyle features. J. Affect. Disord. 295, 245&#x2013;252 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Y., Zhang, R. &amp; Liu, H. Impact of lifestyle behaviors on sleep quality: A machine learning perspective. Comput. Biol. Med. 137, 104799 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, Y. &amp; He, J. Feature selection and attention-based MLP for health behavior prediction. Appl. Soft Comput. 93, 106351 (2020).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>