<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41651736</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-1861</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of science and medicine in sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sci Med Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Thinking outside the box: comparing age at performance milestones of swimmers to cross-country skiers and biathletes.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1440-2440(26)00042-3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jsams.2026.01.014</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To compare age at key performance milestones between technical whole-body endurance sports and performance levels.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Longitudinal big data analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">All top 30 swimmers, cross-country (XC) skiers and biathletes, who competed at the latest World championships (WC) were included and their ages at specific performance milestones (debut, first 17-30 rank, 9-16 rank, top 8) at junior (JWC) and adult WC were extracted from databases (719 women and 850 men). Athletes were divided into various performance levels based on their best individual ranking from adult competitions and compared using linear mixed model analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Only ~40% of the WC swimmers had competed in the JWC compared to ~90% of XC skiers and biathletes. Swimmers were, on average, 2 and 4&#x202f;years younger at JWC and WC, respectively, than XC skiers and biathletes. In all three sports, there was an age gap (p&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;0.05) between the highest junior performance milestone and adult WC debut (3-4&#x202f;years) but no age difference (p&#x202f;&gt;&#x202f;0.05) between the performance milestones or performance levels at JWC. On average, female swimmers reached performance milestones one year earlier than their male counterparts, while there was no sex difference in XC skiing and biathlon.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The present findings encourage reassessment of sport-specific stereotypes regarding long-term athlete development. Although overall development patterns are similar between men and women, sex-specific training and competition planning is necessary at key junior career stages. Analyzing key structural elements of development systems across three technical whole-body endurance sports provides insights to develop future strategies for long-term athlete development.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jonsson K&#xe5;rstr&#xf6;m</LastName><ForeName>Malin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Swedish Winter Sports Research Centre, Department of Health Sciences, Mid Sweden University, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ruiz-Navarro</LastName><ForeName>Jes&#xfa;s J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aquatics Lab, Department of Physical Education and Sports, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Spain; Human Performance and Sports Science Laboratory, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Romann</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Elite Sport, Swiss Federal Institute of Sport Magglingen, Switzerland; Faculty of Science and Medicine, University of Fribourg, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Born</LastName><ForeName>Dennis-Peter</ForeName><Initials>DP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Elite Sport, Swiss Federal Institute of Sport Magglingen, Switzerland; Faculty of Science and Medicine, University of Fribourg, Switzerland; Swiss Development Hub for Strength and Conditioning in Swimming, Swiss Aquatics - National Swimming Federation, Switzerland. Electronic address: dennis.born@swiss-aquatics.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>J Sci Med Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9812598</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1878-1861</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Career trajectories</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Competitive swimming</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elite athlete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Talent</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interest statement The authors have no conflict of interest to report that may have affected data collection, analysis, or interpretation of the present study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41651736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2026.01.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1440-2440(26)00042-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>