<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41212882</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Progressive failure mechanism and stability assessment of high-steep dangerous rock mass: A case study of Heicao dangerous rock mass.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0336115</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0336115</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0336115</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0336115</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Western Hubei Province, China, lies in the transition zone between the second and third topographic steps of China's terrain ladder system. Influenced by the deep incision of the Yangtze River and its tributaries, numerous high-steep slopes have been widely developed in this region.This study focuses on the Heicao dangerous rock mass in Xingshan County, Hubei Province. Through field investigations and Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) photogrammetry, a discrete element numerical model was developed to investigate the progressive failure mechanisms of high-steep dangerous rock masses under varying lengths of the main structural plane.This study will contribute to future prevention and control of such hazardous rock disasters.The principal conclusions are as follows: (1) The failure surface of the Heicao rock mass exhibits composite form,with the upper section displaying a polyline geometry and the lower section approximating an arc-shaped profile. (2) The main structural plane length significantly affects both the damage extent and propagation velocity in the upper rock mass. (3) Dangerous rock mass instability is jointly influenced by the basal rock mass and the overlying rock mass. Under gravity, progressive failure of the basal rock mass triggers crack development and anti-sliding force attenuation, while main structural plane propagation exacerbates damage. Ultimately, rock bridge shearing and crack coalescence lead to the formation of a progressively penetrating failure surface, resulting in global instability. (4) The results of this study have important theoretical and practical implications for future geological disaster assessment and prevention. In particular, the effective protection of the basement rock mass is the key factor to prevent the formation of dangerous rock mass disasters.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Yi et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yi</LastName><ForeName>Wu</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Geological Hazards on Three Gorges Reservoir Area (China Three Gorges University), Ministry of Education, Yichang, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering and Architecture, China Three Gorges University, Yichang, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Yihua</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-9186-2479</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Geological Hazards on Three Gorges Reservoir Area (China Three Gorges University), Ministry of Education, Yichang, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering and Architecture, China Three Gorges University, Yichang, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaohu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5028-5919</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Geological Hazards on Three Gorges Reservoir Area (China Three Gorges University), Ministry of Education, Yichang, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering and Architecture, China Three Gorges University, Yichang, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Tianzuo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Rock Mechanics and Geohazards of Zhejiang Province, Shaoxing, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deng</LastName><ForeName>Yonghuang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Provincial Geological Environment Monitoring Station, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhengyu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xingshan County Land Consolidation Center, Yichang, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008962" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Theoretical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004190" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disasters</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41212882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12599965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0336115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-37999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Huang RQ. Dynamic processes and stability control of high rock slope development. Chinese Journal of Rock Mechanics and Engineering. 2008;27(8):1525&#x2013;44. doi: 10.3321/j.issn:1000-6915.2008.08.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3321/j.issn:1000-6915.2008.08.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HK, Ouyang ZC, Liao SR. Comprehensive treatment techniques and their application for dangerous rock masses in the Three Gorges Reservoir area. Underground Space. 2002;(02):97&#x2013;101, 107&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu WH, Luo Q, Huang RQ. Classification and stability assessment of dangerous rock masses on high slopes in the dam area of the Xiluodu Hydropower Project. Advances in Science and Technology of Water Resources. 2008;(04):48&#x2013;51. doi: 10.3880/j.issn.1006-7647.2008.04.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3880/j.issn.1006-7647.2008.04.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attewell PB, Farmer IW. Principles of Engineering Geology. Dordrecht: Springer. 1976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Li B, Feng Z. Failure modes and genetic mechanisms of large-scale dangerous rock masses in thick limestone mountains at Yangjiaochang Town, Wulong County. Acta Geologica Sinica. 2015;89(02):461&#x2013;71. doi: 10.19762/j.cnki.dizhixuebao.2015.02.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19762/j.cnki.dizhixuebao.2015.02.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paronuzzi P, Bolla A, Rigo E. 3D Stress&#x2013;Strain Analysis of a Failed Limestone Wedge Influenced by an Intact Rock Bridge. Rock Mech Rock Eng. 2016;49(8):3223&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1007/s00603-016-0963-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-016-0963-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T. Discussion on the formation mechanism and instability mode of dangerous rock masses in Qingkou, Wulong, Chongqing. Journal of Geological Hazards and Prevention. 2020;31(03):50&#x2013;7. doi: 10.16031/j.cnki.issn.1003-8035.2020.03.07</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16031/j.cnki.issn.1003-8035.2020.03.07</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frayssines M, Hantz D. Modelling and back-analysing failures in steep limestone cliffs. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences. 2009;46(7):1115&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmms.2009.06.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2009.06.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jixun Z, Jiaqing S, Haibo Z, Xuhua R, Jiang Q. Study on Rock Mass Stability Criterion Based on Catastrophe Theory. Mathematical Problems in Engineering. 2015;2015:1&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1155/2015/850604</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2015/850604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong HG, Chen LD, Huang CS. Influencing factors and stability evaluation of dangerous rock masses in the Yunyang&#x2013;Jiangjin section of the Three Gorges Reservoir area. Journal of Engineering Geology. 2010;18(05):645&#x2013;50. doi: CNKI:SUN:GCDZ.0.2010-05-007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Rey I, Mu&#xf1;iz-Men&#xe9;ndez M, Moreno-Robles J. Some considerations on the role of joint spacing in rock slope stability analyses using a 3D discrete element approach. Arab J Geosci. 2022;15(21). doi: 10.1007/s12517-022-10914-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-022-10914-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B, He K, Han M, Hu X, Wu T, Wu M, et al. Dynamic process simulation of the Xiaogangjian rockslide occurred in shattered mountain based on 3DEC and DFN. Computers and Geotechnics. 2021;134:104122. doi: 10.1016/j.compgeo.2021.104122</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compgeo.2021.104122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He L, An XM, Ma GW, Zhao ZY. Development of three-dimensional numerical manifold method for jointed rock slope stability analysis. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences. 2013;64:22&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmms.2013.08.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2013.08.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An X, Ning Y, Ma G, He L. Modeling progressive failures in rock slopes with non&#x2010;persistent joints using the numerical manifold method. Num Anal Meth Geomechanics. 2013;38(7):679&#x2013;701. doi: 10.1002/nag.2226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nag.2226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang YF, Pei XJ, Cui SH. Structural characteristics of landslide boundary rock masses based on terrestrial 3D laser point cloud data. Chinese Journal of Rock Mechanics and Engineering. 2021;40(6):1209&#x2013;25. doi: 10.13722/j.cnki.jrme.2020.0835</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13722/j.cnki.jrme.2020.0835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oppikofer T, Jaboyedoff M, Pedrazzini A, Derron M, Blikra LH. Detailed DEM analysis of a rockslide scar to characterize the basal sliding surface of active rockslides. J Geophys Res. 2011;116(F2). doi: 10.1029/2010jf001807</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2010jf001807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaboyedoff M, Couture R, Locat P. Structural analysis of Turtle Mountain (Alberta) using digital elevation model: Toward a progressive failure. Geomorphology. 2008;103(1):5&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1016/j.geomorph.2008.04.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geomorph.2008.04.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge Y, Lin Z, Tang H, Zhong P, Cao B. Measurement of Particle Size of Loose Accumulation Based on Alpha Shapes (AS) and Hill Climbing-Region Growing (HC-RG) Algorithms. Sensors (Basel). 2020;20(3):883. doi: 10.3390/s20030883</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s20030883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7039390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32046026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spreafico MC, Francioni M, Cervi F, Stead D, Bitelli G, Ghirotti M, et al. Back Analysis of the 2014 San Leo Landslide Using Combined Terrestrial Laser Scanning and 3D Distinct Element Modelling. Rock Mech Rock Eng. 2016;49(6):2235&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1007/s00603-015-0763-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-015-0763-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturzenegger M, Stead D. Close-range terrestrial digital photogrammetry and terrestrial laser scanning for discontinuity characterization on rock cuts. Engineering Geology. 2009;106(3&#x2013;4):163&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1016/j.enggeo.2009.03.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enggeo.2009.03.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J, Du S, Yong R, Wang C, An P. Drone Photogrammetry for Accurate and Efficient Rock Joint Roughness Assessment on Steep and Inaccessible Slopes. Remote Sensing. 2023;15(19):4880. doi: 10.3390/rs15194880</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs15194880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang ZS, Wang SH, Wang PY. Intelligent identification and parameter extraction of surface fracture networks on rock slopes. Chinese Journal of Geotechnical Engineering. 2021;43(12):2240&#x2013;8. doi: 10.11779/CJGE202112010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11779/CJGE202112010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J, Liu J, Ming J, Sang X. Geological hazard interpretation and hazard evaluation of open pit mines based on Unmanned Aerial Vehicle images. J Phys: Conf Ser. 2021;2006(1):012072. doi: 10.1088/1742-6596/2006/1/012072</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-6596/2006/1/012072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu CL, Zhang YY, Pei XJ. Evolution characteristics of rupture surfaces in anti-dip layered slopes: centrifuge model test and numerical simulation. Hydrogeology &amp; Engineering Geology. 2024;51(1):135&#x2013;44. doi: 10.16030/j.cnki.issn.1000-3665.202210015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16030/j.cnki.issn.1000-3665.202210015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu M, Yu XY, Zhao YP. Seismic dynamic response and failure mode analysis of bedding fractured rock slopes. Rock and Soil Mechanics. 2023;44(2):362&#x2013;72. doi: 10.16285/j.rsm.2022.0438</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16285/j.rsm.2022.0438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Q, Yang Z, Zhang S, Gao Y, Jin X, Liu X, et al. Exploring the toppling deformation mechanisms and failure modes of anti-dip layered rocky slopes: insights from physical model experiments. Landslides. 2024;22(3):895&#x2013;923. doi: 10.1007/s10346-024-02405-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10346-024-02405-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho T, Suk UJ, Lee AS. Investigation of rock slope failures based on physical model study. The Journal of Engineering Geology. 2008;18(4):447&#x2013;57. doi: I410-ECN-0102-2012-480-002216287</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng YR, Zhao SY, Zhang LY. Slope stability analysis using the strength reduction finite element method. Engineering Science. 2002;4(10):57&#x2013;61. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1009-1742.2002.10.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1009-1742.2002.10.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Song Y, Lei M, Shi C, Jia C, Zhang J. Numerical Study on the Damage Characteristics of Layered Shale Using 3D DEM. KSCE Journal of Civil Engineering. 2023;27(12):5436&#x2013;47. doi: 10.1007/s12205-023-0411-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12205-023-0411-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Z, Li S, Qin Z, Zhang Q. Dual-scale 3DEC-GBM Discrete Element Simulation On Mechanical Behavior and Anisotropic Fracture Evolution Mechanism of Rock Induced by True Three-dimensional Stress. Rock Mech Rock Eng. 2024;57(5):3885&#x2013;915. doi: 10.1007/s00603-023-03754-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-023-03754-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Wu Z, Shi X, Yang L, Liu R, Lu N. Exploring mechanism of hidden, steep obliquely inclined bedding landslides using a 3DEC model: A case study of the Shanyang landslide in Shaanxi Province, China. China Geology. 2024;7(2):303&#x2013;14. doi: 10.31035/cg2024044</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31035/cg2024044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh PK, Pradhan SP. Stability Analysis of Himalayan Rock Slope Incorporating Microstructures into Rock Mass Using DEM. Geotech Geol Eng. 2025;43(2). doi: 10.1007/s10706-025-03072-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10706-025-03072-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Z, Zheng J, Zhang R, L&#xfc; Q, Tan S, Li J. A small block treatment method in three-dimensional block identification for rock block system mechanical analysis. Computers and Geotechnics. 2025;186:107385. doi: 10.1016/j.compgeo.2025.107385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compgeo.2025.107385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou WY, Yang RQ. Progressive failure and reliability analysis of dam abutment rock masses. Chinese Journal of Rock Mechanics and Engineering. 1987;(04):321&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu ZJ, Huang SP, Yang WF. Stability analysis of rock slope on toe slab of CFRD based on 3DEC. Chinese Journal of Underground Space and Engineering. 2019;15(S2):966&#x2013;77. doi: CNKI:SUN:BASE.0.2019-S2-062</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen XY, Lin YG. Study on stability analysis and reinforcement effect of rock slopes. China &amp; Foreign Highway. 2012;32(05):24&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Chen Z, Chen J, Zhu H. Automatic characterization of rock mass discontinuities using 3D point clouds. Engineering Geology. 2019;259:105131. doi: 10.1016/j.enggeo.2019.05.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enggeo.2019.05.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Zhu H, Li X. Automatic extraction of discontinuity orientation from rock mass surface 3D point cloud. Computers &amp; Geosciences. 2016;95:18&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1016/j.cageo.2016.06.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cageo.2016.06.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riquelme AJ, Abell&#xe1;n A, Tom&#xe1;s R, Jaboyedoff M. A new approach for semi-automatic rock mass joints recognition from 3D point clouds. Computers &amp; Geosciences. 2014;68:38&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1016/j.cageo.2014.03.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cageo.2014.03.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riquelme A, Tom&#xe1;s R, Cano M, Pastor JL, Abell&#xe1;n A. Automatic Mapping of Discontinuity Persistence on Rock Masses Using 3D Point Clouds. Rock Mech Rock Eng. 2018;51(10):3005&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1007/s00603-018-1519-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-018-1519-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li SZ, Sha P, Wu FQ. Anisotropic deformation characteristics of layered rock masses. Rock and Soil Mechanics. 2018;39(S2):366&#x2013;73. doi: CNKI:SUN:YTLX.0.2018-S2-052</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YZ, Yuan L, Zhang QH. True triaxial experimental study on rockburst characteristics of rock masses with structural planes. Chinese Journal of Rock Mechanics and Engineering. 2024;43(1):120&#x2013;32. doi: 10.13722/j.cnki.jrme.2023.0133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13722/j.cnki.jrme.2023.0133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan GQ. Study on deterioration evolution and failure mechanism of typical limestone bedding slopes in the Three Gorges Reservoir Area. China University of Geosciences (Wuhan). 2022. doi: 10.27492/d.cnki.gzdzu.2022.000230</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.27492/d.cnki.gzdzu.2022.000230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun GZ, Sun Y. Principles of rock mechanics (in Chinese). Beijing: Science Press. 2011.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>