<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41284089</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2730-6011</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Discover oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Discov Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A bibliometric study on microenvironment-mediated drug resistance in interventional liver cancer treatment.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2157</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2157</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2157</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12672-025-03760-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Microenvironment-driven drug resistance is a principal barrier to durable response after transarterial chemoembolisation, ablation or radioembolisation for hepatocellular carcinoma, yet the global structure of scholarship linking these domains remains undefined. This bibliometric analysis mapped 25-year publication trends, thematic evolution and collaboration networks at the intersection of interventional oncology, tumour microenvironment and therapeutic resistance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Web of Science Core Collection was searched (1 January 2000&#x2013;31 December 2024) for records simultaneously referencing liver cancer, interventional therapy, microenvironmental descriptors and resistance terms. After dual-review screening, 939 articles and reviews were retained. Annual output, citation impact and Bradford-zone distributions were generated with bibliometrix 4.2.1. Bradford-zone analysis refers to the distribution of journal productivity, with journals in the first zone representing core literature, and those in subsequent zones reflecting peripheral or niche studies. This method helps assess the concentration of research in key journals and identifies areas of growth in the literature; co-authorship, journal-coupling and keyword-co-occurrence networks were rendered in VOSviewer 1.6.20. Workflow reproducibility was confirmed on a 5% subsample and by comparing fractional with full counting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Yearly publications rose from two in 2000 to 130 in 2024, amassing 36 095 citations (mean 38.4 per item). Output spikes in 2013, 2019 and 2021 paralleled seminal reports on hypoxia-driven angiogenesis, CAF activation, and COVID-19-related endothelial dysfunction. The pathophysiological mechanisms of COVID-19-induced endothelial injury, including cytokine-mediated endothelial dysfunction, have been implicated in compromising loco-regional therapies, contributing to resistance mechanisms that affect the efficacy of embolic treatments. China produced 47.3% of documents and sat at the nexus of global collaboration, with prominent links to the United States, Japan and South Korea. Cancer Research, Hepatology and Journal of Hepatology led citation rankings. Keyword overlays revealed a chronological shift from procedure-centric terms to microenvironmental and immunologic nodes&#x2014;&#x201c;angiogenesis&#x201d;, &#x201c;immune checkpoint&#x201d;, &#x201c;nanoparticles&#x201d;&#x2014;after 2017. Trend-topic mapping documented a transition from device optimisation toward mechanism-informed combination regimens incorporating anti-VEGF or PD-1 blockade.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Research on microenvironment-mediated resistance in interventional liver-cancer therapy has expanded rapidly and pivoted toward molecularly targeted, immune-augmented strategies, driven chiefly by high-volume Chinese centres and trans-Pacific partnerships. Priorities now include single-cell analytics, radiomics-guided adaptive embolisation and multinational trials of combination therapy.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Qiang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interventional Medical Center, The Second People's Hospital of Yibin, Yibin, 644000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Xu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interventional Medical Center, The Second People's Hospital of Yibin, Yibin, 644000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Guo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interventional Medical Center, The Second People's Hospital of Yibin, Yibin, 644000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yaoyong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interventional Medical Center, The Second People's Hospital of Yibin, Yibin, 644000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yue</LastName><ForeName>Quanji</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interventional Medical Center, The Second People's Hospital of Yibin, Yibin, 644000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zhongyao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interventional Medical Center, The Second People's Hospital of Yibin, Yibin, 644000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yanjie</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interventional Medical Center, The Second People's Hospital of Yibin, Yibin, 644000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interventional Medical Center, The Second People's Hospital of Yibin, Yibin, 644000, China. 13890960428@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Discov Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101775142</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2730-6011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drug resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hepatocellular carcinoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Interventional oncology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Single-cell sequencing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spatial transcriptomics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tumour microenvironment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Informed consent: Informed consent was obtained from all patients included in this study prior to submission of data. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41284089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12644389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12672-025-03760-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s12672-025-03760-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bray F, Laversanne M, Sung H, et al. Global cancer statistics 2022: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. Cancer J Clin. 2024;74(3):229&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38572751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangro B, Kudo M, Erinjeri JP, et al. Durvalumab with or without bevacizumab with transarterial chemoembolisation in hepatocellular carcinoma (EMERALD-1): a multiregional, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 study. Lancet. 2025;405(10474):216&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(24)02551-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12282661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39798579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Liu X, Liu J, et al. Lenvatinib in combination with transarterial chemoembolization vs. sorafenib in combination with transarterial chemoembolization for unresectable hepatocellular carcinoma: A network meta-analysis. Oncol Lett. 2024;28(2):347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ol.2024.14480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11170262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38872858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo DZ, Zhang X, Zhang SQ, et al. Single-cell tumor heterogeneity landscape of hepatocellular carcinoma: unraveling the pro-metastatic subtype and its interaction loop with fibroblasts. Mol Cancer. 2024;23(1):157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12943-024-02062-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11295380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39095854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning J, Ye Y, Shen H et al. Macrophage-coated tumor cluster aggravates hepatoma invasion and immunotherapy resistance via generating local immune deprivation. Cell Rep Med, 2024, 5(5).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11148514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38614095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartnik K, Krzyzi&#x144;ski M, Bartczak T, et al. A novel radiomics approach for predicting TACE outcomes in hepatocellular carcinoma patients using deep learning for multi-organ segmentation. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):14779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-65630-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11208561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38926517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Q, Zhang Q, Chen YQ, et al. Risk factors for the development of hepatocellular carcinoma in chengdu: a prospective cohort study. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2022;26(24):9447&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36591853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung SW, Kim JS, Choi WM, et al. Synergistic effects of transarterial chemoembolization and lenvatinib on HIF-1&#x3b1; ubiquitination and prognosis improvement in hepatocellular carcinoma. Clin Cancer Res. 2025;31(10):2046&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-24-1228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39992640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin Y, Maggio A, Hawkins D, et al. Whole-genome bisulfite sequencing data analysis learning module on Google cloud platform. Brief Bioinform. 2024;25(Supplement1):bbae236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bib/bbae236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11264297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39041913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung HW, Leung C, O N, Lau EY, et al. EPHB2 activates &#x3b2;-catenin to enhance cancer stem cell properties and drive Sorafenib resistance in hepatocellular carcinoma. Cancer Res. 2021;81(12):3229&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-21-0184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33903122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi H, Huang J, Yan Y, et al. Unraveling the role of disulfidptosis-related LncRNAs in colon cancer: a prognostic indicator for immunotherapy response, chemotherapy sensitivity, and insights into cell death mechanisms. Front Mol Biosci. 2023;10:1254232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmolb.2023.1254232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10617599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37916187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng AL, Qin S, Ikeda M, et al. Updated efficacy and safety data from IMbrave150: Atezolizumab plus bevacizumab vs. sorafenib for unresectable hepatocellular carcinoma. J Hepatol. 2022;76(4):862&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2021.11.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34902530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung CON, Yang Y, Leung RWH, et al. Broad-spectrum Kinome profiling identifies CDK6 upregulation as a driver of lenvatinib resistance in hepatocellular carcinoma. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):6699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-42360-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10593849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37872167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song G, Peng G, Zhang J, et al. Uncovering the potential role of oxidative stress in the development of periodontitis and Establishing a stable diagnostic model via combining single-cell and machine learning analysis. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1181467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1181467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10355807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37475857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu R, Liu J, Cao Q, et al. Identification of crucial genes through WGCNA in the progression of gastric cancer. J Cancer. 2024;15(11):3284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/jca.95757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11134444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38817876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, et al. Deciphering the role of acetylation-related gene NAT10 in colon cancer progression and immune evasion: implications for overcoming drug resistance. Discov Oncol. 2025;16(1):774. 10.1007/s12672-025-02617-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2024.06.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12081795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40374962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Z, Ma M, Han X, et al. Idarubicin-loaded biodegradable microspheres enhance sensitivity to anti-PD1 immunotherapy in transcatheter arterial chemoembolization of hepatocellular carcinoma. Acta Biomater. 2023;157:337&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actbio.2022.12.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36509402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L, et al. The key role of COA6 in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma: metabolic reprogramming and regulation of the immune microenvironment. J Cell Mol Med. 2025;29(13):e70685. 10.1111/jcmm.70685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1265959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12213452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40596639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Shi J, Mi L, et al. Identification and validation of a lenvatinib resistance-related prognostic signature in HCC, in which PFKFB4 contributes to tumor progression and lenvatinib resistance. BMC Gastroenterol. 2025;25(1):287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12876-025-03861-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12020327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40269756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Guo L, Su K et al. Construction and validation of TACE therapeutic efficacy by ALR score and nomogram: a large, multicenter study. J Hepatocellular Carcinoma, 2023: 1009&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10317537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37405321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M, Hui KM, Shi M, et al. Differential expression of hepatic cancer stemness and hypoxia markers in residual cancer after locoregional therapies for hepatocellular carcinoma. Hepatol Commun. 2022;6(11):3247&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep4.2079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9592798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36097402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim M, Franses JW, Imperial R, et al. EGFR/ERBB2 amplifications and alterations associated with resistance to lenvatinib in hepatocellular carcinoma. Gastroenterology. 2023;164(6):1006&#x2013;8. e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2023.01.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36708791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P, Zhang H, Tang J, et al. The integrated single-cell analysis developed an Immunogenic cell death signature to predict lung adenocarcinoma prognosis and immunotherapy. Aging. 2023;15(19):10305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/aging.205077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10599752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37796202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu B, Zou T, Qin W, et al. Inhibition of EGFR overcomes acquired lenvatinib resistance driven by STAT3&#x2013;ABCB1 signaling in hepatocellular carcinoma. Cancer Res. 2022;82(20):3845&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-21-4140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9574378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36066408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan K, Zhao S, Ye B, et al. A novel T-cell exhaustion-related feature can accurately predict the prognosis of OC patients. Front Pharmacol. 2023;14:1192777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2023.1192777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10239809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37284314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Q, Zhang Q, Zhou KX, et al. Lung cancer screening study from a smoking population in Kunming. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2022;26(19):7091&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36263557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin ZC, Chen JJ, Zhu XL et al. Immune checkpoint inhibitors and anti-vascular endothelial growth factor antibody/tyrosine kinase inhibitors with or without transarterial chemoembolization as first-line treatment for advanced hepatocellular carcinoma (CHANCE2201): a target trial emulation study. EClinicalMedicine, 2024, 72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11090892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38745965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Zhang Q, Cui Y et al. TRACE model: predicting treatment response to transarterial chemoembolization in unresectable hepatocellular carcinoma. J Hepatocellular Carcinoma, 2025: 193&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11787783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39896274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Gao Z, Mohd-Ibrahim I, et al. Pan&#x2010;cancer analyses of bromodomain containing 9 as a novel therapeutic target reveals its diagnostic, prognostic potential and biological mechanism in human tumours. Clin Translational Med. 2024;14(2):e1543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ctm2.1543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10835192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38303608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JX, Cheng Y, Wei J, et al. Transarterial chemoembolization combined with tyrosine kinase inhibitors plus immune checkpoint inhibitors versus tyrosine kinase inhibitors plus immune checkpoint inhibitors in unresectable hepatocellular carcinoma with first-or lower-order portal vein tumor thrombosis. Cardiovasc Interv Radiol. 2024;47(6):751&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00270-024-03724-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38671322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball&#x131; HT, Aikimbaev K, Burak &#x130;G, et al. Short-term changes of angiogenesis factors after transarterial radioembolization in hepatocellular carcinoma patients. Diagn Interventional Radiol. 2023;29(5):704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4274/dir.2021.211255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10679548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36994546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang C, Zhang S, Jiang L, et al. Precision unveiled: synergistic genomic landscapes in breast cancer&#x2014;Integrating single-cell analysis and decoding drug toxicity for elite prognostication and tailored therapeutics. Environ Toxicol. 2024;39(6):3448&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tox.24205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38450906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu D, Zhou L, Zuo Z et al. MRI radiomics to predict early treatment response to TACE combined with lenvatinib plus a PD-1 inhibitor for hepatocellular carcinoma with portal vein tumor thrombus. J Hepatocellular Carcinoma, 2025: 985&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12094907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40406667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu HD, Li HL, Huang MS et al. Transarterial chemoembolization with PD-(L) 1 inhibitors plus molecular targeted therapies for hepatocellular carcinoma (CHANCE001). Signal Transduct. Target. Ther. 2023;8(1): 58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9905571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36750721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>You Y, Chen Y, Zhang Q, et al. Systematic and meta-based evaluation of the relationship between the built environment and physical activity behaviors among older adults. PeerJ. 2023;11:e16173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.16173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10538293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37780389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Z, Wang Y, Jiang D, et al. PD1&#x2009;+&#x2009;Treg cell remodeling promotes immune homeostasis within peripheral blood and tumor microenvironment after microparticles-transarterial chemoembolization in hepatocellular carcinoma. Cancer Immunol Immunother. 2025;74(3):109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00262-025-03962-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11822157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39937280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto E, Pelizzaro F, Cardin R, et al. HIF-1&#x3b1; and VEGF as prognostic biomarkers in hepatocellular carcinoma patients treated with transarterial chemoembolization. Dig Liver Disease. 2024;56(5):872&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dld.2023.09.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37783655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuehu DL, Fu Y, Nasu M et al. Use of microalgae-derived astaxanthin to improve cytoprotective capacity in the ileum of heat-induced oxidative stressed broilers. Animals, 2024, 14(13): 1932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11240551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38998041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, et al. Early-life undernutrition, immune dysregulation, and cancer incidence in later life: a national life-course analysis from the China health and retirement longitudinal study. Front Immunol. 2025;16:1602290. 10.3389/fimmu.2025.1602290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2024.1371682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12420247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40936900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kudo M, Ren Z, Guo Y, et al. Transarterial chemoembolisation combined with lenvatinib plus pembrolizumab versus dual placebo for unresectable, non-metastatic hepatocellular carcinoma (LEAP-012): a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, phase 3 study. Lancet. 2025;405(10474):203&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(24)02575-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39798578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>