<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41474799</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Analysis of bearing mechanism of large-diameter under-reamed piles based on model tests.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0338899</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0338899</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0338899</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0338899</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Given the insufficient understanding of the bearing mechanism and failure modes of large-diameter under-reamed piles in complex strata, this study conducted scaled laboratory model tests based on similarity theory. A visualized "semi-model pile static loading-reaction frame" system was established to systematically investigate the influence of under-reaming angle (0&#xb0;&#x2009;~&#x2009;25&#xb0;) and pile embedment depth (60&#x2009;~&#x2009;80&#x2009;cm) on the bearing characteristics and failure mechanisms of the pile foundation. The results show that: 1) The under-reaming angle is the dominant factor controlling bearing performance. A reasonable increase in this angle can significantly enhance the ultimate bearing capacity, with a 204.99% improvement observed at 20&#xb0; compared to the uniform-section pile. However, the enhancement effect weakens with increasing embedment depth. Comprehensive analysis suggests that 15&#xb0;&#x2009;~&#x2009;20&#xb0; is the optimal under-reaming angle range; an excessive angle induces stress concentration at the "shoulder" of the pile, leading to interfacial detachment between pile and soil, thus limiting further improvement in bearing capacity. 2) The under-reamed structure effectively optimizes the load transfer path along the pile shaft. The end bearing resistance ratio increases first and then decreases with the under-reaming angle, reaching a maximum of 65.09% at 20&#xb0;, indicating a transition of the load transfer mechanism from shaft-resistance-dominated to end-resistance-dominated behavior. 3) The failure morphology of the pile toe rock evolves from "penetrative shear failure" in the uniform pile (failure zone&#x2009;&#x2248;&#x2009;1.25D) to "fan-shaped compaction" at the optimal under-reaming angle (&#x2248; 4D), and further enlarging the angle results in unstable "bulging and collapse" failure. This study systematically reveals the full-process mechanism from load bearing to failure in large-diameter under-reamed piles, providing a theoretical basis for optimizing design parameters and predicting failure behavior. The findings offer valuable references for engineering design and improvement of design codes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Zhou et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Jianhua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Civil Engineering College, Liaoning Technical University, Fuxin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Railway Engineering College, Liaoning Railway Vocational and Technical College, Jinzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5576-0208</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Civil Engineering College, Liaoning Technical University, Fuxin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gong</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shen Kan Engineering &amp; Technology Corporation, MCC, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Shuhai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Natural Resources Science and Technology, Xinjiang University of Technology, Hotan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Heping</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Railway Engineering College, Liaoning Railway Vocational and Technical College, Jinzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012987">Soil</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008962" MajorTopicYN="Y">Models, Theoretical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003252" MajorTopicYN="Y">Construction Materials</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013314" MajorTopicYN="N">Stress, Mechanical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012987" MajorTopicYN="N">Soil</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41474799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12755750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0338899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-56067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abdelgwad A, Nasr A, Azzam W. Utilization of enlarged base to improve the uplift capacity of single pile in sand&#x2014;model study. Innov Infrastruct Solut. 2022;7(5). doi: 10.1007/s41062-022-00922-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41062-022-00922-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulos HG, Randolph MF. Pile Group Analysis: A Study of Two Methods. J Geotech Engrg. 1983;109(3):355&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1061/(asce)0733-9410(1983)109:3(355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(asce)0733-9410(1983)109:3(355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He S, Lai J, Li Y, Wang K, Wang L, Zhang W. Pile group response induced by adjacent shield tunnelling in clay: Scale model test and numerical simulation. Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology. 2022;120:104039. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2021.104039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2021.104039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Zhong Z, He G, Liu X. Response of the ground and adjacent end-bearing piles due to side-by-side twin tunnelling in compound rock strata. Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology. 2019;89:91&#x2013;108. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2019.03.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2019.03.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng GH, Zhou XQ, He QL, Xu CJ. Analysis on the influence of isolation pile on horizontal displacement of adjacent pile under high-speed railway caused by shield driving. Journal of Civil and Environmental Engineering. 2020;42(4):28&#x2013;35. doi: 10.11835/j.issn.2096-6717.2020.033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11835/j.issn.2096-6717.2020.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasr AM, Azzam WR, Khater AI. Experimental studies on the response of single-finned pile under combined vertical-torsional loads in sand. Geomechanics and Geoengineering. 2024;19(4):586&#x2013;604. doi: 10.1080/17486025.2023.2296060</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17486025.2023.2296060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Gao GY. Size effect of large-diameter belled piles. Chinese Journal of Geotechnical Engineering. 2011;33(S2):83&#x2013;7. doi: 10.13206/j.cnki.ytgc.2011.s2.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13206/j.cnki.ytgc.2011.s2.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao CF, Lu J, Sun QC, Zhu T, Li SF. Experimental study of load transmission property of large-diameter bored cast-in-situ deep and long pile in different soil layers. Chinese Journal of Rock Mechanics and Engineering. 2009;28(5):987&#x2013;96. doi: 10.13206/j.cnki.yslx.2009.05.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13206/j.cnki.yslx.2009.05.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W, Liu B, Zhou YQ. Study on model test of super large diameter rock-socketed pile with belled shaft. Journal of Safety Science and Technology. 2017;13(7):7&#x2013;12. doi: 10.13206/j.cnki.ldbk.2017.07.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13206/j.cnki.ldbk.2017.07.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang QQ, Li SC, Li LP, Chen YJ. Resistance hardening simplified method for settlement prediction of pile groups considering skin friction softening and end bearing. Chinese Journal of Rock Mechanics and Engineering. 2013;32(3):615&#x2013;24. doi: 10.13206/j.cnki.yslx.2013.03.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13206/j.cnki.yslx.2013.03.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao MH, Liu S, Yin PB, Liu M. Settlement calculation method of piles considering effect of initial critical friction on pile-soil interface. Journal of Central South University (Science and Technology). 2013;44(8):3425&#x2013;31. doi: 10.13206/j.cnki.zngd.2013.08.046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13206/j.cnki.zngd.2013.08.046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vali R, Mehrinejad Khotbehsara E, Saberian M, Li J, Mehrinejad M, Jahandari S. A three-dimensional numerical comparison of bearing capacity and settlement of tapered and under-reamed piles. International Journal of Geotechnical Engineering. 2019;13(3):236&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1080/19386362.2017.1336586</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19386362.2017.1336586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moayedi H, Mosallanezhad M. Uplift resistance of belled and multi-belled piles in loose sand. Measurement. 2017;109:346&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2017.06.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2017.06.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamderi M. Comprehensive group pile settlement formula based on 3D finite element analyses. Soils and Foundations. 2018;58(1):1&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1016/j.sandf.2017.11.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sandf.2017.11.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao D, Zhao K, Ma B, Han Z, Fan J. Research on the bearing behavior of single pile in self-weight collapsible loess areas. PLoS One. 2023;18(8):e0290878. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0290878</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0290878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10470878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37651427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CJ, Zhang QQ, Liang FY, Zhang Q, Liu HL. Analysis of bearing behavior of a single pile considering progressive failure of pile-soil system. Rock and Soil Mechanics. 2014;35(4):1131&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Chen CR, Zhou ZJ, Lei JT. Distribution of additional stress of rotary squeeze cast-in-place piles in loess area and settlement calculation. Science Technology and Engineering. 2021;21(16):6848&#x2013;56. doi: 10.13206/j.cnki.kxjs.2021.16.046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13206/j.cnki.kxjs.2021.16.046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowthaman S, Nasvi MCM. Three - dimensional Numerical Simulation and Validation of Load-settlement Behaviour of a Pile Group under Compressive Loading. Engineer. 2018;51(1):9. doi: 10.4038/engineer.v51i1.7283</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4038/engineer.v51i1.7283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Jeremi&#x107; B. Numerical analysis of pile behaviour under lateral loads in layered elastic&#x2013;plastic soils. Num Anal Meth Geomechanics. 2002;26(14):1385&#x2013;406. doi: 10.1002/nag.250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nag.250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasr AM, Azzam WR, Harran IS. Geometrical Effect of Under-reamed Pile in Clay under Compression Load Numerical-Study. adv in geol and geotech eng res. 2023;5(1):1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.30564/agger.v5i1.5276</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30564/agger.v5i1.5276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong JR, Lin ST, Dai YM. Load transfer behavior of large-diameter bored piles. Chinese Journal of Geotechnical Engineering. 1994;16(6):123&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1007/BF02591029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02591029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu XK, Shui WH, Chen GD. Vertical bearing capacity of super-long bored piles in soft soil area. Chinese Journal of Geotechnical Engineering. 2011;33(2):502&#x2013;7. doi: 10.13206/j.cnki.ytgc.2011.s2.099</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13206/j.cnki.ytgc.2011.s2.099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu QH, Xie XY. Experimental study on bearing capacity behavior of deep large-diameter cast-in-place belled pile. Journal of Building Structures. 2009;30(4):151&#x2013;7. doi: 10.14006/j.jzjgxb.2009.04.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14006/j.jzjgxb.2009.04.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao G, Gao M, Chen Q, Yang J. Field Load Testing Study of Vertical Bearing Behavior of a Large Diameter Belled Cast-in-Place Pile. KSCE Journal of Civil Engineering. 2019;23(5):2009&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1007/s12205-019-2065-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12205-019-2065-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Li KX, Wang JL. The research on metro station scheduling optimization based on improved critical chain technology. J Zhengzhou Univ (Eng Sci). 2012;33(5):22&#x2013;9. doi: 10.13206/j.cnki.zzgy.2012.05.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13206/j.cnki.zzgy.2012.05.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd HJ, Beuckelaers WJAP, Byrne BW, Gavin KG, Houlsby GT, Igoe DJP, et al. New data analysis methods for instrumented medium-scale monopile field tests. G&#xe9;otechnique. 2020;70(11):961&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1680/jgeot.18.pisa.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1680/jgeot.18.pisa.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Huang Z, Hu R, Bai L, Zheng J, Chen Y, et al. Numerical simulation analysis of pile-soil interaction under earthquake action. PLoS One. 2025;20(3):e0312689. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0312689</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0312689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11892883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40063625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Yang JJ, Song Q, Sun T. Compressive model test and particle flow simulation of single pile in multi-layer sand foundation. Periodical of Ocean University of China. 2020;50(2):116&#x2013;25. doi: 10.16441/j.cnki.hdxb.20190048</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16441/j.cnki.hdxb.20190048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Yang JJ, Song Q, Sun T. Study on discrete element particle flow of multi-layered ground-based expanded bottom uplift pile. Journal of Central South University (Science and Technology). 2019;50(11):2859&#x2013;69. doi: 10.11817/j.issn.1672-7207.2019.11.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11817/j.issn.1672-7207.2019.11.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Q, Yang JJ, Sun T, Li F, Yang NY. Model tests on bearing behavior of dynamic deformation process of uplift piles with enlarged base. Periodical of Ocean University of China. 2021;51(5):105&#x2013;12. doi: 10.16441/j.cnki.hdxb.20180331</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16441/j.cnki.hdxb.20180331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu GM, Zhang WM. Study on particle size effect and boundary effect in centrifugal model. Chinese Journal of Geotechnical Engineering. 1996;18(3):80&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang XL, Gu SD, Ren YQ, Gong WM. Small-scale model tests of lateral bearing capacity of steel pipe in sand. Journal of Forestry Engineering. 2020;5(2):164&#x2013;70. doi: 10.13360/j.issn.2096-1359.201901022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13360/j.issn.2096-1359.201901022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang FY, Yao GS, Chen HB, Li JP. Model tests on behavior of axially loaded piles subjected to lateral soil movement. Chinese Journal of Geotechnical Engineering. 2010;32(10):1603&#x2013;9. doi: 10.13206/j.cnki.ytgc.2010.10.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13206/j.cnki.ytgc.2010.10.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao GS, Liang FY, Li JP, Zhang W, Chen HB. Numerical analysis for behavior of axially loaded pile subjected to lateral soil movement. Journal of Tongji University (Natural Science). 2011;39(1):1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.13206/j.cnki.tjdz.2011.01.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13206/j.cnki.tjdz.2011.01.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y. Est principle of similitude model. Beijing: People&#x2019;s Transportation Press Co., Ltd. 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JX, Wu DY, Du HJ. Testing study on bearing behaviours and failure mode of rock-socketed pile. Chinese Journal of Rock Mechanics and Engineering. 2004;23(2):320&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JX, Wu DY. Research on interaction between end resistance and shaft resistance of pile. Rock and Soil Mechanics. 2008;29(2):541&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S, Zhang HL, Sun YX, Zhang ZH. Research and development of bedrock similar material in karst area. Chinese Journal of Underground Space and Engineering. 2012;8(6):1159&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong XB, Yang MH, Zhao MH, Yin PB, Zhang XW. Load-bearing mechanism model test for bridge pile foundation in high-steep transverse slope. China Journal of Highway and Transport. 2013;26(2):56&#x2013;62. doi: 10.19721/j.cnki.1001-7372.2013.02.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19721/j.cnki.1001-7372.2013.02.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng YS, Wu AL, Chen Z, Zhuang ZY, Zhao HL, Song Q. Static load test of belled pile raft foundation. Engineering Journal of Wuhan University. 2025;1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China. Technical code for testing of building foundation piles (JGJ 106-2014). Beijing: China Architecture &amp; Building Press. 2014.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>