<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41748574</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Millennial land carbon emissions in China offset by carbon sinks of the past four decades.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-70049-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>China experienced substantial millennial-scale climate and anthropogenic land use changes, yet their combined impacts on land carbon dynamics remain largely unexamined. Here, we quantify spatiotemporal changes in terrestrial organic carbon over 851-2022 using a land surface model driven by reconstructed climate and land cover forcings. Simulated results show China's pre-industrial millennial land carbon dynamics aligned with global carbon stock and atmospheric CO<sub>2</sub> fluctuations, such as the ~284 ppm peak in the 12th century linked to land use during the Medieval Climate Anomaly-warmed Song Dynasty. Notably, China's total land carbon emissions (13&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.5 PgC) accounted for 22% of global land carbon emissions during 1700-1900, with Northeast and Southwest China experiencing the largest historical land carbon losses from intensive deforestation. Nevertheless, the 17.0&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.7 PgC emissions during 851-1980 were fully offset by rapid carbon sinks over 1980-2022, driven by CO<sub>2</sub> fertilization and large-scale afforestation. These findings provide insights into China's historical land&#xa0;carbon dynamics, their underlying drivers, and global implications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Weizhe</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5126-3810</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Geomicrobiology and Environmental Changes, Hubei Key Laboratory of Critical Zone Evolution, School of Earth and Planetary Sciences, China University of Geosciences, Wuhan, China. wzchen@cug.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ciais</LastName><ForeName>Philippe</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8560-4943</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire des Sciences du Climat et de l'Environnement, LSCE/IPSL, CEA-CNRS-UVSQ, Universit&#xe9; Paris-Saclay, Gif-sur-Yvette, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Kailiang</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0145-0356</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ecosystem Network Observation and Modeling, Institute of Geographic Sciences and Natural Resources Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Viovy</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9197-6417</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire des Sciences du Climat et de l'Environnement, LSCE/IPSL, CEA-CNRS-UVSQ, Universit&#xe9; Paris-Saclay, Gif-sur-Yvette, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Shicheng</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6296-636X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Key Laboratory of Environment and Culture in Yangtze Regions, Department of Land Resource Management, School of Public Administration, China University of Geosciences, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Liangcheng</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1932-7102</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Loess Science, Institute of Earth Environment, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>42307556, 42230208</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>42325705</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41748574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-70049-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-70049-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Meinshausen, M. et al. Historical greenhouse gas concentrations for climate modelling (CMIP6). Geosci. Model Dev. 10, 2057&#x2013;2116 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubino, M. et al. Revised records of atmospheric trace gases CO2, CH4, N2O, and &#x3b4;13C-CO2 over the last 2000 years from Law Dome, Antarctica. Earth Syst. Sci. Data 11, 473&#x2013;492 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauska, T. K. et al. Links between atmospheric carbon dioxide, the land carbon reservoir and climate over the past millennium. Nat. Geosci. 8, 383&#x2013;387 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legrain, E. et al. Centennial-scale variations in the carbon cycle enhanced by high obliquity. Nat. Geosci. 17, 1154&#x2013;1161 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubino, M. et al. Low atmospheric CO2 levels during the Little Ice Age due to cooling-induced terrestrial uptake. Nat. Geosci. 9, 691&#x2013;694 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan, J. O. et al. Holocene carbon emissions as a result of anthropogenic land cover change. Holocene 21, 775&#x2013;791 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan, J. O. Climate or humans? Nat. Geosci. 8, 335&#x2013;336 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, F., Dong, G. P., Wu, P. F. &amp; He, F. N. Stylized facts of past 1000-year of China&#x2019;s cropland changes. Land Use Policy 144, 107258 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia, X. et al. The carbon budget of China: 1980-2021. Sci. Bull. (Beijing) 69, 114&#x2013;124 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao, Z. M. et al. Growing biomass carbon stock in China driven by expansion and conservation of woody areas. Nat. Geosci. 17, 1127&#x2013;1134 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, K. et al. Carbon storage through China&#x2019;s planted forest expansion. Nat. Commun. 15, 4106 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, X. X. et al. Forest Areas in China are recovering since the 21st century. Geophys. Res. Lett. 51, https://doi.org/10.1029/2024GL110312 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, F., Yang, F. &amp; Wang, Y. Reconstructing forest and grassland cover changes in China over the past millennium. Sci. China Earth Sci. 68, 94&#x2013;110 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis, E. C. et al. People have shaped most of terrestrial nature for at least 12,000 years. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 118, e2023483118 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurtt, G. C. et al. Harmonization of global land use change and management for the period 850-2100 (LUH2) for CMIP6. Geosci. Model Dev. 13, 5425&#x2013;5464 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein Goldewijk, K., Beusen, A., Doelman, J. &amp; Stehfest, E. Anthropogenic land use estimates for the Holocene &#x2013; HYDE 3.2. Earth Syst. Sci. Data 9, 927&#x2013;953 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedlingstein, P. et al. Global carbon budget 2023. Earth Syst. Sci. Data. 15, 5301&#x2013;5369 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, F., He, F., Li, M. &amp; Li, S. Evaluating the reliability of global historical land use scenarios for forest data in China. J. Geog. Sci. 30, 1083&#x2013;1094 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, Z., Jin, X. B., Miao, L. J. &amp; Yang, X. H. A historical reconstruction of cropland in China from 1900 to 2016. Earth Syst. Sci. Data. 13, 3203&#x2013;3218 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia, X. et al. Reconstructing long-term forest cover in china by fusing national forest inventory and 20 land use and land cover data sets. J. Geophys. Res.: Biogeosci. 128, e2022JG007101 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S. C., He, F. N. &amp; Zhang, X. Z. A spatially explicit reconstruction of cropland cover in China from 1661 to 1996. Reg. Environ. Change 16, 417&#x2013;428 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, F. N., Li, S. C. &amp; Zhang, X. Z. A spatially explicit reconstruction of forest cover in China over 1700-2000. Glob. Planet. Change 131, 73&#x2013;81 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X. H. et al. Reconstructing the spatial pattern of historical forest land in China in the past 300 years. Glob. Planet. Change 165, 173&#x2013;185 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, F., Yang, F., Zhao, C., Li, S. &amp; Li, M. Spatially explicit reconstruction of cropland cover for China over the past millennium. Sci. China Earth Sci. 66, 111&#x2013;128 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X. et al. Carbon emissions induced by farmland expansion in China during the past 300 years. Sci. China Earth Sci. 62, 423&#x2013;437 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, F., He, F., Li, S., Li, M. &amp; Wu, P. A new estimation of carbon emissions from land use and land cover change in China over the past 300 years. Sci. Total Environ. 863, 160963 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. et al. Field-experiment constraints on the enhancement of the terrestrial carbon sink by CO2 fertilization. Nat. Geosci. 12, 809&#x2013;814 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PAGES2k Consortium. Consistent multi-decadal variability in global temperature reconstructions and simulations over the Common Era. Nat. Geosci. 12, 643&#x2013;649 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, W. Y. et al. Impacts of major volcanic eruptions over the past two millennia on both global and Chinese climates: A review. Sci. China-Earth Sci. 67, 61&#x2013;78 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc;cke, L. J., Schurer, A. P., Wilson, R. &amp; Hegerl, G. C. Orbital Forcing Strongly Influences Seasonal Temperature Trends During the Last Millennium. Geophys. Res. Lett. 48, https://doi.org/10.1029/2024GL110312 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, X. C., Jiang, D. B. &amp; Lang, X. M. A multi-model analysis of &#x2018;Little Ice Age&#x2019; climate over China. Holocene 29, 592&#x2013;605 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge, Q., Hao, Z., Zheng, J. &amp; Shao, X. Temperature changes over the past 2000 yr in China and comparison with the Northern Hemisphere. Clim 9, 1153&#x2013;1160 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, F., Yang, B. &amp; Von Gunten, L. Preliminary multiproxy surface air temperature field reconstruction for China over the past millennium. Sci. China Earth Sci. 55, 2058&#x2013;2067 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otto-Bliesner, B. L. et al. Climate variability and change since 850 ce: an ensemble approach with the community earth system model. Bull. Am. Meteorol. Soc. 97, 735&#x2013;754 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan, J. H. et al. Dramatic weakening of the East Asian summer monsoon in northern China during the transition from the Medieval Warm Period to the Little Ice Age. Geology 48, 307&#x2013;312 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jungclaus, J. H. et al. The PMIP4 contribution to CMIP6-Part 3: The last millennium, scientific objective, and experimental design for the PMIP4 past1000 simulations. Geosci. Model Dev. 10, 4005&#x2013;4033 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, Z. L., Hakim, G. J. &amp; Steig, E. J. Coupled seasonal data assimilation of sea ice, ocean, and atmospheric dynamics over the last millennium. J. Clim. 38, 7229&#x2013;7247 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, Z. et al. Forest expansion dominates China&#x2019;s land carbon sink since 1980. Nat. Commun. 13, 5374 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris, I., Osborn, T. J., Jones, P. &amp; Lister, D. Version 4 of the CRU TS monthly high-resolution gridded multivariate climate dataset. Sci. Data 7, 109 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, X. B. et al. Farmland dataset reconstruction and farmland change analysis in China during 1661-1985. J. Geog. Sci. 25, 1058&#x2013;1074 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, X. J. et al. Mapping Chinese annual gross primary productivity with eddy covariance measurements and machine learning. Sci. Total Environ. 857, 159390 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, Y. et al. Spatiotemporal pattern of gross primary productivity and its covariation with climate in China over the last thirty years. Glob. Change Biol. 24, 184&#x2013;196 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, W. et al. Global estimates of evapotranspiration and gross primary production based on MODIS and global meteorology data. Remote Sens. Environ. 114, 1416&#x2013;1431 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piao, S. L., He, Y., Wang, X. H. &amp; Chen, F. H. Estimation of China&#x2019;s terrestrial ecosystem carbon sink: Methods, progress and prospects. Sci. China-Earth Sci. 65, 641&#x2013;651 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, L. et al. Changes in global terrestrial live biomass over the 21st century. Sci. Adv. 7, eabe9829 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, L. et al. Carbon storage in China&#x2019;s terrestrial ecosystems: A synthesis. Sci. Rep. 8, 2806 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, L., Yu, G. &amp; He, N. Increased soil organic carbon storage in Chinese terrestrial ecosystems from the 1980s to the 2010s. J. Geog. Sci. 29, 49&#x2013;66 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, R. et al. Estimation of soil carbon storage change from land use and management at a high spatial resolution in China during 2000-2020. Acta Geographica Sin. 78, 2209&#x2013;2222 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, Y. T. et al. A new estimation of China&#x2019;s net ecosystem productivity based on eddy covariance measurements and a model tree ensemble approach. Agric. Meteorol. 253, 84&#x2013;93 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge, Q. S., Dai, J. H., He, F. N., Pan, Y. &amp; Wang, M. M. Land use changes and their relations with carbon cycles over the past 300 a in China. Sci. China Ser. D.-Earth Sci. 51, 871&#x2013;884 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, X. et al. Carbon pools in China&#x2019;s terrestrial ecosystems: New estimates based on an intensive field survey. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 115, 4021&#x2013;4026 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, T. et al. The Tibetan Plateau acts as a net greenhouse gas sink. Sci. Bull. (Beijing) 70, 2147&#x2013;2156 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pongratz, J. &amp; Caldeira, K. Attribution of atmospheric CO2 and temperature increases to regions: importance of preindustrial land use change. Environ. Res. Lett. 7, 034001 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu, C. et al. Large historical carbon emissions from cultivated northern peatlands. Sci. Adv. 7, eabf1332 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spahni, R., Joos, F., Stocker, B. D., Steinacher, M. &amp; Yu, Z. C. Transient simulations of the carbon and nitrogen dynamics in northern peatlands: from the Last Glacial Maximum to the 21st century. Clim 9, 1287&#x2013;1308 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch, A., Brierley, C., Maslin, M. M. &amp; Lewis, S. L. Earth system impacts of the European arrival and Great Dying in the Americas after 1492. Quat. Sci. Rev. 207, 13&#x2013;36 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King, A. C. F. et al. Reconciling ice core CO(2) and land-use change following New World-Old World contact. Nat. Commun. 15, 1735 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norby, R. J. Forest productivity response to elevated CO(2) in free-air CO(2) enrichment experiments: the 23 percent solution, revisited. N. Phytol. 246, 1952&#x2013;1959 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. Y. et al. Dynamic response of the vegetation carbon storage in the sanjiang plain to changes in land use/cover and climate. Herit. Sci. 9, 134 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnone Iii, J. A. et al. Prolonged suppression of ecosystem carbon dioxide uptake after an anomalously warm year. Nature 455, 383&#x2013;386 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bevacqua, E. et al. Direct and lagged climate change effects intensified the 2022 European drought. Nat. Geosci. 17, 1100&#x2013;1107 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, D. et al. Accelerated terrestrial ecosystem carbon turnover and its drivers. Glob. Chang Biol. 26, 5052&#x2013;5062 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, K. et al. Pervasive decreases in living vegetation carbon turnover time across forest climate zones. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 116, 24662&#x2013;24667 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue, C. et al. Representing anthropogenic gross land use change, wood harvest, and forest age dynamics in a global vegetation model ORCHIDEE-MICT v8.4.2. Geosci. Model Dev. 11, 409&#x2013;428 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guimberteau, M. et al. ORCHIDEE-MICT (v8.4.1), a land surface model for the high latitudes: model description and validation. Geosci. Model Dev. 11, 121&#x2013;163 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krinner, G. et al. A dynamic global vegetation model for studies of the coupled atmosphere-biosphere system. Glob. Biogeochem. Cycles 19, GB1015 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piao, S. et al. Spatiotemporal patterns of terrestrial carbon cycle during the 20th century. Glob. Biogeochem. Cycles 23, GB4026 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue, C. et al. Modelling the role of fires in the terrestrial carbon balance by incorporating SPITFIRE into the global vegetation model ORCHIDEE &#x2013; Part 1: simulating historical global burned area and fire regimes. Geosci. Model Dev. 7, 2747&#x2013;2767 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, W. et al. Feedbacks of soil properties on vegetation during the Green Sahara period. Quat. Sci. Rev. 240, 106389 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, W. et al. Enhanced Mid-Holocene Vegetation Growth and Its Biophysical Feedbacks in China. Geophys. Res. Lett. 50, e2023GL104702 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braconnot, P. et al. Evaluation of climate models using palaeoclimatic data. Nat. Clim. Change 2, 417&#x2013;424 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steiger, N. J., Smerdon, J. E., Cook, E. R. &amp; Cook, B. I. A reconstruction of global hydroclimate and dynamical variables over the Common Era. Sci. Data 5, 180086 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;ishi, R. &amp; Abe-Ouchi, A. Influence of dynamic vegetation on climate change and terrestrial carbon storage in the Last Glacial Maximum. Clim 9, 1571&#x2013;1587 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, W. Millennial land carbon in China, Mendeley Data. https://doi.org/10.17632/xgdyj7d8pr (2025).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>