<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41145775</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Instability mapping of Dhaka-Kasiani-Gopalganj railway line in Bangladesh with InSAR time series analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>37449</StartPage><MedlinePgn>37449</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">37449</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-21375-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Previous studies on land subsidence identified Bangladesh and the Ganges-Brahmaputra Delta (GBD) region as a high-risk zone that is vulnerable to sea-level rise and climate change. This regional subsidence will affect the stability of linear rail infrastructure. The possible effect of this subsidence on rail infrastructure health was not scientifically examined before. Dhaka-Kasiani-Gopalganj Railway, which connects the capital city Dhaka to Gopalganj city in the southern part of Bangladesh, is chosen as a case study. This railway is about 150&#xa0;km long, and most of the stations, except the ones within Dhaka city, have been newly constructed during the last few years (construction started in late 2016). In this study, SBAS-InSAR time-series analysis was used to extract LOS displacement along the 60&#xa0;m buffer width of the railway embankment. Sentinel-1&#xa0;A images from both ascending and descending passes were used covering the temporal resolution from January 2020 to October 2023. A mean displacement rate of around -&#x2009;10&#xa0;mm/year was observed for ascending satellite line-of-sight LOS direction and -&#x2009;14&#xa0;mm/year for descending LOS direction. The ascending LOS displacement rate was compared with GPS data to check the instability trend, and the result showed an agreement in LOS displacement trend. The 2.5D analysis was also conducted to compute the quasi-vertical component along railway line for better understanding of local instability. A mean quasi-vertical displacement rate of approximately -&#x2009;16&#xa0;mm/year was observed along the railway line, and it indicates that the railway embankment is subsiding in general. To enhance the accuracy and reliability of displacement interpretation, InSAR measurements were supplemented with contextual analysis incorporating land use/land cover (LULC) and soil data. In regions covered by "Crops" land cover type, a high rate of quasi-vertical displacement was observed indicating that railway line passing through paddy fields are highly prone to instability. Similarly, significant displacement rates were noted in "Deltaic silt" soil type, followed by "Alluvial silt and clay" and "Marsh clay and peat" type. Railway embankment built on these soil types should be prioritized for inspection. The threshold displacement velocity value was also defined based on the results so that it can serve as an early indicator of damage, aiding in the prioritization of inspection and maintenance work. This study aims to broaden the use of InSAR data in engineering practices in linear rail infrastructure health monitoring. Future research will focus on a detailed analysis of current damage conditions compared with satellite-based instability results.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kyaw</LastName><ForeName>Khin Myat</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Industrial Science, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan. khinmk@g.ecc.u-tokyo.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takeuchi</LastName><ForeName>Wataru</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Industrial Science, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Geology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Land cover</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Maintenance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SBAS-InSAR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sentinel-1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Subsidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transport infrastructure</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41145775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12559400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-21375-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-21375-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Railway, B. <i>Information Book.</i> (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steckler, M. S. et al. Synthesis of the distribution of subsidence of the lower Ganges-Brahmaputra Delta, Bangladesh. <i>Earth Sci. Rev.</i><b>224</b>, 103887 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.earscirev.2021.103887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curray, J. R., Emmel, F. J., Moore, D. G. &amp; Raitt, R. W. Structure, tectonics, and geological history of the Northeastern Indian ocean. In <i>The Ocean Basins and Margins</i> (eds Nairn, A. E. M. &amp; Stehli, F. G.) 399&#x2013;450 (Springer, 1982).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umitsu, M. Late quaternary environment and landforms in the Ganges delta. <i>Sed. Geol.</i><b>83</b>, 177&#x2013;186 (1993).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0037-0738(93)90011-S</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam, M. Springer, Dordrecht,. Subsidence of the Ganges-Brahmaputra delta of Bangladesh and associated drainage, sedimentation and salinity problems In <i>Sea-Level Rise and Coastal Subsidence. Coastal Systems and Continental Margins</i> (eds. Milliman, J. D. &amp; Haq, B. U.) 169&#x2013;192 (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allison, M. A. Historical changes in the Ganges-Brahmaputra delta front. <i>J. Coast Res.</i><b>14</b> (4), 1269&#x2013;1275 (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steckler, M. S. et al. Modeling earth deformation from monsoonal flooding in Bangladesh using hydrographic, GPS, and gravity recovery and climate experiment (GRACE) data. <i>J. Geophys. Res.</i><b>115</b>, B08407 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, S. A. et al. InSAR measurements of compaction and subsidence in the Ganges-Brahmaputra delta, Bangladesh. <i>J. Geophys. Res. Earth Surf.</i><b>119</b>, 1768&#x2013;1781 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/2014JF003117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gharehbaghi, V. R. et al. A critical review on structural health monitoring: definitions, methods, and perspectives. <i>Arch. Comput. Methods Eng.</i><b>29</b>, 2209&#x2013;2235 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11831-021-09665-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rioja, F. K. Filling potholes: macroeconomic effects of maintenance versus new investments in public infrastructure. <i>J. Publ. Econ.</i><b>87</b>, 2281&#x2013;2304 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0047-2727(01)00200-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jack, R. &amp; Jackson, P. Imaging attributes of railway track formation and ballast using ground probing radar. <i>NDT E Int.</i><b>32</b>, 457&#x2013;462 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0963-8695(99)00023-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hugenschmidt, J. Railway track inspection using GPR. <i>J. Appl. Geophys.</i><b>43</b>, 147&#x2013;155 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0926-9851(99)00054-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, H. J. P. &amp; Olhoeft, S. S. G. R. &amp; Selig. E. T. Assessment of railway track substructure condition using ground penetrating radar. In <i>Proc. AREMA 2003 Annu. Conf.</i> (2003). https://arema.org/AREMA_MBRR/AREMA_MBRR/Events/Proceedings/2003.aspx</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter, D., Jackson, P. J. &amp; Jay, A. Enhancement of the GPR method of railway trackbed investigation by the installation of radar detectable geosynthetics. <i>NDT E Int.</i><b>37</b>, 95&#x2013;103 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ndteint.2003.06.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao, W. et al. Automatic classification of ground-penetrating radar signals for railway-ballast assessment. <i>IEEE Trans. Geosci. Remote Sens.</i><b>49</b> (10), 3961&#x2013;3972 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TGRS.2011.2128328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donohue, S., Gavin, K. &amp; Tolooiyan, A. Geophysical and geotechnical assessment of a railway embankment failure. <i>Near Surf. Geophys.</i><b>9</b>, 33&#x2013;44 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3997/1873-0604.2010040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shangguan, P., Al-Qadi, I. L. &amp; Leng, Z. Ground-penetrating radar data to develop wavelet technique for quantifying railroad ballast&#x2013;fouling conditions. <i>Transp. Res. Rec</i>. <b>2289</b> (1), 95&#x2013;102 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3141/2289-13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontul, S., Fortunato, E., Chiara, F. D., Burrinha, R. &amp; Baldeiras, M. Railways track characterization using ground penetrating radar. <i>Proc. Eng.</i><b>143</b>, 1193&#x2013;1200 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.proeng.2016.06.120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macchiarulo, V., Milillo, P., Blenkinsopp, C. &amp; Giardina, G. Monitoring deformations of infrastructure networks: A fully automated GIS integration and analysis of InSAR time-series. <i>Struct. Health Monit.</i><b>21</b> (4), 1849&#x2013;1878 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/14759217211045912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L., Dollevoet, R. &amp; Hanssen, R. F. Railway infrastructure monitoring using satellite radar data. <i>Int. J. Railw Technol.</i><b>3</b> (2), 79&#x2013;91 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4203/ijrt.3.2.5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cigna, F. et al. Mapping ground instability in areas of geotechnical infrastructure using satellite InSAR and small UAV surveying: a case study in Northern Ireland. <i>Geosciences</i><b>7</b>, 51 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/geosciences7030051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, Q., Li, J. &amp; Zhang, Y. Monitoring subsidence over the planned Jakarta-Bandung (Indonesia) high-speed railway using Sentinel-1 multi-temporal InSAR data. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>14</b>, 4138 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs14174138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hore, R., Chakraborty, S. &amp; Ansary, M. A. A field investigation to improve soft soils using prefabricated vertical drain. <i>Trans. Infra Geotech.</i><b>7</b>, 127&#x2013;155 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40515-019-00093-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karra, K. et al. Global land use/land cover with Sentinel 2 and deep learning. In <i>Proc. IEEE Int. Geosci. Remote Sens. Symp., Brussels, Belgium</i>, 4704&#x2013;4707 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirza, M. M. Q. Three recent extreme floods in bangladesh: A hydro-meteorological analysis. In <i>Flood Problem and Management in South Asia</i> (eds Mirza, M. M. Q., Dixit, A. &amp; Nishat, A.) 35&#x2013;64 (Springer, 2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, S., Samsonov, S., Yin, H., Ye, S. &amp; Cao, Y. Time-series analysis of subsidence associated with rapid urbanization in Shanghai, China measured with SBAS InSAR method. <i>Environ. Earth Sci.</i><b>72</b>, 677&#x2013;691 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-013-2990-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X. et al. Quantifying the impacts of land use/land cover change on groundwater depletion in Northwestern China - a case study of the Dunhuang Oasis. <i>Agric. Water Manag</i>. <b>146</b>, 270&#x2013;279 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agwat.2014.08.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriel, A. K., Goldstein, R. M. &amp; Zebker, H. A. Mapping small elevation changes over large areas: differential radar interferometry. <i>J. Geophys. Res.</i><b>94</b> (B7), 9183&#x2013;9191 (1989).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/JB094iB07p09183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berardino, P., Fornaro, G., Lanari, R. &amp; Sansosti, E. A new algorithm for surface deformation monitoring based on small baseline differential SAR interferograms. <i>IEEE Trans. Geosci. Rem. Sens.</i><b>40</b>, 2375&#x2013;2383 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TGRS.2002.803792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fornaro, G., Reale, D. &amp; Serafino, F. Four-dimensional SAR imaging for height Estimation and monitoring of single and double scatterers. <i>IEEE Trans. Geosci. Remote Sens.</i><b>47</b>, 224&#x2013;237 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TGRS.2008.2000837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hrysiewicz, A., Wang, X. &amp; Holohan, E. P. EZ-InSAR: an easy-to-use open-source toolbox for mapping ground surface deformation using satellite interferometric synthetic aperture radar. <i>Earth Sci. Inf.</i><b>16</b>, 1929&#x2013;1945 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12145-023-00973-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10040910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37213218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen, P. A., Gurrola, E., Sacco, G. F. &amp; Zebker, H. The InSAR scientific computing environment. In <i>Proc. EUSAR 2012; 9th Eur. Conf. Synthetic Aperture Radar</i>, 730&#x2013;733 (2012). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yunjun, Z., Fattahi, H. &amp; Amelung, F. Small baseline InSAR time series analysis: unwrapping error correction and noise reduction. <i>Comput. Geosci.</i><b>133</b>, 104331 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cageo.2019.104331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekaert, D. P. S., Walters, R. J., Wright, T. J., Hooper, A. J. &amp; Parker, D. J. Statistical comparison of InSAR tropospheric correction techniques. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>170</b>, 40&#x2013;47 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2015.08.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray, A. L., Mattar, K. E. &amp; Sofko, G. Influence of ionospheric electron density fluctuations on satellite radar interferometry. <i>Geophys. Res. Lett.</i><b>27</b>, 1451&#x2013;1454 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2000GL000016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hersbach, H. et al. The ERA5 global reanalysis. <i>Q. J. R Meteorol. Soc.</i><b>146</b>, 1999&#x2013;2049 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/qj.3803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright, T. J., Parsons, B. E. &amp; Lu, Z. Toward mapping surface deformation in three dimensions using InSAR. <i>Geophys. Res. Lett.</i><b>31</b>, L01607 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2003GL018827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujiwara, S., Nishimura, T., Murakami, M., Nakagawa, H. &amp; Tobita, M. 2.5-D surface deformation of M6.1 earthquake near Mt Iwate detected by SAR interferometry. <i>Geophys. Res. Lett.</i><b>27</b>, 2049&#x2013;2052 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/1999GL011291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blewitt, G., Hammond, W. C. &amp; Kreemer, C. Harnessing the GPS data explosion for interdisciplinary science. <i>Eos</i>. <b>99</b>10.1029/2018EO104623 (2018).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>