<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41613504</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Safety and Efficacy of TruBlk&#x2122; Shilajit Resin Supplementation on Physical Performance and Blood Biomarkers in Healthy Adults: A 28-Day Open-Label Pilot Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e102372</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e102372</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e102372</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.102372</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Shilajit is a mineral-rich natural exudate traditionally used as a rejuvenator and performance enhancer. While previous studies have evaluated standardized Shilajit extracts, there is limited clinical evidence on the traditional resin formulation. This study aimed to assess the safety and efficacy profile of&#xa0;Shilajit resin supplementation on physical performance parameters and blood biomarkers in healthy, moderately active adults. Methods This was an open-label, single-arm pilot clinical study conducted over 28 days in 25 healthy male participants aged 21-55 years. Participants received 500 mg/day of TruBlk&#x2122; Shilajit Resin (250 mg twice daily). Primary outcomes included changes in muscle strength (one-repetition maximum [1RM] leg press), muscle endurance, grip strength, fatigue severity (Fatigue Severity Scale [FSS]), and rating of perceived exertion (RPE). Secondary outcomes included aerobic capacity (maximal oxygen uptake [VO&#x2082; max]),&#xa0;body composition parameters, inflammatory markers like C-reactive protein (CRP) levels, muscle damage markers such as creatine kinase (CK) and lactate dehydrogenase (LDH), and hormonal markers (total testosterone). Safety was evaluated through adverse event monitoring and laboratory assessments, including liver and kidney function tests and hematological parameters. Results After 28 days of supplementation, statistically significant and large magnitude within-group improvements were observed in 1RM leg press strength (+12.94%, p &lt; 0.001), muscle endurance (+12.30%, p &lt; 0.001), grip strength of the dominant hand (+5.73%, p = 0.038), and VO&#x2082; max (+1.36%, p &lt; 0.001). FSS scores decreased by 32.40% (p &lt; 0.001), and RPE scores decreased by 23.63% (p &lt; 0.001). CRP levels significantly declined by 25.35% (p = 0.023). Further, CK levels decreased by 41.70% (p = 0.059, a non-significant trend that, considering the high inter-individual variability at baseline, suggests a potential meaningful reduction in exercise-induced muscle damage and improved recovery status. This should be a key focus of future larger-scale studies.&#xa0;Body composition analysis demonstrated a statistically significant increase in lean body mass (+1.5%, p = 0.002) and a reduction in body fat percentage (-2.34%, p = 0.033). No serious adverse events were reported, and all safety laboratory parameters remained within normal limits. Conclusions Shilajit resin supplementation at a dose of 500 mg/day for 28 days was associated with statistically significant improvements&#xa0;in muscle strength, endurance, aerobic capacity, and fatigue parameters, along with favorable changes in inflammatory markers, while demonstrating good safety and tolerability in healthy adult males. These findings support further investigation of Shilajit resin in larger, randomized, placebo-controlled clinical trials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Yadav et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yadav</LastName><ForeName>Divya</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Development, Amaara Botanicals Private Limited, Gurugram, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mishra</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research, Bensups Hospital, New Delhi, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Karan M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Development, Amaara Botanicals Private Limited, Gurugram, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reddy</LastName><ForeName>Surya T</ForeName><Initials>ST</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Trials and Pharmacovigilance, Auriga Research Private Limited, Gurugram, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Rohit</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quality Assurance and Regulatory Affairs, Amaara Botanicals Private Limited, Gurugram, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pandey</LastName><ForeName>Pramod</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Product Development and Innovation, Amaara Botanicals Private Limited, Gurugram, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endurance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ergogenic aid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mumie</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">s: shilajit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">salajit</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. GSER Independent Ethics Committee issued approval GSER/2025/BMR-AP/181. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41613504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12848467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.102372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shilajit: a review. Agarwal SP, Khanna R, Karmarkar R, Anwer MK, Khar RK. Phytother Res. 2007;21:401&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17295385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shilajit: a panacea for high-altitude problems. Meena H, Pandey HK, Arya MC, Ahmed Z. Int J Ayurveda Res. 2010;1:37&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2876922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20532096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shilajit: a natural phytocomplex with potential procognitive activity. Carrasco-Gallardo C, Guzm&#xe1;n L, Maccioni RB. Int J Alzheimers Dis. 2012;2012:674142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3296184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22482077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effects of Shilajit supplementation on fatigue-induced decreases in muscular strength and serum hydroxyproline levels. Keller JL, Housh TJ, Hill EC, Smith CM, Schmidt RJ, Johnson GO. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2019;16:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6364418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30728074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical evaluation of purified Shilajit on testosterone levels in healthy volunteers. Pandit S, Biswas S, Jana U, De RK, Mukhopadhyay SC, Biswas TK. Andrologia. 2016;48:570&#x2013;575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26395129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of the effect of purified aqueous extract of Shilajit in modifying cardiovascular risk with special reference to endothelial dysfunction in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Niranjan K, Ramakanth GSH, Fatima N, Usharani P. https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/EVALUATION-OF-THE-EFFECT-OF-PURIFIED-AQUEOUS-OF-IN-Niranjan-Ramakanth/8d9dd8bbd29600057e8e60586e934af359f806db Int J Ayurveda Pharma Res. 2016;4:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of purified Shilajit (Asphaltum punjabianum) on oxidative stress, arterial stiffness and endothelial function in elderly with hypertension: a randomised controlled study. Patil SG, Patil K, Sarashetti R, Hadimur K. https://ijpp.com/effect-of-purified-shilajit-asphaltum-punjabianum-on-oxidative-stress-arterial-stiffness-and-endothelial-function-in-elderly-with-hypertension-a-randomised-controlled-study/ Indian J Physiol Pharmacol. 2023;67:197&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The human skeletal muscle transcriptome in response to oral Shilajit supplementation. Das A, Datta S, Rhea B, Sinha M, Veeraragavan M, Gordillo G, Roy S. J Med Food. 2016;19:701&#x2013;709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4948208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27414521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle TR, Earle RW. Human Kinetics. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2008. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The step test: a simple method of measuring physical fitness for muscular work in young men. Brouha L. https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/10671188.1943.10621204 Res Q Am Assoc Health Phys Educ Recreat. 1943;14:31&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The fatigue severity scale. Application to patients with multiple sclerosis and systemic lupus erythematosus. Krupp LB, LaRocca NG, Muir-Nash J, Steinberg AD. Arch Neurol. 1989;46:1121&#x2013;1123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2803071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Borg GA. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7154893/ Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1982;14:377&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7154893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shilajit attenuates behavioral symptoms of chronic fatigue syndrome by modulating the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis and mitochondrial bioenergetics in rats. Surapaneni DK, Adapa SR, Preeti K, Teja GR, Veeraragavan M, Krishnamurthy S. J Ethnopharmacol. 2012;143:91&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22771318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safety and efficacy of shilajit (mumie, moomiyo) Stohs SJ. Phytother Res. 2014;28:475&#x2013;479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23733436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>