<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41792573</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1084</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European radiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur Radiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Factors associated with early complete resolution after radiofrequency ablation for low-risk papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a dual-center retrospective study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00330-026-12415-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To identify predictors of early complete ablation zone resolution (within 1 year) after radiofrequency ablation (RFA) for low-risk papillary thyroid microcarcinoma (PTMC).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective dual-center study enrolled 225 patients with low-risk PTMC (2017-2022). Ablation zone volume was tracked during follow-up, with the specific time of complete resolution modeled using exponential decay functions. Multivariable Cox regression and restricted cubic spline (RCS) analyses identified independent predictors of resolution.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Cumulative complete resolution rates were 62.2% at 1 year and 98.7% at 2 years. Independent predictors of complete resolution within 1 year included normal thyroglobulin antibody (TgAb) levels (hazard ratio (HR): 2.64, 95% confidence Interval (CI): 1.38-5.07) and thyroid peroxidase antibody (TPOAb) levels (HR: 1.92, 95% CI: 1.34-2.75), nodule diameter &#x2264; 5&#x2009;mm (HR: 1.53, 95% CI: 1.02-2.29), and absence of intratumoral vascularity (HR: 2.77, 95% CI: 1.83-4.21). Energy density showed an inverted U-shaped relationship with resolution probability within 1 year (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001 for non-linearity).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">RFA achieves favorable long-term efficacy for low-risk PTMC, and complete resolution within 1 year is predictable by normal TgAb/TPOAb, smaller nodule size, absence of intratumoral vascularity, and moderate energy density. These findings may provide valuable insights for refining RFA techniques and the development of personalized follow-up.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="KEY POINTS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Question Predicting early complete resolution of low-risk PTMC after RFA is critical to mitigate concerns about treatment outcomes and optimize follow-up. Findings Normal TgAb/TPOAb, smaller nodule size, absence of intratumoral vascularity, and moderate energy density independently predict early complete ablation zone resolution within 1 year after RFA. Clinical relevance Identifying predictors of early resolution enables optimized RFA energy delivery and pretreatment decision-making. This provides doctors and patients with evidence-based guidance to refine ablation strategies and personalize management plans.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to European Society of Radiology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qiu</LastName><ForeName>Yuxuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Affiliated Hangzhou First People's Hospital, School of Medicine, Westlake University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yina</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Hangzhou Cancer Hospital, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Jingqi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Hangzhou Cancer Hospital, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gong</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Affiliated Hangzhou First People's Hospital, School of Medicine, Westlake University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Hangzhou Cancer Hospital, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Pin</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Hangzhou Cancer Hospital, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Lian</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Hangzhou Cancer Hospital, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bao</LastName><ForeName>Lingyun</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Affiliated Hangzhou First People's Hospital, School of Medicine, Westlake University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Jianhua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Affiliated Hangzhou First People's Hospital, School of Medicine, Westlake University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lou</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Hangzhou Cancer Hospital, Hangzhou, China. loujun173676162@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Chenke</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2676-0430</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Affiliated Hangzhou First People's Hospital, School of Medicine, Westlake University, Hangzhou, China. muerxck@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>LQN25H160046</GrantID><Agency>Zhejiang Provincial Natural Science of Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>A20250259</GrantID><Agency>Hangzhou Health Science and Technology Plan</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2025ZL094</GrantID><Agency>Zhejiang Provincial Traditional Chinese Medicine Science and Technology Program</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur Radiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9114774</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0938-7994</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Radiofrequency ablation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thyroid carcinoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Compliance with ethical standards. Guarantor: The scientific guarantor of this publication is Dr. Yuxuan Qiu. Conflict of interest: The authors of this manuscript declare no relationships with any companies, whose products or services may be related to the subject matter of the article. Statistics and biometry: No complex statistical methods were necessary for this paper. Informed consent: Written informed consent was waived by the Institutional Review Board because it is a retrospective study. Ethical approval: Institutional Review Board approval was obtained. This study was carried out in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki and approved by the medical ethics committee of Hangzhou First People&#x2019;s Hospital. Study subjects or cohorts overlap: Some study subjects or cohorts have never been previously reported. Methodology: Retrospective Case-control study Multicenter study</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41792573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-026-12415-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00330-026-12415-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Toraih E, Hussein M, Elshazli R et al (2025) Therapeutic outcomes and safety of radiofrequency ablation for primary papillary thyroid carcinoma: a game-changing meta-analysis. Radiother Oncol 205:110706</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39862924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radonc.2025.110706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megwalu UC, Moon PK (2022) Thyroid cancer incidence and mortality trends in the United States: 2000&#x2013;2018. Thyroid 32:560&#x2013;570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35132899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/thy.2021.0662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haugen BR, Alexander EK, Bible KC et al (2016) 2015 American Thyroid Association management guidelines for adult patients with thyroid nodules and differentiated thyroid cancer: the American Thyroid Association guidelines task force on thyroid nodules and differentiated thyroid cancer. Thyroid 26:1&#x2013;133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26462967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4739132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/thy.2015.0020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi S, Alexander EK (2023) Active surveillance for low-risk differentiated thyroid cancer. Endocr Pract 29:148&#x2013;153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36270610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eprac.2022.10.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nickel B, Tan T, Cvejic E et al (2019) Health-related quality of life after diagnosis and treatment of differentiated thyroid cancer and association with type of surgical treatment. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 145:231&#x2013;238</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30653212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6439749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoto.2018.3870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang H, Choi JY, Yu HW et al (2023) Surgical outcomes in patients with low-risk papillary thyroid microcarcinoma from MAeSTro study: immediate operation versus delayed operation after active surveillance: a multicenter prospective cohort study. Ann Surg 278:e1087&#x2013;e1095</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36912439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLA.0000000000005841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuttle RM, Fagin JA, Minkowitz G et al (2017) Natural history and tumor volume kinetics of papillary thyroid cancers during active surveillance. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 143:1015&#x2013;1020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28859191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5710258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoto.2017.1442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim CA, Baek SH, Yoo J et al (2024) Tumor growth kinetics based on initial tumor volume doubling time in active surveillance of low-risk papillary thyroid carcinoma. Thyroid 34:846&#x2013;855</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38757584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/thy.2024.0054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao GZ, Zhang MB (2024) Ultrasound-guided radiofrequency ablation for the treatment of papillary thyroid carcinoma: a review of the current state and future perspectives. Ultrasonography 43:79&#x2013;87</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38310872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14366/usg.23091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orloff LA, Noel JE, Stack BC Jr et al (2022) Radiofrequency ablation and related ultrasound-guided ablation technologies for treatment of benign and malignant thyroid disease: an international multidisciplinary consensus statement of the American Head and Neck Society Endocrine Surgery Section with the Asia Pacific Society of Thyroid Surgery, Associazione Medici Endocrinologi, British Association of Endocrine and Thyroid Surgeons, European Thyroid Association, Italian Society of Endocrine Surgery Units, Korean Society of Thyroid Radiology, Latin American Thyroid Society, and Thyroid Nodules Therapies Association. Head Neck 44:633&#x2013;660</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34939714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hed.26960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan L, Zhang M, Song Q, Luo Y (2021) Ultrasound-guided radiofrequency ablation versus thyroid lobectomy for low-risk papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a propensity-matched cohort study of 884 patients. Thyroid 31:1662&#x2013;1672</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34269611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/thy.2021.0100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Dijk SPJ, Coerts HI, Gunput STG et al (2022) Assessment of radiofrequency ablation for papillary microcarcinoma of the thyroid: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 148:317&#x2013;325</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35142816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8832309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoto.2021.4381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Yan L, Xiao J et al (2024) Long-term outcomes and risk factors of radiofrequency ablation for T1N0M0 papillary thyroid carcinoma. JAMA Surg 159:51&#x2013;58</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37878294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10600723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamasurg.2023.5202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan L, Li Y, Li XY, Xiao J, Tang J, Luo Y (2023) Clinical outcomes of ultrasound-guided radiofrequency ablation for solitary T1N0M0 papillary thyroid carcinoma: a retrospective study with more than 5 years of follow-up. Cancer 129:2469&#x2013;2478</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37060239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.34802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G, Li R, Zhong J et al (2025) A multicenter cohort study of thyroidectomy-related decision regret in patients with low-risk papillary thyroid microcarcinoma. Nat Commun 16:2317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40057484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11890561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-025-57627-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong SY, Baek SM, Shin S, Son JM, Kim H, Baek JH (2025) Radiofrequency ablation of low-risk papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a retrospective cohort study including patients with more than 10 years of follow-up. Thyroid 35:143&#x2013;152</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39868683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/thy.2024.0535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin C, Wu X, Zhang K et al (2025) Analysis and prediction of ablation zone absorption in papillary thyroid microcarcinoma undergoing microwave ablation. Endocrine 87:707&#x2013;717</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39365386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12020-024-04049-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Pan XH, Han HT, Zhao YX, Ma LB (2024) Incomplete ablation of thyroid cancer: Achilles&#x2019; heel? BMC Endocr Disord 24:146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39123156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11313020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12902-024-01659-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chai M, Yu J, Liang P (2023) Trajectory analysis of microwave ablation treatment effect on the quality of life and emotional distress in patients with papillary thyroid cancer. Endocrine 82:602&#x2013;612</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37480495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12020-023-03451-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chun YS, Pawlik TM, Vauthey JN (2018) 8th edition of the AJCC cancer staging manual: pancreas and hepatobiliary cancers. Ann Surg Oncol 25:845&#x2013;847</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28752469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1245/s10434-017-6025-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tessler FN, Middleton WD, Grant EG et al (2017) ACR Thyroid Imaging, Reporting and Data System (TI-RADS): white paper of the ACR TI-RADS Committee. J Am Coll Radiol 14:587&#x2013;595</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28372962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacr.2017.01.046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Baek JH, Lim HK et al (2018) 2017 Thyroid radiofrequency ablation guideline: Korean Society of Thyroid Radiology. Korean J Radiol 19:632&#x2013;655</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29962870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6005940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3348/kjr.2018.19.4.632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalilzadeh O, Baerlocher MO, Shyn PB et al (2017) Proposal of a new adverse event classification by the Society of Interventional Radiology Standards of Practice Committee. J Vasc Interv Radiol 28:1432&#x2013;1437.e1433</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28757285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jvir.2017.06.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pace-Asciak P, Russell JO, Tufano RP (2023) Review: Improving quality of life in patients with differentiated thyroid cancer. Front Oncol 13:1032581</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36776310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9911681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2023.1032581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho SJ, Baek SM, Lim HK, Lee KD, Son JM, Baek JH (2020) Long-term follow-up results of ultrasound-guided radiofrequency ablation for low-risk papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: more than 5-year follow-up for 84 tumors. Thyroid 30:1745&#x2013;1751</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32375570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/thy.2020.0106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papini E, Guglielmi R, Novizio R, Pontecorvi A, Durante C (2024) Management of low-risk papillary thyroid cancer. Minimally-invasive treatments dictate a further paradigm shift? Endocrine 85:584&#x2013;592</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38767774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11291527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12020-024-03864-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Zhou W, Xu S et al (2024) Thermal ablation for the treatment of malignant thyroid nodules: present and future. Int J Hyperthermia 41:2379983</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39013550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02656736.2024.2379983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Liang L, Li J (2024) Transcriptomic profiling in low-risk thyroid cancer induced by microwave ablation. Int J Endocrinol 2024:6674506</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38779358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11111303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2024/6674506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deandrea M, Trimboli P, Mormile A et al (2021) Determining an energy threshold for optimal volume reduction of benign thyroid nodules treated by radiofrequency ablation. Eur Radiol 31:5189&#x2013;5197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33409792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-020-07532-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du R, Wang R, Xu H et al (2025) A novel computer-aided energy decision-making system improves patient treatment by microwave ablation of thyroid nodule. Comput Biol Med 188:109823</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39986198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2025.109823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao L, Peng X, Xiong J, Zhu Y, Song M (2025) Microwave ablation for small papillary thyroid carcinomas: clinical outcomes and thyroid function preservation. Endocr Connect 14:e240628</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caturegli P, De Remigis A, Rose NR (2014) Hashimoto thyroiditis: clinical and diagnostic criteria. Autoimmun Rev 13:391&#x2013;397</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24434360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2014.01.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popko K, G&#xf3;rska E (2015) The role of natural killer cells in pathogenesis of autoimmune diseases. Cent Eur J Immunol 40:470&#x2013;476</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26862312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/ceji.2015.56971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krawczyk A, Mi&#x15b;kiewicz J, Strzelec K, Wcis&#x142;o-Dziadecka D, Strzalka-Mrozik B (2020) Apoptosis in autoimmunological diseases, with particular consideration of molecular aspects of psoriasis. Med Sci Monit 26:e922035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32567582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7331484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MSM.922035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai L, Zhou C, Liu Z et al (2025) Impact of Hashimoto&#x2019;s thyroiditis on radiofrequency ablation for papillary thyroid micro-carcinoma: a cohort study of 391 patients. Int J Hyperthermia 42:2426607</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39956545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02656736.2024.2426607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo RE, Kim JH, Paeng JC, Park YJ (2018) Radiofrequency ablation for treatment of locally recurrent thyroid cancer presenting as a metastatic lymph node with dense macrocalcification: a case report and literature review. Medicine 97:e0003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29489641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5851762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000010003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai L, Liu Z, Zhang J et al (2022) Effect of Hashimoto&#x2019;s thyroiditis on the extent of the ablation zone in early stages of ultrasound-guided radiofrequency ablation for papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a large cohort study of 772 patients. Int J Hyperthermia 39:397&#x2013;404</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35209788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02656736.2022.2041736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan WK, Sun JH, Liou MJ et al (2024) Novel and advanced ultrasound techniques for thyroid thermal ablation. Endocrinol Metab (Seoul) 39:40&#x2013;46</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3803/EnM.2024.1917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santi F, Mattarello MJ, Vendraminelli R, Peron C, Mazzucco M (2024) Thermoablative treatment of papillary microcarcinomas of thyroid. Endocr Metab Immune Disord Drug Targets. https://doi.org/10.2174/0118715303322372240611075403</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu C, Liang S, Liu H et al (2023) Prediction of ablation zone disappearance after microwave ablation for the patients with papillary thyroid microcarcinoma using nomograph. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 14:1145958</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37600691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10433776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2023.1145958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong M, Wang L, Gai Z, Zhu Y, Che Y (2023) Clinical outcomes of radiofrequency ablation for solitary T1aN0M0 versus T1bN0M0 papillary thyroid carcinoma: a propensity-matched cohort study. Int J Hyperthermia 40:2257908</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37848402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02656736.2023.2257908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu C, Li X, Chu X et al (2021) Clinical effects of microwave ablation in the treatment of low-risk papillary thyroid microcarcinomas and related histopathological changes. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 12:751213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34603216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8482998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2021.751213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He H, Zhang Y, Song Q et al (2021) Nomogram prediction for the involution of the ablation zone after radiofrequency ablation treatment in patients with low-risk papillary thyroid carcinoma. Int J Hyperthermia 38:1133&#x2013;1139</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34348562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02656736.2021.1960434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>