<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41576259</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effectiveness of a 10-Week Concurrent Strength and Endurance Training Program on the Physical Readiness of Trained British Army Soldiers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e189</StartPage><EndPage>e196</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e189-e196</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005275</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Nevin, J, Suffield, C, Mutch, S, Glass, M, Sadler, S, Mclay, W, Coonan, L, Glass, M, Sadler, S, Penver, R, and Beckingham, J. The effectiveness of a 10-week concurrent strength and endurance training program on the physical readiness of trained British Army soldiers. J Strength Cond Res 40(2): e189-e196, 2026-The aim of this study was to investigate the efficacy of a 10-week concurrent strength and endurance training program in comparison with traditional military physical training (PT) practices on the physical readiness of trained British Army personnel. Forty-eight, fully trained British Army infantry soldiers (men: n = 45; women: n = 3) were randomly assigned into either an experimental or control group. Baseline and post-testing measures included body mass, standing broad jump, seated medicine ball throw, 1 repetition maximum (1RM) hex bar deadlift, 100-m shuttle run, pull-ups, and 2-km run. Subjects in the experimental group followed a 10-week concurrent strength and endurance training program based on a block periodization model, whereas subjects in the control group completed a 10-week program based on traditional military PT practices (i.e., circuit training, steady-state running). Results indicated a greater effect size in all measures in the experimental group than in the control group with a significant (p &lt; 0.001) improvement observed in 1RM hex bar deadlift and pull-up performance. Findings from this study demonstrate that a concurrent training program based on a block periodization model elicits superior improvements in certain components of physical than traditional military PT practices. However, data suggest that a greater frequency and/or volume of endurance training may be required to elicit improvements in aerobic capacity. As such, it is recommended that warfighters conduct at least 2 strength and 2 endurance training sessions per week in addition to occupational task-specific training.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nevin</LastName><ForeName>Jonpaul</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Buckinghamshire New University (BNU), High Wycombe, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suffield</LastName><ForeName>Colin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Royal Army Physical Training Corps (RAPTC), Aldershot, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mutch</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Royal Army Physical Training Corps (RAPTC), Aldershot, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glass</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Royal Army Physical Training Corps (RAPTC), Aldershot, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sadler</LastName><ForeName>Shane</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Royal Army Physical Training Corps (RAPTC), Aldershot, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mclay</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Royal Army Physical Training Corps (RAPTC), Aldershot, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coonan</LastName><ForeName>Lee</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Royal Air Force (RAF), Buckinghamshire, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Penver</LastName><ForeName>Ross</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Royal Army Physical Training Corps (RAPTC), Aldershot, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beckingham</LastName><ForeName>Jodie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Royal Army Physical Training Corps (RAPTC), Aldershot, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008889" MajorTopicYN="Y">Military Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076663" MajorTopicYN="Y">Endurance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006113" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United Kingdom</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010809" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Fitness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064797" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Conditioning, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concurrent training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">periodisation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">warfighter</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41576259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202602000-00024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abt JP, Oliver JM, Nagai T, et al. Block-periodized training improves physiological and tactically relevant performance in naval special warfare operators. J Strength Cond Res 30: 39&#x2013;52, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Army General and Administrative Instructions. Physical Training (Vol 1), Chapter 7: DTrg(A)/ITrg/PhysDev/05/09. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blacker S, Wilkinson DM, Bilzon JLJ, Rayson M. Risk factors for training injuries among British Army recruits. Mil Med 173: 278&#x2013;286, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for Behavioural Sciences (2nd ed.). Hillsdale, NJ: Erlbaum Associates, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigel ED, Sterczala AJ, Krajewski KT, et al. Physiological characteristics predictive of passing military physical employment standard tasks for ground close combat occupations in men and women. Eur J Sport Sci 24: 1247&#x2013;1259, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedl KE, Knapik JJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K, et al. Perspectives on aerobic and strength influences on military physical readiness: Report of an international military physiology roundtable. J Strength Cond Res 29: S10&#x2013;S23, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedl KE, Breivik TJ, Carter R III, et al. Soldier health habits and the metabolically optimized brain. Mil Med 181: e1499&#x2013;e1507, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Florhaug JA, Franklin J, et al. A new approach to monitoring exercise training. J Strength Cond Res 15: 109&#x2013;115, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fosb&#xf8;l M&#xd8;, Zerahn B. Contemporary methods of body composition measurement. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 35: 81&#x2013;97, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harman EA, Gutekunst DJ, Frykman PN, et al. Effects of two different eight-week training programs on military physical performance. J Strength Cond Res 22: 524&#x2013;534, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauschild VD, DeGroot DW, Hall SM, et al. Fitness tests and occupational tasks of military interest: A systematic review of correlations. Occup Environ Med 74: 144&#x2013;153, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hel&#xe9;n J, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H, Ojanen T, et al. High-intensity functional training induces superior training adaptations compared with traditional military physical training. J Strength Cond Res 37: 2477&#x2013;2483, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heilbronn BE, Doma K, Gormann D, Schumann M, Sinclair WH. Effects of periodized vs. nonperiodized resistance training on Army-specific fitness and skills performance. J Strength Cond Res 34: 738&#x2013;753, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henning PC, Park BS, Kim JS. Physiological decrements during sustained military operational stress. Mil Med 176: 991&#x2013;997, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Individual Training Requirements. Core Health &amp; Fitness: Soldiers Conditioning Review (SCR) and Role Fitness Test (Soldier)(RFT(S))&#x2014;V3.0. Module Guidance Notes, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Individual Training Requirements. Core Health &amp; Fitness: Soldiers Conditioning Review (SCR) and Role Fitness Test (Soldier)(RFT(S))&#x2014;V3.0. Conduct Notes, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issurin VB. New horizons for the methodology and physiology of training periodization. Sports Med 40: 189&#x2013;206, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knapik JJ, Reynolds KL, Harman E. Soldier load carriage: Historical, physiological, biomechanical, and medical aspects. Mil Med 169: 545&#x2013;556, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Vescovi JD, Volek JS, et al. Effects of concurrent resistance and aerobic training on load&#x2013;bearing performance and the Army physical fitness test. Mil Med 169: 994&#x2013;999, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Szivak TK. Strength training for the warfighter. J Strength Cond Res 26: S107&#x2013;S118, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H, Pihlainen K, Vaara JP, Ojanen T, Santtila M. Optimising training adaptations and performance in military environment. J Sci Med Sport 21: 1131&#x2013;1138, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroni TD, Siddall AG, Rue CA, et al. Beyond change scores: Employing an improved statistical approach to analyze the impact of entry fitness on physical performance during British Army basic training in men and women. Scand J Med Sci Sports 34: e14610, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikkonen RS, Drain JR, Vaara J, Nindl B, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H. Importance of strength training for sustaining performance and health in military personnel. BMJ Mil Health: 1&#x2013;002744, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevin JP. Is the British Army Fit to Fight in Afghanistan? Optimising Physical Performance for Dismounted Close Combat. Upavon, Wiltshire: Headquarters Land Forces, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevin JP. Autoregulated resistance training: Does velocity-based training represent the future? Strength Cond J 41: 34&#x2013;39, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevin JP, Jones MI. Human Performance Optimization (HPO) for the warfighter&#x2014;Keeping it simple in a complex age: A narrative review. Strength Cond J 45: 578&#x2013;586, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nindl BC, Barnes BR, Alemany JA, Frykman PN, Shippee RL, Friedl KE. Physiological consequences of U.S. Army Ranger Training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 39: 1380&#x2013;1387, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nindl BC, Castellani JW, Warr BJ, et al. Physiological employment standards III: Physiological challenges and consequences encountered during international military deployments. Eur J Appl Physiol 113: 2655&#x2013;2672, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce JR, Cohen BS, Hauret KG, et al. Likelihood of fitness improvements during a standardised physical fitness programme in US Army trainees of different fitness levels. BMJ Mil Health 13: e002763, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Rhea MR, Alvar BA. Maximizing strength development in athletes: A meta-analysis to determine the dose-response relationship. J Strength Cond Res 18: 377&#x2013;382, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Rhea MR, Alvar BA. Applications of the dose-response for muscular strength development: A review of meta-analytic efficacy and reliability for designing training prescription. J Strength Cond Res 19: 950&#x2013;958, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetovich TK, et al. American College of Sports Medicine&#x2014;Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rue C, Needham-Beck S, Maroni T, et al. A comparison of role-related physical fitness between British Army trainees and trained soldiers. Eur J Sport Sci 25: e12227, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Bellon CR, Hornsby WG, Stone MH. Training for muscular strength: Methods for monitoring and adjusting training intensity. Sports Med 51: 2051&#x2013;2066, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solberg PA, Paulsen G, Slaathaag OG, et al. Development and implementation of a new physical training concept in the Norwegian Navy Special Operations Command. J Strength Cond Res 29: S204&#x2013;S210, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterczala AJ, Krajewski KT, Peterson PA, et al. Twelve weeks of concurrent resistance and interval training improves military occupational task performance in men and women. Eur J Sport Sci 23: 2411&#x2013;2424, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szivak TK, Kraemer WJ. Physiological readiness, and resilience: Pillars of military preparedness. J Strength Cond Res 29: S34&#x2013;S39, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomczak M, Tomzcak E. The need to report effect size estimates revisited. An overview of some recommended measures of effect size. Trends Sports Sci 1: 19&#x2013;25, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner A. Strength and conditioning for British soldiers. Strength Cond J 38: 59&#x2013;68, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaara JP, Groeller H, Drain J, et al. Physical training considerations for optimizing performance in essential military tasks. Eur J Sport Sci 22: 43&#x2013;57, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vrijkotte S, Roelands BL, Meeusen R, Pattyn N. Sustained military operations and cognitive performance. Aerosp Med Hum Perform 87: 718&#x2013;727, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley J, Mann B, Banyard H, McLaren S, Scott T, Garcia-Ramos A. Velocity-based training: From theory to application. Strength Cond J 43: 31&#x2013;49, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson D, Blacker S, Richmond V, et al. Injuries and injury risk factors among British Army infantry soldiers during predeployment training. Inj Prev 17: 381&#x2013;387, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Marin PJ, Rhea MR, Wilson SMC, Loenneke JP, Anderson JC. Concurrent training: A meta-analysis examining interference of aerobic and resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res 26: 2293&#x2013;2307, 2012.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>