<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41823943</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2405-5018</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JACC. Clinical electrophysiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JACC Clin Electrophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Combined Analysis of Cardiac Repolarization Entropy and Magnetic Resonance Imaging Enhances Risk Stratification of Patients Receiving a Primary-Prevention ICD.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2405-500X(26)00126-X</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jacep.2026.01.051</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Accurate selection of patients who will benefit from a primary-prevention implantable cardioverter-defibrillator (ICD) remains a challenge. Cardiac magnetic resonance imaging (CMR) of myocardial tissue heterogeneity and EntropyX<sub>QT</sub>, a nonlinear electrocardiographic (ECG) measure of cardiac repolarization dynamics, predict ventricular tachyarrhythmias (VTs) and sudden cardiac arrest.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Because CMR and EntropyX<sub>QT</sub> are fundamentally distinct structural and electrical measures, we hypothesized that they add major independent prognostic value to conventional clinical predictors of sudden cardiac arrest.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In 230 consecutive patients with a left ventricular ejection fraction &#x2264;35% in sinus rhythm, baseline exposures before primary prevention ICD implantation included demographics, history, medications, laboratory results, conventional ECG indices of heart rate and QT variability, CMR myocardial tissue characterization, and EntropyX<sub>QT</sub>. The primary endpoint was ICD shock for VT, and secondary endpoints included all-cause events, including mortality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Over 6.1 &#xb1; 3.3 years of follow-up, 62 patients (27%) received appropriate ICD shocks. In multivariable analyses, EntropyX<sub>QT</sub> and CMR gray zone mass yielded adjusted hazard ratios (per SD change) of 1.8 (95% CI: 1.4-2.3) and 1.5 (95% CI: 1.2-1.8), respectively, and improved Harrell's C-statistic from 0.59 to 0.73 in a model composed of conventional clinical predictors, left ventricular end-systolic volume (LVESV) and prescribed diuretics. EntropyX<sub>QT</sub> was the strongest predictor in years 1-3, whereas CMR and LVESV were stronger in years &gt;3. Moreover, EntropyX<sub>QT</sub> independently predicted the secondary endpoints.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">EntropyX<sub>QT</sub> and CMR gray zone mass complement each other and conventional risk factors, improving risk stratification for appropriate ICD shock and mortality, and together may enhance the selection of primary prevention ICD recipients. (Prospective Observational Study of the ICD in Sudden Cardiac Death Prevention (PROSe-ICD; NCT00733590).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gokhale</LastName><ForeName>Tanmay A</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heart and Vascular Institute, University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Global Engineering Network for Intelligent Unified Healthcare Solutions, McGowan Institute for Regenerative Medicine and Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine and University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Section of Cardiac Electrophysiology, Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Veterans Affairs Pittsburgh Health System, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Veterans Health Foundation, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dey</LastName><ForeName>Swati</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Engineering Network for Intelligent Unified Healthcare Solutions, McGowan Institute for Regenerative Medicine and Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Section of Cardiac Electrophysiology, Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Veterans Affairs Pittsburgh Health System, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Veterans Health Foundation, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Department of Surgery, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Limpitikul</LastName><ForeName>Worawan B</ForeName><Initials>WB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA; Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gautam</LastName><ForeName>Nitesh</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, University of Arkansas for Medical Sciences, Little Rock, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al'Aref</LastName><ForeName>Subhi J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, University of Arkansas for Medical Sciences, Little Rock, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cross</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Cardiac Electrophysiology, Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Veterans Affairs Pittsburgh Health System, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Veterans Health Foundation, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saba</LastName><ForeName>Samir</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heart and Vascular Institute, University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine and University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Estes</LastName><ForeName>N A Mark</ForeName><Initials>NAM</Initials><Suffix>3rd</Suffix><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heart and Vascular Institute, University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine and University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vaughan</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin L</ForeName><Initials>BL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Engineering Network for Intelligent Unified Healthcare Solutions, McGowan Institute for Regenerative Medicine and Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Section of Cardiac Electrophysiology, Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Veterans Affairs Pittsburgh Health System, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Veterans Health Foundation, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Department of Surgery, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Steven R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Engineering Network for Intelligent Unified Healthcare Solutions, McGowan Institute for Regenerative Medicine and Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomaselli</LastName><ForeName>Gordon F</ForeName><Initials>GF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA; Albert Einstein College of Medicine and Montefiore Medicine, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Katherine C</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DeMazumder</LastName><ForeName>Deeptankar</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heart and Vascular Institute, University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Global Engineering Network for Intelligent Unified Healthcare Solutions, McGowan Institute for Regenerative Medicine and Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine and University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Section of Cardiac Electrophysiology, Division of Cardiology, Department of Internal Medicine, Veterans Affairs Pittsburgh Health System, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Veterans Health Foundation, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Department of Surgery, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA; Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, USA; Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA. Electronic address: deeptankar@pitt.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT00733590</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JACC Clin Electrophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101656995</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2405-500X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fibrosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">implantable cardioverter-defibrillator</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sudden cardiac arrest</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ventricular tachyarrhythmia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Funding Support and Author Disclosures This study was supported by grant awards to Dr DeMazumder from National Institutes of Health (NIH) Common Fund Director&#x2019;s New Innovator Award DP2 HL157941, NIH National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI) R00 HL130662, American Heart Association (AHA) 19AIML34930039, and AHA 17UNPG33860002; jointly to Dr DeMazumder and Dr Dey from AHA 19TPA34850151, Department of Defense (DOD) W81XWH-191-0640 #PR182372, and DOD W81XWH-201-0701 #PR191442; jointly to Dr Gokhale and Dr DeMazumder from the McKamish Family Foundation; to Dr Gokhale from NIH NHLBI T32HL129964; to Dr Wu from NIH NHLBI R01 HL103812; jointly to Dr Wu and Dr Tomaselli from NIH NHLBI R01 HL132181; and to Dr Tomaselli from NIH NHLBI R01 HL091062. The authors have no relationships relevant to the contents of this paper to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41823943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacep.2026.01.051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2405-500X(26)00126-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>