<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41849592</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2375-2548</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Science advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Isostructural electronic transition in MoS<sub>2</sub> probed by solid-state high-harmonic generation spectroscopy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>eadz5621</StartPage><MedlinePgn>eadz5621</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">eadz5621</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1126/sciadv.adz5621</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Studying materials under extreme pressure in diamond anvil cells (DACs) is key to discovering emergent states of matter, yet no method currently allows the direct measurement of the electronic structure in this environment. Solid-state high-harmonic generation (sHHG) offers a unique all-optical window into the electronic structure of materials. We demonstrate sHHG spectroscopy inside a DAC by probing 2H-MoS<sub>2</sub>, up to 30 GPa, revealing a pressure-induced crossover of the lowest direct bandgap from the <b>K</b>-point to the [Formula: see text]-point. This transition manifests as a sharp minimum in harmonic intensity and a 30&#xb0; rotation of the sHHG polarization anisotropy, despite the absence of a structural phase change. First-principles simulations attribute these features to interference between competing excitation pathways at distinct points in the Brillouin zone. Our results establish sHHG as a sensitive probe of electronic transitions at high pressure, enabling access to quantum phenomena that evade detection by conventional techniques.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nebgen</LastName><ForeName>Bailey R</ForeName><Initials>BR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1006-7092</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, University of California Berkeley, Berkeley, CA 94720, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Sciences Division, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, Berkeley, CA 94720, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Victor Chang</ForeName><Initials>VC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1767-6229</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Materials Science, Yale University, New Haven, CT 06520, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spies</LastName><ForeName>Jacob A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0148-4823</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, University of California Berkeley, Berkeley, CA 94720, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Sciences Division, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, Berkeley, CA 94720, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sterbentz</LastName><ForeName>Randy M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5464-0383</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Nevada Las Vegas, Las Vegas, NV 89154, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schwartz</LastName><ForeName>Craig P</ForeName><Initials>CP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nevada Extreme Conditions Laboratory, University of Nevada Las Vegas, Las Vegas, NV 89154, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Dean</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5491-747X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nevada Extreme Conditions Laboratory, University of Nevada Las Vegas, Las Vegas, NV 89154, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Pressure Collaborative Access Team (HPCAT), X-Ray Science Division, Argonne National Laboratory, Lemont, IL 60439, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qiu</LastName><ForeName>Diana Y</ForeName><Initials>DY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3067-6987</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Materials Science, Yale University, New Haven, CT 06520, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuerch</LastName><ForeName>Michael W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5151-2119</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, University of California Berkeley, Berkeley, CA 94720, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Sciences Division, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, Berkeley, CA 94720, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101653440</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2375-2548</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41849592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12998508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.adz5621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McMillan P. F., New materials from high-pressure experiments. Nat. Mater. 1, 19&#x2013;25 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12618843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castellanos-Gomez A., Rold&#xe1;n R., Cappelluti E., Buscema M., Guinea F., van der Zant H., Steele G. A., 
Local strain engineering in atomically thin MoS<sub>2</sub>. Nano Lett.
13, 
5361&#x2013;5366 (2013).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24083520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh W.-P., Lin C.-H., Chen C.-C., Chang J.-W., Testing the validity of the Wiedemann-Franz law for metals and alloys at high pressures. Appl. Phys. Lett. 125, 252201 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y. L., Yu X. H., Hasaien J. Z. L., Hong F., Shan P. F., Tian Z. Y., Zhai Y. N., Hu J. P., Cheng J. G., Zhao J., 
Ultrafast dynamics evidence of strong coupling superconductivity in LaH<sub>10&#xb1;&#x3b4;</sub>. Nat. Commun.
15, 
9683 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11549371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39516225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Y., Yang Y., Sun H., Zhang S., Luo J., Chen L., Ma X., Wang M., Hong F., Wang X., Yu X., 
Density-wave-like gap evolution in La<sub>3</sub>Ni<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub> under high pressure revealed by ultrafast optical spectroscopy. Nat. Commun.
15, 
10408 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11606956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39613749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Pincelli T., Jozwiak C., Kondo T., Ernstorfer R., Sato T., Zhou S., Angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy. Nat. Rev. Methods Primers 2, 54 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heide C., Kobayashi Y., Haque S. R. U., Ghimire S., Ultrafast high-harmonic spectroscopy of solids. Nat. Phys. 20, 1546&#x2013;1557 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sing You Y., Reis D. A., Ghimire S., Anisotropic high-harmonic generation in bulk crystals. Nat. Phys. Lett. 13, 345&#x2013;349 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue L., Hollinger R., Uzundal C. B., Nebgen B., Gan Z., Najafidehaghani E., George A., Spielmann C., Kartashov D., Turchanin A., Qiu D. Y., Gaarde M. B., Zuerch M., 
Signatures of multiband effects in high-harmonic generation in monolayer MoS<sub>2</sub>. Phys. Rev. Lett.
129, 
147401 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36240395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Y. L., Guo J., Gao F. Y., Liu X. S., Dynamical symmetry and valley-selective circularly polarized high-harmonic generation in monolayer molybdenum disulfide. Phys. Rev. B 105, 024305 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langer F., Hohenleutner M., Schmid C. P., Poellmann C., Nagler P., Korn T., Sch&#xfc;ller C., Sherwin M. S., Huttner U., Steiner J. T., Koch S. W., Kira M., Huber R., Lightwave-driven quasiparticle collisions on a subcycle timescale. Nature 533, 225&#x2013;229 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5034899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27172045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva R. E., Blinov I. V., Rubtsov A. N., Smirnova O., Ivanov M., High-harmonic spectroscopy of ultrafast many-body dynamics in strongly correlated systems. Nat. Photonics 12, 266&#x2013;270 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bionta M. R., Haddad E., Leblanc A., Gruson V., Lassonde P., Ibrahim H., Chaillou J., &#xc9;mond N., Otto M. R., Jim&#xe9;nez-Gal&#xe1;n &#xc1;., Silva R. E. F., Ivanov M., Siwick B. J., Chaker M., L&#xe9;gar&#xe9; F., Tracking ultrafast solid-state dynamics using high harmonic spectroscopy. Phys. Rev. Res. 3, 023250 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baykusheva D., Chac&#xf3;n A., Lu J., Bailey T. P., Sobota J. A., Soifer H., Kirchmann P. S., Rotundu C., Uher C., Heinz T. F., Reis D. A., Ghimire S., All-optical probe of three-dimensional topological insulators based on high-harmonic generation by circularly polarized laser fields. Nano Lett. 21, 8970&#x2013;8978 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34676752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heide C., Kobayashi Y., Baykusheva D. R., Jain D., Sobota J. A., Hashimoto M., Kirchmann P. S., Oh S., Heinz T. F., Reis D. A., Ghimire S., Probing topological phase transitions using high-harmonic generation. Nat. Photonics 16, 620&#x2013;624 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vampa G., Hammond T. J., Thir&#xe9; N., Schmidt B. E., L&#xe9;gar&#xe9; F., McDonald C., Brabec T., Klug D. D., Corkum P. B., All-optical reconstruction of crystal band structure. Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26588381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parks A. M., Kolesik M., Full Brillouin zone, multi-band reconstruction of the electronic structure from high-harmonic spectra. Opt. Express 33, 13986&#x2013;13999 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40798200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghimire S., Di Chiara A. D., Sistrunk E., Agostini P., Di Mauro L. F., Reis D. A., Observation of high-order harmonic generation in a bulk crystal. Nat. Phys. 7, 138&#x2013;141 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>You Y. S., Lu J., Cunningham E. F., Roedel C., Ghimire S., Crystal orientation-dependent polarization state of high-order harmonics. Opt. Lett. 44, 530&#x2013;533 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30702671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Li Y., You Y. S., Ghimire S., Heinz T. F., Reis D. A., High-harmonic generation from an atomically thin semiconductor. Nat. Phys. 13, 262&#x2013;265 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshikawa N., Nagai K., Uchida K., Takaguchi Y., Sasaki S., Miyata Y., Tanaka K., Interband resonant high-harmonic generation by valley polarized electron-hole pairs. Nat. Commun. 10, 3709 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6697745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31420551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heide C., Kobayashi Y., Johnson A. C., Liu F., Heinz T. F., Reis D. A., Ghimire S., Probing electron-hole coherence in strongly driven 2D materials using high-harmonic generation. Optica 9, 512&#x2013;516 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taucer M., Hammond T. J., Corkum P. B., Vampa G., Couture C., Thir&#xe9; N., Schmidt B. E., L&#xe9;gar&#xe9; F., Selvi H., Unsuree N., Hamilton B., Echtermeyer T. J., Denecke M. A., Nonperturbative harmonic generation in graphene from intense midinfrared pulsed light. Phys. Rev. B 96, 195420 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshikawa N., Tamaya T., Tanaka K., High-harmonic generation in graphene enhanced by elliptically polarized light excitation. Science 356, 736&#x2013;738 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28522530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv Y. Y., Xu J., Han S., Zhang C., Han Y., Zhou J., Yao S. H., Liu X. P., Lu M. H., Weng H., Xie Z., Chen Y. B., Hu J., Chen Y. F., Zhu S., 
High-harmonic generation in Weyl semimetal &#x3b2;-WP<sub>2</sub> crystals. Nat. Commun.
12, 
6437 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34750384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zong A., Nebgen B. R., Lin S.-C., Spies J. A., Zuerch M., Emerging ultrafast techniques for studying quantum materials. Nat. Rev. Mater. 8, 224&#x2013;240 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghimire S., Reis D. A., High-harmonic generation from solids. Nat. Phys. 15, 10&#x2013;16 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu S.-Q., Chen D.-Q., Du L.-L., Meng S., Solid-state high harmonic spectroscopy for all-optical band structure probing of high-pressure quantum states. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 121, e2316775121 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10861900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38300874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou Z., Zheng Y., Liu C., Zhang L., Ge X., Li Y., Wang J., Zeng Z., Li R., Xu Z., 
Ellipticity dependence of nonperturbative harmonic generation in few-layer MoS<sub>2</sub>. Opt. Commun.
469, 
125769 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Lee V., Yue L., Gaarde M. B., Chan Y., Qiu D. Y., 
Many-body enhancement of high-harmonic generation in monolayer MoS<sub>2</sub>. Nat. Commun.
15, 
6228 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11266681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39043647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nayak A. P., Bhattacharyya S., Zhu J., Liu J., Wu X., Pandey T., Jin C., Singh A. K., Akinwande D., Lin J. F., Pressure-induced semiconducting to metallic transition in multilayered molybdenum disulphide. Nat. Commun. 5, 3731 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24806118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewaele A., Torrent M., Loubeyre P., Mezouar M., Compression curves of transition metals in the Mbar range: Experiments and projector augmented-wave calculations. Phys. Rev. B 78, 104102 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aksoy R., Ma Y., Selvi E., Chyu M. C., Ertas A., White A., X-ray diffraction study of molybdenum disulfide to 38.8 GPa. J. Phys. Chem. Solid 67, 1914&#x2013;1917 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hromadov&#xe1; L., Marto&#x148;&#xe1;k R., Tosatti E., 
Structure change, layer sliding, and metallization in high-pressure MoS<sub>2</sub>. Phys. Rev. B
87, 
144105 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandaru N., Kumar R. S., Sneed D., Tschauner O., Baker J., Antonio D., Luo S.-N., Hartmann T., Zhao Y., Venkat R., 
Effect of pressure and temperature on structural stability of MoS<sub>2</sub>. J. Phys. Chem. C
118, 
3230&#x2013;3235 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan X., Chang C.-H., Zheng W. T., Kuo J.-L., Singh D. J., 
The electronic properties of single-layer and multilayer MoS<sub>2</sub> under high pressure. J. Phys. Chem. C
119, 
10189&#x2013;10196 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohn W., Sham L. J., Self-consistent equations including exchange and correlation effects. Phys. Rev. 140, A1133&#x2013;A1138 (1965).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perdew J. P., Burke K., Ernzerhof M., Generalized gradient approximation made simple. Phys. Rev. Lett. 77, 3865&#x2013;3868 (1996).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10062328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimme S., Hansen A., Brandenburg J. G., Bannwarth C., Dispersion-corrected mean-field electronic structure methods. Chem. Rev. 116, 5105&#x2013;5154 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27077966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedin L., New method for calculating the one-particle Green&#x2019;s function with application to the electron-gas problem. Phys. Rev. 139, 796&#x2013;823 (1965).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ataei S. S., Varsano D., Molinari E., Rontani M., 
Evidence of ideal excitonic insulator in bulk MoS<sub>2</sub> under pressure. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A.
118, 
e2010110118 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8020749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33758098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peelaers H., Van de Walle C. G., 
Elastic constants and pressure-induced effects in MoS<sub>2</sub>. J. Phys. Chem. C
118, 
12073&#x2013;12076 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan Y.-H., Qiu D. Y., da Jornada F. H., Louie S. G., Giant exciton-enhanced shift currents and direct current conduction with subbandgap photo excitations produced by many-electron interactions. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 118, e1906938118 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8237677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34155136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemper A. F., Moritz B., Freericks J. K., Devereaux T. P., Theoretical description of high-order harmonic generation in solids. New J. Phys. 15, 023003 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tancogne-Dejean N., Mucke O. D., Kartner F. X., Rubio A., Impact of the electronic band structure in high-harmonic generation spectra of solids. Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 087403 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28282201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue L., Gaarde M. B., Introduction to theory of high-harmonic generation in solids: Tutorial. J. Opt. Soc. Am. B 39, 535&#x2013;555 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao J., Li F., Bai Y., Liu P., Li R., 
Inter-half-cycle spectral interference in high-order harmonic generation from monolayer MoS<sub>2</sub>. Opt. Express
29, 
4830&#x2013;4841 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33726030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novoselov K. S., Jiang D., Schedin F., Booth T. J., Khotkevich V. V., Morozov S. V., Geim A. K., Two-dimensional atomic crystals. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 102, 10451&#x2013;10453 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1180777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16027370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haley K. L., Cloninger J. A., Cerminara K., Sterbentz R. M., Taniguchi T., Watanabe K., Island J. O., Heated assembly and transfer of Van der Waals heterostructures with common nail polish. Nanomanufacturing 1, 49&#x2013;56 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith D., Shelton D. P., Ellison P. B., Salamat A., Simple imaging for the diamond anvil cell: Applications to hard-to-reach places. Rev. Sci. Instr. 89, 103902 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30399781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eaton-Magana S., Shigley J. E., Observations on CVD-grown synthetic diamonds: A review. Gems Gemol. 52, 222&#x2013;245 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korican-Barlay E., Nebgen B. R., Spies J. A., Zuerch M. W., Solid-state high harmonic generation in common large bandgap substrate materials. J. Phys. Chem. A 128, 9337&#x2013;9344 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11514018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39388635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannozzi P., Baroni S., Bonini N., Calandra M., Car R., Cavazzoni C., Ceresoli D., Chiarotti G. L., Cococcioni M., Dabo I., Dal Corso A., de Gironcoli S., Fabris S., Fratesi G., Gebauer R., Gerstmann U., Gougoussis C., Kokalj A., Lazzeri M., Martin-Samos L., Marzari N., Mauri F., Mazzarello R., Paolini S., Pasquarello A., Paulatto L., Sbraccia C., Scandolo S., Sclauzero G., Seitsonen A. P., Smogunov A., Umari P., Wentzcovitch R. M., QUANTUM ESPRESSO: A modular and open-source software project for quantum simulations of materials. J. Phys. Condens. Matter 21, 395502 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21832390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherpelz P., Govoni M., Hamada I., Galli G., Implementation and validation of fully relativistic GW calculations: Spin-orbit coupling in molecules, nanocrystals, and solids. J. Chem. Theory Comput. 12, 3523&#x2013;3544 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27331614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taghizadeh A., Pedersen T. G., Nonlinear excitonic spin Hall effect in monolayer transition metal dichalcogenides. 2D Mater. 7, 015003 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attaccalite C., Gr&#xfc;ning M., Nonlinear optics from an ab initio approach by means of the dynamical Berry phase: Application to second- and third-harmonic generation in semiconductors. Phys. Rev. B 88, 235113 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klotz S., Chervin J.-C., Munsch P., Le Marchand G., Hydrostatic limits of 11 pressure transmitting media. J. Phys. D Appl. Phys. 42, 075413 (2009).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>