<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41214519</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2731-4553</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC primary care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Prim Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cost-effectiveness of a periodic fasting-mimicking diet programme in patients with type 2 diabetes: a trial-based analysis and a lifetime model-based analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>351</StartPage><MedlinePgn>351</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">351</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12875-025-03027-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The prevalence of type 2 diabetes continues to rise worldwide, which is associated with a decrease in quality of Life and an increase in healthcare costs. The aim of this study was to determine cost-effectiveness of a one year monthly 5-consecutive day fasting-mimicking diet (FMD) programme for patients with type 2 diabetes treated with lifestyle advice only or lifestyle advice plus metformin, compared to usual care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A trial-based cost-utility analysis with quality-adjusted life-years (QALYs) and healthcare costs was performed. These results were extrapolated to a lifetime horizon using the United Kingdom Prospective Diabetes Study Outcomes Model, predicting cardiovascular events and mortality. Cost-effectiveness acceptability curves were assessed, representing the probability of the FMD programme being cost-effective compared to usual care across a range of willingness-to-pay (WTP) thresholds per QALY.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">In the trial-based analysis (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;92), QALYs were insignificantly lower (-0.04, 95% CI -0.10 to&#x2009;+&#x2009;0.03), while healthcare costs were significantly higher (+&#x2009;&#x20ac;2241, 95% CI&#x2009;+&#x2009;182 to&#x2009;+&#x2009;2660) in the FMD group. In contrast, from a lifetime horizon, QALYs were insignificantly higher in the FMD group (+&#x2009;0.16, 95% CI -1.16 to&#x2009;+&#x2009;1.48) and costs were insignificantly higher as well (+&#x2009;&#x20ac;1336, 95% CI -753 to&#x2009;+&#x2009;3425), yielding an incremental cost-effectiveness ratio of &#x20ac;8369/QALY. Thus, in the lifetime analysis the probability of cost-effectiveness of the FMD programme was around 0.6 as compared to usual care at most WTP thresholds.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The FMD programme does not appear to be cost-effective over the first year of its application in the context of the Dutch healthcare system. However, this conclusion should be interpreted with caution due to the small sample size. In the extrapolations of the lifetime model-based cost-effectiveness analysis, a gain in QALYs in the FMD group was seen and the FMD programme&#x2019; costs were largely offset by savings in the costs of diabetic complications. This suggests that adding an FMD programme to usual care may potentially be cost-effective in the long term.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">ClinicalTrials.gov: NCT03811587. Registered 22 January 2019.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12875-025-03027-1.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van den Burg</LastName><ForeName>Elske L</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health and Primary Care, Leiden University Medical Centre (LUMC), Post Zone V0-P, Postbus 9600, 2300 RC, Leiden, The Netherlands. e.l.van_den_burg@lumc.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Peet</LastName><ForeName>Petra G</ForeName><Initials>PG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health and Primary Care, Leiden University Medical Centre (LUMC), Post Zone V0-P, Postbus 9600, 2300 RC, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoonakker</LastName><ForeName>Marjolein P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health and Primary Care, Leiden University Medical Centre (LUMC), Post Zone V0-P, Postbus 9600, 2300 RC, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esmeijer</LastName><ForeName>Ayla C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health and Primary Care, Leiden University Medical Centre (LUMC), Post Zone V0-P, Postbus 9600, 2300 RC, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lamb</LastName><ForeName>Hildo J</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Leiden University Medical Centre (LUMC), Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Numans</LastName><ForeName>Mattijs E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health and Primary Care, Leiden University Medical Centre (LUMC), Post Zone V0-P, Postbus 9600, 2300 RC, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pijl</LastName><ForeName>Hanno</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health and Primary Care, Leiden University Medical Centre (LUMC), Post Zone V0-P, Postbus 9600, 2300 RC, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Leiden University Medical Centre (LUMC), Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van den Akker-van Marle</LastName><ForeName>M Elske</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Data Sciences, Medical Decision Making, Leiden University Medical Centre (LUMC), Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Prim Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918300889006676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2731-4553</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cost-effectiveness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fasting-mimicking diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primary care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The Fasting In diabetes Treatment (FIT) trial protocol and amendments were approved by the Medical Research Ethics Committee of the LUMC (identifiers NL63892.058.18 and P18.049). All study participants provided informed consent. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: HJL has received consulting fees from Royal Philips and was member of the board of trustees of the Society for Cardiovascular Magnetic Resonance and European Union of Medical Specialists Radiology section without payment. The remaining authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41214519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12599020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12875-025-03027-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12875-025-03027-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sun H, Saeedi P, Karuranga S, Pinkepank M, Ogurtsova K, Duncan BB, et al. IDF diabetes atlas: global, regional and country-level diabetes prevalence estimates for 2021 and projections for 2045. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2022;183:109119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabres.2021.109119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11057359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34879977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alva M, Gray A, Mihaylova B, Clarke P. The effect of diabetes complications on health-related quality of life: the importance of longitudinal data to address patient heterogeneity. Health Econ. 2014;23(4):487&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hec.2930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23847044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zurita-Cruz JN, Manuel-Apolinar L, Arellano-Flores ML, Gutierrez-Gonzalez A, Najera-Ahumada AG, Cisneros-Gonz&#xe1;lez N. Health and quality of life outcomes impairment of quality of life in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a cross-sectional study. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2018;16(1):94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-018-0906-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5952418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29764429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bommer C, Sagalova V, Heesemann E, Manne-Goehler J, Atun R, B&#xe4;rnighausen T, et al. Global economic burden of diabetes in adults: projections from 2015 to 2030. Diabetes Care. 2018;41(5):963&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc17-1962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29475843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Einarson TR, Acs A, Ludwig C, Panton UH. Economic burden of cardiovascular disease in type 2 diabetes: a systematic review. Value Health. 2018;21(7):881&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jval.2017.12.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30005761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Bilik D, Brown MB, Zhang P, Ettner SL, Ackermann RT, et al. Medical costs associated with type 2 diabetes complications and comorbidities. Am J Manag Care. 2013;19(5):421&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4337403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23781894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alva ML, Gray A, Mihaylova B, Leal J, Holman RR. The impact of diabetes-related complications on healthcare costs: new results from the UKPDS (UKPDS 84). Diabet Med. 2015;32(4):459&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dme.12647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25439048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of a long-term behavioural weight loss intervention on nephropathy in overweight or obese adults with type 2 diabetes: a secondary analysis of the Look AHEAD randomised clinical trial. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2014;2(10):801&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4443484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25127483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G, Li Y, Pan A, Hu Y, Chen S, Qian F, et al. Adherence to a healthy lifestyle in association with microvascular complications among adults with type 2 diabetes. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6(1):e2252239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.52239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9880795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36701156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sone H, Tanaka S, Iimuro S, Tanaka S, Oida K, Yamasaki Y, et al. Long-term lifestyle intervention lowers the incidence of stroke in Japanese patients with type 2 diabetes: a nationwide multicentre randomised controlled trial (the Japan Diabetes Complications Study). Diabetologia. 2010;53(3):419&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-009-1622-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2815795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20054522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin RR, Wadden TA, Bahnson JL, Blackburn GL, Brancati FL, Bray GA, et al. Impact of intensive lifestyle intervention on depression and health-related quality of life in type 2 diabetes: the Look AHEAD trial. Diabetes Care. 2014;37(6):1544&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc13-1928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4030096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24855155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ley SH, Hamdy O, Mohan V, Hu FB. Prevention and management of type 2 diabetes: dietary components and nutritional strategies. Lancet. 2014;383(9933):1999&#x2013;2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(14)60613-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4751088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24910231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajala O, English P, Pinkney J. Systematic review and meta-analysis of different dietary approaches to the management of type 2 diabetes. Am J Clin Nutr. 2013;97(3):505&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.112.042457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23364002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Burg EL, Schoonakker MP, van Peet PG, van den Akker-van Marle ME, Willems van Dijk K, Longo VD, et al. Fasting in diabetes treatment (FIT) trial: study protocol for a randomised, controlled, assessor-blinded intervention trial on the effects of intermittent use of a fasting-mimicking diet in patients with type 2 diabetes. BMC Endocr Disord. 2020;20(1):94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7315472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32580710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Burg EL, Schoonakker MP, van Peet PG, van den Akker-van Marle EM, Lamb HJ, Longo VD, et al. Integration of a fasting-mimicking diet programme in primary care for type 2 diabetes reduces the need for medication and improves glycaemic control: a 12-month randomised controlled trial. Diabetologia. 2024;67(7):1245&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11153305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38546821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei M, Brandhorst S, Shelehchi M, Mirzaei H, Cheng CW, Budniak J, et al. Fasting-mimicking diet and markers/risk factors for aging, diabetes, cancer, and cardiovascular disease. Sci Transl Med. 2017. 10.1126/scitranslmed.aai8700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.aai8700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6816332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28202779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandhorst S, Longo VD. Protein quantity and source, fasting-mimicking diets, and longevity. Adv Nutr. 2019;10(Suppl_4):S340&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/advances/nmz079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6855936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31728501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes AJ, Leal J, Gray AM, Holman RR, Clarke PM. UKPDS outcomes model 2: a new version of a model to simulate lifetime health outcomes of patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus using data from the 30 year United Kingdom prospective diabetes study: UKPDS 82. Diabetologia. 2013;56(9):1925&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-013-2940-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23793713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herdman M, Gudex C, Lloyd A, Janssen M, Kind P, Parkin D, et al. Development and preliminary testing of the new five-level version of EQ-5D (EQ-5D-5L). Qual Life Res. 2011;20(10):1727&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-011-9903-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3220807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21479777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versteegh MM, Vermeulen KM, Evers SMAA, de Wit GA, Prenger R, Stolk EA. Dutch tariff for the five-level version of EQ-5D. Value Health. 2016;19(4):343&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jval.2016.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27325326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakkaart-van Roijen L, van der Linden N, Bouwmans C, Kanters T, Tan SS. Costing manual: methodology of costing research and reference prices for economic evaluations in healthcare [in Dutch: Kostenhandleiding: Methodologie van kostenonderzoek en referentieprijzen voor economische evaluaties in de gezondheidszorg]. Erasmus Universiteit Rotterdam. 2015:p. 2&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Central Bureau of Statistics [in Dutch: Centraal Bureau voor de Statistiek]. Consumentenprijzen; prijsindex 2015=100. Available from: https://www.cbs.nl/nl-nl/cijfers/detail/83131ned. Cited 26&#x2013;10&#x2013;2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin DB. Multiple Imputatino for Nonresponse in Surveys.1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutubuki EN, El Alili M, Bosmans JE, Oosterhuis T, F JS, Ostelo R, et al. The statistical approach in trial-based economic evaluations matters: get your statistics together! BMC Health Serv Res. 2021;21(1):475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8135982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute of Budget Education [in Dutch: Nationaal Instituut voor Budgetvoorlichting (nibud)]. Huishoudelijke uitgaven. Available from: https://www.nibud.nl/consumenten/wat-geeft-u-uit-aan-voeding/. Cited 28&#x2013;11&#x2013;2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanters TA, Bouwmans CAM, van der Linden N, Tan SS, Hakkaart-van RL. Update of the Dutch manual for costing studies in health care. PLoS One. 2017;12(11):e0187477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0187477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5679627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29121647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holman RR, Paul SK, Bethel MA, Matthews DR, Neil HA. 10-year follow-up of intensive glucose control in type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med. 2008;359(15):1577&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0806470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18784090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal J, Alva M, Gregory V, Hayes A, Mihaylova B, Gray AM, et al. Estimating risk factor progression equations for the UKPDS outcomes model 2 (UKPDS 90). Diabet Med. 2021;38(10):e14656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dme.14656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34297424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dakin HA, Farmer A, Gray AM, Holman RR. Economic evaluation of factorial trials: cost-utility analysis of the Atorvastatin in factorial with Omega EE90 risk reduction in Diabetes 2 &#xd7; 2 &#xd7; 2 factorial trial of Atorvastatin, Omega-3 fish oil, and action planning. Value Health. 2020;23(10):1340&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jval.2020.05.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7537832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33032778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwaap J, Knies S, Meijden Cvd, Staal P, Heiden Lvd. Cost-effectiveness in practice [in Dutch: Kosteneffectiviteit in de praktijk]. National Health Care Institute [in Dutch: Zorginstituut Nederland]. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulaj A, Kopf S, von Rauchhaupt E, Kliemank E, Brune M, Kender Z, et al. Six-month periodic fasting in patients with type 2 diabetes and diabetic nephropathy: a proof-of-concept study. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2022;107(8):2167&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/clinem/dgac197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9282263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35661214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang F, Lin X. Effects of Fasting-Mimicking Diet and Specific Meal Replacement Foods on Blood Glucose Control in Patients with Type 2 Diabetes: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2020;2020:6615295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/6615295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7744181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33376581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalziel K, Segal L. Time to give nutrition interventions a higher profile: cost-effectiveness of 10 nutrition interventions. Health Promot Int. 2007;22(4):271&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapro/dam027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17916604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheils JF, Rubin R, Stapleton DC. The estimated costs and savings of medical nutrition therapy: the Medicare population. J Am Diet Assoc. 1999;99(4):428&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0002-8223(99)00105-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10207394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franz MJ, Splett PL, Monk A, Barry B, McClain K, Weaver T, et al. Cost-effectiveness of medical nutrition therapy provided by dietitians for persons with non-insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus. J Am Diet Assoc. 1995;95(9):1018&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0002-8223(95)00277-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7657903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin Y, Davies A, Briggs A, McCombie L, Messow CM, Grieve E, et al. Type 2 diabetes remission: 2 year within-trial and lifetime-horizon cost-effectiveness of the Diabetes Remission Clinical Trial (DiRECT)/counterweight-plus weight management programme. Diabetologia. 2020;63(10):2112&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-020-05224-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7476973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32776237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuijten M, Marczewska A, Araujo Torres K, Rasouli B, Perugini M. A health economic model to assess the cost-effectiveness of OPTIFAST for the treatment of obesity in the United States. J Med Econ. 2018;21(9):835&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13696998.2018.1468334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29678127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nathan DM. The diabetes control and complications trial/epidemiology of diabetes interventions and complications study at 30 years: overview. Diabetes Care. 2014;37(1):9&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc13-2112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3867999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24356592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Natarajan R. Epigenetic modifications in metabolic memory: what are the memories, and can we erase them? Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2022;323(2):C570&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00201.2022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9359656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35785987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>