<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41220426</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-744X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2025</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>TheScientificWorldJournal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ScientificWorldJournal</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Avian Diversity in the Ethiopian Orthodox Churches and Monasteries in the Case of Jer Silase Monastery in North Shoa Zone, Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2958149</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2958149</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2958149</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/tswj/2958149</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ethiopian Orthodox churches and monasteries help as critical biodiversity sanctuaries, mainly for bird species. The study was carried out in and around Jer Silase Monastery between October and January of 2021 using a stratified sample design by dividing the study area into four habitat types: riverine, cliff, natural forest, and farmland. Both the transect and point count method techniques were employed. A total of nine transects and 96-point stations methodically created. Of the transects, five were applied in the cliff habitat and four were in the riverine. Of the point stations, 51 were applied in the natural forest and 45 were applied at the farmland. The data was analyzed using Mann-Whitney and Kruskal-Wallis statistical tests. A total of 116 species, belonging to 16 orders and 49 families, were recorded during the study period. Four species, namely, Abyssinian catbird, Abyssinian woodpecker, Harwood's francolin, and yellow-fronted parrot, are unique to Ethiopia, while the scavengers white-backed vultures and hooded vultures are critically endangered species. In all four habitat categories, there were significant differences in the mean abundance of bird species (<i>p</i> = 0.001). There was no visible variation in bird species abundance between the wet and dry seasons (<i>p</i> = 0.085). During the dry season, the cliff had the lowest diversity index (<i>H</i>' = 2.33), while the natural forest had the highest diversity (<i>H</i>' = 4.24). The natural forest had the maximum diversity (<i>H</i>' = 4.16) during the rainy season, whereas the cliff habitat had the lowest diversity (<i>H</i>' = 2.94). During the dry season, the highest evenness (<i>J</i> = 0.85) was recorded at the riverine, and the least evenness (<i>J</i> = 0.39) was recorded at the cliff. Also, during the wet season, the highest evenness (<i>J</i> = 0.72) was recorded in the natural forest, and the least (<i>J</i> = 0.57) was recorded at the cliff. Enhancing community-based protection and integration traditional spiritual values with contemporary conservation strategies is essential for safeguarding bird species and their habitats in the current study area as well as in other Ethiopian monasteries.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Tamenut Desalegn et al. The Scientific World Journal published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Desalegn</LastName><ForeName>Tamenut</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1508-2419</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Wildlife and Ecotourism Management, Wolkite University, Wolkite, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alemneh</LastName><ForeName>Chalachew</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-0452-693X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Wildlife and Ecotourism Management, Wolkite University, Wolkite, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diriba</LastName><ForeName>Guta</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Wildlife and Ecotourism Management, Wolkite University, Wolkite, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shasho</LastName><ForeName>Geleta</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Wildlife and Ecotourism Management, Wolkite University, Wolkite, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ScientificWorldJournal</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101131163</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1537-744X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044822" MajorTopicYN="Y">Biodiversity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001717" MajorTopicYN="Y">Birds</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017753" MajorTopicYN="N">Ecosystem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003247" MajorTopicYN="N">Conservation of Natural Resources</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065928" MajorTopicYN="N">Forests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056727" MajorTopicYN="N">Endangered Species</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Orthodox church</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">avian species</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">distribution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">habitat preference</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">monastery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">relative abundance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sanctuaries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">species composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">species richness</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41220426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12602040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/tswj/2958149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amare B., Berhane M., Wubetie G., Berhanu A. T. Review: Church Forests-the Green Spots of Ethiopian Highlands. Asian Journal of Forestry . 2019;3(2):45&#x2013;53. doi: 10.13057/asianjfor/r00300201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13057/asianjfor/r00300201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyene A. D., Blufstone R., Mekonnen A. Community Forests, Carbon Sequestration and REDD: Evidence From Ethiopia. Environment and Development Economics . 2016;21(2):249&#x2013;272. doi: 10.1017/S1355770X15000297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1355770X15000297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekonen A., Gebreegziabher B., Wassie A., Tsegay B. Review: Church Forests-the Green Spots of Ethiopian Highlands. Asian Journal of Forestry . 2019;3(2):45&#x2013;53. doi: 10.13057/asianjfor/r030201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13057/asianjfor/r030201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilahun A., Terefe H., Soromessa T. The Contribution of Ethiopian Orthodox Tewahido Church in Forest Management and Its Best Practices to Be Scaled Up in North Shewa Zone of Amhara Region, Ethiopia. Agriculture, Forestry and Fisheries . 2015;4(3):123&#x2013;137. doi: 10.11648/j.aff.20150403.18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11648/j.aff.20150403.18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woldemedhin T., Teketay D. Forest Conservation Tradition of the Ethiopian Orthodox Tewahdo Church: A Case Study in West Gojjam Zone, North-Western Ethiopia. Symbolae Botanicae Upsalienses . 2016;38:57&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilma G., Derero A. Carbon Stock and Woody Species Diversity Patterns in Church Forests Along Church Age Gradient in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. Ethiopia, Urban Ecosystems . 2020;23(5):971&#x2013;983. doi: 10.1007/s11252-020-00961-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11252-020-00961-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teku D., Abebe A., Fetene M. Ethiopian Orthodox Tewahedo Church Sacred Forests as Sanctuaries for Endangered Species: Key Roles, Challenges and Prospects. Sustainable Environment . 2024;10(1) doi: 10.1080/27658511.2024.2391614.2391614</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/27658511.2024.2391614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolde A. Review on Selected Church Forests of Ethiopia: Implication for Plant Species Conservation and Climate Change Mitigation. International Journal of Forestry Research . 2023;2023 doi: 10.1155/2023/7927301.7927301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/7927301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berhe D. H., Retta A. N., Tefera A. S., et al. Ecological Study and Forest Degradation of the Waldiba Monastery Woodland in Tigrai, Ethiopia. Discover Sustainability . 2024;5(1):p. 57. doi: 10.1007/s43621-024-00223-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43621-024-00223-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desalegn T., Negussie F. Diversity, Species Composition, and Relative Abundance of Avifauna at Debre Libanos Monastery, Ethiopia. International Journal of Zoology . 2022;2022 doi: 10.1155/2022/8697842.8697842</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/8697842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mequanint F., Wassie A., Aynalem S., et al. Larger and Older Church Forests Promote Bird Species Richness, Diversity and Resilience Across Northwest Ethiopia's Deforested Landscapes. Global Ecology and Conservation . 2024;54 doi: 10.1016/j.gecco.2024.e03165.e03165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gecco.2024.e03165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desalegn T. Behavioral Activity and Range Patterns of the Endemic Gelada Monkey (Theropithecus gelada) in and Around Jer Silase Monastery in North Shoa Zone, Ethiopia. Israel Journal of Ecology and Evolution . 2023;70(1-2):1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1163/22244662-bja10065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1163/22244662-bja10065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zebrowski W. M., Reynolds T. W. Consumed From Within? Social and Ecological Drivers of Internal Clearings in Ethiopian Orthodox Church Forests. Land Degradation &amp; Development . 2024;35(1):334&#x2013;349. doi: 10.1002/ldr.4919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ldr.4919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wassie A., Sterck F. J., Bongers F. Species and Structural Diversity of Church Forests in a Fragmented Ethiopian Highland Landscape. Journal of Vegetation Science . 2010;21(5):938&#x2013;948. doi: 10.1111/j.1654-1103.2010.01202.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1654-1103.2010.01202.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asefa A., Davies A. B., McKechnie A. E., Kinahan A. A., van Rensburg B. J. Effects of Anthropogenic Disturbance on Bird Diversity in Ethiopian Montane Forests. Ornithological Applications . 2017;119(3):416&#x2013;430. doi: 10.1650/CONDOR-16-81.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1650/CONDOR-16-81.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desalegn T. Distribution, Challenges, and Conservation Mechanism of Endemic Bird Species in Ethiopia. Israel Journal of Ecology &amp; Evolution . 2023;69(1-2):56&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BirdLife International. Country Factsheet: Ethiopia.  accessed July 30, 2025,  https://datazone.birdlife.org/country/factsheet/ethiopia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desalegn T. Threats to Gelada Baboons (Theropithecus Gelada) in and Around Jer Silase Monastry in Amhara National Regional State, North Shoa Zone, Ethiopia. Journal of Natural Sciences Research . 2020;11(19):p. 17. doi: 10.7176/JNSR/11-19-03.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7176/JNSR/11-19-03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desalegn T. Diversity of Medium and Large-Sized Mammal Species in Chilimo Forest, West Shoa Zone, Ethiopia. Israel Journal of Ecology and Evolution . 2023;69(3):1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1163/22244662-bja10064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1163/22244662-bja10064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derebe Y., Derebe B., Kassaye M., Gibru A. Species Diversity, Relative Abundance, and Distribution of Avifauna in Different Habitats Within Lewi Mountain, Awi zone, Ethiopia. Heliyon . 2023;9(6) doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e17127.e17127</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e17127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10361310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37484391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meffert P. J., Dziock F. The Influence of Urbanisation on Diversity and Trait Composition of Birds. Landscape Ecology . 2013;28(5):943&#x2013;957. doi: 10.1007/s10980-013-9867-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10980-013-9867-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiferaw A., Yazezew D. Diversity, Distribution and Relative Abundance of Avifauna at Ansas Dam and Surrounding Farmland Site Debre Berhan Town, Ethiopia. Avian Biology Research . 2021;14(1):8&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1177/1758155920963200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1758155920963200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ESRI. Arc GIS Software 10.8.1 . California: Environmental Systems Research Institute; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekele S., Tekalign W. Diversity and Relative Abundance of Avian Species in the Wetland Area Northwest of Lake Abaya, Southern Ethiopia. Scientific World Journal . 2023;2023 doi: 10.1155/2023/9964189.9964189</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/9964189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dessalegn T. Species Diversity and Abundance of Birds of Addis Ababa Bole International Airport . Addis Ababa, Ethiopia: Addis Ababa University; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desalegn T., Aynalem S., Tassie N. Diversity, Abundance and Habitat Association of Avifauna in Menagesha Amba Mariam and Gara Medhanialem Forest, in Oromia Region, Ethiopia. International Journal of Avian &amp; Wildlife Biology . 2020;5(2):1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.15406/ijawb.2020.05.00175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15406/ijawb.2020.05.00175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin G. R. Visual Fields and Their Functions in Birds. Journal of Ornithology . 2007;148(S2):547&#x2013;562. doi: 10.1007/s10336-007-0213-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10336-007-0213-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman N., Stevenson T., Fanshawe J. Birds of the Horn of Africa Ethiopia, Eritrea, Djibouti, Somalia, Socotra . Princeton, NJ USA: Princeton University Press; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain M. M., Baki M. A. Present Status of the Preliminary Survey on Avifauna Diversity and Distribution in the most Polluted River Buriganga, Dhaka, Bangladesh. International Journal of Pure and Applied Zoology . 2015;3(1):59&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I.B. Corp, IBM. Released, SPSS Statistics for Windows, Version 23.0 . Armonk, NY, USA: IBM, Corp; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammer O., Harper D., Ryan P. Past: Paleontological Statistics Software Package for Education and Data Analysis. Palaeontologia Electronica . 2001;4:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bibby C. J., Hill D. A., Mustoe S. H. Bird Census Techniques . Second. London: Academic Press; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamrat M., Bekele A. Species Composition, Distribution, Relative Abundance and Habitat Association of Bird Species From Aba Asrat Monastery, East Gojam Zone, Ethiopia. International Journal of Ecology and Environmental Sciences . 2014;40(2-3):111&#x2013;121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wani Z. A., Bhat J. A., Negi V. S., Satish K. V., Siddiqui S., Pant S. Conservation Priority Index of Species, Communities, and Habitats for Biodiversity Conservation and Their Management Planning: A Case Study in Gulmarg Wildlife Sanctuary, Kashmir Himalaya. Frontiers in Forests and Global Change . 2022;5 doi: 10.3389/ffgc.2022.995427.995427</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/ffgc.2022.995427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsegaye M., Gadisa T., Micchael G. G. Avian Diversity in Dhati Walel National Park of Western Ethiopia. International Journal of Molecular Evolution and Biodiversity . 2016;6(1):1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.5376/ijmeb.2016.06.0001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5376/ijmeb.2016.06.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tessfa E., Ejigu D., Degife G., Tassie N. Diversity, Relative Abundance, and Habitat Association of Avian Species in Tara Gedam Monastery Forest and Adjacent Habitats, Northwestern Ethiopia. Ethiopian Journal of Science and Technology . 2020;13(1):65&#x2013;80. doi: 10.4314/ejst.v13i1.5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ejst.v13i1.5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desalegn A., Subramanian C. Studies on Avian Diversity in Angereb Forest and Adjacent Farm Land With Reference to Rainy and Post Rainy Seasons, Northwestern Ethiopia. International Journal of Pure and Applied Zoology . 2015;3:219&#x2013;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin O. L., Gill F., Clench M. H.  
Passeriform
. Encyclopedia Britannica; 2022.  
 https://www.britannica.com/animal/passeriform
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siriwardena G. M., Cooke I. R., Sutherland W. J. Landscape, Cropping and Field Boundary Influences on Bird Abundance. Ecography . 2012;35(2):162&#x2013;173. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0587.2011.06839.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0587.2011.06839.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mola M., Ejigu D., Yitayih Y. Species Composition, Relative Abundance, and Habitat Association of Avifauna in Zegie Peninsula Forest Patches and Associated Wetlands, Bahir Dar, Ethiopia. International Journal of Zoology . 2021;2021 doi: 10.1155/2021/9928284.9928284</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/9928284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M. B., Chen D., Zou F. Winter Bird Diversity and Abundance in Small Farmlands in a Megacity of Southern China. Frontiers in Ecology and Evolution . 2022;10 doi: 10.3389/fevo.2022.859199.859199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fevo.2022.859199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esayas K., Bekele A. Species Composition, Relative Abundance and Distribution of the Avian Fauna of Entoto Natural Park and Escarpment, Addis Ababa. SINET: Ethiopian Journal of Science . 2011;34(2):113&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamecnik V. Metodicka prirucka pro praktickou ochranu ptaku v zemedelske krajine . AOPK CR: Praha. B; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsegaye Y., Tilahun B., Sahle M. Urban Bird Species Diversity and Abundance in Case of Wolkite Town, Southwestern Ethiopia. International Journal of Ecology and Environmental Sciences . 2019;45(3):293&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamura K., Yamaura Y., Senzaki M., Ueta M., Nakamura F. Seasonality in Spatial Distribution: Climate and Land Use Have Contrasting Effects on the Species Richness of Breeding and Wintering Birds. Ecology and Evolution . 2019;9(13):7549&#x2013;7561. doi: 10.1002/ece3.5286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ece3.5286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6636198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31346421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girma Z., Mamo Y., Mengesha G., Verma A., Asfaw T. Seasonal Abundance and Habitat Use of Bird Species in and Around Wondo Genet Forest, South-Central Ethiopia. Ecology and Evolution . 2017;7(10):3397&#x2013;3405. doi: 10.1002/ece3.2926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ece3.2926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5433982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28515875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awash N., Tekalign W. Comparison of Bird Assemblage Structures and Diversity Patterns Between Seasons Among Two Ethiopian Wetlands. BMC Zoology . 2023;8(1):p. 3. doi: 10.1186/s40850-023-00164-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40850-023-00164-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10127002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37170360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nepali A. Seasonal Variation of Bird Diversity in Dhaneshwor Baikiwa Community Forest, Kavrepalanchowk District, Nepal . Doctoral dissertation, Central Department of Zoology; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katuwal H. B., Pradhan N. B., Thakuri J. J., Bhusal K. P., Aryal P. C., Thapa I. Effect of Urbanization and Seasonality in Bird Communities of Kathmandu Valley, Nepal. Proceedings of the Zoological Society . 2018;71(2):103&#x2013;113. doi: 10.1007/s12595-018-0265-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12595-018-0265-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzortzakaki O., Kati V., Kassara C., Tietze D. T., Giokas S. Seasonal Patterns of Urban Bird Diversity in a Mediterranean Coastal City: The Positive Role of Open Green Spaces. Urban Ecosystem . 2018;21(1):27&#x2013;39. doi: 10.1007/s11252-017-0695-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11252-017-0695-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almazan-Nunez R. C., Arizmendi M. C., Eguiarte L. E., Corcuera P. Distribution of the Community of Frugivorous Birds Along a Successional Gradient in a Tropical Dry Forest in Southwestern Mexico. Journal of Tropical Ecology . 2015;31(1):57&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1017/S0266467414000601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0266467414000601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genet Y., Ejigu D. Community Composition, Relative Abundance and Habitat Association of Avian Species in Apini and Dikuma Forest Patches, Awi Administrative Zone, Ethiopia. Ethiopian Journal of Science and Technology . 2017;10(1):33&#x2013;50. doi: 10.4314/ejst.v10i1.3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ejst.v10i1.3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahanbakhsh M., Khorasani N., Ganjeh M., Javad D., Afshin N. Factors Influencing Abundance and Species Richness of Overwintered Waterbirds in Parishan International Wetland in Iran. Applied Ecology and Environmental Research . 2017;15(4):1565&#x2013;1579. doi: 10.15666/aeer/1504_15651579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15666/aeer/1504_15651579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>