<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41739357</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1861-6429</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of computer assisted radiology and surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Comput Assist Radiol Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>AURA-CVC: Autonomous Ultrasound-guided Robotic Assistance for Central Venous Catheterization.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11548-026-03572-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Central venous catheterization (CVC) is a critical medical procedure for vascular access, hemodynamic monitoring, and life-saving interventions. Its success remains challenging due to the need for continuous ultrasound-guided visualization of a target vessel and approaching needle, which is further complicated by anatomical variability and operator dependency. Errors in needle placement can lead to life-threatening complications. While robotic systems offer a potential solution, achieving full autonomy remains challenging. In this work, we propose an end-to-end robotic ultrasound-guided CVC pipeline, from scan initialization to needle insertion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We introduce a deep-learning model to identify clinically relevant anatomical landmarks from a depth image of the patient's neck, obtained using an RGB-D camera, to autonomously define the scanning region and paths. Then, a robot motion planning framework is proposed to scan, segment, reconstruct, and localize vessels (veins and arteries), followed by the identification of the optimal insertion zone. Finally, a needle guidance module plans the insertion under ultrasound guidance with operator's feedback. This pipeline was validated on a high-fidelity commercial phantom across 10 simulated clinical scenarios.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The proposed pipeline achieved 10 out of 10 successful needle placements on the first attempt. Vessels were reconstructed with a mean error of 2.15 mm, and autonomous needle insertion was performed with an error less than or close to 1&#xa0;mm.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">To our knowledge, this is the first robotic CVC system demonstrated on a high-fidelity phantom with integrated planning, scanning, and insertion. Experimental results show its potential for clinical translation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. CARS.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raina</LastName><ForeName>Deepak</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5863-6111</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Malone Center for Engineering in Healthcare, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD 21218, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Indian Institute of Technology Mandi, Himachal Pradesh, 175005, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Zogbi</LastName><ForeName>Lidia</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Whiting School of Engineering, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD 21218, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN, 37235, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teixeira</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Imaging Technologies, Siemens Medical Solutions, Inc., Princeton, NJ 08540, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Vivek</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Imaging Technologies, Siemens Medical Solutions, Inc., Princeton, NJ 08540, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kapoor</LastName><ForeName>Ankur</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Imaging Technologies, Siemens Medical Solutions, Inc., Princeton, NJ 08540, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fleiter</LastName><ForeName>Thorsten</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>R. Cowley Shock Trauma Center, Department of Diagnostic Radiology, School of Medicine, University of Maryland, Baltimore, MD 21201, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Bell</LastName><ForeName>Muyinatu A Lediju</ForeName><Initials>MAL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8394-4482</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Pandian</LastName><ForeName>Vinciya</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2260-1080</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ross and Carol Nese College of Nursing, The Pennsylvania State University, University Park, PA 16802, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Krieger</LastName><ForeName>Axel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Whiting School of Engineering and Malone Centre for Engineering in Healthcare, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD 21218, USA. axel@jhu.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>7R18HS029124-03</GrantID><Acronym>HS</Acronym><Agency>AHRQ HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2222716</GrantID><Agency>National Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2431810</GrantID><Agency>National Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Malone Postdoctoral Fellowship</GrantID><Agency>Whiting School of Engineering, Johns Hopkins University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2144348</GrantID><Agency>Whiting School of Engineering, Johns Hopkins University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Comput Assist Radiol Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101499225</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1861-6410</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Central venous catheterization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Motion-planning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Robotic ultrasound</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasound-guided interventions</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41739357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11548-026-03572-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11548-026-03572-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kehagias E, Galanakis N, Tsetis D (2023) Central venous catheters: Which, when and how. Br J Radiol 96(1151):20220894</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1259/bjr.20220894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37191031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10607393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govindan S, Snyder A, Flanders SA, Chopra V (2018) Peripherally inserted central catheters in the icu: a retrospective study of adult medical patients in 52 hospitals. Crit Care Med 46(12):1136&#x2013;1144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0000000000003423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teja B, Bosch NA, Diep C, Pereira TV, Mauricio P, Sklar MC, Sankar A, Wijeysundera HC, Saskin R, Walkey A et al (2024) Complication rates of central venous catheters: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Intern Med 184(5):474&#x2013;482</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2023.8232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38436976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12285596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas P, Sikander S, Kulkarni P (2023) Recent advances in robot-assisted surgical systems. Biomed Eng Adv 6:100109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bea.2023.100109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raina D, Singh H, Saha SK, Arora C, Agarwal A, Chandrashekhara S, Rangarajan K, Nandi S (2021) Comprehensive telerobotic ultrasound system for abdominal imaging: Development and in-vivo feasibility study. In: 2021 International Symposium on Medical Robotics (ISMR), 1&#x2013;7. IEEE</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raina D, Balakuntala MV, Kim BW, Wachs J, Voyles R (2024) Coaching a robotic sonographer: Learning robotic ultrasound with sparse expert&#x2019;s feedback. IEEE Transactions on Medical Robotics and Bionics</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slocum A, Bassett E, Karp JM, Langer RS, Farokhzad OC (2014) Methods and devices for sensing tissues and tissue compartments. Google Patents. US Patent 8,920,388</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Z, Davies BL, Caldwell DG, Mattos LS (2019) A hand-held robot for precise and safe pivc. IEEE Robot Autom Lett 4(2):655&#x2013;661</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LRA.2019.2892380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikhsan M, Tan KK, Putra AS (2018) Assistive technology for ultrasound-guided central venous catheter placement. J Med Ultrason 45:41&#x2013;57</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10396-017-0789-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zevallos N, Harber E, Patel K, Gu Y, Sladick K, Guyette F, Weiss L, Pinsky MR, Gomez H, Galeotti J et al (2021) Toward robotically automated femoral vascular access. In: 2021 International Symposium on Medical Robotics (ISMR), 1&#x2013;7. IEEE</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zevallos N, Morales CG, Orekhov A, Rane T, Gomez H, Guyette FX, Pinsky MR, Galeotti J, Dubrawski A, Choset H (2025) Automatic cannulation of femoral vessels in a porcine shock model. arXiv preprint arXiv:2506.14467</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Wang F, Lin Y, Shi Q, Wang Y (2021) Ultrasound-guided needle insertion robotic system for percutaneous puncture. Int J Comput Assist Radiol Surg 16:475&#x2013;484</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11548-020-02300-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33484429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koskinopoulou M, Cheng Z, Acemoglu A, Caldwell DG, Mattos LS (2023) Robotic devices for assisted and autonomous intravenous access. IEEE Trans Med Robot Bionics 5(2):170&#x2013;179</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMRB.2023.3269844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herlihy JP, Cohn WE, Ebner A (2025) Centrally inserted central catheter placement using a novel, handheld, image-guided, robotic device: Results of initial feasibility trial in patients. The Journal of Vascular Access, 11297298241273637</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong J, Dohi T, Hashizume M, Konishi K, Hata N (2004) An ultrasound-driven needle-insertion robot for percutaneous cholecystostomy. Phys Med Biol 49(3):441</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/0031-9155/49/3/007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15012012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neubach Z, Shoham M (2009) Ultrasound-guided robot for flexible needle steering. IEEE Trans Biomed Eng 57(4):799&#x2013;805</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TBME.2009.2030169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19709957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Jia Z-Z, Song Z-J, Yang X-D, Chen K, Liang P (2010) Three-dimensional ultrasound image-guided robotic system for accurate microwave coagulation of malignant liver tumours. Int J Med Robot Comput Assisted Surg 6(3):256&#x2013;268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rcs.313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatelain P, Krupa A, Navab N (2015) 3d ultrasound-guided robotic steering of a flexible needle via visual servoing. In: 2015 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2250&#x2013;2255 (2015). IEEE</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zettinig O, Frisch B, Virga S, Esposito M, Rienm&#xfc;ller A, Meyer B, Hennersperger C, Ryang Y-M, Navab N (2017) 3d ultrasound registration-based visual servoing for neurosurgical navigation. Int J Comput Assist Radiol Surg 12:1607&#x2013;1619</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11548-017-1536-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28236117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kojcev R, Fuerst B, Zettinig O, Fotouhi J, Lee SC, Frisch B, Taylor R, Sinibaldi E, Navab N (2016) Dual-robot ultrasound-guided needle placement: closing the planning-imaging-action loop. Int J Comput Assist Radiol Surg 11:1173&#x2013;1181</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11548-016-1408-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27097600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell MAL, Shubert J (2018) Photoacoustic-based visual servoing of a needle tip. Sci Rep 8:15519</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-33931-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubbi MR, Bell MAL (2021) Deep learning-based photoacoustic visual servoing: Using outputs from raw sensor data as inputs to a robot controller. In: Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA). IEEE</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubbi MR, Kolandaivelu A, Venkatayogi N, Zhang J, Warbal P, Keene GC, Khairalseed M, Chrispin J, Bell MAL (2026) In Vivo demonstration of deep learning-based photoacoustic visual servoing system. IEEE Trans Biomed Eng 73(1):417&#x2013;431</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Z, Davies BL, Caldwell DG, Mattos LS (2016) A venipuncture detection system for robot-assisted intravenous catheterization. In: 2016 6th IEEE International Conference on Biomedical Robotics and Biomechatronics (BioRob), 80&#x2013;86. IEEE</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koskinopoulou M, Acemoglu A, Penza V, Mattos LS (2023) Dual robot collaborative system for autonomous venous access based on ultrasound and bioimpedance sensing technology. In: 2023 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 4648&#x2013;4653. IEEE</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim C, Chang D, Petrisor D, Chirikjian G, Han M, Stoianovici D (2013) Ultrasound probe and needle-guide calibration for robotic ultrasound scanning and needle targeting. IEEE Trans Biomed Eng 60(6):1728&#x2013;1734</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosnik N, Kowalski T, Lorenz L, Valacer M, Sakthi-Velavan S (2024) Anatomical review of internal jugular vein cannulation. Folia Morphol 83(1):1&#x2013;19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5603/FM.a2023.0008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira B, Singh V, Tamersoy B, Prokein A, Kapoor A (2023) Automated ct lung cancer screening workflow using 3d camera. In: International Conference on Medical Image Computing and Computer-Assisted Intervention, 423&#x2013;431. Springer</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Chen H, Qi X, Dou Q, Fu C-W, Heng P-A (2018) H-denseunet: hybrid densely connected unet for liver and tumor segmentation from ct volumes. IEEE Trans Med Imaging 37(12):2663&#x2013;2674</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMI.2018.2845918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29994201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Zogbi L, Raina D, Pandian V, Fleiter T, Krieger A (2025) Robotic ultrasound-guided femoral artery reconstruction of anatomically-representative phantoms. arXiv preprint arXiv:2503.06795</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi UG, Rigamonti P, Tich&#xe0; V, Zoffoli E, Giordano A, Gallieni M, Cariati M (2014) Percutaneous ultrasound-guided central venous catheters: the lateral in-plane technique for internal jugular vein access. J Vasc Access 15(1):56&#x2013;60</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5301/jva.5000177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24101418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>