<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41535801</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2318</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC geriatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Geriatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Feasibility and preliminary effects of non-immersive virtual reality motor-cognitive treadmill training in older Veterans: a single-arm pilot study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>193</StartPage><MedlinePgn>193</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">193</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12877-025-06914-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Daily life involves the successful completion of dual task walking activities and is a dynamic integration of motor and cognitive skills to meet environmental and postural demands to avoid a fall. Older Veterans face greater cognitive decline risk, greater comorbidities, and poorer health than non-veterans and have a higher age-related fall risk. Non-immersive VR motor-cognitive treadmill (VR-TM) training can improve balance, walking, and fall risk in older adults but has not been studied in older Veterans and has been largely studied in neurological populations. This pilot study proposed to investigate the acceptance and feasibility of using VR-TM among older Veterans with a history of falls or documented fall risk.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY">Thirty community-dwelling older Veterans aged 65-to-88&#xa0;years (26 male, 4 female) consented and twenty-three completed this single-arm pilot study. Participants received 14 treatment sessions over 7-weeks using a VR-TM system to walk over virtual obstacles on a treadmill. Balance performance, walking endurance, quality of life (QOL), fear of falling and balance confidence were assessed pre- and post-training. A satisfaction survey was conducted post-training. Descriptive statistics examined fall incidence prior to training and over a six-month retention. Paired t-test and Wilcoxon signed-ranked test performed on the twenty-three completers examined longitudinal change at significance level <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The Mini Balance Evaluation Systems Test (Mini-BESTest) had a statistically significant change (20.9&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.20; 23.13&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;3.03; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01) and six participants had a 4-point improvement reflective of a minimal clinically important difference (MCID). The Activities-specific Balance Confidence scale improved post-training (65.18&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;21.68; 73.04&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;18.40; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.02) and four participants had a&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;18% (MCID) confidence gain. VR-TM training was a feasible intervention in this population and twenty-three out of the thirty consented Veterans (76.6%) completed the protocol. Ninety-four percent of these completers would recommend the VR-TM training to a friend. No significant change was seen in walking performance, walking endurance, QOL outcomes or fall incidence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The VR-TM training was well accepted and feasible in a small heterogenous cohort of older Veterans with complex comorbidities. Larger randomized trials will be needed to confirm its benefits to balance performance, dual task ability and fall prevention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">This small, non-randomized, non-blinded single-arm feasibility pilot with restricted enrollment to patients at a single medical center was not posted to ClinicalTrials.gov.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Conroy</LastName><ForeName>Susan S</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baltimore VA Medical Center Geriatric Research, Education and Clinical Center, Veterans Health Administration, Baltimore, MD, USA. susan.conroy@va.gov.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy and Rehabilitation Science, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, USA. susan.conroy@va.gov.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stookey</LastName><ForeName>Alyssa</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baltimore VA Medical Center Geriatric Research, Education and Clinical Center, Veterans Health Administration, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Division of Gerontology, Geriatrics and Palliative Medicine, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beamer</LastName><ForeName>Brock A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baltimore VA Medical Center Geriatric Research, Education and Clinical Center, Veterans Health Administration, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Division of Gerontology, Geriatrics and Palliative Medicine, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sorkin</LastName><ForeName>John D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baltimore VA Medical Center Geriatric Research, Education and Clinical Center, Veterans Health Administration, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Division of Gerontology, Geriatrics and Palliative Medicine, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P30 AG028747</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Geriatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968548</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2318</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ageing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Balance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dual-task training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fall prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Falls</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-immersive virtual reality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Virtual reality</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study protocol was reviewed and approved University of Maryland Baltimore Institutional Review Board (IRB) approval no. HP 00099764 and the Baltimore Veterans Affairs Research and Development Committee and study procedures were conducted in accordance with Helsinki Declarations and in compliance with all ethical practices and guidelines. Informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to participation. Consent for publication: Consent for photography and publication was obtained and is on record and available on request from the corresponding author [SC]. Competing interests: The authors declare the following conflict of interest with respect to the research design. GaitBetter, Inc. contributed the virtual reality study equipment utilized in the study but was not involved in study activities, data collection or interpretation and did not contribute to authorship or writing.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41535801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12888129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-025-06914-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12877-025-06914-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Older Adult Falls Data. Older adult fall prevention. CDC. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/falls/data-research/index.html. Cited 2025 Jun 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Florence CS, Bergen G, Atherly A, Burns E, Stevens J, Drake C. Medical costs of fatal and nonfatal falls in older adults. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2018;66(4):693&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6089380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29512120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malcolm BR, Foxe JJ, Butler JS, De Sanctis P. The aging brain shows less flexible reallocation of cognitive resources during dual-task walking: a mobile brain/body imaging (MoBI) study. Neuroimage. 2015;117:230&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5080979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25988225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolan M, Nitz J, Choy NL, Illing S. Age-related changes in musculoskeletal function, balance and mobility measures in men aged 30&#x2013;80 years. Aging Male. 2010;13(3):194&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20441404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughton CA, Slavin M, Katdare K, Nolan L, Bean JF, Kerrigan DC, et al. Aging, muscle activity, and balance control: physiologic changes associated with balance impairment. Gait Posture. 2003;18(2):101&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14654213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bureau UC. Census.gov. Aging veterans: America&#x2019;s veterans in later life. Available from: https://www.census.gov/library/publications/2023/acs/acs-54.html. Cited 2025 Jun 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marciniak D, Alexander NB, Hoffman GJ. Physical activity and falls among a national cohort of older veterans. J Appl Gerontol. 2021;40(3):310&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7554127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32274955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao LL. The prevalence of mild cognitive impairment in a convenience sample of 202 gulf war veterans. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(19):7158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7579246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33007845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herold F, Hamacher D, Schega L, M&#xfc;ller NG. Thinking while moving or moving while thinking &#x2013; concepts of motor-cognitive training for cognitive performance enhancement. Front Aging Neurosci. 2018;6(10):228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6089337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30127732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buele J, Palacios-Navarro G. Cognitive-motor interventions based on virtual reality and instrumental activities of daily living (iADL): an overview. Front Aging Neurosci. 2023;15(15):1191729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10311491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37396651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirelman A, Rochester L, Maidan I, Del Din S, Alcock L, Nieuwhof F, et al. Addition of a non-immersive virtual reality component to treadmill training to reduce fall risk in older adults (V-TIME): a randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2016;388(10050):1170&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27524393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evidence-based falls prevention programs for older adults. 2023. Available from: https://www.ncoa.org/article/evidence-based-falls-prevention-programs/. Cited 2025 Jun 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwan RYC, Liu JYW, Fong KNK, Qin J, Leung PKY, Sin OSK, et al. Feasibility and effects of virtual reality motor-cognitive training in community-dwelling older people with cognitive frailty: pilot randomized controlled trial. JMIR Serious Games. 2021;9(3):e28400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8380584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34383662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dockx K, Alcock L, Bekkers E, Ginis P, Reelick M, Pelosin E, et al. Fall-prone older people&#x2019;s attitudes towards the use of virtual reality technology for fall prevention. Gerontology. 2017;63(6):590&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28817828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf8;eg ER, Povlsen TM, Bruun-Pedersen JR, Lange B, Nilsson NC, Haugaard KB, et al. System immersion in virtual reality-based rehabilitation of motor function in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Virtual Real. 2021;12(2):647993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Almagro D, Achalandabaso-Ochoa A, Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Vera AJ, G&#xf3;ngora-Rodr&#xed;guez J, Rodr&#xed;guez-Huguet M. Effectiveness of virtual reality therapy on balance and gait in the elderly: a systematic review. Healthcare. 2024;12(2):158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10815791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38255047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peruzzi A, Zarbo IR, Cereatti A, Della Croce U, Mirelman A. An innovative training program based on virtual reality and treadmill: effects on gait of persons with multiple sclerosis. Disabil Rehabil. 2017;39(15):1557&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27808596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shema SR, Brozgol M, Dorfman M, Maidan I, Sharaby-Yeshayahu L, Malik-Kozuch H, et al. Clinical experience using a 5-week treadmill training program with virtual reality to enhance gait in an ambulatory physical therapy service. Phys Ther. 2014;94(9):1319&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24786944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummings-Vaughn LA, Chavakula NN, Malmstrom TK, Tumosa N, Morley JE, Cruz-Oliver DM. Veterans affairs saint Louis university mental status examination compared with the Montreal cognitive assessment and the short test of mental status. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2014;62(7):1341&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24916485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godi M, Franchignoni F, Caligari M, Giordano A, Turcato AM, Nardone A. Comparison of reliability, validity, and responsiveness of the mini-BESTest and Berg balance scale in patients with balance disorders. Phys Ther. 2013;93(2):158&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23023812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnani PE, Genovez MB, Porto JM, Zanellato NFG, Alvarenga IC, Freire RC, et al. Use of the BESTest and the Mini-BESTest for fall risk prediction in community-dwelling older adults between 60 and 102 years of age. J Geriatr Phys Ther. 2020;43(4):179&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31162155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleary K, Skornyakov E. Predicting falls in older adults using the four square step test. Physiother Theory Pract. 2017;33(10):766&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28771062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng S, Chan S, Chan A, Chung H, Lee N, Ngan A, et al. Reliability and concurrent validity of standardized walking obstacle course test in people with stroke. J Rehabil Med. 2017;49(9):705&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28862316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohannon RW, Wang YC, Gershon RC. Two-minute walk test performance by adults 18 to 85 years: normative values, reliability, and responsiveness. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2015;96(3):472&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25450135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shumway-Cook A, Brauer S, Woollacott M. Predicting the probability for falls in community-dwelling older adults using the timed up &amp; go test. Phys Ther. 2000;80(9):896&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10960937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima LCA, Ansai JH, Andrade LP, Takahashi ACM. The relationship between dual-task and cognitive performance among elderly participants who exercise regularly. Braz J Phys Ther. 2015;19(2):159&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4481837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25993629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syddall HE, Martin HJ, Harwood RH, Cooper C, Sayer AA. The SF-36: a simple, effective measure of mobility-disability for epidemiological studies. J Nutr Health Aging. 2009;13(1):57&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2654814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19151909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walters SJ, Campbell MJ, Lall R. Design and analysis of trials with quality of life as an outcome: a practical guide. J Biopharm Stat. 2001;11(3):155&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11725929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell LE, Myers AM. The Activities-specific Balance Confidence (ABC) scale. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 1995;50A(1):M28-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7814786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lajoie Y, Gallagher SP. Predicting falls within the elderly community: comparison of postural sway, reaction time, the Berg balance scale and the Activities-specific Balance Confidence (ABC) scale for comparing fallers and non-fallers. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2004;38(1):11&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14599700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellons RD, Duhe SE, MacDowell SG, Hodge A, Oxborough S, Levitzky EE. Estimating the minimal clinically important difference for balance and gait outcome measures in individuals with vestibular disorders. J Vestib Res. 2022;32(3):223&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35147571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinetti ME, Richman D, Powell L. Falls efficacy as a measure of fear of falling. J Gerontol. 1990;45(6):P239&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2229948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falls. Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/falls. Cited 2025 Jun 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R: the R project for statistical computing. Available from: https://www.r-project.org/. Cited 2025 Jun 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Streitberg B, Roehmel J. Exact distributions for permuttion and rank tests: an introduction to some recently published algorithms. Stat Softw Newsl. 1986. Available from: ISSN 1609&#x2013;361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dite W, Temple VA. A clinical test of stepping and change of direction to identify multiple falling older adults. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2002;83(11):1566&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12422327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lord SR, Murray SM, Chapman K, Munro B, Tiedemann A. Sit-to-stand performance depends on sensation, speed, balance, and psychological status in addition to strength in older people. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2002;57(8):M539&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12145369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirelman A, Maidan I, Herman T, Deutsch JE, Giladi N, Hausdorff JM. Virtual reality for gait training: can it induce motor learning to enhance complex walking and reduce fall risk in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease? J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2011;66A(2):234&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21106702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joubert C, Chainay H. Aging brain: the effect of combined cognitive and physical training on cognition as compared to cognitive and physical training alone &amp;ndash; a systematic review. Clin Interv Aging. 2018;13:1267&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6057553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30057444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes-Osman J, Cabral DF, Morris TP, McInerney K, Cahalin LP, Rundek T, et al. Exercise for cognitive brain health in aging: a systematic review for an evaluation of dose. Neurol Clin Pract. 2018;8(3):257&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6075983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30105166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelosin E, Ponte C, Putzolu M, Lagravinese G, Hausdorff JM, Nieuwboer A, et al. Motor-cognitive treadmill training with virtual reality in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: the effect of training duration. Front Aging Neurosci. 2022;13:753381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8767105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35069171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Din S, Galna B, Lord S, Nieuwboer A, Bekkers EMJ, Pelosin E, et al. Falls risk in relation to activity exposure in high-risk older adults. Magaziner J, editor. J Gerontol Ser A. 2020;75(6):1198&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7243591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31942969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asai T, Oshima K, Fukumoto Y, Yonezawa Y, Matsuo A, Misu S. The association between fear of falling and occurrence of falls: a one-year cohort study. BMC Geriatr. 2022;22(1):393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9069732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35509040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freiberger E, De Vreede P. Falls recall&#x2014;limitations of the most used inclusion criteria. Eur Rev Aging Phys Act. 2011;8(2):105&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson KI, Hillman C, Stillman CM, Ballard RM, Bloodgood B, Conroy DE, et al. Physical activity, cognition, and brain outcomes: a review of the 2018 physical activity guidelines. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(6):1242&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6527141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31095081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elgaddal N. Physical activity among adults aged 18 and over: United States, 2020. NCHS Data Brief. 2022;(443).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36043905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Schaik P, Blake J, Pernet F, Spears I, Fencott C. Virtual augmented exercise gaming for older adults. Cyberpsychol Behav. 2008;11(1):103&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18275322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishchyk A, Chen W, Pripp AH, Bergland A. The effect of mixed reality technologies for falls prevention among older adults: systematic review and meta-analysis. JMIR Aging. 2021;4(2):e27972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34255643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phu S, Vogrin S, Al Saedi A, Duque G. Balance training using virtual reality improves balance and physical performance in older adults at high risk of falls. Clin Interv Aging. 2019;14:1567&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6717859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31695345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osho O, Owoeye O, Armijo-Olivo S. Adherence and attrition in fall prevention exercise programs for community-dwelling older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Aging Phys Act. 2018;26(2):304&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28771111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bevilacqua, Maranesi, Riccardi, Donna, Pelliccioni, Luzi, et al. Non-immersive virtual reality for rehabilitation of the older people: a systematic review into efficacy and effectiveness. J Clin Med. 2019;8(11):1882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6912349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31694337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva De Sousa JC, Torriani-Pasin C, Tosi AB, Fecchio RY, Costa LAR, Forjaz CLDM. Aerobic stimulus induced by virtual reality games in stroke survivors. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2018;99(5):927&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29428343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turan&#xa0;Kavradim S, Yang&#xf6;z &#x15e;T, &#xd6;zer Z. Effectiveness of virtual reality interventions on physiological and psychological outcomes of adults with cardiovascular disease: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Nurs Scholarsh. 2023:jnu.12885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36942847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turan Kavradim S, Yang&#xf6;z &#x15e;T, &#xd6;zer Z. Effectiveness of virtual reality interventions on physiological and psychological outcomes of adults with cardiovascular disease: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Nurs Scholarsh. 2023 Mar 21;55(5):946-966.&#xa0;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36942847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Streitberg B, Roehmel J. Exact Distributions for Permuttion and Rank Tests: An Introduction to Some Recently Published Algorithms [Internet]. Statistical Software Newsletter. 1986;12:18&#x2013;19. Available from: ISSN 1609-361</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>