<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41771951</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The impact of fly ash and slag on the microscopic interface of recycled concrete and its destruction evolution.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9565</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-17035-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The interfacial transition zones in recycled concrete are the main factors affecting their durability and strength. The interfacial transition zones (ITZS) in recycled concrete are the main factors affecting durability and strength, yet their response to combined use of fly ash and slag remains insufficiently understood. This study investigates the influence of different replacement levels of recycled aggregate, fly ash, and slag on ITZS properties through both microscopic and macroscopic testing, combined with numerical simulation of the failure process. The results show that the minimal ITZS effect occurred when the recycled aggregate content was 40% and slag content was 10%, under which the compressive strength reached 32.8&#xa0;MPa and the splitting tensile strength reached 3.21&#xa0;MPa, representing reductions of only 4.5% and 5.2% compared with ordinary concrete, respectively. Microscopic observations revealed that cracks initiate predominantly in porous ITZS regions and propagate inward, a process well captured by the cohesive zone model simulations. These findings indicate that a balanced combination of recycled aggregate, fly ash, and slag can achieve mechanical performance comparable to conventional concrete, offering a viable approach to promote sustainable utilization of industrial by-products in structural applications. Specifically, under these conditions, the compressive strength reached 32.8&#xa0;MPa and the splitting tensile strength reached 3.21&#xa0;MPa, representing reductions of only 4.5% and 5.2% compared with ordinary concrete, respectively. These results indicate that partial substitution of recycled aggregate combined with moderate slag content can produce concrete with mechanical performance comparable to that of conventional concrete, while promoting sustainable use of industrial by-products in structural applications. In addition, the failure of recycled concrete was demonstrated based on microscopic results, from which the failure of recycled concrete was found to be a gradual failure from the outside to the inside. The failure zone first appeared in the interfacial transition zones with large porosities and large area, where internal cracks were generated and gradually spread. Structural failure occurred after the cracks had penetrated.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liuzhou Railway Vocational Technical College, Liuzhou, 545616, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Key Laboratory of Engineering Disaster Prevention and Structural Safety of Ministry of Eduction, Guangxi University, Nanning, 530004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Zi'er</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liuzhou Railway Vocational Technical College, Liuzhou, 545616, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jingming</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liuzhou Railway Vocational Technical College, Liuzhou, 545616, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liuzhou Railway Vocational Technical College, Liuzhou, 545616, China. zhang906412703@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Key Laboratory of Engineering Disaster Prevention and Structural Safety of Ministry of Eduction, Guangxi University, Nanning, 530004, China. zhang906412703@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangxi Key Laboratory of Disaster Prevention and Engineering Safety, Guangxi University, Nanning, 530004, China. zhang906412703@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Fujun</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil and Engineering, Xi'an University of Technology, Xi'an, 710000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Planning and Construction Bureau of the Management Committee of Xinjiang Zhundong Economic and Technological Development Zone, Changji, 831700, Xinjiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023KY1451</GrantID><Agency>Guangxi University young and middle-aged research basic ability improvement project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Damage mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Interfacial transition zones</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recycled concrete</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41771951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13009516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-17035-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-17035-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fang, Y. et al. Carbon emissions in the life cycle of urban Building system in China&#x2014;A case study of residential Buildings. <i>Ecol. Complex.</i><b>8</b>(2), 201&#x2013;212. 10.1016/j.ecocom.2011.02.003 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecocom.2011.02.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallis, S. L., Lemckert, C. &amp; Hardy, R. Disposal &amp; or treatment: Future considerations for solid waste from the construction and demolition industry. <i>International Conference on Waste Management and the Environment</i>. 10.2495/wm200161 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva, R. V., Brito, J. D. &amp; Dhir, R. K. Properties and composition of recycled aggregates from construction and demolition waste suitable for concrete production. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>65</b>, 201&#x2013;217. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.04.117 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuaklong, P. et al. Enhancement of mechanical properties of fly Ash geopolymer containing fine recycled concrete aggregate with micro carbon fiber. <i>J. Building Eng.</i><b>41</b>, 102403. 10.1016/j.jobe.2021.102403 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.102403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zareei, S. A. et al. Rice husk Ash as a partial replacement of cement in high strength concrete containing micro silica: evaluating durability and mechanical properties. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>7</b>, 73&#x2013;81. 10.1016/j.cscm.2017.05.001 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2017.05.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sab&#x103;u, M., Bompa, D. V. &amp; Silva, L. F. O. Comparative carbon emission assessments of recycled and natural aggregate concrete: environmental influence of cement content. <i>Geosci. Front.</i><b>12</b>(6), 101235. 10.1016/j.gsf.2021 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gsf.2021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adessina, A. et al. Experimental and micromechanical investigation on the mechanical and durability properties of recycled aggregates concrete. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>126</b>, 105900 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pani, L. et al. Influence of replacement percentage of recycled aggregates on recycled aggregate concrete properties (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asahina, D., Landis, E. N. &amp; Bolander, J. E. Modeling of phase interfaces during pre-critical crack growth in concrete - ScienceDirect. <i>Cement Concr. Compos.</i><b>33</b>(9), 966&#x2013;977. 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2011.01.007 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2011.01.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, H., Xu, W. &amp; Li, Y. Random aggregate model for mesoscopic structures and mechanical analysis of fully-graded concrete. <i>Comput. Struct.</i>, <b>177</b>, 103&#x2013;113. 10.1016/j.compstruc.2016.09.005 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai, G. et al. An evaluation of the recycled aggregate characteristics and the recycled aggregate concrete mechanical properties. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>240</b>(2), 117978. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117978 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, L. et al. Impact of twin shield tunnel construction on the deformation of Bridge pile groups beneath multiple Bridges: a case study. <i>Front. Built Environ.</i><b>11</b>, 1602817. 10.3389/fbuil.2025.1602817 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbuil.2025.1602817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revilla-Cuesta, V., Serrano-L&#xf3;pez, R., Espinosa, A. B., Ortega-L&#xf3;pez, V. &amp; Skaf, M. Analyzing the relationship between compressive strength and modulus of elasticity in concrete with ladle furnace slag. <i>Buildings</i><b>13</b>(12), 3100. 10.3390/buildings13123100 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings13123100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nukah, P. D., Abbey, S. J., Booth, C. A. &amp; Nounu, G. Mapping and synthesizing the viability of cement replacement materials via a systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>405</b>, 133290. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124907 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, S. et al. Experimental study and numerical simulation of gas-solid flow characteristics in 1MWth compact-fast dual fluidized bed. <i>Powder Technol.</i><b>459</b>, 119396. 10.1016/j.powtec.2024.119396 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.powtec.2024.119396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santamar&#xed;a, A., Revilla-Cuesta, V., Skaf, M. &amp; Romera, J. M. Full-scale sustainable structural concrete containing high proportions of by-products and waste. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>18</b>, e02142. 10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02142 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiol, F., Revilla-Cuesta, V., Skaf, M., Thomas, C. &amp; Manso, J. M. Scaled concrete beams containing maximum levels of coarse recycled aggregate: structural verifications for precast&#x2010;concrete Building applications. <i>Struct. Concrete</i>. <b>24</b>(3), 3476&#x2013;3497. 10.1002/suco.202200963 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/suco.202200963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, B. et al. Superhydrophobic coatings based on bionic mineralization for improving the durability of marine concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>262</b>, 129705. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119882 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, K. et al. Heavy metal pollution in the soil of contaminated sites in china: research status and pollution assessment over the past two decades. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>373</b>, 133780. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.120188 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.120188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L., Zhang, P., Golewski, G. &amp; Guan, J. Fabrication and properties of concrete containing industrial waste. <i>Front. Mater.</i><b>10</b>, 1169715. 10.3389/fmats.2023.1169715 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmats.2023.1169715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golewski, G. L. Using digital image correlation to evaluate fracture toughness and crack propagation in the mode I testing of concretes involving fly Ash and synthetic nano-SiO<sub>2</sub>. <i>Mater. Res. Express</i>. <b>11</b>(9), 095504. 10.1088/2053-1591/ad7df2 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2053-1591/ad7df2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golewski, G. L. Determination of fracture mechanic parameters of concretes based on cement matrix enhanced by fly Ash and nano-silica. <i>Materials</i><b>17</b>(17), 4230. 10.3390/ma17174230 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17174230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11396222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39274618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X. et al. Mechanical properties and hydration mechanism of nano-silica modified alkali-activated thermally activated recycled cement. <i>J. Building Eng.</i><b>98</b>, 110998. 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.110998 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.110998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X. et al. Influence of water glass modulus and alkali content on the properties of alkali-activated thermally activated recycled cement. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>452</b>, 138867. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138867 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golewski, G. L. Investigating the effect of using three Pozzolans (including the nanoadditive) in combination on the formation and development of cracks in concretes using non-contact measurement method. <i>Adv. Nano Res.</i><b>16</b>(3), 217&#x2013;229. 10.12989/anr.2024.16.3.217 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12989/anr.2024.16.3.217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, J., Zhang, Z. &amp; Hou, G. Utilization of fly Ash microsphere powder as a mineral admixture of cement: effects on early hydration and microstructure at different curing temperatures. <i>Powder Technol.</i><b>375</b>, 262&#x2013;270 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.powtec.2020.07.084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, C. &amp; Chen, Z. Mechanical properties of recycled concrete made with different types of coarse aggregate. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>134</b>, 497&#x2013;506. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.12.163 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.12.163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, X. S. et al. Mechanical properties and microstructure analysis of fly Ash geopolymeric recycled concrete. <i>J. Hazard. Mater.</i><b>237</b>, 20&#x2013;29. 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2012.07.070 (2012).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2012.07.070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22954605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, P. &amp; Singh, N. Influence of recycled concrete aggregates and coal bottom Ash on various properties of high volume fly ash-self compacting concrete. <i>J. Building Eng.</i><b>32</b>, 101491. 10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101491 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, Y. et al. Compressive behavior and microstructural analysis of low and high volume fly Ash concrete containing recycled concrete aggregate. <i>Eur. J. Environ. Civil Eng.</i><b>26</b>(12), 6115&#x2013;6132. 10.1080/19648189.2021.1934551 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19648189.2021.1934551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasyap, S. S., Li, S. &amp; Senetakis, K. Investigation of the mechanical properties and the influence of micro-structural characteristics of aggregates using micro-indentation and Weibull analysis. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>271</b>, 121509. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121509 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai, W. et al. Study on mechanical properties and damage mechanism of recycled concrete containing silica fume in freeze&#x2013;thaw environment. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>375</b>, 130872. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunayana, S. &amp; Barai, S. V. Partially fly Ash incorporated recycled coarse aggregate based concrete: microstructure perspectives and critical analysis. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>278</b>, 122322. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122322 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, H., Sandeep, C. S. &amp; Senetakis, K. The interface behavior of recycled concrete aggregate: A micromechanical grain-scale experimental study. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>210</b>, 627&#x2013;638. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.03.106 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.03.106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, Y. et al. Mechanical properties and meso-microscopic mechanism of basalt fiber-reinforced recycled aggregate concrete. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>370</b>, 133555. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.133555 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.133555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai, W. et al. Research on the mechanical properties of recycled aggregate concrete under uniaxial compression based on the statistical damage model. <i>Materials</i><b>13</b>(17), 3765. 10.3390/ma13173765 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7504230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32858902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, Z. et al. Study on the failure mechanism of geopolymeric recycled concrete using digital image correlation method. <i>J. Sustainable Cement-Based Mater.</i><b>11</b>(2), 113&#x2013;126. 10.1080/21650373.2021.1897706 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21650373.2021.1897706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemian, F., Rooholamini, H. &amp; Hassani, A. Mechanical and fracture properties of concrete containing treated and untreated recycled concrete aggregates. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>209</b>, 690&#x2013;700. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.03.179 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.03.179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. et al. Characterization of surface mechanical properties of various aggregates from micro scale using AFM. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>286</b>, 122847. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122847 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdem, S., G&#xfc;rb&#xfc;z, E. &amp; Uysal, M. Micro-mechanical analysis and X-ray computed tomography quantification of damage in concrete with industrial by-products and construction waste. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>189</b>, 933&#x2013;940. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.04.089 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.04.089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. Numerical simulation of mechanical properties of recycled concrete based on characterization of interfacial transition zone characteristics. <i>J. Phys.</i><b>1865</b>(3), 032013. 10.1088/1742-6596/1865/3/032013 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, Q. et al. Capillary water absorption performance and damage constitutive model of recycled concrete under freeze&#x2013;thaw action. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>353</b>, 129120. 10.2139/ssrn.4184139 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.4184139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdem, S., Hanbay, S. &amp; G&#xfc;ler, Z. Micromechanical damage analysis and engineering performance of concrete with colloidal nano-silica and demolished concrete aggregates. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>171</b>, 634&#x2013;642 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.03.197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nerella, V. N., Hempel, S. &amp; Mechtcherine, V. Effects of layer-interface properties on mechanical performance of concrete elements produced by extrusion-based 3D-printing. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>205</b>, 586&#x2013;601. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.01.235 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.01.235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, R. et al. Effect of concrete Micro-Mechanical properties under the coupled corrosion of sulfate and high water head. <i>Energies</i><b>14</b>(16), 5039. 10.3390/en14165039 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en14165039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, K. Q. et al. Micro-structural and mechanical properties of ultra-high performance engineered cementitious composites (UHP-ECC) incorporation of recycled fine powder (RFP). <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>124</b>, 105813. 10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105813 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying, L., Peng, Y. &amp; Kamel, M. M. A. Mesoscopic numerical analysis of dynamic tensile fracture of recycled concrete. <i>Eng. Comput.</i><b>37</b>(6), 1899&#x2013;1922. 10.1108/ec-05-2019-0214 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/ec-05-2019-0214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying, L., Peng, Y. &amp; Kamel, M. M. A. 3-D base force element method on meso&#x2010;damage analysis for recycled concrete. <i>Struct. Concrete</i><b>23</b>(4), 1962&#x2013;1980. 10.1002/suco.202000125 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arulrajah, A. et al. Discrete element analysis of recycled concrete aggregate responses during repeated load triaxial testing. <i>Transp. Geotechnics</i>. <b>23</b>, 100356. 10.1016/j.trgeo.2020.100356 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trgeo.2020.100356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, W. et al. Numerical modelling of plastic&#x2013;damage response and crack propagation in RAC under uniaxial loading. <i>Magazine Concrete Res.</i><b>70</b>(9), 459&#x2013;472. 10.1680/jmacr.17.00042 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1680/jmacr.17.00042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, J. &amp; Zhang, B. Repair of ordinary Portland cement concrete using alkali activated slag/fly ash: Freeze-thaw resistance and pore size evolution of adhesive interface. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>300</b>, 124334 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pablos, J. M., Sichieri, E. P. &amp; Zago, M. S. A. Study for utilization of industrial solid waste, generated by the discharge of casting sand agglomeration with clay an d of blast furnace slag, in concrete composition. <i>Key Eng. Mater.</i><b>517</b>, 611&#x2013;616. 10.4028/www.scientific.net/kem.517.611 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;neyisi, E. et al. Effect of different substitution of natural aggregate by recycled aggregate on performance characteristics of pervious concrete. <i>Mater. Struct.</i><b>49</b>, 521&#x2013;536. 10.1617/s11527-014-0517-y (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-014-0517-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, T., Gholampour, A. &amp; Ozbakkaloglu, T. Toward the development of sustainable concretes with recycled concrete aggregates: comprehensive review of studies on mechanical properties. <i>J. Mater. Civ. Eng.</i><b>30</b>(9), 04018211. 10.1061/(asce)mt.19435533.0002304 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(asce)mt.19435533.0002304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas, C. et al. Macro-and micro-properties of multi-recycled aggregate concrete. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>245</b>, 118843 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.118843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kou, S. C., Poon, C. S. &amp; Chan, D. Influence of fly ash as cement replacement on the properties of recycled aggregate concrete. <i>J. Mater. Civ. Eng.</i><b>19</b>(9), 709&#x2013;717 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalkader, A. &amp; Elzaroug, O. Hardened properties of recycled aggregate concrete incorporating pulverised fly Ash. <i>AL-Mukhtar J. Eng. Res.</i><b>1</b>(4), 62&#x2013;67 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed, S. I. &amp; Najim, K. B. Mechanical strength, flexural behavior and fracture energy of recycled concrete aggregate self-compacting concrete. <i>Structures</i><b>23</b>, 34&#x2013;43. 10.1016/j.istruc.2019.09.010 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2019.09.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Z. et al. Experimental study on mechanical properties and microstructures of steel fiber-reinforced fly ash-metakaolin geopolymer-recycled concrete. <i>Rev. Adv. Mater. Sci.</i><b>60</b>(1), 578&#x2013;590. 10.1515/rams-2021-0050 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/rams-2021-0050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GB/T 50081&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;2019. <i>Standard for Test Methods of Concrete Physical and Mechanical Properties</i>(China Architecture &amp; Building, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GB/T 50080&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;2016. <i>Standard for Test Method of Performance on Ordinary Fresh Concrete Mixture</i>(China Architecture &amp; Building, 2016).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>