<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41760821</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Vaccination trends and operational challenges in Peste des Petits Ruminants eradication in Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">11259</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-41404-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Peste des Petits Ruminants (PPR) is a major transboundary disease in Ethiopia, where the national goal is eradication by 2027. However, evidence on vaccination performance and operational challenges remains limited. This study assessed vaccination trends over six years (September 2018&#x2013;August 2024) and conducted surveys with animal health professionals (AHPs) (January&#x2013;May 2024) to identify key enabling factors and constraints influencing eradication efforts in the North Shewa Zone. The findings revealed that a risk-based vaccination strategy (RBVS) has been implemented since 2018, focusing on high-risk areas and employing rapid antigen detection tests to confirm outbreaks. Once an outbreak is confirmed, AHPs collaborate with regional coordinators to isolate at-risk populations and administer a live attenuated PPR vaccine. Over the study period, 62 vaccination campaigns were conducted, averaging 10.3 campaigns per year. The highest number occurred in 2019 (16 campaigns, 25.81%), while the lowest was in 2022 (one campaign). Kewet district recorded the highest number of campaigns (six), whereas six districts received no vaccinations. A total of 2,917,330 small ruminants were vaccinated, with Minjar-Shenkora district reporting the highest number (384,989 animals). The year 2023 saw the peak in vaccination coverage, with 1,284,339 animals vaccinated. The study identified factors affecting eradication efforts, with key enablers including a national policy (82.6%), sufficient vaccine production (71.74%), and adequate vaccination tools (80.43%). Major challenges included budget constraints (84.78%) and security concerns (65.22%), along with operational issues such as lack of animal identification, absence of post-vaccination sero-monitoring (PVS), high herd mobility, and rapid turnover of young stock. In conclusion, these challenges may compromise vaccination effectiveness and hinder eradication efforts. Nevertheless, strong regional commitment and enabling factors provide a promising foundation for progress. To enhance PPR control and achieve eradication, the study recommends strengthening surveillance, improving post-vaccination sero-monitoring, optimizing vaccine distribution, and addressing key operational barriers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41598-026-41404-7.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alamerew</LastName><ForeName>Enyiew Alemnew</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Amhara Agricultural Research Institute, Debre Birhan Agricultural Research Centre, Debre Birhan, P.O. Box 112, Ethiopia. alemnewenyiew@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Pathobiology, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia. alemnewenyiew@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cherenet</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Livestock and Fishery Sector Development Project, Ministry of Agriculture, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aklilu</LastName><ForeName>Fasil</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Serology, Animal Health Institute, Sebeta, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yitayew</LastName><ForeName>Zelalem</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Livestock and Fishery Office, Diseases Control and Prevention, Debre Birhan, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aydefruhim</LastName><ForeName>Derib</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Amhara Agricultural Research Institute, Debre Birhan Agricultural Research Centre, Debre Birhan, P.O. Box 112, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayele</LastName><ForeName>Firdawok</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Amhara Agricultural Research Institute, Debre Birhan Agricultural Research Centre, Debre Birhan, P.O. Box 112, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abat</LastName><ForeName>Anmaw Shite</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Pathobiology, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Constraints</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">North Shewa Zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Progress towards eradication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk-based vaccination strategy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Small ruminants</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical approval: Ethical approval for the study, including its human participant component, was obtained from the Institutional Review Board of the University of Gondar (Protocol Number: CVMASc/UoG/RERC/29/12/2023). All research activities were conducted in accordance with the relevant institutional and national ethical standards for research involving human participants. Informed consent: Written informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to data collection.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41760821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-41404-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-41404-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13049157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alary, V., Corniaux, C. &amp; Gautier, D. Livestock&#x2019;s Contribution to Poverty Alleviation: How to Measure It? <i>World Dev.</i><b>39</b>, 1638&#x2013;1648 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.worlddev.2011.02.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parida, S. et al. Peste des petits ruminants. <i>Vet. Microbiol.</i><b>181</b>, 90&#x2013;106 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vetmic.2015.08.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4655833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26443889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO. <i>Supporting livelihoods and building resilience through Peste des Petits Ruminants and small ruminant diseases control</i> (Animal Production and Health Position Paper, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jemberu, W. T. et al. Economic impact of a peste des petits ruminants outbreak and vaccination cost in northwest Ethiopia. <i>Transbound. Emerg. Dis.</i><b>69</b>, e2084&#x2013;e2092 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tbed.14544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9790723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35353947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govindaraj, G. N. et al. Evaluation of effectiveness of Mass Vaccination Campaign against Peste des petits ruminants in Chhattisgarh state, India. <i>Vaccine</i><b>32</b>, 3155&#x2013;3161 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30839170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pruvot, M. et al. Outbreak of peste des petits ruminants virus among critically endangered mongolian saiga and other wild ungulates, Mongolia, 2016&#x2013;2017. <i>Emerg. Infect. Dis.</i><b>26</b>, 51&#x2013;62 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid2601.181998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6924898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31855146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fine, A. E. et al. Eradication of Peste des Petits Ruminants Virus and the Wildlife-Livestock Interface. <i>Front. Veterinary Sci.</i><b>7 March</b>, 1&#x2013;8 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7082352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32232059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WOAH and FAO. Global strategy for the control and eradication of PPR (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO and WOAH. Peste des petits ruminants global eradication programme: Contributing to food security, poverty alleviation and resilience, Five years (2017&#x2013;2021). (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron, M. D., Diop, B., Njeumi, F., Willett, B. J. &amp; Bailey, D. Future research to underpin successful peste des petits ruminants virus (PPRV) eradication. <i>J. Gen. Virol.</i><b>98</b>, 2635&#x2013;2644 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/jgv.0.000944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5845661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29022862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esonu, D. et al. Epidemiology of Peste des Petits Ruminants in Nigeria: A review. <i>Front. Veterinary Sci.</i><b>9</b>, 1&#x2013;13 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fvets.2022.898485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9298765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35873688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niedbalski, W. Progress in vaccines against peste des petits ruminants virus. <i>Medycyna Weterynaryjna</i>. <b>79</b>, 163&#x2013;167 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebre, T., Deneke, Y. &amp; Begna, F. Seroprevalence and Associated Risk Factors of Peste Des Petits Ruminants (PPR) in Sheep and Goats in Four Districts of Bench Maji and Kafa Zones, South West Ethiopia. <i>Global Vet.</i><b>20</b>, 260&#x2013;270 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yalew, S. T. &amp; Mamo, G. W. Seroprevalence of Peste Des Petits Ruminant&#x2019;s Virus Antibody in Assosa Zone, Benishangulgumuz Region, Ethiopia. <i>ARC J. Anim. Veterinary Sci.</i><b>5</b>, 29&#x2013;33 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afera, B., Hussien, D. &amp; Amsalu, K. Seroprevalence of peste des petits ruminants in goats of southern parts of tigray region. <i>Global Vet.</i><b>12</b>, 512&#x2013;516 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagim, B. G., Minda, A. &amp; Aynalem, T. Peste des Petits Ruminants: Seropositivity and associated risk factors in goats and camel in Dello Mena and Madda Walabu Districts of Bale Zone, South Eastern Ethiopia. <i>J. Veterinary Med. Anim. Health</i>. <b>13</b>, 15&#x2013;21 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/JVMAH2018.0684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubie, T. et al. Seroprevalence and associated risk factors of peste des petits ruminants among ovine and caprine in selected districts of Afar region, Ethiopia. <i>BMC Vet. Res.</i><b>18</b>, 1&#x2013;9 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12917-022-03528-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9733059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36494681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abesha, H. et al. Seroepidemiology of peste des petits ruminants virus in small ruminants in selected districts in Northwest Ethiopia. <i>Veterinary Med. Sci.</i><b>9</b>, 884&#x2013;890 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/vms3.994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10029864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36367532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ejigu, E., Tolosa, T., Begna, F. &amp; Tegegne, H. Sero-Prevalence and Associated Risk Factors of Peste Des Petits Ruminants in Dera and Gerar Jarso Districts of Oromia Region, Ethiopia. <i>Veterinary Medicine: Res. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 111&#x2013;123 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10353565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37469859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumbe, A. et al. Epidemiology of peste des petits ruminants in selected districts of Borena zone, Ethiopia. <i>BMC Vet. Res.</i><b>20</b>, 451 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12917-024-04312-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11457360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39375652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senbeto, Y. A., Sibhatu, D. &amp; Jibril, Y. Seroprevalence and associated risk factors of Peste des petits ruminants in selected districts of Awi zone, Northwest Ethiopia. <i>Heliyon</i><b>10</b>, e38882 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e38882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11489383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39430495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO. The State of Food and Agriculture. Livestock in the balance. (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemnew, E., Asfaw, T., Demis, C., Yitagesu, E. &amp; Areaya, A. Clinical report on outbreaks of peste des petits ruminants in goat in north Shewa. <i>Ethiopia Res. in: Agricultural Veterinary Sci.</i><b>4</b>, 125&#x2013;131 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamerew, E. A. et al. Spatial and temporal dynamics of Peste des Petits Ruminants Outbreaks and their clinical impact in small Ruminants in North Shewa Zone, Ethiopia: Implications for eradication. <i>Transbound. Emerg. Dis.</i><b>2025</b>, 11 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/tbed/9047158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12626705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41262885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathelrahman, E. M. et al. Epidemiology and cost of peste des petits ruminants eradication in small ruminants in the united arab emirates&#x2014;disease spread and control strategies simulations. <i>Animals</i><b>11</b>, 2649 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani11092649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8468282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34573618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urke, B. D. A Review on: Peste Des Petits Ruminants and its Epidemiology in Ethiopia. <i>Int. J. Adv. Res. Biol. Sci.</i><b>10</b>, 55&#x2013;72 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diallo, A. Control of peste des petits ruminants and poverty alleviation? <i>J. Veterinary Med. Ser. B: Infect. Dis. Veterinary Public. Health</i>. <b>53</b>(SUPPL. 1), 11&#x2013;13 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1439-0450.2006.01012.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, H., Njeumi, F., Parida, S. &amp; Benfield, C. T. O. Progress towards eradication of peste des petits ruminants through vaccination. <i>Viruses</i><b>13</b>, 1&#x2013;15 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v13010059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7824732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33466238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemnew, E. et al. Evaluation of immune response of small ruminant flocks to ovine Pasteurellosis and Peste Des Petits Ruminants vaccines in North Shewa, Ethiopia. <i>J. Sci. Incl. Dev.</i><b>4</b>, 55&#x2013;69 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO-Ethiopia. FAO and Ethiopian government reaffirm commitment to eradicate peste des petits ruminants (PPR) (2018). https://www.fao.org/ppr/news-and-events/news/news-.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham, G. et al. Antibody seroprevalences against peste des petits ruminants (PPR) virus in camels, cattle, goats and sheep in Ethiopia. <i>Prev. Vet. Med.</i><b>70</b>, 51&#x2013;57 (2005).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prevetmed.2005.02.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15967242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Central Statistical Agency (CSA). Federal democratic republic of Ethiopia central statistical agency agricultural sample survey; report on livestock and livestock characteristics (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamerew, E. A., Shite, A., Cherenet, T. &amp; Aklilu, F. Progress and challenges in peste des petits ruminants control and eradication: a comprehensive review of global strategies and Ethiopia&#x2019;s efforts. <i>Cogent Food Agric.</i><b>11</b>, 2581911 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23311932.2025.2581911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kairu-Wanyoike, S. W. et al. Willingness to pay for contagious bovine pleuropneumonia vaccination in Narok South District of Kenya. <i>Prev. Vet. Med.</i><b>115</b>, 130&#x2013;142 (2014).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prevetmed.2014.03.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4062942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24774477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekezie, W. et al. Access to vaccination among disadvantaged, isolated and difficult-to-reach communities in the WHO European Region: A systematic Review. <i>Vaccines</i><b>10</b>, 1038 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vaccines10071038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9324407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35891201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abegaz, W. B. &amp; Mekoya, A. Rainfall Variability and Trends over Central. <i>Int. J. Environ. Sci. Nat. Resour.</i><b>24</b>, 556144 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fekadu, K. Ethiopian seasonal rainfall variability and prediction using canonical correlation analysis (CCA). <i>Earth Sci.</i><b>4</b>, 112 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamane, T. Statistics an Introductory Analysis, 2nd edn (John Weatherhill, New York, 1967).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Njeumi, F., Bailey, D., Jacques Soula, J., Diop, B. &amp; Tekola, B. G. Eradicating the scourge of Peste des Petits ruminants from the world. <i>Viruses</i><b>12</b>, 1&#x2013;12 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v12030313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7150808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32183412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, N. et al. Isolation, identification and characterization of a Peste des Petits Ruminants virus from an outbreak in Nanakpur, India. <i>J. Virol. Methods</i>. <b>189</b>, 388&#x2013;392 (2013).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jviromet.2013.03.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23500799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamerew, E. A. <i>Evaluation of risk-based vaccination for peste des petits ruminants eradication: flock immunity and seroprevalence in small ruminants of North Shewa Zone, Ethiopia</i> (University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dejene, D. Retrospective Study of PPR Disease Occurrence in South West Ethiopia Regional State from 2018 to 2022. <i>J. Veterinary Sci. Technol.</i><b>15</b>, 234&#x2013;238 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acosta, D., Hendrickx, S. &amp; McKune, S. The livestock vaccine supply chain: Why it matters and how it can help eradicate peste des petits Ruminants, based on findings in Karamoja, Uganda. <i>Vaccine</i><b>37</b>, 6285&#x2013;6290 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2019.09.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31526623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra, R., Ludgate, N., Florillo, K., McKune, S. &amp; Russo, S. Beyond the gender of the Livestock holder: Learnings from. <i>Animals</i><b>1</b>, 1&#x2013;16 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8833455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35158565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anonymous Scientific Opinion on peste des petits ruminants1 2 EFSA Panel on Animal Health and Welfare (AHAW). <i>EFSA J.</i><b>13</b>, 3985 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Njue, S. et al. Sero-prevalence study to determine the effectiveness of Peste de Petits Ruminants vaccination in Somalia. <i>Pastoralism</i><b>8</b>, 17 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13570-018-0122-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akwongo, C. J., Quan, M., Byaruhanga, C. &amp; Prevalence risk factors for exposure, and socio-economic impact of Peste des Petits Ruminants in Karenga district, Karamoja region, Uganda. <i>Pathogens</i><b>11</b>, 1&#x2013;18 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pathogens11010054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8780034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35056002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mdetele, D. et al. Review of Peste des petits ruminants occurrence and spread in Tanzania. <i>Animals</i><b>11</b>, 1698 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani11061698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8230322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34200290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balamurugan, V., Hemadri, D., Gajendragad, M. R., Singh, R. K. &amp; Rahman, H. Diagnosis and control of peste des petits ruminants: a comprehensive review. <i>Virus Disease</i>. <b>25</b>, 39&#x2013;56 (2014).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3889233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24426309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balamurugan, V. et al. Post-vaccination Sero-monitoring of Peste des Petits Ruminants in sheep and goats in Karnataka: Progress towards PPR eradication in India. <i>Viruses</i><b>16</b>, 333 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v16030333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10974862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38543699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO-Ethiopia. Strategy for progressive control of PPR in Ethiopia (Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senthil Kumar, K. et al. Molecular characterisation of lineage IV peste des petits ruminants virus using multi gene sequence data. <i>Vet. Microbiol.</i><b>174</b>, 39&#x2013;49 (2014).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vetmic.2014.08.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25248690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfaye, A. <i>Seroprevalence and associated risk factors of peste des petits of small ruminants in selected districts with outbreak study in West Arsi and Arsi zones, Oromia Region, Ethiopia</i> (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roeder, P., Mariner, J. &amp; Kock, R. Rinderpest the veterinary perspective on eradication. <i>Philos. Trans. Royal Soc. B: Biol. Sci.</i><b>368</b>, 20120139 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rstb.2012.0139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3720037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23798687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kansiime, C. et al. Community perceptions on integrating animal vaccination and health education by veterinary and public health workers in the prevention of brucellosis among pastoral communities of south western Uganda. <i>PLoS ONE</i>. <b>10</b>, 1&#x2013;15 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0132206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4517904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26218368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robi, D. T., Bogale, A., Temteme, S., Aleme, M. &amp; Urge, B. Evaluation of livestock farmers&#x2019; knowledge, attitudes and practices regarding the use of veterinary vaccines in Southwest Ethiopia. <i>Veterinary Med. Sci.</i><b>9</b>, 2871&#x2013;2884 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/vms3.1290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10650347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37788141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wane, A. et al. Willingness to vaccinate (WTV) and willingness to pay (WTP) for vaccination against Peste des Petits Ruminants (PPR) in Mali. <i>Front. Vet. Sci.</i><b>6</b>, 488 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fvets.2019.00488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6974520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32010711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ElArbi, A. S. et al. PPR Control in a Sahelian Setting: What Vaccination Strategy for Mauritania? <i>Front. Veterinary Sci.</i><b>6 July</b>, 1&#x2013;18 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6664874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31396525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yirga, A. et al. Post-vaccination herd immunity against Peste des Petits Ruminants and inter-vaccination population turnover in small ruminant flocks in northwest Ethiopia. <i>Prev. Vet. Med.</i><b>174</b>, 104850 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prevetmed.2019.104850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31794918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, S. et al. Barriers to vaccine use in small ruminants and poultry in Tanzania. <i>Onderstepoort J. Vet. Res.</i><b>89</b>, 1&#x2013;11 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4102/ojvr.v89i1.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9453132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36073111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intisar, K. S. et al. Peste des petits ruminants infection in domestic ruminants in Sudan. <i>Trop. Anim. Health Prod.</i><b>49</b>, 747&#x2013;754 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11250-017-1254-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28321790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>