<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41712166</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1572-8595</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of interventional cardiac electrophysiology : an international journal of arrhythmias and pacing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Interv Card Electrophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ventricular tachycardia exit site location within myocardial reinnervation zones predicts hemodynamic stability in ischemic cardiomyopathy.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10840-026-02255-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Hemodynamic stability during ischemic ventricular tachycardia (VT) critically influences mapping strategies and ablation outcomes. This study investigated whether VT exit site location within distinct myocardial scar zones affects hemodynamic stability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We analyzed 51 VTs in 27 patients with ischemic scar-mediated VT who underwent electroanatomic mapping and catheter ablation (2014-2017). Exit sites were categorized by voltage mapping as adjacent to central scar zone (CSZ, bipolar voltage&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.5 mV) or peri-infarct border zone (PIBZ, voltage 0.5-1.5 mV). Hemodynamic stability was defined as sustained VT without precipitous blood pressure drop requiring cardioversion. Multivariate logistic regression identified independent predictors of instability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of 51 VTs, 30 (58.8%) were hemodynamically unstable. Among stable VTs, 81% had PIBZ exit sites versus 19% CSZ exits (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01). CSZ exit site location independently predicted hemodynamic instability (OR 6.8, 95% CI 1.3-35.8; P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.02) after adjusting for cycle length and ejection fraction. Unstable VTs had lower ejection fraction (28.7&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;10.5% vs. 35.7&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;11.4%, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.03) and shorter cycle length (330.5&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;78.5 ms vs. 403.2&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;107.7 ms, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.007).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">VT exit site location adjacent to distinct scar zones independently predicts hemodynamic stability. CSZ exits are associated with instability, while PIBZ exits maintain stability. These findings may reflect differential post-infarction reinnervation patterns and mechanical forces between scar zones, enhancing risk stratification and guiding ablation strategy selection in ischemic VT.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. This is a U.S. Government work and not under copyright protection in the US; foreign copyright protection may apply.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reyes</LastName><ForeName>Jorge L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Interventional Cardiac Electrophysiology, LAA Closure Program, Cardiovascular Division, Minneapolis VA Health Care System, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN, 55417, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Minneapolis VA Health Care System, Minneapolis, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krishnappa</LastName><ForeName>Darshan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Interventional Cardiac Electrophysiology, LAA Closure Program, Cardiovascular Division, Minneapolis VA Health Care System, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN, 55417, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Lucy Q</ForeName><Initials>LQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology Division, Oregon Health Sciences University, Portland, OR, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haddadin</LastName><ForeName>Faris</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Interventional Cardiac Electrophysiology, LAA Closure Program, Cardiovascular Division, Minneapolis VA Health Care System, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN, 55417, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benditt</LastName><ForeName>David G</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Interventional Cardiac Electrophysiology, LAA Closure Program, Cardiovascular Division, Minneapolis VA Health Care System, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN, 55417, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tholakanahalli</LastName><ForeName>Venkatakrishna N</ForeName><Initials>VN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Interventional Cardiac Electrophysiology, LAA Closure Program, Cardiovascular Division, Minneapolis VA Health Care System, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN, 55417, USA. thola001@umn.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Minneapolis VA Health Care System, Minneapolis, MN, USA. thola001@umn.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Interv Card Electrophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9708966</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1383-875X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomic nervous system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiac electrophysiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hemodynamic stability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ischemic cardiomyopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ventricular tachycardia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Disclosures: None of the authors report potential conflicts of interest pertinent to this report.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41712166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10840-026-02255-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10840-026-02255-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kuck KH, Schaumann A, Eckardt L, et al. Catheter ablation of stable ventricular tachycardia before defibrillator implantation in patients with coronary heart disease (VTACH): a multicentre randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2010;375(9708):31&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(09)61755-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung R, Vaseghi M, Frankel DS, et al. Freedom from recurrent ventricular tachycardia after catheter ablation is associated with improved survival in patients with structural heart disease: an international VT ablation center collaborative group study. Heart Rhythm. 2015;12(9):1997&#x2013;2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hrthm.2015.05.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4549209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S, Tedrow UB, Stevenson WG. Entrainment mapping. Card Electrophysiol Clin. 2017;9(1):55&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccep.2016.10.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santangeli P, Frankel DS, Tung R, et al. Early mortality after catheter ablation of ventricular tachycardia in patients with structural heart disease. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2017;69(17):2105&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2017.02.044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briceno DF, Romero J, Gianni C, et al. Substrate ablation of ventricular tachycardia: late potentials, scar dechanneling, local abnormal ventricular activities, core isolation, and homogenization. Card Electrophysiol Clin. 2017;9(1):81&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccep.2016.10.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piers SR, Everaerts K, van der Geest RJ, et al. Myocardial Scar predicts monomorphic ventricular tachycardia but not polymorphic ventricular tachycardia or ventricular fibrillation in nonischemic dilated cardiomyopathy. Heart Rhythm. 2015;12(10):2106&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hrthm.2015.05.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijnmaalen AP, Schalij MJ, von der Thusen JH, Klautz RJ, Zeppenfeld K. Early reperfusion during acute myocardial infarction affects ventricular tachycardia characteristics and the chronic electroanatomic and histological substrate. Circulation. 2010;121(17):1887&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.109.891242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Bakker JM, van Capelle FJ, Janse MJ, et al. Slow conduction in the infarcted human heart. &#x201c;Zigzag&#x201d; course of activation. Circulation. 1993;88(3):915&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.88.3.915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue H, Zipes DP. Results of sympathetic denervation in the canine heart: supersensitivity that may be arrhythmogenic. Circulation. 1987;75(4):877&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.75.4.877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber MJ, Mueller TM, Henry DP, Felten SY, Zipes DP. Transmural myocardial infarction in the dog produces sympathectomy in noninfarcted myocardium. Circulation. 1983;67(4):787&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.67.4.787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchlinski FE, Callans DJ, Gottlieb CD, Zado E. Linear ablation lesions for control of unmappable ventricular tachycardia in patients with ischemic and nonischemic cardiomyopathy. Circulation. 2000;101(11):1288&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.101.11.1288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes JW, Borg TK, Covell JW. Structure and mechanics of healing myocardial infarcts. Annu Rev Biomed Eng. 2005;7:223&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.bioeng.7.060804.100453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jugdutt BI. Ventricular remodeling after infarction and the extracellular collagen matrix: when is enough enough? Circulation. 2003;108(11):1395&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.0000085658.98621.49</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleber AG, Rudy Y. Basic mechanisms of cardiac impulse propagation and associated arrhythmias. Physiol Rev. 2004;84(2):431&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00025.2003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gornick CC, Tobler HG, Pritzker MC, Tuna IC, Almquist A, Benditt DG. Electrophysiologic effects of papillary muscle traction in the intact heart. Circulation. 1986;73(5):1013&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.73.5.1013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson WG, Friedman PL, Sager PT, et al. Exploring postinfarction reentrant ventricular tachycardia with entrainment mapping. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1997;29(6):1180&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0735-1097(97)00065-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wit AL, Janse MJ. Experimental models of ventricular tachycardia and fibrillation caused by ischemia and infarction. Circulation. 1992;85(1 Suppl):I32&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh YS, Jong AY, Kim DT, et al. Spatial distribution of nerve sprouting after myocardial infarction in mice. Heart Rhythm. 2006;3(6):728&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hrthm.2006.02.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luke RA, Saffitz JE. Remodeling of ventricular conduction pathways in healed canine infarct border zones. J Clin Invest. 1991;87(5):1594&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI115173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">295242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ursell PC, Gardner PI, Albala A, Fenoglio JJ Jr., Wit AL. Structural and electrophysiological changes in the epicardial border zone of canine myocardial infarcts during infarct healing. Circ Res. 1985;56(3):436&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.RES.56.3.436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen PS, Chen LS, Cao JM, Sharifi B, Karagueuzian HS, Fishbein MC. Sympathetic nerve sprouting, electrical remodeling and the mechanisms of sudden cardiac death. Cardiovasc Res. 2001;50(2):409&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-6363(00)00308-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajijola OA, Yagishita D, Patel KJ, et al. Focal myocardial infarction induces global remodeling of cardiac sympathetic innervation: neural remodeling in a Spatial context. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2013;305(7):H1031&#x2013;1040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.00434.2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3798751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S, Chen LS, Miyauchi Y, et al. Mechanisms of cardiac nerve sprouting after myocardial infarction in dogs. Circ Res. 2004;95(1):76&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.RES.0000133678.22968.e3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao JM, Fishbein MC, Han JB, et al. Relationship between regional cardiac hyperinnervation and ventricular arrhythmia. Circulation. 2000;101(16):1960&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.101.16.1960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huikuri HV, Zaman L, Castellanos A, et al. Changes in spontaneous sinus node rate as an estimate of cardiac autonomic tone during stable and unstable ventricular tachycardia. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1989;13(3):646&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0735-1097(89)90606-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavrakis S, Kulkarni K, Singh JP, Katritsis DG, Armoundas AA. Autonomic modulation of cardiac arrhythmias: methods to assess treatment and outcomes. JACC Clin Electrophysiol. 2020;6(5):467&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacep.2020.02.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7370838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinik AI, Maser RE, Mitchell BD, Freeman R. Diabetic autonomic neuropathy. Diabetes Care. 2003;26(5):1553&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diacare.26.5.1553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>