<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41706062</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1558-3597</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Am Coll Cardiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of the European Society of Cardiology 0/1-Hour and High-Sensitivity Troponin in the Evaluation of Patients With Suspected Acute Coronary Syndrome 0/2-or-0/3-Hour Algorithms for Rapid Myocardial Infarction Diagnosis: A Prospective Multicenter Study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0735-1097(25)10588-3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jacc.2025.12.056</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The optimal approach for the early diagnosis of non-ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction (NSTEMI) remains uncertain, because no large trials have been performed. Accordingly, guideline recommendations differ and do not overall give a clear answer.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The authors aimed to directly compare the European Society of Cardiology 0/1-hour algorithm (ESC 0/1h-algorithm) and the high-sensitivity troponin in the evaluation of patients with acute coronary syndrome 0/2-hour or 0/3-hour pathway (High-STEACS 0/2h-0/3h-pathway) in patients presenting with acute chest discomfort.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This prospective, international, multicenter, diagnostic study enrolled patients presenting to the emergency department with acute chest discomfort. Final diagnoses were centrally adjudicated by 2 independent cardiologists. The primary diagnostic endpoint was NSTEMI type 1. Both algorithms were applied in parallel using 3 high-sensitivity cardiac troponin (hs-cTn) assays: hs-cTnI-Architect, hs-cTnI-Centaur/Atellica, and hs-cTnT-Elecsys. The findings were externally validated in an independent prospective diagnostic study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among 4,663 eligible patients (median age: 61 years; 32% women), 663 (14.2%) had NSTEMI type 1. The ESC 0/1h-algorithm had higher sensitivity when using hs-cTnI-Architect (100% [95% CI: 99.4-100]) compared with the High-STEACS 0/2h-pathway (98.1% [95% CI: 96.7-99], P &lt; 0.001), but the proportion of patients assigned to the rule-out group was lower (52% vs 72.5%, P &lt; 0.001). Differences were similar but were less pronounced for hs-cTnI-Centaur/Atellica and absent for hs-cTnT-Elecsys. Specificity was consistently higher for the ESC 0/1h-algorithms vs the High-STEACS 0/2h-0/3h-pathways for all hs-cTnT/I-assays. These findings were confirmed when using High-STEACS 0/3h-pathways and in the external validation cohort (n = 2,485; median age: 64 years; 37% women).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Overall, both algorithms exhibited comparable and excellent performance. When using hs-cTnI, the ESC-0/1h-algorithms showed higher sensitivity, whereas the High-STEACS 0/2h-0/3h-pathways demonstrated higher efficacy. Consistently, the ESC 0/1h-algorithms showed higher specificity for NSTEMI. These findings provide direct, validated evidence to guide hospitals in selecting an hs-cTn pathway aligned with their clinical and operational priorities. (Advantageous Predictors of Acute Coronary Syndromes Evaluation [APACE] Study [APACE], NCT00470587; Biomarkers in Acute Cardiac Care [BACC], NCT02355457).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 American College of Cardiology Foundation. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glaeser</LastName><ForeName>Jonas</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland; GREAT Network, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lopez-Ayala</LastName><ForeName>Pedro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland; GREAT Network, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kellner</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Heart and Vascular Center Hamburg, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boeddinghaus</LastName><ForeName>Jasper</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland; GREAT Network, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nestelberger</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland; GREAT Network, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koechlin</LastName><ForeName>Luca</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland; GREAT Network, Rome, Italy; Department of Cardiac Surgery, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xf6;rensen</LastName><ForeName>Nils A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Heart and Vascular Center Hamburg, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany; German Centre for Cardiovascular Research (DZHK), Partner Site Hamburg/Kiel/L&#xfc;beck, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haller</LastName><ForeName>Paul M</ForeName><Initials>PM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Heart and Vascular Center Hamburg, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany; German Centre for Cardiovascular Research (DZHK), Partner Site Hamburg/Kiel/L&#xfc;beck, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bima</LastName><ForeName>Paolo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland; GREAT Network, Rome, Italy; Department of Medical Sciences, University of Turin, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crisanti</LastName><ForeName>Luca</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland; GREAT Network, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spagnuolo</LastName><ForeName>Carlos C</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland; GREAT Network, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strebel</LastName><ForeName>Ivo</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland; GREAT Network, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hure</LastName><ForeName>Gabrielle</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland; GREAT Network, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sieber</LastName><ForeName>Stefan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rubini Gimenez</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GREAT Network, Rome, Italy; Cardiology Department, Herzzentrum Leipzig, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wildi</LastName><ForeName>Karin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland; GREAT Network, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wussler</LastName><ForeName>Desiree</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland; GREAT Network, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miro</LastName><ForeName>Oscar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GREAT Network, Rome, Italy; Emergency Department, Hospital Clinic, University of Barcelona, Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martin-Sanchez</LastName><ForeName>Francisco Javier</ForeName><Initials>FJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GREAT Network, Rome, Italy; Emergency Department, Hospital Cl&#xed;nico San Carlos, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keller</LastName><ForeName>Dagmar I</ForeName><Initials>DI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency Department, University Hospital Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Christ</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Luzerner Kantonsspital, Luzern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Twerenbold</LastName><ForeName>Raphael</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Heart and Vascular Center Hamburg, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany; German Centre for Cardiovascular Research (DZHK), Partner Site Hamburg/Kiel/L&#xfc;beck, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahfoud</LastName><ForeName>Felix</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland; GREAT Network, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neumann</LastName><ForeName>Johannes</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Heart and Vascular Center Hamburg, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany; German Centre for Cardiovascular Research (DZHK), Partner Site Hamburg/Kiel/L&#xfc;beck, Hamburg, Germany; Department of Epidemiology and Preventive Medicine, School of Public Health and Preventive Medicine, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mueller</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland; GREAT Network, Rome, Italy. Electronic address: christian.mueller@usb.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>APACE and BACC Investigators</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT02355457</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Am Coll Cardiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8301365</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0735-1097</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ESC 0/1h-algorithm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">external validation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myocardial infarction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">observe zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rule-out</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">troponin</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Funding Support and Author Disclosures The APACE study was supported by research grants from the Swiss National Science Foundation, Swiss Heart Foundation, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Abbott, Beckman Coulter, Brahms, Idorsia, LSI Medience Corporation, Ortho Clinical Diagnostics, Quidel, Roche, Siemens, Singulex, and SpinChip Diagnostics. The BACC study was supported by the German Heart Research Foundation and an unrestricted grant from Roche. The investigated hs-cTn assays were donated by the manufacturers (Roche, Abbott and Siemens), who had no role in the design of the study, analysis of the data, preparation of the manuscript, or decision to submit the manuscript for publication. Dr Lopez-Ayala has received research grants from the Swiss Heart Foundation (FF20079, FF21103 and FF24149) and speaker&#x2019;s honoraria from Quidel, Roche Diagnostics, and Polymedco in the last 36 months, all outside the submitted work. Dr Boeddinghaus is supported by an Edinburgh Doctoral College Scholarship and research grants from the University of Basel, University Hospital of Basel, Division of Internal Medicine, Swiss Academy of Medical Sciences, Gottfried and Julia Bangerter-Rhyner Foundation, Swiss National Science Foundation, and Swiss Heart Foundation and has received honoraria from Siemens, Roche Diagnostics, Ortho Clinical Diagnostics, Quidel Corporation, and Beckman Coulter and travel support from Medtronic and Vascularmedical, all outside the submitted work. Dr Nestelberger has received research support from the Swiss National Science Foundation (P400PM_191037/1), Prof Dr Max Clo&#xeb;tta Foundation, Margarete und Walter Lichtenstein-Stiftung (3MS1038), and University Hospital Basel as well as speaker/consulting honoraria or research support from Edwards Lifesciences, Pronova Medical, Meril, Boston Scientific, Medtronic, Abbott, Beckman Coulter, Bayer, Ortho Clinical Diagnostics, and Orion Pharma, outside the submitted work. Dr Koechlin has received a research grant from the Swiss Heart Foundation, University of Basel, Swiss Academy of Medical Sciences, Gottfried and Julia Bangerter-Rhyner Foundation, and the &#x201c;Freiwillige Akademische Gesellschaft Basel&#x201d; as well as speaker honoraria from Roche Diagnostics, Abbott, and Siemens, paid to the institution and outside the submitted work. Dr Haller reports travel support from the German Center of Cardiovascular Research (DZHK) and research support by the Faculty of Medicine, University of Hamburg, German Foundation for Heart Research, and German Research Foundation. Dr Rubini Gimenez has received research grants from the Swiss Heart Foundation and Swiss National Science Foundation (P400PM_180828) as well as speaker/consulting honoraria from Abbott, Ortho Clinical Diagnostics, Roche, and Siemens, outside the submitted work. Dr Wildi has received research support from the University of Queensland (PhD scholarship), Wesley Medical Research Foundation, and University of Basel. Dr Mahfoud has received research grants from Deutsche Gesellschaft f&#xfc;r Kardiologie, Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (SFB TRR219, Project-ID 322900939), and Deutsche Herzstiftung; his former employer (Saarland University) has received scientific support from Ablative Solutions, Medtronic, and ReCor Medical; and he has received speaker honoraria/consulting fees from Ablative Solutions, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Inari, Medtronic, Merck, ReCor Medical, Servier, and Terumo. Dr Twerenbold reports research support from the Swiss National Science Foundation (grant no. P300PB_167803), Swiss Heart Foundation, Swiss Society of Cardiology, and Cardiovascular Research Foundation Basel and speaker/consulting honoraria from Abbott, Amgen, Astra Zeneca, Psyros, Roche, Siemens, Singulex, and Thermo Fisher. Dr Neumann reports speaker honoraria/consulting honoraria from Abbott, PHC, Roche, and Siemens. Drs Twerenbold and Neumann are listed as co-inventors of an international patent on the use of a computing device to estimate the probability of myocardial infarction (International Publication Number WO2022043229A1) as well as co-founders and shareholders of the ART-EMIS Hamburg GmbH. Dr Mueller reports receiving research support from the Swiss National Science Foundation, Swiss Heart Foundation, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Abbott, Astra Zeneca, Beckman Coulter, Boehringer Ingelheim, Brahms, Idorsia, LSI Medience Corporation, Novartis, Ortho Diagnostics, Quidel, Roche, Siemens, SpinChip, Singulex, and Sphingotec, outside the submitted work, as well as speaker/consulting honoraria from Abbott, Amgen, Astra Zeneca, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, BMS, Idorsia, Novartis, Osler, Roche, SpinChip, and Sanofi, all paid to the institution. All other authors have reported that they have no relationships relevant to the contents of this paper to disclose.</CoiStatement><InvestigatorList><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zimmermann</LastName><ForeName>Tobias</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Switzerland; GREAT network, Rome, Italy; (c)Department of Cardiology, Inselspital, University of Bern, Switzerland; (d)Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Luzern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reinhardt</LastName><ForeName>Julia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Switzerland; GREAT network, Rome, Italy; (c)Department of Cardiology, Inselspital, University of Bern, Switzerland; (d)Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Luzern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meier</LastName><ForeName>Mario</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Switzerland; GREAT network, Rome, Italy; (c)Department of Cardiology, Inselspital, University of Bern, Switzerland; (d)Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Luzern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawecki</LastName><ForeName>Damian</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GREAT network, Rome, Italy; (c)Department of Cardiology, Inselspital, University of Bern, Switzerland; (d)Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Luzern, Switzerland; 2nd Department of Cardiology, School of Medicine with the Division of Dentistry in Zabrze, Medical University of Katowice, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morawiec</LastName><ForeName>Beata</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GREAT network, Rome, Italy; (c)Department of Cardiology, Inselspital, University of Bern, Switzerland; (d)Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Luzern, Switzerland; 2nd Department of Cardiology, School of Medicine with the Division of Dentistry in Zabrze, Medical University of Katowice, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Munzk</LastName><ForeName>Piotr</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GREAT network, Rome, Italy; (c)Department of Cardiology, Inselspital, University of Bern, Switzerland; (d)Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Luzern, Switzerland; 2nd Department of Cardiology, School of Medicine with the Division of Dentistry in Zabrze, Medical University of Katowice, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geigy</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Liestal, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rentsch</LastName><ForeName>Katharina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory Medicine, University Hospital Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shrestha</LastName><ForeName>Samyut</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Switzerland; GREAT network, Rome, Italy; (c)Department of Cardiology, Inselspital, University of Bern, Switzerland; (d)Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Luzern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Breidthardt</LastName><ForeName>Tobias</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Institute Basel (CRIB) and Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Switzerland; GREAT network, Rome, Italy; (c)Department of Cardiology, Inselspital, University of Bern, Switzerland; (d)Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Luzern, Switzerland; Department of Internal Medicine, University Hospital Basel, University of Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lehmacher</LastName><ForeName>Jonas</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, University Heart and Vascular Center Hamburg, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schock</LastName><ForeName>Alina</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, University Heart and Vascular Center Hamburg, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toprak</LastName><ForeName>Bet&#xfc;l</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, University Heart and Vascular Center Hamburg, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thie&#xdf;en</LastName><ForeName>Niklas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, University Heart and Vascular Center Hamburg, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martinez-Nadal</LastName><ForeName>Gemma</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GREAT network, Rome, Italy; (c)Department of Cardiology, Inselspital, University of Bern, Switzerland; (d)Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Luzern, Switzerland; Emergency Department, Hospital Clinic, Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fuenzalida</LastName><ForeName>Carolina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GREAT network, Rome, Italy; (c)Department of Cardiology, Inselspital, University of Bern, Switzerland; (d)Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Luzern, Switzerland; Emergency Department, Hospital Clinic, Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Calder&#xf3;n</LastName><ForeName>Sofia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GREAT network, Rome, Italy; (c)Department of Cardiology, Inselspital, University of Bern, Switzerland; (d)Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Luzern, Switzerland; Emergency Department, Hospital Clinic, Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodriguez Adrada</LastName><ForeName>Esther</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GREAT network, Rome, Italy; (c)Department of Cardiology, Inselspital, University of Bern, Switzerland; (d)Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Luzern, Switzerland; Emergency Department, Hospital Cl&#xed;nico San Carlos, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ganovsk&#xe1;</LastName><ForeName>Eva</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GREAT network, Rome, Italy; (c)Department of Cardiology, Inselspital, University of Bern, Switzerland; (d)Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Luzern, Switzerland; Department of Cardiology, University Hospital Brno, Brno, Czech Republic and Medical Faculty, Masaryk University, Brno, Czech Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parenica</LastName><ForeName>Jiri</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GREAT network, Rome, Italy; (c)Department of Cardiology, Inselspital, University of Bern, Switzerland; (d)Emergency Department, Kantonsspital Luzern, Switzerland; Department of Laboratory Medicine, University Hospital Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>von Eckardstein</LastName><ForeName>Arnold</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine, University Hospital Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campodarve</LastName><ForeName>Isabel</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital del Mar, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gea</LastName><ForeName>Joachim</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital del Mar, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blankenberg</LastName><ForeName>Stefan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, University Heart and Vascular Center Hamburg, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mueller</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Investigator></InvestigatorList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41706062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2025.12.056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0735-1097(25)10588-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>