<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41603150</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-9239</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Epilepsia open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Epilepsia Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Semiology in spontaneous versus cortical stimulation-induced seizures during SEEG: A within-patient comparison study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>488</StartPage><EndPage>503</EndPage><MedlinePgn>488-503</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/epi4.70221</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We aimed to study the concordance of seizure semiology in direct electrical stimulation-induced seizures (SIS) compared to spontaneous seizures during stereoelectroencephalography (SEEG) and to report on patient-level variables associated with habitual and atypical SIS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We retrospectively studied consecutive SEEG cases, performing a within-patient comparison of semiology in spontaneous seizures versus SIS. We classified each patient's SIS as "habitual" or "atypical" using a new electroclinical definition. We then classified patients by maximum clinical expression of habitual SIS: "Aura," "Fragment" (objective fragment &#xb1; aura), or "Full." Patient groups with/without SIS and with/without atypical seizures were analyzed regarding demographics, clinical and SEEG characteristics. Reported patient-level variables were categorically expressed as percentages or continuous.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the 67 patients undergoing SEEG, all underwent 50&#x2009;Hz stimulation. Prevalence of patients with SIS was 48/67 (71.6%); most patients had 1-2 SIS. Of 97 SIS, 91/97 (93.8%) were semiologically concordant with habitual spontaneous seizures. Patients' maximum clinical expression of habitual SIS was "Aura" in 14/47 (25.5%), "Fragment" in 16/47 (38.3%), and "Full" in 17/47 (36.2%). Patients presenting any atypical SIS (5/67) accounted for 7.5%; only 1 patient had atypical SIS as the sole SIS. Patients presenting atypical SIS had a tendency to a more widespread epileptogenic zone (EZ) (&gt;1 lobe); none proceeded to surgery following SEEG. There was also a tendency toward female predominance. Rarely, patients with habitual SIS could report "old" habitual semiology triggered during stimulation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SIGNIFICANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This within-patient comparison of semiology of spontaneous versus cortical stimulation-induced seizures (SIS), with semiologic stratification and a proposed electroclinical definition of atypical SIS, shows overall high semiologic concordance and a fairly low proportion (7.5%) of patients presenting atypical SIS at 50&#x2009;Hz. Atypical seizures may occur in conditions where there is an altered stimulation threshold. No correlation was seen between dominant SIS semiologic subtype and surgical outcome.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PLAIN LANGUAGE SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study reports on semiology (clinical symptoms and signs of seizures) in people with epilepsy undergoing in-depth brain exploration for presurgical evaluation. It compares the semiology in seizures occurring spontaneously with the semiology in seizures triggered by direct cortical stimulation. Semiologic similarity was high between spontaneous and stimulation-induced seizures. Atypical seizures triggered by stimulation were fairly rare. Atypical seizures may occur in conditions of altered stimulation threshold. Some patients experienced past seizure semiology reactivated by cortical stimulation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Epilepsia Open published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of International League Against Epilepsy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahizhnan</LastName><ForeName>Marai</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8706-6034</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epilepsy Unit, Mater Hospital, South Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mater Research Institute, University of Queensland, South Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dufau</LastName><ForeName>St&#xe9;phane</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2692-2084</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mater Research Institute, University of Queensland, South Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Brain Institute, University of Queensland, South Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phamnguyen</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9532-7003</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epilepsy Unit, Mater Hospital, South Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kahrom</LastName><ForeName>Arash</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3927-5485</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epilepsy Unit, Mater Hospital, South Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Craig</LastName><ForeName>Donald</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9732-1171</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epilepsy Unit, Mater Hospital, South Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McGonigal</LastName><ForeName>Aileen</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6775-5318</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epilepsy Unit, Mater Hospital, South Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mater Research Institute, University of Queensland, South Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Brain Institute, University of Queensland, South Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Epilepsia Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101692036</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-9239</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012640" MajorTopicYN="Y">Seizures</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004569" MajorTopicYN="Y">Electroencephalography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004558" MajorTopicYN="Y">Electric Stimulation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013238" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stereotaxic Techniques</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002540" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cerebral Cortex</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SEEG</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epilepsy surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">seizure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">semiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stimulation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41603150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/epi4.70221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez&#x2010;Martinez J, Bulacio J, Alexopoulos A, Jehi L, Bingaman W, Najm I. Stereoelectroencephalography in the &#x201c;difficult to localize&#x201d; refractory focal epilepsy: early experience from a North American epilepsy center. Epilepsia. 2013;54:323&#x2013;330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGonigal A, Kahane P, Maillard L, Russo GL, Chauvel P. SEEG around the world. Neurophysiol Clin. 2025;55:103074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGonigal A, Wong C, Archer JS, Nikpour A, Lawn ND, Neal A, et&#xa0;al. Stereoelectroencephalography for Epilepsy Presurgical Assessment: A Nationwide Survey of Evolution of Practice in Australia. Neurol Clin Pract. 2025;15:e200512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei F, Nica A, Valenti&#x2010;Hirsch MP, Adam C, Denuelle M. Interpretation of SEEG recordings. Neurophysiol Clin. 2018;48:53&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGonigal A, Shaker H, Kheder A, Chauvel P. Anatomo&#x2010;electro&#x2010;clinical Correlations. Stereoelectroencephalography. St Louis: Elsevier; 2025. p. 95&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tr&#xe9;buchon A, Chauvel P. Electrical Stimulation for Seizure Induction and Functional Mapping in Stereoelectroencephalography. J Clin Neurophysiol. 2016;33:511&#x2013;521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cockle E, Rayner G, Malpas C, Alpitsis R, Rheims S, O'Brien TJ, et&#xa0;al. An international survey of SEEG cortical stimulation practices. Epilepsia Open. 2023;8:1084&#x2013;1095.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chauvel P, Tr&#xe9;buchon A, McGonigal A. Method of Direct Cortical Stimulation for Triggering Seizures. Stereoelectroencephalography. St Louis: Elsevier; 2025. p. 121&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trebuchon A, Racila R, Cardinale F, Lagarde S, McGonigal A, Russo GL, et&#xa0;al. Electrical stimulation for seizure induction during SEEG exploration: a useful predictor of postoperative seizure recurrence? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2021;92:22&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovac S, Kahane P, Diehl B. Seizures induced by direct electrical cortical stimulation&#x2013;Mechanisms and clinical considerations. Clin Neurophysiol. 2016;127:31&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oderiz CC, von Ellenrieder N, Dubeau F, Eisenberg A, Gotman J, Hall J, et&#xa0;al. Association of cortical stimulation&#x2013;induced seizure with surgical outcome in patients with focal drug&#x2010;resistant epilepsy. JAMA Neurol. 2019;76:1070&#x2013;1078.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei F, Lagarde S, Wendling F, McGonigal A, Jirsa V, Guye M, et&#xa0;al. Defining epileptogenic networks: Contribution of SEEG and signal analysis. Epilepsia. 2017;58:1131&#x2013;1147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wieser H, Bancaud J, Talairach J, Bonis A, Szikla G. Comparative value of spontaneous and chemically and electrically induced seizures in establishing the lateralization of temporal lobe seizures. Epilepsia. 1979;20:47&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landr&#xe9; E, Turak B, Toussaint D, Trottier S. Int&#xe9;r&#xea;t des stimulations &#xe9;lectriques intrac&#xe9;r&#xe9;brales en st&#xe9;r&#xe9;o&#xe9;lectroenc&#xe9;phalographie dans les &#xe9;pilepsies partielles. Epilepsies. 2004;16:213&#x2013;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chauvel P, Landr&#xe9; E, Trottier S, Vignel JP, Biraben A, Devaux B, et&#xa0;al. Electrical stimulation with intracerebral electrodes to evoke seizures. Adv Neurol. 1993;63:115&#x2013;121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernier GP, Richer F, Giard N, Bouvier G, Merrier M, Turmel A, et&#xa0;al. Electrical stimulation of the human brain in epilepsy. Epilepsia. 1990;31:513&#x2013;520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox J, Yu Y, Englot DJ, Ssentongo P, Lekoubou A. Seizure outcomes after cortical stimulation&#x2010;induced seizures: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Epilepsy Behav. 2025;172:110518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isnard J, Taussig D, Bartolomei F, Bourdillon P, Catenoix H, Chassoux F, et&#xa0;al. French guidelines on stereoelectroencephalography (SEEG). Neurophysiol Clin. 2017;48:5&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ley M, Pel&#xe1;ez N, Principe A, Langohr K, Zucca R, Rocamora R. Validation of direct cortical stimulation in presurgical evaluation of epilepsy. Clin Neurophysiol. 2022;137:38&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrowsky K, Desestret V, Ryvlin P, Coste S, Maugui&#xe8;re F. Direct electrical stimulations of the temporal pole in human. Epileptic Disord. 2002;4:S23&#x2013;S27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudio M, Kahane P, Tassi L, Francione S, Hoffmann D, Russo GL, et&#xa0;al. Intracerebral low frequency electrical stimulation: a new tool for the definition of the &#x201c;epileptogenic area&#x201d;? Advances in Stereotactic and Functional Neurosurgery 10: Proceedings of the 10th Meeting of the European Society for Stereotactic and Functional Neurosurgery Stockholm 1992. Vienna: Springer Vienna; 1993. p. 181&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivaraju A, Quraishi I, Collins E, McGrath H, Ramos A, Turk&#x2010;Browne NB, et&#xa0;al. Systematic 1 Hz direct electrical stimulation for seizure induction: A reliable method for localizing seizure onset zone and predicting seizure freedom. Brain Stimul. 2024;17:339&#x2013;345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGonigal A, Bartolomei F, Chauvel P. On seizure semiology. Epilepsia. 2021;62:2019&#x2013;2035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL. Gender differences in the reporting of physical and somatoform symptoms. Psychosom Med. 1998;60:150&#x2013;155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson P, Perry KN. Psychological interventions for psychogenic non&#x2010;epileptic seizures: a meta&#x2010;analysis. Seizure. 2017;45:142&#x2013;150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reindl C, Unger M, Walther K, Lang JD, Gollwitzer S, Cuny J, et&#xa0;al. The prognostic value of cortical stimulation induced seizures using stereo EEG in presurgical evaluation of focal epilepsies. Sci Rep. 2025;15:7941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe4;mpfer C, Racz A, Quesada CM, Elger CE, Surges R. Predictive value of electrically induced seizures for postsurgical seizure outcome. Clin Neurophysiol. 2020;131:2289&#x2013;2297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bratu I&#x2010;F, El Youssef N, Lagarde S, Bartolomei F. Modulation of neural complexity and consciousness in temporal lobe seizures: Effects of high&#x2010;frequency pulvinar stimulation. Epileptic Disord. 2025;27:1004&#x2013;1010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGonigal A, Lagarde S, Tr&#xe9;buchon&#x2010;Dafonseca A, Roehri N, Bartolomei F. Early onset motor semiology in seizures triggered by cortical stimulation during SEEG. Epilepsy Behav. 2018;88:262&#x2013;267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojemann WKS, Armstrong C, Pattnaik A, Petillo N, Josyula M, Daum A, et&#xa0;al. Can electrical stimulation replace spontaneous seizures in epilepsy surgery? medRxiv. 2025;2025.2008.2029.25334082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmedt&#x2010;Aristizabal D, Armin MA, Hayder Z, Garcia&#x2010;Cairasco N, Petersson L, Fookes C, et&#xa0;al. Deep learning approaches for seizure video analysis: A review. Epilepsy Behav. 2024;154:109735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauld C, Bartolomei F, Micoulaud&#x2010;Franchi JA, McGonigal A. Symptom network analysis of prefrontal seizures. Epilepsia. 2025;66:2566&#x2013;2577.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>