<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41418072</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3708</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>96</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of plastic surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Plast Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effect of Bradykinin B2 Receptor on Multiterritory Perforator Flap Survival in Rats: An Experimental Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>179</StartPage><EndPage>186</EndPage><MedlinePgn>179-186</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/SAP.0000000000004598</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The bradykinin B2 receptor (B2R), a type of G protein-coupled receptor, exerts several beneficial biological effects on flaps. Accordingly, we investigated the role of the bradykinin B2R in the survival of perforator flaps.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this study, a total of 50 male Sprague-Dawley rats were allocated equally into 2 groups: one receiving a bradykinin B2R blocker and the other serving as a control, with both groups undergoing flap procedures. Flap viability was assessed 7 days postoperatively by quantifying the surviving flap area. Blood perfusion within the flap was evaluated using laser Doppler imaging. The levels of Beclin-1, p62, and LC3-II/I were used to assess autophagy. The extent of flap angiogenesis was evaluated using immunohistochemistry and hematoxylin and eosin staining. Western blotting revealed the expression levels of vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) and the apoptotic index. Moreover, superoxide dismutase (SOD) activity and malondialdehyde (MDA) levels were used to evaluate oxidative stress. This study used a nitric oxide (NO) assay kit to determine NO production.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The bradykinin B2R blocker group exhibited significantly reduced flap survival areas (blocker group: 64.7 &#xb1; 3.36%; control group: 85.6 &#xb1; 3.35%; P &lt; 0.01), diminished blood perfusion (blocker group: 389.8 &#xb1; 7.92; control group: 491.8 &#xb1; 5.81; P &lt; 0.05), and decreased neovascularization (blocker group: 20.13 &#xb1; 1.58; control group: 52.17 &#xb1; 1.49; P &lt; 0.05). Compared to the control group, the bradykinin B2R blocker group also demonstrated lower SOD activity, NO content, and VEGF expression, and increased MDA levels (all P &lt; 0.05). Rats treated with the bradykinin B2R blocker exhibited higher levels of autophagy and apoptosis than those observed in the control group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">According to our research, the bradykinin B2R protects multiterritory perforator flaps through diverse molecular pathways, which involve inhibiting apoptosis, combating oxidation, modulating autophagy, and fostering angiogenesis to improve the blood supply to the flap.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jieke</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Hand and Plastic Surgery, The Second Affiliated Hospital and Yuying Children's Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Manli</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Laboratory Center, The Second Affiliated Hospital and Yuying Children's Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Plast Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7805336</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-7043</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D043782">Receptor, Bradykinin B2</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D065094">Bradykinin B2 Receptor Antagonists</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D042461">Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor A</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017207" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Sprague-Dawley</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061525" MajorTopicYN="Y">Perforator Flap</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000098" MajorTopicYN="N">blood supply</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006085" MajorTopicYN="Y">Graft Survival</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D043782" MajorTopicYN="Y">Receptor, Bradykinin B2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065094" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bradykinin B2 Receptor Antagonists</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018384" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative Stress</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018919" MajorTopicYN="N">Neovascularization, Physiologic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001343" MajorTopicYN="N">Autophagy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017209" MajorTopicYN="N">Apoptosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042461" MajorTopicYN="N">Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor A</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">B1R: Bradykinin B1 receptor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">B2R: Bradykinin B2 receptor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CST: Cell Signaling Technology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CVZ: Choke vessel zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DCI: Deep circumflex iliac</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DCIA: Deep circumflex iliac artery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GPCR: G protein-coupled receptor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">H&amp;E: Hematoxylin and eosin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">I/R: Ischemia-reperfusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IC: Intercostal artery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IHC: Immunohistochemistry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">KDR/Flk-1: Kinase insert domain receptor/fetal liver kinase-1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MDA: Malondialdehyde</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MVD: Microvascular density</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NO: Nitric oxide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NOS: Nitric oxide synthase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">POD: Postoperative day</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PU: Perfusion units</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SD: Sprague-Dawley</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SOD: Superoxide dismutase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SPF: Specific-pathogen-free</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TD: Thoracodorsal artery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VEGF: Vascular endothelial growth factor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">angiogenesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apoptosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autophagy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blo: blocker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bradykinin B2 receptor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">con: control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eNOS: endothelial nitric oxide synthase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">perforator flap</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest and sources of funding: none declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41418072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SAP.0000000000004598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00000637-202602000-00012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Taylor GI, Corlett RJ, Dhar SC, et al. The anatomical (angiosome) and clinical territories of cutaneous perforating arteries: development of the concept and designing safe flaps. Plast Reconstr Surg . 2011;127:1447&#x2013;1459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor GI, Corlett RJ, Caddy CM, et al. An anatomic review of the delay phenomenon: II. Clinical applications. Plast Reconstr Surg . 1992;89:408&#x2013;416 discussion 417-418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, Sheng L, Li H, et al. Improvement of the skin flap survival with the bone marrow-derived mononuclear cells transplantation in a rat model. Microsurgery . 2010;30:275&#x2013;281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Jin Z, Wang J, et al. Detrimental effect of hypoxia-inducible factor-1&#x3b1;-induced autophagy on multiterritory perforator flap survival in rats. Sci Rep . 2017;7:11791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima LP, de Oliveira Albuquerque A, de Lima Silva JJ, et al. Electroacupuncture attenuates oxidative stress in random skin flaps in rats. Aesthetic Plast Surg . 2012;36:1230&#x2013;1235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosnuter M, Babuc&#xe7;u O, Kargi E, et al. Dual preconditioning: effects of pharmacological plus ischemic preconditioning on skin flap survival. Ann Plast Surg . 2003;50:398&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Ji E, Lin C, et al. Effects of bradykinin on the survival of multiterritory perforator flaps in rats. World J Surg Oncol . 2019;17:44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeb-Lundberg LM, Marceau F, M&#xfc;ller-Esterl W, et al. International Union of Pharmacology. XLV. Classification of the kinin receptor family: from molecular mechanisms to pathophysiological consequences. Pharmacol Rev . 2005;57:27&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takano M, Matsuyama S. Intracellular and nuclear bradykinin B2 receptors. Eur J Pharmacol . 2014;732:169&#x2013;172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Tu L, Jiang W, et al. Bradykinin prevents the apoptosis of NIT-1 cells induced by TNF-&#x3b1; via the PI3K/Akt and MAPK signaling pathways. Int J Mol Med . 2012;29:891&#x2013;898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sang H, Liu L, Wang L, et al. Opposite roles of bradykinin B1 and B2 receptors during cerebral ischaemia-reperfusion injury in experimental diabetic rats. Eur J Neurosci . 2016;43:53&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miura S, Matsuo Y, Saku K. Transactivation of KDR/Flk-1 by the B2 receptor induces tube formation in human coronary endothelial cells. Hypertension . 2003;41:1118&#x2013;1123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalka C, Tehrani H, Laudenberg B, et al. VEGF gene transfer mobilizes endothelial progenitor cells in patients with inoperable coronary disease. Ann Thorac Surg . 2000;70:829&#x2013;834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song K, Zhang M, Hu J, et al. Methane-rich saline attenuates ischemia/reperfusion injury of abdominal skin flaps in rats via regulating apoptosis level. BMC Surg . 2015;15:92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvestre JS, Bergaya S, Tamarat R, et al. Proangiogenic effect of angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibition is mediated by the bradykinin B(2) receptor pathway. Circ Res . 2001;89:678&#x2013;683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji B, Cheng B, Pan Y, et al. Neuroprotection of bradykinin/bradykinin B2 receptor system in cerebral ischemia. Biomed Pharmacother . 2017;94:1057&#x2013;1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith CM, Chen Y, Sullivan ML, et al. Autophagy in acute brain injury: feast, famine, or folly? Neurobiol Dis . 2011;43:52&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishida K, Yamaguchi O, Otsu K. Crosstalk between autophagy and apoptosis in heart disease. Circ Res . 2008;103:343&#x2013;351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moraes MS, Costa PE, Batista WL, et al. Endothelium-derived nitric oxide (NO) activates the NO-epidermal growth factor receptor-mediated signaling pathway in bradykinin-stimulated angiogenesis. Arch Biochem Biophys . 2014;558:14&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loiola RA, Reis FC, Kawamoto EM, et al. Role of vascular Kinin B1 and B2 receptors in endothelial nitric oxide metabolism. Peptides . 2011;32:1700&#x2013;1705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao XY, Wang L, Gao WY, et al. The effect of inducible nitric oxide synthase on multiterritory perforator flap survival in rats. J Reconstr Microsurg . 2016;32:643&#x2013;649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogawa R, Oki K, Hyakusoku H. Skin perforator freeways and pathways: understanding the role of true and choke anastomoses between perforator angiosomes and their impact on skin flap planning and outcomes. Plast Reconstr Surg . 2014;133:719e&#x2013;720e.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy S, Ganguly A, Haque M, et al. Angiogenic host defense peptide AG-30/5C and bradykinin B 2 receptor antagonist Icatibant are G protein biased agonists for MRGPRX2 in mast cells. J Immunol . 2019;202:1229&#x2013;1238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griesbacher T, Kolbitsch C, Tiran B, et al. Effects of the bradykinin antagonist, icatibant (Hoe 140), on pancreas and liver functions during and after caerulein-induced pancreatitis in rats. Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol . 1995;352:557&#x2013;564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth KJ, Gehring D, Sch&#xf6;lkens BA. Effect of Hoe 140 on bradykinin-induced bronchoconstriction in anesthetized guinea pigs. Am Rev Respir Dis . 1993;148:702&#x2013;706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farmer SG, Burch RM. Biochemical and molecular pharmacology of kinin receptors. Annu Rev Pharmacol Toxicol . 1992;32:511&#x2013;536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marceau F, Regoli D. Bradykinin receptor ligands: therapeutic perspectives. Nat Rev Drug Discov . 2004;3:845&#x2013;852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida H, Zhang JJ, Chao L, et al. Kallikrein gene delivery attenuates myocardial infarction and apoptosis after myocardial ischemia and reperfusion. Hypertension . 2000;35(1 Pt 1):25&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oeseburg H, Iusuf D, van der Harst P, et al. Bradykinin protects against oxidative stress-induced endothelial cell senescence. Hypertension . 2009;53:417&#x2013;422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishihara K, Kamata M, Hayashi I, et al. Roles of bradykinin in vascular permeability and angiogenesis in solid tumor. Int Immunopharmacol . 2002;2:499&#x2013;509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikeda Y, Hayashi I, Kamoshita E, et al. Host stromal bradykinin B2 receptor signaling facilitates tumor-associated angiogenesis and tumor growth. Cancer Res . 2004;64:5178&#x2013;5185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakita T, Suzuki M, Takeuchi H, et al. Significance of xanthine oxidase in the production of intracellular oxygen radicals in an in-vitro hypoxia-reoxygenation model. J Hepatobiliary Pancreat Surg . 2002;9:249&#x2013;255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah AM, Channon KM. Free radicals and redox signalling in cardiovascular disease. Heart . 2004;90:486&#x2013;487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angel MF, Im MJ, Chung HK, et al. Effects of combined cold and hyperbaric oxygen storage on free flap survival. Microsurgery . 1994;15:648&#x2013;651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Im MJ, Hoopes JE, Yoshimura Y, et al. Xanthine:acceptor oxidoreductase activities in ischemic rat skin flaps. J Surg Res . 1989;46:230&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ushio-Fukai M, Tang Y, Fukai T, et al. Novel role of gp91(phox)-containing NAD(P)H oxidase in vascular endothelial growth factor-induced signaling and angiogenesis. Circ Res . 2002;91:1160&#x2013;1167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West XZ, Malinin NL, Merkulova AA, et al. Oxidative stress induces angiogenesis by activating TLR2 with novel endogenous ligands. Nature . 2010;467:972&#x2013;976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okuno Y, Nakamura-Ishizu A, Otsu K, et al. Pathological neoangiogenesis depends on oxidative stress regulation by ATM. Nat Med . 2012;18:1208&#x2013;1216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydogan H, Gurlek A, Parlakpinar H, et al. Beneficial effects of caffeic acid phenethyl ester (CAPE) on the ischaemia-reperfusion injury in rat skin flaps. J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg . 2007;60:563&#x2013;568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng GM, Yang WG, Huan-Tang Chen S, et al. Periodic alterations of jejunal mucosa morphology following free microvascular transfer for pharyngoesophageal reconstruction. J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg . 2006;59:1312&#x2013;1317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang WZ, Baynosa RC, Zamboni WA. Update on ischemia-reperfusion injury for the plastic surgeon: 2011. Plast Reconstr Surg . 2011;128:685e&#x2013;692e.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Heuvel MG, Buurman WA, Bast A, et al. Review: Ischaemia-reperfusion injury in flap surgery. J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg . 2009;62:721&#x2013;726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia CF, Yin H, Yao YY, et al. Kallikrein protects against ischemic stroke by inhibiting apoptosis and inflammation and promoting angiogenesis and neurogenesis. Hum Gene Ther . 2006;17:206&#x2013;219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia CF, Yin H, Borlongan CV, et al. Kallikrein gene transfer protects against ischemic stroke by promoting glial cell migration and inhibiting apoptosis. Hypertension . 2004;43:452&#x2013;459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang M, Cui M, Dong Q, et al. The bradykinin B2 receptor mediates hypoxia/reoxygenation induced neuronal cell apoptosis through the ERK1/2 pathway. Neurosci Lett . 2009;450:40&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwak SJ, Paeng J, Kim DH, et al. Local kallikrein-kinin system is involved in podocyte apoptosis under diabetic conditions. Apoptosis . 2011;16:478&#x2013;490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizushima N, Levine B, Cuervo AM, et al. Autophagy fights disease through cellular self-digestion. Nature . 2008;451:1069&#x2013;1075.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabryel B, Kost A, Kasprowska D. Neuronal autophagy in cerebral ischemia&#x2014;a potential target for neuroprotective strategies? Pharmacol Rep . 2012;64:1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherz-Shouval R, Elazar Z. Regulation of autophagy by ROS: physiology and pathology. Trends Biochem Sci . 2011;36:30&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vande Velde C, Cizeau J, Dubik D, et al. BNIP3 and genetic control of necrosis-like cell death through the mitochondrial permeability transition pore. Mol Cell Biol . 2000;20:5454&#x2013;5468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsui Y, Takagi H, Qu X, et al. Distinct roles of autophagy in the heart during ischemia and reperfusion: roles of AMP-activated protein kinase and Beclin 1 in mediating autophagy. Circ Res . 2007;100:914&#x2013;922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng B, Mao JH, Qian L, et al. Pre-clinical evaluation of AZD-2014, a novel mTORC1/2 dual inhibitor, against renal cell carcinoma. Cancer Lett . 2015;357:468&#x2013;475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou KL, Zhang YH, Lin DS, et al. Effects of calcitriol on random skin flap survival in rats. Sci Rep . 2016;6:18945.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bola&#xf1;os JP, Heales SJ. Persistent mitochondrial damage by nitric oxide and its derivatives: neuropathological implications. Front Neuroenergetics . 2010;2:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thuringer D, Maulon L, Frelin C. Rapid transactivation of the vascular endothelial growth factor receptor KDR/Flk-1 by the bradykinin B2 receptor contributes to endothelial nitric-oxide synthase activation in cardiac capillary endothelial cells. J Biol Chem . 2002;277:2028&#x2013;2032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R, Peng L, Zhao J, et al. Gardenamide A protects RGC-5 cells from H 2 O 2 -induced oxidative stress insults by activating PI3K/Akt/eNOS signaling pathway. Int J Mol Sci . 2015;16:22350&#x2013;22367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaminskyy VO, Zhivotovsky B. Free radicals in cross talk between autophagy and apoptosis. Antioxid Redox Signal . 2014;21:86&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Numajiri N, Takasawa K, Nishiya T, et al. On-off system for PI3-kinase-Akt signaling through S-nitrosylation of phosphatase with sequence homology to tensin (PTEN). Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A . 2011;108:10349&#x2013;10354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Lin M, Dai J, et al. Ultrasound-activated directional and controllable nitric oxide therapy for vascular calcification repair through the modulation of eNOS/iNOS homeostasis. Acta Biomater . 2025:S1742&#x2013;7061(25)00690-7. doi: 10.1016/j.actbio.2025.09.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actbio.2025.09.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma T, Zhang Z, Chen Y, et al. Delivery of nitric oxide in the cardiovascular system: implications for clinical diagnosis and therapy. Int J Mol Sci . 2021;22:12166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furuhashi K, Kakiuchi M, Ueda R, et al. Bone marrow niches orchestrate stem-cell hierarchy and immune tolerance. Nature . 2025;638:206&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>