<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41140973</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2251-6581</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of diabetes and metabolic disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Diabetes Metab Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A bibliometric and visual analysis of global gestational diabetes mellitus over the past 24 years.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>247</StartPage><MedlinePgn>247</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">247</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40200-025-01752-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Pregnancy is associated with a metabolic burden on women,&#xa0;along with weight gain and insulin resistance. Gestational diabetes mellitus&#xa0;(GDM) is the most common complication of pregnancy and can be defined as&#xa0;a state of glucose intolerance with onset or first recognition during&#xa0;pregnancy. This study presents a bibliometric and visual analysis of GDM&#xa0;research over the past 24 years.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To present a bibliometric and visual analysis of GDM research over&#xa0;the past 24 years and provide new insights for the future development and&#xa0;research direction of GDM.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We retrieved and collected the research literature about GDM in&#xa0;the past 24 years from Web of Science, and analyzed and visualized the&#xa0;research literature from multiple aspects using CiteSpace and VOS viewer.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">An analysis of 27660 articles in the field of GDM revealed a&#xa0;significant upward trend in the number of publications over the past 24 years,&#xa0;with authors primarily from the USA and China. Peter Damm and Boyd E&#xa0;Metzger were identified as the most prolific and highly cited authors,&#xa0;respectively. The journal with the highest number of publications was The&#xa0;Journal of Maternal-Fetal &amp; Neonatal Medicine. In addition, keyword&#xa0;co-occurrence analysis indicated that research on GDM mainly focused on&#xa0;risk factors of the disease, clinical diagnosis, and management. The keyword&#xa0;burst analysis of cited references indicated that gut microbiome association&#xa0;with GDM is a hot topic in recent years and requires further long-term&#xa0;planning.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">For the first time, this study conducted a multi-index&#xa0;bibliometric analysis of articles in the field of global GDM in the past 24&#xa0;years. The USA and China are in a leading position in this field. The&#xa0;development of GDM research has transitioned from basic risk factors and&#xa0;clinical classification management to more complex intervention and&#xa0;mechanism studies. The association research between gut microbiome and&#xa0;GDM may be a hot topic in the future. This study is the first to analyze the&#xa0;global field of GDM from multiple indicators by bibliometrics, thus providing&#xa0;new insights into the research hotspots and development trends in the field&#xa0;of GDM.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1007/s40200-025-01752-z.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Tehran University of Medical Sciences 2025. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhengzhou KingMed Center for Clinical Laboratory, 1&#x2009;st Building, No. 116, 16th Street (Jingkai) China (Henan) Pilot Free Trade Zone Zhengzhou Area, Henan Province Zhengzhou City, 450000 P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Li-Meng</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhengzhou KingMed Center for Clinical Laboratory, 1&#x2009;st Building, No. 116, 16th Street (Jingkai) China (Henan) Pilot Free Trade Zone Zhengzhou Area, Henan Province Zhengzhou City, 450000 P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Chen-Xi</ForeName><Initials>CX</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhengzhou KingMed Center for Clinical Laboratory, 1&#x2009;st Building, No. 116, 16th Street (Jingkai) China (Henan) Pilot Free Trade Zone Zhengzhou Area, Henan Province Zhengzhou City, 450000 P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Jia</ForeName><Initials>YJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhengzhou KingMed Center for Clinical Laboratory, 1&#x2009;st Building, No. 116, 16th Street (Jingkai) China (Henan) Pilot Free Trade Zone Zhengzhou Area, Henan Province Zhengzhou City, 450000 P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Diabetes Metab Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101590741</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2251-6581</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bibliometric analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bibliometrics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Citespace</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GDM</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gestational diabetes mellitus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VOSviewer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interestsThe authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41140973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12549507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40200-025-01752-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Castilla C, Hernandez M, Bergua M, Alvarez MC, Arce MA, Rodriguez K, Martinez-Alonso M, Iglesias M, Mateu M, Santos MD, et al. Low-carbohydrate diet for the treatment of gestational diabetes mellitus: a randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Care. 2013;36(8):2233&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3714525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23564917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon JH, Jang HC. Gestational diabetes mellitus: diagnostic approaches and maternal-offspring complications. Diabetes Metab J. 2022;46(1):3&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8831816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35135076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen L, Poulsen CW, Kampmann U, Smedegaard SB, Ovesen PG, Fuglsang J. Diet and healthy lifestyle in the management of gestational diabetes mellitus. Nutrients. 2020. 10.3390/nu12103050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12103050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7602804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33081105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang HC, Cho NH, Min YK, Han IK, Jung KB, Metzger BE. Increased macrosomia and perinatal morbidity independent of maternal obesity and advanced age in Korean women with GDM. Diabetes Care. 1997;20(10):1582&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9314639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metzger BE, Lowe LP, Dyer AR, Trimble ER, Chaovarindr U, Coustan DR, Hadden DR, McCance DR, Hod M, McIntyre HD, et al. Hyperglycemia and adverse pregnancy outcomes. N Engl J Med. 2008;358(19):1991&#x2013;2002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18463375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vounzoulaki E, Khunti K, Abner SC, Tan BK, Davies MJ, Gillies CL. Progression to type 2 diabetes in women with a known history of gestational diabetes: systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ. 2020;369:m1361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7218708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32404325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mijatovic-Vukas J, Capling L, Cheng S, Stamatakis E, Louie J, Cheung NW, et al. Associations of diet and physical activity with risk for gestational diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients. 2018;10(6):698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6024719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29849003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehnen H, Zechner U, Haaf T. Epigenetics of gestational diabetes mellitus and offspring health: the time for action is in early stages of life. Mol Hum Reprod. 2013;19(7):415&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3690806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23515667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeting A, Wong J, Murphy HR, Ross GP. A clinical update on gestational diabetes mellitus. Endocr Rev. 2022;43(5):763&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9512153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35041752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicklow B, Retnakaran R. Gestational diabetes mellitus and its implications across the life span. Diabetes Metab J. 2023;47(3):333&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10244196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36750271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninkov A, Frank JR, Maggio LA. Bibliometrics: methods for studying academic publishing. Perspect Med Educ. 2022;11(3):173&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9240160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34914027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zen &#xc7;&#x131;nar &#x130;. Bibliometric analysis of breast cancer research in the period 2009&#x2013;2018. Int J Nurs Pract. 2020;26(3):e12845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32406145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicks D, Wouters P, Waltman L, de Rijcke S, Rafols I. Bibliometrics: the Leiden manifesto for research metrics. Nature. 2015;520(7548):429&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25903611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuaib W, Khan MS, Shahid H, Valdes EA, Alweis R. Bibliometric analysis of the top 100 cited cardiovascular articles. Am J Cardiol. 2015;115(7):972&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25670637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhri AF, Siddiqui A, Khan NR, Cohen HL. Understanding bibliometric parameters and analysis. Radiographics. 2015;35(3):736&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25969932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Zhang Y, Zhang Y, Li B. A bibliometric analysis of gastric cancer liver metastases: advances in mechanisms of occurrence and treatment options. Int J Surg. 2024;110(4):2288&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11020032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38215249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson M, Sampson M, Barrowman N, Doja A. Bibliometric analysis of neurology articles published in general medicine journals. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(4):e215840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8050738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33856477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferdaus J, Rochy EA, Biswas U, Tiang JJ, Nahid AA. Analyzing diabetes detection and classification: a bibliometric review (2000&#x2013;2023). Sensors. 2024. 10.3390/s24165346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24165346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11359783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39205040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y, Wan K, Liu C, Cheng W, Wang R. Mechanisms of exercise intervention in type 2 diabetes: a bibliometric and visualization analysis based on CiteSpace. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2024;15:1401342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11324446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39149117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, He Z, Chen Q, Chen Y, Chen G, Liu C. Global research trends of diabetes remission: a bibliometric study. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2023;14:1272651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10715259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38089622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Hu Z, Liu S, Tseng H. Emerging trends in regenerative medicine: a scientometric analysis in CiteSpace. Expert Opin Biol Ther. 2012;12(5):593&#x2013;608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22443895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eck NJ, Waltman L. Software survey: VOSviewer, a computer program for bibliometric mapping. Scientometrics. 2010;84(2):523&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2883932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20585380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damm P, K&#xfc;hl C, Hornnes P, M&#xf8;lsted-Pedersen L. A longitudinal study of plasma insulin and glucagon in women with previous gestational diabetes. Diabetes Care. 1995;18(5):654&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8586003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bytoft B, Knorr S, Vlachova Z, Jensen RB, Mathiesen ER, Beck-Nielsen H, et al. Long-term cognitive implications of intrauterine hyperglycemia in adolescent offspring of women with type 1 diabetes (the EPICOM study). Diabetes Care. 2016;39(8):1356&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27271191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houshmand A, Jensen DM, Mathiesen ER, Damm P. Evolution of diagnostic criteria for gestational diabetes mellitus. Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2013;92(7):739&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23600679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clausen TD, Mathiesen ER, Hansen T, Pedersen O, Jensen DM, Lauenborg J, et al. Overweight and the metabolic syndrome in adult offspring of women with diet-treated gestational diabetes mellitus or type 1 diabetes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2009;94(7):2464&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19417040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Rawal S, Chong YS. Risk factors for gestational diabetes: is prevention possible? Diabetologia. 2016;59(7):1385&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6364673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27165093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Williams MA, Frederick IO, King IB, Sorensen TK, Kestin MM, Dashow EE, Luthy DA. Vitamin C and the risk of gestational diabetes mellitus: a case-control study. J Reprod Med. 2004;49(4):257&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15134150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Ning Y. Effect of dietary and lifestyle factors on the risk of gestational diabetes: review of epidemiologic evidence. Am J Clin Nutr. 2011;94(6 Suppl):s1975&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Zhu Y, Wu J, Hinkle SN, Tobias DK, Ma RCW, et al. Changes of plasma phospholipid fatty acids profiles in pregnancy in relation to the diagnosis and treatment of gestational diabetes mellitus. Clin Chem. 2021;67(12):1660&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34632496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons D, Immanuel J, Hague WM, Coat S, Teede H, Nolan CJ, et al. Effect of treatment for early gestational diabetes mellitus on neonatal respiratory distress: a secondary analysis of the TOBOGM study. Bjog. 2024. 10.1111/1471-0528.17938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1471-0528.17938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12137773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39157877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seifu CN, Immanuel J, Hague WM, Teede H, Cheung NW, Hibbert EJ, Nolan CJ, Peek MJ, Wong VW, Flack JR, et al. Association between immediate treatment of early gestational diabetes mellitus and breastfeeding outcomes: findings from the TOBOGM study. Diabetes Care. 2024;47(12):e99&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38441605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kautzky-Willer A, Winhofer Y, Weitgasser R, Lechleitner M, Harreiter J. [Clinical practice recommendations for diabetes in pregnancy (Update 2023)]. Wien Klin Wochenschr. 2023;135(Suppl 1):129&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10133056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37101033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dieberger AM, van Poppel MNM, Desoye G, Simmons D, Harreiter J, Devlieger R, Medina C, Lawlor DA, Elhakeem A. Effect of a physical activity and healthy eating lifestyle intervention in pregnancy on fetal growth trajectories: the DALI randomised controlled trial. Pediatr Obes 2025:e13199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnostic criteria and classification. Of hyperglycaemia first detected in pregnancy: a world health organization guideline. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2014;103(3):341&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24847517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinert LS. International association of diabetes and pregnancy study groups recommendations on the diagnosis and classification of hyperglycemia in pregnancy: comment to the international association of diabetes and pregnancy study groups consensus panel. Diabetes Care. 2010;33(7):e97. author reply e98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20587717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Cianni G, Volpe L, Lencioni C, Miccoli R, Cuccuru I, Ghio A, et al. Prevalence and risk factors for gestational diabetes assessed by universal screening. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2003;62(2):131&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14581150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cypryk K, Szymczak W, Czupryniak L, Sobczak M, Lewi&#x144;ski A. Gestational diabetes mellitus - an analysis of risk factors. Endokrynol Pol. 2008;59(5):393&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18979449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleary-Goldman J, Malone FD, Vidaver J, Ball RH, Nyberg DA, Comstock CH, et al. Impact of maternal age on obstetric outcome. Obstet Gynecol. 2005;105(5 Pt 1):983&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15863534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon CG, Willett WC, Carey VJ, Rich-Edwards J, Hunter DJ, Colditz GA, et al. A prospective study of pregravid determinants of gestational diabetes mellitus. JAMA. 1997;278(13):1078&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9315766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamberlain C, McNamara B, Williams ED, Yore D, Oldenburg B, Oats J, et al. Diabetes in pregnancy among Indigenous women in Australia, Canada, New Zealand and the United States. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2013;29(4):241&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3698691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23315909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Wei Y, Gao X, Xu X, Fan L, He J, et al. Risk factors for gestational diabetes mellitus in Chinese women: a prospective study of 16,286 pregnant women in China. Diabet Med. 2009;26(11):1099&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19929987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morisset AS, St-Yves A, Veillette J, Weisnagel SJ, Tchernof A, Robitaille J. Prevention of gestational diabetes mellitus: a review of studies on weight management. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2010;26(1):17&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19943327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss JL, Malone FD, Emig D, Ball RH, Nyberg DA, Comstock CH, et al. Obesity, obstetric complications and cesarean delivery rate&#x2013;a population-based screening study. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2004;190(4):1091&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15118648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powe CE, Nodzenski M, Talbot O, Allard C, Briggs C, Leya MV, Perron P, Bouchard L, Florez JC, Scholtens DM, et al. Genetic determinants of glycemic traits and the risk of gestational diabetes mellitus. Diabetes. 2018;67(12):2703&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6245229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30257980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Y, Huang C, He Q, Liao S, Luo B. Effects of mHealth-based lifestyle interventions on gestational diabetes mellitus in pregnant women with overweight and obesity: systematic review and meta-analysis. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2024;12:e49373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10831670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38231555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berggren EK, Boggess KA, Funk MJ, Stuebe AM. Racial disparities in perinatal outcomes among women with gestational diabetes. J Womens Health. 2012;21(5):521&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeting AN, Appelblom H, Ross GP, Wong J, Kouru H, Williams PF, et al. First trimester prediction of gestational diabetes mellitus: a clinical model based on maternal demographic parameters. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2017;127:44&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28319801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syngelaki A, Visser GH, Krithinakis K, Wright A, Nicolaides KH. First trimester screening for gestational diabetes mellitus by maternal factors and markers of inflammation. Metabolism. 2016;65(3):131&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26892524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanda S, Savvidou M, Syngelaki A, Akolekar R, Nicolaides KH. Prediction of gestational diabetes mellitus by maternal factors and biomarkers at 11 to 13 weeks. Prenat Diagn. 2011;31(2):135&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21268030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Leeuwen M, Opmeer BC, Zweers EJ, van Ballegooie E, ter Brugge HG, de Valk HW, Visser GH, Mol BW. Estimating the risk of gestational diabetes mellitus: a clinical prediction model based on patient characteristics and medical history. <i>Bjog</i> 2010, 117(1):69&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedderson MM, Gunderson EP, Ferrara A. Gestational weight gain and risk of gestational diabetes mellitus. Obstet Gynecol. 2010;115(3):597&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3180899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20177292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;hl C. Etiology and pathogenesis of gestational diabetes. Diabetes Care. 1998;21(Suppl 2):B19&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9704223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbour LA, McCurdy CE, Hernandez TL, Kirwan JP, Catalano PM, Friedman JE. Cellular mechanisms for insulin resistance in normal pregnancy and gestational diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2007;30(Suppl 2):S112&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17596458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchanan TA, Kitzmiller JL. Metabolic interactions of diabetes and pregnancy. Annu Rev Med. 1994;45:245&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8198381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeting AN, Ross GP, Hyett J, Molyneaux L, Constantino M, Harding AJ, et al. Gestational diabetes mellitus in early pregnancy: evidence for poor pregnancy outcomes despite treatment. Diabetes Care. 2016;39(1):75&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26645084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;imj&#xe1;k P, Cinkajzlov&#xe1; A, Anderlov&#xe1; K, Pa&#x159;&#xed;zek A, Mr&#xe1;z M, Kr&#x161;ek M, et al. The role of obesity and adipose tissue dysfunction in gestational diabetes mellitus. J Endocrinol. 2018;238(2):R63&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29743342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S, Jin J, Hu KL, Wu Y, Zhang D. Prevention of gestational diabetes mellitus and gestational weight gain restriction in overweight/obese pregnant women: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Nutrients. 2022. 10.3390/nu14122383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14122383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9823842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36615841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye W, Luo C, Huang J, Li C, Liu Z, Liu F. Gestational diabetes mellitus and adverse pregnancy outcomes: systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ. 2022;377:e067946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9131781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35613728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malaza N, Masete M, Adam S, Dias S, Nyawo T, Pheiffer C. A systematic review to compare adverse pregnancy outcomes in women with pregestational diabetes and gestational diabetes. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022. 10.3390/ijerph191710846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph191710846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9517767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36078559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenport MH, Ruchat SM, Poitras VJ, Jaramillo Garcia A, Gray CE, Barrowman N, Skow RJ, Meah VL, Riske L, Sobierajski F, et al. Prenatal exercise for the prevention of gestational diabetes mellitus and hypertensive disorders of pregnancy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(21):1367&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30337463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotie LM, Prince SA, Elliott CG, Ziss MC, McDonnell LA, Mullen KA, et al. The effectiveness of ehealth interventions on physical activity and measures of obesity among working-age women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev. 2018;19(10):1340&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30156044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutchesson MJ, Rollo ME, Krukowski R, Ells L, Harvey J, Morgan PJ, et al. Ehealth interventions for the prevention and treatment of overweight and obesity in adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Obes Rev. 2015;16(5):376&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25753009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez-Arango LF, Barrett HL, McIntyre HD, Callaway LK, Morrison M, Dekker Nitert M. Connections between the gut microbiome and metabolic hormones in early pregnancy in overweight and obese women. Diabetes. 2016;65(8):2214&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27217482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrocino I, Ponzo V, Gambino R, Zarovska A, Leone F, Monzeglio C, et al. Changes in the gut microbiota composition during pregnancy in patients with gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM). Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):12216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6093919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30111822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuang YS, Lu JH, Li SH, Li JH, Yuan MY, He JR, et al. Connections between the human gut microbiome and gestational diabetes mellitus. Gigascience. 2017;6(8):1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5647792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29046044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Pan LL, Lv S, Yang Q, Zhang H, Chen W, et al. Alterations of gut microbiota and blood lipidome in gestational diabetes mellitus with hyperlipidemia. Front Physiol. 2019;10:1015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6691352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31447702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Zheng J, Shi W, Du N, Xu X, Zhang Y, et al. Dysbiosis of maternal and neonatal microbiota associated with gestational diabetes mellitus. Gut. 2018;67(9):1614&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6109274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29760169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cani PD, Osto M, Geurts L, Everard A. Involvement of gut microbiota in the development of low-grade inflammation and type 2 diabetes associated with obesity. Gut Microbes. 2012;3(4):279&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3463487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22572877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amar J, Chabo C, Waget A, Klopp P, Vachoux C, Berm&#xfa;dez-Humar&#xe1;n LG, et al. Intestinal mucosal adherence and translocation of commensal bacteria at the early onset of type 2 diabetes: molecular mechanisms and probiotic treatment. EMBO Mol Med. 2011;3(9):559&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3265717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21735552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagarolli RA, Tobar N, Oliveira AG, Ara&#xfa;jo TG, Carvalho BM, Rocha GZ, et al. Probiotics modulate gut microbiota and improve insulin sensitivity in DIO mice. J Nutr Biochem. 2017;50:16&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28968517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill C, Guarner F, Reid G, Gibson GR, Merenstein DJ, Pot B, Morelli L, Canani RB, Flint HJ, Salminen S, et al. Expert consensus document. The international scientific association for probiotics and prebiotics consensus statement on the scope and appropriate use of the term probiotic. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2014;11(8):506&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24912386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saez-Lara MJ, Gomez-Llorente C, Plaza-Diaz J, Gil A. The role of probiotic lactic acid bacteria and bifidobacteria in the prevention and treatment of inflammatory bowel disease and other related diseases: a systematic review of randomized human clinical trials. Biomed Res Int. 2015;2015:505878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4352483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25793197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;ez-Lara MJ, Robles-Sanchez C, Ruiz-Ojeda FJ, Plaza-Diaz J, Gil A. Effects of probiotics and synbiotics on obesity, insulin resistance syndrome, type 2 diabetes and non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a review of human clinical trials. Int J Mol Sci. 2016. 10.3390/ijms17060928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms17060928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4926461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27304953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>