<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41906108</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1746-4269</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of ethnobiology and ethnomedicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Ethnobiol Ethnomed</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Indigenous knowledge-based production practices and utilization of stingless bee honey in humid Afromontane Forest zones of the Southwest and Semi-Arid Forest zone of Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13002-026-00893-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study investigated indigenous knowledge-based production practices and utilization of stingless bee honey (SBH) among rural communities in Ethiopia's humid Afromontane Forest zones of the Southwest (Kaffa, Sheka, Majang, Jimma) and the semi-arid Borena Zone in the South. SBH is an important medicinal, nutritional and cultural resource for these communities, yet information on local production systems, species used, harvest practices and threats are limited.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional survey was conducted among 253 respondents selected from communities identified as potential stingless bee producers and users in the humid Afromontane Forest districts of the Southwest and the semi-arid forest district of southern Ethiopia. Data were collected using a combination of structured interviews and direct field observations to collect comprehensive information on local production practices, species distribution, harvesting techniques, utilization patterns, and the major challenges associated with stingless bee honey (SBH) production.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The findings show that SBH harvesting is primarily conducted by men (93.3%), with most harvesters also engaged in agriculture and livestock production. Traditional ecological knowledge is predominantly passed down from elders (78.7%). Educational levels vary, with primary education being the most common. The majority of SBH is obtained from wild colonies (97.6%), with limited efforts toward domestication (2.4%). In Yabello, honey is collected from three species: Plebeina armata, Meliponula beccarii, and Hypotrigona species, known locally as "Dama Damu Guracha," "Dama Damu Dimma," and "Tunale," respectively, in the Oromifa language. In the Southwest region (Kaffa, Sheka, Majang, and Jimma), M. beccarii and H. trigona are identified as the primary species, each with distinct local names depending on the zone. Communities in the study area possess traditional knowledge and skills that are primarily focused on digging around colonies to create nesting spaces. However, there are significant seasonal variations in harvesting times across different zones. The peak harvesting periods in Kaffa, Sheka, Majang, and Jimma zones occur in April, while in the Borena Zone, it extends from April to June. Colonies are located by observing and tracking the movement of worker bees. Harvesting techniques differ, with the majority (74.3%) employing squeezing methods, while 21.3% use a combination of squeezing and colony destruction. SBH is mainly harvested once a year, predominantly for medicinal purposes (94.9%). There are notable differences in production volume across regions, with the highest estimated yield from Sheka Zone (4.8&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;8 kg) over the past 12 months and the lowest from Majang (1.2&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.6 kg). The honey is consumed in various ways, often before meals, for its medicinal properties, such as treating asthma, colds, and respiratory diseases. The study also highlights major threats to meliponine colonies, including predators, land-use changes, unsustainable harvesting practices, and agrochemical use, with 83% of respondents concerned about the potential endangerment of these bees. Despite the longstanding tradition of SBH production, only 1.9% of respondents have received training in meliponiculture.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Indigenous knowledge of stingless bee honey production remains a vital component of local culture and livelihoods in Ethiopia. However, the practice faces serious challenges due to limited training, lack of modern meliponiculture practices, and environmental pressures. Strengthening conservation efforts, providing technical training, and integrating traditional knowledge with modern practices are essential for sustaining stingless bee populations and promoting the sustainable production of this valuable honey.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gebreyes</LastName><ForeName>Belay Gezahegn</ForeName><Initials>BG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2042-8541</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Postharvest Management, Jimma University College of Agriculture and Veterinary Medicine, P.O Box 307, Jimma, Ethiopia. belayg735@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Centre of Insect Physiology and Ecology (ICIPE) Nairobi, Nairobi, Kenya. belayg735@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ethiopian Institute of Agricultural Research, Teppi Agricultural research center, P.O Box 34, Teppi, Ethiopia. belayg735@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abro</LastName><ForeName>Zewdu Ayalew</ForeName><Initials>ZA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4116-7945</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Centre of Insect Physiology and Ecology (ICIPE) Nairobi, Nairobi, Kenya.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kassie</LastName><ForeName>Menale</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6754-2432</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Centre of Insect Physiology and Ecology (ICIPE) Nairobi, Nairobi, Kenya.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tola</LastName><ForeName>Yetenayet Bekele</ForeName><Initials>YB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8247-4546</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Postharvest Management, Jimma University College of Agriculture and Veterinary Medicine, P.O Box 307, Jimma, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiatoko</LastName><ForeName>Nkoba</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5612-4801</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Centre of Insect Physiology and Ecology (ICIPE) Nairobi, Nairobi, Kenya.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Ethnobiol Ethnomed</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101245794</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1746-4269</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Afromontane Forest</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Indigenous knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meliponiculture practices</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stingless bee honey</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sustainable production</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Traditional ecological knowledge</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41906108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13002-026-00893-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13002-026-00893-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mekonnen Z, Kidemu M, Abebe H, Semere M, Gebreyesus M, Worku A, et al. Traditional knowledge and institutions for sustainable climate change adaptation in Ethiopia. Current Research in Environmental Sustainability. 2021;3:100080.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe9;ger M, Noiset P, Nkoba K, Vereecken NJ. Traditional ecological knowledge and non-food uses of stingless bee honey in Kenya&#x2019;s last pocket of tropical rainforest. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2023;19(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidane AA, Tegegne FM, Tack AJM. Indigenous knowledge of ground-nesting stingless bees in southwestern Ethiopia. Int J Trop Insect Sci. 2021;41(4):2617&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bak-Badowska J, Zeber-Dzikowska I, Gworek B, Kacprzyk W, Chmielewski J. The role and significance of stingless bees (Hymenoptera: Apiformes: Meliponini) in the natural environment. Ochr Srodow Zasob Nat. 2019;30(2):1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manuel V, Vel&#xe1;zquez H, Lormendez CC, Jim&#xe9;nez JT, Ram&#xed;rez YR. Review article the stingless bees (Hymenoptera: Apidae&#x202f;: Meliponini): a review of the current threats to their survival. Apidologie. 2022;53(8):1&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebreyes BG. The environmental and ecological benefits of edible insects: a review. Food Sci Nutr. 2025;13(8):2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadge AS, Shirsat DV, Soumia PS, Pote CL, Pushpalatha M, Pandit TR, et al. Physiochemical, biological, and therapeutic uses of stingless bee honey. Front Sustain Food Syst. 2024;7:1324385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebreyes BG, Teka TA, Tola YB, Tamiru M, Kiatoko N. The physicochemical properties, biochemical makeup, and health benefits of honey produced from stingless bees ( Apidae&#x202f;: Meliponini ). J Food Qual. 2025;2025:24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braghini F, Biluca FC, Schulz M, Gonzaga LV, Costa ACO, Fett R. Stingless bee honey: a precious but unregulated product - reality and expectations. Food Rev Int. 2022;38(S1):683&#x2013;712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assefa A, Lemma M. Ecological niche modeling for stingless bees (genus Melipona) in Waghemira and North Wollo zones of Amhara Regional State, Ethiopia. Sci African. 2022;15:e01102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson KM, Baudier KM. Stingless bee foragers experience more thermally stressful microclimates and have wider thermal tolerance breadths than other worker subcastes. Front Ecol Evol. 2024;12:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gyeltshen T, Bhatta CP, Gurung T, Dorji P, Tenzin J. Ethno-medicinal uses and cultural importance of stingless bees and their hive products in several ethnic communities of Bhutan. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2024;20(1):1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athayde S, Stepp JR, Ballester WC. Engaging indigenous and academic knowledge on bees in the Amazon: implications for environmental management and transdisciplinary research. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2016;12(1):1&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chemurot M, Otim AS, Namayanja D, Onen H, Angiro C, Mugume R, et al. Stingless beekeeping in Uganda: an industry in its infancy. Afr Entomol. 2021;29(1):165&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakuya J, Gandiwa E, Muboko N, Muposhi VK. A review of habitat and distribution of common stingless bees and honeybees species in African savanna ecosystems. Trop Conserv Sci. 2022;15:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farhall K, Rickards L. The &#x201c;Gender Agenda&#x201d; in agriculture for development and its (lack of) alignment with feminist scholarship. Front Sustain Food Syst. 2021;5:573424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makate C, Angelsen A, Holden ST, Westengen OT. Crops in crises: shocks shape smallholders&#x2019; diversification in rural Ethiopia. World Dev. 2022;159:106054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autio A, Johansson T, Motaroki L, Minoia P, Pellikka P. Constraints for adopting climate-smart agricultural practices among smallholder farmers in Southeast Kenya. Agric Syst. 2021;194:103284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adler M, Esc&#xf3;bar-M&#xe1;rquez L, Solis-Soto MT, Pinto CF. Stingless bees: uses and management by meliponiculturist women in the Chaco region of Bolivia. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2023;19(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavinas FC, Gomes BA, Silva MVT, Nunes RM, Leit&#xe3;o SG, Moura MRL, et al. Discriminant analysis of Brazilian stingless bee honey reveals an iron-based biogeographical origin. Foods. 2023;12(1):1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demetrio RA, Leon DC, Delgado C, Correa R, Espinoza RV. Traditional ecological knowledge on stingless bees in two Ashaninka communities in the central rainforest of Peru. Ethnobiol Conserv. 2025;14:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pimentel TC, Rosset M, de Sousa JMB, de Oliveira LIG, Mafaldo IM, Pintado MME, et al. Stingless bee honey: an overview of health benefits and main market challenges. J Food Biochem. 2022;46(3):1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayan M, Saravanan PA, Srinivasan MR. Effect of season and timings on the foraging behaviour of stingless bee, Tetragonula iridipennis Smith (Hymenoptera: Apidae). Madras Agric J. 2018;105:286&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begna D, Motuma G, Chimdi A, Boki S, Bekele N, Kuru T. Ecology and nest structures of ground-nesting stingless bees in the high and midlands of West Shewa Zone,Ethiopia. East Afri Journal of Vet and Animal Sci. 2021;5:57&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samejima H, Marzuki M, Nagamitsu T, Nakasizuka T. The effects of human disturbance on a stingless bee community in a tropical rainforest. Biol Conserv. 2004;120(4):577&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toledo-Hern&#xe1;ndez E, Pe&#xf1;a-Chora G, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Vel&#xe1;zquez VM, Lormendez CC, Toribio-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Romero-Ram&#xed;rez Y, et al. The stingless bees (Hymenoptera: Apidae: Meliponini): a review of the current threats to their survival. Apidologie. 2022;53:8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanahan M, Spivak M. Resin use by stingless bees: a review. Insects. 2021;12(8):719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aina FAZ, Sabri S, Mohammad SM, Ismail M, Chan KW, Ismail N, et al. Therapeutic properties of stingless bee honey in comparison with European bee honey honey and European bee honey. Adv Pharmacol Sci. 2018;2018:6179596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venturelli A, Tagliazucchi L, Lima C, Venuti F, Malpezzi G, Magoulas GE, et al. Current treatments to control African Trypanosomiasis and one health perspective. Microorganisms. 2022;10(7):1298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldasoro Maya EM, Rodr&#xed;guez Robles U, Mart&#xed;nez Guti&#xe9;rrez ML, Chan Mutul GA, Avilez L&#xf3;pez T, Morales H, et al. Stingless bee keeping: biocultural conservation and agroecological education. Front Sustain Food Syst. 2023;6:1081400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe9;ger M, Noiset P, Nkoba K, Vereecken NJ. Traditional ecological knowledge and non &#x2011; food uses of stingless bee honey in Kenya &#x2019; s last pocket of tropical rainforest. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2023;19(1):42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mduda CA, Hussein JM, Muruke MH. Traditional knowledge and uses of stingless bees (Hymenoptera, Apidae, Meliponini) in Tanzania. Int J Trop Insect Sci. 2023;43(3):1071&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byarugaba D. Short communication stingless bees (Hymenoptera: Apidae) of Bwindi impenetrable forest, Uganda and Abayanda indigenous knowledge. Int J Trop Insect Sci. 2004;24(1):117&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mduda CA, Hussein JM, Vit P, Newa NJ, Chemurot M, Kimoloi S, et al. Stingless bee honey in East Africa: sustainability, chemical composition and quality compliance. Food Humanit. 2025;25:100733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manickavasagam G. Impact of prolonged storage on quality assessment properties and constituents of honey: a systematic review. J Food Sci. 2024;89(2):811&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combey R, Stingless Bees. In: Carso AG, editor. Importance, Management and Utilisation : A Training Manual for Stingless Bee Keeping. Accra North, Ghana: A division of Macmillan Publishers Limited 2010. 1-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quezada-Eu&#xe1;n JJG, Nates-Parra G, Mau&#xe9;s MM, Roubik DW, Imperatriz-Fonseca VL. The economic and cultural values of stingless bees (Hymenoptera: Meliponini) among ethnic groups of tropical America. Sociobiology. 2018;65(4):534&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez VH, Oyen K, Vitale N, Ospina R. Neotropical stingless bees display a strong response in cold tolerance with changes in elevation. Conserv Physiol. 2022;10:1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchori D, Rizali A, Priawandiputra W, Sartiami D. Population growth and insecticide residues of honey bees in tropical agricultural landscapes. Diversity. 2020;12(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakuya J, Gandiwa E, Muboko N, Muposhi VK. A review of habitat and distribution of common stingless bees and honeybees species in African savanna ecosystems. Trop Conserv Sci. 2022;15:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vides-borrell E, Porter-bolland L, Ferguson BG, Gasselin P, Vaca R. Polycultures, pastures and monocultures : E ff ects of land use intensity on wild bee diversity in tropical landscapes of southeastern Mexico. Biol Conserv. 2019;236:269&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiatoko N, Raina SK, Muli E, Mueke J. Enhancement of fruit quality in Capsicum annum through pollination by Hypotrigona gribodoi in Kakamega, Western Kenya. Entomol Soc Japan. 2014;17:106&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atmowidi T, Prawasti TS, Rianti P, Prasojo FA, Pradipta NB. Stingless bees pollination increases fruit formation of strawberry (Fragaria x annanassa Duch) and melon (Cucumis melo L). Trop Life Sci Res. 2022;33(1):43&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>