<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41365949</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development of a novel solar system incorporating a heat pipe within a porous enclosure for simulating paraffin melting.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>43465</StartPage><MedlinePgn>43465</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">43465</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-27501-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In current work, a new design of a heat pipe solar collector coupled with a parabolic reflector is numerically analyzed to boost the overall efficiency. The design incorporates several advanced thermal management strategies aimed at improving both heat transfer and energy storage capabilities. The region surrounding the heat pipe inside the evacuated tube is filled with paraffin (RT31), which serves as a phase change material (PCM) and is reinforced with MWCNT nanoparticles to boost its thermal conductivity and accelerate the melting process. In the condenser section, water mixed with hybrid nanoparticles (Ag-MoS<sub>2</sub>) is employed as the working fluid to significantly enhance convective heat transfer. Moreover, porous metallic foam is embedded within the PCM zone to further improve heat diffusion and reduce melting time. The thermophysical characteristics of the mixtures are incorporated through User-Defined Functions (UDFs), whereas the radiative heat transfer within the evacuated zone is also considered. The outputs reveal that the inclusion of the parabolic reflector notably increases the temperature of the heat pipe, paraffin, and water zones by approximately 31.62%, 31.43%, and 11.82%, respectively. The liquid fraction of the PCM in structure equipped with the reflector is about 2.897 times greater than that of the conventional system, demonstrating a significant improvement in melting performance. Furthermore, as the operating time increases from 10 to 40&#xa0;min, the temperatures of the heat pipe, paraffin, and water zones rise by 23.77%, 24.97%, and 9.18%, respectively. When all enhancement techniques-including the reflector, hybrid nanoparticles, and porous foam-are combined, the system achieves remarkable temperature increases of 8.81%, 23.61%, and 27.18% for the water, PCM, and heat pipe zones, respectively, with the PCM liquid fraction reaching 3.247 times that of the base design. Overall, this integrated configuration demonstrates a significant advancement over conventional heat pipe solar systems by coupling optical concentration, nanomaterial enhancement, and porous media conduction within a single structure. The results highlight the strong potential of this design for improving solar thermal efficiency, accelerating energy storage, and promoting sustainable energy utilization.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sheikholeslami</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Babol Noshirvani University of Technology, Babol, Islamic Republic of Iran. mohsen.sheikholeslami@nit.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Renewable Energy Systems and Nanofluid Applications in Heat Transfer Laboratory, Babol Noshirvani University of Technology, Babol, Iran. mohsen.sheikholeslami@nit.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sarmadi</LastName><ForeName>M J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Babol Noshirvani University of Technology, Babol, Islamic Republic of Iran. javadsarmadi@stu.nit.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Renewable Energy Systems and Nanofluid Applications in Heat Transfer Laboratory, Babol Noshirvani University of Technology, Babol, Iran. javadsarmadi@stu.nit.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Momayez</LastName><ForeName>Ladan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Engineering and Computer Science, University of Pittsburgh at Johnstown, Pittsburgh, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ashorynejad</LastName><ForeName>H R</ForeName><Initials>HR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Industrial, Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, Buein Zahra Technical University, Buein Zahra, Qazvin, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ANSYS FLUENT simulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Evacuated tube collector</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heat pipe solar collector</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hybrid nanofluid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PCM</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parabolic reflector</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Porous foam</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">User-defined functions (UDFs)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41365949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12689830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-27501-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-27501-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wolde, I., Calder&#xf3;n-V&#xe1;squez, I., Molina, M., Pailahueque, N. &amp; Cardemil, J. M. Parametric analysis of a modular solar drying and packed bed thermal energy storage system. <i>Sol. Energy</i>. <b>300</b>, 113764. 10.1016/j.solener.2025.113764 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2025.113764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y. et al. Enhancement strategies and engineering applications of photothermal conversion for evacuated tube solar collectors coupling heat pipes. <i>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</i><b>220</b>, 115893. 10.1016/j.rser.2025.115893 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2025.115893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammed G&#xfc;r, E., G&#xfc;rgen&#xe7;, H., Co&#x15f;anay, Hakan, F. &amp; &#xd6;ztop January, Solar-assisted radiant heating system with nano-B4C enhanced PCM for nearly zero energy buildings. <i>Case Stud. Therm. Eng.</i><b>65</b>, 105544. 10.1016/j.csite.2024.105544 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karabuga, A. Exergy and economic analysis of evacuated tube heat pipe solar collector and parabolic trough solar collectors based power, cooling and hydrogen production. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i>. <b>146</b>, 150006. 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.06.196 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.06.196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younis, O. S. et al. Drying characteristics, environmental and economic analysis of a solar dryer with evacuated tube solar collector for drying nile tilapia slices. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 9822. 10.1038/s41598-025-94194-9 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-94194-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11928521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40118930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezgi Gurgenc, M., Gur, H., Cosanay, T., Gurgenc, H. F. &amp; Oztop. Effects of position of semi-circular body on melting of a novel B4C/RT44HC PCM nanocomposite in a closed space. <i>Case Stud. Therm. Eng.</i><b>65</b>, 105628. 10.1016/j.csite.2024.105628 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remlaoui, A. et al. Numerical simulation of a forced circulation solar water heating system. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 28999. 10.1038/s41598-024-80576-y (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-80576-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11584696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39578513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonkar, M. &amp; Naik, B. K. Performance assessment of sustainable evacuated tube heat pipe solar collector driven seawater desalination system. <i>Solar Compass</i>. <b>14</b>, 100112. 10.1016/j.solcom.2025.100112 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solcom.2025.100112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammed G&#xfc;r, Hakan, F., &#xd6;ztop, F. &amp; Selimefendigil. Analysis of solar underfloor heating system assisted with nano enhanced phase change material for nearly zero energy buildings approach. <i>Renew. Energy</i>. <b>218</b>, 119265. 10.1016/j.renene.2023.119265 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayanthi, N., Venkatesh, M., Kumar, S., Babu, R. R. &amp; Prabakar, S. P. Experimental evaluation of CuO and Al2O3 nanofluids for enhanced heat transfer in evacuated tube heat pipe solar collectors. <i>Results Eng.</i><b>27</b>, 106299. 10.1016/j.rineng.2025.106299 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong, J., hao Sun, Z., Wang, J. &amp; Lund, P. D. Performance studies of novel all-glass heat pipe evacuated collector tube integrating numerical simulation and experiment method. <i>Solar Energy</i>. <b>253</b>, 491&#x2013;500. 10.1016/j.solener.2023.02.028 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawar, V. R. &amp; Sobhansarbandi, S. CFD modeling of a thermal energy storage based heat pipe evacuated tube solar collector. <i>J. Energy Storage</i>. <b>30</b>10.1016/j.est.2020.101528 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farjallah, R., Chaabane, M., Mhiri, H., Bournot, P. &amp; Dhaouadi, H. Thermal performance of the U-tube solar collector using computational fluid dynamics simulation. <i>J. Solar Energy Eng. Trans. ASME</i>. <b>138</b> (6). 10.1115/1.4034517 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, L., Lu, Z., Zhang, J. &amp; Liang, R. Thermal performance analysis of the glass evacuated tube solar collector with U-tube, Building and environment. <i>Sep</i><b>45</b> (9), 1959&#x2013;1967. 10.1016/j.buildenv.2010.01.015 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.buildenv.2010.01.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim, C. S. L. &amp; Sobhansarbandi, S. CFD modeling of an evacuated U-tube solar collector integrated with a novel heat transfer fluid. <i>Sustain. Energy Technol. Assess.</i><b>52</b>10.1016/j.seta.2022.102051 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiari, S. &amp; Qiu, S. Three-dimensional simulation of high temperature latent heat thermal energy storage system assisted by finned heat pipes. <i>Energy. Conv. Manag.</i><b>105</b>, 260&#x2013;271. 10.1016/j.enconman.2015.08.004 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staliulionis, Z. et al. Thermal modelling and design of on-board DC-DC power converter using finite element method. <i>Elektronika ir. Elektrotechnika</i>. <b>20</b> (7), 38&#x2013;44. 10.5755/j01.eee.20.7.8022 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5755/j01.eee.20.7.8022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdi, J. M. &amp; Nsofor, E. C. Melting enhancement in triplex-tube latent heat energy storage system using nanoparticles-metal foam combination. <i>Appl. Energy</i>. <b>191</b>, 22&#x2013;34. 10.1016/j.apenergy.2016.11.036 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2016.11.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamada, A., Emam, M., Refaey, H. A., Moawed, M. &amp; Abdelrahman, M. A. Investigating the performance of a water-based PVT system using encapsulated PCM balls: an experimental study. <i>Energy</i>. <b>284</b>, 128574. 10.1016/j.energy.2023.128574 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi, S. H., Sohn, D. K. &amp; Ko, H. S. Experimental study on PVT&#x2013;PCM system performance using bubble-driven flow. <i>Int. Commun. Heat. Mass. Transf.</i><b>146</b>, 106919. 10.1016/j.icheatmasstransfer.2023.106919 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, C. et al. Numerical investigation and optimization of the melting performance of latent heat thermal energy storage unit strengthened by graded metal foam and mechanical rotation. <i>Renew. Energy</i>. <b>227</b>, 120537. 10.1016/j.renene.2024.120537 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2024.120537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hai, T. et al. Optimization of nano-finned enclosure-shaped latent heat thermal energy storage units using CFD, RSM, and enhanced hill climbing algorithm. <i>Sci. Rep.</i> 1512486. 10.1038/s41598-025-96599-y (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11992072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40216899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anter, A. G., Sultan, A. A., Hegazi, A. A. &amp; El Bouz, M. A. Thermal performance and energy saving using phase change materials (PCM) integrated in Building walls. <i>J. Energy Storage</i>. <b>67</b>, 107568. 10.1016/j.est.2023.107568 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, D. K. Free convection with MWCNT/water nanofluid having varying aspect ratio of MWCNT nanoparticle in thermally undulated enclosures. <i>Int. J. Mech. Sci.</i><b>178</b>, 105626, 10.1016/j.ijmecsci.2020.105626 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbas, M., Khan, N., Hashmi, M. S. &amp; Younis, J. Numerically analysis of Marangoni convective flow of hybrid nanofluid over an infinite disk with thermophoresis particle deposition. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>13</b>, 5036. 10.1038/s41598-023-32011-x (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-32011-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10050390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36977723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsaady, W., Moughton, C., Nasser, A. &amp; lacovides, H. Coupled numerical modelling and experimental analysis of domestic induction heating systems. <i>Appl. Therm. Eng.</i><b>227</b>, 120170. 10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2023.120170 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alnakeeb, M. A., Abdel Salam, M. A., Hassab, M. A. &amp; El-Maghlany, W. M. Numerical study of thermal and electrical performance of a new configuration of hybrid photovoltaic solar panel phase-change material cooling system. <i>J. Energy Storage</i>. <b>97</b>, 112945. 10.1016/j.est.2024.112945 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2024.112945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadeem, M., Siddique, I., Awrejcewicz, J. &amp; Bilal, M. Numerical analysis of a second-grade fuzzy hybrid nanofluid flow and heat transfer over a permeable stretching/shrinking sheet. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>12</b>, 1631. 10.1038/s41598-022-05393-7 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-05393-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8803883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35102223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, X. &amp; Wang, T. Investigation of radiation models in entrained-flow coal gasification simulation. <i>Int. J. Heat Mass Transf.</i><b>67</b>, 377&#x2013;392. 10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2013.08.011 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben-Mansour, R., Abuelyamen, A. &amp; Mokheimer, E. M. A. CFD analysis of radiation impact on Stirling engine performance. <i>Energy. Conv. Manag.</i><b>152</b>, 354&#x2013;365. 10.1016/j.enconman.2017.09.056 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdi, J. M. &amp; Nsofor, E. C. Solidification enhancement in a triplex-tube latent heat energy storage system using nanoparticles-metal foam combination. <i>Energy</i><b>126</b>, 501e512. 10.1016/j.energy.2017.03.060 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2017.03.060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdavi, M., Tiari, S. &amp; Pawar, V. A numerical study on the combined effect of dispersed nanoparticles and embedded heat pipes on melting and solidification of a shell and tube latent heat thermal energy storage system. <i>J. Energy Storage</i>. <b>27</b>, 101086. 10.1016/j.est.2019.101086 (2020).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>