<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41671193</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5636</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Melanoma research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Melanoma Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An atypical Spitz tumor with metastasis in an adolescent patient.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>139</StartPage><EndPage>142</EndPage><MedlinePgn>139-142</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CMR.0000000000001081</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Despite the large number of studies published in the dermatologic and anatomopathologic literature, there are still many doubts and controversies regarding the natural history and behavior of atypical Spitz tumors (ASTs) in children. We report the case of an AST that developed metastases 5 years after the first surgical excision. In 2012, a 12-year-old boy underwent surgical excision of a melanocytic lesion of the right forearm, which was histologically classified as an AST. After multidisciplinary evaluation, a wide local excision was performed, avoiding sentinel lymph node biopsy. During follow-up, metastatic disease was diagnosed in 2017, leading to a diagnosis of stage IV melanoma. Despite multimodal treatments, including therapies that were off-label at the time due to the patient's age, disease progression occurred and the patient died in 2021. The management of AST remains controversial, reflecting the clinicopathologic gray zone occupied by borderline spitzoid tumors, in which morphology alone may be inadequate to predict biological behavior.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tabanelli</LastName><ForeName>Michela</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dermatology Unit, Santa Maria delle Croci Hospital, AUSL della Romagna, Ravenna.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morelli</LastName><ForeName>Enrico</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Dermatology, Department of Medical Sciences, University of Ferrara, Ferrara.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiarion Sileni</LastName><ForeName>Vanna</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, IOV-Istituto Oncologico Veneto IRCCS, Melanoma Oncology Unit, Padua.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crisanti</LastName><ForeName>Emilia</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Pathological Anatomy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pannacci</LastName><ForeName>Nicola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Vascular and Interventional Radiology, Santa Maria delle Croci Hospital, AUSL della Romagna, Ravenna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Savoia</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dermatology Unit, Santa Maria delle Croci Hospital, AUSL della Romagna, Ravenna.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Melanoma Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9109623</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0960-8931</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atypical Reed nevus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atypical Spitz tumor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">melanocytic tumor of uncertain malignant potential, melanoma</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41671193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CMR.0000000000001081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00008390-990000000-00243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lee CY, Sholl LM, Zhang B, Merkel EA, Amin SM, Guitart J, Gerami P. Atypical spitzoid neoplasms in childhood: a molecular and outcome study. Am J Dermatopathol 2017; 39:181&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lallas A, Apalla Z, Ioannides D, Lazaridou E, Kyrgidis A, Broganelli P, et al.; International Dermoscopy Society. Update on dermoscopy of Spitz/Reed naevi and management guidelines by the International Dermoscopy Society. Br J Dermatol 2017; 177:645&#x2013;655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerroni L, Barnhill R, Elder D, Gottlieb G, Heenan P, Kutzner H, et al. Melanocytic tumors of uncertain malignant potential: results of a tutorial held at the XXIX Symposium of the International Society of Dermatopathology in Graz, October 2008. Am J Surg Pathol 2010; 34:314&#x2013;326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dika E, Fanti PA, Fiorentino M, Capizzi E, Neri I, Piraccini BM, et al. Spitzoid tumors in children and adults: a comparative clinical, pathological, and cytogenetic analysis. Melanoma Res 2015; 25:295&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludgate MW, Fullen DR, Lee J, Lowe L, Bradford C, Geiger J, et al. The atypical Spitz tumor of uncertain biologic potential: a series of 67 patients from a single institution. Cancer 2009; 115:631&#x2013;641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urso C. Time to reconsider Spitzoid neoplasms? Dermatol Pract Concept 2016; 6:43&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerami P, Cooper C, Bajaj S, Wagner A, Fullen D, Busam K, et al. Outcomes of atypical spitz tumors with chromosomal copy number aberrations and conventional melanomas in children. Am J Surg Pathol 2013; 37:1387&#x2013;1394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerami P, Scolyer RA, Xu X, Elder DE, Abraham RM, Fullen D, et al. Risk assessment for atypical spitzoid melanocytic neoplasms using FISH to identify chromosomal copy number aberrations. Am J Surg Pathol 2013; 37:676&#x2013;684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnhill RL, Argenyi ZB, From L, Glass LF, Maize JC, Mihm MC Jr, et al. Atypical Spitz nevi/tumors: lack of consensus for diagnosis, discrimination from melanoma, and prediction of outcome. Hum Pathol 1999; 30:513&#x2013;520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnhill RL. The Spitzoid lesion: rethinking Spitz tumors, atypical variants, &#x2018;Spitzoid melanoma&#x2019; and risk assessment. Mod Pathol 2006; 19(Suppl 2):S21&#x2013;S33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lallas A, Kyrgidis A, Ferrara G, Kittler H, Apalla Z, Castagnetti F, et al. Atypical Spitz tumours and sentinel lymph node biopsy: a systematic review. Lancet Oncol 2014; 15:e178&#x2013;e183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marghoob NG, Liopyris K, Jaimes N. Dermoscopy: a review of the structures that facilitate melanoma detection. J Am Osteopath Assoc 2019; 119:380&#x2013;390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massi D, De Giorgi V, Mandal&#xe0; M. The complex management of atypical Spitz tumours. Pathology (Phila) 2016; 48:132&#x2013;141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urso C, De Giorgi V, Massi D. Conceptual evolution and current approach to spitz tumors. Dermatopathology (Basel) 2022; 9:136&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Giorgi V, Venturi F, Silvestri F, Trane L, Savarese I, Scarf&#xec; F, et al. Atypical Spitz tumours: an epidemiological, clinical and dermoscopic multicentre study with 16 years of follow-up. Clin Exp Dermatol 2022; 47:1464&#x2013;1471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAfee JL, Scarborough R, Jia XS, Azzato EM, Astbury C, Ronen S, et al. Combined utility of p16 and BRAF V600E in the evaluation of spitzoid tumors: superiority to PRAME and correlation with FISH. J Cutan Pathol 2023; 50:155&#x2013;168.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>