<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41912570</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Surface water quality and heavy metal assessment in a tropical coastal zone for identifying favorable crop production seasons.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10622</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-44051-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">This study evaluates seasonal variations in surface water quality and heavy metal contamination in the southern coastal region of Bangladesh, specifically in Amtali and Kalapara. Water samples were collected during summer, monsoon, and winter to assess physicochemical parameters, Water Quality Index (WQI), Irrigation Water Quality Index (IWQI), and heavy metal concentrations (Cd, As, Cu, Pb, and Cr). The updated WQI and IWQI values indicate that seasonal changes influence water quality and irrigation suitability. Monsoon samples exhibited the best water quality with WQI values ranging from 17.88&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;6.37 in summer to 46.04&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;16.96 in winter at Amtali, and from 26.45&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;17.73 in summer to 60.51&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;31.47 in winter at Kalapara, reflecting shifts from &#x201c;good&#x201d; to &#x201c;unsuitable&#x201d; conditions. The IWQI, however, remained in the &#x201c;excellent&#x201d; to &#x201c;good&#x201d; range across all seasons, with mean values of 22.27&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;19.02 during the monsoon and 41.36&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;7.59 in winter at Kalapara, indicating suitability for irrigation. Heavy metal concentrations were highest in winter, with Cd levels rising from 1.20&#xa0;&#xb5;g/L in summer to 2.15&#xa0;&#xb5;g/L in winter, exceeding WHO limits. Arsenic ranged from 0.10 to 0.50&#xa0;&#xb5;g/L, well below the WHO threshold of 10&#xa0;&#xb5;g/L. Lead (Pb) and Chromium (Cr) also showed elevated concentrations in winter. Principal Component Analysis (PCA) highlighted that rock-water interactions, evaporation, and anthropogenic inputs were significant contributors to seasonal variations in water quality. This study concludes that the monsoon and pre/post-monsoon seasons are the most favorable for crop irrigation in the region, minimizing the risk of heavy metal accumulation and salinity. It provides critical baseline data for sustainable water management and agricultural planning in coastal Bangladesh with relevant Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41598-026-44051-0.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roy</LastName><ForeName>Tusar Kanti</ForeName><Initials>TK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0321-8534</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agricultural Chemistry, Khulna Agricultural University, Khulna, 9202, Bangladesh. tusar@kau.ac.bd.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Joy</LastName><ForeName>Md Nahid Hasan</ForeName><Initials>MNH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology and Genetic Engineering, Gopalganj Science and Technology University, Gopalganj, 8100, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahriar</LastName><ForeName>Shahad</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Mathematics, Agricultural University, Mymensingh, 2200, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hossen</LastName><ForeName>Sarowar</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Deaprtment of Agricultural Economics, Sher-e-Bangla Agricultural University, Dhaka, 1207, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sheikh</LastName><ForeName>Shahjahan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Science, Patuakhali Science and Technology University, Patuakhali, 8660, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Islam</LastName><ForeName>Md Saiful</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3598-0315</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Soil Science, Patuakhali Science and Technology University, Patuakhali, Bangladesh. msaifulpstu@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ismail</LastName><ForeName>Zulhilmi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for River and Coastal Engineering (CRCE), Universiti Teknologi Malaysia (UTM), 81310, Johor Bahru, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Water &amp; Environmental Engineering, Faculty of Civil Engineering, Universiti Teknologi Malaysia (UTM), 81310, Johor Bahru, Johor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Idris</LastName><ForeName>Abubakr M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4038-4769</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, College of Science, King Khalid University, 62529, Abha, Saudi Arabia. dramidris@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Advanced Materials Science (RCAMS), King Khalid University, 62529, Abha, Saudi Arabia. dramidris@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41912570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13040047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-44051-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-44051-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Odnorih, Z., Manko, R., Malovanyy, M. &amp; Soloviy, K. Results of surface water quality monitoring of the Western Bug River Basin in Lviv Region. <i>J. Ecol. Eng. 21, 18-26.</i>10.12911/22998993/118303 (2020).&#xa0;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12911/22998993/118303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kormoker, T. et al. Spatial distribution, multivariate statistical analysis, and health risk assessment of some parameters controlling drinking water quality at selected primary schools located in the southwestern coastal region of Bangladesh. <i>Toxin Rev</i><b>41</b>, 247-260, 10.1080/15569543.2020.1866012 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam, M. S., Ahmed, M. K., Raknuzzaman, M., Habibullah -Al- Mamun, M. &amp; Islam, M. K. Heavy metal pollution in surface water and sediment: A preliminary assessment of an urban river in a developing country. <i>Ecol. Indic. </i>8, 282-291<i>.</i>10.1016/j.ecolind.2014.08.016 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2014.08.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam, M. J. et al. Nutrient and heavy metal dynamics in the coastal waters of St. Martin&#x2019;s island in the Bay of Bengal. <i>Heliyon</i><b>9</b>, e20458. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e20458 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10556782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37810842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, M. et al. Water quality assessment of alpine glacial blue water lakes and glacial-fed rivers. <i>Geomat. Nat. Hazards Risk</i>. <b>13</b>, 2597-2617. 10.1080/19475705.2022.2126800 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19475705.2022.2126800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabir, M. H. et al. Changes of heavy metal concentrations in Shitalakhya river water of Bangladesh with seasons. <i>Indonesian J. Sci. Technology</i><b>5</b>, 95-409. DOI:10.17509/ijost.v5i3.25007 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastami, K. D. et al. Distribution and ecological risk assessment of heavy metals in surface sediments along southeast coast of the Caspian Sea. <i>Mar Pollut Bull</i><b>81, </b>262-267. 10.1016/j.marpolbul.2014.01.029 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24606766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, J. et al. Heavy metals in surface sediments of the Jialu River, China: Their relations to environmental factors. <i>J Hazard. Mater</i><b>270, </b>102-109. 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2014.01.044 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24561322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishna, A. K., Satyanarayanan, M. &amp; Govil, P. K. Assessment of heavy metal pollution in water using multivariate statistical techniques in an industrial area: A case study from Patancheru, Medak District, Andhra Pradesh, India. <i>J. Hazard. Mater. </i><b>167</b><i>, </i>366-373. 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2008.12.131 (2009).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2008.12.131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19304387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed, A. A. J., Rahman, I., Lim, L. H. &amp; Muharram, S. H. Assessment of groundwater quality parameters in Northern Region of Zanzibar Island. <i>J. Chem. Eng. Bioanal. Chem.</i><b>1</b> (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam, M. S., Idris, A. M., Islam, A. R. M. T., Ali, M. M. &amp; Rakib, M. R. J. Hydrological distribution of physicochemical parameters and heavy metals in surface water and their ecotoxicological implications in the Bay of Bengal coast of Bangladesh. <i>Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res.</i>&#xa0;28, 68585&#x2013;68599.&#xa0;10.1007/s11356-021-15353-9 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-021-15353-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34275081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakib, M. R. J. et al. A comprehensive review of heavy metal pollution in the coastal areas of Bangladesh: abundance, bioaccumulation, health implications, and challenges. <i>Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res.</i>&#xa0;29,&#xa0;67532&#x2013;67558.&#xa0;10.1007/s11356-022-22122-9 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-022-22122-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35921010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, P. et al. Water quality degradation due to heavy metal contamination: Health impacts and eco-friendly approaches for heavy metal remediation. <i>Toxics </i><b>11</b><i>,</i> 828. 10.3390/toxics11100828 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/toxics11100828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10611083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37888679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sultana, S., Sultana, N., Moniruzzaman, M., Dastagir, M. R. &amp; Hossain, M. K. Unmasking heavy metal contamination: Tracing, risk estimating and source fingerprinting from coastal sediments of the Payra River in Bangladesh. <i>Mar. Pollut. Bull.</i>&#xa0;<b>21</b>,&#xa0;117455.&#xa0;10.1016/j.marpolbul.2024.117455 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpolbul.2024.117455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39700706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandit, D. et al. A comprehensive scenario of heavy metals pollution in the rivers of Bangladesh during the last two decades. <i>Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res.</i><b>32, </b>10240&#x2013;10257. 10.1007/s11356-024-34225-6 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38995333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman, A., Jahanara, I. &amp; Jolly, Y. N. Assessment of physicochemical properties of water and their seasonal variation in an urban river in Bangladesh. <i>Water Sci. Eng.</i><b>14, </b>139-148. 10.1016/j.wse.2021.06.006 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam, M. S., Ahmed, M. K., Habibullah-Al-Mamun, M. &amp; Hoque, M. F. Preliminary assessment of heavy metal contamination in surface sediments from a river in Bangladesh. <i>Environ Earth Sci</i><b>73, </b>1837&#x2013;1848. 10.1007/s12665-014-3538-5 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahan, S., Jewel, M. A. S. &amp; Ara, J. Heavy metal concentrations in water from Bakkhali River estuary, Cox&#x2019;s Bazar, Bangladesh. <i>Arch. Agric. Environ. Sci.</i>10.26832/24566632.2024.0901022 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26832/24566632.2024.0901022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitehead, P. et al. Restoring water quality in the polluted Turag-Tongi-Balu river system, Dhaka: Modelling nutrient and total coliform intervention strategies. <i>Sci. Total Environ.</i>&#xa0;<b>631-632</b>, 223-232.&#xa0;10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.03.038 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.03.038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29525703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain, M. B. et al. Seasonal variation, contamination and ecological risk assessment of heavy metals in sediments of coastal wetlands along the Bay of Bengal. <i>Mar Pollut Bull</i><b>194, </b>115337. 10.1016/j.marpolbul.2023.115337 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37516095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vega, M., Pardo, R., Barrado, E. &amp; Deb&#xe1;n, L. Assessment of seasonal and polluting effects on the quality of river water by exploratory data analysis. <i>Water Res. </i><b>32</b>,&#xa0;3581-3592. 10.1016/S0043-1354(98)00138-9 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0043-1354(98)00138-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury, T. R. et al. Assessment of heavy metals and radionuclides in groundwater and associated human health risk appraisal in the vicinity of Rooppur nuclear power plant, Bangladesh. <i>J. Contam. Hydrol. </i><b>251</b>,&#xa0;104072. 10.1016/j.jconhyd.2022.104072 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jconhyd.2022.104072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36084350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raknuzzaman, M., Mamun, M. A., Ahmed, M., Tokumura, M. &amp; Masunaga, S. Monitoring of seasonal variation of some trace metals concentration in surface water collected from the coastal area of Bangladesh. <i>J. Biodivers. Conserv. Bioresour. Manag. </i><b>4</b>, 67-80<i>.</i>&#xa0;10.3329/jbcbm.v4i2.39851 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3329/jbcbm.v4i2.39851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timalsina, R. et al. An assessment of seasonal water quality in Phewa Lake, Nepal, by integrating geochemical indices and statistical techniques: A sustainable approach. <i>Water. </i><b>17</b>, 238. 10.3390/w17020238 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w17020238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pant, R. R. et al. Comprehensive assessment of water quality of a transboundary river in Nepal using hydro-chemical, chemometric, health risk and index-based approaches. <i>Water Air Soil Pollut.</i>&#xa0;<b>236</b>, 211.&#xa0;10.1007/s11270-025-07844-z (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11270-025-07844-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pant, R. R. et al. How sand mining is shaping the Trishuli River in the Himalayas of South Asia. <i>Earth Syst. Environ.&#xa0;</i><b>10</b>, 185&#x2013;201<i>.</i>10.1007/s41748-025-00569-3 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41748-025-00569-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanal, B. et al. Evaluation of water quality in lowland Ramsar Wetlands: Insights on hydrochemistry analysis-sustainable development goals nexus. <i>Physics Chem. Earth</i><b>141, </b>104097. 10.1016/j.pce.2025.104097 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allison, M. A. &amp; Kepple, E. Modern sediment supply to the lower delta plain of the Ganges-Brahmaputra River in Bangladesh. <i>Geo-Mar. Lett.&#xa0;</i><b>21</b>, 66&#x2013;74. 10.1007/s003670100069 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s003670100069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brammer, H. Bangladesh&#x2019;s dynamic coastal regions and sea-level rise. <i>Clim. Risk Manag. </i><b>1</b>, 51-62<i>.&#xa0;</i>10.1016/j.crm.2013.10.001 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.crm.2013.10.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury, K. R., Hossain, M. S. &amp; Khan, M. S. H. Bangladesh geosciences and resources potential. <i>Bangladesh Geosci. Resour. Potential.</i>&#xa0;632.&#xa0;10.1201/9781003080817 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1201/9781003080817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara, M. H., Uddin, M. N., Sarkar, S. C. &amp; Kumar, U. Seasonal variation of temperature dependent physico-chemical parameters of a coastal River Bhadra, Bangladesh. <i>J. Trop. Biol. Conserv. (JTBC)</i>10.51200/jtbc.v14i0.886 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.51200/jtbc.v14i0.886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mojid, M. A., Mainuddin, M., Karim, F. &amp; Wahid, S. M. Historical and projected future hydrological characteristics of the Mangrove Forest in the Ganges Delta: a review. <i>Water (Switzerland),&#xa0;</i><b>17</b>, 838. 10.3390/w17060838 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w17060838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akter, J., Sarker, M. H., Popescu, I. &amp; Roelvink, D. Evolution of the Bengal Delta and its prevailing processes. <i>J. Coast. Res.</i><b>32</b>,1212-1226.&#xa0;10.2112/JCOASTRES-D-14-00232.1 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2112/JCOASTRES-D-14-00232.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahid, S. B., Gani, M. R. &amp; Gani, N. D. 32 years of changes in river paths and coastal landscape in Bangladesh, Bengal Basin. <i>J. Sediment. Environ.&#xa0;</i><b>9</b>, 1035&#x2013;1053. 10.1007/s43217-024-00207-4 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43217-024-00207-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodbred, S. L. &amp; Kuehl, S. A. Enormous Ganges-Brahmaputra sediment discharge during strengthened early Holocene monsoon. <i>Geology</i><b>28, </b>1083-1086. 10.1130/0091-7613(2000)28&lt;1083:EGSDDS&gt;2.0.CO;2 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamsudduha, M. &amp; Uddin, A. Quaternary shoreline shifting and hydrogeologic influence on the distribution of groundwater arsenic in aquifers of the Bengal Basin. <i>J. Asian Earth Sci. </i><b>31</b>,&#xa0;177-194<i>.</i>10.1016/j.jseaes.2007.07.001 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jseaes.2007.07.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Method 3005A acid digestion of waters for total recoverable or dissolved metals for analysis by FLAA or ICP spectroscopy&#xa0;(1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal, S. et al. A coupled novel framework for assessing vulnerability of water resources using hydrochemical analysis and data-driven models. <i>J. Clean. Prod. </i><b>336</b>,&#xa0;130407. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.130407 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.130407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayers, R. S. &amp; Westcot, D. W. Water quality for agriculture&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;6. Water quality for livestock and poultry,&#xa0;1&#x2013;5 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, G., Zhang, M., Liu, C., Li, L. &amp; Chen, Z. Heavy metal(loid)s and organic contaminants in groundwater in the Pearl River Delta that has undergone three decades of urbanization and industrialization: Distributions, sources, and driving forces. <i>Sci. Total Environ.</i><b>635, </b>913-925. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.04.210 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29710613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Method Development for Unregulated Contaminants in Drinking Water Meeting Materials - June. 2018 | US EPA. https://www.epa.gov/dwanalyticalmethods/method-development-unregulated-contaminants-drinking-water-meeting-materials</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Primary Drinking Water Regulations | US EPA. https://www.epa.gov/ground-water-and-drinking-water/national-primary-drinking-water-regulations</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Methods for the Examination of Water Wastewater 24. (2023). https://secure.apha.org/imis/ItemDetail?iProductCode=978-087553-2998&amp;CATEGORY=BK</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hounslow, A. W. Water quality data: Analysis and interpretation. <i>Water Qual. Data: Anal. Interpret.</i>&#xa0;416.&#xa0;10.1201/9780203734117 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1201/9780203734117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy, T. K. et al. Presence of heavy metals in pulses and cereals ploughed adjacent to the Rampal power plant: a probabilistic health risk assessment. <i>Int J. Environ. Anal. Chem</i><b>105, </b>2857-2873. 10.1080/03067319.2024.2332484 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>APHA Standard Methods for the Examination of Water and Wastewater.<i>Standard Methods</i>.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Determination Of Trace Elements By Stabilized Temperature Graphite Furnace Atomic Absorption. In <i>Methods for the Determination of Metals in Environmental Samples</i>. (1996). 10.1016/b978-0-8155-1398-8.50012-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanlan, J., Skoog, D. A. &amp; West, D. M. Principles of instrumental analysis. <i>Stud. Conserv.</i>10.2307/1505543 (1973).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/1505543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanoranga, &amp; Khalid, S. An assessment of groundwater quality for irrigation and drinking purposes around brick kilns in three districts of Balochistan province, Pakistan, through water quality index and multivariate statistical approaches. <i>J Geochem. Explor</i><b>197</b>, 14&#x2013;26.&#xa0;10.1016/j.gexplo.2018.11.007 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gexplo.2018.11.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horton, R. K. An index number system for rating water quality. <i>J. Water Pollut. Control Fed.</i><b>37,</b> 300-306. http://www.scirp.org/ (1965).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awasthi, M. P. et al. Integrating multivariate statistical techniques and geochemical indices for water quality assessment in pond ecosystems of Kirtipur Municipality, Kathmandu, Nepal. <i>Sustain. Water Resour. Manag.</i><b>11</b>, 13.&#xa0;&#xa0;10.1007/s40899-024-01182-4 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40899-024-01182-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wampler, P., Lang, M. &amp; Romanski, A. Exploring a more elegant water quality index - do we dare? (2024). 10.1130/abs/2023nc-386523</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matta, G. et al. Determination of water quality of Ganga River System in Himalayan region, referencing indexing techniques. <i>Arab. J. Geosci.</i><b>13</b>, 1027.&#xa0;10.1007/s12517-020-05999-z (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-020-05999-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surface-and-Ground-Water-Quality-Report-2023 - Department of Environment-Government of the People\&#x2019;s Republic of Bangladesh. (2023). https://doe.gov.bd/site/publications/da1b687c-2137-4db2-a0fd-0ea32b5fadba/Surface-and-Ground-Water-Quality-Report-</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meireles, A. C. M., de Andrade, E. M., Chaves, L. C. G., Frischkorn, H. &amp; Crisostomo, L. A. A new proposal of the classification of irrigation water. <i>Rev. Cienc. Agron. </i><b>41</b>, 349-357<i>.</i>10.1590/S1806-66902010000300005 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1806-66902010000300005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abusam, A. &amp; Al-Anzi, B. Comparison between the irrigation qualities of conventional tertiary and UF&#x2009;+&#x2009;RO advanced treated wastewaters. <i>Agric. Sci. </i><b>2</b>,&#xa0;526-532. 10.4236/as.2011.24068 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/as.2011.24068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayers, R. S. &amp; Westcot, D. W. <i>Water Quality for Agriculture</i> (FAO of the UNITED NATIONS, 1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagaraju, A., Muralidhar, P. &amp; Sreedhar, Y. Hydrogeochemistry and groundwater quality assessment of Rapur Area, Andhra Pradesh, South India. <i>J. Geosci. Environ. Prot.&#xa0;</i><b>4</b>, 88-99. 10.4236/gep.2016.44012 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/gep.2016.44012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Guidelines for drinking-water quality: small water supplies - Executive summary. <i>World Health Organization</i><b>220</b> (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan, I. et al. Assessment of groundwater vulnerability for seawater intrusion using DRASTIC model in coastal area at Patuakhali District, Bangladesh. <i>Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res. </i><b>30</b>,&#xa0;109021&#x2013;109040. 10.1007/s11356-023-29988-3 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-023-29988-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37759055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallatah, O. &amp; Khattab, M. R. Study of hydrogeochemical factors affecting groundwater quality used for land reclamation: Application of multivariate statistical analysis. <i>Stoch. Environ. Res. Risk Assess. </i><b>37</b>,&#xa0;4719&#x2013;4735. 10.1007/s00477-023-02537-7 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00477-023-02537-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain, M. R. et al. Assessing coastal vulnerabilities impacting drinking water sources and sanitation: spatial, multivariate and ML approach in Satkhira, Bangladesh. <i>Environ Monit. Assess</i><b>197, </b>5. DOI:10.1007/s10661-025-14002-9 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40259012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasmin, F., Hossain, T., Shahrukh, S., Hossain, M. E. &amp; Sultana, G. N. N. Evaluation of seasonal changes in physicochemical and bacteriological parameters of Gomti River in Bangladesh. <i>Environ. Sustain. Indic.</i>&#xa0;<b>17</b>,&#xa0;100224.&#xa0;10.1016/j.indic.2023.100224 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.indic.2023.100224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabir, M. H. et al. Evaluation of spatio-temporal variations in water quality and suitability of an ecologically critical urban river employing water quality index and multivariate statistical approaches: A study on Shitalakhya River, Bangladesh. <i>Hum. Ecol. Risk Assess.</i>&#xa0;<b>27,</b>&#xa0;1388-1415.&#xa0;10.1080/10807039.2020.1848415 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10807039.2020.1848415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akter, S. &amp; Ahmed, K. R. Water chemistry and water quality of a tidal river system in relation with riverbank land use pattern and regional climate in the southwest Bengal Delta of Bangladesh. <i>Sustain. Water Resour. Manag.</i>&#xa0;<b>5</b>,&#xa0;1259&#x2013;1279.&#xa0;10.1007/s40899-019-00308-3 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40899-019-00308-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kibria, G. &amp; Haroon, A. K. Y. Climate change impacts on Wetlands of bangladesh, its biodiversity and ecology, and actions and programs to reduce risks. In <i>Wetland Science: Perspectives From South Asia,&#xa0;189&#x2013;204</i> (2017). 10.1007/978-81-322-3715-0_10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tikadar, K. K. et al. Assessing the potential ecological and human health risks of trace metal pollution in surface water, sediment, and commercially valuable fish species in the Pashur River, Bangladesh. <i>Environ Monit. Assess</i><b>196, </b>1042. 10.1007/s10661-024-13192-y (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39387976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy, T. K. et al. Assessing seasonal fluctuations in physicochemical properties and heavy metals in the Pasur River, Bangladesh. <i>Int. J. Environ. Anal. Chem. </i><b>105</b>,&#xa0; 8698-8717. 10.1080/03067319.2025.2483319 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03067319.2025.2483319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vlaming, V. L. Effects of photoperiod and temperature on gonadal activity in the cyprinid teleost, <i>Notemigonus crysoleucas</i>. <i>Biol. Bull.</i>&#xa0;<b>148</b>, 402-415.&#xa0;10.2307/1540517 (1975).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/1540517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1171702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semesi, I. S., Kangwe, J. &amp; Bj&#xf6;rk, M. Alterations in seawater pH and CO<sub>2</sub> affect calcification and photosynthesis in the tropical coralline alga, <i>Hydrolithon sp.</i> (Rhodophyta). <i>Estuar. Coast. Shelf Sci.</i>&#xa0;<b>84</b>,&#xa0;337-341.&#xa0;10.1016/j.ecss.2009.03.038 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecss.2009.03.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jewel, M. A. S. et al. Ecological and public health risk assessment of potentially toxic elements in the surface sediments of the Pasur River Estuary, Bangladesh. <i>Heliyon</i><b>10</b>,&#xa0;e29278. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e29278 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e29278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11043945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38665555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudra, A. K. &amp; Alam, A. K. M. R. Streamflow characteristics of Sangu-Matamuhuri Watershed in the southeastern part of Bangladesh. <i>Heliyon</i><b>9</b>, e14559.&#xa0; 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e14559 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e14559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10031487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36967872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meride, Y. &amp; Ayenew, B. Drinking water quality assessment and its effects on residents health in Wondo Genet Campus, Ethiopia. <i>Environ. Syst. Res.</i><b>5</b>, 1-20. 10.1186/s40068-016-0053-6 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40068-016-0053-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shammi, M., Karmakar, B., Rahman, M. M. &amp; Rahman Assessment of Salinity Hazard of Irrigation Water Quality in Monsoon Season of Batiaghata Upazila, Khulna District, Bangladesh and adaptation strategies. <i>Pollution</i><b>2</b>, 183&#x2013;197 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Guidelines for drinking-water quality: Fourth edition. World Health Organization. <i>Encycl. Earth Sci. Ser.</i> (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain, M. S. et al. Hydro-chemical characteristics and groundwater quality evaluation in south-western region of Bangladesh: A GIS-based approach and multivariate analyses. <i>Heliyon</i><b>10</b>,&#xa0;e24011. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e24011 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e24011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10806273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38268585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uddin, M. R. et al. Assessment of coastal river water quality in Bangladesh: Implications for drinking and irrigation purposes. <i>PLoS One</i><b>19, </b>e0300878. 10.1371/journal.pone.0300878(2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11025935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38635835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter, S. R. Eutrophication of aquatic ecosystems: Bistability and soil phosphorus. <i>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A.</i>&#xa0;<b>102</b>,&#xa0;10002-10005.&#xa0;10.1073/pnas.0503959102 (2005).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0503959102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1177388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15972805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, R. M., Mcclelland, N. I., Deininger, R. A. &amp; O&#x2019;connor, M. F. A Water quality index &#x2013; crashing the psychological barrier. In <i>Advances in Water Pollution Research,&#xa0;173&#x2013;182</i> (1973). 10.1016/b978-0-08-017005-3.50067-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jollife, I. T. &amp; Cadima, J. Principal component analysis: A review and recent developments. <i>Philos. Trans. R. Soc. A: Math. Phys. Eng. Sci.&#xa0;20150202</i>10.1098/rsta.2015.0202 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rsta.2015.0202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4792409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26953178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helena, B. Temporal evolution of groundwater composition in an alluvial aquifer (Pisuerga River, Spain) by principal component analysis. <i>Water Res.</i><b>34</b>,&#xa0;807-816. 10.1016/S0043-1354(99)00225-0 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0043-1354(99)00225-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, C., Men, B. H. &amp; Yin, S. Y. Analysis of groundwater chemical characteristics and spatiotemporal evolution trends of influencing factors in Southern Beijing Plain. <i>Front. Environ. Sci.</i>&#xa0;<b>10</b>,&#xa0;913542.&#xa0;10.3389/fenvs.2022.913542 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenvs.2022.913542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves, D. D. et al. Seasonal assessment and apportionment of surface water pollution using multivariate statistical methods: Sinos River, southern Brazil. <i>Environ Monit. Assess</i><b>190, </b>384. 10.1007/s10661-018-6759-3 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29884932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, K. P., Malik, A., Mohan, D. &amp; Sinha, S. Multivariate statistical techniques for the evaluation of spatial and temporal variations in water quality of Gomti River (India) - A case study. <i>Water Res.</i>&#xa0;<b>38</b>,&#xa0;3980-3992.&#xa0;10.1016/j.watres.2004.06.011 (2004).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2004.06.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15380988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbs, R. J. Mechanisms controlling world water chemistry. <i>Science (1979)</i><b>170, </b>1088-1090. doi: 10.1126/science.170.3962.1088 (1970).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17777828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hem, J. D. Study and interpretation of the chemical characteristics of natural water. <i>US Geol. Surv. Water-Supply Paper</i><b>2254. </b>10.3133/wsp2254 (1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>House, W. A. &amp; Denison, F. H. Factors influencing the measurement of equilibrium phosphate concentrations in river sediments. <i>Water Res.</i>&#xa0;<b>34</b>,&#xa0;1187-1200.&#xa0;10.1016/s0043-1354(99)00249-3 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0043-1354(99)00249-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meybeck, M. Global analysis of river systems: From Earth system controls to Anthropocene syndromes. <i>Philos. Trans. R. Soc. B: Biol. Sci.</i><b>358</b>, 1935-1955 10.1098/rstb.2003.1379 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rstb.2003.1379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1693284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14728790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter, S. R. et al. Nonpoint pollution of surface waters with phosphorus and nitrogen. <i>Ecol. Appl.</i><b>8, </b>559-568. 10.1890/1051-0761(1998)008[0559:NPOSWW]2.0.CO;2 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrestha, S. &amp; Kazama, F. Assessment of surface water quality using multivariate statistical techniques: A case study of the Fuji River Basin, Japan. <i>Environ. Model. Softw.</i>&#xa0;<b>22</b>, 464-475. 10.1016/j.envsoft.2006.02.001 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envsoft.2006.02.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, B. et al. Hydrochemical characteristics and water quality assessment of surface water and groundwater in Songnen plain, Northeast China. <i>Water Res</i><b>46, </b>2737-2748. 10.1016/j.watres.2012.02.033 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22417739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thivya, C. et al. Identification of recharge processes in groundwater in hard rock aquifers of Madurai District using stable isotopes. <i>Environ. Processes</i><b>3, </b>463&#x2013;477. 10.1007/s40710-016-0137-3 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varol, M. &amp; &#x15e;en, B. Assessment of surface water quality using multivariate statistical techniques: A case study of Behrimaz Stream, Turkey. <i>Environ Monit. Assess</i><b>159, </b>543&#x2013;553. 10.1007/s10661-008-0650-6 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19051048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain, C. K., Sharma, S. K. &amp; Singh, S. Assessment of groundwater quality and determination of hydrochemical evolution of groundwater in Shillong, Meghalaya (India). <i>SN Appl. Sci</i><b>3, </b>33. 10.1007/s42452-020-03993-4 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, A. T. et al. Hydrograph apportionment of the Chandra River draining from a semi-arid region of the Upper Indus Basin, western Himalaya. <i>Sci. Total Environ.</i><b>780, </b>146500. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.146500 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33773352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser, H. F. An index of factorial simplicity. <i>Psychometrika</i><b>39, </b>31&#x2013;36. 10.1007/BF02291575 (1974).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath Roy, B. et al. Principal component analysis incorporated water quality index modeling for Dhaka-based rivers. <i>City Environ. Interact.</i><b>23, </b>100150. 10.1016/j.cacint.2024.100150 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferog, M. <i>Impacts of Climate Change on Water Quality in Selected Coastal Areas of Bangladesh</i>. (2020). http://rulrepository.ru.ac.bd/handle/123456789/1081</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain, M. N. et al. Application of multi-indexing approach within a GIS framework to investigate the quality and contamination of ground water in Barisal sadar, Bangladesh. <i>Heliyon</i><b>11</b>,&#xa0; e42262. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2025.e42262 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2025.e42262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11808679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39931472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varol, M. &amp; &#x15e;en, B. Assessment of nutrient and heavy metal contamination in surface water and sediments of the upper Tigris River, Turkey. <i>Catena</i><b>92</b>, 1-10. 10.1016/j.catena.2011.11.011 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.catena.2011.11.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, G., Patel, N., Jindal, T., Srivastava, P. &amp; Bhowmik, A. Assessment of spatial and temporal variations in water quality by the application of multivariate statistical methods in the Kali River, Uttar Pradesh, India. <i>Environ. Monit. Assess.</i><b>192</b>, 394-406. 10.1007/s10661-020-08307-0 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10661-020-08307-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32458103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C. et al. Effects of sediment geochemical properties on heavy metal bioavailability. <i>Environ. Int.</i>&#xa0;<b>73</b>,&#xa0;270-281.&#xa0;10.1016/j.envint.2014.08.010 (2014).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envint.2014.08.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25173943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, J. <i>et al. Determining the Priority Control Source of Heavy Metals in the Surface Water of the Yangtze River Basin: Evidence from Source-Oriented Ecological Risk Assessment Determining the Priority Control Source of Heavy Metals in the Surface Water of the Yangtze River Basin: Evidence from Source-Oriented Ecological Risk Assessment</i>. (2024). https://ssrn.com/abstract=4956881</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundaray, S. K., Panda, U. C., Nayak, B. B. &amp; Bhatta, D. Multivariate statistical techniques for the evaluation of spatial and temporal variations in water quality of the Mahanadi river-estuarine system (India) - A case study. <i>Environ. Geochem. Health</i><b>8</b>, 317-330. 10.1007/s10653-005-9001-5 (2006).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10653-005-9001-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16724245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogwueleka, T. C. Use of multivariate statistical techniques for the evaluation of temporal and spatial variations in water quality of the Kaduna River, Nigeria. <i>Environ. Monit. Assess.</i>&#xa0;<b>87</b>, 137-143.10.1007/s10661-015-4354-4 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10661-015-4354-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25707603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, C. et al. Assessment of heavy metal contamination in the sediments of the Shuangtaizi Estuary using multivariate statistical techniques. <i>Soil Sediment Contam.: An Int. J.</i>&#xa0;<b>6</b>,&#xa0;45-58.&#xa0;10.1080/15320383.2017.1245710 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15320383.2017.1245710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angon, P. B. et al. Sources, effects and present perspectives of heavy metals contamination: Soil, plants and human food chain. <i>Heliyon</i><b>10</b>,&#xa0;e28357. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e28357 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e28357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10999863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38590838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Y., Yan, H. &amp; Wang, F. Distribution, source, and ecological risk of heavy metals in sewage irrigation of Taiyuan, Shanxi Province, China. <i>Toxics</i><b>12</b>, 102. 10.3390/toxics12020120 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/toxics12020120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10892418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38393215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. &amp; Liu, C. L. Riverine composition and estuarine geochemistry of particulate metals in China - Weathering features, anthropogenic impact and chemical fluxes. <i>Estuar. Coast. Shelf Sci.</i>&#xa0;<b>54</b>,&#xa0;1051-1070.&#xa0;10.1006/ecss.2001.0879 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/ecss.2001.0879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qaiser, F. U. R. et al. Characterization and health risk assessment of arsenic in natural waters of the Indus River Basin, Pakistan. <i>Sci. Total Environ.</i><b>857, </b>159408. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.159408 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36243075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smedley, P. L. &amp; Kinniburgh, D. G. A review of the source, behaviour and distribution of arsenic in natural waters. <i>Appl. Geochem.</i>&#xa0;<b>17</b>,&#xa0;517-568.&#xa0;10.1016/S0883-2927(02)00018-5 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0883-2927(02)00018-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yustika, R. D., Somura, H., Yuwono, S. B. &amp; Masunaga, T. Impact of human activities and natural processes on the seasonal variability of river water quality in two watersheds in Lampung, Indonesia. <i>Water</i>&#xa0;<b>11</b>, 2983.&#xa0;10.3390/w11112363 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w11112363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjeeta Kar. Heavy metal contamination in river systems of upper Assam, India: A review. <i>Int. J. Sci. Res. Arch.</i><b>16, </b>e0283665. 10.1371/journal.pone.0283665 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devrajani, S. K. et al. Mechanism of arsenic removal using brown seaweed derived impregnated with iron oxide biochar for batch and column studies. <i>Sci. Rep.</i>&#xa0;<b>14</b>, 18102 10.1038/s41598-024-69117-9 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-69117-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11300829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39103501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hama Aziz, K. H. et al. Heavy metal pollution in the aquatic environment: efficient and low-cost removal approaches to eliminate their toxicity: a review. <i>RSC Adv.</i><b>13</b>,&#xa0;17595-17610.&#xa0; 10.1039/d3ra00723e (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d3ra00723e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10258679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37312989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranabhat, S. et al. Hydrochemical modeling and water quality assessment of Chepe River (Nepal): Exploring the water-environment nexus. <i>Environ. Earth Sci.</i><b>84</b>, 385-401. 10.1007/s12665-025-12384-0 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-025-12384-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>