<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41885788</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Internal Load and Fatigue Characteristics in Male Cross-Country Skiers During Summer Training.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005444</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Du, C, Xu, H, Shi, J, Wei, J, Quan, H, and Zhu, T. Internal load and fatigue characteristics in male cross-country skiers during summer training. J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2026-This study aims to measure the internal load and fatigue responses of cross-country skiers during a 3-week summer training period, comparing differences across various training methods and their combinations. Twelve male cross-country skiers participated in this longitudinal observational study. We recorded the internal load for each training session via Firstbeat sport devices on the basis of the Banister training impulse (bTRIMP) model. The fatigue assessment metrics included the resting heart rate (RHR) and quick recovery test percentage (QRT%). Physiological performance was assessed by measuring maximal oxygen consumption (V&#x307;o2max). Statistical significance was considered at p &lt; 0.05. The internal load progressively decreased over the 3-week period. The bTRIMP during the competition session was significantly greater than that during the routine training session (p &lt; 0.05). Among the different training modalities and their combinations, strength-related sessions produced the lowest bTRIMP values, followed by running and competition, whereas roller skiing presented the highest values. Resting heart rate and QRT% displayed different temporal patterns. No significant differences in RHR were found after different training modalities (p &gt; 0.05). However, the postcompetition QRT% was significantly lower than the post-training value (p &lt; 0.05). Neither RHR nor QRT% significantly differed after various combined training sessions (p &gt; 0.05). A moderate negative correlation was observed between RHR and QRT% (r = -0.361, p &lt; 0.001). V&#x307;o2max did not significantly differ (p &gt; 0.05). Overall, although there was considerable variation in the internal load across different types of sessions, no significant cumulative signs of fatigue were detected.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Du</LastName><ForeName>ChongJie</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center of Exercise Capacity Assessment and Promotion, Northeast Normal University, Changchun, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Hongqi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Jipeng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Jinpeng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quan</LastName><ForeName>Helong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Tianrui</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2018YFF0300806</GrantID><Agency>Key Technologies Research and Development Program</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endurance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart rate variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">training impulse</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41885788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alexiou H, Coutts AJ. A comparison of methods used for quantifying internal training load in women soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 3: 320&#x2013;330, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardig&#xf2; LP, Saibene F, Minetti AE. The optimal locomotion on gradients: Walking, running or cycling? Eur J Appl Physiol 90: 365&#x2013;371, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banister EW, Calvert TW. Planning for future performance: Implications for long term training. Can J Appl Sport Sci 5: 170&#x2013;176, 1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigg JL, Gamble ASD, Spriet LL. Internal load of male varsity ice hockey players during training and games throughout an entire season. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 286&#x2013;295, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borresen J, Lambert MI. Changes in heart rate recovery in response to acute changes in training load. Eur J Appl Physiol 101: 503&#x2013;511, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosquet L, Merkari S, Arvisais D, Aubert AE. Is heart rate a convenient tool to monitor over-reaching? A systematic review of the literature. Br J Sports Med 42: 709&#x2013;714, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard C, Boulay MR, Simoneau JA, Lortie G, P&#xe9;russe L. Heredity and trainability of aerobic and anaerobic performances: An update. Sports Med 5: 69&#x2013;73, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Chivot A, Parouty J, et al. Monitoring endurance running performance using cardiac parasympathetic function. Eur J Appl Physiol 108: 1153&#x2013;1167, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Mendez-Villanueva A, Quod MJ, Poulos N, Bourdon P. Determinants of the variability of heart rate measures during a competitive period in young soccer players. Eur J Appl Physiol 109: 869&#x2013;878, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Racinais S, Bilsborough JC, et al. Monitoring fitness, fatigue and running performance during a pre-season training camp in elite football players. J Sci Med Sport 16: 550&#x2013;555, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M. Monitoring training status with HR measures: Do all roads lead to Rome? Front Physiol 5: 73, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Prampero PE. Factors limiting maximal performance in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol 90: 420&#x2013;429, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas A, Rotondi MA, Baker J, Jamnik VK, Macpherson AK. On-ice physical demands of world-class women's ice hockey: From training to competition. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 14: 1227&#x2013;1232, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards T, Spiteri T, Piggott B, Bonhotal J, Haff GG, Joyce C. Monitoring and managing fatigue in basketball. Sports 6: 19, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Florhaug JA, Franklin J, et al. A new approach to monitoring exercise training. J Strength Cond Res 15: 109&#x2013;115, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Monitoring training load to understand fatigue in athletes. Sports Med 44: 139&#x2013;147, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 3&#x2013;13, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Marcora SM, Coutts AJ. Internal and external training load: 15 years on. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 14: 270&#x2013;273, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin N, Tian J, Li Y, Mi J. A validation study of heart rate variability index in monitoring basketball training load. Front Physiol 13: 881927, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiviniemi AM, Hautala AJ, Kinnunen H, et al. Daily exercise prescription on the basis of HR variability among men and women. Med Sci Sports Exerc 42: 1355&#x2013;1363, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiviniemi AM, Hautala AJ, Kinnunen H, Tulppo MP. Endurance training guided individually by daily heart rate variability measurements. Eur J Appl Physiol 101: 743&#x2013;751, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin SA, Hadma&#x15f; RM. Individual adaptation in cross-country skiing based on tracking during training conditions. Sports 7: 211, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: A participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 317&#x2013;331, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Midgley AW, McNaughton LR, Wilkinson M. Is there an optimal training intensity for enhancing the maximal oxygen uptake of distance runners? Empirical research findings, current opinions, physiological rationale and practical recommendations. Sports Med 36: 117&#x2013;132, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishica C, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H, Hynynen E, Nummela A, Holmberg HC, Linnamo V. Evaluation of nocturnal vs. morning measures of heart rate indices in young athletes. PLoS One 17: e0262333, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I. Quantification of training and competition loads in endurance sports: Methods and applications. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 12: S29&#x2013;S217, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuuttila OP, Nikander A, Polomoshnov D, Laukkanen J, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Effects of HRV-guided vs. predetermined block training on performance, HRV and serum hormones. Int J Sports Med 38: 909&#x2013;920, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olshansky B, Ricci F, Fedorowski A. Importance of resting heart rate. Trends Cardiovasc Med 33: 502&#x2013;515, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parmar A, Jones TW, Hayes PR. The dose-response relationship between interval-training and VO2max in well-trained endurance runners: A systematic review. J Sports Sci 39: 1410&#x2013;1427, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plews DJ, Laursen PB, Buchheit M. Day-to-day heart-rate variability recordings in world-champion rowers: A ppreciating unique athlete characteristics. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 12: 697&#x2013;703, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plews DJ, Laursen PB, Kilding AE, Buchheit M. Evaluating training adaptation with heart-rate measures: A methodological comparison. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 8: 688&#x2013;691, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plews DJ, Laursen PB, Stanley J, Kilding AE, Buchheit M. Training adaptation and heart rate variability in elite endurance athletes: Opening the door to effective monitoring. Sports Med 43: 773&#x2013;781, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rago V, Vigh-Larsen JF, Deylami K, Muschinsky A, Mohr M. Use of rating of perceived exertion-based training load in elite ice hockey training and match-play. J Strength Cond Res 36: 2837&#x2013;2843, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reimers AK, Knapp G, Reimers CD. Effects of exercise on the resting heart rate: A systematic review and meta-analysis of interventional studies. J Clin Med 7: 503, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roos L, Taube W, Brandt M, Heyer L, Wyss T. Monitoring of daily training load and training load responses in endurance sports: What do coaches want? Schweiz Z Sportmed Sporttraumatol 61: 30&#x2013;36, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russomando L, Bono V, Mancini A, et al. The effects of short-term high-intensity interval training and moderate intensity continuous training on body fat percentage, abdominal circumference, BMI and VO2max in overweight subjects. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 5: 41, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandbakk &#xd8;, Holmberg HC. A reappraisal of success factors for Olympic cross-country skiing. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 9: 117&#x2013;121, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandbakk &#xd8;, Holmberg HC. Physiological capacity and training routines of elite cross-country skiers: Approaching the upper limits of human endurance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 12: 1003&#x2013;1011, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanley J, D'Auria S, Buchheit M. Cardiac parasympathetic activity and race performance: An elite triathlete case study. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 10: 528&#x2013;534, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanley J, Peake JM, Buchheit M. Cardiac parasympathetic reactivation following exercise: Implications for training prescription. Sports Med 43: 1259&#x2013;1277, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweet TW, Foster C, McGuigan MR, Brice G. Quantitation of resistance training using the session rating of perceived exertion method. J Strength Cond Res 18: 796&#x2013;802, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talsnes RK, Moxnes EF, Nystad T, Sandbakk &#xd8;. The return from underperformance to sustainable world-class level: A case study of a male cross-country skier. Front Physiol 13: 1089867, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xf8;nnessen E, Haugen TA, Hem E, Leirstein S, Seiler S. Maximal aerobic capacity in the winter-Olympics endurance disciplines: Olympic-medal benchmarks for the time period 1990-2013. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 10: 835&#x2013;839, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treff G, Leppich R, Winkert K, Steinacker JM, Mayer B, Sperlich B. The integration of training and off-training activities substantially alters training volume and load analysis in elite rowers. Sci Rep 11: 17218, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uusitalo AL, Uusitalo AJ, Rusko HK. Heart rate and blood pressure variability during heavy training and overtraining in the female athlete. Int J Sports Med 21: 45&#x2013;53, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto K, Miyachi M, Saitoh T, Yoshioka A, Onodera S. Effects of endurance training on resting and post-exercise cardiac autonomic control. Med Sci Sports Exerc 33: 1496&#x2013;1502, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zadro JR, Shirley D, Andrade TB, Scurrah KJ, Bauman A, Ferreira PH. The beneficial effects of physical activity: Is it down to your genes? A systematic review and meta-analysis of twin and family studies. Sports Med Open 3: 4, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zurutuza U, Castellano J, Echeazarra I, Casamichana D. Absolute and relative training load and its relation to fatigue in football. Front Psychol 8: 878, 2017.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>