<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41509136</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2251-7251</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Iranian journal of otorhinolaryngology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Iran J Otorhinolaryngol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effects of Hesperidin on the Healing Process of Cleft Lip Surgical Wounds in Rats: A Histological Evaluation and Therapeutic Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>291</StartPage><EndPage>302</EndPage><MedlinePgn>291-302</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.22038/ijorl.2025.85555.3890</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Cleft lip and palate are the most common congenital craniofacial anomalies, and inadequate treatment of these defects may lead to serious psychosocial and economic consequences. Hesperidin, a flavanone extracted from citrus fruit peels, is a potent antioxidant. However, no study has yet investigated the effects of hesperidin on surgical wound healing in cleft lips. The aim of the present study was to evaluate the histological effects of hesperidin on the healing process of surgically induced cleft lip wounds in rats.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In this&#xa0;<i>in vivo</i>&#xa0;study, sixteen male Wistar rats were randomly divided into four groups: the control group (normal saline), intervention group 1 (25 mg/kg hesperidin), intervention group 2 (50 mg/kg hesperidin), and intervention group 3 (100 mg/kg hesperidin). A surgical wound was created on the left upper lip of each rat and sutured in two layers. The treatments were administered for 21 days. On day 28 post-surgery, the rats were euthanized, and histopathological analyses were performed to evaluate epithelial proliferation, inflammatory cell density, neovascularization, fibroblast proliferation, and collagen deposition. The samples were stained with hematoxylin and eosin and Masson's trichrome stains. Statistical significance was set at&#xa0;<i>P</i>&lt; 0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The findings showed that the mean scores for fibroblast proliferation, collagen deposition, and inflammatory cell density were significantly higher in the placebo group compared to the 100 mg/kg hesperidin group (<i>P</i>= 0.006,&#xa0;<i>P</i>&#xa0;=0.009, and&#xa0;<i>P</i>&#xa0;= 0.035, respectively). Conversely, epithelial proliferation was significantly higher in the 100 mg/kg hesperidin group compared to the placebo group (<i>P</i>= 0.006). However, higher doses of hesperidin resulted in reduced collagen deposition and fibroblast proliferation, although these differences were not statistically significant (<i>P</i>&gt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">&#xa0;Administration of 100 mg/kg hesperidin decreased fibroblast proliferation, collagen deposition, and inflammatory cell density, while increasing epithelial proliferation during the healing of surgically induced cleft lip wounds in rats. These results suggest that hesperidin may modulate wound repair and contribute to reduced scar formation, which could be particularly beneficial in the aesthetic zone.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;2025 Mashhad University of Medical Sciences.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Namdar</LastName><ForeName>Parastoo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthodontics, Faculty of Dentistry, Dental Research Center, Mazandaran University of Medical Sciences, Sari, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shiva</LastName><ForeName>Atena</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Professor of Oral and Maxillofacial Pathology, Faculty of Dentistry, Dental Research Center, Mazandaran University of Medical Sciences, Sari, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barzegar</LastName><ForeName>Fatemeh</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dentist, Mazandaran University of Medical Sciences, Sari, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saeedi</LastName><ForeName>Majid</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Professor of Pharmaceutics,&#xa0; Mazandaran University of Medical Sciences , Sari, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rahimnia</LastName><ForeName>Seyyed Mobin</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, Faculty of Pharmacy, Mazandaran University of Medical Sciences, Sari, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khatami</LastName><ForeName>Maziar</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Periodontist, Researcher, Mazandaran, Sari, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arab</LastName><ForeName>Shahin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD in Clinical Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine, Mazandaran University of Medical Sciences, Sari, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>Iran J Otorhinolaryngol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101577699</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2251-7251</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cleft Lip</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hesperidin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Histopathological Techniques</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wound Healing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41509136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12777729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22038/ijorl.2025.85555.3890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bing S, Yuchuan F, Ningbei Y, Hong-Zhang H, Jianhua L, Renji C, et al. [Application of team approach and key techniques of cleft lip and palate] Hua Xi Kou Qiang Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2017 Feb;35(1):8&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7030207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28326722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavlova NI, Kurtanov KA, Diakonova AT, Mironova LS, Solovyeva NA, Borisova YP, et al. Genetic predictors for the development of congenital orofacial clefts. International Journal of Biomedicine. 2020;10(1):50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michaels JR, Husami A, Vontell AM, Brugmann SA, Stottmann RW. Genetic Analysis and Functional Assessment of a&#xa0;TGFBR2&#xa0;Variant in Micrognathia and Cleft Palate. bioRxiv [Preprint]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12148102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40489498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Meng R, Wang Z, Liu D, Huang H, Kang C, et al. Prevalence of Oral Clefts among Live Births in Gansu Province,China. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2018 Feb;15(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5858449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29473843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariano NCR, Sano MN, Curv&#xea;llo VP, de Almeida ALPF, Neppelenbroek KH, Oliveira TM, Soares S. Impact of Orofacial Dysfunction on the Quality of Life of Adult Patients with Cleft Lip and Palate. Cleft Palate Craniofac J. 2018 Sep;55(8):1138&#x2013;1144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29589979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahanbin A, Namdar P, Ghazi N, Kazemian M. Histologic Evaluation of Healing Lip Defects Namdar . J Craniofac Surg. 2019 Nov-Dec;30(8):2646&#x2013;2649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31567767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mascharak S, desJardins-Park HE, Longaker MT. Fibroblast Heterogeneity in Wound Healing: Hurdles to Clinical Translation. Trends Mol Med. 2020 Dec;26(12):1101&#x2013;1106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32800679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu L, Zou Y, Chang SJ, Qiu Y, Chen H, Gang M, Jin Y, Lin X. Effects of Botulinum Toxin on Improving Facial Surgical Scars: A Prospective, Split-Scar, Double-Blind, Randomized Controlled Trial. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2018 Mar;141(3):646&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29481395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karppinen SM, Heljasvaara R, Gullberg D, Tasanen K, Pihlajaniemi T. Toward understanding scarless skin wound healing and pathological scarring. F1000Res. 2019 Jun;8:F1000 Faculty Rev&#x2013;787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6556993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31231509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafiei S, Keshavarzi S, Noura M, Edalatmanesh MA. The effect of swimming exercise and hesperidin on hippocampal cell damage after pentylenetetrazol induced prenatal seizures in rats. J Phys Act Horm. 2020;4(3)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Kandhare AD, Mukherjee AA, Bodhankar SL. Hesperidin, a plant flavonoid accelerated the cutaneous wound healing in streptozotocin-induced diabetic rats: Role of TGF-&#xdf;/Smads and Ang-1/Tie-2 signaling pathways. EXCLI J. 2018 May;: 399&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5962903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29805347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagher Z, et al. Wound healing with alginate/chitosan hydrogel containing hesperidin in rat model. J Drug Deliv Sci Technol.2020. 55:101379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Man MQ, Yang B, Elias PM. Benefits of Hesperidin for Cutaneous Functions. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2019 Apr;:2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6466919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31061668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Q, Tang L, Zhang D. Molecular mechanisms of uterine incision healing and scar formation. Eur J Med Res. 2023 Nov;28(1):496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10631001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37941058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta P, Sheikh A, Abourehab MAS, Kesharwani P. Amelioration of Full-Thickness Wound Using Hesperidin Loaded Dendrimer-Based Hydrogel Bandages. Biosensors (Basel). 2022 Jun;12(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9313408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35884268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddadi G, Abbaszadeh A, Mosleh-Shirazi MA, Okhovat MA, Salajeghe A, Ghorbani Z. Evaluation of the effect of hesperidin on vascular endothelial growth factor gene expression in rat skin animal models following cobalt-60 gamma irradiation. J Cancer Res Ther. 2018 Dec;14(Supplement):S1098&#x2013;S1104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30539852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghartavol MM, Gholizadeh-Ghaleh Aziz S, Babaei G, Hossein Farjah G, Hassan Khadem Ansari M. The protective impact of betaine on the tissue structure and renal function in isoproterenol- induced myocardial infarction in rat. Mol Genet Genomic Med. 2019 Apr;7(4):e00579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6465653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30811871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>David EM, Pacharinsak C, Jampachaisri K, Hagan L, Marx JO. Use of Ketamine or Xylazine to Provide Balanced Anesthesia with Isoflurane in C57BL/6J Mice. J Am Assoc Lab Anim Sci. 2022 Sep;61(5):457&#x2013;467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9536832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35940848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiva A, Soltani P, Moaddabi A, Yazdian R, Saeedi M, Mozoun Z, Esfandpour A, Rengo C, Namdar P, Spagnuolo G. In-vivo assessment of application of folinic acid and botulinum toxin A in cleft lip surgical defects. Orthod Craniofac Res. 2024 Jun;:27 Suppl 1:115&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38459796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duman N, Duman R, Tosun M, Ak&#x131;c&#x131; M, G&#xf6;ksel E, G&#xf6;k&#xe7;e B, Alag&#xf6;z O. Topical folinic acid enhances wound healing in rat model. Adv Med Sci. 2018 Sep;63(2):347&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30092503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin M, Xu X. MicroRNA-182-5p Inhibits Hypertrophic Scar Formation by Inhibiting the Proliferation and Migration of Fibroblasts via SMAD4 Pathway. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol. 2023 Mar;16:565&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10008340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36919011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namdar P, Moaddabi A, Yazdian R, Saeedi M, Ahmadian F, Shiva A, Del Giudice C, Soltani P, Spagnuolo G. Histologic Evaluation of the Effects of Folinic Acid Chitosan Hydrogel and Botulinum Toxin A on Wound Repair of Cleft Lip Surgery in Rats. J Funct Biomater. 2022 Sep;13(3):142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9502383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36135577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi M, Sun P, Li D, Dong Z, Chen Z. Intralesional Injection of Botulinum Toxin Type A Compared with Intralesional Injection of Corticosteroid for the Treatment of Hypertrophic Scar and Keloid: A Systematic Review and Meta- Analysis. Med Sci Monit. 2019 Apr;25:2950&#x2013;2958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6489528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31006769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirakami E, Yamakawa S, Hayashida K. Strategies to prevent hypertrophic scar formation: a review of therapeutic interventions based on molecular evidence. Burns Trauma. 2020 Jan;8:tkz003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7175766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32341924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster R, Younesi F, Ezzo M, Hinz B. The Role of Myofibroblasts in Physiological and Pathological Tissue Repair. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol. 2023 Jan;15(1):a041231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9808581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36123034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hom DB, Bernstein JD. Reducing Risks of Facial Scarring. Facial Plast Surg Clin North Am. 2023 May;31(2):195&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37001923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud NN, Hamad K, Al Shibitini A, Juma S, Sharifi S, Gould L, Mahmoudi M. Investigating nflammatory Markers in Wound Healing: Understanding Implications and Identifying Artifacts. ACS Pharmacol Transl Sci. 2024 Jan;7(1):18&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10789122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38230290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heras-Parets A, Ginebra MP, Manero JM, Guillem-Marti J. Guiding Fibroblast Activation Using an RGD-Mutated Heparin Binding II Fragment of Fibronectin for Gingival Titanium Integration. Adv Healthc Mater. 2023 Aug;12(21):e2203307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11468578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37100430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng W, Tang Y, Zhang X, Hu X, Huang Y, Shen HM, Luo G, He W. P311 promotes type II transforming growth factor-&#x3b2; receptor mediated fibroblast activation and granulation tissue formation in wound healing. Burns Trauma. 2022 Oct;:10:tkac027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9562783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37469904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan R, Weissman JP, Grundman K, Lang L, Grybowski DJ, Galiano RD. Diabetic wound healing: The impact of diabetes on myofibroblast activity and its potential therapeutic treatments. Wound Repair Regen. 2021 Jul;29(4):573&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34157786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang P, Zhong J, Zhao X, Ali K, Wu L, Bu Z. Exploring the Potential of Hesperidin in Preventing Hypertrophic Scars: Insights from a Rabbit Ear Model. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol. 2023 Oct;16:2957&#x2013;2963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10591605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37876381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Huo H, Tang Q. Hesperidin Inhibits the p53-MDMXInteraction-Induced Apoptosis of Non-Small-Cell Lung Cancer and Enhances the Antitumor Effect of Carboplatin. J Oncol. 2022 Sep;2022:5308577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9507700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36157229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;nder G&#xd6;, G&#xf6;ktepe &#xd6;, Baran M, Bitgen N, Ayd&#x131;n F, Yay A. Therapeutic potential of hesperidin: Apoptosis induction in breast cancer cell lines. Food Chem Toxicol. 2023 Jun;176:113791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37080525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usman K, Fouadi M, Nwozor KO, Aminazadeh F, Nair P, Luo H, Sin DD, Osei ET, Hackett TL. Interleukin-1&#x3b1; inhibits transforming growth factor- &#x3b2;1 and &#x3b2;2-induced extracellular matrix production, remodeling and signaling in human lung fibroblasts: Master regulator in lung mucosal repair. Matrix Biol. 2024 Sep;132:47&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39147560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasehi Z, Kheiripour N, Taheri MA, Ardjmand A, Jozi F, Shahaboddin ME. Efficiency of Hesperidin against Liver Fibrosis Induced by Bile Duct Ligation in Rats. Biomed Res Int. 2023 Apr;:2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10113046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37082190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byun JK, Jung GS. Gemigliptin mitigates TGF-&#x3b2;-induced renal fibrosis through FGF21-mediated inhibition of the TGF-&#x3b2;/Smad3 signaling pathway. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2024 Nov;733:150425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39053104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ru Z, Hu Y, Huang S, Bai L, Zhang K, Li Y. Bioflavonoid&#xa0;Galangin&#xa0;Suppresses Hypertrophic Scar Formation by the TGF-&#x3b2;/Smad Signaling Pathway. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2021 Sep;2021:2444839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8434902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34518767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiva A, Mousavi S J. Evaluation of Dentists Knowledge about Oral Cancer in Sari-Iran in 2013. J Mazandaran Univ Med Sci. 2014;23: :164&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>