<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41243668</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1613-6829</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Small (Weinheim an der Bergstrasse, Germany)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Small</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Advanced Solid-State Polymeric Lithium Metal Batteries via Inhibiting Side Reaction of Residual Solvents.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e09582</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e09582</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/smll.202509582</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Polyvinylidene fluoride-co-hexafluoropropylene (PVDF-HFP)-based electrolytes are considered among the most promising candidates for solid-state electrolytes owing to their high safety performance and superior flexibility. Nonetheless, the interfacial side reactions between the residual N, N-dimethylformamide (DMF) and Li metal anode have significantly impeded their wide applications in solid-state Li metal batteries (SLMBs). To address such an issue, a certain amount of fluoroethylene carbonate (FEC) is directly introduced into the PVDF-HFP-based electrolyte membrane. As verified, a robust solid electrolyte interphase layer enriched with LiF/Li<sub>3</sub>N is formed because of the decomposition of FEC, thereby effectively suppressing the unwanted interactions between the leftover DMF and Li metal, and achieving precise regulation of lithium deposition behavior. The optimized electrolyte exhibits high ionic conductivity (0.97&#xa0;mS&#xa0;cm<sup>-1</sup>) and significantly enhanced Li&#x207a; transference number (0.53). The Li symmetric cell with this optimized electrolyte achieves stable cycling for over 1800&#xa0;h at 0.1&#xa0;mA&#xa0;cm<sup>-2</sup>, while the Li || LiFePO<sub>4</sub> cell retains an impressive 81.4% capacity after 1300 cycles at 2 C. Moreover, the assembled pouch cell maintai&#xa0;stability for 50 cycles at 0.2 C, indicating a good commercial application prospect. This study presents valuable insights for forming a stable and robust electrolyte/Li interface for long-lifespan and high-safety SLMBs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley&#x2010;VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Le</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Provincial Key Laboratory of Chemical Power Sources, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Yihua New Energy Co., Ltd, Changsha, 410000, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Zheting</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Provincial Key Laboratory of Chemical Power Sources, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Yihua New Energy Co., Ltd, Changsha, 410000, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Wenyao</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Yihua New Energy Co., Ltd, Changsha, 410000, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Sihan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Provincial Key Laboratory of Chemical Power Sources, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Na</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Provincial Key Laboratory of Chemical Power Sources, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Hunan Institute of Technology, Hengyang, 421002, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Huapeng</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of New Energy, Chenzhou Vocational Technical College, Chenjiang Laboratory, Chenzhou, 423000, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Huanhuan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Henan Normal University, Xinxiang, 453007, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Yougen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Provincial Key Laboratory of Chemical Power Sources, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Haiyan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4206-0215</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Provincial Key Laboratory of Chemical Power Sources, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Yihua New Energy Co., Ltd, Changsha, 410000, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2017TP1001</GrantID><Agency>Hunan Provincial Science and Technology Plan Projects of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CX20220158</GrantID><Agency>Fundamental Research Funds for Hunan Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023sfq11</GrantID><Agency>Chenzhou National Sustainable Development Agenda Innovation Demonstration Zone Provincial Special Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024ZZTS0012and2024ZZTS0717</GrantID><Agency>the Fundamental Research Funds for the Central South University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Small</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101235338</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1613-6810</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">N, N&#x2010;dimethylformamide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PVDF&#x2010;HFP&#x2010;based solid&#x2010;state electrolytes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fluoroethylene carbonate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interface modification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lithium metal anode</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41243668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202509582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>J. B. Goodenough, Acc. Chem. Res. 2013, 46, 1053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Poizot, S. Laruelle, S. Grugeon, L. Dupont, J. M. Tarascon, Nature 2000, 407, 496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhang, J. Yang, T. Dong, M. Zhang, J. Chai, S. Dong, T. Wu, X. Zhou, G. Cui, Small 2018, 14, 1800821.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. H. Xie, Y. Zhou, C. H. Ling, X. Zhu, Z. Fang, X. Fu, W. Yan, Y. Yang, Chin. Chem. Lett. 2022, 33, 1407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Guo, S. C. Wu, Y. B. He, K. Feiyu, C. Liquan, L. Hong, Y. Quan&#x2010;Hong, Escience 2022, 2, 138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Y. Liu, S. D. Pu, C. Doerrer, D. Spencer Jolly, R. A. House, D. L. R. Melvin, P. Adamson, P. S. Grant, X. Gao, P. G. Bruce, Susmat 2023, 3, 721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Sun, Y. Wang, L. Kong, S. Chen, C. Peng, J. Zheng, Yu Li, W. Feng, Escience 2024, 4, 100188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z.&#x2010;W. Dong, Y.&#x2010;F. Du, M. Geng, J.&#x2010;X. Guo, X. Shen, W&#x2010;Bo Tang, K. Chen, Li&#x2010;F Chen, X.&#x2010;S. Liu, X.&#x2010;B. Cheng, Susmat 2025, 5, 70004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Fan, B. Ding, T. Zhang, Q. Lin, V. Malgras, J. Wang, H. Dou, X. Zhang, Y. Yamauchi, Small 2019, 15, 1903952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Q. Wu, Y. T. Wang, X. W. Guo, P. Ding, Z. Lin, H. Yu, Susmat 2022, 2, 264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Zheng, C. Li, Z. Li, X. Cao, H. Luo, J. Liang, X. Zhao, J. Kong, Small 2023, 19, 2206355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Liu, G. Yang, X. Li, S. Zhang, R. Chen, X. Wang, Y. Gao, Z. Wang, L. Chen, Energy Storage Mater. 2022, 51, 443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. You, K. Duan, G. Zhang, W. Song, T. Yang, X. Song, S. Wang, J. Liu, J. Phys. Chem. C 2019, 123, 5942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Shi, J. Ma, M. Liu, S. Guo, Y. Huang, S. Wang, L. Zhang, L. Chen, Ke Yang, X. Liu, Y. Li, X. An, D. Zhang, X. Cheng, Q. Li, W. Lv, G. Zhong, Y.&#x2010;B. He, F. Kang, Nat. Nanotechnol. 2023, 18, 602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Meng, F. Lian, G. Cui, Small 2021, 17, 2005762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Wang, Z. Yao, C. Zhao, T. Verhallen, D. P. Tabor, M. Liu, F. Ooms, F. Kang, A. Aspuru&#x2010;Guzik, Y.&#x2010;S. Hu, M. Wagemaker, B. Li, Nat. Commun. 2020, 11, 4188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhu, S. He, H. Tian, Y. Hu, C. Xin, X. Xie, L. Zhang, J. Gao, S.&#x2010;M. Hao, W. Zhou, L. Zhang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2023, 33, 2301165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zhang, S. Wang, C. J. Xue, C. Xin, Y. Lin, Y. Shen, L. Li, C. W. Nan, Adv. Mater. 2019, 31, 1806082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. L. Xu, S. G. Deng, Q. Y. Guo, D. Zhou, X. Y. Yao, Small Methods 2021, 5, 2100262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Xu, Le Zhao, Z. Liu, H. Sun, D. Sun, Z. Peng, Y. Tang, W. Wang, H. Wang, Chem. Commun. 2025, 61, 7887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Hu, S. Zhang, S. Dong, W. Li, H. Li, G. Cui, L. Chen, Chem. Mater. 2017, 29, 4682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Hu, Y. Ma, Ji Qian, W. Qu, Yu Li, R. Luo, H. Wang, A. Zhou, Yi Chen, K. Shi, Li Li, F. Wu, R. Chen, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2303710.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. He, D. Bresser, S. Passerini, F. Baakes, U. Krewer, J. Lopez, C. T. Mallia, Y. Shao&#x2010;Horn, I. Cekic&#x2010;Laskovic, S. Wiemers&#x2010;Meyer, F. A. Soto, V. Ponce, J. M. Seminario, P. B. Balbuena, H. Jia, Wu Xu, Y. Xu, C. Wang, B. Horstmann, R. Amine, C.&#x2010;C. Su, J. Shi, K. Amine, M. Winter, A. Latz, R. Kostecki, Nat. Rev. Mater. 2021, 6, 1036.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Piao, R. Gao, Y. Liu, G. Zhou, H.&#x2010;M. Cheng, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2206009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. L. Chen, Y. Lin, Q. Li, H. Ren, L. Zhang, Y. Sun, S. Zhang, X. Shang, W. Zhou, M. Wu, Z. Li, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202407024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wei, H. Wang, X. Lin, T. Wang, Y. Cui, Yu Huang, J. Yang, Te&#x2010;H Liu, Y. Ren, X. Fan, H. Xu, Y. Huang, Energy Environ. Sci. 2025, 18, 786.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Chen, G. S. Zhu, K. P. Jiang, H. Xu, Y. Zhao, H. Wang, P. Pang, Y. Bai, P. Wang, H. Wu, Chem. Eng. J. 2024, 479, 147761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Sun, Su Wang, Y. Ma, D. Song, H. Zhang, X. Shi, Na Zhang, L. Zhang, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2300998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke Yang, L. Chen, J. Ma, C. Lai, Y. Huang, J. Mi, J. Biao, D. Zhang, P. Shi, H. Xia, G. Zhong, F. Kang, Y.&#x2010;B. He, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2021, 60, 24668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Liu, D. Zhang, J. Zhao, J. Shen, F. Li, Y. Yang, Z. Liu, W. He, W. Zhao, J. Liu, ACS Appl. Energy Mater. 2022, 5, 2484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zhang, T. Liu, S. Zhang, X. Huang, B. Xu, Y. Lin, B. Xu, L. Li, Ce&#x2010;W Nan, Y. Shen, J. Mater. Chem. A 2017, 139, 13779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. A. Li, S. C. Ma, Y. H. Zhao, S. Chen, T. Xiao, H. Yin, H. Song, X. Pan, L. Cong, H. Xie, Energy Environ. Mater. 2024, 7, 12648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chen, T. Liu, M. Chu, K. Yu, X. Xie, K. Lin, Y. Cheng, X. Zhang, J. Li, Z. Shi, J. Mater. Chem. A 2024, 12, 25222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Fang, M. Zhang, Z. Zhang, J. Li, H. Peng, J. Wu, H. Zhou, Z. Xu, M. Wu, Adv. Sci. 2024, 11, 2411421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Song, J. Liao, S. Huang, W. Yuan, C. Li, J. He, J. Energy Storage 2024, 75, 109591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Chen, T. Gu, J. Ma, Ke Yang, P. Shi, J. Biao, J. Mi, M. Liu, W. Lv, Y.&#x2010;B. He, Nano Energy 2022, 100, 107470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhang, Y. Zeng, Q. Li, Z. Tang, D. Sun, D. Huang, Le Zhao, Y. Tang, H. Wang, Energy Storage Mater. 2023, 54, 440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Jin, Y. Roh, T. Jo, M.&#x2010;H. Ryou, H. Lee, Y. M. Lee, Adv. Energy Mater. 2021, 11, 2003769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Li, H. Duan, S. He, J. Li, Y. Hu, Y. Li, S. Wu, H. Wu, G. Xu, G. Wang, Small 2024, 20, 2404835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. J. Yang, Y. W. Liu, X. Y. Sun, Z. He, P. He, H. Zhou, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202401428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Duan, Yu You, G. Wang, X. Ou, J. Wen, Q. Huang, P. Lyu, Y. Liang, Q. Li, J. Huang, Y.&#x2010;X. Wang, H.&#x2010;K. Liu, S. X. Dou, W.&#x2010;H. Lai, Nano&#x2010;Micro Lett. 2024, 16, 78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Lu, B. Sheng, M. Chen, M. Xu, Y. Zhang, S. Zhao, Q. Zhou, C. Li, B. Wang, J. Liu, J. Chen, Z. Lou, X. Han, Energy Storage Mater. 2024, 71, 103570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu You, H. Duan, H. Tan, Q. Huang, Q. Li, X. Wang, J. Huang, G. Xu, G. Wang, Small 2024, 20, 2310843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Zhang, Y. Liu, S. Yang, J. Zhu, Hu Hong, S. Li, Qi Xiong, Z. Huang, S. Wang, J. Liu, C. Zhi, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2401549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Chen, J. M. Zhang, B. R. Hu, Q. W. Liang, X. H. Xiong, Nat. Commun. 2023, 14, 4018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Yu, X. Ma, X. Zou, Y. Hu, M. Yang, J. Yang, S. Sun, F. Yan, Energy Environ. Sci. 2024, 17, 4519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. X. Zhang, Y. S. Ren, J. X. Liang, M. Xiao, S. Wang, S. Huang, D. Han, Y. Meng, Energy Storage Mater. 2024, 71, 103667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Han, J. Lu, Q. Zou, H. Wang, M. Chen, T. Liu, R. Liu, X. Wang, S. Zhao, M. Zhao, B. Sheng, Y. Chen, J. Chen, R. Wen, Z. Tian, Z. Peng, G. Zhong, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2504419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Yang, J. Lou, L. Hu, Qi Liu, Z. Huang, Q. Zhou, H. Zhang, W. Song, H. Huang, Y. Wang, X. Tao, Y. Xia, W. Zhang, J. Zhang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 35, 2423719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. C. Zou, C. Y. Wang, Y. B. He, H. L. Xin, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202319427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. P. Zeng, L. Zhao, J. M. Zhang, Q. Li, D. Sun, Y. Ren, Y. Tang, G. Jin, H. Wang, Small Sci. 2023, 3, 2300017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Yang, M. C. Zhang, S. Hong, J. Cao, M. Wang, B. Hong, Y. Lai, Small 2025, 21, 06662.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>