<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41362083</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1552-6844</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurorehabilitation and neural repair</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurorehabil Neural Repair</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effectiveness of Functional Electrical Stimulation Assisted Locomotor Training on walking Outcomes Following Incomplete Spinal Cord Injury: Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>144</StartPage><EndPage>156</EndPage><MedlinePgn>144-156</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/15459683251395722</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>IntroductionFunctional electrical stimulation (FES) may enhance the impact of locomotor training on walking impairments following spinal cord injury (SCI).ObjectiveThis systematic review (PROSPERO: CRD42023435210) evaluated the therapeutic effectiveness of FES-assisted locomotor training (FALT) on improving walking speed and endurance for individuals with motor incomplete SCI (iSCI).MethodsDatabases (MEDLINE, EMBASE, CINAHL) were searched for interventional studies of FALT in iSCI that assessed the therapeutic effects on walking speed and/or endurance when the FES was not active. Study characteristics and findings were extracted, summarized, and narratively synthesized. Risk of bias was assessed using the Cochrane tools for interventional studies. Random effects meta-analyses were conducted to generate standardized pooled effect sizes for both outcomes.ResultsThirteen studies were identified: 4 randomized controlled trials (RCTs) and 9 pre-post tests. RCTs scored low (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;1 study), intermediate (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;1), and high (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;2) on the RoB2, and all pre-post tests studies (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;9) scored high on the ROBINS-I. Meta-analyses of 3 RCTs found that treadmill-based FALT was associated with a small, non-significant effect on walking speed (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;76 participants; Hedge's <i>g</i>: -0.01; 95% CI: -0.46, 0.43; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.96) and a small, non-significant effect on walking endurance (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;71; Hedge's <i>g</i>: 0.20; 95% CI: -0.25, 0.65; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.39) when compared to control conditions.DiscussionThis review did not find evidence that FALT improves walking speed or endurance for people with iSCI relative to other types of locomotor training. Future trials of FALT for SCI should aim to better standardize and report training dose and stimulation parameters to improve comparability.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Unger</LastName><ForeName>Janelle</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6731-2728</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Health Sciences, Western University, London, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gray Centre for Mobility and Activity, Parkwood Institute, St. Joseph's Healthcare, London, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wiener</LastName><ForeName>Joshua C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4559-4098</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Health Sciences, Western University, London, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patel</LastName><ForeName>Prachi</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Medical Sciences Program, Schulich School of Medicine &amp; Dentistry, Western University, London, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shakir</LastName><ForeName>Usman</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Medical Sciences Program, Schulich School of Medicine &amp; Dentistry, Western University, London, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eng</LastName><ForeName>Janice J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2093-0788</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Medicine, University of British Columbia and Centre for Aging SMART, Vancouver, BC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neurorehabil Neural Repair</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100892086</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1545-9683</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013119" MajorTopicYN="Y">Spinal Cord Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004599" MajorTopicYN="Y">Electric Stimulation Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016138" MajorTopicYN="Y">Walking</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017063" MajorTopicYN="Y">Outcome Assessment, Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electric stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gait</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spinal cord injuries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">walk test</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Conflicting InterestThe authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41362083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12891249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15459683251395722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kirchberger I, Biering-S&#xf8;rensen F, Charlifue S, et al. Identification of the most common problems in functioning of individuals with spinal cord injury using the International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health. Spinal Cord. 2010;48(3):221-229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19752871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson LA, Eng JJ, Hsieh JT, Wolfe DL, Spinal Cord Injury Rehabilitation Evidence Scire Research Team. The health and life priorities of individuals with spinal cord injury: a systematic review. J Neurotrauma. 2012;29(8):1548-1555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3501530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22320160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scivoletto G, Tamburella F, Laurenza L, Torre M, Molinari M. Who is going to walk? A review of the factors influencing walking recovery after spinal cord injury. Front Hum Neurosci. 2014;8:141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3952432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24659962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fouad K, Pearson K. Restoring walking after spinal cord injury. Prog Neurobiol. 2004;73(2):107-126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15201036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrman AL, Bowden MG, Nair PM. Neuroplasticity after spinal cord injury and training: an emerging paradigm shift in rehabilitation and walking recovery. Phys Ther. 2006;86(10):1406-1425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17012645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilchak JN, Caron G, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; M-P. Exercise-induced plasticity in signaling pathways involved in motor recovery after spinal cord injury. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(9):4858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8124911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34064332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrman AL, Ardolino EM, Harkema SJ. Activity-based therapy: from basic science to clinical application for recovery after spinal cord injury. J Neurol Phys Ther. 2017;41(Suppl 3):S39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5477660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28628595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam T, Eng J, Wolfe D, Hsieh J, Whittaker M. A systematic review of the efficacy of gait rehabilitation strategies for spinal cord injury. Top Spinal Cord Inj Rehabil. 2007;13(1):32-57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3423445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22915835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donovan J, Snider B, Miller A, Kirshblum S. Walking after spinal cord injury: current clinical approaches and future directions. Curr Phys Med Rehabil Rep. 2020;8:149-158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrholz J, Kugler J, Pohl M. Locomotor training for walking after spinal cord injury. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012;11(11):CD006676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11848707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23152239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F-A, Chen S-C, Chiu J-F, et al. Body weight-supported gait training for patients with spinal cord injury: a network meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):19262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9649733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36357483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Lin F, Sun L, Chen C. Comparison of efficacy of Lokomat and wearable exoskeleton-assisted gait training in people with spinal cord injury: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Front Neurol. 2022;13:772660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9044921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35493806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morawietz C, Moffat F. Effects of locomotor training after incomplete spinal cord injury: a systematic review. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2013;94(11):2297-2308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23850614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James ND, McMahon SB, Field-Fote EC, Bradbury EJ. Neuromodulation in the restoration of function after spinal cord injury. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17(10):905-917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30264729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marquez-Chin C, Popovic MR. Functional electrical stimulation therapy for restoration of motor function after spinal cord injury and stroke: a review. Biomed Eng Online. 2020;19(1):1-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7245767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32448143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. Updating guidance for reporting systematic reviews: development of the PRISMA 2020 statement. J Clin Epidemiol. 2021;134:103-112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33577987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, Moher D, Bossuyt PM, et al. PRISMA 2020 explanation and elaboration: updated guidance and exemplars for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller SA, Forrest JL. Enhancing your practice through evidence-based decision making: PICO, learning how to ask good questions. J Evid Based Dent Pract. 2001;1(2):136-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Reeves BC, et al. ROBINS-I: a tool for assessing risk of bias in non-randomised studies of interventions. BMJ. 2016;355:i4919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5062054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27733354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher CG, Sherrington C, Herbert RD, Moseley AM, Elkins M. Reliability of the PEDro scale for rating quality of randomized controlled trials. Phys Ther. 2003;83(8):713-721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12882612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley NC, Teasell RW, Bhogal SK, Speechley MR. Stroke rehabilitation evidence-based review: methodology. Top Stroke Rehabil. 2003;10(1):1-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12970828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufanaru C, Munn Z, Stephenson M, Aromataris E. Fixed or random effects meta-analysis? Common methodological issues in systematic reviews of effectiveness. JBI Evid Implement. 2015;13(3):196-207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26355603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Li T, Deeks JJ. Choosing effect measures and computing estimates of effect. In: Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, et al., eds. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Cochrane; 2019:143-176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges LV, Olkin I. Statistical Methods for Meta-Analysis. Academic Press; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG. Quantifying heterogeneity in a meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2002;21(11):1539-1558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327(7414):557-560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Sutton AJ, Ioannidis JP, et al. Recommendations for examining and interpreting funnel plot asymmetry in meta-analyses of randomised controlled trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d4002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21784880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giangregorio L, Richards K, Kapadia N, Hitzig SL, Masani K, Popovic MR. A randomized trial of functional electrical stimulation for walking in incomplete spinal cord injury: effects on body composition. J Spinal Cord Med. 2012;35(5):351-360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3459564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23031172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapadia N, Masani K, Catharine Craven B, et al. A randomized trial of functional electrical stimulation for walking in incomplete spinal cord injury: effects on walking competency. J Spinal Cord Med. 2014;37(5):511-524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4166186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25229735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kressler J, Nash MS, Burns PA, Field-Fote EC. Metabolic responses to 4 different body weight-supported locomotor training approaches in persons with incomplete spinal cord injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2013;94(8):1436-1442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23473703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field-Fote EC, Roach KE. Influence of a locomotor training approach on walking speed and distance in people with chronic spinal cord injury: a randomized clinical trial. Phys Ther. 2011;91(1):48-60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3017322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21051593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones ML, Evans N, Tefertiller C, et al. Activity-based therapy for recovery of walking in chronic spinal cord injury: results from a secondary analysis to determine responsiveness to therapy. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2014;95(12):2247-2252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25102385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones ML, Evans N, Tefertiller C, et al. Activity-based therapy for recovery of walking in individuals with chronic spinal cord injury: results from a randomized clinical trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2014;95(12):2239-2246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25102384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postans NJ, Hasler JP, Granat MH, Maxwell DJ. Functional electric stimulation to augment partial weight-bearing supported treadmill training for patients with acute incomplete spinal cord injury: a pilot study. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2004;85(4):604-610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15083437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granat M, Ferguson A, Andrews B, Delargy M. The role of functional electrical stimulation in the rehabilitation of patients with incomplete spinal cord injury-observed benefits during gait studies. Spinal Cord. 1993;31(4):207-215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8493035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wieler M, Stein RB, Ladouceur M, et al. Multicenter evaluation of electrical stimulation systems for walking. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1999;80(5):495-500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10326910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladouceur M, Barbeau H. Functional electrical stimulation-assisted walking for persons with incomplete spinal injuries. Longitudinal changes in maximal overground walking speed. Scand J Rehabil Med. 2000;32(1):28-36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10782939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field-Fote EC. Combined use of body weight support, functional electric stimulation, and treadmill training to improve walking ability in individuals with chronic incomplete spinal cord injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2001;82(6):818-824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11387589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field-Fote EC, Tepavac D. Improved intralimb coordination in people with incomplete spinal cord injury following training with body weight support and electrical stimulation. Phys Ther. 2002;82(7):707-715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12088467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesse S, Werner C, Bardeleben A. Electromechanical gait training with functional electrical stimulation: case studies in spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord. 2004;42(6):346-352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14993895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thrasher T, Flett H, Popovic M. Gait training regimen for incomplete spinal cord injury using functional electrical stimulation. Spinal Cord. 2006;44(6):357-361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16249784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharif H, Gammage K, Chun S, Ditor D. Effects of FES-ambulation training on locomotor function and health-related quality of life in individuals with spinal cord injury. Top Spinal Cord Inj Rehabil. 2014;20(1):58-69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3919695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24574823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Street T, Singleton C. A clinically meaningful training effect in walking speed using functional electrical stimulation for motor-incomplete spinal cord injury. J Spinal Cord Med. 2018;41(3):361-366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6055946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29108487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladouceur M, Barbeau H. Functional electrical stimulation-assisted walking for persons with incomplete spinal injuries: changes in the kinematics and physiological cost of overground walking. Scand J Rehabil Med. 2000;32(2):72-79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10853721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berkelmans S, Dominici N, Afschrift M, Bruijn S, Janssen TW. Feasibility and safety of automated multi-channel FES-assisted gait training in incomplete spinal cord injury. J Rehabil Med. 2025;57:42638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12128624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40420401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguirre-G&#xfc;emez AV, P&#xe9;rez-Sanpablo AI, Quinza&#xf1;os-Fresnedo J, P&#xe9;rez-Zavala R, Barrera-Ortiz A. Walking speed is not the best outcome to evaluate the effect of robotic assisted gait training in people with motor incomplete spinal cord injury: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Spinal Cord Med. 2019;42(2):142-154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6419626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29065788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Westhuizen L, Mothabeng DJ, Nkwenika TM. The relationship between physical fitness and community participation in people with spinal cord injury. S Afr J Physiother. 2017;73(1):354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6093096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forrest GF, Hutchinson K, Lorenz DJ, et al. Are the 10 meter and 6 minute walk tests redundant in patients with spinal cord injury? PloS One. 2014;9(5):e94108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4006773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24788068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginis KAM, Hicks AL. Exercise research issues in the spinal cord injured population. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2005;33(1):49-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15640721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IntHout J, Ioannidis JP, Borm GF, Goeman JJ. Small studies are more heterogeneous than large ones: a meta-meta-analysis. J Clin Epidemiol. 2015;68(8):860-869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25959635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scivoletto G, Galli G, Torre M, Molinari M, Pazzaglia M. The overlooked outcome measure for spinal cord injury: use of assistive devices. Front Neurol. 2019;10:441542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6438886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30967836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musselman KE, Lemay JF, Walden K, Harris A, Gagnon DH, Verrier MC. The standing and walking assessment tool for individuals with spinal cord injury: a qualitative study of validity and clinical use. J Spinal Cord Med. 2019;42(sup1):108-118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6781478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31573439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arienti C, Armijo-Olivo S, Minozzi S, et al. Methodological issues in rehabilitation research: a scoping review. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;102(8):1614-1622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33989598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arienti C, Armijo-Olivo S, Ferriero G, et al. The influence of bias in randomized controlled trials on rehabilitation intervention effect estimates: what we have learned from meta-epidemiological studies. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2024;60(1):135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10938941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38088137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreopoulou G, Busselli G, Street T, et al. Is functional electrical stimulation effective in improving walking in adults with lower limb impairment due to an upper motor neuron lesion? An umbrella review. Artif Organs. 2024;48(3):210-231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37259954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Zhao L, Gao Y, Liu C, Dong X, He X. The difference between the effectiveness of body-weight-supported treadmill training combined with functional electrical stimulation and sole body-weight-supported treadmill training for improving gait parameters in stroke patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Neurol. 2022;13:1003723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9682182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36438963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>