<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41737658</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2090-908X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2026</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientifica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Scientifica (Cairo)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Productive Performance and Egg Quality Traits of Exotic Chicken Breeds Reared Under Traditional Management System in Misrak Silte District, Central Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1200900</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1200900</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1200900</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/sci5/1200900</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study assessed feeding practices, egg production performance, egg quality, and production constraints of exotic chicken breeds (Sasso and Bovans Brown) reared under traditional management systems in Misrak Silte District, Central Ethiopia. Purposive and random sampling was used to select study kebeles and 316 households. Data were collected on household characteristics, husbandry practices, egg production performance, and egg quality traits, and 160 eggs were sampled for quality evaluation. Results showed that 87.7% of respondents provided supplementary feed, mainly household food leftovers (70.8%) and grain leftovers (17.5%). Most respondents (60.76%) housed chickens only at night. The average age at first lay (days) for Sasso chickens in the midland and lowland was 170.35&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;14.54 and 149.06&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;8.21, respectively, while Bovans Brown recorded 180.69&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;12.17 and 168.22&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;8.73. Annual egg production (eggs/hen/year) was higher in the midland than the lowland for both breeds (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.05), with Sasso producing 167.9&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;8.48 and 149.6&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;6.92 eggs and Bovans Brown producing 145.2&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.04 and 136.6&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.73 eggs, respectively. Agroecology significantly affected (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.05) both external and internal egg quality traits, and higher values for most quality parameters were recorded in the midland agroecology than in the lowland. Disease, feed shortage, predator attacks, and lack of capital were the major constraints in both agroecologies. In conclusion, productive performance and egg quality traits of exotic chickens under traditional management were significantly influenced by breed and agroecology, with Sasso chickens and the midland agroecology showing superior performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Mohammed Sirmolo et al. Scientifica published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sirmolo</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Misrak Silte District Agriculture and Rural Development Office, Silte Zone, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asresie</LastName><ForeName>Aleme</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8688-8511</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Sciences, Wollo University, Dessie, Ethiopia, wu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salo</LastName><ForeName>Sefa</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-2492-5207</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Sciences, Wachemo University, Hossana, Ethiopia, wcu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tadele</LastName><ForeName>Yilkal</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8678-1308</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Sciences, Arba Minch University, Arba Minch, Ethiopia, amu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Scientifica (Cairo)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101589932</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2090-908X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">constraints</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">egg production</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">husbandry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">smallholder farmers</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41737658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12927972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/sci5/1200900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">SCI51200900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>CSA, Agricultural sample survey. Report on livestock and livestock characteristics. The Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia, Private Peasant Holdings, Statistical Bulletin. (2021) 570, 20&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kejela Y., Production Performance of Chicken Under Farmers&#x2019; Management and Their Roles at Urban Household Economy in Southern Ethiopia, Agricultural Sciences. (2020) 11, no. 02, 178&#x2013;190, 10.4236/as.2020.112011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/as.2020.112011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habtamu A., Asmamaw Y., Godadaw M. et al., Performance Evaluation and Sustainability Challenges of Tropically Adopted Exotic Chicken Breeds in Northwest Ethiopia, Cogent Food &amp; Agriculture. (2023) 9, no. 1, 2202221, 10.1080/23311932.2023.2202221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23311932.2023.2202221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desalew T., Harpal S., Ashenafi M., Wondimeneh E., and Tadelle D., Study on Productive Performances and Egg Quality Traits of Exotic Chickens Under Village Production System in East Shewa, Ethiopia, African Journal of Agricultural Research. (2013) 8, no. 13, 1123&#x2013;1128, 10.5897/AJAR2013.6987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/AJAR2013.6987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yizengaw M., Ewonetu K., and Ashenafi G., Review of Chicken Productive and reproRuctive perfoPmance and its challCnges in Ethiopia, Life. (2022) 15, no. 1, 118&#x2013;125, 10.1080/26895293.2021.2024894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/26895293.2021.2024894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SzboA, Siltie Zone Bureau of Agriculture, Socio-Economic Profile Description of Siltie Zone, Ethiopia, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamane Y., Statistics: An Introductory Analysis, 1967, Harper and Row, New York.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeidler G., Shell Egg Quality and Preservation in Commercial Chicken Meat and Egg Production, 2002, Kluwer Academic, Dordrecht, 1199&#x2013;1217, 10.1007/978-1-4615-0811-3_60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-4615-0811-3_60</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Den Bran D., Parmentier H., and Kemp B., Effects of Housing System (Outdoor Vs Cages) and Age of Laying Hens on Egg Characteristics, British Poultry Science. (2004) 45, no. 6, 745&#x2013;752, 10.1080/00071660400014283, 2-s2.0-12244253354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00071660400014283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15697013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stadelman W. J. C., Egg Science and Technology, 1986, AVI Publishing Company, Westport, CT, USA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter T. C., The Hen&#x2019;s Egg: A Rapid Method for Routine Estimation of Flock Mean Shell Thickness, British Poultry Science. (1975) 16, no. 2, 131&#x2013;143, 10.1080/00071667508416171, 2-s2.0-84972997123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00071667508416171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haugh R., The Haugh Unit of Measuring Egg Quality.Us Egg Poult, Magazine. (1937) 43, 552&#x2013;555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spss, Statistical Package for Social Sciences for Windows: User&#x2019;s Guide, Statistics Version 21, 2017, SPSS Inc, Cary, NC, USA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adem A. and Teshome G., Indigenous Chicken Production System and Their Productive Performance in Yeki Woreda,South Western Ethiopia, Agriculture and Biology Journal of North America. (2016) 7, no. 5, 266&#x2013;274, 10.5251/abjna.2016.7.5.266.274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5251/abjna.2016.7.5.266.274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Tsadik E. T., 
Tamir B., and 
Sahile Z., Husbandry practices of village poultry technology package and the nutritional quality of majorly used poultry feeds in the Central Oromia Region, Ethiopia, 2015, 27, Livestock Research for Rural Development, http://www.lrrd.org/lrrd27/4/tsad27074.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesfin F., Asresie A., and Tadele Y., Husbandry Practices, Productive Performances, and egg Quality Traits of SassoT44 and Koekoek Chicken Breeds in Urban and Rural Production Systems of Jama District, South Wollo Zone, Ethiopia, Veterinary Medicine International. (2025) 2025, 10.1155/vmi/30253552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/vmi/30253552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11986885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40224250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kibreab Y., Dakamo F., and Desseye T., Survey on Chicken Production Performance and Marketing Systems in Kaffa and Benchmaji Zone, Southwest Ethiopia, European Journal of Biological Sciences. (2016) 8, no. 1, 21&#x2013;25, 10.5829/idosi.ejbs.2016.8.01.10231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5829/idosi.ejbs.2016.8.01.10231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse H. F., Banu M. G., Awalom T., Tadelle H., and Mawcha G. T., Assessment of Chicken Feed, Feeding Management and Chicken Productivity in Intensive Poultry Farms at Selected Farms of Three Zones in Tigray Region, Journal of Veterinary Science and Technolgy. (2017) 8, no. 5, 10.4172/2157-7579.1000472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2157-7579.1000472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salo S., Tadesse G., and Hilemeskel D., Village Chicken Production System and Constraints in Lemo District, Hadiya Zone, Ethiopia, Poult Fish Wild Sci. (2016) 4, no. 2, 10.4172/2375-446X.1000158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2375-446X.1000158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Mengesha M., 
Tamir B., and 
Dessie T., Village Chicken Constraints and Traditional Management Practices in Jamma District, South Wollo, Ethiopia, Livestock Research for Rural Development. (2011) 23, no. 2, https://www.lrrd.org/lrrd23/2/meng23037.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eyerus A. T., Yilkal M. T., and Tekle O., Assessment of Husbandry Practices, Egg Production Performance and Egg Quality Traits of Chickens in the Baka Dawula District, Southern Ethiopia, Anbar Journal of Agricultural Sciences. (2024) 22, no. 1, 283&#x2013;300, 10.32649/ajas.2024.148584.1204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32649/ajas.2024.148584.1204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadessa E., Tulu D., Bogale A. et al., Characterization of Smallholder Poultry Production Systems in Mezhenger, Sheka and Benchi-Maji Zones of South Western Ethiopia, Academic Research Journal of Agricultural Science and Research. (2017) 5, no. 1, 10&#x2013;19, 10.14662/ARJASR2016.041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14662/ARJASR2016.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musa S. A., Kebede K., and Yusuf Y., Identification of Farmers&#x2019; Breeding Objective and Traits Preferences of Local Chicken in Doba and Mesala Districts, West Hararghe Zone, Ethiopia, International Journal of Veterinary Sciences Research. (2024) 10, no. 3, 034&#x2013;045, 10.17352/ijvsr.000148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17352/ijvsr.000148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekete M. S., Assessment of Chicken Husbandry Practices in Selected Districts of Gamo Zone, Southern Nation Nationality and Peoples Region, Ethiopia, International Journal of Science and Research Archive. (2023) 08, no. 02, 429&#x2013;444, 10.30574/ijsra.2023.8.2.0117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30574/ijsra.2023.8.2.0117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yonas K., Production Performance of Chicken Under Farmers&#x2019; Management and Their Roles at Urban Respondent Economy in Southern Ethiopia, 2020, Scientific Research Publishing Inc, 178&#x2013;190, 10.4236/as.2020.112011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/as.2020.112011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serkalem A., Aberra M., and Sandip B., Egg Production and Egg Quality Traits of Exotic Breeds (Bovans Brown, Koekoeck and Sasso) and Local Chickens Reared in Two agro-ecologies Under Traditional Management System, Research Journal of Food and Nutrition. (2019) 3, no. 1, 11&#x2013;17, 10.22259/2637-5583.0301003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22259/2637-5583.0301003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birtukan M., Fisseha M., Asaminew T., and Firew T., Productivity, Economic Performances and Survivability of Exotic Chicken Breeds Under small-scale Chicken Production System in South Gondar Zone, Ethiopia, Journal of Agricultural and Environtal Sciences. (2023) 8, no. 2, 10.20372/jaes.v8i2.9090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20372/jaes.v8i2.9090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aberra M., Yoseph M., Kefyalew B., and Banerjee S., Effect of Feeding Graded Levels of Moringa stenopetala Leaf Meal on Growth Performance, Carcass Traits and Some Serum Biochemical Parameters of Koekoek Chickens, Livestock Science. (2013) 157, 498&#x2013;505, 10.1016/j.livsci.2013.08.012, 2-s2.0-84886721009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.livsci.2013.08.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berhanu B., Aberra M., Wondmeneh E., and Tadelle D., Production Performance and Egg Quality Evaluation of Indigenous Chickens Across Different agro-ecologies of Southern Ethiopia, Veterinary Integrative Sciences. (2022) 20, no. 1, 133&#x2013;145, 10.12982/VIS.2022.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12982/VIS.2022.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Aberra M., 
Maak S., and 
Lengerken G., Effect of long-term Heat Stress on Egg Quality Traits of Ethiopian Naked Neck Chickens and their F1 Crosses with Lohmann White and New Hampshire Chicken Breeds, Livestock Research for Rural Development. (2010) 22, https://www.lrrd.org/lrrd22/4/aber22071.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaman M. A., Ahimed A., and Sutradhar B. C., Study on Egg Quality of Breed and Three Cros Breds at Various Age Under Semi Scavenging Management System, Pakistan Journal of Biology Science. (2005) 8, 211&#x2013;214, 10.3923/pjbs.2005.211.214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3923/pjbs.2005.211.214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raziq F., Hussain J., Ahmad S. et al., Effect of Body Weight at Photostimulation on Productive Performance and Welfare Aspects of Commercial Layers, Anim Biosci. (2024) 37, no. 3, 500&#x2013;508, 10.5713/ab.22.0365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5713/ab.22.0365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10915190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36915928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesfn F., Aleme A., and Yilkal T., Husbandry Practices, Productive Performances, and Egg Quality Traits of SassoT44 and Koekoek Chicken Breeds in Urban and Rural, 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11986885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40224250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Production Systems of Jama District South Wollo Zone, Ethiopia. Veterinary Medicine, International, 2025, 10.1155/vmi/3025355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/vmi/3025355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11986885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40224250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>