<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41727328</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2008-2835</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Oct-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Avicenna journal of medical biotechnology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Avicenna J Med Biotechnol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nanosilver from Mangosteen Peel Extract (<i>Garcinia mangostana L.</i>) for Antibacterial Dental Preventive Agents.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>277</StartPage><EndPage>285</EndPage><MedlinePgn>277-285</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.18502/ajmb.v17i4.20073</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Teeth are vital structures prone to issues such as caries and plaque formation, often caused by <i>Streptococcus mutans (</i>S. <i>mutans)</i>. This issue can be mitigated using natural ingredients like mangosteen fruit (<i>Garcinia mangostana</i> <i>L</i>.), especially its peel, is known for its medicinal benefits. However, its extract may take time to show effects, so it is being combined with nanosilver for improved drug distribution. To observe the antibacterial and antibiofilm potential of Mangosteen Peel Extract (MPE) in nanosilver form as a preventive agent in dentistry.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The extraction was succeeded by a phytochemical assay and biosynthesis of MPE into Mangosteen Peel Extract Nanosilver (MPNs). Particle Size Analysis (PSA) and Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM) were used to study this procedure. Disc diffusion tests were used to evaluate the antibacterial properties, and the Minimum Inhibition Concentration (MIC) and Minimum Bactericidal Concentration (MBC) were also determined. Furthermore, the antibiofilm activity against S. <i>mutans</i> was investigated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">the phytochemical contents in MPE were flavonoids, tannins, saponins, phenols, alkaloids, triterpenoids, and terpenoids. Particle size of MPNs was 126.1 <i>nm</i> and the Polydispersity Index (PDI) was 0.419. The highest antibacterial concentration as inhibition zone against <i>S. mutans</i> was 16.37&#xb1;0.38 <i>mm</i> and 119.37&#xb1;2.16% inhibitory activity, at the highest concentration (100%) p&lt;0.05. The percentage of biofilm inhibition against <i>S. mutans</i> was 27.64-105.94% which was concentration dependent.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">MPNs has potential as an antibacterial and antibiofilm agent that can be used as a preventive agent in medicine.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Avicenna Journal of Medical Biotechnology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sugiaman</LastName><ForeName>Vinna Kurniawati</ForeName><Initials>VK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Dentistry, Maranatha Christian University, Bandung 40164, West Java, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saputri</LastName><ForeName>Rosalina Intan</ForeName><Initials>RI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Dentistry, Maranatha Christian University, Bandung 40164, West Java, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeffrey</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Dentistry, Universitas Jenderal Achmad Yani, Cimahi 40531, West Java, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Widowati</LastName><ForeName>Wahyu</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Maranatha Christian University, Bandung 40164, West Java, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elisabeth</LastName><ForeName>Mariska</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Maranatha Christian University, Bandung 40164, West Java, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomolecular and Biomedical Research Center, Aretha Medika Utama, Bandung 40163, West Java, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayuni</LastName><ForeName>Vini</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomolecular and Biomedical Research Center, Aretha Medika Utama, Bandung 40163, West Java, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hadiprasetyo</LastName><ForeName>Dhanar Septyawan</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomolecular and Biomedical Research Center, Aretha Medika Utama, Bandung 40163, West Java, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Pharmacy, Universitas Jenderal Achmad Yani, Cimahi 40531, West Java, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>Avicenna J Med Biotechnol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101511065</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2008-2835</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-bacterial agents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Garcinia mangostana</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nanoparticle drug delivery system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Phytochemicals</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Streptococcus mutans</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest. The authors alone are responsible for the accuracy and integrity of the paper content.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41727328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12919320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18502/ajmb.v17i4.20073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">AJMB-17-277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tj&#xe4;derhane L, Paju S. Dentin-Pulp and Periodontal Anatomy and Physiology. In: Essential Endodontology: Prevention and Treatment of Apical Periodontitis. 2019. p. 11&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiradona I, Setyowati FI, Sadimin S, Utami WJD, Yodong Y. The effectiveness of counselling using animated video on the behaviour regarding dental caries among elementary school students. J Kesehatan Gigi 2022;9(1):47&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitts NB, Zero DT, Marsh PD, Ekstrand K, Weintraub JA, Ramos-Gomez F. Dental caries. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2017;3(17030):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28540937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AA. Biological features of dental caries. JSM Dent 2016;4(3):1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Setyarini W, Widjiastuti I, Ridwan RD, Kuntaman K. The distribution of Streptococcus mutans and Streptococcus sobrinus in children with dental caries severity level. Majalah Kedokteran Gigi 2020;53(1):36&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Choi YS, Lee HG. Synergistic antimicrobial properties of nanoencapsulated clove oil. Food Sci Biotechnol 2020;29(11):1597&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7561649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33088608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivakumar A, Ravi V, Prasad AS, Sivakumar JS. Herbendodontics&#x2013;Phytotherapy in endodontics: A review. Biomed Pharmacol J 2018;11(2):1073&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazir M, Al-Ansari A, Al-Khalifa K, Alhareky M, Gaffar B, Almas K. Global prevalence of periodontal disease and lack of its surveillance. Sci World J 2020;2020: 2146160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7275199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32549797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes R, Broering MF, De Faveri R, Goldoni FC, Mariano LNB, Mafessoli PCM, et al. Effect of the methanolic extract from the leaves of Garcinia humilis Vahl (Clusiaceae) on acute inflammation. Inflammopharmacology 2021;29:423&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31552547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andani R, Fajrina A, Asra R, Eriadi A. Antibacterial activity test of mangosteen plants (Garcinia mangostana L.): A review. Asian J Pharm Res Dev 2021;9(1):164&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azam B, Javanzad S, Saleh T, Hashemi M, Aghasadeghi MR. Nanoparticles: Potent vectors for vaccine delivery targeting cancer and infectious diseases. Hum Vaccines Immunother 2014;10(2):321&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4185908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24128651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan KF, K&#xf3;cz&#xe1;n Z, Horv&#xe1;th PG, Bak M, Horv&#xe1;th A, Bej&#xf3; L, et al. Green synthesis of nanosilver using Fomes fomentarius mushroom extract over aramid fabrics with improved coloration effects. Text Res J 2022;92(19&#x2013;20):3567&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravanakumar K, Chelliah R, Shanmugam S, Varukattu NB, Oh DH, Kathiresan K, et al. Green synthesis and characterization of biologically active nanosilver from seed extract of Gardenia jasminoides Ellis. J Photochem Photobiol B Biol 2018;185:126&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29886331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin IX, Zhang J, Zhao IS, Mei ML, Li Q, Chu CH. The Antibacterial Mechanism of Silver Nanoparticles and Its Application in Dentistry. Int J Nanomedicine 2020;15: 2555&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7174845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32368040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porenczukl A, Grzeczkowicz A, Maciejewska I, Go&#x142;a&#x15b; M, Piskorska K, Kolenda A, et al. An initial evaluation of cytotoxicity, genotoxicity and antibacterial effectiveness of a disinfection liquid containing silver nanoparticles alone and combined with a glass-ionomer cement and dentin bonding systems. Adv Clin Exp Med 2019;28(1):75&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30010256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De-Deus G, Brand&#xe3;o MC, Fidel RAS, Fidel SR. The sealing ability of GuttaFlow&#x2122; in oval-shaped canals: An ex vivo study using a polymicrobial leakage model. Int Endod J 2017;40:794&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17714465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil P, Rathore VP, Hotkar C, Savgave SS, Raghavendra K, Ingale P. A comparison of apical sealing ability between GuttaFlow and AH plus: An in vitro study. Int Soc Prev Community Dent 2016;6:e377&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4981942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27583228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cataldi A, Gallorini M, Di Giulio M, Guarnieri S, Mariggi&#xf2; MA, Traine T, et al. Adhesion of human gingival fibroblasts/Streptococcus mitis co-culture on the nano-composite system Chitlac-nAg. J Mater Sci Mater Med 2016;27:e88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4789204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26970770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Matteis V, Cascione M, Toma CC, Albanese G, De Giorgi ML, Corsalini M, et al. Silver Nanoparticles Addition in Poly (Methyl Methacrylate) Dental Matrix: Topographic and Antimycotic Studies. Int J Mol Sci 2019;20(19):4691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6801538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31546661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng L, Zhang K, Zhou CC, Weir MD, Zhou XD, Xu HHK. One-year water-ageing of calcium phosphate composite containing nano-silver and quaternary ammonium to inhibit biofilms. Int J Oral Sci 2016;8:172&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5113087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27281037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freire PLL, Albuquerque AJR, Sampaio FC, Galembeck A, Flores MA, Stamford T, et al. AgNPs: The New Allies against S. Mutans Biofilm Radhakrishnan&#x2014;A Pilot Clinical Trial and Microbiological Assay. Braz Dent J 2017;28:417&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29160391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruttkay-Nedeck&#xfd; B, Skal&#xed;&#x10d;kov&#xe1; S, Kepinsk&#xe1; M, &#x10c;&#xed;halov&#xe1; K, Do&#x10d;ekalov&#xe1; M, Sta&#x148;kov&#xe1; M, et al. Development of new silver nanoparticles suitable for materials with antimicrobial properties. J Nanoscience Nanotechnology 2019;19(5):2762&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30501777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widowati W, Janeva W, Nadya S, Amalia A, Arumwardana S, Kusuma HSW, et al. Antioxidant and antiaging activities of Jasminum sambac extract, and its compounds. J Rep Pharm Sci 2018;7(3):270&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prahastuti S, Hidayat M, Hasiana ST, Widowati W, Widodo WS, Handayani AS, et al. The ethanol extract of the bastard cedar (Guazuma ulmifolia L.) as antioxidants. Pharmaceuticana 2020;10(1):77&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatima F, Aldawsari MF, Ahmed MM, Anwer MK, Naz M, Ansari MJ, et al. Green synthesized silver nanoparticles using Tridax procumbens for topical application: Excision wound model and histopathological studies. Pharmaceutics 2021;13(11):1754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8623640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34834169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atun S, Arianingrum R, Cahyaningsih L, Pratiwi FA, Kusumaningrum R, Khairuddean M. Formulation and characterization of quercitrin nanoemulsion isolated from Dendropthoe falcata and its antioxidant activity test. Rasayan J Chem 2020;13(3):1347&#x2013;356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widowati W, Wargasetia TL, Kurniawati V, Rachmaniar R, Yuninda VA, Sabrina AHN, et al. In-vitro study of potential antioxidant activities of mangosteen and its nanoemulsions. Med Plants-Int J Phytomed Ind 2023;15(3):534&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koeth LM, DiFranco-Fisher JM, Scangarella-Oman NE, Miller LA. Analysis of MIC and disk diffusion testing variables for gepotidacin and comparator agents against select bacterial pathogens. J Clin Microbiol 2017;55(6): 1767&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5442533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28330893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugiaman VK, Jeffrey J, Naliani S, Pranata N, Lelyana S, Widowati W, et al. Brazilin cream from Caesalpinia sappan inhibits periodontal disease: in vivo study. PeerJ 2024;12:e17642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11229682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38978754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balouiri M, Sadiki M, Ibnsouda SK. Methods for in vitro evaluating antimicrobial activity: A review. J Pharm Anal. 2016;6(2):71&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5762448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29403965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#x119;pie&#x144;-Py&#x15b;niak D, Hauschild T, Kosikowska U, Dec M, Urban-Chmiel R. Biofilm formation capacity and presence of virulence factors among commensal Enterococcus spp. from wild birds. Sci Rep 2019;9(1):11204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6671946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31371744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong-Hyon K, Bon-Hyuk G, Sang-Soo N, Yeon-Cheol P. A review of rat models of periodontitis treated with natural extracts. J Tradit Chin Med Sci 2020;7(2):95&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widyarman AS, Lay SH, Wendhita IP, Tjakra EE, Murdono FI, Binartha CTO. Indonesian Mangosteen Fruit (Garcinia mangostana L.) Peel Extract Inhibits Streptococcus mutans and Porphyromonas gingivalis in Bio-films In vitro. Contemp Clin Dent 2019;10(1):123&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6975002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widowati W, Ginting CN, Lister INE, Girsang E, Amalia A, Wibowo SHB, et al. Anti-aging Effects of Mango-steen Peel Extract and Its Phytochemical Compounds: Antioxidant Activity, Enzyme Inhibition and Molecular Docking Simulation. Trop Life Sci Res 2020;31(3):127&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33214860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widowati W, Darsono L, Suherman J, Yelliantty Y, Maesaroh M. High Performance Liquid Chromatography (HPLC) analysis, antioxidant, antiaggregation of mango-steen peel extract (Garcinia mangostana L.). Int J Biosci Biochem Bioinforma 2014;4(6):458&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gondokesumo ME, Pardiajnto B, Sumitro BS, Widowati W, Handono K. Xanthones analysis and antioxidant activity analysis (applying ESR) of six different maturity levels of mangosteen peel extract (Garcinia mangostana Linn.). Pharmacogn J 2019;11(2):369&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danaei M, Dehghankhold M, Ataei S, Hasanzadeh Davarani F, Javanmard R, Dokhani A, et al. Impact of particle size and polydispersity index on the clinical applications of lipidic nanocarrier systems. Pharmaceutics 2018;10(2):57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6027495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29783687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granbohm H, Larismaa J, Ali S, Johansson LS, Hannula SP. Control of the size of silver nanoparticles and release of silver in heat treated SiO2-Ag composite powders. Materials 2018;11(1):80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5793578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29304021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, Yin Y, Mayers B, Herricks T, Xia Y. Uniform silver nanowires synthesis by reducing AgNO3 with ethylene glycol in the presence of seeds and poly(vinyl pyrrolidone). Chem Mater 2022;14(11):4736&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuzharov A, Milov A, Gerasina J, Soldatov M, Butova V, Soldatov A. Effect of a stabilizer on the structure, synthesis, and tribological properties of silver nanoparticles. Proc Inst Mech Eng Part J J Eng Tribol 2022;237(3):601&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mousavi-Khattat M, Keyhanfar M, Razmjou A. A comparative study of stability, antioxidant, DNA cleavage and antibacterial activities of green and chemically synthesized silver nanoparticles. Artif Cells Nanomed Biotechnol 2018;46(sup3):1022&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30449178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangeetha J, Bhor G, Nitnaware KPG. Biosynthesis of silver nanoparticles using rice grass (Oryza sativa) aqueous leaf extract. J Curr Pharma Res 2019;9(2):2792&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bratov&#x10d;i&#x107; A, Dautovic A. Green synthesis of silver nanoparticles using aqueous orange and lemon peel extract and evaluation of their antimicrobial properties. Adv Nanoparticles 2024;13(02):11&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed R, Mustafa D. Green synthesis of silver nanoparticles mediated by traditionally used medicinal plants in Sudan. Int Nano Lett 2019;10(1):1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rani K. Brief review on recent outcomes of applications of green synthesis vs chemical synthesis of silver nanoparticles. Ip Int J Compr Adv Pharmacol 2020;5(1):9&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tailor G, Yadav B, Chaudhary J, Joshi M, Suvalka C. Green synthesis of silver nanoparticles using Ocimum canum and their anti-bacterial activity. Biochem Biophys Rep 2020;24:100848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7718455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33305022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakshmanan G, Sathiyaseelan A, Altemimi A, Lakshminarayanan K, Sivaranjan K, Pratap-Singh A, et al. Efficacy of antimicrobial and larvicidal activities of green synthesized silver nanoparticles using leaf extract of Plumbago auriculata Lam. Plants 2020;9(11):1577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7698226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33202641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;elebio&#x11f;lu H, &#x130;mamo&#x11f;lu R, Ta&#x15f; R. Biogenic synthesis of silver nanoparticles using Trachystemon orientalis L. and their antibacterial activities. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taha AA, Patel MP, Hill RG, Fleming PS. The effect of bioactive glasses on enamel remineralization: A systematic review. J Dent 2017;67:9&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28939485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pooja Y, Chaitanya P, Vinay C, Uloopi KS, Alla RK, Ahalya P. Antimicrobial and mechanical properties of GIC incorporated with silver vanadate nanoparticles: An in-vitro study. J Clin Diagn Res 2023;17(6):ZC29&#x2013;ZC32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abed FM, Kotha SB, AlShukairi H, Almotawah FN, Alabdulaly RA, Mallineni SK. Effect of different concentrations of silver nanoparticles on the quality of the chemical bond of glass ionomer cement dentine in primary teeth. Front Bioeng Biotechnol 2022;10:816652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8940235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35330624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunmodede O, Johnson J, Osunlana R, Olarenwaju S, Ndu-Okeke H. Green biosynthesis of silver nanoparticles using Musa acuminata aqueous flower extract and its antimicrobial activities. CMR 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moaddabi A, Soltani P, Rengo C, Molaei S, Mousavi SJ, Mehdizadeh M, et al. Comparison of antimicrobial and wound-healing effects of silver nanoparticle and chlorhexidine mouthwashes: an in vivo study in rabbits. Odontology 2022;110(3):577&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9170635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35218448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craciunescu O, Seciu AM, Zarnescu O. In vitro and in vivo evaluation of a biomimetic scaffold embedding silver nanoparticles for improved treatment of oral lesions. Mater Sci Eng C 2021;123:112015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33812634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phuong TNM, Hai NTT, Thuy NTT, Phu NV, Huong NT, Nga DTH, et al. Factors affecting synthesis of silver-nanoparticles and antimicrobial applications. Hue Univ J Sci: Nat Sci 2020;129(1D):25&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen PT, Nguyen MT, Quach LT, Nguyen LL, Quyen DV. Antibiofilm activity of alpha-mangostin loaded nanoparticles against Streptococcus mutans. Asian Pac J Trop Biomed 2020;10(7):325&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Pan X, Liao S, Jiang C, Wang L, Tang Y, et al. Quantitative proteomics reveals the mechanism of silver nanoparticles against multidrug-resistant Pseudomonas aeruginosa biofilms. Journal of Proteome Research 2020. Jun 22;19(8):3109&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32567865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed DS, Abd El-Baky RM, Sandle T, Mandour SA, Ahmed EF. Antimicrobial activity of silver-treated bacteria against other multi-drug resistant pathogens in their environment. Antibiotics 2020;9(4):181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7235873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32326384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooti M, Sedeh AN, Motamedi H, Rezatofighi SE. Magnetic graphene oxide inlaid with silver nanoparticles as antibacterial and drug delivery composite. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol 2018;102:3607&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29511845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dakal TC, Kumar A, Majumdar RS, Yadav V. Mechanistic basis of antimicrobial actions of silver nanoparticles. Front Microbiol 2016;7:1831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5110546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27899918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalawati AN, Suyatma NE, Wardhana DI. Synthesis of silver nanoparticle (NPAg) using seed aqueous extract of Jatropha curcas L and their anti-bacterial activity assessment. J Teknol dan Industri Pangan 2022;32(2):98&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu GY, Zhao IS, Lung CY, Yin IX, Lo EC, Chu CH. Silver Compounds for Caries Management. Int Dent J 2023;74(2):179&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10988255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38008704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata MA, Matoba Y, Tosa H, Iinuma M. Effects of mangosteen pericarp extracts against mammary cancer. Altern Integr Med 2013;2(8):1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miladiyah I, Rachmawaty FJ. Potency of xanthone derivatives as antibacterial agents against Methicillin-Resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA). JKKI: Jurnal Kedokteran dan Kesehatan Indonesia 2017;124&#x2013;135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recordati C, Maglie M, Bianchessi S, Argentiere S, Cella C, Mattiello S, et al. Tissue distribution and acute toxicity of silver after single intravenous administration in mice: nano-specific and size-dependent effects. Part Fibre Toxicol 2015;13(1):12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4772516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26926244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>