<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41129309</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-6860</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>20</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>FASEB J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Correlation of Body Mass Index and Exercise on Telomere Length and Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number in Saliva Samples.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e71159</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e71159</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1096/fj.202501961R</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) copy number and telomere length are widely recognized as biomarkers of cellular aging and metabolic health. This study aimed to investigate the relationships between BMI, exercise modality, mtDNA copy number, and telomere length using saliva samples from Iranian adults. Participants (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;96) were categorized into four groups: endurance athletes, strength athletes, overweight/obese individuals (BMI &gt;&#x2009;25), and healthy controls (BMI 18-25). Saliva samples were collected for DNA extraction, and mtDNA copy number and telomere length were quantified using real-time PCR. Statistical analyses included Kruskal-Wallis and Dunnett's post hoc tests, as well as linear regression to assess correlations among variables. The results indicated that endurance athletes exhibited a significantly higher mtDNA copy number compared to controls and strength athletes, reflecting enhanced mitochondrial biogenesis from aerobic training. No significant differences in telomere length were observed among groups. While BMI showed no significant correlation with telomere length or mtDNA copy number overall, a significant negative correlation between mtDNA copy number and BMI was found exclusively in endurance athletes. Additionally, a strong positive correlation between mtDNA copy number and telomere length was observed in all groups except strength athletes. No significant differences were found between saliva and blood samples for either biomarker, and women demonstrated longer telomeres than men. This study highlights the positive impact of endurance exercise on mitochondrial biogenesis while revealing complex relationships between BMI, exercise modality, and cellular aging biomarkers. These findings offer insights into exercise-specific effects on cellular aging.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masoudi</LastName><ForeName>Fatemeh</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-3250-582X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Life Sciences and Biotechnology, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arjmand</LastName><ForeName>Sareh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4225-5891</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Life Sciences and Biotechnology, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Protein Research Center, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fayazmilani</LastName><ForeName>Rana</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7493-037X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences in Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences and Health, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pourmirzaei</LastName><ForeName>Samira</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-2511-5595</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences in Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences and Health, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>FASEB J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804484</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0892-6638</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004272">DNA, Mitochondrial</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012463" MajorTopicYN="Y">Saliva</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004272" MajorTopicYN="Y">DNA, Mitochondrial</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056915" MajorTopicYN="Y">DNA Copy Number Variations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016615" MajorTopicYN="Y">Telomere</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059505" MajorTopicYN="Y">Telomere Homeostasis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body mass index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endurance athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mitochondrial DNA copy number</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telomere length</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41129309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202501961R</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>M. Brand, &#x201c;The Role of Mitochondrial Function and Cellular Bioenergetics in Ageing and Disease,&#x201d; British Journal of Dermatology 169, no. s2 (2013): 1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. P. Rossmann, S. M. Dubois, S. Agarwal, and L. I. Zon, &#x201c;Mitochondrial Function in Development and Disease,&#x201d; Disease Models and Mechanisms 14, no. 6 (2021): dmm048912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Romero&#x2010;Garcia and H. Prado&#x2010;Garcia, &#x201c;Mitochondrial Calcium: Transport and Modulation of Cellular Processes in Homeostasis and Cancer,&#x201d; International Journal of Oncology 54, no. 4 (2019): 1155&#x2013;1167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. S. Ng and D. M. Turnbull, &#x201c;Mitochondrial Disease: Genetics and Management,&#x201d; Journal of Neurology 263, no. 1 (2016): 179&#x2013;191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. A. Castellani, R. J. Longchamps, J. Sun, E. Guallar, and D. E. Arking, &#x201c;Thinking Outside the Nucleus: Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number in Health and Disease,&#x201d; Mitochondrion 53 (2020): 214&#x2013;223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Filograna, M. Mennuni, D. Alsina, and N. G. Larsson, &#x201c;Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number in Human Disease: The More the Better?,&#x201d; FEBS Letters 595, no. 8 (2021): 976&#x2013;1002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Mengel&#x2010;From, M. Thinggaard, C. Dalg&#xe5;rd, K. O. Kyvik, K. Christensen, and L. Christiansen, &#x201c;Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number in Peripheral Blood Cells Declines With Age and Is Associated With General Health Among Elderly,&#x201d; Human Genetics 133 (2014): 1149&#x2013;1159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Dang, &#x201c;Low Copy Number of Mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) Predicts Worse Prognosis in Early&#x2010;Stage Laryngeal Cancer Patients,&#x201d; Diagnostic Pathology 9 (2014): 1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Mi, G. Tian, S. Liu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Relationship Between Altered Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number and Cancer Risk: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 5, no. 1 (2015): 10039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Sundquist, J. Sundquist, K. Palmer, and A. A. Memon, &#x201c;Role of Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number in Incident Cardiovascular Diseases and the Association Between Cardiovascular Disease and Type 2 Diabetes: A Follow&#x2010;Up Study on Middle&#x2010;Aged Women,&#x201d; Atherosclerosis 341 (2022): 58&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J.&#x2010;j. Mou, J. Peng, Y. Y. Shi, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Mitochondrial DNA Content Reduction Induces Aerobic Glycolysis and Reversible Resistance to Drug&#x2010;Induced Apoptosis in SW480 Colorectal Cancer Cells,&#x201d; Biomedicine and Pharmacotherapy 103 (2018): 729&#x2013;737.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Kobayashi and S. Imanaka, &#x201c;Mitochondrial DNA Damage and Its Repair Mechanisms in Aging Oocytes,&#x201d; International Journal of Molecular Sciences 25, no. 23 (2024): 13144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. P. Rooney, &#x201c;PCR Based Determination of Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number in Multiple Species,&#x201d; in Mitochondrial Regulation: Methods and Protocols (Springer, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Spano, B. Etain, M. Meyrel, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Telomere Length and Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number in Bipolar Disorder: Identification of a Subgroup of Young Individuals With Accelerated Cellular Aging,&#x201d; Translational Psychiatry 12, no. 1 (2022): 135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Zheng, J. Huang, and G. Wang, &#x201c;Mitochondria, Telomeres and Telomerase Subunits,&#x201d; Frontiers in Cell and Development Biology 7, no. 274 (2019): 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Moslehi, R. A. DePinho, and E. Sahin, &#x201c;Telomeres and Mitochondria in the Aging Heart,&#x201d; Circulation Research 110, no. 9 (2012): 1226&#x2013;1237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Gao, X. Yu, C. Zhang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Telomeres and Mitochondrial Metabolism: Implications for Cellular Senescence and Age&#x2010;Related Diseases,&#x201d; Stem Cell Reviews and Reports 18, no. 7 (2022): 2315&#x2013;2327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Srivastava, &#x201c;The Mitochondrial Basis of Aging and Age&#x2010;Related Disorders,&#x201d; Genes 8, no. 12 (2017): 398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Rossiello, U. Herbig, M. P. Longhese, M. Fumagalli, and F. d&#x2019;Adda di Fagagna, &#x201c;Irreparable Telomeric DNA Damage and Persistent DDR Signalling as a Shared Causative Mechanism of Cellular Senescence and Ageing,&#x201d; Current Opinion in Genetics and Development 26 (2014): 89&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Huang, L. Huang, J. Lu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Relationship Between Telomere Length and Aging&#x2010;Related Diseases,&#x201d; Clinical and Experimental Medicine 25, no. 1 (2025): 72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. J. Longchamps, C. A. Castellani, S. Y. Yang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Evaluation of Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number Estimation Techniques,&#x201d; PLoS One 15, no. 1 (2020): e0228166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. O'Hara, E. Tedone, A. Ludlow, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Quantitative Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number Determination Using Droplet Digital PCR With Single&#x2010;Cell Resolution,&#x201d; Genome Research 29, no. 11 (2019): 1878&#x2013;1888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Shen, L. Zhang, M. R. Bonner, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Association Between Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number, Blood Cell Counts, and Occupational Benzene Exposure,&#x201d; Environmental and Molecular Mutagenesis 49, no. 6 (2008): 453&#x2013;457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. N. Malik and A. Czajka, &#x201c;Is Mitochondrial DNA Content a Potential Biomarker of Mitochondrial Dysfunction?,&#x201d; Mitochondrion 13, no. 5 (2013): 481&#x2013;492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Lei and Y. Liu, &#x201c;Identifying Blood Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number as a Biomarker for Development of Neurodegenerative Diseases: Evidence From Mendelian Randomization Analysis,&#x201d; Neuroscience 573 (2025): 421&#x2013;429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Y. Takahashi, G. D. Jenkins, B. P. Welkie, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Association of Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number With Self&#x2010;Rated Health Status,&#x201d; Application of Clinical Genetics 11 (2018): 121&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Sanchez&#x2010;Espiridion, M. Chen, J. Y. Chang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Telomere Length in Peripheral Blood Leukocytes and Lung Cancer Risk: A Large Case&#x2013;Control Study in Caucasians,&#x201d; Cancer Research 74, no. 9 (2014): 2476&#x2013;2486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Ko, H. W. Seo, and G. Jung, &#x201c;Telomere Length and Reactive Oxygen Species Levels Are Positively Associated With a High Risk of Mortality and Recurrence in Hepatocellular Carcinoma,&#x201d; Hepatology 67, no. 4 (2018): 1378&#x2013;1391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Ningarhari, S. Caruso, T. Z. Hirsch, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Telomere Length Is Key to Hepatocellular Carcinoma Diversity and Telomerase Addiction Is an Actionable Therapeutic Target,&#x201d; Journal of Hepatology 74, no. 5 (2021): 1155&#x2013;1166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Reznik, M. L. Miller, Y. &#x15e;enbabao&#x11f;lu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number Variation Across Human Cancers,&#x201d; eLife 5 (2016): e10769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. W. McLester&#x2010;Davis, &#x201c;A Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis: Cross&#x2010;Tissue Telomere Length Correlations in Healthy Humans. Ageing Research Reviews,&#x201d; (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. P. Rath, R. Gupta, E. Todres, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Mitochondrial Genome Copy Number Variation Across Tissues in Mice and Humans,&#x201d; Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 121, no. 33 (2024): e2402291121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Bhattacharya, P. Bhaumik, and S. Kumar&#x2010;Dey, &#x201c;Telomere Length Comparison Between Oral Cells and Blood Cells Among Neonates,&#x201d; Turkish Journal of Pediatrics 61, no. 4 (2019): 520&#x2013;524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Thomas, N. J. O'Callaghan, and M. Fenech, &#x201c;Telomere Length in White Blood Cells, Buccal Cells and Brain Tissue and Its Variation With Ageing and Alzheimer's Disease,&#x201d; Mechanisms of Ageing and Development 129, no. 4 (2008): 183&#x2013;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Xu, Z. Qiu, and Y.&#x2010;S. Cong, &#x201c;Comparison of Telomere Length Between Buccal Cells and Blood Cells,&#x201d; Bulletin of Experimental Biology and Medicine 173, no. 5 (2022): 677&#x2013;679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Freyssenet, P. Berthon, and C. Denis, &#x201c;Mitochondrial Biogenesis in Skeletal Muscle in Response to Endurance Exercises,&#x201d; Archives of Physiology and Biochemistry 104, no. 2 (1996): 129&#x2013;141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Irrcher, P. J. Adhihetty, A. M. Joseph, V. Ljubicic, and D. A. Hood, &#x201c;Regulation of Mitochondrial Biogenesis in Muscle by Endurance Exercise,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 33 (2003): 783&#x2013;793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. B. Kurniawan, U. Bahrun, M. Hatta, and M. Arif, &#x201c;BMI and Waist Circumference Have Positive Correlation With Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number in Young Adult Male,&#x201d; Open Obesity Journal 8, no. 1 (2018): 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Skuratovskaia, L. Litvinova, M. Vulf, P. Zatolokin, K. Popadin, and I. Mazunin, &#x201c;From Normal to Obesity and Back: The Associations Between Mitochondrial DNA Copy Number, Gender, and Body Mass Index,&#x201d; Cells 8, no. 5 (2019): 430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Agius, N. P. Pace, and S. Fava, &#x201c;Reduced Leukocyte Mitochondrial Copy Number in Metabolic Syndrome and Metabolically Healthy Obesity,&#x201d; Frontiers in Endocrinology 13 (2022): 886957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Gielen, G. J. Hageman, E. E. Antoniou, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Body Mass Index Is Negatively Associated With Telomere Length: A Collaborative Cross&#x2010;Sectional Meta&#x2010;Analysis of 87 Observational Studies,&#x201d; American Journal of Clinical Nutrition 108, no. 3 (2018): 453&#x2013;475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Kim, C. G. Parks, L. A. DeRoo, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Obesity and Weight Gain in Adulthood and Telomere Length,&#x201d; Cancer Epidemiology, Biomarkers &amp; Prevention 18, no. 3 (2009): 816&#x2013;820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Junker, J. Wang, G. Gouspillou, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Human Studies of Mitochondrial Biology Demonstrate an Overall Lack of Binary Sex Differences: A Multivariate Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; FASEB Journal 36, no. 2 (2022): e22146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. K. Kresovich, C. G. Parks, D. P. Sandler, and J. A. Taylor, &#x201c;Reproductive History and Blood Cell Telomere Length,&#x201d; Aging (Albany NY) 10, no. 9 (2018): 2383&#x2013;2393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Gardner, D. Bann, L. Wiley, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Gender and Telomere Length: Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Experimental Gerontology 51 (2014): 15&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>