<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41871255</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1091-6490</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>123</Volume><Issue>13</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Amplifying toughness in silica-reinforced natural rubber by preserving long chains.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2530834123</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2530834123</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e2530834123</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1073/pnas.2530834123</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Natural rubber outperforms synthetic rubbers because of its long chains and strain-induced crystallization (SIC). However, these advantages are largely lost when the natural rubber chains are masticated during processing, and silica particles are added for reinforcement. Mastication eases mixing but shortens chains and lowers performance. Silica particles require covalent interlinks with rubber chains, but these interlinks restrict chain stretch and alignment, reducing SIC. Here, we show that the performance of silica-reinforced natural rubber can be markedly enhanced by preserving long natural rubber chains. We use a solvent to dissolve natural rubber latex into individual rubber chains and use the solution to uniformly disperse silica particles. After drying, the uncured compound can be stored and molded prior to curing. The long rubber chains are then sparsely crosslinked with one another and interlinked with the silica particles. The long strands readily align under stretch and increase SIC. Preserving long chains elevates toughness by an order of magnitude, from ~2 to 44 kJ m<sup>-2</sup>. High toughness arises from energy dissipation across multiple length scales, over long rubber strands, silica particles, and a zone of SIC. High modulus of ~19 MPa arises from two interpenetrating networks: the network of densely entangled rubber chains and the network of percolated silica particles. The resulting material achieves high toughness while maintaining high modulus, a combination uncommon in silica-reinforced synthetic and natural rubbers.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Matthew Wei Ming</ForeName><Initials>MWM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>John A. Paulson School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, Harvard University, Cambridge, MA 02138.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore 639798, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Nian</LastName><ForeName>Guodong</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7005-634X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>John A. Paulson School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, Harvard University, Cambridge, MA 02138.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zheqi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7193-5426</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>John A. Paulson School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, Harvard University, Cambridge, MA 02138.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bao</LastName><ForeName>Xianyang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>John A. Paulson School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, Harvard University, Cambridge, MA 02138.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kutsovsky</LastName><ForeName>Yakov</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Expert-in-Residence, Office of Technology Development, Harvard University, Cambridge, MA 02138.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suo</LastName><ForeName>Zhigang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4068-4844</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>John A. Paulson School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, Harvard University, Cambridge, MA 02138.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>DMR-2011754</GrantID><Agency>NSF (NSF)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>FA9550-20-1-0397</GrantID><Agency>DOD | AF | AMC | AFRL | Air Force Office of Scientific Research (AFOSR)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0027-8424</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">natural rubber</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">particles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polymers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">processing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests statement:The authors declare no competing interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41871255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13037892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2530834123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Westall B., The molecular weight distribution of natural rubber latex. Polymer 9, 243&#x2013;248 (1968).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayeemasae N., Soontaranon S., Masa A., Structure&#x2014;Property relationships of different natural rubber grades. Prog. Rubber Plastics Recycl. Technol. 41, 14777606241243112 (2024), 10.1177/14777606241243113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/14777606241243113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka Y., Tarachiwin L., Recent advances in structural characterization of natural rubber. Rubber Chem. Technol. 82, 283&#x2013;314 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosaka M., et al. , Effect of network-chain length on strain-induced crystallization of NR and IR vulcanizates. Rubber Chem. Technol. 77, 711&#x2013;723 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohjiya S., Ikeda Y., Chemistry, Manufacture and Applications of Natural Rubber (Elsevier, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H. P., Niemczura J., Dennis G., Ravi-Chandar K., Marder M., Toughening effect of strain-induced crystallites in natural rubber. Phys. Rev. Lett. 102, 245503 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19659026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nian G., et al. , Natural rubber with high resistance to crack growth. Nat. Sustain. 8, 692&#x2013;701 (2025), 10.1038/s41893-025-01559-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41893-025-01559-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mooibroek H., Cornish K., Alternative sources of natural rubber. Appl. Microbiol. Biotechnol. 53, 355&#x2013;365 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10803889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayaram T. R., A technical review on rubber. Int. J. Des. Manuf. Technol. 3, 25&#x2013;37 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y., Fowler G. D., Zhao M., The past, present and future of carbon black as a rubber reinforcing filler&#x2014;A review. J. Clean. Prod. 247, 119115 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans M. S., Tyre Compounding for Improved Performance (iSmithers Rapra Publishing, 2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmon D. J., Jacobs H. L., Degradation of natural rubber during mill mastication. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 10, 253&#x2013;257 (1966).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao T., Xie R., Zhang L., Gui H., Huang M., Use of rubber process analyzer for characterizing the molecular weight parameters of natural rubber. Int. J. Polym. Sci. 2015, 517260 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehabe E. E., Bonfils F., Sainte-Beuve J., Collet A., Schu&#xe9; F., High-temperature mastication of raw natural rubber: Changes in macrostructure and mesostructure. Polymer Eng. Sci. 46, 222&#x2013;227 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angier D. J., Chambers W. T., Watson W. F., Mastication of rubber. VI. Viscosity and molecular weight relationships for natural rubber after cold mastication. J. Polym. Sci. 25, 129&#x2013;138 (1957).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao X., et al. , Low-intensity mixing process of high molecular weight polymer chains leads to elastomers of long network strands and high fatigue threshold. Soft Matter 19, 5956&#x2013;5966 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37490335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong L., et al. , Designing highly entangled, homogeneous, and low-defect networks for high-performance rubbers. Macromolecules 58, 3109&#x2013;3118 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkawi S. S., Kaewsakul W., Sahakaro K., Dierkes W. K., Noordermeer J. W. M., A review on reinforcement of natural rubber by silica fillers for use in low-rolling resistance tires. J. Rubber Res. 18, 203&#x2013;233 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neethirajan J., Parathodika A. R., Hu G.-H., Naskar K., Functional rubber composites based on silica-silane reinforcement for green tire application: The state of the art. Funct. Compos. Mater. 3, 1&#x2013;15 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>OECD, Nanotechnology and Tyres: Greening Industry and Transport (OECD, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katueangngan K., Tulyapitak T., Saetung A., Soontaranon S., Nithi-Uthai N., Interfacial interactions of silica and natural rubber enhanced by hydroxyl telechelic natural rubber as interfacial modifier. J. Vinyl Addit. Technol. 26, 291&#x2013;303 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengloyluan K., Sahakaro K., Dierkes W. K., Noordermeer J. W. M., Silane grafted natural rubber and its compatibilization effect on silica-reinforced rubber tire compounds. Express Polym. Lett. 11, 1003&#x2013;1022 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borapak W., Chueangchayaphan N., Pichaiyut S., Chueangchayaphan W., Natural rubber-graft-poly(2-hydroxyethyl acrylate) on cure characteristics and mechanical properties of silica-filled natural rubber composites. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 137, 48738 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spratte T., Plagge J., Wunde M., Kl&#xfc;ppel M., Investigation of strain-induced crystallization of carbon black and silica filled natural rubber composites based on mechanical and temperature measurements. Polymer 115, 12&#x2013;20 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chenal J.-M., Gauthier C., Chazeau L., Guy L., Bomal Y., Parameters governing strain induced crystallization in filled natural rubber. Polymer 48, 6893&#x2013;6901 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phumnok E., Khongprom P., Ratanawilai S., Preparation of natural rubber composites with high silica contents using a wet mixing process. ACS Omega 7, 8364&#x2013;8376 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8928548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35309431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., et al. , High silica content graphene/natural rubber composites prepared by a wet compounding and latex mixing process. Polymers 12, 2549 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7692359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33143314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetters L. J., Lohse D. J., Richter D., Witten T. A., Zirkel A., Connection between polymer molecular weight, density, chain dimensions, and melt viscoelastic properties. Macromolecules 27, 4639&#x2013;4647 (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerveny S., Marzocca A. J., Analysis of variation of molecular parameters of natural rubber during vulcanization in conformational tube model. Part II. Influence of sulfur/accelerator ratio. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 74, 2747&#x2013;2755 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amnuaypornsri S., Sakdapipanich J., Tanaka Y., Green strength of natural rubber: The origin of the stress&#x2013;strain behavior of natural rubber. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 111, 2127&#x2013;2133 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steck J., Kim J., Kutsovsky Y., Suo Z., Multiscale stress deconcentration amplifies fatigue resistance of rubber. Nature 624, 303&#x2013;308 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38092910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommer J. G., Molding of rubber for high performance applications. Rubber Chem. Technol. 58, 662&#x2013;683 (1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dluzneski P. R., Peroxide vulcanization of elastomers. Rubber Chem. Technol. 74, 451&#x2013;492 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diani J., Fayolle B., Gilormini P., A review on the Mullins effect. Eur. Polym. J. 45, 601&#x2013;612 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C., Yin T., Suo Z., Polyacrylamide hydrogels. I. Network imperfection. J. Mech. Phys. Solids 131, 43&#x2013;55 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J., Xian B., Li H., Zhang L., Han D., Preparation of silica/natural rubber masterbatch using solution compounding. Polymer 244, 124661 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail H., Salleh S. Z., Ahmad Z., Properties of halloysite nanotubes-filled natural rubber prepared using different mixing methods. Mater. Des. 50, 790&#x2013;797 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon A., Pillai C., Jin W., Nah C., Fatigue resistance of silica-filled natural rubber vulcanizates: Comparative study of the effect of phosphorylated cardanol prepolymer and a silane coupling agent. Polym. Int. 54, 629&#x2013;635 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamed G. R., Park B. H., The mechanism of carbon black reinforcement of SBR and NR vulcanizates. Rubber Chem. Technol. 72, 946&#x2013;959 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berki P., G&#xf6;bl R., Karger-Kocsis J., Structure and properties of styrene-butadiene rubber (SBR) with pyrolytic and industrial carbon black. Polym. Test. 61, 404&#x2013;415 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padenko E., Berki P., Wetzel B., Karger-Kocsis J., Mechanical and abrasion wear properties of hydrogenated nitrile butadiene rubber of identical hardness filled with carbon black and silica. J. Reinf. Plast. Compos. 35, 81&#x2013;91 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson C. G., Sto&#x10d;ek R., Kipscholl C., Mars W. V., Characterizing the intrinsic strength (fatigue threshold) of natural rubber/butadiene rubber blends. Tire Sci. Technol. 47, 292&#x2013;307 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mzabi S., Berghezan D., Roux S., Hild F., Creton C., A critical local energy release rate criterion for fatigue fracture of elastomers. J. Polym. Sci. B Polym. Phys. 49, 1518&#x2013;1524 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q., Xu S., Lu M., Liu J., Shull K. R., Temperature-dependent viscoelastic energy dissipation and fatigue crack growth in filled silicone elastomers. ACS Appl. Polym. Mater. 3, 6207&#x2013;6217 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerns M. L., Xu Z., Christian S. M., Synthesis of styrene-butadiene rubber (2002), U.S. Patent US6372863B1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikolaus S., Gottfried P., Josef W., Process for the manufacture of polybutadiene (1967), U.S. Patent US3299031A.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recker C., et al. , Rubber blend, sulfur-crosslinkable rubber mixture, and vehicle tire (2021), U.S. Patent US11015041B2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciullo P. A., Hewitt N., &#x201c;Rubber processing&#x201d; in The Rubber Formulary, Plastics Design Library, Ciullo P. A., Hewitt N., Eds. (William Andrew Publishing, 1999), pp. 49&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., et al. , Wet mixing with organic solvent for synthesized cis-1, 4-polyisoprene-based rubber composites. ACS Omega 5, 30444&#x2013;30453 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7711689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33283092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong L., et al. , Silica masterbatches produced with liquid phase mixing; Part III. Quasi-Static Stress-Softening. J. Macromol. Sci., Part B 61, 796&#x2013;810 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue J., et al. , Preparation of ablation-resistant ethylene propylene trioxide/polyimide staple fiber composite insulation layer by solution wet mixing process. Polym. Degrad. Stab. 227, 110879 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M., Song J., Dai D., Continuous manufacturing process for rubber masterbatch and rubber masterbatch prepared therefrom (2018), U.S. Patent 10125229B2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z.-R., Araki S., Cole W. M., Hergenrother W., Warren S., Solution masterbatch process using fine particle silica for low hysteresis rubber (2007), U.S. Patent US7312271B2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maxam Tire, EcoPoint3 Technology (2025), https://maxamtire.com/ecopoint3/ [7 September 2025, Date Last Accessed].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aboagye E. A., Chea J. D., Yenkie K. M., Systems level roadmap for solvent recovery and reuse in industries. iScience 24, 103114 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8479785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34622166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox W. L., Parks C. R., Effect of curing systems on fatigue of natural rubber vulcanizates. Rubber Chem. Technol. 39, 785&#x2013;797 (1966).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanyo L. C., Effect of crosslink type on the fracture of natural rubber vulcanizates. Int. J. Fract. 39, 103&#x2013;110 (1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J., Zhang G., Shi M., Suo Z., Fracture, fatigue, and friction of polymers in which entanglements greatly outnumber cross-links. Science 374, 212&#x2013;216 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34618571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nian G., Kim J., Bao X., Suo Z., Making highly elastic and tough hydrogels from doughs. Adv. Mater. 34, 2206577 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36126085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Zhang G., Luo Y., Suo Z., Rubber-glass nanocomposites fabricated using mixed emulsions. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 121, e2322684121 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11032485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38588426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas D. K., Crosslinking efficiency of dicumyl peroxide in natural rubber. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 6, 613&#x2013;616 (1962).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>