<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41745434</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2313-433X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of imaging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>YOLO11s-UAV: An Advanced Algorithm for Small Object Detection in UAV Aerial Imagery.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">69</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/jimaging12020069</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) are now widely used in various applications, including agriculture, urban traffic management, and search and rescue operations. However, several challenges arise, including the small size of objects occupying only a sparse number of pixels in images, complex backgrounds in aerial footage, and limited computational resources onboard. To address these issues, this paper proposes an improved UAV-based small object detection algorithm, YOLO11s-UAV, specifically designed for aerial imagery. Firstly, we introduce a novel FPN, called Content-Aware Reassembly and Interaction Feature Pyramid Network (CARIFPN), which significantly enhances small object feature detection while reducing redundant network structures. Secondly, we apply a new downsampling convolution for small object feature extraction, called Space-to-Depth for Dilation-wise Residual Convolution (S2DResConv), in the model's backbone. This module effectively eliminates information loss caused by strided convolution or pooling operations and facilitates the capture of multi-scale context. Finally, we integrate a simple, parameter-free attention module (SimAM) with C3k2 to form Flexible SimAM (FlexSimAM), which is applied throughout the entire model. This improved module not only reduces the model's complexity but also enables efficient enhancement of small object features in complex scenarios. Experimental results demonstrate that on the VisDrone-DET2019 dataset, our model improves mAP@0.5 by 7.8% on the validation set (reaching 46.0%) and by 5.9% on the test set (increasing to 37.3%) compared to the baseline YOLO11s, while reducing model parameters by 55.3%. Similarly, it achieves a 7.2% improvement on the TinyPerson dataset and a 3.0% increase on UAVDT-DET. Deployment on the NVIDIA Jetson Orin NX SUPER platform shows that our model achieves 33 FPS, which is 21.4% lower than YOLO11s, confirming its feasibility for real-time onboard UAV applications.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mi</LastName><ForeName>Qi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-5922-4364</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanical and Electrical Engineering, Fujian Agriculture and Forestry University, Fuzhou 350108, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quanzhou Institute of Equipment Manufacturing, Haixi Institutes, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Quanzhou 362216, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fujian Institute of Research on the Structure of Matter, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Fuzhou 350025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fujian College, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Fuzhou 350025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chao</LastName><ForeName>Jianshu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7197-5919</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quanzhou Institute of Equipment Manufacturing, Haixi Institutes, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Quanzhou 362216, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fujian Institute of Research on the Structure of Matter, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Fuzhou 350025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fujian College, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Fuzhou 350025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Anqi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-2993-450X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanical and Electrical Engineering, Fujian Agriculture and Forestry University, Fuzhou 350108, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quanzhou Institute of Equipment Manufacturing, Haixi Institutes, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Quanzhou 362216, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fujian Institute of Research on the Structure of Matter, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Fuzhou 350025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fujian College, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Fuzhou 350025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Kaiyuan</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-0991-9784</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quanzhou Institute of Equipment Manufacturing, Haixi Institutes, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Quanzhou 362216, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fujian Institute of Research on the Structure of Matter, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Fuzhou 350025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fujian College, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Fuzhou 350025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Advanced Manufacturing, Fuzhou University, Quanzhou 362251, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Jiahua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-2179-6745</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quanzhou Institute of Equipment Manufacturing, Haixi Institutes, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Quanzhou 362216, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fujian Institute of Research on the Structure of Matter, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Fuzhou 350025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024T3102</GrantID><Agency>STS Project of Fujian Science and Technology Program</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023FX0002</GrantID><Agency>Collaborative Innovation Platform Project of the Fuzhou-Xiamen-Quanzhou National Independent Innovation Demonstration Zone</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101698819</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2313-433X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">UAV aerial imagery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VisDrone-DET2019</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">YOLO11s</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">feature pyramid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lightweight object detector</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">small object detection</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41745434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12942582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jimaging12020069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jimaging12020069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yao H., Qin R., Chen X. Unmanned Aerial Vehicle for Remote Sensing Applications&#x2014;A Review. Remote Sens. 2019;11:1443. doi: 10.3390/rs11121443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs11121443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Z., Savkin A.V. Strategies for Optimized UAV Surveillance in Various Tasks and Scenarios: A Review. Drones. 2024;8:193. doi: 10.3390/drones8050193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones8050193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X., Smith A., Bourchier R., Hodge K., Ostrander D., Houston B. Mapping flowering leafy spurge infestations in a heterogeneous landscape using unmanned aerial vehicle Red-Green-Blue images and a hybrid classification method. Int. J. Remote Sens. 2021;42:8930&#x2013;8951. doi: 10.1080/01431161.2021.1973686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431161.2021.1973686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng J., Yi C. Lightweight Detection Network for Arbitrary-Oriented Vehicles in UAV Imagery via Global Attentive Relation and Multi-Path Fusion. Drones. 2022;6:108. doi: 10.3390/drones6050108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones6050108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsamhi S.H., Shvetsov A.V., Kumar S., Shvetsova S.V., Alhartomi M.A., Hawbani A., Rajput N.S., Srivastava S., Saif A., Nyangaresi V.O. UAV Computing-Assisted Search and Rescue Mission Framework for Disaster and Harsh Environment Mitigation. Drones. 2022;6:154. doi: 10.3390/drones6070154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones6070154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua W., Chen Q. A survey of small object detection based on deep learning in aerial images. Artif. Intell. Rev. 2025;58:162. doi: 10.1007/s10462-025-11150-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-025-11150-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habash N., Alqumsan A.A., Zhou T. Recent Real-Time Aerial Object Detection Approaches, Performance, Optimization, and Efficient Design Trends for Onboard Performance: A Survey. Sensors. 2025;25:7563. doi: 10.3390/s25247563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25247563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12736610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41471559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin T.Y., Doll&#xe1;r P., Girshick R., He K., Hariharan B., Belongie S. Feature Pyramid Networks for Object Detection; Proceedings of the 2017 IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Honolulu, HI, USA. 21&#x2013;26 July 2017; pp. 936&#x2013;944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/CVPR.2017.106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S., Qi L., Qin H., Shi J., Jia J. Path Aggregation Network for Instance Segmentation; Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Salt Lake City, UT, USA. 18&#x2013;23 June 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghiasi G., Lin T.Y., Le Q.V. NAS-FPN: Learning Scalable Feature Pyramid Architecture for Object Detection; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Long Beach, CA, USA. 15&#x2013;20 June 2019;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/CVPR.2019.00720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chollet F. Xception: Deep Learning with Depthwise Separable Convolutions; Proceedings of the 2017 IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Honolulu, HI, USA. 21&#x2013;26 July 2017; pp. 1800&#x2013;1807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/CVPR.2017.195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Zhou A., Yao A. Omni-Dimensional Dynamic Convolution. arXiv. 2022 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2209.07947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2209.07947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han K., Wang Y., Tian Q., Guo J., Xu C., Xu C. GhostNet: More Features From Cheap Operations; Proceedings of the 2020 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Seattle, WA, USA. 13&#x2013;19 June 2020; pp. 1577&#x2013;1586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/CVPR42600.2020.00165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaswani A., Shazeer N., Parmar N., Uszkoreit J., Jones L., Gomez A.N., Kaiser L.u., Polosukhin I. Attention is All you Need. In: Guyon I., Luxburg U.V., Bengio S., Wallach H., Fergus R., Vishwanathan S., Garnett R., editors. Proceedings of the Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems. Volume 30 Curran Associates, Inc.; New York, NY, USA: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katharopoulos A., Vyas A., Pappas N., Fleuret F. Transformers are RNNs: Fast Autoregressive Transformers with Linear Attention. In: Daum&#xe9; H., Singh A., editors. Proceedings of the 37th International Conference on Machine Learning, 13&#x2013;18 July 2020. Volume 119. ACM; New York, NY, USA: 2020. pp. 5156&#x2013;5165. PMLR.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Q., Huang H., Ai Y., He R. Rectifying Magnitude Neglect in Linear Attention; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV); Honolulu, HI, USA. 19&#x2013;23 October 2025; pp. 21505&#x2013;21514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L., Wang X., Ke Z., Zhang W., Lau R.W. BiFormer: Vision Transformer With Bi-Level Routing Attention; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Vancouver, BC, Canada. 18&#x2013;22 June 2023; pp. 10323&#x2013;10333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du D., Zhu P., Wen L., Bian X., Lin H., Hu Q., Peng T., Zheng J., Wang X., Zhang Y., et al. VisDrone-DET2019: The Vision Meets Drone Object Detection in Image Challenge Results; Proceedings of the 2019 IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision Workshop (ICCVW); Seoul, Republic of Korea. 27&#x2013;28 October 2019; pp. 213&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ICCVW.2019.00030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X., Gong Y., Jiang N., Ye Q., Han Z. Scale Match for Tiny Person Detection; Proceedings of the 2020 IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV); Snowmass Village, CO, USA. 1&#x2013;5 March 2020; pp. 1246&#x2013;1254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/WACV45572.2020.9093394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du D., Qi Y., Yu H., Yang Y., Duan K., Li G., Zhang W., Huang Q., Tian Q. The Unmanned Aerial Vehicle Benchmark: Object Detection and Tracking. In: Ferrari V., Hebert M., Sminchisescu C., Weiss Y., editors. Proceedings of the Computer Vision&#x2014;ECCV 2018. Springer; Cham, Switzerland: 2018. pp. 375&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-01249-6_23</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren S., He K., Girshick R., Sun J. Faster R-CNN: Towards Real-Time Object Detection with Region Proposal Networks. IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell. 2017;39:1137&#x2013;1149. doi: 10.1109/TPAMI.2016.2577031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2016.2577031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27295650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Z., Vasconcelos N. Cascade R-CNN: Delving Into High Quality Object Detection; Proceedings of the 2018 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Salt Lake City, UT, USA. 18&#x2013;22 June 2018; pp. 6154&#x2013;6162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/CVPR.2018.00644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin T.Y., Goyal P., Girshick R., He K., Doll&#xe1;r P. Focal Loss for Dense Object Detection; Proceedings of the 2017 IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV); Venice, Italy. 22&#x2013;29 October 2017; pp. 2999&#x2013;3007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ICCV.2017.324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu C., He Y., Savvides M. Feature Selective Anchor-Free Module for Single-Shot Object Detection; Proceedings of the 2019 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Long Beach, CA, USA. 16&#x2013;20 June 2019; pp. 840&#x2013;849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/CVPR.2019.00093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jocher G., Stoken A., Borovec J., Changyu L., Hogan A., Diaconu L., Poznanski J., Yu L., Rai P., Ferriday R., et al. ultralytics/yolov5: V3.0. Zenodo. 2020 doi: 10.5281/zenodo.3983579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5281/zenodo.3983579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redmon J., Farhadi A. YOLOv3: An Incremental Improvement. arXiv. 2018 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1804.02767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1804.02767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohan M., Sai Ram T., Reddy R., Venkata C. A review on YOLOv8 and its advancements; Proceedings of the International Conference on Data Intelligence and Cognitive Informatics; Tirunelveli, India. 18&#x2013;20 November 2024; pp. 529&#x2013;545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-99-7962-2_39</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C.Y., Yeh I.H., Mark Liao H.Y. YOLOv9: Learning What You Want to Learn Using Programmable Gradient Information. In: Leonardis A., Ricci E., Roth S., Russakovsky O., Sattler T., Varol G., editors. Proceedings of the Computer Vision&#x2014;ECCV 2024. Springer; Cham, Switzerland: 2025. pp. 1&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-031-72751-1_1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang A., Chen H., Liu L., Chen K., Lin Z., Han J., Ding G. YOLOv10: Real-Time End-to-End Object Detection. arXiv. 2024 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2405.14458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2405.14458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Li L., Jiang H., Weng K., Geng Y., Li L., Ke Z., Li Q., Cheng M., Nie W., et al. YOLOv6: A Single-Stage Object Detection Framework for Industrial Applications. arXiv. 2022 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2209.02976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2209.02976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carion N., Massa F., Synnaeve G., Usunier N., Kirillov A., Zagoruyko S. End-to-end object detection with transformers; Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision; Glasgow, UK. 23&#x2013;28 August 2020; pp. 213&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-58452-8_13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Y., Ye Q., Doermann D. YOLOv12: Attention-Centric Real-Time Object Detectors. arXiv. 2025 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2502.12524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2502.12524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei M., Li S., Wu Y., Hu H., Zhou Y., Zheng X., Ding G., Du S., Wu Z., Gao Y. YOLOv13: Real-Time Object Detection with Hypergraph-Enhanced Adaptive Visual Perception. arXiv. 2025 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2506.17733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2506.17733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu X., Wei G., Yuan X., Liang Y., Bo Y. Efficient YOLOv7-Drone: An Enhanced Object Detection Approach for Drone Aerial Imagery. Drones. 2023;7:616. doi: 10.3390/drones7100616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones7100616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahir N.U.A., Long Z., Zhang Z., Asim M., ELAffendi M. PVswin-YOLOv8s: UAV-Based Pedestrian and Vehicle Detection for Traffic Management in Smart Cities Using Improved YOLOv8. Drones. 2024;8:84. doi: 10.3390/drones8030084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones8030084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Li Q., Pan J., Zhou Y., Zhu H., Wei H., Liu C. SOD-YOLO: Small-Object-Detection Algorithm Based on Improved YOLOv8 for UAV Images. Remote Sens. 2024;16:3057. doi: 10.3390/rs16163057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs16163057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Gao J., Zhang B. A small object detection model in aerial images based on CPDD-YOLOv8. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:770. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-84938-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-84938-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11700085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39755781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H.I., Tseng Y.W., Chang K.C., Wang P.J., Shuai H.H., Cheng W.H. A DeNoising FPN With Transformer R-CNN for Tiny Object Detection. IEEE Trans. Geosci. Remote Sens. 2024;62:4704415. doi: 10.1109/TGRS.2024.3396489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TGRS.2024.3396489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y., Chai L., Jin L. Scale decoupled pyramid for object detection in aerial images. IEEE Trans. Geosci. Remote Sens. 2023;61:4704314. doi: 10.1109/TGRS.2023.3298852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TGRS.2023.3298852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z., Li Z., Lei H., Zhao H., Yang W. RC-SODet: Reparameterized dual convolutions and compact feature enhancement for small object detector. Image Vis. Comput. 2025;159:105552. doi: 10.1016/j.imavis.2025.105552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.imavis.2025.105552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanam R., Hussain M. Yolov11: An overview of the key architectural enhancements. arXiv. 2024 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2410.17725.2410.17725</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2410.17725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin T.Y., Maire M., Belongie S., Hays J., Perona P., Ramanan D., Doll&#xe1;r P., Zitnick C.L. Microsoft coco: Common objects in context; Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision; Zurich, Switzerland. 6&#x2013;12 September 2014; pp. 740&#x2013;755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-10602-1_48</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X., Jiang Y., Chen W., Huang Y., Zhang Y., Sun X. Damo-yolo: A report on real-time object detection design. arXiv. 2022 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2211.15444.2211.15444</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2211.15444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y., Tan Z., Wang J., Sun X., Lin M., Li H. GiraffeDet: A heavy-neck paradigm for object detection. arXiv. 2022 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2202.04256.2202.04256</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2202.04256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Chen K., Xu R., Liu Z., Loy C.C., Lin D. CARAFE: Content-Aware ReAssembly of FEatures; Proceedings of the 2019 IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV); Seoul, Republic of Korea. 27 October&#x2013;2 November 2019; pp. 3007&#x2013;3016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ICCV.2019.00310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunkara R., Luo T. No More Strided Convolutions or Pooling: A New CNN Building Block for Low-Resolution Images and Small Objects; Proceedings of the Machine Learning and Knowledge Discovery in Databases; Turin, Italy. 18&#x2013;22 September 2023; pp. 443&#x2013;459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-031-26409-2_27</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei H., Liu X., Xu S., Dai Z., Dai Y., Xu X. DWRSeg: Rethinking efficient acquisition of multi-scale contextual information for real-time semantic segmentation. arXiv. 2022 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2212.01173.2212.01173</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2212.01173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Zhang R.Y., Li L., Xie X. SimAM: A Simple, Parameter-Free Attention Module for Convolutional Neural Networks; Proceedings of the 38th International Conference on Machine Learning, PMLR; Virtual. 18&#x2013;24 July 2021; pp. 11863&#x2013;11874.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webb B.S., Dhruv N.T., Solomon S.G., Tailby C., Lennie P. Early and late mechanisms of surround suppression in striate cortex of macaque. J. Neurosci. 2005;25:11666&#x2013;11675. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3414-05.2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3414-05.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6726034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16354925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillyard S.A., Vogel E.K., Luck S.J. Sensory gain control (amplification) as a mechanism of selective attention: Electrophysiological and neuroimaging evidence. Philos. Trans. R. Soc. Lond. Ser. B Biol. Sci. 1998;353:1257&#x2013;1270. doi: 10.1098/rstb.1998.0281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rstb.1998.0281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1692341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9770220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W., Lu H., Fu H., Cao Z. Learning to Upsample by Learning to Sample; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV); Paris, France. 2&#x2013;6 October 2023; pp. 6027&#x2013;6037.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Dai X., Liu M., Chen D., Yuan L., Liu Z. Dynamic Convolution: Attention Over Convolution Kernels; Proceedings of the 2020 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Seattle, WA, USA. 13&#x2013;19 June 2020; pp. 11027&#x2013;11036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/CVPR42600.2020.01104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J., Liu S., Wu J., Su X., Hai N., Huang X. Pinwheel-shaped Convolution and Scale-based Dynamic Loss for Infrared Small Target Detection. Proc. AAAI Conf. Artif. Intell. 2025;39:9202&#x2013;9210. doi: 10.1609/aaai.v39i9.32996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1609/aaai.v39i9.32996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning T., Wu W., Zhang J. Small object detection based on YOLOv8 in UAV perspective. Pattern Anal. Appl. 2024;27:103. doi: 10.1007/s10044-024-01323-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10044-024-01323-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z. Drone-YOLO: An Efficient Neural Network Method for Target Detection in Drone Images. Drones. 2023;7:526. doi: 10.3390/drones7080526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones7080526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S., Zhou H. Detection Based on Semantics and a Detail Infusion Feature Pyramid Network and a Coordinate Adaptive Spatial Feature Fusion Mechanism Remote Sensing Small Object Detector. Remote Sens. 2024;16:2416. doi: 10.3390/rs16132416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs16132416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S., Song L., Yin J., Chen Q., Zhan T., Huang W. MFFCI&#x2013;YOLOv8: A Lightweight Remote Sensing Object Detection Network Based on Multiscale Features Fusion and Context Information. IEEE J. Sel. Top. Appl. Earth Obs. Remote Sens. 2024;17:19743&#x2013;19755. doi: 10.1109/JSTARS.2024.3474689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSTARS.2024.3474689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge Q., Da W., Wang M. MARFPNet: Multiattention and Adaptive Reparameterized Feature Pyramid Network for Small Target Detection on Water Surfaces. IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas. 2024;73:5039617. doi: 10.1109/TIM.2024.3485463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2024.3485463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battish N., Kaur D., Chugh M., Poddar S. SDMNet: Spatially dilated multi-scale network for object detection for drone aerial imagery. Image Vis. Comput. 2024;150:105232. doi: 10.1016/j.imavis.2024.105232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.imavis.2024.105232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Q., Li Y., Deveci M., Zhong K., Kadry S. LUD-YOLO: A novel lightweight object detection network for unmanned aerial vehicle. Inf. Sci. 2025;686:121366. doi: 10.1016/j.ins.2024.121366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ins.2024.121366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge X., Qi L., Yan Q., Sun J., Zhu Y., Zhang Y. Enhancing Real-Time Aerial Image Object Detection with High-Frequency Feature Learning and Context-Aware Fusion. Remote Sens. 2025;17:1994. doi: 10.3390/rs17121994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs17121994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao M., Peng C., Yun L., Zhang C., Wang H., Chen Z. A lightweight small object detection model for UAV images based on deep semantic integration. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:31888. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-16878-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-16878-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12397394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40883434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>