<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41731443</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6874</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC women's health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Womens Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of concurrent training on body composition, metabolic, and inflammatory in postmenopausal women: a meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">186</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12905-026-04359-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To evaluate the effects of concurrent training (CT) on body composition, metabolic health, and inflammatory outcomes in postmenopausal middle-aged and older women, and to examine whether training experience, exercise order, and training dose moderate these effects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This review followed PRISMA 2020. Web of Science, PubMed, Scopus, and the Cochrane Library were searched for randomized controlled and randomized crossover trials last searched on July 1, 2025. Effect sizes (Hedges&#x2019; g) were synthesized using multilevel mixed-effects models (REML) with robust variance estimation to account for within-study dependence. Subgroup analyses and meta-regression explored potential moderators, and certainty of evidence was assessed using GRADE.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Twenty-three studies (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;1001) involving naturally postmenopausal women were included. CT significantly improved body composition (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;&#x2212;&#x2009;0.11, 95% CI [&#x2212;&#x2009;0.20, &#x2212;&#x2009;0.02], <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.02) and metabolic health (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;&#x2212;&#x2009;0.22, 95% CI [&#x2212;&#x2009;0.40, &#x2212;&#x2009;0.04], <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.02), with moderate-certainty evidence for both outcomes. The pooled effect on inflammatory markers was not statistically significant (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.39; low-certainty evidence). No significant moderators were identified, and meta-regression showed no significant dose&#x2013;response relationship for training volume or intervention duration. Subgroup analyses suggested reductions in body fat percentage and increases in lean mass, alongside small-to-moderate improvements in blood pressure, blood glucose, triglycerides, and maximal oxygen uptake. Biomarker-specific analyses suggested changes in IL-10, IL-6, and TNF-&#x3b1; (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), but these findings were based on limited data and were low certainty. Exploratory within-group analyses indicated significant effects in sedentary participants and in studies prescribing resistance training before endurance training or three sessions per week.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">CT may be associated with small improvements in body composition and modest improvements in metabolic health in postmenopausal women. Given the small pooled effect sizes and the lack of MCID-based interpretation, the clinical relevance of these changes remains uncertain. Because moderator analyses were non-significant, subgroup patterns should be considered hypothesis-generating. Larger, adequately powered trials with standardized reporting are needed to clarify clinically meaningful effects and potential effect modifiers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="GRAPHICAL ABSTRACT">[Image: see text]</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12905-026-04359-5.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chenghao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-8907-4218</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Exercise, Tianjin University of Sport, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zhenyu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-2174-5633</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education, Tianjin University of Sport, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yilin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Exercise, Tianjin University of Sport, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kong</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Exercise, Tianjin University of Sport, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Enran</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology and Health, Capital University of Physical Education And Sports, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-1960-671X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Exercise, Tianjin University of Sport, Tianjin, China. xieyun@tjus.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Womens Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088690</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6874</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="eng"><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">1.Body Composition: CT improved body composition by reducing body fat and increasing lean mass. 2. Metabolic Health: CT enhanced metabolic markers, lowering blood pressure, glucose, triglycerides, and improving VO&#x2082;max. 3. Inflammation: Overall inflammatory markers showed no significant change, but CT affected cytokines such as IL-10, IL-6, and TNF-&#x3b1;. 4. Moderating Factors: Within-group (exploratory) analyses suggested that sedentary postmenopausal women, resistance-before-aerobic sequencing, and three sessions/week may be associated with greater improvements in body composition and metabolic outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12905-026-04359-5.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Concurrent training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolic health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postmenopausal women</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41731443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13037181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-026-04359-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12905-026-04359-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nelson HD, Menopause. Lancet. 2008;371:760&#x2013;70. 10.1016/S0140-6736(08)60346-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(08)60346-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18313505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKinlay SM. The normal menopause transition: an overview. Maturitas. 1996;23:137&#x2013;45. 10.1016/0378-5122(95)00985-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0378-5122(95)00985-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8735352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaber M, Wilson AS, Millen AE, Hovey KM, LaMonte MJ, Wactawski-Wende J, et al. Visceral adiposity in postmenopausal women is associated with a pro-inflammatory gut microbiome and immunogenic metabolic endotoxemia. Microbiome. 2024;12:192. 10.1186/s40168-024-01901-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40168-024-01901-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11453046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39367431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samargandy S, Matthews KA, Brooks MM, Barinas-Mitchell E, Magnani JW, Janssen I, et al. Abdominal Visceral Adipose Tissue Over the Menopause Transition and Carotid Atherosclerosis: The SWAN Heart Study. Menopause N Y N. 2021;28:626&#x2013;33. 10.1097/GME.0000000000001755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/GME.0000000000001755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8141004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33651741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abildgaard J, Ploug T, Al-Saoudi E, Wagner T, Thomsen C, Ewertsen C, et al. Changes in abdominal subcutaneous adipose tissue phenotype following menopause is associated with increased visceral fat mass. Sci Rep. 2021;11:14750. 10.1038/s41598-021-94189-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-94189-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8292317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34285301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi Y-J, Kim GS, Chu SH, Lee KH, Park CG, Sohn M. Metabolic syndrome clustering patterns and the association with cardiovascular disease among post-menopausal Korean women. Sci Rep. 2024;14:22702. 10.1038/s41598-024-72403-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-72403-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11442489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39349570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty S, Suvarna R, Bhattacharya S, Seetharaman K. Visceral Adiposity and Cardiometabolic Risk: Clinical Insights and Assessment. Cardiol Rev. 10.1097/CRD.0000000000000984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40622164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou Y-J, Lee J-I, Huang S-P, Chen S-C, Geng J-H, Su C-H. Association between Menopause, Postmenopausal Hormone Therapy and Metabolic Syndrome. J Clin Med. 2023;12:4435. 10.3390/jcm12134435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12134435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10342857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37445470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman V, Kose V, Somalwar S, Dwidmuthe KS, Rao S. Prevalence of Metabolic Syndrome and Its Association With Menopausal Symptoms in Post-Menopausal Women: A Scoping Review. Cureus 15:e39069. 10.7759/cureus.39069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10267665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37323357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Khoudary SR, Aggarwal B, Beckie TM, Hodis HN, Johnson AE, Langer RD, et al. Menopause Transition and Cardiovascular Disease Risk: Implications for Timing of Early Prevention: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2020;142:e506&#x2013;32. 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33251828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson T, Karlsson T, Bliuc D, Schmitz D, Ek WE, Skalkidou A et al. Contemporary menopausal hormone therapy and risk of cardiovascular disease: Swedish nationwide register based emulated target trial. 2024. 10.1136/bmj-2023-078784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11600536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39603704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu F, Yang J, Liu Y, Zhang Y. Extremely High Systemic Immune Inflammation Levels Increase the Risk of All-Cause and Cardiovascular Mortality in Postmenopausal Women. Int J Womens Health. 2025;17:1457&#x2013;68. 10.2147/IJWH.S504664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJWH.S504664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12103204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40417642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Khoudary SR, Chen X, Qi M, Matthews KA, Karlamangla AS, Gold EB, et al. The Relation Between Systemic Inflammation and the Menopause Transition: The Study of Women&#x2019;s Health Across the Nation. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2025;dgaf175. 10.1210/clinem/dgaf175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12527447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40123296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An S-M, Cho S-H, Yoon JC. Adipose Tissue and Metabolic Health. Diabetes Metab J. 2023;47:595&#x2013;611. 10.4093/dmj.2023.0011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4093/dmj.2023.0011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10555533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37482656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawai T, Autieri MV, Scalia R. Adipose tissue inflammation and metabolic dysfunction in obesity. Am J Physiol - Cell Physiol. 2021;320:C375&#x2013;91. 10.1152/ajpcell.00379.2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00379.2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8294624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33356944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickson RC. Interference of strength development by simultaneously training for strength and endurance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1980;45:255&#x2013;63. 10.1007/BF00421333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00421333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7193134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAvoy CR, Batrakoulis A, Camhi SM, Sansone J (Sudock), Stanfield JT, Reed R, editors. 2026 ACSM Worldwide Fitness Trends: Future Directions of the Health and Fitness Industry: ERRATUM. ACSMs Health Fit J. 2026;30:64. 10.1249/FIT.0000000000001130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiorana A, O&#x2019;Driscoll G, Cheetham C, Collis J, Goodman C, Rankin S, et al. Combined aerobic and resistance exercise training improves functional capacity and strength in CHF. J Appl Physiol Bethesda Md 1985. 2000;88:1565&#x2013;70. 10.1152/jappl.2000.88.5.1565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2000.88.5.1565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10797113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, Borodulin K, Buman MP, Cardon G, et al. World Health Organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:1451&#x2013;62. 10.1136/bjsports-2020-102955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-102955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AL-Mhanna SB, Alghannam AF, Alkhamees NH, Sheeha BB, Omar N, Albalawi H, et al. Impact of concurrent aerobic and resistance training on body composition, lipid metabolism and physical function in patients with type 2 diabetes and overweight/obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PeerJ. 2025;13:e19537. 10.7717/peerj.19537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.19537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12166852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40520633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalafi M, Fatolahi S, Symonds ME, Dinizadeh F, Rosenkranz SK, Batrakoulis A. Comparative Efficacy of Exercise Type on Visceral Adipose Tissue in Patients With Prediabetes and Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus: A Systematic Review With Pairwise and Network Meta-Analyses. Obes Rev. 2025;e70031. 10.1111/obr.70031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41062106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A, Jamurtas AZ, Metsios GS, Perivoliotis K, Liguori G, Feito Y, et al. Comparative Efficacy of 5 Exercise Types on Cardiometabolic Health in Overweight and Obese Adults: A Systematic Review and Network Meta-Analysis of 81 Randomized Controlled Trials. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2022;15:e008243. 10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.121.008243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.121.008243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35477256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenti VE, Chagas ADS, Chedraui P, de Souza IS, Porto AA, Sorpreso ICE, et al. Effect of combined aerobic exercise and resistance training on postmenopausal women with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Gynecol Endocrinol Off J Int Soc Gynecol Endocrinol. 2025;41:2450338. 10.1080/09513590.2025.2450338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09513590.2025.2450338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39797630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AL-Mhanna SB, Batrakoulis A, Ghazali WSW, Mohamed M, Aldayel A, Alhussain MH, et al. Effects of combined aerobic and resistance training on glycemic control, blood pressure, inflammation, cardiorespiratory fitness and quality of life in patients with type 2 diabetes and overweight/obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PeerJ. 2024;12:e17525. 10.7717/peerj.17525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.17525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11182026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38887616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovejoy JC, Champagne CM, de Jonge L, Xie H, Smith SR. Increased visceral fat and decreased energy expenditure during the menopausal transition. Int J Obes 2005. 2008;32:949&#x2013;58. 10.1038/ijo.2008.25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ijo.2008.25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2748330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18332882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsh ML, Oliveira MN, Vieira-Potter VJ. Adipocyte Metabolism and Health after the Menopause: The Role of Exercise. Nutrients. 2023;15:444. 10.3390/nu15020444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15020444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9862030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36678314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pernoud LE, Gardiner PA, Fraser SD, Dillon-Rossiter K, Dean MM, Schaumberg MA. A systematic review and meta-analysis investigating differences in chronic inflammation and adiposity before and after menopause. Maturitas. 2024;190:108119. 10.1016/j.maturitas.2024.108119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2024.108119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39332331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebong IA, Schreiner P, Lewis CE, Appiah D, Ghelani A, Wellons M. The association between high sensitivity C-reactive protein and hypertension in women of the CARDIA study. Menopause N Y N. 2016;23:662&#x2013;8. 10.1097/GME.0000000000000609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/GME.0000000000000609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4874866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27093616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedenreich CM, Neilson HK, Woolcott CG, Wang Q, Stanczyk FZ, McTiernan A, et al. Inflammatory marker changes in a yearlong randomized exercise intervention trial among postmenopausal women. Cancer Prev Res Phila Pa. 2012;5:98&#x2013;108. 10.1158/1940-6207.CAPR-11-0369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1940-6207.CAPR-11-0369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21982875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markov A, Hauser L, Chaabene H. Effects of Concurrent Strength and Endurance Training on Measures of Physical Fitness in Healthy Middle-Aged and Older Adults: A Systematic Review with Meta-Analysis. Sports Med Auckl Nz. 2023;53:437&#x2013;55. 10.1007/s40279-022-01764-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01764-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9876872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36222981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Higgins JPT. RoB 2: A revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ Clin Res. 2019;366:l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Green S. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Wiley-Blackwell; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huiberts RO, W&#xfc;st RCI, van der Zwaard S. Concurrent Strength and Endurance Training: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis on the Impact of Sex and Training Status. Sports Med. 2024;54:485&#x2013;503. 10.1007/s40279-023-01943-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01943-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10933151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37847373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng Y, Wu X, Zhang Y, Zhang M. Potential Moderators of the Effects of Blood Flow Restriction Training on Muscle Strength and Hypertrophy: A Meta-analysis Based on a Comparison with High-Load Resistance Training. Sports Med - Open. 2024;10:58. 10.1186/s40798-024-00719-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-024-00719-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11109065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38773002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, Martin DT, Mujika I, Goosey-Tolfrey VL et al. Defining Training and Performance Caliber: A Participant Classification Framework. 2021. 10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34965513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Gong Y, Yin M, Zhang L, Wu X. Optimal dosage of group-based organized physical activity for enhancing social abilities in autistic children: insights from a multilevel meta-analysis. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2025;22:87. 10.1186/s12966-025-01787-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12966-025-01787-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12210644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40597379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung WL. A Guide to Conducting a Meta-Analysis with Non-Independent Effect Sizes. Neuropsychol Rev. 2019;29(4):387&#x2013;96. 10.1007/s11065-019-09415-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6892772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31446547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges LV, Tipton E, Johnson MC. Robust variance estimation in meta-regression with dependent effect size estimates. Res Synth Methods. 2010;1(1):39&#x2013;65. 10.1002/jrsm.5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26056092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Noortgate W, L&#xf3;pez-L&#xf3;pez JA, Mar&#xed;n-Mart&#xed;nez F, S&#xe1;nchez-Meca J. Three-level meta-analysis of dependent effect sizes. Behav Res Methods. 2013;45:576&#x2013;94. 10.3758/s13428-012-0261-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/s13428-012-0261-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23055166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic I, Castilla AP, Ramos AG, Van Hooren B, McGuigan MR, Helms ER. The Acute and Chronic Effects of Implementing Velocity Loss Thresholds During Resistance Training: A Systematic Review, Meta-Analysis, and Critical Evaluation of the Literature. Sports Med. 2023;53:177&#x2013;214. 10.1007/s40279-022-01754-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01754-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9807551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36178597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nash JC, Varadhan R. Unifying Optimization Algorithms to Aid Software System Users: optimx for R. J Stat Softw. 2011;43:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v043.i09</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hooren B, Jukic I, Cox M, Frenken KG, Bautista I, Moore IS. The Relationship Between Running Biomechanics and Running Economy: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Observational Studies. Sports Med. 2024;54:1269&#x2013;316. 10.1007/s40279-024-01997-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-01997-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11127892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38446400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt G, Oxman AD, Akl EA, Kunz R, Vist G, Brozek J, et al. GRADE guidelines: 1. Introduction-GRADE evidence profiles and summary of findings tables. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64:383&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.04.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21195583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santesso N, Carrasco-Labra A, Langendam M, Brignardello-Petersen R, Holger J, Sch&#xfc;nemann. Improving GRADE evidence tables part 3: detailed guidance for explanatory footnotes supports creating and understanding GRADE certainty in the evidence judgments. J Clin Epidemiol. 2016;74:28&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2015.12.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26796947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalafi M, Habibi Maleki A, Sakhaei MH, Rosenkranz SK, Pourvaghar MJ, Ehsanifar M, et al. The effects of exercise training on body composition in postmenopausal women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Endocrinol. 2023;14:1183765. 10.3389/fendo.2023.1183765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2023.1183765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10306117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37388207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willis LH, Slentz CA, Bateman LA, Shields AT, Piner LW, Bales CW, et al. Effects of aerobic and/or resistance training on body mass and fat mass in overweight or obese adults. J Appl Physiol. 2012;113:1831&#x2013;7. 10.1152/japplphysiol.01370.2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01370.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3544497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23019316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes PRP, Castro-e-Souza P, De Oliveira AA, Camilo BDF, Cristina-Souza G, Vieira-Souza LM, et al. Effect of resistance training volume on body adiposity, metabolic risk, and inflammation in postmenopausal and older females: Systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Sport Health Sci. 2024;13:145&#x2013;59. 10.1016/j.jshs.2023.09.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2023.09.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10980902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37788790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalafi M, Kheradmand S, Habibi Maleki A, Symonds ME, Rosenkranz SK, Batrakoulis A. The Effects of Concurrent Training Versus Aerobic or Resistance Training Alone on Body Composition in Middle-Aged and Older Adults: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Healthcare. 2025;13:776. 10.3390/healthcare13070776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare13070776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11989159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40218073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reznick RM, Shulman GI. The role of AMP-activated protein kinase in mitochondrial biogenesis. J Physiol. 2006;574:33&#x2013;9. 10.1113/jphysiol.2006.109512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2006.109512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1817787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16709637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Jensen TE, Goodman CA, Hornberger TA. Resistance Exercise-Induced Hypertrophy: A Potential Role for Rapamycin-Insensitive mTOR. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2019;47:188&#x2013;94. 10.1249/JES.0000000000000189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JES.0000000000000189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6659995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30870215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna SB, Franklin BA, Tarnopolsky MA, Hawley JA, Jakicic JM, Stamatakis E, et al. Impact of high-intensity interval training on cardiometabolic health in patients with diabesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2025;17:406. 10.1186/s13098-025-01974-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13098-025-01974-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12553184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41137077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna SB, Poon ET-C, Franklin BA, Tarnopolsky MA, Hawley JA, Jakicic JM, et al. Comparative effectiveness of high-intensity interval training and moderate-intensity continuous training on cardiometabolic health in patients with diabesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2025;17:331. 10.1186/s13098-025-01909-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13098-025-01909-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12344893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40804647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna SB, Franklin BA, Jakicic JM, Stamatakis E, Pescatello LS, Riebe D, et al. Impact of aerobic exercise on cardiometabolic health in patients with diabesity: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Diabetes Complications. 2025;39:109203. 10.1016/j.jdiacomp.2025.109203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdiacomp.2025.109203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41135244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna SB, Franklin BA, Jakicic JM, Stamatakis E, Pescatello LS, Riebe D, et al. Impact of resistance training on cardiometabolic health-related indices in patients with type 2 diabetes and overweight/obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Br J Sports Med. 2025;59:733&#x2013;46. 10.1136/bjsports-2024-108947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2024-108947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39773835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loaiza-Betancur A, Chulvi-Medrano I, D&#xed;az-L&#xf3;pez V, G&#xf3;mez-Tom&#xe1;s C. The effect of exercise training on blood pressure in menopause and postmenopausal women: A systematic review of randomized controlled trials. MATURITAS. 2021;149:40&#x2013;55. 10.1016/j.maturitas.2021.05.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2021.05.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34108092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalafi M, Sakhaei MH, Habibi Maleki A, Rosenkranz SK, Pourvaghar MJ, Fang Y, et al. Influence of exercise type and duration on cardiorespiratory fitness and muscular strength in post-menopausal women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2023;10:1190187. 10.3389/fcvm.2023.1190187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2023.1190187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10204927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37229231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xi H, He Y, Niu Y, Sui X, Zhang J, Zhu R, et al. Effect of combined aerobic and resistance exercise on blood pressure in postmenopausal women: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Exp Gerontol. 2021;155:111560. 10.1016/j.exger.2021.111560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2021.111560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34560198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundby C, Montero D, Joyner M. Biology of VO2 max: looking under the physiology lamp. Acta Physiol Oxf Engl. 2017;220:218&#x2013;28. 10.1111/apha.12827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apha.12827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27888580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez MW, Kim JH, Shah AB, Phelan D, Emery MS, Wasfy MM, et al. Exercise-Induced Cardiovascular Adaptations and Approach to Exercise and Cardiovascular Disease. JACC. 2021;78:1453&#x2013;70. 10.1016/j.jacc.2021.08.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2021.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34593128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva RSN da, Silva DS da, Oliveira PC de, Waclawovsky G, Schaun MI. Effects of aerobic, resistance and combined training on endothelial function and arterial stiffness in older adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2024;19:e0308600. 10.1371/journal.pone.0308600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0308600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11611152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39621701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bueno-Notivol J, Calvo-Latorre J, Alonso-Ventura V, Pasupuleti V, Hernandez AV, P&#xe9;rez-L&#xf3;pez FR, et al. Effect of programmed exercise on insulin sensitivity in postmenopausal women: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Menopause N Y N. 2017;24:1404&#x2013;13. 10.1097/GME.0000000000000936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/GME.0000000000000936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28654627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva FM, Duarte-Mendes P, Teixeira AM, Soares CM, Ferreira JP. The effects of combined exercise training on glucose metabolism and inflammatory markers in sedentary adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2024;14:1936. 10.1038/s41598-024-51832-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-51832-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10803738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38253590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuff DJ, Meneilly GS, Martin A, Ignaszewski A, Tildesley HD, Frohlich JJ. Effective Exercise Modality to Reduce Insulin Resistance in Women With Type 2 Diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2003;26:2977&#x2013;82. 10.2337/diacare.26.11.2977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diacare.26.11.2977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14578226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell WL. The influence of exercise on the concentrations of triglyceride and cholesterol in human plasma. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 1984;12:205&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00003677-198401000-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6376133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Xu D. Effects of aerobic exercise on lipids and lipoproteins. Lipids Health Dis. 2017;16:132. 10.1186/s12944-017-0515-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12944-017-0515-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5498979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28679436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao J, Hu M, Imm K, Holmes CJ, Zhu J, Cao C, et al. Association of daily sitting time and leisure-time physical activity with body fat among U.S. adults. J Sport Health Sci. 2024;13:195&#x2013;203. 10.1016/j.jshs.2022.10.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2022.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10980870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36240998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SR, Hawley JA. Update on the effects of physical activity on insulin sensitivity in humans. BMJ Open Sport &#x2014; Exerc Med. 2017;2:e000143. 10.1136/bmjsem-2016-000143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2016-000143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5569266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28879026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kullmann S, Goj T, Veit R, Fritsche L, Wagner L, Schneeweiss P, et al. Exercise restores brain insulin sensitivity in sedentary adults who are overweight and obese. JCI Insight. 2022;7. 10.1172/jci.insight.161498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9675563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36134657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan K, Dai Z, Wong P, Huang WY, Lei EF, Little JP, et al. Effects of Exercise Snacks on Cardiometabolic Health and Body Composition in Adults: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2025;35:e70114. 10.1111/sms.70114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.70114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12354995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40814152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Ishii N, Sugihara S, Yoshioka T, Takamatsu K. Effects of resistance exercise on lipolysis during subsequent submaximal exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:308&#x2013;15. 10.1249/01.mss.0000246992.33482.cb.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000246992.33482.cb</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17277595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley JA, Burke LM. Carbohydrate Availability and Training Adaptation: Effects on Cell Metabolism. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2010;38:152. 10.1097/JES.0b013e3181f44dd9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JES.0b013e3181f44dd9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20871231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Andersen JL, Magnusson P, Dyhre-Poulsen P. Increased rate of force development and neural drive of human skeletal muscle following resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2002;93:1318&#x2013;26. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00283.2002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00283.2002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12235031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter EA, Hargreaves M, Exercise. GLUT4, and Skeletal Muscle Glucose Uptake. Physiol Rev. 2013;93:993&#x2013;1017. 10.1152/physrev.00038.2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00038.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23899560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Izquierdo M, Alberton CL, Pinto RS, Concei??O M, Cunha G, et al. Strength prior to endurance intra-session exercise sequence optimizes neuromuscular and cardiovascular gains in elderly men. Exp Gerontol. 2012;47:164&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2011.11.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22178632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Izquierdo M, Pinto SS, Alberton CL, Pinto RS, Baroni BM, et al. Neuromuscular adaptations to concurrent training in the elderly: effects of intrasession exercise sequence. Age Dordr Neth. 2013;35:891&#x2013;903. 10.1007/s11357-012-9405-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11357-012-9405-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3636398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22453934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Button KS, Ioannidis JPA, Mokrysz C, Nosek BA, Flint J, Robinson ESJ, et al. Power failure: why small sample size undermines the reliability of neuroscience. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2013;14:365&#x2013;76. 10.1038/nrn3475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrn3475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23571845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon YK, Kim SS, Kim JH, Kim HJ, Kim HJ, Park JJ, et al. Combined Aerobic and Resistance Exercise Training Reduces Circulating Apolipoprotein J Levels and Improves Insulin Resistance in Postmenopausal Diabetic Women. Diabetes Metab J. 2020;44:103&#x2013;12. 10.4093/dmj.2018.0160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4093/dmj.2018.0160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7043986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32097999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Gemert WA, Monninkhof EM, May AM, Peeters PH, Schuit AJ. Effect of Exercise on Insulin Sensitivity in Healthy Postmenopausal Women: The SHAPE Study. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2015;24:81&#x2013;7. 10.1158/1055-9965.EPI-14-0722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1055-9965.EPI-14-0722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25342388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Magalh&#xe3;es ACL, Carvalho VF, da Cruz SP, Ramalho A. Dose&#x2013;Response Relationship of Resistance Training on Metabolic Phenotypes, Body Composition and Lipid Profile in Menopausal Women. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:10369. 10.3390/ijerph191610369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph191610369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9408617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36012004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doma K, Bede Deakin G. The Effects of Combined Strength and Endurance Training on Running Performance the Following Day. Int J Sport Health Sci. 2013;11:1&#x2013;9. 10.5432/ijshs.201230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5432/ijshs.201230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taipale RS, Forssell J, Ihalainen JK, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H, H&#xe4;kkinen K. A 10-Week Block of Combined High-Intensity Endurance and Strength Training Produced Similar Changes in Dynamic Strength, Body Composition, and Serum Hormones in Women and Men. Front Sports Act Living. 2020;2. 10.3389/fspor.2020.581305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33345149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taipale RS, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Acute Hormonal and Force Responses to Combined Strength and Endurance Loadings in Men and Women: The Order Effect. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e55051. 10.1371/journal.pone.0055051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0055051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3567118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23408956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies RW, Carson BP, Jakeman PM. Sex Differences in the Temporal Recovery of Neuromuscular Function Following Resistance Training in Resistance Trained Men and Women 18 to 35 Years. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1480. 10.3389/fphys.2018.01480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2018.01480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6206044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30405436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leveritt M, Abernethy PJ, Barry BK, Logan PA. Concurrent Strength and Endurance Training. Sports Med. 1999;28:413&#x2013;27. 10.2165/00007256-199928060-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199928060-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10623984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>