<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41606507</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2334</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC infectious diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Delay antiretroviral therapy initiation and factors affecting it among patients on antiretroviral treatment at North Shewa zone public health facilities, Amhara region, Ethiopia, 2024: a mixed method approach.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">413</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12879-026-12715-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Although the beginning of antiretroviral therapy shortly after HIV infection results in better outcomes compared to waiting until symptoms appear, globally, there is a research gap in this area. Specifically, in Ethiopia, where the burden of the disease is high, little is known about the timing of the initiation, and previous studies assessed the area either qualitatively or quantitatively only. Therefore, this study aimed to assess the factors that affect the timely initiation of ART by employing a mix of both qualitative and quantitative methods in the North Shewa Zone of the Amhara region in Ethiopia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A concurrent mixed method was used to gather information about antiretroviral therapy initiators in health facilities under the North Shewa zonal health department from February to April 2024. A total of 596 patients were selected using a multistage random sampling method for the quantitative study, while 28 participants were selected for the qualitative study using purposive sampling. The quantitative data were collected using structured data collection forms, and interview guides supported by an audio recorder were used for qualitative data. The quantitative part was uploaded to the Kobo toolbox for collection. Bivariable and multivariable logistic regression analyses were used to determine the relationships between the independent and dependent variables. The quantitative data were analyzed using Stata version 16.0 software, while the qualitative data were analyzed thematically by OpenCode version 4.03 software. The P-value of less than 0.05 was declared statistically significant. The qualitative data were analyzed thematically.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT">The prevalence of delayed ART initiation was 22% (95% CI, 18.99&#x2013;25.67%). Individuals who had ambulatory functional status (AOR 2.65, 95% CI 1.18&#x2013;5.97), clients who took prophylaxis for opportunistic infection (AOR 5.77, 95% CI 2.16&#x2013;15.41), prior opportunistic infection (AOR 3.93, 95% CI 1.89&#x2013;8.16) and disclosure status (AOR 0.46, 95% CI 0.26&#x2013;0.82) were significantly associated with delay ART initiation. Moreover, the qualitative findings revealed clinical, client, and provider/facility-related challenges.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The study highlights a high prevalence of delayed antiretroviral therapy initiation compared to the WHO test and treat target, with factors result disclosure status, functional status, baseline OI prophylaxis, and OI development. Therefore, client counseling should focus on disclosure, ensuring HIV-positive linkage to ART, and provision of OI prophylaxis and treatment as per the updated guidelines.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL">Not applicable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12879-026-12715-x.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mersha</LastName><ForeName>Melaku Walie</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HIV/AIDS Prevention, Control, and Treatment, Debre Berhan Comprehensive Specialized Hospital (in Collaboration with CDC), Debre Berhan, Ethiopia. melakuwalelign25@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gebreegziabher</LastName><ForeName>Zenebe Abebe</ForeName><Initials>ZA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, Asrat Woldeyes Health Science Campus, Debre Berhan University, Debre Berhan, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bilchut</LastName><ForeName>Awraris Hailu</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Asrat Woldeyes Health Campus, Debre Berhan University, Debre Berhan, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2334</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antiretroviral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Delay initiation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Human immunodeficiency virus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval was obtained from the Institutional Review Board (IRB) of Debre Berhan University AWHSC School of Public Health Ethical Committee (Ref. No: IRB 01/60/2016). A formal permission letter was obtained from the administrative bodies of each selected health facility to access the records of the study participants. Informed consent from patients was obtained only for those who participated in the qualitative interview since quantitative information was gathered retrospectively from their medical records. To ensure confidentiality, the identities of all participants were kept anonymous, and all data collected was treated with strict confidentiality. The research was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41606507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12924364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-026-12715-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12879-026-12715-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ethiopian ministry of health. National Comprehensive HIV Prevention, care and treatment participant manual. Antiretroviral therapy. Ethiopia2022. p. 216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World health organization. HIV and AIDS key facts 2022 [updated 13 July 2023. Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/hiv-aids</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World health organization. Consolidated guidelines on HIV prevention, testing, treatment, service delivery and monitoring. Antiretroviral therapy2021. p. 592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34370423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Program on HIV/AIDS, Global HIV. &amp; AIDS statistics &#x2014; fact sheet 2022 [updated 31 Aug 2023. Available from: https://www.unaids.org/en/resources/fact-sheet</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethiopian ministry of health. HIV/AIDS national strategic plan for. Ethiopia 2021&#x2013;2025. Federal HIV/AIDS Prevention and Control Office (FHAPCO); 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for disease control. CDC Impact in Ethiopia 2022 [Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/globalhealth/countries/ethiopia/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Program on HIV/AIDS. HIV and AIDS Estimates 2022 [Available from: https://www.unaids.org/en/regionscountries/countries/ethiopia</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Presidence emergency plan for AIDS relief (PEPFAR) and, Global AIDS. 2022 July 20, 2023. [cited 2023]. Available from: https://www.hiv.gov/federal-response/pepfar-global-aids/global-hiv-aids-overview/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS. HIV treatment [Available from: https://www.unaids.org/en/topic/treatment#:~:text=Current%20World%20Health%20Organization%20recommended%20standard%20first-line%20antiretroviral,inhibitor.%20Fixed-dose%20combinations%20and%20once-daily%20regimens%20are%20preferred</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12349391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World health organization. Guidelines for managing advanced hiv disease and rapid initiation of antiretroviral therapy. World Health Organization. 2017 July 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29341560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS. 90-90-90: Treatment for all. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>New York State Department of Health AIDS Institute (NYSDOH AI), Rapid. ART Initiation 2023 [updated january, 27 2020. Available from: https://www.hivguidelines.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/NYSDOH-AI-Rapid-ART-Initiation_10-5-2023_HG.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Susa Coffey M, AETC National Coordinating Resource Center, Center for UCSF, Information HIV, Bacon O, MPH M. Immediate ART Initiation &amp; Restart: Guide for Clinicians 2021 [Available from: https://aidsetc.org/sites/default/files/resources_files/ncrc-rapid-art-6-10-21_0.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panel on Antiretroviral Guidelines for Adults and Adolescents. Guidelines for the Use of Antiretroviral Agents in Adults and Adolescents with HIV. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moges NA, Adesina OA, Okunlola MA, Berhane Y. Barriers and facilitators of same-day antiretroviral therapy initiation among people newly diagnosed with HIV in Ethiopia: qualitative study using the transtheoretical model of behavioral change. J Multidisciplinary Healthc. 2020:1801&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33293823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayisa L, Tadesse A, Reta MM, Gebeye E. Prevalence and factors associated with delayed initiation of antiretroviral therapy among people living with HIV in Nekemte Referral Hospital, Western Ethiopia. HIV/AIDS-Research and Palliative Care. 2020:457&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7522430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33061657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bantie B, Kassaw Yirga G, Abate MW, Amare AT, Nigat AB, Tigabu A, et al. Delayed ART initiation in test and treat era and its associated factors among adults receiving antiretroviral therapy at public health institutions in Northwest ethiopia: A multicenter cross-sectional study. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(7):e0271127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0271127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9312408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35877661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moges NA, Adesina OA, Okunlola MA, Berhane Y. Same-day antiretroviral treatment (ART) initiation and associated factors among HIV positive people in Northwest ethiopia: baseline characteristics of prospective cohort. Archives Public Health. 2020;78(1):1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13690-020-00473-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7510057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32983450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayisa L, Abera T, Mulisa D, Mosisa G, Mosisa A, Tolosa T et al. Time to Antiretroviral Therapy Initiation and Its Predictors Among Newly Diagnosed HIV-Positive People in Nekemte Town, Western Ethiopia: Claim of Universal Test and Treat. HIV/AIDS-Research and Palliative Care. 2021:959&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8519411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34675687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiyingi M, Nankabirwa JI, Wiltshire CS, Nangendo J, Kiweewa JM, Katahoire AR, et al. Perspectives of people living with HIV on barriers to timely ART initiation following referral for antiretroviral therapy: a qualitative study at an urban HIV clinic in Kampala, Uganda. PLOS Global Public Health. 2023;3(7):e0001483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0001483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10370709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37494338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debre Berhan town health department. Annual woreda based plan. In: Health, editor. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>North Shewa zonal health department. Annual woreda based plan. In: Health, editor. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AncaVitcu EL, Vitcu L, Marcu A. Multi-stage maximum variation sampling in health promotion programs&#x2019; evaluation. J Prev Med. 2007;15(14):5&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethiopian ministry of health. HIV Care/ ART clinic Intake form- A. In: health, editor. 2014. p. 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethiopian ministry of health. HIV Care/ART followup form. In: health, editor.; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon L, Young D, Pardoe I. 10.7&#x2014;detecting multicollinearity using variance inflation factors. STAT. 2018;462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montebatsi M, Lavoie M-CC, Blanco N, Marima R, Sebina K, Mangope J, et al. Improving same-day antiretroviral therapy in botswana: effects of a multifaceted National intervention. AIDS. 2022;36(4):533&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/QAD.0000000000003139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34873088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Li Y, Xiao X, Qian H-Z, Wang H. Perceptions toward antiretroviral therapy and delayed ART initiation among people living with HIV in Changsha, china: mediating effects of treatment willingness. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1105208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2023.1105208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10294673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37383264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nembot FD, Wirsiy FS, Tshimwanga EK, Nkfusai CN, Eveline MK, Esa I et al. Time to Antiretroviral Treatment Initiation and Factors associated to Same Day Initiation in the West Region of Cameroon. mortality.8:9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mi T, Li X, Zhou G, Qiao S, Shen Z, Zhou Y. HIV disclosure to family members and medication adherence: role of social support and self-efficacy. AIDS Behav. 2020;24:45&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10461-019-02456-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30863978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Li X, Qiao S, Yang X, Zhou Y, Shen Z. Perceived benefits and costs of disclosing HIV diagnosis to family members among people living with HIV in Southern china: an application of a decision-making framework. AIDS Care. 2021;33(3):403&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09540121.2020.1728217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7431366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32070115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ssali SN, Atuyambe L, Tumwine C, Segujja E, Nekesa N, Nannungi A, et al. Reasons for disclosure of HIV status by people living with HIV/AIDS and in HIV care in uganda: an exploratory study. AIDS Patient Care STDs. 2010;24(10):675&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/apc.2010.0062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3826576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20863244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>