<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41647682</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2169-7574</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Plastic and reconstructive surgery. Global open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rehabilitation Approach for Relative Motion Flexion Orthoses After Flexor Digitorum Profundus Zone I-II Repair: A Prospective Case Series.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e7464</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e7464</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e7464</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/GOX.0000000000007464</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Relative motion flexion orthoses (RMFOs) are a type of early mobilization based on the "quadriga effect." Currently, there are few published clinical outcome data and no documented treatment protocols. This study aimed to standardize our a rehabilitation protocol for early mobilization with relative motion for flexor tendon injuries within a 9-week program.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A prospective study was conducted from April 2023 to June 2024, which included all patients who had undergone relative motion orthoses and rehabilitation for flexor digitorum profundus repair in zone I or II. The exclusion criteria were as follows: age younger than 18 years, more than 3 injured fingers, and lack of adherence, associated fracture, and surgical repair for more than 10 days. Final measurements at weeks 8 and 12 included total active motion; Strickland and Glogovac formula; Quick Disability of the Arm, Shoulder, and Hand questionnaire; grip strength (Jamar); and pain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Ten patients underwent the RMFO protocol between April 2023 and June 2024, with at least 3 months of follow-up. Two patients were excluded from the study; the remaining patients (8) showed improvements in range of motion; Disabilities of the Arm, Shoulder, and Hand; Jamar; and visual analog scale scores. No complications such as proximal interphalangeal joint contracture, tenolysis, or rupture were reported. All patients returned to work by week 10.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In this small prospective case report of RMFOs, we continue to increase the number of patients in the literature, and our results are compared with those of previous studies. In addition, we present our step-by-step approach to a 9-week program.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of The American Society of Plastic Surgeons.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagliaro</LastName><ForeName>Rossella</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the University Department of Hand Surgery &amp; Rehabilitation, San Giuseppe Hospital, IRCCS MultiMedica Group, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Occupational Therapy, Milan University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pajardi</LastName><ForeName>Giorgio Eugenio</ForeName><Initials>GE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the University Department of Hand Surgery &amp; Rehabilitation, San Giuseppe Hospital, IRCCS MultiMedica Group, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Specialization in Plastic, Reconstructive and Aesthetic Surgery, Milan University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vizcay</LastName><ForeName>Macarena</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the University Department of Hand Surgery &amp; Rehabilitation, San Giuseppe Hospital, IRCCS MultiMedica Group, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Specialization in Plastic, Reconstructive and Aesthetic Surgery, Milan University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101622231</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2169-7574</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors have no financial interest to declare in relation to the content of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41647682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12871937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/GOX.0000000000007464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">GOX-D-25-00589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>de Jong JP, Nguyen JT, Sonnema AJM, et al. The incidence of acute traumatic tendon injuries in the hand and wrist: a 10-year population-based study. Clin Orthop Surg. 2014;6:196&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4040381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24900902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manley OWG, Wormald JCR, Furniss D. The changing shape of hand trauma: an analysis of hospital episode statistics in England. J Hand Surg Eur Vol. 2019;44:532&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30764703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JB. Outcomes of flexor tendon repairs and methods of evaluation. In: Tang JB, Amadio PC, Guimberteau JC, et al., eds. Tendon Surgery of the Hand. Elsevier Saunders; 2012: 246&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JB. Recent evolutions in flexor tendon repairs and rehabilitation. J Hand Surg Eur Vol. 2018;43:469&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29690810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasor SE, Chung KC. Surgical considerations for Flexor tendon repair: timing and choice of repair technique and rehabilitation. Hand Clin. 2023;39:151&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37080647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neiduski RL, Powell RK. Flexor tendon rehabilitation in the 21st century: a systematic review. J Hand Ther. 2019;32:165&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30545730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sindel D, Akpinar FM. Effects of different rehabilitation approaches after surgery for flexor tendon injuries of the hand: a Cochrane review summary with commentary. Turk J Phys Med Rehabil. 2022;68:538&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9791701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36589361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newington L, Bamford E, Henry SL. Relative motion flexion following zone I&#x2013;III flexor tendon repair: concepts, evidence and practice. J Hand Ther. 2023;36:294&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37029053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry SL, Howell JW. Use of a relative motion flexion orthosis for postoperative management of zone I/II flexor digitorum profundus repair: a retrospective consecutive case series. J Hand Ther. 2020;33:296&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31350131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung B, Chiu DTW, Thanik V. Relative motion flexion splinting for flexor tendon lacerations: proof of concept. Hand (N Y). 2019;14:193&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6436129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28975818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strickland JW, Glogovac SV. Digital function following flexor tendon repair in zone II: a comparison of immobilization and controlled passive motion techniques. J Hand Surg Am. 1980;5:537&#x2013;543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7430595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaton DE, Wright JG, Katz JN; Upper Extremity Collaborative Group. Development of the QuickDASH: comparison of three item-reduction approaches. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2005;87:1038&#x2013;1046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15866967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts HC, Denison HJ, Martin HJ, et al. A review of the measurement of grip strength in clinical and epidemiological studies: towards a standardised approach. Age Ageing. 2011;40:423&#x2013;429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21624928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peck FH, Roe AE, Ng CY, et al. The Manchester short splint: a change to splinting practice in the rehabilitation of zone II flexor tendon repairs. Hand Therapy. 2014;19:47&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slade SC, Dionne CE, Underwood M, et al. Consensus on exercise reporting template (CERT): modified Delphi study. Phys Ther. 2016;96:1514&#x2013;1524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27149962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayhan E, Tuna Z, Oksuz C. Getting better results in flexor tendon surgery and therapy. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2021;9:e3432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33680676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JB. New developments are improving flexor tendon repair. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2018;141:1427&#x2013;1437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29579022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JB, Lalonde D, Harhaus L, et al. Flexor tendon repair: recent changes and current methods. J Hand Surg. 2021;47:31&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34738496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cholok D, Burgess J, Fox PM, et al. Tenolysis and salvage procedures. Hand Clin. 2023;39:203&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37080652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>May EJ, Silfverski&#xf6;ld KL. Rate of recovery after flexor tendon repair in zone II a prospective longitudinal study of 145 digits. Scand J Plast Reconstr Surg Hand Surg. 1993;27:89&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8351502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>