<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41718096</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1948-8270</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of bronchology &amp; interventional pulmonology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Bronchology Interv Pulmonol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Real-world Comparative Analysis of Transbronchial Versus Transthoracic Biopsy for Middle Lung Zone Pulmonary Lesions in the Preadvanced Bronchoscopy Era.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e01057</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/LBR.0000000000001057</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The optimal diagnostic approach for indeterminate pulmonary lesions in the middle lung zone remains unclear, particularly in settings without advanced bronchoscopic technologies. This study explores factors influencing diagnostic approach selection and differences in diagnostic flow in facilities operating without such advanced technologies, aiming to clarify practice patterns that may help bridge the technological gap in current clinical guidance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We retrospectively analyzed patients referred to a tertiary thoracic oncology program for middle lung zone lesion diagnosis between January 2015 and June 2016. Patients were grouped by the initial diagnostic approach: transbronchial-first (TBF) or transthoracic-first (TTF). We compared diagnostic yield, complications, diagnostic workup duration, and costs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The study included 108 TBF and 99 TTF patients. TBF had larger lesions (P = 0.0087) and more pulmonary lesions with a positive bronchus sign (P &lt; 0.0001). TBF had a lower initial diagnostic yield (77.8% vs 89.9%, P = 0.0238), but a lower pneumothorax rate (P &lt; 0.0001) and shorter workup duration (P = 0.0001). Overall costs were similar (P = 0.6773), but TBF was more cost-effective for cases requiring pathologic nodal staging (P = 0.0002).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Experienced clinician-driven triage of middle lung zone lesions, based on lesion characteristics, effectively guided initial diagnostic approaches. When appropriately triaged, an initial transbronchial approach resulted in fewer complications, shorter workup duration, and lower costs for pathologic nodal staging, even in an era predating advanced bronchoscopy. Although limited by its retrospective and historical design, these findings provide descriptive insights and underscore the continued value of established diagnostic practices in settings without universal access to newer technologies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishiwata</LastName><ForeName>Tsukasa</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2369-2698</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Surgery.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respirology, Toronto General Hospital, University Health Network, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gregor</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Surgery.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Waddell</LastName><ForeName>Thomas K</ForeName><Initials>TK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Surgery.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yasufuku</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Surgery.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Czarnecka-Kujawa</LastName><ForeName>Kasia</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Surgery.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respirology, Toronto General Hospital, University Health Network, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Bronchology Interv Pulmonol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101496866</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1948-8270</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001999" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bronchoscopy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001706" MajorTopicYN="N">Biopsy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000191" MajorTopicYN="N">economics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">middle lung zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary lesions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transbronchial biopsy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transthoracic biopsy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41718096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/LBR.0000000000001057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01436970-202604010-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>DiBardino DM, Yarmus LB, Semaan RW. Transthoracic needle biopsy of the lung. J Thorac Dis. 2015;7(suppl 4):S304&#x2013;S316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heerink WJ, de Bock GH, de Jonge GJ, et al. Complication rates of CT-guided transthoracic lung biopsy: meta-analysis. Eur Radiol. 2017;27:138&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asano F, Aoe M, Ohsaki Y, et al. Deaths and complications associated with respiratory endoscopy: a survey by the Japan Society for Respiratory Endoscopy in 2010. Respirology. 2012;17:478&#x2013;485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ost DE, Ernst A, Lei X, et al. Diagnostic yield and complications of bronchoscopy for peripheral lung lesions. Results of the AQuIRE registry. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2016;193:68&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera MP, Mehta AC, Wahidi MM. Establishing the diagnosis of lung cancer: diagnosis and management of lung cancer, 3rd ed: American College of Chest Physicians evidence-based clinical practice guidelines. Chest. 2013;143(suppl 5):e142S&#x2013;e1465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadig TR, Thomas N, Nietert PJ, et al. Guided bronchoscopy for the evaluation of pulmonary lesions: an updated meta-analysis. Chest. 2023;163:1589&#x2013;1598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baaklini WA, Reinoso MA, Gorin AB, et al. Diagnostic yield of fiberoptic bronchoscopy in evaluating solitary pulmonary nodules. Chest. 2000;117:1049&#x2013;1054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaeta M, Pandolfo I, Volta S, et al. Bronchus sign on CT in peripheral carcinoma of the lung: value in predicting results of transbronchial biopsy. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 1991;157:1181&#x2013;1185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bila&#xe7;ero&#x11f;lu S, Kumcuo&#x11f;lu Z, Alper H, et al. CT bronchus sign-guided bronchoscopic multiple diagnostic procedures in carcinomatous solitary pulmonary nodules and masses. Respiration. 1998;65:49&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali MS, Sethi J, Taneja A, et al. Computed tomography bronchus sign and the diagnostic yield of guided bronchoscopy for peripheral pulmonary lesions. a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2018;15:978&#x2013;987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson JM, Murchison J, Patel D. CT-guided lung biopsy: factors influencing diagnostic yield and complication rate. Clin Radiol. 2003;58:791&#x2013;797.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohno Y, Hatabu H, Takenaka D, et al. CT-guided transthoracic needle aspiration biopsy of small (&lt; or = 20 mm) solitary pulmonary nodules. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2003;180:1665&#x2013;1669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Yu L, Wang Y, et al. Radial EBUS versus CT-guided needle biopsy for evaluation of solitary pulmonary nodules. Oncotarget. 2018;9:15122&#x2013;15131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aktas AR, Gozlek E, Yazkan R, et al. Transthoracic biopsy of lung masses: non technical factors affecting complication occurrence. Thorac Cancer. 2015;6:151&#x2013;158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Filippo M, Saba L, Silva M, et al. CT-guided biopsy of pulmonary nodules: is pulmonary hemorrhage a complication or an advantage? Diagn Interv Radiol. 2014;20:421&#x2013;425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin SH, Jeong DY, Lee KS, et al. Which definition of a central tumour is more predictive of occult mediastinal metastasis in nonsmall cell lung cancer patients with radiological N0 disease? Eur Respir J. 2019;53:1801508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casal RF, Sepesi B, Sagar AS, et al. Centrally located lung cancer and risk of occult nodal disease: an objective evaluation of multiple definitions of tumour centrality with dedicated imaging software. Eur Respir J. 2019;53:1802220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naidich DP, Bankier AA, MacMahon H, et al. Recommendations for the management of subsolid pulmonary nodules detected at CT: a statement from the Fleischner Society. Radiology. 2013;266:304&#x2013;317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folch EE, Mahajan AK, Oberg CL, et al. Standardized definitions of bleeding after transbronchial lung biopsy: a Delphi consensus statement from the nashville working group. Chest. 2020;158:393&#x2013;400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tai R, Dunne RM, Trotman-Dickenson B, et al. Frequency and severity of pulmonary hemorrhage in patients undergoing percutaneous CT-guided transthoracic lung biopsy: single-institution experience of 1175 cases. Radiology. 2016;279:287&#x2013;296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J, Qu Y, Wang X, et al. Risk factors associated with pulmonary hemorrhage and hemoptysis following percutaneous CT-guided transthoracic lung core needle biopsy: a retrospective study of 1,090 cases. Quant Imaging Med Surg. 2020;10:1008&#x2013;1020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S, Li J, Wang W, et al. Development and validation of a predictive model for pulmonary hemorrhage in computed tomography-guided percutaneous lung biopsy. Postgrad Med J. 2023;99:1173&#x2013;1181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bank of Canada. Inflation. Accessed October 1, 2024. https://www.bankofcanada.ca/core-functions/monetary-policy/inflation/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Guo F, Wang H, et al. Comparative analysis of electromagnetic navigation bronchoscopy versus computed tomography-guided lung puncture for the sampling of indeterminate pulmonary nodules in the middle of an anatomic lung segment: a cohort study. Thorac Cancer. 2023;14:149&#x2013;155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeow KM, Su IH, Pan KT, et al. Risk factors of pneumothorax and bleeding: multivariate analysis of 660 CT-guided coaxial cutting needle lung biopsies. Chest. 2004;126:748&#x2013;754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HK, Jeon YJ, Um SW, et al. Role of invasive mediastinal nodal staging in survival outcomes of patients with non-small cell lung cancer and without radiologic lymph node metastasis: a retrospective cohort study. EClinicalMedicine. 2024;69:102478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyaz F, Verhoeven RLJ, Schuurbiers OCJ, et al. Occult lymph node metastases in clinical N0/N1 NSCLC; a single center in-depth analysis. Lung Cancer. 2020;150:186&#x2013;194.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>