<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41049999</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Diagnostic Accuracy of Bedside Lung Ultrasound Versus Chest X-ray for Pediatric Pneumonia in Children Under Five: A Comparative Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e91509</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e91509</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e91509</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.91509</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Pneumonia remains a major cause of under-five mortality, particularly in low-resource settings where early diagnosis is crucial. While chest X-ray (CXR) is the conventional imaging modality, it is limited by radiation exposure and accessibility. Bedside lung ultrasound (LUS) has emerged as a promising, radiation-free alternative, offering real-time pulmonary assessment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the diagnostic accuracy of bedside LUS compared to CXR in children under five presenting with clinical signs of pneumonia, and to analyze the sonographic features associated with pneumonia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A prospective observational study was conducted on 161 children aged one month to five years with clinical suspicion of pneumonia at a tertiary care hospital over 18 months. LUS was performed at the bedside using a standardized 10-zone protocol. Chest radiographs were interpreted by radiologists blinded to LUS findings. Statistical analysis included sensitivity, specificity, predictive values, and logistic regression for significant predictors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">LUS showed significantly higher sensitivity (86.2%, n=139/161, p=0.0001) and specificity (94.4%, n=85/90, p=0.0001) than CXR (75.6%, n=122/161,&#xa0;and 85.4%, n=77/90, respectively). Key sonographic markers such as shred sign and air bronchograms demonstrated strong diagnostic value. Subpleural consolidations and pleural effusions were better detected with LUS. Shred sign (odds ratio (OR)=8.45) and CRP &gt;20 mg/L (OR=3.50) emerged as strong independent predictors of pneumonia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Bedside LUS is a reliable and accurate diagnostic modality for pediatric pneumonia. It is especially valuable in early detection and in resource-limited settings, supporting its broader clinical integration.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Sankar et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sankar</LastName><ForeName>Kumaraguru</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics, Dr. Susheela Tiwari Government Hospital, Government Medical College, Haldwani, Haldwani, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rakholia</LastName><ForeName>Ritu</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics, Dr. Susheela Tiwari Government Hospital, Government Medical College, Haldwani, Haldwani, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maroof</LastName><ForeName>Mohd</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Community Medicine, Rani Durgavati Medical College, Banda, Banda, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chamoli</LastName><ForeName>Prerna</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics, Dr. Susheela Tiwari Government Hospital, Government Medical College, Haldwani, Haldwani, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raipa</LastName><ForeName>Tapish</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiodiagnosis, Dr. Susheela Tiwari Government Hospital, Government Medical College, Haldwani, Haldwani, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chest x-ray</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic accuracy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lung ultrasound</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatrics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pneumonia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Institutional Ethics Committee, Government Medical College, Haldwani, Uttarakhand issued approval 772/GMC/IEC/2023/Reg. No. 727/IEC/R-01-05-2023 dated 08/12/2023. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41049999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12491745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.91509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Childhood pneumonia: an update in the post-COVID-19 era. Irvine S, Logan P, Shields MD, McCrossan P. Paediatr Child Health. 2025;17:214&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. World Health Organization: WHO; [ Aug; 2025 ]. 2022. Pneumonia in children.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health and Family Welfare, Government of India. Health Management Information System. Child pneumonia report 2022-2023.  [
Aug;
2025 
]. 2023. https://sansad.in/getFile/loksabhaquestions/annex/1714/AU1004.pdf?source=pqals https://sansad.in/getFile/loksabhaquestions/annex/1714/AU1004.pdf?source=pqals</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Community-acquired pneumonia in childhood. Popovsky EY, Florin TA. Encyclopedia of Respiratory Medicine. 2021:119&#x2013;131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The radiological diagnosis of pneumonia in children. O'Grady KF, Torzillo PJ, Frawley K, Chang AB. Pneumonia (Nathan) 2014;5:38&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5922330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31641573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The diagnostic value of lung ultrasound in children with community-acquired pneumonia [Article in Chinese] Cai SJ, Zhang LL, Chen SY, Zhu TT, Xu M, Zheng YM, Zhang HL. Zhonghua Er Ke Za Zhi. 2024;62:331&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38527503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of the diagnostic performance of physician lung ultrasound versus chest radiography for pneumonia diagnosis in a peri-urban South African cohort. Venkatakrishna SS, Stadler JA, Kilborn T, le Roux DM, Zar HJ, Andronikou S. Pediatr Radiol. 2024;54:413&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37311897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Integrated management of childhood illness - chart booklet.  [
Aug;
2025 
]. 2014. https://cdn.who.int/media/docs/default-source/mca-documents/9789241506823_chartbook_eng.pdf?sfvrsn=cccea3a6_1&amp;download=true https://cdn.who.int/media/docs/default-source/mca-documents/9789241506823_chartbook_eng.pdf?sfvrsn=cccea3a6_1&amp;download=true</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>How to calculate sample size for different study designs in medical research? Charan J, Biswas T. Indian J Psychol Med. 2013;35:121&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3775042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24049221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lung ultrasound as a diagnostic tool for radiographically-confirmed pneumonia in low resource settings. Ellington LE, Gilman RH, Chavez MA, et al. Respir Med. 2017;128:57&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5480773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28610670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Integrated management of neonatal and childhood illness.  [
Aug;
2025 
]. 2013. https://nhm.gov.in/images/pdf/programmes/child-health/guidelines/module_1.pdf https://nhm.gov.in/images/pdf/programmes/child-health/guidelines/module_1.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pediatric chest ultrasound for bedside diagnosis of pneumonia: a validation study for diagnostic options in developing countries. Basanti CWS, Kotb MA, Seif HM, Farag FI, Abdelmegeid AK. Pediatri Sci J. 2021;1:15&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lung ultrasound for the diagnosis of community-acquired pneumonia in infants and children. Osman AM, Sarhan AA, Abd-Elrahman AM, Abo-Salha MA. Egypt J Chest Dis Tuberc. 2020;69:227&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lung ultrasonography for the diagnosis of severe neonatal pneumonia. Liu J, Liu F, Liu Y, Wang HW, Feng ZC. Chest. 2014;146:383&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24833216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Point-of-care lung ultrasound in children with community acquired pneumonia. Yilmaz HL, &#xd6;zkaya AK, Sar&#x131; G&#xf6;kay S, Tolu Kendir &#xd6;, &#x15e;enol H. Am J Emerg Med. 2017;35:964&#x2013;969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28202294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lung ultrasonography: a viable alternative to chest radiography in children with suspected pneumonia? Ambroggio L, Sucharew H, Rattan MS, et al. J Pediatr. 2016;176:93&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27318374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lung ultrasound for the diagnosis of pneumonia in children: a meta-analysis. Pereda MA, Chavez MA, Hooper-Miele CC, et al. Pediatrics. 2015;135:714&#x2013;722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9923609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25780071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Point-of-care lung ultrasound in detecting pneumonia: a systematic review. Abid I, Qureshi N, Lategan N, Williams S, Shahid S. Can J Respir Ther. 2024;60:37&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10830142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38299193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of lung ultrasonography in etiologic diagnosis of acute dyspnea in a resource limited setting. Phung NT, Vo TT, Hon KL. Bull Emerg Trauma. 2020;8:121&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7211395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32420398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Performance of chest ultrasound in pediatric pneumonia. Claes AS, Clapuyt P, Menten R, Michoux N, Dumitriu D. Eur J Radiol. 2017;88:82&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28189214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lung ultrasound in children with pneumonia: interoperator agreement on specific thoracic regions. de Souza TH, Nadal JA, Peixoto AO, Pereira RM, Giatti MP, Soub AC, Brand&#xe3;o MB. Eur J Pediatr. 2019;178:1369&#x2013;1377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31312938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>