<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41781949</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1475-2875</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Malaria journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Malar J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Utilization and associated factors of long-lasting insecticide-treated nets among households in Gondar Zuria district, Northwest Ethiopia: a mixed methods study, 2025.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12936-026-05839-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Malaria is a major public health problem in Ethiopia, and long-lasting insecticide-treated nets (LLINs) are one of the primary preventive strategies used to control it. Gondar Zuria District, Central Gondar Zone's highest malaria-reporting district, reached 100% LLIN coverage in 2023. However, malaria cases remain high, suggesting gaps in LLIN utilization. Therefore, this study aimed to assess LLIN usage and determinants in Gondar Zuria District.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Community-based mixed-methods study was conducted from February 1 to 28, 2025 among 700 participants selected through multistage sampling. Quantitative data was collected via interviewer-administered questionnaires and entered into EpiData version 4.6.0.2 and exported to SPSS version 25 for analysis. A binary logistic regression model was fitted, and statistical significance was determined using 95% confidence intervals (CI) and a p-value&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.05. Qualitative data were collected through purposively sampled interviews (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;7) and key informant interviews (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;3) and analyzed thematically.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The prevalence of ITN utilization was 55.6% (95% CI: 51.9%-59.3%) and was significantly associated with perceived severity (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.74; 95% CI: 1.27-2.39), LLINs-to-family size ratio (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.09; 95% CI: 1.51-2.91), and occupation specifically, being a government employee (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.45; 95% CI: 1.57-7.58). The mixed methods design therefore provided a more comprehensive understanding by revealing behavioral and contextual factors that were not captured through quantitative data alone. Qualitative findings complemented the quantitative results by explaining why LLIN utilization remained low, highlighting misconceptions about net safety, doubts about effectiveness, discomfort due to heat, and structural barriers such as lack of space for hanging nets.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">LLIN utilization in Gondar Zuria District fell below the national target (100%). Misconceptions and misinformation contribute to irregular use and reduced trust. Beyond distribution and health education, community-based behavior changes strategies such as household follow-ups by health workers and integrating LLIN promotion into local forums alongside routine net condition monitoring are essential to improve consistent use and advance malaria elimination efforts.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Begashaw</LastName><ForeName>Desalegn Tesfaye</ForeName><Initials>DT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Field Epidemiology and Laboratory Training Program, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia. desut1221@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alemayehu</LastName><ForeName>Meron Asmamaw</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Institute of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Science, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Animut</LastName><ForeName>Yaregal</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Institute of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Science, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marie</LastName><ForeName>Shegaw</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Informatics, Institute of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Science, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Digital Health and Implementation Science, College of Medicine and Health Science, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Malar J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101139802</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1475-2875</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LLINs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Malaria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Utilization,mixed method</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical clearance was obtained from the Institute of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Science, University of Gondar, Ethiopia, and submitted to Amhara Public Health Institute (APHI). Research and technology transfer directorate. Permission letter was secured. The purposes and the Importance of the study was explained to PHEM directorate. Confidentiality was assured at all Levels of the study using password protected computer and through deleting all identifiers. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41781949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12936-026-05839-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12936-026-05839-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>MOH. Malaria case management training manual for health professionals in Ethiopia. MOH: Addis Ababa; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatt S, et al. The effect of malaria control on Plasmodium falciparum in Africa between 2000 and 2015. Nature. 2015;526(7572):207&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moses M, KI University Ix. Comparing the effectiveness of long-lasting insecticidal nets versus indoor residual spraying in reducing malaria cases among children under five. 2025. 7: p. 89&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC. Insecticide-treated nets. 2024. https://www.cdc.gov/malaria/php/public-health-strategy/insecticide-treated-nets.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Guidelines for malaria vector control. 2019. https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/310862/9789241550499-eng.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wubishet MK, et al. Effectiveness of long-lasting insecticidal nets in prevention of malaria among individuals visiting health centres in Ziway-Dugda District, Ethiopia: matched case-control study. Malar J. 2021;20(1):301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wassie E. Assessment of effectiveness of insecticide treated bednets for Malaria prevention in under-five children of Aletawondo Woreda, Southern Ethiopia. 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MOH. National malaria elimination roadmap. 2017. https://www.moh.gov.et/en/National_Malaria_Elimination_Program?language_content_entity=en.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merga T, et al. Utilization of insecticide-treated bed nets and associated factors among households in Pawie District, Benshangul Gumuz, Northwest Ethiopia. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):31712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemu MB, et al. Utilization of insecticide treated bed net and associated factors among households of Kola Diba town, North Gondar, Amhara region, Ethiopia. BMC Res Notes. 2018;11(1):575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse EM, Baruda YS, Tadesse TM. Assessment of household insecticide-treated bed net ownership, utilization, and associated factors in Kersa Woreda, Jimma Zone, Southwest Ethiopia. J Health Popul Nutr. 2024;43(1):214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. World malaria report 2023. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taffese HS, et al. Malaria epidemiology and interventions in Ethiopia from 2001 to 2016. Infect Dis Poverty. 2018;7(1):103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayou FD, et al. Under utilization of long-lasting insecticidal nets (LLINs) is challenging malaria elimination program in Ethiopia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Public Health. 2024;24(1):815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endriyas M, et al. Low long-lasting insecticidal net use in malaria elimination areas in Southern Ethiopia: results from community based cross-sectional study. Malar J. 2024;23(1):94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niguse W, et al. Low ITN utilization among households in SWEPR Ethiopia: challenge for malaria elimination, a mixed design approach. BMC Public Health. 2025;25(1):472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekuria M, et al. Insecticide-treated bed net utilization and associated factors among households in Ilu Galan district, Oromia region, Ethiopia. Environ Health Insights. 2022;16:11786302221078122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watiro AH, Awoke W. Insecticide-treated net ownership and utilization and factors that influence their use in Itang, Gambella region, Ethiopia: cross-sectional study. Risk Manag Healthc Policy. 2016;9:101&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyinyechi OM, Mohd Nazan AIN, Ismail S. Effectiveness of health education interventions to improve malaria knowledge and insecticide-treated nets usage among populations of sub-Saharan Africa: systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1217052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garley AE, et al. Gender differences in the use of insecticide-treated nets after a universal free distribution campaign in Kano State, Nigeria: post-campaign survey results. Malar J. 2013;12(1):119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olapeju B, et al. Age and gender trends in insecticide-treated net use in sub-Saharan Africa: a multi-country analysis. Malar J. 2018;17(1):423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atieli HE, et al. Insecticide-treated net (ITN) ownership, usage, and malaria transmission in the highlands of western Kenya. Parasit Vectors. 2011;4(1):113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yirsaw AN, et al. Insecticide-treated net utilization and associated factors among pregnant women and under-five children in East Belessa District, Northwest Ethiopia: using the Health Belief model. Malar J. 2021;20(1):130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malede A, et al. Barriers of persistent long-lasting insecticidal nets utilization in villages around Lake Tana, Northwest Ethiopia: a qualitative study. BMC Public Health. 2019;19(1):1303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asingizwe D, et al. Role of individual perceptions in the consistent use of malaria preventive measures: mixed methods evidence from rural Rwanda. Malar J. 2019;18(1):270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Programs, J.H.C.f.C., et al. Malaria behavior survey toolkit. Malaria behavior survey 2024. https://www.malariabehaviorsurvey.org/toolkit. Accessed 29 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebede W, et al. Utilization of insecticide-treated nets in households for under-5 children and associated factors in East Mesekan District, Gurage Zone, Southern Ethiopia. Environ Health Insights. 2023;17:11786302231164287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tassew A, Hopkins R, Deressa W. Factors influencing the ownership and utilization of long-lasting insecticidal nets for malaria prevention in Ethiopia. Malar J. 2017;16(1):262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duodu PA, et al. Rural&#x2013;urban dimensions of the perception of malaria severity and practice of malaria preventive measures: insight from the 2018 Nigeria Demographic and Health Survey. J Biosoc Sci. 2022;54(5):858&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coalson JE, et al. Insufficient ratio of long-lasting insecticidal nets to household members limited universal usage in Western Kenya: a 2015 cross-sectional study. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2020;102(6):1328&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinchoff J, et al. Factors associated with sustained use of long-lasting insecticide-treated nets following a reduction in malaria transmission in Southern Zambia. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2015;93(5):954&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zegene GM, Alemayehu B, Gebremedhin T, Gebremichael MA, Niguse W, Negeri E. Perceptions and practices of household heads toward malaria: a community based cross sectional study in Southwest Ethiopia. Malar J. 2025;24(1):176. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12936-025-05413-7.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>