<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41316491</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2056-9920</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of retina and vitreous</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Retina Vitreous</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Retinal microvasculature and macular-choroidal thickness in oral contraceptive users: an OCTA and OCT comparative study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>8</StartPage><MedlinePgn>8</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40942-025-00775-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Potential retinal vascular changes associated with hormonal contraceptive use remain insufficiently characterized in the literature. Optical coherence tomography angiography (OCTA) enables a noninvasive and highly detailed evaluation of retinal microvasculature. This study aimed to assess the superficial and deep retinal capillary plexuses, and macular and choroidal thickness in women using combined oral contraceptives (COC) or progestogen-only contraceptives (POC) compared with women who had never used hormonal contraceptives. The potential influence of the duration of use was also investigated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A cross-sectional analysis was conducted in 120 healthy women aged 20&#x2013;40 years, equally distributed into the COC, POC, and control groups. OCTA was used to measure foveal avascular zone (FAZ) parameters and vessel densities of the superficial and deep plexuses in a 3&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;3&#xa0;mm scan. Macular and choroidal thickness were obtained using spectral-domain optical coherence tomography. One randomly selected eye of each participant was analyzed. Intergroup comparisons were performed using analysis of variance (ANOVA) or Kruskal&#x2013;Wallis test, with appropriate post-hoc analyses; significance was set at 5%.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">No significant differences were observed among the groups in FAZ parameters, macular thickness, or choroidal thickness. A small but statistically significant reduction in vessel density of the nasal parafoveal sector of the superficial capillary plexus was found in the POC subgroup with less than two years of use compared with controls (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.033; post-hoc <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.049). No other significant differences were detected in the superficial or deep plexuses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Hormonal contraceptive use was not associated with significant alterations in FAZ parameters, macular or choroidal thickness, or overall retinal vessel density. A slight reduction in nasal parafoveal vessel density was observed in women with POC use for less than 2 years compared with controls, although the clinical significance of this finding remains uncertain. These results suggest that retinal vascular changes associated with hormonal contraceptives are minimal, underscoring the need for longitudinal studies with larger samples to confirm these observations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s40942-025-00775-1.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dias</LastName><ForeName>Alana Ferreira Gomes</ForeName><Initials>AFG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3753-7920</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Faculty of Medicine, INTA University Center, Sobral, CE, Brazil. alanafgd@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drug Research and Development Center (NPDM), Faculty of Medicine, Federal University of Cear&#xe1;, Fortaleza, CE, Brazil. alanafgd@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vieira</LastName><ForeName>M&#xe1;rcio Fragoso</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-0571-1520</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Faculty of Medicine, Federal University of Cear&#xe1;, Sobral, CE, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jamacaru</LastName><ForeName>Francisco Vagnaldo Fechine</ForeName><Initials>FVF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8893-5323</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drug Research and Development Center (NPDM), Faculty of Medicine, Federal University of Cear&#xe1;, Fortaleza, CE, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Moraes</LastName><ForeName>Maria Elisabete Amaral</ForeName><Initials>MEA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6826-8930</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drug Research and Development Center (NPDM), Faculty of Medicine, Federal University of Cear&#xe1;, Fortaleza, CE, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Retina Vitreous</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101677897</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2056-9920</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Angiography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Choroid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hormonal oral contraceptives</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Optical coherence tomography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Retinal vasculature</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Research Ethics Committee of the Federal University of Cear&#xe1; - CEP/UFC/PROPESQ (CAAE 55193422.1.0000.5054). Written informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to enrollment. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41316491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12781684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40942-025-00775-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40942-025-00775-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sitruk-Ware R. Hormonal contraception and thrombosis. Fertil Steril. 2016;106(6):1289&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fertnstert.2016.08.039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27678035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vessey MP, Hannaford P, Mant J, Painter R, Frith P, Chappel D. Oral contraception and eye disease: findings in two large cohort studies. Br J Ophthalmol. 1998;82(5):538&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjo.82.5.538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1722595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9722322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaaban YM, Badran TAF. The effect of oral contraceptive pills on the macula, the retinal nerve fiber layer, the ganglion cell layer and the choroidal thickness. BMC Ophthalmol. 2019;19:250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12886-019-1263-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6904990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31823761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Icoz M, Gurturk-Icoz SG, Kolsuz-Koldamca H. Effect of oral contraceptive pills on the retinal microvascular structure: an optical coherence tomography angiography study. Photodiagnosis Photodyn Ther. 2023;42:103635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pdpdt.2023.103635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37244452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Icoz M, Yuzbas&#x131;oglu S. Evaluation of choroidal thickness and choroidal vascular index in patients using combined oral contraceptive pills. Cutan Ocul Toxicol. 2023;42(4):232&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15569527.2023.2235429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37437218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipriani V, Quartilho A, Bunce C, Freemantle N, Dor&#xe9; CJ, Ophthalmic Statistics Group. Ophthalmic statistics note 7: multiple hypothesis testing&#x2014;to adjust or not to adjust. Br J Ophthalmol. 2015;99(9):1155&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjophthalmol-2015-306784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26112870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkema L, Kantorova V, Menozzi C, Biddlecom A. National, regional, and global rates and trends in contraceptive prevalence and unmet need for family planning between 1990 and 2015: a systematic and comprehensive analysis. Lancet. 2013;381(9878):1642&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(12)62204-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23489750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta PD, Johar K, Nagpal K, Vasavada AR. Sex hormone receptors in the human eye. Surv Ophthalmol. 2005;50(3):274&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.survophthal.2005.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15850816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Souza MAM, De Souza BM, Geber S. Progesterone increases resistance of ophthalmic and central retinal arteries in climacteric women. Climacteric. 2013;16(2):284&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/13697137.2012.720620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23046107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viana LC, Faria M, Pettersen H, Sampaio M, Geber S. Menstrual phase-related differences in the pulsatility index on the central retinal artery suggest an oestrogen vasodilatation effect that antagonizes with progesterone. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2011;283(3):569&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00404-010-1403-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20213131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz SG, Grzybowski A, Wasinska-Borowiec W, Flynn HW, Mieler WF. Update on Pharmacologic retinal vascular toxicity. Curr Pharm Des. 2015;21(32):4694&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1381612821666150909101621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26350526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ESHRE Capri Workshop Group, Eichinger S, Evers JLH, Glasier A, La Vecchia C, Martinelli I, et al. Venous thromboembolism in women: a specific reproductive health risk. Hum Reprod Update. 2013;19(5):471&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/humupd/dmt028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23825156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal RS, Mishra VV, Aggarwal SV. Oral contraceptive pills: A risk factor for retinal vascular occlusion in in-vitro fertilization patients. J Hum Reprod Sci. 2013;6(1):79&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0974-1208.112389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3713585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23869159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rifkin L, Schaal S. Teenage acute macular neuroretinopathy. Eur J Ophthalmol. 2012;22(4):674&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5301/ejo.5000076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22034018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan JJ, Hassoun A, Elmalem VI. Cerebral venous sinus thrombosis with ophthalmic manifestations in 18-year-olds on oral contraceptives. Clin Pediatr (Phila). 2014;53(9):826&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0009922814533405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24803635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eski Y&#xfc;cel O, G&#xfc;ngor I, G&#xfc;l A, Turgut M, Arit&#xfc;rk N. Papillophlebitis associated with the use of oral contraceptive: a case report. Gynecol Endocrinol. 2015;31(8):601&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/09513590.2015.1056139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26291803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stepanov A, Hejsek L, Jiraskova N, Feuermannova A, Rencova E, Rozsival P. Transient branch retinal artery occlusion in a 15-year-old Girl and review of the literature. Biomed Pap Med Fac Univ Palacky Olomouc Czechoslov. 2015;159(3):508&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5507/bp.2015.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26160228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matti AI, Lee AW, Chen CS. Concurrent branch retinal vein occlusion and cerebral venous thrombosis from oral contraceptive pill use. Can J Ophthalmol. 2010;45(5):541&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3129/i10-039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20436530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allaf AM, Wang J, Simms AG, Jiang H. Age-related alterations in retinal capillary function. Microvasc Res. 2023;148:104508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mvr.2023.104508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10258153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36822365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozgur G, Gokmen O. Associations between body mass index and choroidal thickness, superficial and deep retinal vascular indices, and foveal avascular zone measured by OCTA. Photodiagnosis Photodyn Ther. 2023;42:103515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pdpdt.2023.103515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36924979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madendag Y, Acmaz G, Atas M, Sahin E, Tayyar AT, Madendag I&#xc7;, et al. The effect of oral contraceptive pills on the Macula, the retinal nerve fiber Layer, and choroidal thickness. Med Sci Monit Int Med J Exp Clin Res. 2017;23:5657&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5708262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29176540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulut M, Ak&#x131;dan M, G&#xf6;zkaya O, Erol MK, Cengiz A, &#xc7;ay HF. Optical coherence tomography angiography for screening of hydroxychloroquine-induced retinal alterations. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2018;256(11):2075&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00417-018-4117-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30159602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Pan M, Liu Y, Cheng F, Shuai Z. Evaluation of early retinal changes in patients on long-term hydroxychloroquine using optical coherence tomography angiography. Ther Adv Drug Saf. 2024;15:20420986231225851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20420986231225851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10823852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38300766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdol Homayuni MR, Sadeghi R, Poshtdar S, Ramandi A, Nikfar R, Ebrahimiadib N. Optical coherence tomography angiography measurements in Tamoxifen associated retinopathy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Ophthalmol. 2025;25(1):373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12886-025-03971-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12217189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40597899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alibhai AY, Moult EM, Shahzad R, Rebhun CB, Moreira-Neto C, McGowan M, et al. Quantifying microvascular changes using OCT angiography in diabetic eyes without clinical evidence of retinopathy. Ophthalmol Retina. 2018;2(5):418&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oret.2017.09.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6391050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30820483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F, Zou W, Li Z, Du Y, Gao W, Zhang J, et al. Optical coherence tomography angiography for detection of microvascular changes in early diabetes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2024;40(4):e3812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dmrr.3812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38738481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua J, Chin CWL, Hong J, Chee ML, Le TT, Ting DSW, et al. Impact of hypertension on retinal capillary microvasculature using optical coherence tomographic angiography. J Hypertens. 2019;37(3):572&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HJH.0000000000001916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6365272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30113530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donati S, Maresca AM, Cattaneo J, Grossi A, Mazzola M, Caprani SM, et al. Optical coherence tomography angiography and arterial hypertension: A role in identifying subclinical microvascular damage? Eur J Ophthalmol. 2021;31(1):158&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1120672119880390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31617414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee WH, Park JH, Won Y, Lee MW, Shin YI, Jo YJ, et al. Retinal microvascular change in hypertension as measured by optical coherence tomography angiography. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-36474-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6336859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30655557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dogan M, Akdogan M, Gulyesil FF, Sabaner MC, Gobeka HH. Cigarette smoking reduces deep retinal vascular density. Clin Exp Optom. 2020;103(6):838&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cxo.13070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32285487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokmen O, Ozgur G. The effects of chronic smoking on retinal vascular densities and choroidal thicknesses measured by optical coherence tomography angiography. Eur J Ophthalmol. 2023;33(1):455&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/11206721221124650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36083180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>