<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41872377</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Seasonal variation in particulate organic carbon sequestration in subarctic and subtropical gyres of the western North Pacific.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-43514-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The ocean's biological carbon pump regulates climate by transferring a portion of surface-fixed CO<sub>2</sub> to the deep ocean through sinking particulate organic carbon (POC). Although this flux is strongly attenuated in the twilight zone, the seasonal controls on attenuation remain poorly understood. We examined seasonal variations in POC flux, the nitrogen isotope ratio of sinking particulate nitrogen (&#x3b4;<sup>15</sup>N<sub>sink</sub>), and mineral composition using sediment traps observations at subarctic (K2) and subtropical (S1) stations in the western North Pacific. POC sequestration efficiency at 500&#xa0;m [Seq<sub>(500)</sub>&#x2009;=&#x2009;POC flux/NPP] was quantified, with net primary productivity (NPP) reconstructed from &#x3b4;<sup>15</sup>N<sub>sink</sub> using an empirical framework. Seq<sub>(500)</sub> remained nearly constant at K2 (7.4-8.1%) but varied substantially at S1 (3.4-6.5%). At K2, CaCO<sub>3</sub> and opal contents exhibited complementary seasonal patterns, whereas S1 showed pronounced variability primarily in CaCO<sub>3</sub>. We propose that mineral composition modulates aggregate settling velocity and adhesive strength, thereby regulating POC attenuation through fragmentation processes. These findings indicate that seasonal shifts in surface ecosystem structure influence the physical properties of sinking aggregates and ultimately control the fate of NPP in the twilight zone.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mino</LastName><ForeName>Yoshihisa</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Space-Earth Environmental Research, Nagoya University, Nagoya, Japan. mino.yoshihisa.i0@f.mail.nagoya-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sukigara</LastName><ForeName>Chiho</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Japan Agency for Marine-Earth Science and Technology, Yokosuka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsumoto</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Japan Agency for Marine-Earth Science and Technology, Yokosuka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujiki</LastName><ForeName>Tetsuichi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Japan Agency for Marine-Earth Science and Technology, Yokosuka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kitamura</LastName><ForeName>Minoru</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Japan Agency for Marine-Earth Science and Technology, Yokosuka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wakita</LastName><ForeName>Masahide</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mutsu Institute for Oceanography, Japan Agency for Marine-Earth Science and Technology, Mutsu, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoshikawa</LastName><ForeName>Chisato</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Japan Agency for Marine-Earth Science and Technology, Yokosuka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Honda</LastName><ForeName>Makio C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Japan Agency for Marine-Earth Science and Technology, Yokosuka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>JP15H05822</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biogenic opal and CaCO3 fraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biological carbon pump</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon sequestration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Net primary productivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nitrogen isotope ratios</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Particulate organic carbon flux</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41872377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-43514-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-43514-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Volk, T., &amp; Hoffert, M. I. Ocean carbon pumps: analysis of relative strengths and efficiencies in ocean-driven atmospheric CO<sub>2</sub> changes. In The Carbon Cycle and Atmospheric CO<sub>2</sub>: Natural Variations Archean to Present 99&#x2013;110, Vol 32 (1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Moigne, F. A. C. Pathways of organic carbon downward transport by the oceanic biological carbon pump. Front. Mar. Sci. 6, 634 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyd, P. W. &amp; Trull, T. W. Understanding the export of biogenic particles in oceanic waters: Is there consensus?. Prog. Oceanogr. 72, 276&#x2013;312 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buesseler, K., Boyd, P., Black, E. &amp; Siegel, D. Metrics that matter for assessing the ocean biological carbon pump. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 117, 201918114 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin, J. H., Knauer, G. A., Karl, D. M. &amp; Broenkow, W. W. VERTEX: Carbon cycling in the Northeast Pacific. Deep Sea Res. A. Oceanogr. Res. Pap. 34, 267&#x2013;285 (1987).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinberg, D. K. et al. Bacterial vs. zooplankton control of sinking particle flux in the ocean&#x2019;s twilight zone. Limnol. Oceanogr. 53, 1327&#x2013;1338 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giering, S. L. et al. Reconciliation of the carbon budget in the ocean&#x2019;s twilight zone. Nature 507, 480&#x2013;483 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins, J. R. et al. The multiple fates of sinking particles in the North Atlantic Ocean. Global Biogeochem. Cycles 29, 1471&#x2013;1494 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavia, F. J. et al. Shallow particulate organic carbon regeneration in the South Pacific Ocean. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 116, 9753&#x2013;9758 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsay, C. M. et al. Attenuation of sinking particulate organic carbon flux through the mesopelagic ocean. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 112, 1089&#x2013;1094 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutz, M. J., Caldeira, K., Dunbar, R. B. &amp; Behrenfeld, M. J. Seasonal rhythms of net primary production and particulate organic carbon flux to depth describe the efficiency of biological pump in the global ocean. J. Geophys. Res. Oceans 112, C10011 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henson, S. A., Sanders, R. &amp; Madsen, E. Global patterns in efficiency of particulate organic carbon export and transfer to the deep ocean. Glob. Biogeochem. Cycles 26, GB1028 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidi, L. et al. A new look at ocean carbon remineralization for estimating deepwater sequestration. Glob. Biogeochem. Cycles 29, 1044&#x2013;1059 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong, R. A., Lee, C., Hedges, J. I., Honjo, S. &amp; Wakeham, S. G. A new, mechanistic model for organic carbon fluxes in the ocean based on the quantitative association of POC with ballast minerals. Deep Sea Res. Part II Top. Stud. Oceanogr. 49, 219&#x2013;236 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francois, R., Honjo, S., Krishfield, R. &amp; Manganini, S. Factors controlling the flux of organic carbon to the bathypelagic zone of the ocean. Glob. Biogeochem. Cycles 16, 1087 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges, J. et al. Evidence for non-selective preservation of organic matter in sinking marine particles. Nature 409, 801&#x2013;804 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cram, J. A. et al. The role of particle size, ballast, temperature, and oxygen in the sinking flux to the deep sea. Global Biogeochem. Cycles 32, 858&#x2013;876 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trull, T. W. et al. In-situ measurement of mesopelagic particle sinking rates and the control of carbon transfer to the ocean interior during the Vertical Flux in the Global Ocean (VERTIGO) voyages in the North Pacific. Deep Sea Res. Part II Top. Stud. Oceanogr. 55, 1684&#x2013;1695 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iversen, M. H. &amp; Ploug, H. Ballast minerals and the sinking carbon flux in the ocean: Carbon-specific respiration rates and sinking velocities of marine snow aggregates. Biogeosciences 7, 2613&#x2013;2624 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer, G. &amp; Karakas, G. Sinking rates and ballast composition of particles in the Atlantic Ocean: Implications for the organic carbon fluxes to the deep ocean. Biogeosciences 6, 85&#x2013;102 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shigemitsu, M., Watanabe, Y., Yamanaka, Y., Kawakami, J. &amp; Honda, M. Relationship between sinking organic matter and minerals in the shallow zone of the western Subarctic Pacific. J. Oceanogr. 66, 697&#x2013;708 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bressac, M. et al. Decoding drivers of carbon flux attenuation in the oceanic biological pump. Nature 633, 587&#x2013;593 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacquet, S. H. M., Lam, P. J., Trull, T. &amp; Dehairs, F. Carbon export production in the subantarctic zone and polar front zone south of Tasmania. Deep Sea Res. Part II Top. Stud. Oceanogr. 58(21&#x2013;22), 2277&#x2013;2292 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujiki, T. et al. Seasonal cycle of phytoplankton community structure and photophysiological state in the western subarctic gyre of the North Pacific. Limnol. Oceanogr. 59, 887&#x2013;900 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujiki, T., Sasaoka, K., Matsumoto, K., Wakita, M. &amp; Mino, Y. Seasonal variability of phytoplankton community structure in the subtropical western North Pacific. J. Oceanogr. 72, 343&#x2013;358 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honda, M. C. Effective vertical transport of particulate organic carbon in the Western North Pacific Subarctic Region. Front. Earth Sci. 8, 366 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galcia, H. E. et al. World Ocean Atlas 2023, Volume 4: Dissolved Inorganic Nutrients (phosphate, nitrate, silicate). In NOAA Atlas NESDIS (ed Mishonov, A.) 34, Vol. 92 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mino, Y. et al. Seasonal variations in the nitrogen isotopic composition of settling particles at station K2 in the western subarctic North Pacific. J. Oceanogr. 72, 819&#x2013;836 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mino, Y. et al. Seasonal and interannual variations in nitrogen availability and particle export in the Northwestern North Pacific subtropical gyre. J. Geophys. Res. Oceans 125, e2019JC015600 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto, K. et al. Seasonal variability of primary production and phytoplankton biomass in the western Pacific subarctic gyre: Control by light availability within the mixed layer. J. Geophys. Res. Oceans 119, 6523&#x2013;6534 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujiki, T., Hosoda, S. &amp; Harada, N. Phytoplankton blooms in summer and autumn in the northwestern subarctic Pacific detected by the mooring and float systems. J. Oceanogr. 78, 63&#x2013;72 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakita, M. et al. Biological organic carbon export estimated from the annual carbon budget observed in the surface waters of the western subarctic and subtropical North Pacific Ocean from 2004 to 2013. J. Oceanogr. 72, 665&#x2013;685 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshikawa, C., Yamanaka, Y. &amp; Nakatsuka, T. An ecosystem model including nitrogen isotopes: Perspectives on a study of the marine nitrogen cycle. J. Oceanogr. 61, 921&#x2013;942 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honda, M. C. et al. Comparison of carbon cycle between the western Pacific subarctic and subtropical time-series stations: Highlights of the K2S1 project. J. Oceanogr. 73, 647&#x2013;667 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue, R. et al. Western North Pacific Integrated Physical-Biogeochemical Ocean Observation Experiment (INBOX): Part 2. Biogeochemical responses to eddies and typhoons revealed from shipboard measurements and the S1 biogeochemical moorings during S1-INBOX. J. Mar. Res. 74, 71&#x2013;99 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto, K., Abe, O., Fujiki, T., Sukigara, C. &amp; Mino, Y. Primary productivity at the time-series stations in the northwestern Pacific Ocean: Is the subtropical station unproductive?. J. Oceanogr. 72, 359&#x2013;371 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dugdale, R. &amp; Goering, J. Uptake of new and regenerated forms of nitrogen in primary productivity. Limnol. Oceanogr. 12, 196&#x2013;206 (1967).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honda, M. C. et al. Comparison of sinking particles in the upper 200 m between subarctic station K2 and subtropical station S1 based on drifting sediment trap experiments. J. Oceanogr. 72, 373&#x2013;386 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buesseler, K. O. et al. An assessment of the use of sediment traps for estimating upper ocean particle fluxes. J. Mar. Res. 65, 345&#x2013;416 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honjo, S. The rain of ocean particles and Earth&#x2019;s carbon cycle. Oceanus 40, 4&#x2013;8 (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshikawa, C. et al. Nitrogen isotopes of sinking particles reveal the seasonal transition of the nitrogen source for phytoplankton. Geophys. Res. Lett. 49, e20220GL98670 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minagawa, M. &amp; Wada, E. Nitrogen isotope ratios of red tide organisms in the East China Sea: A characterization of biological nitrogen fixation. Mar. Chem. 19, 245&#x2013;259 (1986).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshikawa, C., Makabe, A., Matsui, Y., Nunoura, T. &amp; Ohkouchi, N. Nitrate isotope distribution in the subarctic and subtropical North Pacific. Geochem. Geophys. Geosyst. 19, 2212&#x2013;2224 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zehr, J. P. &amp; Kudela, R. M. Nitrogen cycle of the open ocean: From genes to ecosystems. Annu. Rev. Mar. Sci. 3, 197&#x2013;225 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson, R. Differential photoinhibition of marine nitrifying bacteria: A possible mechanism for the formation of the primary nitrite maximum. J. Mar. Res. 39, 227&#x2013;238 (1981).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujiki, T. et al. Time-series observations of photosynthetic oxygen production in the subtropical western North Pacific by an underwater profiling buoy system. Limnol. Oceanogr. 65, 1072&#x2013;1084 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyake, Y. &amp; Wada, E. The abundance ratio of 15N/14N in marine environments. Rec. Oceanogr. Works Jpn. 9, 37&#x2013;53 (1967).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sverdrup, H. U. On conditions for the vernal blooming of phytoplankton. ICES J. Mar. Sci. 18, 287&#x2013;295 (1953).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto, K., Sasai, Y., Sasaoka, K., Siswanto, E. &amp; Honda, M. C. The formation of subtropical phytoplankton blooms is dictated by water column stability during winter and spring in the oligotrophic Northwestern North Pacific. J. Geophys. Res. Oceans 126, e2020JC016864 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahadevan, A., D&#x2019;Asaro, E., Lee, C. &amp; Perry, M. J. Eddy-driven stratification initiates North Atlantic spring phytoplankton blooms. Science 337, 54&#x2013;580 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukigara, C. et al. Biophysical interactions stimulate the spring phytoplankton bloom in the North Pacific subtropical recirculation gyre. J. Geophys. Res. Oceans 130, e2025JC022718 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saino, T. &amp; Hattori, A. 15N natural abundance in oceanic suspended particulate matter. Nature 283, 752&#x2013;754 (1980).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minagawa, M. &amp; Wada, E. Stepwise enrichment of <sup>15</sup>N along food chains: Further evidence and the relation between &#x3b4;<sup>15</sup>N and animal age. Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta 48, 1135&#x2013;1140 (1984).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silfer, J. A., Engel, M. H. &amp; Macko, S. A. Kinetic fractionation of stable carbon and nitrogen isotopes during peptide bond hydrolysis: Experimental evidence and geochemical implications. Chem. Geol. 101, 211&#x2013;221 (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobius, J. Isotope fractionation during nitrogen remineralization (ammonification): Implications for nitrogen isotope biogeochemistry. Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta. 105, 422&#x2013;432 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mino, Y., Sukigara, C., Kawakami, H., Wakita, M. &amp; Honda, M. C. Mesopelagic particulate nitrogen dynamics in the subarctic and subtropical regions of the Western North Pacific. Front. Earth Sci. 11, 1176889 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrenfeld, M. J. &amp; Falkowski, P. G. Photosynthetic rates derived from satellite-based chlorophyll concentration. Limnol. Oceanogr. 42, 1&#x2013;20 (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasakawa, M., Ooki, A. &amp; Uematsu, M. Aerosol size distribution during sea fog and its scavenge process of chemical substances over the Northwestern North Pacific. J. Geophys. Res. Atmos. 108(D3), 1&#x2013;9 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel, D. A. et al. Bio-optical modeling of primary production on regional scales: The Bermuda BioOptics project. Deep Sea Res. Part II(48), 1865&#x2013;1896 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westberry, T., Behrenfeld, M. J., Siegel, D. A. &amp; Boss, E. Carbon-based primary productivity modeling with vertically resolved photoacclimation. Glob. Biogeochem. Cycles 22, GB2024 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukigara, C. et al. Sinking dynamics of particulate matter in the subarctic and subtropical regions of the western North Pacific. Deep Sea Res. Part I Oceanogr. Res. Pap. 144, 17&#x2013;27 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson, S. E., Steinberg, D. K. &amp; Buesseler, K. O. Changes in fecal pellet characteristics with depth as indicators of zooplankton repackaging of particles in the mesopelagic zone of the subtropical and subarctic North Pacific Ocean. Deep Sea Res. Part II Top. Stud. Oceanogr. 55(14&#x2013;15), 1636&#x2013;1647 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobari, T. et al. Impacts of the wintertime mesozooplankton community to downward carbon flux in the subarctic and subtropical Pacific Oceans. Deep Sea Res. Part I(81), 78&#x2013;88 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alldredge, A. L., Passow, U. &amp; Logan, B. E. The abundance and significance of a class of large, transparent organic particles in the ocean. Deep Sea Res. Part I 40, 1131&#x2013;1140 (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passow, U. et al. The origin of transparent exopolymer particles (TEP) and their role in the sedimentation of particulate matter. Cont. Shelf Res. 21, 327&#x2013;346 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mari, X., Passow, U., Migon, C., Burd, A. B. &amp; Legendre, L. Transparent exopolymer particles: Effects on carbon cycling in the ocean. Prog. Oceanogr. 151, 13&#x2013;37 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passow, U. Production of transparent exopolymer particles (TEP) by phyto- and bacterioplankton. Mar. Ecol. Prog. Ser. 236, 1&#x2013;12 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega-Retuerta, E., Duarte, C. M. &amp; Reche, I. Significance of bacterial activity for the distribution and dynamics of transparent exopolymer particles in the Mediterranean Sea. Microb. Ecol. 59, 808&#x2013;818 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamanillo, M. et al. Main drivers of transparent exopolymer particle distribution across the surface Atlantic Ocean. Biogeosciences 16, 733&#x2013;749 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buesseler, K. O. &amp; Boyd, P. W. Shedding light on processes that control particle export and flux attenuation in the twilight zone of the open ocean. Limnol. Oceanogr. 54, 1210&#x2013;1232 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel, D. A. et al. Prediction of the export and fate of global ocean net primary production: the EXPORTS Science Plan. Front. Mar. Sci. 3, 22 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel, D. A., DeVries, T., Doney, S. C. &amp; Bell, T. Assessing the sequestration time scales of some ocean-based carbon dioxide reduction strategies. Environ. Res. Lett. 16, 104003 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannides, C. C. S. et al. Seasonal dynamics of midwater zooplankton and relation to particle cycling in the North Pacific Subtropical Gyre. Prog. Oceanogr. 182, 102266 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojtal, P. K. et al. Deconvolving mechanisms of particle flux attenuation using nitrogen isotope analyses of amino acids. Limnol. Oceanogr. 68, 1965&#x2013;1981 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minor, E. C., Wakeham, S. G. &amp; Lee, C. Changes in the molecular-level characteristics of sinking marine particles with water column depth. Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta 67, 4277&#x2013;4288 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passow, U. &amp; De La Rocha, C. L. Accumulation of mineral ballast on organic aggregates. Glob. Biogeochem. Cycles 20, GB1013 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briggs, N. et al. High-resolution observations of aggregate flux during a sub-polar North Atlantic spring bloom. Deep Sea Res. Part I(58), 1031&#x2013;1039 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briggs, N., Dall&#x2019;Olmo, G. &amp; Claustre, H. Major role of particle fragmentation in regulating biological sequestration of CO2 by the oceans. Science 367, 791&#x2013;793 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engel, A., Szlosek, J., Abramson, L., Liu, Z. &amp; Lee, C. Investigating the effect of ballasting by CaCO<sub>3</sub> in Emiliania huxleyi: I. Formation, settling velocities and physical properties of aggregates. Deep Sea Res. Part II Top. Stud. Oceanogr. 56, 1396&#x2013;1407 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, C. et al. Particulate organic matter and ballast fluxes measured using time-series and settling velocity sediment traps in the northwestern Mediterranean Sea. Deep Sea Res. Part II Top. Stud. Oceanogr. 56, 1420&#x2013;1436 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balch, W. M., Bowler, B. C., Drapeau, D. T., Poulton, A. &amp; Holligan, P. Biominerals and the vertical flux of particulate organic carbon from the surface ocean. Geophys. Res. Lett. 37, L22605 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mari, X. &amp; Burd, A. Seasonal size spectra of transparent exopolymer particles (TEP) in a coastal sea and comparison with those predicted using coagulation theory. Mar. Ecol. Prog. Ser. 163, 63&#x2013;76 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Y., Burd, A. B. &amp; Rau, M. J. The deformation of marine snow enables its disaggregation in simulated oceanic shear. Front. Mar. Sci. 10, 1224518 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, C.-S. et al. Stickiness of extracellular polymeric substances on different surfaces via magnetic tweezers. Sci. Total Environ. 757, 143766 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi, Y., Wada, S., Seto, M. &amp; Adachi, Y. Cohesive bond strength of marine aggregates and its role in fragmentation. Front. Mar. Sci. 10, 1167169 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akshaya, T. R., Sudhakar, S., Mani, E. &amp; Murali, K. Effect of biopolymer concentration on the kinetics of marine snow formation. Deep Sea Res. Part I Oceanogr. Res. Pap. 207, 104291 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd, A. B. &amp; Jackson, G. A. Particle aggregation. Annu. Rev. Mar. Sci. 1, 65&#x2013;90 (2009).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>