<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41490065</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Spatial-temporal evolution and influencing factors of sudden environmental accidents in China from 2008 to 2022.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0339526</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0339526</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0339526</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0339526</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The spatiotemporal evolution characteristics and influencing factors of sudden environmental accidents are analyzed by employing exploratory spatial analysis and Pearson correlation analysis, based on the statistical data of sudden environmental accidents in 31 provinces, municipalities, and autonomous regions in China from 2008 to 2022. The results provide valuable insights for the prevention and treatment of sudden environmental pollution emergencies. The results showed that: (1) the total of sudden environmental accidents exhibited an inverted V shaped structure with 2013 as the turning point, showing an overall decreasing trend in China. (2) The seasons when the sudden environmental accidents occurred from the highest to lowest proportions were autumn (29.01%), summer (26.29%), spring (24.80%), and winter (20.19%). The months with the highest frequency were May and July, while October and December had the lowest. The dates with the most occurrences were the 5th, 7th, 4th, 2nd, 11th, and 9th, while the 31st, 30th, 29th, and 27th were the lowest. Regarding weekdays, Monday (16.56%), Wednesday (15.94%), and Thursday (14.38%) were the highest proportions, while Sunday (12.50%) was the lowest. (3) Spatial distribution revealed an overall imbalance, with the eastern coastal comprehensive economic zone being the highest frequency of environmental accidents, followed by the middle reaches of the Yellow River comprehensive economic zone, and the northeast comprehensive economic zone having the lowest. Provinces with the highest number of sudden environmental accidents were mainly in Shanghai (1129), Shaanxi Province (472), and Jiangsu Province (419). Based on the cold and hot spot analysis, H-H areas were mainly located in the southeast coastal regions, L-L areas were concentrated in the western and northeastern regions, and L-H areas were distributed in the central regions. (4) Pearson correlation analysis indicated that investment in the treatment of industrial pollution as percentage of GDP and secondary industry output value as Percentage of GDP were the main driving factors for sudden environmental accidents in China. Per capita GDP, pollutant emissions, and the total of letters and phone calls regarding environmental pollution had inhibitory effects on the occurrence of sudden environmental accidents, while single factors had relatively minor impacts. To effectively prevent and control sudden environmental accidents, it is necessary to improve the risk management system for sudden environmental accidents and strengthen monitoring and management of accident-prone industries, dates, and regions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Yan et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7407-1934</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Geographic Sciences, Xinyang Normal University, Xinyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henan Key Laboratory for Synergistic Prevention of Water and Soil Environmental Pollution, Xinyang Normal University, Xinyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Shi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Geographic Sciences, Xinyang Normal University, Xinyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Shihan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Geographic Sciences, Xinyang Normal University, Xinyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xinying</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Geographic Sciences, Xinyang Normal University, Xinyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xuemei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Geographic Sciences, Xinyang Normal University, Xinyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Geographic Sciences, Xinyang Normal University, Xinyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062211" MajorTopicYN="N">Spatio-Temporal Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012621" MajorTopicYN="N">Seasons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004787" MajorTopicYN="Y">Environmental Pollution</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000059" MajorTopicYN="Y">Accidents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The author declares no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41490065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12768231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0339526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-25601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The Ministry of Ecology and Environment. Emergency Management Measures of Emergency Environmental Events. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Wang W. The impact of major pollution incidents on environmental performance. Journal of Cleaner Production. 2024;434:139975. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.139975</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.139975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du L, Wang H, Xu H. Analysis of spatial-temporal association and factors influencing environmental pollution incidents in China. Environmental Impact Assessment Review. 2020;82:106384. doi: 10.1016/j.eiar.2020.106384</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eiar.2020.106384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan J, Mao S, Xie P, Lang J, Li A, Tong J, et al. Key emergency response technologies for abrupt air pollution accidents in China. J Environ Sci (China). 2023;123:235&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1016/j.jes.2022.03.030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jes.2022.03.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36521987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley MM. NARAC: an emergency response resource for predicting the atmospheric dispersion and assessing the consequences of airborne radionuclides. J Environ Radioact. 2007;96(1&#x2013;3):116&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvrad.2007.01.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvrad.2007.01.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17507121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JZ, Li SY, Li LL, Zhang M. Thoughts on whole-process environmental risk management in China. Environmental Protection. 2018;46(15):41&#x2013;3. doi: 10.14026/j.cnki.0253-9705.2018.15.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14026/j.cnki.0253-9705.2018.15.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo QW, Bing YX, Chen SL, Huang DW, Hu LC, Chang S. Pattern of evolution, experience of response, and suggestions of prevention and control of environmental emergencies in China based on typical case studies. Chinese Journal of Environmental Engineering. 2021;15(7):2223&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li QQ, Xie C, Tang HL. Research on emergency monitoring technology for sudden environmental pollution accidents in water bodies. Environment and Development. 2019;31(01):123&#x2013;5. doi: 10.16647/j.cnki.cn15-1369/X.2019.01.069</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16647/j.cnki.cn15-1369/X.2019.01.069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Huang YJ, Liu PH, Wang G, Bi J. Research on regional comprehensive environmental risk assessment method system. China Environmental Science. 2020;40(12):5468&#x2013;74. doi: 10.19674/j.cnki.issn1000-6923.2020.0605</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19674/j.cnki.issn1000-6923.2020.0605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen ZX, Ding Y, Mao XH, Wang Z, Jia HF. Source identification of accidental water pollution in a tidal river network based on a water environment model and database. Journal of Tsinghua University (Science and Technology). 2017;57(11):1170&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang JP, Wang P, Liu J, Yuan YX. Methodological analysis on the research and practices on the warning and emergency response to river chemical spill incidents. Acta Scientiae Circumstantiae. 2017;37(09):3621&#x2013;8. doi: 10.13671/j.hjkxxb.2017.0089</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13671/j.hjkxxb.2017.0089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XQ, Mao XQ, Liu SQ. Evaluation methodology of environmental accidents loss and a case study. Ecological Economy. 2011;40(01):24&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao GZ, Yu F, Wang JN, Zhu WY, Wang D, Zhou XF. Situation, Problems and Countermeasures of Risk Prevention and Control of Environmental Emergencies in the Yangtze River Economic Belt. Chinese Journal of Environmental Management. 2018;10(01):81&#x2013;5. doi: 10.16868/j.cnki.1674-6252.2018.01.081</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16868/j.cnki.1674-6252.2018.01.081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai ZJ, Liang CY, Zhao SP. Research on emergency environmental accidents grade evaluation. Application Research of Computers. 2014;31(11):3217&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao G, Yang L, Liu L, Ma Z, Wang J, Bi J. Environmental incidents in China: Lessons from 2006 to 2015. Sci Total Environ. 2018;633:1165&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.03.271</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.03.271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29758868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu F, Cao GZ, Qi J, Zhao D, Zhang YS, Tian C. Status Quo and prospect of ecological environment risk management and damage compensation in China. Chinese Journal of Environmental Management. 2021;13(05):143&#x2013;50. doi: 10.16868/j.cnki.1674-6252.2021.05.143</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16868/j.cnki.1674-6252.2021.05.143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu G-H, Wang F-F, Liu X-Z, Li W-H, Xiang Y-B. Spatiotemporal characteristics and influencing factors of environment emergency incident in China from 1991 to 2018. Huan Jing Ke Xue. 2023;44(1):572&#x2013;82. doi: 10.13227/j.hjkx.202201182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13227/j.hjkx.202201182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36635845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, L&#xfc; Y, He G, Wang T, Luo W, Shi Y. Spatial and temporal changes of emerging environmental pollution accidents and impact factors in China. Huan Jing Ke Xue. 2008;29(9):2684&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19068665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding L, Huang YL, Liu YL, Liu C, Cheng SG. Spatiotemporal variability of sudden environmental pollution incidents and influencing factors in China, 1995-2012. Progress in Geography. 2015;34(06):749&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Lv JP, Pei YY, Guo CS, Xu J. Analysis of the characteristics of environmental emergencies in China. Journal of Environmental Engineering Technology. 2021;11(02):401&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Xu M, Zhao Y, Wang S, Tao M, Wang Y. Spatial-temporal distribution and evolutionary characteristics of water environment sudden pollution incidents in China from 2006 to 2018. Sci Total Environ. 2021;801:149677. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.149677</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.149677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34418617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan J, Wang X, Wang T, Zhang X. Research on the spatiotemporal evolution and influencing factors of sudden environmental incidents in China from 2008 to 2021. Pol J Environ Stud. 2024;34(1):891&#x2013;903. doi: 10.15244/pjoes/186481</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15244/pjoes/186481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei B, Liang J, Xie LY, Liu J. Characteristics of environmental emergencies in Gansu Province from 2011 to 2019 and prevention and control countermeasures. Journal of Northwest Normal University (Natural Science). 2021;57(06):124&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Bureau of Statistics of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China. Chinese Statistical Yearbook. Beijing: China Statistics Press; 2009. 20&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Bureau of Statistics of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China, Ministry of Ecology and Environment of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China. China Statistical Yearbook on Environment. Beijing: China Statistics Press; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Editorial Department of Journal of Safety and Environment. Journal of Safety and Environment. Beijing: Beijing Institute of Technology; 2008. https://navi.cnki.net/knavi/detail?p=Y0gULjk4ovWJ7jKw-F8BpQDpfz-UCmtLLHN6S94Q70NrcEiiWoIjKWz7sCRE0o7icQpxIpNuAjtZYqktwiRe6W_RGlRtbBLkiwRX0Vgplvs=&amp;uniplatform=NZKPT</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan J, Wang X, Zhang J, Qin Z, Wang T, Tian Q, et al. Research on the spatial and temporal patterns of ozone concentration and population health effects in the Central Plains Urban Agglomeration from 2017 to 2020. PLoS One. 2024;19(5):e0303274. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0303274</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0303274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11098328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38753663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jie MH, Li LY. Environmental governance performance measurement and spatio temporal evolution of eight comprehensive economic zones in China. Chinese Journal of Population, Resources and Environment. 2023;33(09):86&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H, Hu X, Zhao DN, Xie HY, Zhang XJ, Chen C, et al. Status quo and main influencing factors of environmental emergencies in China. Environmental Protection Science. 2022;49(03):130&#x2013;8. doi: 10.16803/j.cnki.issn.1004-6216.2022070016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16803/j.cnki.issn.1004-6216.2022070016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng LX. Study on the distribution characteristics and influencing factors of sudden environmental emergencies in China during 2011-2020. Modern Chemical Research. 2022;(01):98&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>