<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41345040</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2923</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>60</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical education</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Educ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Residents' perceptions of impaired wellness in China: Accepting the inevitable, questioning the preventable.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>431</StartPage><EndPage>441</EndPage><MedlinePgn>431-441</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/medu.70107</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Impaired wellness among residents has become a global concern, with burnout, stress and fatigue linked to negative outcomes for both residents and patients. To date, most of the existing research has come from Western contexts, where cultural norms and training structures may significantly differ from those in other regions. However, there remains limited understanding of how residents in non-Western settings experience and interpret impaired wellness. This study aims to explore the perceptions and experiences of residents' impaired wellness within the context of residency training in China.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a constructivist qualitative study. Participants were recruited through purposive and snowball sampling from a teaching hospital in Shanghai. Semi-structured interviews were conducted in Chinese between March 2024 and February 2025, guided by a six-dimensional wellness framework developed from existing literature. We used reflexive thematic analysis to analyse the data both deductively and inductively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Chinese residents perceived some degree of wellness impairment across physical, psychological and social dimension as acceptable, often framing such impairments as contributing to professional and personal growth, reflecting cultural values emphasising acceptance of and growth through hardship. In contrast, impairments in the intellectual and financial dimensions, exacerbated by unfair compensation, limited supervision and research pressure, were seen as unreasonable yet preventable. Residents' recognition of these challenges as rooted in systemic and structural conditions of residency training, largely beyond their control, often led to resignation, passive endurance, and in some cases, consideration of leaving the profession. Harmonious work relationships were described as central to navigating impaired wellness, serving as vital buffers when present but vulnerabilities when absent, largely echoing cultural ideals of harmony.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study sheds light on how the inherently demanding nature of clinical practice, cultural values and local systemic and structural conditions of residency training intersect to shape residents' perceptions and experiences of impaired wellness.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Association for the Study of Medical Education and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Guoyang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2335-1984</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Professions Education, Faculty of Health, Medicine and Life Sciences, Maastricht University, Maastricht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Runzhi</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2302-7305</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Burn Surgery, Changhai Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Jiale</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-6231-5670</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yifan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0189-7900</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xihui</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-8050-5639</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Education Centre, Changhai Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ji</LastName><ForeName>Shizhao</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5083-288X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Burn Surgery, Changhai Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Med Educ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605655</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0308-0110</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007396" MajorTopicYN="Y">Internship and Residency</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002055" MajorTopicYN="Y">Burnout, Professional</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007407" MajorTopicYN="N">Interviews as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001291" MajorTopicYN="Y">Attitude of Health Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010465" MajorTopicYN="N">Perception</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41345040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/medu.70107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Wallace JE, Lemaire JB, Ghali WA. Physician wellness: a missing quality indicator. Lancet. 2009;374(9702):1714&#x2010;1721. doi:10.1016/S0140&#x2010;6736(09)61424&#x2010;0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas LR, Ripp JA, West CP. Charter on physician well&#x2010;being. Jama. 2018;319(15):1541&#x2010;1542. doi:10.1001/jama.2018.1331</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ripp JA, Privitera MR, West CP, et al. Well&#x2010;being in graduate medical education: a call for action. Acad Med. 2017;92(7):914&#x2010;917. doi:10.1097/ACM.0000000000001735</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratanawongsa N, Wright SM, Carrese JA. Well&#x2010;being in residency: effects on relationships with patients, interactions with colleagues, performance, and motivation. Patient Educ Couns. 2008;72(2):194&#x2010;200. doi:10.1016/j.pec.2008.04.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefebvre DC. Perspective: resident physician wellness: a new hope. Acad Med. 2012;87(5):598&#x2010;602. doi:10.1097/ACM.0b013e31824d47ff</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bynum W IV, Varpio L, Teunissen P. Why impaired wellness may be inevitable in medicine, and why that may not be a bad thing. Med Educ. 2021;55(1):16&#x2010;22. doi:10.1111/medu.14284</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sla B. Physician burnout: a global crisis. Lancet. 2016;388(10193):2272&#x2010;2281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyrbye LN, West CP, Satele D, et al. Burnout among U.S. medical students, residents, and early career physicians relative to the general U.S. population. Acad Med. 2014;89(3):443&#x2010;451. doi:10.1097/ACM.0000000000000134</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas NK. Resident Burnout. Jama. 2004;292(23):2880&#x2010;2889. doi:10.1001/jama.292.23.2880</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai S, Chang Q, Yao D, Zhang Y, Wu B, Zhao Y. Anxiety in residents in China: prevalence and risk factors in a multicenter study. Acad Med. 2021;96(5):718&#x2010;727. doi:10.1097/ACM.0000000000003913</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Caspari JH, Sun X, et al. Risk and protective factors for burnout among physicians from standardized residency training programs in Shanghai: a cross&#x2010;sectional study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2020;20(1):965. doi:10.1186/s12913&#x2010;020&#x2010;05816&#x2010;z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Huang X, Li H, Zeng X, Shen T. Survey results of job status of residents in a standardized residency training program. BMC Med Educ. 2019;19(1):281. doi:10.1186/s12909&#x2010;019&#x2010;1718&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford K, Oda J. Family medicine residency training and burnout: a qualitative study. Can Med Ed J. 2014;5(1):e13. doi:10.36834/cmej.36664</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prins JT, Gazendam&#x2010;Donofrio SM, Dillingh GS, van de Wiel HBM, van der Heijden FMMA, Hoekstra&#x2010;Weebers JEHM. The relationship between reciprocity and burnout in Dutch medical residents. Med Educ. 2008;42(7):721&#x2010;728. doi:10.1111/j.1365&#x2010;2923.2008.03041.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers E, Polonijo AN, Carpiano RM. Getting by with a little help from friends and colleagues: testing how residents' social support networks affect loneliness and burnout. Can Fam Physician. 2016;62(11):e677&#x2010;e683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian L, Pu J, Liu Y, et al. Relationship between burnout and career choice regret among Chinese neurology postgraduates. BMC Med Educ. 2019;19(1):162. doi:10.1186/s12909&#x2010;019&#x2010;1601&#x2010;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S, Zhu W, Li H, Wang Z, Wang M. Relationship between job burnout and occupational stress among doctors in China. Stress Health. 2008;24(2):143&#x2010;149. doi:10.1002/smi.1169</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Zhang M, Lu Z, et al. Turnover intention and related factors among resident physicians in China under the standardised residency training programme: a cross&#x2010;sectional survey. BMJ Open. 2022;12(4):e061922. doi:10.1136/bmjopen&#x2010;2022&#x2010;061922</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stucky ER, Dresselhaus TR, Dollarhide A, et al. Intern to attending: assessing stress among physicians. Acad Med. 2009;84(2):251&#x2010;257. doi:10.1097/ACM.0b013e3181938aad</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou AY, Panagioti M, Esmail A, Agius R, van Tongeren M, Bower P. Factors associated with burnout and stress in trainee physicians: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3(8):e2013761. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.13761</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu RQ, Davidson J, Van Hooren TA, et al. Impostorism and anxiety contribute to burnout among resident physicians. Med Teach. 2022;44(7):758&#x2010;764. doi:10.1080/0142159X.2022.2028751</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West CP, Huschka MM, Novotny PJ, et al. Association of perceived medical errors with resident distress and empathy: a prospective longitudinal study. Jama. 2006;296(9):1071&#x2010;1078. doi:10.1001/jama.296.9.1071</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mata DA, Ramos MA, Bansal N, et al. Prevalence of depression and depressive symptoms among resident physicians: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Jama. 2015;314(22):2373&#x2010;2383. doi:10.1001/jama.2015.15845</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahrenkopf AM, Sectish TC, Barger LK, et al. Rates of medication errors among depressed and burnt out residents: prospective cohort study. BMJ. 2008;336(7642):488&#x2010;491. doi:10.1136/bmj.39469.763218.BE</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legassie J, Zibrowski EM, Goldszmidt MA. Measuring resident well&#x2010;being: impostorism and burnout syndrome in residency. J Gen Intern Med. 2008;23(7):1090&#x2010;1094. doi:10.1007/s11606&#x2010;008&#x2010;0536&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Kong X, Qian M, et al. The effect of work&#x2010;family conflict on employee well&#x2010;being among physicians: the mediating role of job satisfaction and work engagement. BMC Psychol. 2024;12(1):530. doi:10.1186/s40359&#x2010;024&#x2010;02026&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckleberry&#x2010;Hunt J, Kirkpatrick H, Barbera T. The problems with burnout research. Acad Med. 2018;93(3):367&#x2010;370. doi:10.1097/ACM.0000000000001890</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eskander J, Rajaguru PP, Greenberg PB. Evaluating wellness interventions for resident physicians: a systematic review. J Grad Med Educ. 2021;13(1):58&#x2010;69. doi:10.4300/JGME&#x2010;D&#x2010;20&#x2010;00359.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyrbye L, Shanafelt T. A narrative review on burnout experienced by medical students and residents. Med Educ. 2016;50(1):132&#x2010;149. doi:10.1111/medu.12927</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckleberry&#x2010;Hunt J, Van Dyke A, Lick D, et al. Changing the conversation from burnout to wellness: physician well&#x2010;being in residency training programs. J Grad Med Educ. 2009;1(2):225&#x2010;230. doi:10.4300/JGME&#x2010;D&#x2010;09&#x2010;00026.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slama EM, Batarseh L, Bryan F, et al. Wellbeing as defined by resident physicians: a qualitative study. Am Surg. 2023;89(6):2861&#x2010;2864. doi:10.1177/00031348211065092</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prentice S, Benson J, Dorstyn D, Elliott T. Wellbeing conceptualizations in family medicine trainees: a hermeneutic review. Teach Learn Med. 2022;34(1):60&#x2010;68. doi:10.1080/10401334.2021.1919519</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hale AJ, Ricotta DN, Freed J, Smith CC, Huang GC. Adapting Maslow's hierarchy of needs as a framework for resident wellness. Teach Learn Med. 2019;31(1):109&#x2010;118. doi:10.1080/10401334.2018.1456928</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corgan S, Ford Winkel A, Sugarman R, Young JQ. From burnout to wholehearted engagement: a qualitative exploration of psychiatry residents' experience of stress. Acad Med. 2021;96(5):709&#x2010;717. doi:10.1097/ACM.0000000000003912</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harsh JS, Lawrence TJ, Koran&#x2010;Scholl JB, Bonnema R. A new perspective on burnout: snapshots of the medical resident experience. Clin Med Insights Psychiatry. 2019;10:10. doi:10.1177/1179557319858991</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odom A, Romain A, Phillips J. Using photovoice to explore family medicine residents' burnout experiences and resiliency strategies. Fam Med. 2022;54(4):277&#x2010;284. doi:10.22454/FamMed.2022.985247</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prentice S, Elliott T, Dorstyn D, Benson J. Burnout, wellbeing and how they relate: a qualitative study in general practice trainees. Med Educ. 2023;57(3):243&#x2010;255. doi:10.1111/medu.14931</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain A, Tabatabai R, Vo A, Riddell J. &#x201c;I have nothing else to give&#x201d;: a qualitative exploration of emergency medicine residents' perceptions of burnout. Teach Learn Med. 2021;33(4):407&#x2010;415. doi:10.1080/10401334.2021.1875833</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coverdill JE, Bittner J IV, Park M, Pipkin W, Mellinger J. Fatigue as impairment or educational necessity? Insights into surgical culture. Acad Med. 2011;86(10 Suppl):S69&#x2010;S72. doi:10.1097/ACM.0b013e31822a6b40</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor TS, Watling CJ, Teunissen PW, Dornan T, Lingard L. Principles of fatigue in residency education: a qualitative study. CMAJ Open. 2016;4(2):E200&#x2010;E204. doi:10.9778/cmajo.20150086</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Law M, Lam M, Wu D, Veinot P, Mylopoulos M. Changes in personal relationships during residency and their effects on resident wellness: a qualitative study. Acad Med. 2017;92(11):1601&#x2010;1606. doi:10.1097/ACM.0000000000001711</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyman JH, Doolittle B. Thriving in residency: a qualitative study. J Gen Intern Med. 2022;37(9):2173&#x2010;2179. doi:10.1007/s11606&#x2010;022&#x2010;07504&#x2010;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeks LM, Ramsey J, Lyons M, Spencer AL, Lee WW. Wellness and work: mixed messages in residency training. J Gen Intern Med. 2019;34(7):1352&#x2010;1355. doi:10.1007/s11606&#x2010;019&#x2010;04952&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melvin A, Pearson A, Carrieri D, et al. Support for hospital doctors' workplace well&#x2010;being in England: the care under pressure 3 realist evaluation. BMJ Qual Saf. 2025;34(7):443&#x2010;456. doi:10.1136/bmjqs&#x2010;2024&#x2010;017698</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendelsohn D. Self in medicine: determinants of physician well&#x2010;being and future directions in improving wellness. Med Educ. 2022;56(1):48&#x2010;55. doi:10.1111/medu.14671</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aalto AM, Heponiemi T, Josefsson K, Arffman M, Elovainio M. Social relationships in physicians' work moderate relationship between workload and wellbeing&#x2014;9&#x2010;year follow&#x2010;up study. Eur J Public Health. 2018;28(5):798&#x2010;804. doi:10.1093/eurpub/ckx232</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira T. Doctors' pay in the United Kingdom: evaluating the broader impacts of change. Postgrad Med J. 2024;100(1180):65&#x2010;67. doi:10.1093/postmj/qgad099</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mello M, Moscelli G, Laliotis I, Sayli M. Work Pay, Contractual Changes and Employee Attrition: Evidence from NHS Trainee Doctors. 2024. 10.2139/ssrn.4979603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson HCP, Abrams S, Simpkin BA. Drexit: understanding why junior doctors leave their training programs to train overseas: an observational study of UK physicians. Health Sci Rep. 2021;4(4):e419. doi:10.1002/hsr2.419</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards JL, Brook K. How the physician's financial wellness could impact patient safety. Postgrad Med J. 2024;100(1182):276&#x2010;278. doi:10.1093/postmj/qgad076</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg AL, Doherty DV, Cevallos JR, Tahir P, Lebares CC. Making the financial case for surgical resident well&#x2010;being: a scoping review. Ann Surg. 2023;277(3):397&#x2010;404. doi:10.1097/SLA.0000000000005719</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He K, Sell NM, Chugh P, et al. Improving the financial wellness of general surgery residents: a nationwide survey. Am J Surg. 2022;224(3):888&#x2010;892. doi:10.1016/j.amjsurg.2022.04.035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster E, Biery N, Dostal J, Larson D. Supporting resident well&#x2010;being through an integrated advising and assessment process. Fam Med. 2012;44(10):731&#x2010;734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebares CC, Guvva EV, Olaru M, et al. Efficacy of mindfulness&#x2010;based cognitive training in surgery: additional analysis of the mindful surgeon pilot randomized clinical trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2019;2(5):e194108. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2019.4108</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thimmapuram J, Pargament R, Sibliss K, Grim R, Risques R, Toorens E. Effect of heartfulness meditation on burnout, emotional wellness, and telomere length in health care professionals. J Commun Hosp Intern Med Perspect. 2017;7(1):21&#x2010;27. doi:10.1080/20009666.2016.1270806</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simard AA, Henry M. Impact of a short yoga intervention on medical students' health: a pilot study. Med Teach. 2009;31(10):950&#x2010;952. doi:10.3109/01421590902874063</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheepers RA, Emke H, Epstein RM, Lombarts KMJMH. The impact of mindfulness&#x2010;based interventions on doctors' well&#x2010;being and performance: a systematic review. Med Educ. 2020;54(2):138&#x2010;149. doi:10.1111/medu.14020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann K, MacLeod A. Constructivism: learning theories and approaches to research. In: Cleland J, Durning SJ, eds. Researching medical education. John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd; 2015:25&#x2010;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams T, Bezner J, Steinhardt M. The conceptualization and measurement of perceived wellness: integrating balance across and within dimensions. Am J Health Promot. 1997;11(3):208&#x2010;218. doi:10.4278/0890&#x2010;1171&#x2010;11.3.208</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbin CB, Pangrazi RP. Toward a uniform definition of wellness: a commentary. Vol. 3. President's council on physical fitness and sports research digest; 2001:3&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roscoe LJ. Wellness: a review of theory and measurement for counselors. J Couns Dev. 2011;87(2):216&#x2010;226. doi:10.1002/j.1556&#x2010;6678.2009.tb00570.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavakol M, O'Brien D. Psychometrics for physicians: everything a clinician needs to know about assessments in medical education. Int J Med Educ. 2022;13:100&#x2010;106. doi:10.5116/ijme.625f.bfb1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwong SP, Yu SR, Liao KC, Liao SC, Hsiao CT, Chaou CH. From learner to provider: navigating role tensions in postgraduate medical training through activity theory. Perspect Med Educ. 2025;14(1):55&#x2010;65. doi:10.5334/pme.1499</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Federation for Medical Education/Organization. WFME declaration on institutions' responsibility to support medical students, physicians in postgraduate education and physicians in practice. WFME; 2025. [cited Aug 1].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L. Chinese well&#x2010;being. In: Bond MH, ed. Oxford handbook of Chinese psychology. Oxford University Press; 2010:327&#x2010;341. doi:10.1093/oxfordhb/9780199541850.013.0021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Q, Wong DFK. Culturally sensitive conceptualization of resilience: a multidimensional model of Chinese resilience. Transcult Psychiatry. 2021;58(3):323&#x2010;334. doi:10.1177/1363461520951306</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang D, Zhou H. The comparison between Chinese and Western well&#x2010;being. Open J Soc Sci. 2017;05(11):181&#x2010;188. doi:10.4236/jss.2017.511013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng C, Cheung SF, Chio J, Chan MP. Cultural meaning of perceived control: a meta&#x2010;analysis of locus of control and psychological symptoms across 18 cultural regions. Psychol Bull. 2013;139(1):152&#x2010;188. doi:10.1037/a0028596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mencius. The works of Mencius. Legge J, translator. At the Author's [London Missionary Society's Printing Office]; 1861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CC, Chen X&#x2010;P, Huang S. Chinese Guanxi: an integrative review and new directions for future research. Manag Organ Rev. 2015;9(1):167&#x2010;207. doi:10.1111/more.12010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang KK. Chinese relationalism: theoretical construction and methodological considerations. J Theory Soc Behav. 2001;30(2):155&#x2010;178. doi:10.1111/1468&#x2010;5914.00124</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y. Guanxi: principles, philosophies, and implications. Hum Syst Manage. 1997;16(1):43&#x2010;51. doi:10.3233/HSM&#x2010;1997&#x2010;16106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei X, Li Q. The Confucian value of harmony and its influence on Chinese social interaction. Cross&#x2010;Cult Commun. 2013;9(1):60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peacock J. Suffering in mind: the aetiology of suffering in early Buddhism. Contemp Buddhism. 2008;9(2):209&#x2010;226. doi:10.1080/14639940802574068</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windle G. What is resilience? A review and concept analysis. Rev Clin Gerontol. 2011;21(2):152&#x2010;169. doi:10.1017/S0959259810000420</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng C, Hui W&#x2010;m, Lam S&#x2010;k. Perceptual style and behavioral pattern of individuals with functional gastrointestinal disorders. Health Psychol. 2000;19(2):146&#x2010;154. doi:10.1037/0278&#x2010;6133.19.2.146</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X, Zhang J. Factor analysis and psychometric evaluation of the Connor&#x2010;Davidson Resilience Scale (CD&#x2010;RISC) with Chinese people. Soc Behav Pers: an Int J. 2007;35(1):19&#x2010;30. doi:10.2224/sbp.2007.35.1.19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Kao S&#x2010;F, Chang T&#x2010;T, Wu HP, Jin Z. The individual&#x2010;and social&#x2010;oriented Chinese bicultural self: a subcultural analysis contrasting mainland Chinese and Taiwanese. Soc Behav Pers. 2008;36(3):337&#x2010;346. doi:10.2224/sbp.2008.36.3.337</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng AK, Ho DY, Wong SS, Smith I. In search of the good life: a cultural odyssey in the east and west. Genet Soc Gen Psychol Monogr. 2003;129(4):317&#x2010;363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitayama S, Markus HR. The pursuit of happiness and the realization of sympathy: cultural patterns of self, social relations, and well&#x2010;being; 2000. doi:10.7551/mitpress/2242.003.0010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SL, Chen Q, Liu Y. Medical resident training in China. Int J Med Educ. 2018;9:108&#x2010;110. doi:10.5116/ijme.5ad1.d8be</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J, Li W, Chen L. Doctors in China: improving quality through modernisation of residency education. Lancet. 2016;388(10054):1922&#x2010;1929. doi:10.1016/S0140&#x2010;6736(16)00582&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinese Medical Doctor Association/Organization. Common program requirement [Internet]. CMDA; 2022 [cited Jul 16]. http://www.hbydsy.com/20230530121144853108.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varpio L, Ajjawi R, Monrouxe LV, O'Brien BC, Rees CE. Shedding the cobra effect: problematising thematic emergence, triangulation, saturation and member checking. Med Educ. 2017;51(1):40&#x2010;50. doi:10.1111/medu.13124</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual Res Psychol. 2006;3(2):77&#x2010;101. doi:10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Supporting best practice in reflexive thematic analysis reporting in palliative medicine: a review of published research and introduction to the reflexive thematic analysis reporting guidelines (RTARG). Palliat Med. 2024;38(6):608&#x2010;616. doi:10.1177/02692163241234800</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiger ME, Varpio L. Thematic analysis of qualitative data: AMEE guide no. 131. Med Teach. 2020;42(8):846&#x2010;854. doi:10.1080/0142159X.2020.1755030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldwin DC Jr, Daugherty SR, Ryan PM. How residents view their clinical supervision: a reanalysis of classic national survey data. J Grad Med Educ. 2010;2(1):37&#x2010;45. doi:10.4300/JGME&#x2010;D&#x2010;09&#x2010;00081.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farnan JM, Petty LA, Georgitis E, et al. A systematic review: the effect of clinical supervision on patient and residency education outcomes. Acad Med. 2012;87(4):428&#x2010;442. doi:10.1097/ACM.0b013e31824822cc</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Underwood PW, Balch JA, Filiberto AC, et al. Resident and fellow performance and supervision in surgical oncology procedures. J am Coll Surg. 2024;239(6):528&#x2010;537. doi:10.1097/XCS.0000000000001131</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson MD, Smigielski EM, Naifeh MM, Abramson EL, Todd C, Li STT. Increasing scholarly activity productivity during residency: a systematic review. Acad Med. 2017;92(2):250&#x2010;266. doi:10.1097/ACM.0000000000001169</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan H&#x2010;F, Xu W&#x2010;D, Hu H&#x2010;Y. Young Chinese doctors and the pressure of publication. Lancet. 2013;381(9864):e4. doi:10.1016/S0140&#x2010;6736(13)60174&#x2010;9</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>