<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41600397</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>PSgANet: Polar Sequence-Guided Attention Network for Edge-Related Defect Classification in Contact Lenses.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">601</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26020601</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The integration of artificial intelligence (AI) into industrial processes is a promising method for enhancing operational efficiency and quality control. In particular, contact lens manufacturing requires specialized artificial intelligence technologies owing to stringent safety requirements. This study introduces a novel approach that employs polar coordinate transformation and a customized deep learning model, the Polar Sequence-guided Attention Network (PSgANet), to improve the accuracy of defect detection in the rim-connected zone (RCZ) of contact lenses. PSgANet is specifically designed to process polar coordinate-transformed image data by integrating sequence learning and attention mechanisms to maximise the capability for detecting and classifying defective patterns. This model converts irregularities along the edges of contact lenses into linear arrays via polar coordinate transformation, enabling a clearer and more consistent identification of defective regions. To achieve this, we applied sequence learning architectures such as GRU, LSTM, and Transformer within PSgANet and compared their performances with those of conventional models, including GoogleNetv4, EfficientNet, and Vision Transformer. The experimental results demonstrated that the PSgANet models outperformed the existing CNN-based models. In particular, the LSTM-based PSgANet achieved the highest accuracy and balanced precision and recall metrics, showing up to a 7.75% improvement in accuracy compared with the traditional GoogleNetv4 model. These results suggest that the proposed method is an effective tool for detecting and classifying defects within the RCZ during contact lens manufacturing processes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Sung-Hoon</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-5641-3724</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, Chungbuk National University, Cheongju 28644, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Joo</LastName><ForeName>In</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4704-9501</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, Chungbuk National University, Cheongju 28644, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoo</LastName><ForeName>Kwan-Hee</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2299-4216</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, Chungbuk National University, Cheongju 28644, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>IITP-2025-RS-2020-II201462</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Science and ICT</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">attention guided network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">contact lens</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">manufacturing quality control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polar coordinate transformation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sequence learning</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The data used in this study were provided under a corporate agreement and are subject to confidentiality obligations. All authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41600397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12845803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26020601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26020601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Holmstr&#xf6;m J. From AI to digital transformation: The AI readiness framework. Bus. Horizons. 2022;65:329&#x2013;339. doi: 10.1016/j.bushor.2021.03.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bushor.2021.03.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jo S.-J., Kang S.-H. Industrial Applications of Machine Learning (Artificial Intelligence) Ind. Eng. Mag. 2016;23:34&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J.-M. Trends in AI technology development for manufacturing technology innovation. Proc. Korean Inst. Illum. Electr. Install. Eng. 2020;34:12&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee E., Bae H., Kim H., Han H., Lee Y., Son J. Trends in AI technology for smart manufacturing in the future. Electron. Telecommun. Trends. 2020;35:60&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovrec-Krsti&#x10d; T., Orthaber K., Maver U., Sarenac T. Review of potential drug-eluting contact lens technologies. Materials. 2023;16:3653. doi: 10.3390/ma16103653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16103653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10222559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37241280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x162;&#x103;lu &#x15e;., &#x162;&#x103;lu M., Giovanzana S., Shah R.D. A brief history of contact lenses. Hum. Vet. Med. 2011;3:33&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris V., Pifer R., Shannon P., Crary M. Comparative evaluation of pseudomonas aeruginosa adhesion to a poly-(2-methacryloyloxyethyl phosphorylcholine)-modified silicone hydrogel contact lens. Vision. 2023;7:27. doi: 10.3390/vision7010027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vision7010027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10056565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36977307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M.-J., Park S.-Y., Sung A.-Y. Ophthalmic Hydrogel Contact Lens Material Containing Magnesium Oxide Nanoparticles and 3-(Trifluoromethyl) styrene for Biomedical Application. Micromachines. 2022;13:1897. doi: 10.3390/mi13111897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/mi13111897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9694811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36363917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meretoudi A., Banti C.N., Raptis P.K., Papachristodoulou C., Kourkoumelis N., Ikiades A.A., Zoumpoulakis P., Mavromoustakos T., Hadjikakou S.K. Silver nanoparticles from oregano leaves&#x2019; extracts as antimicrobial components for non-infected hydrogel contact lenses. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2021;22:3539. doi: 10.3390/ijms22073539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22073539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8037402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33805476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Marqu&#xe9;s J.V., Talens-Estarelles C., Garc&#xed;a-L&#xe1;zaro S., Cervi&#xf1;o A. The effects of soft contact lens wear on the tear film and meibomian gland drop-out and visibility. Life. 2022;12:1177. doi: 10.3390/life12081177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/life12081177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9409842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36013356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim G.-N., Kim S.-H., Joo I., Kim G.-B., Yoo K.-H. Center deviation measurement of color contact lenses based on a deep learning model and hough circle transform. Sensors. 2023;23:6533. doi: 10.3390/s23146533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s23146533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10384653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37514827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seggio M., Nostro A., Ginestra G., Quaglia F., Sortino S. Contact lenses delivering nitric oxide under daylight for reduction of bacterial contamination. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2019;20:3735. doi: 10.3390/ijms20153735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms20153735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6696341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31370152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ophthalmic Optics&#x2014;Contact Lenses&#x2014;Part 1: Vocabulary, Classification System and Recommendations for Labelling Specifications. International Organization for Standardization; Geneva, Switzerland: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ophthalmic Optics&#x2014;Contact Lenses and Contact Lens Care Products&#x2014;Fundamental Requirements. International Organization for Standardization; Geneva, Switzerland: 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebsamen M., Boucheix J.-M., Fayol M. Quality control in the optical industry: From a work analysis of lens inspection to a training programme, an experimental case study. Appl. Ergon. 2010;41:150&#x2013;160. doi: 10.1016/j.apergo.2009.07.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apergo.2009.07.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19747675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhary M., Tiwari V. An approach for iris contact lens detection and classification using ensemble of customized DenseNet and SVM. Future Gener. Comput. Syst. 2019;101:1259&#x2013;1270. doi: 10.1016/j.future.2019.07.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.future.2019.07.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera J.A., Vilaseca M., D&#xfc;ll J., Arjona M., Torrecilla E., Pujol J. Iris color and texture: A comparative analysis of real irises, ocular prostheses, and colored contact lenses. Color Res. Appl. 2011;36:373&#x2013;382. doi: 10.1002/col.20635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/col.20635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu M.-Y., Hong P.-Y., Liou J.-C., Wang Y.-P., Chen C. Assessment of ocular surface response to tinted soft contact lenses with different characteristics and pigment location. Int. J. Optomechatronics. 2020;14:119&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1080/15599612.2020.1859657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15599612.2020.1859657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim G.-N., Kim S.-H., Joo I., Yoo K.-H. Detection of Contact Lens Defects using a Modified GoogLeNet; Proceedings of the Korea Computer Congress 2022 (KCC2022); Jeju, Republic of Korea. 29 June&#x2013;1 July 2022; Seoul, Republic of Korea: Korean Institute of Information Scientists and Engineers; 2022. pp. 894&#x2013;896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S.-H., Joo S.-J., Yoo K.-H. DHS-CNN: A Defect-Adaptive Hierarchical Structure CNN Model for Detecting Anomalies in Contact Lenses. Appl. Sci. 2025;15:2697. doi: 10.3390/app15052697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app15052697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parzianello L., Czajka A. Saliency-guided textured contact lens-aware iris recognition; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision 2022; Waikoloa, HI, USA. 3&#x2013;8 January 2022; pp. 330&#x2013;337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghavendra R., Raja K.B., Busch C. Contlensnet: Robust iris contact lens detection using deep convolutional neural networks; Proceedings of the 2017 IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV); Santa Rosa, CA, USA. 24&#x2013;31 March 2017; pp. 1160&#x2013;1167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Z., Fang F., Yan N., Wu Y. State of the art in defect detection based on machine vision. Int. J. Precis. Eng.-Manuf.-Green Technol. 2022;9:661&#x2013;691. doi: 10.1007/s40684-021-00343-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40684-021-00343-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seibel E.J., Trilsch W.R., Lee D. Evaluating soft contact lens quality: A manufacturer&#x2019;s perspective. Optom. Vis. Sci. 1988;65:298&#x2013;307. doi: 10.1097/00006324-198804000-00010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00006324-198804000-00010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3377065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohal A.S. Quality Control in Soft Contact Lens Manufacture&#x2014;A Case Study. Int. J. Qual. Reliab. Manag. 1988;5:33&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1108/eb002894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/eb002894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres M., Santhanam K. Quality Control of Silicone Hydrogel Contact Lenses by Impedance Spectroscopy. MRS Online Proc. Libr. (OPL) 2014;1626:mrsf13-1626-k08-18. doi: 10.1557/opl.2014.201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1557/opl.2014.201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C.-L., Wu W.-H., Hwang C.-C. Automatic optical inspection method for soft contact lenses; Proceedings of the International Conference on Optical and Photonic Engineering (icOPEN 2015); Singapore. 14&#x2013;16 April 2015; pp. 17&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott C. Automatic optical measurement of contact lenses. Autom. Opt. Insp. 1986;654:125&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim T.-Y., Park D., Moon H., Hwang S.-S. A Deep Learning Technique for Optical Inspection of Color Contact Lenses. Appl. Sci. 2023;13:5966. doi: 10.3390/app13105966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app13105966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zin N.A.M., Asmuni H., Hamed H.N.A., Othman R.M., Kasim S., Hassan R., Zakaria Z., Roslan R. Contact lens classification by using segmented lens boundary features. Indones. J. Electr. Eng. Comput. Sci. 2018;11:1129&#x2013;1135. doi: 10.11591/ijeecs.v11.i3.pp1129-1135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11591/ijeecs.v11.i3.pp1129-1135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalal N., Triggs B. Histograms of oriented gradients for human detection; Proceedings of the 2005 IEEE Computer Society Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR&#x2019;05); San Diego, CA, USA. 20&#x2013;25 June 2005; pp. 886&#x2013;893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowe D.G. Distinctive image features from scale-invariant keypoints. Int. J. Comput. Vis. 2004;60:91&#x2013;110. doi: 10.1023/B:VISI.0000029664.99615.94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/B:VISI.0000029664.99615.94</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes C., Vapnik V. Support-vector networks. Mach. Learn. 1995;20:273&#x2013;297. doi: 10.1023/A:1022627411411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1022627411411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chunhachatrachai P., Lin C.-Y. CLensRimVision: A novel computer vision algorithm for detecting rim defects in contact lenses. Sensors. 2023;23:9610. doi: 10.3390/s23239610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s23239610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10708832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38067983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim G.-N., Kim S.-H., Joo I., Yoo K. Detection of Color Contact Lens Defects using Various CNN Models. J. Korea Contents Assoc. 2022;22:160&#x2013;170. doi: 10.5392/JKCA.2022.22.12.160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5392/JKCA.2022.22.12.160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He K., Zhang X., Ren S., Sun J. Deep residual learning for image recognition; Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2016; Las Vegas, NV, USA. 27&#x2013;30 June 2016; pp. 770&#x2013;778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szegedy C., Vanhoucke V., Ioffe S., Shlens J., Wojna Z. Rethinking the inception architecture for computer vision; Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2016; Las Vegas, NV, USA. 27&#x2013;30 June 2016; pp. 2818&#x2013;2826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szegedy C., Ioffe S., Vanhoucke V., Alemi A. Inception-v4, inception-resnet and the impact of residual connections on learning; Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence 2017; San Francisco, CA, USA. 4&#x2013;9 February 2017;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang G., Liu Z., Van DerMaaten L., Weinberger K.Q. Densely connected convolutional networks; Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition 2017; Honolulu, HI, USA. 21&#x2013;26 July 2017; pp. 4700&#x2013;4708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard A.G., Zhu M., Chen B., Kalenichenko D., Wang W., Wey T., Andreetto M., Adam H. Mobilenets: Efficient convolutional neural networks for mobile vision applications. arXiv. 2017 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1704.04861.1704.04861</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1704.04861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan M., Le Q. Efficientnet: Rethinking model scaling for convolutional neural networks; Proceedings of the International Conference on Machine Learning 2019; Long Beach, CA, USA. 9&#x2013;15 June 2019; pp. 6105&#x2013;6114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dosovitskiy A., Beyer L., Kolesnikov A., Weissenborn D., Zhai X., Unterthiner T., Dehghani M., Minderer M., Heigold G., Gelly S., et al. An image is worth 16 &#xd7; 16 words: Transformers for image recognition at scale. arXiv. 20202010.11929</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo Y., Gang S., Guan C. FCIHMRT: Feature cross-layer interaction hybrid method based on Res2Net and transformer for remote sensing scene classification. Electronics. 2023;12:4362. doi: 10.3390/electronics12204362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics12204362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghu M., Unterthiner T., Kornblith S., Zhang C., Dosovitskiy A. Do vision transformers see like convolutional neural networks? Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst. 2021;34:12116&#x2013;12128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duda R.O., Hart P.E. Use of the Hough transformation to detect lines and curves in pictures. Commun. ACM. 1972;15:11&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1145/361237.361242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/361237.361242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kekre H., Sarode T., Thepade S. Grid based image scaling technique. Int. J. Comput. Sci. Appl. 2008;1:95&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochreiter S., Schmidhuber J. Long short-term memory. Neural Comput. 1997;9:1735&#x2013;1780. doi: 10.1162/neco.1997.9.8.1735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1162/neco.1997.9.8.1735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9377276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho K., Van Merri&#xeb;nboer B., Gulcehre C., Bahdanau D., Bougares F., Schwenk H., Bengio Y. Learning phrase representations using RNN encoder-decoder for statistical machine translation. arXiv. 2014 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1406.1078.1406.1078</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1406.1078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaswani A., Shazeer N., Parmar N., Uszkoreit J., Jones L., Gomez A.N., Kaiser &#x141;., Polosukhin I. Attention is all you need. Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst. 2017;30:5998&#x2013;6008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiranyaz S., Avci O., Abdeljaber O., Ince T., Gabbouj M., Inman D.J. 1D convolutional neural networks and applications: A survey. Mech. Syst. Signal Process. 2021;151:107398. doi: 10.1016/j.ymssp.2020.107398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymssp.2020.107398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang Q., Wang X., Song Y., Lei L., Li R., Lai J. One-dimensional convolutional neural networks for high-resolution range profile recognition via adaptively feature recalibrating and automatically channel pruning. Int. J. Intell. Syst. 2021;36:332&#x2013;361. doi: 10.1002/int.22302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/int.22302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>