<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41234761</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1817-1737</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Oct-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of thoracic medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Thorac Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of respiratory muscle training on clinical outcomes in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>213</StartPage><EndPage>221</EndPage><MedlinePgn>213-221</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/atm.atm_230_24</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The effectiveness and clinical significance of respiratory muscle training for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) patients remain controversial. Our aim is to systematically review and conduct a meta analysis on the impact of respiratory muscle training on the clinical outcomes of patients with COPD. We systematically searched electronic databases (PubMed, Web of Science, Cochrane Library, and Embase) for randomized controlled trials evaluating the effects of respiratory muscle training on clinical outcomes in COPD patients. We utilized fixed or random effects models to assess the impact of respiratory muscle training on the 6 min walk test (6MWT), dyspnea, pulmonary function, respiratory muscle strength, and quality of life (QOL). Thirteen studies met the inclusion criteria for this review, involving 1178 COPD patients, of whom 588 completed respiratory muscle training. Meta analysis results indicated that respiratory muscle training significantly improved 6MWT (mean difference [MD]: 17.99; 95% confidence interval [CI]: 3.73, 32.26), dyspnea (standardized MD [SMD]: -0.81; 95% CI: -1.28, -0.34), forced expiratory volume in 1 s (FEV1; MD: 0.09; 95% CI: 0.02, 0.17), forced vital capacity (FVC; MD: 0.13; 95% CI: 0.03, 0.23), maximum inspiratory pressure (MD: 14.43; 95% CI: 8.71, 20.14), maximal expiratory pressure (MD: 15.06; 95% CI: 5.69, 24.43), and QOL (SMD: -0.77; 95% CI: -1.43, -0.11). However, no significant effect of respiratory muscle training on FEV1 /FVC was found (MD: 1.22; 95% CI: -1.61, 4.06). Respiratory muscle training is a positive intervention for improving exercise tolerance, pulmonary function, respiratory muscle strength, and QOL in COPD patients. Further high quality studies are needed to validate the findings of this review.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Annals of Thoracic Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qi</LastName><ForeName>Xiao-Hui</ForeName><Initials>XH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Respiratory Intensive Care Unit, Affiliated Hospital of Hebei University, Baoding City, Hebei Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Hai-Mei</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Affiliated Hospital of Hebei University, Baoding City, Hebei Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ning</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrated Traditional Chinese and Western Medicine, Affiliated Hospital of Hebei University, Baoding City, Hebei Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Xiao-Pan</ForeName><Initials>XP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrated Traditional Chinese and Western Medicine, Affiliated Hospital of Hebei University, Baoding City, Hebei Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiao-Xing</ForeName><Initials>XX</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Respiratory Intensive Care Unit, Affiliated Hospital of Hebei University, Baoding City, Hebei Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrated Traditional Chinese and Western Medicine, Affiliated Hospital of Hebei University, Baoding City, Hebei Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Thorac Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101280721</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1998-3557</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise endurance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory muscle training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41234761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12609738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/atm.atm_230_24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ATM-20-213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>GBD 2019 Chronic Respiratory Diseases Collaborators Global burden of chronic respiratory diseases and risk factors, 1990&#x2013;2019: An update from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;59:101936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7614570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37229504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization  World Health Statistics 2023: Monitoring Health for the SDGs, Sustainable Development Goals. 2023.  Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240074323 . [Last accessed on 2023 Dec 02]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Xu J, Yang L, Xu Y, Zhang X, Bai C, et al. Prevalence and risk factors of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease in China (the China Pulmonary Health [CPH] study): A national cross-sectional study. Lancet. 2018;391:1706&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29650248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negi H, Sarkar M, Raval AD, Pandey K, Das P. Health-related quality of life in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease in North India. J Postgrad Med. 2014;60:7&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24625932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guimar&#xe3;es Paiva L, Oliveira TM, Souza NB, Alberto KC, Almeida DP, Oliveira CC, et al. Exploring the impact of the environment on physical activity in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (EPCOT)-A comparative analysis between suggested and free walking: Protocol study. PLoS One. 2024;19:e0306045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11321554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39137186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spruit MA, Singh SJ, Garvey C, ZuWallack R, Nici L, Rochester C, et al. An official American Thoracic Society/European Respiratory Society statement: Key concepts and advances in pulmonary rehabilitation. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2013;188:e13&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24127811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gloeckl R, Schneeberger T, Jarosch I, Kenn K. Pulmonary rehabilitation and exercise training in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2018;115:117&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5852307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29526182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosselink R, De Vos J, van den Heuvel SP, Segers J, Decramer M, Kwakkel G. Impact of inspiratory muscle training in patients with COPD: What is the evidence? Eur Respir J. 2011;37:416&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21282809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wouters EF, Posthuma R, Koopman M, Liu WY, Sillen MJ, Hajian B, et al. An update on pulmonary rehabilitation techniques for patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Expert Rev Respir Med. 2020;14:149&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31931636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammous O, Feki W, Lotfi T, Khamis AM, Gosselink R, Rebai A, et al. Inspiratory muscle training, with or without concomitant pulmonary rehabilitation, for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2023;1:CD013778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9817429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36606682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill K, Cecins NM, Eastwood PR, Jenkins SC. Inspiratory muscle training for patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: A practical guide for clinicians. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2010;91:1466&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20801269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Templeman L, Roberts F. Effectiveness of expiratory muscle strength training on expiratory strength, pulmonary function and cough in the adult population: A systematic review. Physiotherapy. 2020;106:43&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32026845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Z, Li Z, Yan M, Zheng J, Huang W, Hong L, et al. Effect of respiratory muscle training in patients with stable chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Heliyon. 2024;10:e28733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10990946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38576558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geddes EL, Reid WD, Crowe J, O&#x2019;Brien K, Brooks D. Inspiratory muscle training in adults with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: A systematic review. Respir Med. 2005;99:1440&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15894478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen AP, Bj&#xf8;rnvad CR. Clinical effect of probiotics in prevention or treatment of gastrointestinal disease in dogs: A systematic review. J Vet Intern Med. 2019;33:1849&#x2013;1864. doi: 10.1111/jvim.15554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6766488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31313372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill K, Jenkins SC, Philippe DL, Cecins N, Shepherd KL, Green DJ, et al. High-intensity inspiratory muscle training in COPD. Eur Respir J. 2006;27:1119&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16772388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mota S, G&#xfc;ell R, Barreiro E, Solanes I, Ram&#xed;rez-Sarmiento A, Orozco-Levi M, et al. Clinical outcomes of expiratory muscle training in severe COPD patients. Respir Med. 2007;101:516&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16942867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leelarungrayub J, Pinkaew D, Puntumetakul R, Klaphajone J. Effects of a simple prototype respiratory muscle trainer on respiratory muscle strength, quality of life and dyspnea, and oxidative stress in COPD patients: A preliminary study. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2017;12:1415&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5440008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28553094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaminsky DA, Guntupalli KK, Lippmann J, Burns SM, Brock MA, Skelly J, et al. Effect of yoga breathing (Pranayama) on exercise tolerance in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: A randomized, controlled trial. J Altern Complement Med. 2017;23:696&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5610410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28714735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaumont M, Mialon P, Le Ber C, Le Mevel P, P&#xe9;ran L, Meurisse O, et al. Effects of inspiratory muscle training on dyspnoea in severe COPD patients during pulmonary rehabilitation: Controlled randomised trial. Eur Respir J. 2018;51:1701107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29371379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz K, Jelusic D, Wittmann M, Kr&#xe4;mer B, Huber V, Fuchs S, et al. Inspiratory muscle training does not improve clinical outcomes in 3-week COPD rehabilitation: Results from a randomised controlled trial. Eur Respir J. 2018;51:1702000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29371382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langer D, Ciavaglia C, Faisal A, Webb KA, Neder JA, Gosselink R, et al. Inspiratory muscle training reduces diaphragm activation and dyspnea during exercise in COPD. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2018;125:381&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29543134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W, Li R, Guan L, Wang K, Hu Y, Xu L, et al. Combination of inspiratory and expiratory muscle training in same respiratory cycle versus different cycles in COPD patients: A randomized trial. Respir Res. 2018;19:225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6245535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30458805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutrim AL, Duarte AA, Silva-Filho AC, Dias CJ, Urtado CB, Ribeiro RM, et al. Inspiratory muscle training improves autonomic modulation and exercise tolerance in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease subjects: A randomized-controlled trial. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2019;263:31&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30853602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saka S, Gurses HN, Bayram M. Effect of inspiratory muscle training on dyspnea-related kinesiophobia in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: A randomized controlled trial. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2021;44:101418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34034036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceyhan Y, Tekinsoy Kartin P. The effects of breathing exercises and inhaler training in patients with COPD on the severity of dyspnea and life quality: A randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2022;23:707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9419340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36028881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichiba T, Miyagawa T, Tsuda T, Kera T, Yasuda O. Changes in diaphragm thickness and 6-min walking distance improvement after inspiratory muscle training in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: Clinical trial. Heliyon. 2023;9:e20079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10559799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37809500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Wu X, Huang Y, Chen L. Internet of things-based home respiratory muscle training for patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: A randomized clinical trial. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2024;19:1093&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11128236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38800522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Wei L, Wang S, Ke L, Zhao H, Mao J, et al. The effects of pursed lip breathing combined with diaphragmatic breathing on pulmonary function and exercise capacity in patients with COPD: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Physiother Theory Pract. 2022;38:847&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32808571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paix&#xe3;o C, Rocha V, Brooks D, Marques A. Unsupervised physical activity interventions for people with COPD: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Pulmonology. 2024;30:53&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35151622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;tters F, van Tol B, Kwakkel G, Gosselink R. Effects of controlled inspiratory muscle training in patients with COPD: A meta-analysis. Eur Respir J. 2002;20:570&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12358330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lansing RW, Gracely RH, Banzett RB. The multiple dimensions of dyspnea: Review and hypotheses. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2009;167:53&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2763422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18706531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MT, Lewthwaite H, Paquet C, Johnston K, Olsson M, Belo LF, et al. Dyspnoea-12 and multidimensional dyspnea profile: Systematic review of use and properties. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2022;63:e75&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34273524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yun R, Bai Y, Lu Y, Wu X, Lee SD. How breathing exercises influence on respiratory muscles and quality of life among patients with COPD? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Can Respir J. 2021;2021:1904231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7864742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33574969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang I, Dabscheck E, George J, et al.  The COPD X Plan: Australian and New Zealand Guidelines for the Management of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease 2020 [EB/OL] Australian Lung Foundation and Thoracic Society of Australia and New Zealand.  Available from: https://www.copdx.org.au/  [Last accessed on 2020 Oct 20]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dechman G, Aceron R, Beauchamp M, Bhutani M. Delivering pulmonary rehabilitation during the COVID-19 pandemic: A Canadian Thoracic Society position statement. Can J Respir Crit Care Sleep Med. 2020;4:232&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo RI, Azambuja AM, Cureau FV, Sbruzzi G. Inspiratory muscle training in COPD. Respir Care. 2020;65:1189&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32209709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>