<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41557695</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Study on gas-water two-phase seepage law and flow characteristics of the matrix-fracture system in shale gas reservoirs.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0337079</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0337079</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0337079</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0337079</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As a clean energy source, shale gas plays a vital role in supporting China's strategic objectives of carbon peaking and carbon neutrality through its efficient development. Due to the low porosity, low permeability, complex pore structure, and strong heterogeneity of deep shale gas reservoirs, the gas-water two-phase seepage law and flow characteristics remain unclear. This study focuses on deep shale gas in the Western Chongqing block as the research subject. Through the gas-water displacement experiments combined with NMR techniques, the gas-water two-phase seepage laws and flow characteristics of the shale gas matrix-fracture system were revealed. The results show that: (1) In the water displacement gas experiment, formation water cannot break through the matrix-type sample, with its displacement velocity decreasing over time and eventually approaching zero. Under the same time conditions, the higher the displacement pressure, the faster the displacement velocity, and the higher the NMR signal. The matrix-fracture type sample breaks through in a short time, and the time when the NMR signal is stable is much less than that of the matrix-type sample. The displacement pressure is negatively correlated with the NMR signal. (2) In the reverse gas displacement experiment, the gas cannot break through the matrix-type sample. For the matrix-fracture type sample, as the displacement pressure increases, the water phase relative permeability increases, the irreducible water saturation decreases, the gas phase relative permeability decreases, the co-permeability zone slightly expands, and the equal permeability point shifts to the lower left. The findings provide a theoretical basis for the efficient development of shale gas in China.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 He et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Sijie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-3691-5030</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Energy Resources, China University of Geosciences (Beijing), Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Feifei</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0354-134X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Petroleum Engineering, Chongqing University of Science and Technology, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Jin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Petroleum Exploration and Development, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xizhe</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Petroleum Exploration and Development, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Porous Flow and Fluid Mechanics, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Langfang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Ruilan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Petroleum Exploration and Development, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Petroleum Engineering, Chongqing University of Science and Technology, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D059206">Natural Gas</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005740">Gases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059206" MajorTopicYN="Y">Natural Gas</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061329" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oil and Gas Fields</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016062" MajorTopicYN="N">Porosity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009682" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005740" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41557695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12818680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0337079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-58891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ma Y, Cai X, Zhao P. China&#x2019;s shale gas exploration and development: understanding and practice. Petroleum Explorat Devel. 2018;45(4):589&#x2013;603. doi: 10.1016/s1876-3804(18)30065-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1876-3804(18)30065-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X, Wang R, Shen B, Wang G, Wan C, Wang Q. Geological characteristics, resource potential, and development direction of shale gas in China. Petroleum Explorat Devel. 2025;52(1):17&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1016/s1876-3804(25)60002-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1876-3804(25)60002-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo PY, Zhu SY. Theoretical and technical fundamentals of a 100 billion-cubic-meter-scale large industry of coalbed methane in China. Acta Petrolei Sinica. 2023;44(11):1755&#x2013;63. doi: 10.7623/syxb202311001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7623/syxb202311001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen GS, Shi XW, Liu Y, Wu W, Yang YR, Zhu YQ, et al. New understandings of the factors controlling of deep shale gas enrichment in the wufeng formation-longmaxi formation of the southern sichuan basin. Nat Gas Ind. 2024;44(1):58&#x2013;71. doi: 10.3787/j.issn.1000-0976.2024.01.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3787/j.issn.1000-0976.2024.01.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie H, Li P, Dang W, Ding J, Sun C, Liu M, et al. Enrichment characteristics and exploration directions of deep shale gas of Ordovician&#x2013;Silurian in the Sichuan Basin and its surrounding areas, China. Petroleum Explorat Develnt. 2022;49(4):744&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1016/s1876-3804(22)60307-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1876-3804(22)60307-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X, Xie J, Yong R, Zhu Y. Geological characteristics and high production control factors of shale gas reservoirs in Silurian Longmaxi Formation, southern Sichuan Basin, SW China. Petroleum Exploration and Development. 2020;47(5):901&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1016/s1876-3804(20)60105-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1876-3804(20)60105-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang YB, Xiao WL, Han J, Gou L, Li M, Zhou KM, et al. Gas-water flow characteristics and influencing factors of tight sandstone in Danfengchang Gas Field. Petroleum Reservoir Evaluation and Development. 2022;12(2):356&#x2013;64. doi: 10.13809/j.cnki.cn32-1825/te.2022.02.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13809/j.cnki.cn32-1825/te.2022.02.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Liu D, Cai Y, Yao Y, Pan Z, Zhou Y. Application of nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) in coalbed methane and shale reservoirs: a review. Int J Coal Geol. 2020;218:103261. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2019.103261</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2019.103261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue DJ, Liu YT, Zhou J, Sun XT. Visualization of helium-water flow in tight coal by the low-field NMR imaging: An experimental observation. J Petroleum Sci Eng. 2020;188:106862. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2019.106862</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2019.106862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hun L, Bing Y, Xixiang S, Xinyi S, Lifei D. Fracturing fluid retention in shale gas reservoir from the perspective of pore size based on nuclear magnetic resonance. J Hydrol. 2021;601:126590. doi: 10.1016/j.jhydrol.2021.126590</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhydrol.2021.126590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge ZL, Wang HM, Zhou Z, Lu YY, Gao FF. Experimental study on flow characteristics of gas flooding water in coal by real-time nuclear magnetic resonance. J Mining Safety Eng. 2023;40(1):194&#x2013;203. doi: 10.13545/j.cnki.jmse.2021.0103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13545/j.cnki.jmse.2021.0103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G, Wang Y, Yin H, Ding Y, Lan Y, Yang D. Determination of gas-water seepage characteristics with consideration of dynamic pore-throat structure in a tight sandstone gas formation. Marine Petroleum Geol. 2022;136:105440. doi: 10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2021.105440</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2021.105440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Fang F, He S, Hu Y, Wang J, Jiao C, et al. Experimental study on damage evaluation of working fluid invasion in tight sandstone gas reservoirs. Processes. 2024;12(12):2857. doi: 10.3390/pr12122857</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr12122857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rui Y, Wang CJ, Zhang FS, Yao YB, Guo N, Zheng R. Characterization of micro-pore throats in the shale gas reservoirs of zhaotong national shale gas demonstration area. Natural Gas Industry. 2021;41(S1):78&#x2013;85. doi: 10.3787/j.issn.1000-0976.2021.S1.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3787/j.issn.1000-0976.2021.S1.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He S, Fang F, Song K, Li X, Zhang J, Cao J, et al. Research progress on the method of determining gas&#x2013;water relative permeability curve in unconventional reservoirs. J Petrol Explor Prod Technol. 2025;15(2). doi: 10.1007/s13202-024-01895-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13202-024-01895-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu SH, Cen F, Zhang Y, Liu SG, Zhang GD. Experimental study on gas-water relative permeability of ultra-deep marine carbonate reservoir. Petroleum Geol Recovery Efficiency. 2022;29(2):117&#x2013;23. doi: 10.13673/j.cnki.cn37-1359/te.2022.02.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13673/j.cnki.cn37-1359/te.2022.02.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai YD, Yang C, Li Q, Liu DM, Sun FR, Guo GS. Research progress of relative permeability experiment and numerical simulation technique in coalbed methane reservoir. Coal Sci Technol. 2023;51(S1):192&#x2013;205. doi: 10.13199/j.cnki.cst.2022-0835</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13199/j.cnki.cst.2022-0835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FANG J, GUO P, XIAO X, DU J, DONG C, XIONG Y, et al. Gas-water relative permeability measurement of high temperature and high pressure tight gas reservoirs. Petroleum Explorat Develt. 2015;42(1):92&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/s1876-3804(15)60010-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1876-3804(15)60010-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G, Ren W, Meng Y, Wang C, Wei N. Micro-flow kinetics research on water invasion in tight sandstone reservoirs. J Natural Gas Sci Eng. 2014;20:184&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2014.06.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2014.06.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Shi JT, Zhang QH, Qiao XY, Xin CP, Shi LY, et al. Experimental study on the nuclear magnetic resonance of shale in the southeastern Ordos Basin. J China Coal Society. 2018;43(10):2876&#x2013;85. doi: 10.13225/j.cnki.jccs.2018.0051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13225/j.cnki.jccs.2018.0051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou WY, Wang XM, Chen WW, Dang Z, He MQ, Zheng AW, et al. Influence of high-pressure conditions on the occurrence characteristics of shale adsorbed water: A case study of a shale reservoir in the Jiaoshiba area, Fuling, Chongqing. Bulletin Geological Sci Technol. 2024;43(5):95&#x2013;104. doi: 10.19509/j.cnki.dzkq.tb20230316</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19509/j.cnki.dzkq.tb20230316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu HY, Xu X, An LZ, Guo CM, Xiao JR. An experimental on occurrence and mobility of pore water in tight gas reservoirs. Acta Petrolei Sinica. 2016;37(2):230&#x2013;6. doi: 10.7623/syxb201602009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7623/syxb201602009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui YQ. Study of the microscopic remaining oil state and availability of extra-low/ultra-low permeability sandstone reservoirs - Take the Long 6 layer of Ansai oil field in Ordos Basin as an example. Northeast Petroleum University. 2023. doi: 10.26995/d.cnki.gdqsc.2023.000464</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26995/d.cnki.gdqsc.2023.000464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge H-K, Yang L, Shen Y-H, Ren K, Meng F-B, Ji W-M, et al. Experimental investigation of shale imbibition capacity and the factors influencing loss of hydraulic fracturing fluids. Pet Sci. 2015;12(4):636&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1007/s12182-015-0049-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12182-015-0049-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma H-L, Feng X-L, Liu L-L, Zhang A, Wang D. Changes in the effective absolute permeability of hydrate-bearing sands during isotropic loading and unloading. Petroleum Science. 2025. doi: 10.1016/j.petsci.2025.10.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petsci.2025.10.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan TT, Zhang F, Cao XM, Cai YT, Guo LB, Wang YZ. Normalization method for relative-permeability curves on flow units and its application. Science Technol Engineering. 2013;13(31):9322&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>