<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41419964</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Predicting and classifying type 2 diabetes using a transparent ensemble model combining random forest, k-nearest neighbor, and neural networks.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1892</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1892</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1892</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-31562-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diabetes is one of the major health challenges in today's world, since chronic elevation of blood sugar can cause serious and sometimes irreparable damage to organs such as the heart, kidneys, and nervous system. Early detection of this disease plays a vital role in reducing its complications. However, machine learning and deep learning models often face distrust in medical settings due to their opaque, "black-box" nature. The aim of this study was to combine three machine learning algorithms using stacking and voting methods to propose a model for type 2 diabetes detection, and to increase transparency by using the explainability techniques LIME and SHAP to identify important features. This study used medical data from 768 Pima Indians Diabetes samples, including 8 features such as age, BMI, glucose, insulin, blood pressure, skin thickness, pregnancies, and family history. Data preprocessing included mean imputation for missing or zero values, Min-Max normalization, and classification into "Normal", "Prediabetes", and "Diabetes" based on fasting glucose thresholds. Feature selection was performed using Spearman correlation to retain the most relevant variables. A hybrid machine learning model was developed using three base models Neural Network (NN), k-Nearest Neighbors (KNN), and Random Forest (RF) with automated hyperparameter tuning. The outputs of these models were combined via stacking using a logistic regression (LR) meta-model and in parallel using a soft voting method. Nested cross-validation (5 outer and 5 inner folds) was applied to prevent data leakage and ensure robust evaluation. Model interpretability was assessed using LIME for local explanations and SHAP for global feature importance. Decision thresholds and influential feature regions were identified, and model calibration and decision curves evaluated clinical reliability. Models performance was evaluated using accuracy, precision, recall, specificity, F1-score, AUROC, Brier Score (1-B), and Expected Calibration Error (1-E). Statistical reliability was assessed using bootstrap resampling to compute 95% confidence intervals, as well as paired tests to compare the hybrid model with the base models and voting ensemble. Based on the evaluation metrics, the stacking ensemble achieved perfect performance for Class 0, with 100% accuracy, precision, recall, specificity, F1 score, and AUROC, alongside the highest calibration metrics (Brier Score: 99.9, ECE: 98.7). The Random Forest model also excelled, achieving 100% accuracy, precision, recall, specificity, and F1 score for Class 0 and Class 2. In contrast, the KNN model consistently underperformed, particularly for Class 0 (F1: 83.3, Precision: 83.3, Recall: 83.3). The Neural Network demonstrated strong recall for Class 0 (100%), while the voting ensemble showed balanced results but was slightly outperformed by the top ensemble methods. Explainable AI analyses using LIME and SHAP revealed that glucose was the most influential predictor for identifying the Pre-diabetes state. Both methods consistently identified a decision band between 0.35 and 0.47 (corresponding to 100-125&#xa0;mg/dL) as the transition zone between "Normal" and "Prediabetes", confirming the model's alignment with WHO/ADA diagnostic criteria. The stacking model achieved perfect performance and superior calibration, outperforming all other models in type 2 diabetes prediction and classification. Explainability techniques (LIME and SHAP) identified glucose level, body mass index, and blood pressure as key predictive factors. This approach provides an accurate and interpretable tool for clinical decision support in healthcare systems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaferani</LastName><ForeName>Niloufar</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IT Department, Iran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Afrash</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Reza</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Smart University of Medical Sciences, Artificial Intelligence in Medical Sciences Research Center, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moulaei</LastName><ForeName>Khadijeh</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Management and Economics Research Center, Health Management Research Institute, Iran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran. Moulaei.kh91@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001786">Blood Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="N">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001786" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Glucose</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000093743" MajorTopicYN="N">Random Forest</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prediction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transparent ensemble learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41419964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12804783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-31562-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-31562-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Blair, M. Diabetes Mellitus Review. <i>Urol. Nurs.</i><b>36</b>(1), 27&#x2013;36 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27093761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, A., Gangwar, R., Ahmad Zargar, A., Kumar, R. &amp; Sharma, A. Prevalence of diabetes in India: A review of IDF diabetes atlas 10th edition. <i>Curr. Diab. Rev.</i><b>20</b>(1), 105&#x2013;114 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1573399819666230413094200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37069712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain, M. J., Al-Mamun, M. &amp; Islam, M. R. Diabetes mellitus, the fastest growing global public health concern: Early detection should be focused. <i>Health Sci. Rep.</i> 7(3), e2004 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10958528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38524769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auvinen, A.-M. et al. Type 1 and type 2 diabetes after gestational diabetes: a 23 year cohort study. <i>Diabetologia</i><b>63</b>(10), 2123&#x2013;2128 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-020-05215-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7476985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32725280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu, A. et al. Dietary blueberry and soluble fiber improve serum antioxidant and adipokine biomarkers and lipid peroxidation in pregnant women with obesity and at risk for gestational diabetes. <i>Antioxidants</i><b>10</b>(8), 1318 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox10081318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8389321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34439566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bovolini, A., Garcia, J., Andrade, M. A. &amp; Duarte, J. A. Metabolic syndrome pathophysiology and predisposing factors. <i>Int. J. Sports Med.</i><b>42</b>(03), 199&#x2013;214 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1263-0898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33075830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yen, F.-S. Wei JC-C, Shih Y-H, Hsu C-C, Hwu C-M: Impact of individual microvascular disease on the risks of macrovascular complications in type 2 diabetes: a nationwide population-based cohort study. <i>Cardiovasc. Diabetol.</i><b>22</b>(1), 109 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-023-01821-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10170797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37161539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usman, M. S., Khan, M. S., Butler, J. The interplay between diabetes, cardiovascular disease, and kidney disease. (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34279879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;z&#xe7;elik, Y. B., Altan, A. Classification of diabetic retinopathy by machine learning algorithm using entorpy-based features. In <i>Proceedings of the &#xc7;Ankaya International Congress on Scientific Research: 2023</i>. (IKSAD Golbasi, Adiyaman Province, Turkey, 2023) 10&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayalakshmi, R. &amp; Tamilvizhi, T. Privacy preservation in diabetic disease prediction using federated learning based on efficient cross stage recurrent model. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>(1), 37258 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-21229-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12552717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41136513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinitha, G., Rambabu, B., Surendran, R., Balamurugan, K. S. Optimizing diabetic kidney disease diagnosis with machine learning: a novel approach. In <i>2025 8th International Conference on Electronics, Materials Engineering &amp; Nano-Technology (IEMENTech): 2025</i>. (IEEE, 2025) 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiran, M. et al. Machine learning and artificial intelligence in type 2 diabetes prediction: a comprehensive 33-year bibliometric and literature analysis. <i>Front. Digit. Health</i><b>7</b>, 1557467 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fdgth.2025.1557467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11983615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40212895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J. et al. Optimizing diabetic retinopathy detection with inception-V4 and dynamic version of snow leopard optimization algorithm. <i>Biomed. Signal Process. Control</i><b>96</b>, 106501 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2024.106501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavakiotis, I. et al. Machine learning and data mining methods in diabetes research. <i>Comput. Struct. Biotechnol. J.</i><b>15</b>, 104&#x2013;116 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csbj.2016.12.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5257026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28138367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson, J. P. et al. Reverse engineering and evaluation of prediction models for progression to type 2 diabetes: an application of machine learning using electronic health records. <i>J. Diabetes Sci. Technol.</i><b>10</b>(1), 6&#x2013;18 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1932296815620200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4738229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26685993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainan, U. H., Por, L. Y., Chen, Y. L., Yang, J. &amp; Ku, C. S. Advancing bankruptcy forecasting with hybrid machine learning techniques: Insights from an unbalanced polish dataset. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>12</b>, 9369&#x2013;9381 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3354173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H., Lim, D. H. &amp; Kim, Y. Classification and prediction on the effects of nutritional intake on overweight/obesity, dyslipidemia, hypertension and type 2 diabetes mellitus using deep learning model: 4&#x2013;7th Korea national health and nutrition examination survey. <i>Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health</i><b>18</b>(11), 5597 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18115597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8197245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34073854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanim, S. A. et al. Explainable deep learning for diabetes diagnosis with DeepNetX2. <i>Biomed. Signal Process. Control</i><b>99</b>, 106902 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2024.106902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan, R., Dattana, V., Mahmood, S. &amp; Hussain, S. Towards transparent diabetes prediction: combining automl and explainable AI for improved clinical insights. <i>Information</i><b>16</b>(1), 7 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/info16010007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dweekat, O. Y., Lam, S. S. Optimized design of hybrid genetic algorithm with multilayer perceptron to predict patients with diabetes. <i>Soft Comput. Fus. Found. Methodol. Appl. </i>27(10) (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alex, S. A., Nayahi, J. J. V., Shine, H. &amp; Gopirekha, V. Deep convolutional neural network for diabetes mellitus prediction. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>34</b>(2), 1319&#x2013;1327 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-021-06431-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olisah, C. C., Smith, L. &amp; Smith, M. Diabetes mellitus prediction and diagnosis from a data preprocessing and machine learning perspective. <i>Comput. Methods Programs Biomed.</i><b>220</b>, 106773 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmpb.2022.106773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35429810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L. et al. RETRACTED: Enhancing lung cancer detection through hybrid features and machine learning hyperparameters optimization techniques. <i>Heliyon</i><b>10</b>(4), e26192 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e26192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10884486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38404820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. et al. MSPO: A machine learning hyperparameter optimization method for enhanced breast cancer image classification. <i>Digit. Health</i><b>11</b>, 20552076251361604 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552076251361603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12277558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40693252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabeel, S. M. et al. Optimizing lung cancer classification through hyperparameter tuning. <i>Digit. Health</i><b>10</b>, 20552076241249660 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552076241249661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11064752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38698834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daza, A., S&#xe1;nchez, C. F. P., Apaza-Perez, G., Pinto, J. &amp; Ramos, K. Z. Stacking ensemble approach to diagnosing the disease of diabetes. <i>Inf. Med. Unlock.</i><b>44</b>, 101427 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.imu.2023.101427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollapalli, M. et al. A novel stacking ensemble for detecting three types of diabetes mellitus using a Saudi Arabian dataset: Pre-diabetes, T1DM, and T2DM. <i>Comput. Biol. Med.</i><b>147</b>, 105757 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2022.105757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35777087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganie, S. M. &amp; Malik, M. B. An ensemble machine learning approach for predicting type-II diabetes mellitus based on lifestyle indicators. <i>Healthcare Anal.</i><b>2</b>, 100092 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.health.2022.100092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reza, M. S., Amin, R., Yasmin, R., Kulsum, W., Ruhi, S. Improving diabetes disease patients classification using stacking ensemble method with PIMA and local healthcare data. <i>Heliyon</i> 10(2) (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10834804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38312584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Lawati, J. A. Diabetes mellitus: A local and global public health emergency!. <i>Oman Med J</i><b>32</b>(3), 177&#x2013;179 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5001/omj.2017.34</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5447787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28584596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husain, A. &amp; Khan, M. H. Early diabetes prediction using voting based ensemble learning. In <i>International conference on advances in computing and data sciences: 2018</i> 95&#x2013;103 (Springer, Cham, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira, G. P., Fonseca, A. &amp; Rodrigues, P. C. Diabetes diagnosis based on hard and soft voting classifiers combining statistical learning models. <i>Braz. J. Biometr.</i><b>40</b>(4), 415&#x2013;427 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.28951/bjb.v40i4.605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan-Benita, J. A., Galv&#xe1;n-Tejada, C. E., Cruz, M., Galv&#xe1;n-Tejada, J. I., Gamboa-Rosales, H., Arceo-Olague, J. G., Luna-Garc&#xed;a, H., Celaya-Padilla, J. M. Hard voting ensemble approach for the detection of Type 2 diabetes in mexican population with non-glucose related features. <i>Healthcare (Basel)</i> 10(8) (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9331873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35893185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahabub, A. A robust voting approach for diabetes prediction using traditional machine learning techniques. <i>SN Appl. Sci.</i><b>1</b>(12), 1667 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42452-019-1759-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal, C. C., Hinneburg, A. &amp; Keim, D. A. On the surprising behavior of distance metrics in high dimensional space. In <i>International conference on database theory 2001</i> 420&#x2013;434 (Springer, Cham, 2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidey-Gibbons, J. A. &amp; Sidey-Gibbons, C. J. Machine learning in medicine: a practical introduction. <i>BMC Med. Res. Methodol.</i><b>19</b>(1), 64 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-019-0681-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6425557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30890124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moulaei, K., Ghasemian, F., Bahaadinbeigy, K., Ershad Sarbi, R. &amp; Mohamadi Taghiabad, Z. Predicting mortality of COVID-19 patients based on data mining techniques. <i>J. Biomed. Phys. Eng.</i><b>11</b>(5), 653&#x2013;662 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31661/jbpe.v0i0.2104-1300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8546157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34722410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Delgado, M., Cernadas, E., Barro, S. &amp; Amorim, D. Do we need hundreds of classifiers to solve real world classification problems?. <i>J. Mach. Learn. Res.</i><b>15</b>(1), 3133&#x2013;3181 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, H. &amp; Garcia, E. A. Learning from imbalanced data. <i>IEEE Trans. Knowl. Data Eng.</i><b>21</b>(9), 1263&#x2013;1284 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TKDE.2008.239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salem Alzboon M, Al-Batah M, Alqaraleh M, Abuashour A, Fuad Bader A: A comparative study of machine learning techniques for early prediction of diabetes. <i>arXiv e-prints</i> 2025:arXiv: 2506.10180.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>