<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41382253</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1348-8945</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>54</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Tropical medicine and health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Trop Med Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Caregiver experiences and healthcare provider perspectives on managing sick young infants in primary care: a qualitative study in Awi Zone, Northwest Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7</StartPage><MedlinePgn>7</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s41182-025-00873-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Ethiopia implemented the community-based management of possible serious bacterial infection to improve access to lifesaving care for sick young infants aged 0-2&#xa0;months. However, service utilization has been low, and the quality of care was&#xa0;sub-optimal, emphasizing the need to identify challenges within the primary healthcare system. This study explored mothers' and healthcare providers' experiences and perspectives on the management of sick young infants, including those with possible serious bacterial infections to inform policy and practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a qualitative study including 25 in-depth and six key informant interviews with purposively selected participants, including mothers seeking facility care for their infants, health extension workers, health center staff, and supervisors of health extension workers. We audio-recorded and transcribed the interviews, and conducted inductive thematic analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We present four major themes: caregivers' perceptions of young infant illnesses, caregivers' choice of place to seek care, caregivers' experiences with caring for sick young infants at the health facility, and factors affecting the provision of quality care. Mothers acknowledged the need to seek care if their young infants became ill, although often delayed when not recognizing signs of illness, believing that it would resolve. Once identified, they had the autonomy to seek care but lacked awareness of health post services, bypassing these and seeking care at health centers, which were further away. Health extension workers viewed poor infrastructure and the perceived low quality of service as being linked to low service utilization at health posts. Mothers described long waiting times at health centers, inadequate assessment, and missing communication about their children's conditions and treatment. Health extension workers felt they had gaps in knowledge and skills. Inconsistent availability of drugs, weak referral and feedback mechanisms, low-quality supervision, limited mentorship, and inadequate district-level ownership of newborn care constrained the delivery of high-quality services.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study identifies the challenges from the community to health system on sick young infants' service utilization and quality of care at primary healthcare settings. It highlights the importance of a comprehensive approach that integrates demand-creation activities with health system strengthening efforts to ensure the consistent availability of high-quality care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Getahun</LastName><ForeName>Tigist</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine and Health Science, Institute of Public Health, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia. tgforblessing@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azale</LastName><ForeName>Telake</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Promotion and Health Behaviour, Institute of Public Health, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alemayehu</LastName><ForeName>Mekuriaw</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine and Health Science, Institute of Public Health, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yitayal</LastName><ForeName>Mezgebu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health System and Policy, Institute of Public Health, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Persson</LastName><ForeName>Lars &#xc5;ke</ForeName><Initials>L&#xc5;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Systems and Reproductive Health Research Directorate, Ethiopian Public Health Institute, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Disease Control, London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schellenberg</LastName><ForeName>Joanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Disease Control, London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berhanu</LastName><ForeName>Della</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Systems and Reproductive Health Research Directorate, Ethiopian Public Health Institute, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Disease Control, London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>INV-009691</GrantID><Acronym>GATES</Acronym><Agency>Gates Foundation</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>INV-009691</GrantID><Acronym>GATES</Acronym><Agency>Gates Foundation</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Trop Med Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101215093</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1348-8945</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community-based newborn care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health extension workers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Possible serious bacterial infection</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This qualitative study obtained ethical approval from the University of Gondar (VP/RTT/05/2941/2021). Support letters were obtained from the Amhara Public Health Institute and the district health office. All study participants were informed about the purpose of the study and their right to participate and withdraw from the study at any time. Written informed consent was obtained from each participant to be interviewed and audio recorded. All identifiers were removed from the data to maximize confidentiality. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41382253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12781729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41182-025-00873-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s41182-025-00873-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>UNICEF, World Health Organization. Levels and Trends Child Mortality-Report 2023: Estimates Developed by the United Nations Inter-agency Group for Child Mortality Estimation. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed I, Ali SM, Amenga-Etego S, Ariff S, Bahl R, Baqui AH, et al. Population-based rates, timing, and causes of maternal deaths, stillbirths, and neonatal deaths in south Asia and sub-Saharan Africa: a multi-country prospective cohort study. Lancet Glob Health. 2018;6(12):e1297&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(18)30385-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6227247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30361107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black RE, Levin C, Walker N, Chou D, Liu L, Temmerman M. Reproductive, maternal, newborn, and child health: key messages from disease control priorities 3rd edition. Lancet. 2016;388(10061):2811&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(16)00738-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27072119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Guideline: Managing possible serious bacterial infection in young infants when referral is not feasible. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26447263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hailegebriel TD, Mulligan B, Cousens S, Mathewos B, Wall S, Bekele A, et al. Effect on neonatal mortality of newborn infection management at health posts when referral is not possible: a cluster-randomized trial in rural Ethiopia. Glob Health Sci Pract. 2017;5(2):202&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9745/GHSP-D-16-00312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5487084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28611102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lokangaka A, Ishoso D, Tshefu A, Kalonji M, Takoy P, Kokolomami J, et al. Simplified antibiotic regimens for young infants with possible serious bacterial infection when the referral is not feasible in the Democratic Republic of the Congo. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(6):e0268277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0268277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9246187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35771738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ariff S, Soofi SB, Suhag Z, Chanar S, Bhura M, Dahar Z, et al. Implementation research to increase treatment coverage of possible serious bacterial infections in young infants when a referral is not feasible: lessons learnt. J Public Health. 2023;45(1):176&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/pubmed/fdab409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10017086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35138390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awasthi S, Kesarwani N, Verma RK, Agarwal GG, Tewari LS, Mishra RK, et al. Identification and management of young infants with possible serious bacterial infection where referral was not feasible in rural Lucknow district of Uttar Pradesh, India: an implementation research. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(6):e0234212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0234212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7272098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32497092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assefa Y, Gelaw YA, Hill PS, Taye BW, Van Damme W. Community health extension program of Ethiopia, 2003&#x2013;2018: successes and challenges toward universal coverage for primary healthcare services. Glob Health. 2019;15(1):24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12992-019-0470-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6434624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30914055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Federal Ministry of Health. National strategy for newborn and child survival in Ethiopia (2015/16&#x2013;2019/20). Addis Abeba Ethiopia; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berhanu D, Avan B. Community based newborn care programme in Ethiopia 2013&#x2013;2017: final evaluation report, March 2019. London: IDEAS, London School of Hygiene &amp; Tropical Medicine. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameha A, Legesse H, Sylla M, Oulare M, Ayalew Y, Tensou B, et al. The effect of community-based newborn care intervention on service utilization for sick newborn and children. Ethiop Med J. 2019;(Supp. 3):239-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mengistu B, Paulos M, Agonafir N, Ameha A, Legesse H, Dankenbring E, et al. Barriers to the uptake of community-based curative child health services in Ethiopia. BMC Public Health. 2021;21:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-021-11558-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8364059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34391398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tareke KG, Lemu YK, Feyissa GT. Exploration of facilitators of and barriers to the community-based service utilization for newborn possible serious bacterial infection management in Debre Libanos District, Ethiopia: descriptive qualitative study. BMC Pediatr. 2020;20:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12887-020-02211-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7305601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32563243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getahun T, Azale T, Alemayehu M, Yitayal M, Persson L&#xc5;, Berhanu D. Management of bacterial infections in young infants in Ethiopia: facility preparedness, health workers&#x2019; knowledge and quality of care. Acta Paediatr. 2022;111(11):2178&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apa.16364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35445443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebremedhin T, Daka DW, Alemayehu YK, Yitbarek K, Debie A. Process evaluation of the community-based newborn care program implementation in Geze Gofa district, south Ethiopia: a case study evaluation design. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2019;19(1):492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-019-2616-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6907260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31829193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berhanu D, Allen E, Beaumont E, Tomlin K, Taddesse N, Dinsa G, et al. Coverage of antenatal, intrapartum, and newborn care in 104 districts of Ethiopia: a before and after study four years after the launch of the national Community-Based Newborn Care programme. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(8):e0251706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0251706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8341496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34351944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebretsadik A, Melaku N, Haji Y. Community acceptance and utilization of maternal and community-based neonatal care services provided by health extension workers in rural Sidama zone: barriers and enablers: a qualitative study. Pediatr Health Med Ther. 2020. 10.2147/PHMT.S254409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/PHMT.S254409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7335842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32669919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semahegn A, Torpey K, Manu A, Assefa N, Ankomah A. Adapted tool for the assessment of domestic violence against women in a low-income country setting: a reliability analysis. Int J Womens Health. 2019. 10.2147/IJWH.S181385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJWH.S181385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6361225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30774451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tefera BB, Yihunie W, Bekele A. Integrated pharmaceutical logistics system implementation in Chagni Primary Hospital and Injibara General Hospital, Awi Zone, Ethiopia. J Multidiscip Healthc. 2021. 10.2147/JMDH.S316595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JMDH.S316595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8254555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34234454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berhanu D, Okwaraji YB, Defar A, Bekele A, Lemango ET, Medhanyie AA, et al. Does a complex intervention targeting communities, health facilities and district health managers increase the utilisation of community-based child health services? A before and after study in intervention and comparison areas of Ethiopia. BMJ Open. 2020;10(9):e040868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-040868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7493123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32933966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders B, Sim J, Kingstone T, Baker S, Waterfield J, Bartlam B, et al. Saturation in qualitative research: exploring its conceptualization and operationalization. Qual Quant. 2018;52:1893&#x2013;907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11135-017-0574-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5993836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29937585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okuga M, Waiswa P, Mandu R, Wachira J, Hanson C, Manzi F. Illness recognition and care-seeking for maternal and newborn complications in rural eastern Uganda. J Health Popul Nutr. 2017;36:75&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41043-017-0125-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5764049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29297398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birhanu BG, Mathibe-Neke JM. Service utilization and impact on quality care of sick young infants in the primary healthcare units, West Gojjam, Amhara, Ethiopia. J Glob Health Sci. 2021. 10.35500/jghs.2021.3.e17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.35500/jghs.2021.3.e17</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma V, Leight J, AbdulAziz F, Giroux N, Nyqvist MB. Illness recognition, decision-making, and care-seeking for maternal and newborn complications: a qualitative study in Jigawa State, Northern Nigeria. J Health Popul Nutr. 2017;36:59&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41043-017-0124-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5764051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29297412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosales A, Sulistyo S, Miko O, Hairani LK, Ilyana M, Thomas J, et al. Recognition of and care-seeking for maternal and newborn complications in Jayawijaya district, Papua province, Indonesia: a qualitative study. J Health Popul Nutr. 2017;36:35&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41043-017-0122-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5764054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29297380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamba D, Tancred T, Hanson C, Wachira J, Manzi F. Delayed illness recognition and multiple referrals: a qualitative study exploring care-seeking trajectories contributing to maternal and newborn illnesses and death in southern Tanzania. BMC Health Serv Res. 2019;19:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-019-4019-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6460539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30975142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lama TP, Khatry SK, Katz J, LeClerq SC, Mullany LC. Illness recognition, decision-making, and care-seeking for maternal and newborn complications: a qualitative study in Sarlahi District, Nepal. J Health Popul Nutr. 2017;36:45&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41043-017-0123-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5764053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29297386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesele M, Abebe K, Dessu S, Anmut W, Yeshambel A, Dawit Z, et al. Mothers&#x2019; health care seeking behavior for neonatal danger sign in southern Ethiopia: community based cross&#x2013;sectional study. PLoS ONE. 2023;18(7):e0280993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0280993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10355418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37467224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fung A, Hamilton E, Du Plessis E, Askin N, Avery L, Crockett M. Training programs to improve identification of sick newborns and care-seeking from a health facility in low-and middle-income countries: a scoping review. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2021;21(1):831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-021-04240-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34906109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onarheim KH, Moland KM, Molla M, Miljeteig I. &#x2018;I wanted to go, but they said wait&#x2019;: mothers&#x2019; bargaining power and strategies in care-seeking for ill newborns in Ethiopia. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(6):e0233594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0233594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7274445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32502223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berhane M, Girma T, Tesfaye W, Jibat N, Abera M, Abrahim S, et al. Implementation research on management of sick young infants with possible serious bacterial infection when referral is not possible in Jimma Zone, Ethiopia: challenges and solutions. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(8):e0255210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0255210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8351942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34370744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leul A, Hailu T, Abraham L, Bayray A, Terefe W, Godefay H, et al. Innovative approach for potential scale-up to jump-start simplified management of sick young infants with possible serious bacterial infection when a referral is not feasible: findings from implementation research. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(2):e0244192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0244192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7864440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33544712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiruneh GT, Fesseha N, Emaway D, Betemariam W, Nigatu TG, Magge H, et al. Effect of community-based newborn care implementation strategies on access to and effective coverage of possible serious bacterial infection (PSBI) treatment for sick young infants during COVID-19 pandemic. PLoS ONE. 2024;19(3):e0300880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0300880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10962833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38527000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill Z, Dumbaugh M, Benton L, K&#xe4;llander K, Strachan D, Ten Asbroek A, et al. Supervising community health workers in low-income countries&#x2013;a review of impact and implementation issues. Glob Health Action. 2014;7(1):24085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3402/gha.v7.24085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4016747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24815075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruk ME, Gage AD, Arsenault C, Jordan K, Leslie HH, Roder-DeWan S, et al. High-quality health systems in the Sustainable Development Goals era: time for a revolution. Lancet Glob Health. 2018;6(11):e1196&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(18)30386-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7734391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30196093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Standards for improving the quality of care for children and young adolescents in health facilities. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abtew S, Negatou M, Wondie T, Tadesse Y, Alemayehu WA, Tsegaye DA, et al. Poor adherence to the integrated community case management of newborn and child illness protocol in rural Ethiopia. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2022;107(6):1337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.21-1018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9768262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36316002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jebessa S, Litch JA, Senturia K, Hailu T, Kahsay A, Kuti KA, et al. Qualitative assessment of the quality of care for preterm, low birth weight, and sick newborns in Ethiopia. Health Serv Insights. 2021;14:11786329211025150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/11786329211025150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8216415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34211278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lange S, Mwisongo A, M&#xe6;stad O. Why don&#x2019;t clinicians adhere more consistently to guidelines for the Integrated Management of Childhood Illness (IMCI)? Soc Sci Med. 2014;104:56&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2013.12.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24581062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdella YM, Bekele A, Mathewos B, Tadesse Y, Wall S, Gardner H, et al. Do caretakers of sick young infants with possible serious bacterial infection adhere to referrals from health posts to health centers? Ethiop Med J. 2019;(Supp. 3):215-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller NP, Bagheri Ardestani F, Wong H, Stokes S, Mengistu B, Paulos M, et al. Barriers to the utilization of community-based child and newborn health services in Ethiopia: a scoping review. Health Policy Plan. 2021;36(7):1187&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapol/czab047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8496769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33885143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiruneh GT, Odwe G, K&#x2019;Oduol K, Gwaro H, Fesseha N, Moraa Z, et al. Improving possible serious bacterial infection (PSBI) management in young infants when referral is not feasible: lessons from embedded implementation research in Ethiopia and Kenya. BMC Pediatr. 2024;24(1):599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12887-024-05070-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11415999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39304861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legesse H, Seyoum H, Abdo A, Ameha A, Abdulber S, Sylla M, et al. Supply chain management for community-based newborn care in Rural Ethiopia: challenges, strategies implemented and recommendations. Ethiop Med J. 2019;(Supp. 3):247-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berhanu D, Hashmi I, Schellenberg J, Avan B. District health managers perspectives of introducing a new service: a qualitative study of the community-based newborn care programme in Ethiopia. BMC Health Serv Res. 2021;21(1):783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-021-06792-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8351343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34372850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semu Y, Tekle E, Bekele A, Teferi E, Taddesse L, Betamariam W, et al. Making community based newborn care sustainable in Ethiopia. Ethiop Med J. 2019;(Supp. 3):281-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiruneh GT, Nigatu TG, Magge H, Hirschhorn LR. Using the implementation research logic model to design and implement community-based management of possible serious bacterial infection during COVID-19 pandemic in Ethiopia. BMC Health Serv Res. 2022;22(1):1515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-022-08945-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9745284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36514111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>