<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41247275</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-4798</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cornea</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cornea</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of Topical Fluorescein on Scheimpflug-Based Corneal Densitometry and Potential Applications.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/ICO.0000000000004025</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the effect of topical fluorescein on Scheimpflug-based corneal densitometry and to determine the optimal timing for reliable imaging. In addition, a patient with dry eye disease (DED) was examined to assess the potential of fluorescein-enhanced densitometry for detecting superficial punctate keratitis (SPK).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty healthy participants underwent Scheimpflug imaging at baseline and 1-, 5-, 10-, 15-, and 20-minute postinstillation of 2% fluorescein sodium. Corneal densitometry values across 3 corneal layers and 4 concentric zones and central corneal thickness (CCT) were measured. Imaging was repeated at a second visit to assess reproducibility. A linear mixed-effects model was used to analyze time-dependent changes. One patient with DED with SPK was included for a proof-of-concept examination.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A significant increase in corneal densitometry after fluorescein instillation was only observed in the anterior layer, with an increase in the 0- to 2-mm zone at visit 1 from 26.6 &#xb1; 2.4 gray scale units (GSU) to 62.5 &#xb1; 18.9 GSU (P &lt; 0.001) at 5-minute postinstillation and a gradual decrease toward baseline values by 20 minutes (32.0 &#xb1; 11.4 GSU, P = 0.045). Reproducibility between visits was high for 10- to 20-minute postinstillation examinations (P &gt; 0.05). In the patient with DED, fluorescein-enhanced densitometry revealed localized signal elevations consistent with SPK seen on slit-lamp examination.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Topical fluorescein induces time-dependent changes in anterior corneal densitometry, with measurements returning close to baseline by 20-minute postinstillation in healthy eyes. In patients with DED, fluorescein may locally enhance densitometry of epithelial defects and could offer a novel, objective method for assessing corneal surface integrity. Further studies are needed to validate its clinical utility.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sadeghi</LastName><ForeName>Nima</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-5751-8463</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Pharmacy, Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Universitair Ziekenhuis Brussel (UZB), Jette, Belgium; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oellerich</LastName><ForeName>Silke</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Pharmacy, Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Universitair Ziekenhuis Brussel (UZB), Jette, Belgium; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Savieri</LastName><ForeName>Perseverence</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Core Facility Support for Quantitative and Qualitative Research (SQUARE), Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ni Dhubhghaill</LastName><ForeName>Sorcha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Pharmacy, Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Universitair Ziekenhuis Brussel (UZB), Jette, Belgium; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cornea</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8216186</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0277-3740</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pentacam</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scheimpflug imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">backscattering</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cornea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">densitometry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dry eye disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fluorescein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quantitative analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">superficial punctate keratitis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41247275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ICO.0000000000004025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00003226-990000000-01013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ambr&#xf3;sio R, Belin MW. Imaging of the cornea: topography vs tomography. J Refractive Surg. 2010;26:847&#x2013;849.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belin MW, Ambr&#xf3;sio R. Scheimpflug imaging for keratoconus and ectatic disease. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2013;61:401&#x2013;406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der S, M&#xe4;urer S, Eppig T, et al. Comparison of corneal tomography: repeatability, precision, misalignment, mean elevation, and mean pachymetry. Curr Eye Res. 2018;43:709&#x2013;716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanclerz P, Radomski SA. Corneal tomography in a commercially available optical coherence tomography device and comparison with a rotating scheimpflug camera. Eye Contact Lens. 2024;50:138&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanavaty MA, Favor MP, Lake DB. Comparison of equivalent keratometric indices on Scheimpflug tomography with Placido-based topography system at different optical zones. Br J Ophthalmol. 2013;97:350&#x2013;356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira CM, Ribeiro C, Franco S. Corneal imaging with slit-scanning and Scheimpflug imaging techniques. Clin Exp Optom. 2011;94:33&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirnschall N, Crnej A, Gangwani V, et al. Effect of fluorescein dye staining of the tear film on Scheimpflug measurements of central corneal thickness. Cornea. 2012;31:18&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briggs S, Bin Moammar M. Effect of 2% fluorescein on Scheimpflug central corneal thickness measurements. Int J Ophthalmol. 2016;9:239&#x2013;242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padmanabhan P, Belin MW, Sudhir RR, et al. Implications of diagnostic drops on scheimpflug tomography: the proper order for clinical testing. Cornea. 2022;41:958&#x2013;964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soifer M, Azar NS, Blanco R, et al. Fluorescein CorneoGraphy (FCG): use of a repurposed fluorescein imaging technique to objectively standardize corneal staining. Ocul Surf. 2023;27:77&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhubhghaill SN, Rozema JJ, Jongenelen S, et al. Normative values for corneal densitometry analysis by scheimpflug optical assessment. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2013;55:162&#x2013;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustafsson I, Bizios D, Ivarsen A, et al. The intra- and inter-day repeatability of corneal densitometry measurements in subjects with keratoconus and in healthy controls. Sci Rep. 2023;13:5566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pakbin M, Khabazkhoob M, Pakravan M, et al. Repeatability of corneal densitometry measurements using a scheimpflug camera in healthy normal corneas. J Curr Ophthalmol. 2022;34:50&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang H, Zhou X, Xu J. A novel method for pachymetry mapping of human precorneal tear film using pentacam with fluorescein. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2010;51:156&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macedo M, Hatanaka M, Barboza WL, et al. The influence of topical anesthetic and fluorescein on non-contact tonometry measurements using ultra-high-speed dynamic Scheimpflug. Sci Rep. 2023;13:17864.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sher I, Tzameret A, Szalapak AM, et al. Multimodal assessment of corneal erosions using optical coherence tomography and automated grading of fluorescein staining in a rabbit dry eye model. Transl Vis Sci Technol. 2019;8:27.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>