<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">41156462</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2072-6643</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>20</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrients</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutrients</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Artificial Intelligence in Endurance Sports: Metabolic, Recovery, and Nutritional Perspectives.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3209</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/nu17203209</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Background</b>: Artificial Intelligence (AI) is increasingly applied in endurance sports to optimize performance, enhance recovery, and personalize nutrition and supplementation. This review synthesizes current knowledge on AI applications in endurance sports, emphasizing implications for metabolic health, nutritional strategies, and recovery optimization, while also addressing ethical considerations and future directions. <b>Methods</b>: A narrative review was conducted using targeted searches of PubMed, Scopus, and Web of Science with cross-referencing. Extracted items included sport/context, data sources, AI methods including machine learning (ML), validation type (internal vs. external/field), performance metrics, comparators, and key limitations to support a structured synthesis; no formal risk-of-bias assessment or meta-analysis was undertaken due to heterogeneity. <b>Results</b>: AI systems effectively integrate multimodal physiological, environmental, and behavioral data to enhance metabolic health monitoring, predict recovery states, and personalize nutrition. Continuous glucose monitoring combined with AI algorithms allows precise carbohydrate management during prolonged events, improving performance outcomes. AI-driven supplementation strategies, informed by genetic polymorphisms and individual metabolic responses, have demonstrated enhanced ergogenic effectiveness. However, significant challenges persist, including measurement validity and reliability of sensor-derived signals and overall dataset quality (e.g., noise, missingness, labeling error), model performance and generalizability, algorithmic transparency, and equitable access. Furthermore, limited generalizability due to homogenous training datasets restricts widespread applicability across diverse athletic populations. <b>Conclusions</b>: The integration of AI in endurance sports offers substantial promise for improving performance, recovery, and nutritional strategies through personalized approaches. Realizing this potential requires addressing existing limitations in model performance and generalizability, ethical transparency, and equitable accessibility. Future research should prioritize diverse, representative, multi-site data collection across sex/gender, age, and race/ethnicity. Coverage should include performance level (elite to recreational), sport discipline, environmental conditions (e.g., heat, altitude), and device platforms (multi-vendor/multi-sensor). Equally important are rigorous external and field validation, transparent and explainable deployment with appropriate governance, and equitable access to ensure scientifically robust, ethically sound, and practically relevant AI solutions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grivas</LastName><ForeName>Gerasimos V</ForeName><Initials>GV</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7917-2512</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education and Sports, Division of Humanities and Political Sciences, Hellenic Naval Academy, 18539 Piraeus, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Safari</LastName><ForeName>Kousar</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8390-9003</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Sciences, Faculty of Education and Psychology, Shiraz University, Shiraz 84334-71946, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Nutrients</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101521595</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2072-6643</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001185" MajorTopicYN="Y">Artificial Intelligence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064133" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sports Nutritional Physiological Phenomena</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="N">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athlete monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">performance analytics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physiological modeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports technology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wearable technology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The expanding role of AI in endurance sport is tightly coupled to commercial incentives. Technology vendors, wearable manufacturers, and digital-health platforms drive innovation to enhance performance&#x2014;and to grow market share, engagement, and data assets. Popular systems (e.g., WHOOP, Boston, MA, USA; Garmin Connect, Supersapiens) are marketed as performance tools, yet their business models often depend on continuous collection of biometric and behavioral data to power proprietary algorithms [88,89]. While these platforms can deliver useful feedback and individualized recommendations, product design is frequently steered by subscription economics, stickiness metrics, and long-term data retention. This raises concerns about data ownership, secondary use, and transparency, with terms of service that many athletes cannot realistically audit or understand [90]. Commercial pressures can also create conflicts of interest. Features that prioritize engagement or upselling, such as prominent stress or recovery scores, may outpace physiological validation, potentially misleading users or prompting unnecessary behavior changes. This dynamic of &#x201c;data capitalism&#x201d;, whereby athlete-generated data are monetized, conflicts with the beneficence expected in sport science and health technology [91]. Reliance on opaque, proprietary algorithms can shift the athlete&#x2013;coach relationship toward passive compliance, and cost barriers for premium devices or subscriptions risk widening access gaps across programs and regions [92]. Practical safeguards are therefore essential. Athlete-centered data rights (clear ownership, portability, meaningful opt-in/opt-out), plain-language privacy policies, and data-minimization with privacy-by-design should be the default. Independent validation of algorithms, public model and dataset summaries (&#x201c;model cards&#x201d;/&#x201c;data sheets&#x201d;), disclosure of commercial interests, and firewalls between engagement metrics and health-critical outputs help maintain scientific integrity. Open or auditable interfaces and transparent update logs support accountability, while tiered pricing, institutional licensing, and community access programs can reduce inequities. Progress will require coordination between vendors, teams, regulators, and researchers so that commercialization does not override athlete welfare, scientific validity, or ethical accountability. Require independent external validation of vendor algorithms and firewall engagement metrics from health-critical outputs. Provide plain-language data rights (ownership, portability, opt-in/opt-out) and offer tiered pricing or institutional licenses to reduce access inequities. The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41156462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12566783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu17203209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">nu17203209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amawi A., AlKasasbeh W., Jaradat M., Almasri A., Alobaidi S., Hammad A.A., Bishtawi T., Fataftah B., Turk N., Saoud H.A., et al. Athletes&#x2019; Nutritional Demands: A Narrative Review of Nutritional Requirements. Front. Nutr. 2024;10:1331854. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2023.1331854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2023.1331854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10848936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38328685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cossich V.R.A., Carlgren D., Holash R.J., Katz L. Technological Breakthroughs in Sport: Current Practice and Future Potential of Artificial Intelligence, Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, and Modern Data Visualization in Performance Analysis. Appl. Sci. 2023;13:12965. doi: 10.3390/app132312965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app132312965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou D., Keogh J.W.L., Ma Y., Tong R.K.Y., Khan A.R., Jennings N.R. Artificial Intelligence in Sport: A Narrative Review of Applications, Challenges and Future Trends. J. Sports Sci. 2025 doi: 10.1080/02640414.2025.2518694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2025.2518694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40518658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menges T. Advancing Endurance Sports with Artificial Intelligence: Application-Focused Perspectives. In: Dindorf C., Bartaguiz E., Gassmann F., Fr&#xf6;hlich M., editors. Artificial Intelligence in Sports, Movement, and Health. Springer Nature; Cham, Switzerland: 2024. pp. 31&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerebourg L., Saboul D., Cl&#xe9;men&#xe7;on M., Coquart J.B. Prediction of Marathon Performance Using Artificial Intelligence. Int. J. Sports Med. 2023;44:352&#x2013;360. doi: 10.1055/a-1993-2371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1993-2371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36473492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothschild J.A., Stewart T., Kilding A.E., Plews D.J. Predicting Daily Recovery during Long-Term Endurance Training Using Machine Learning Analysis. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2024;124:3279&#x2013;3290. doi: 10.1007/s00421-024-05530-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-024-05530-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11519101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38900201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smaranda A.M., Dr&#x103;goiu T.S., Caramoci A., Afetelor A.A., Ionescu A.M., B&#x103;d&#x103;r&#x103;u I.A. Artificial Intelligence in Sports Medicine: Reshaping Electrocardiogram Analysis for Athlete Safety&#x2014;A Narrative Review. Sports. 2024;12:144. doi: 10.3390/sports12060144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports12060144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11209071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38921838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasb M., Zhang Y., Chen N. The Role of Artificial Intelligence in Precision Exercise Nutrition: A Shift from Data to Diets. Food Sci. Hum. Wellness. 2025 doi: 10.26599/FSHW.2025.9250623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26599/FSHW.2025.9250623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X., Oniani D., Shao Z., Arciero P., Sivarajkumar S., Hilsman J., Mohr A.E., Ibe S., Moharir M., Li L.-J., et al. A Scoping Review of Artificial Intelligence for Precision Nutrition. Adv. Nutr. 2025;16:100398. doi: 10.1016/j.advnut.2025.100398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.advnut.2025.100398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11994916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40024275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flockhart M., Larsen F.J. Continuous Glucose Monitoring in Endurance Athletes: Interpretation and Relevance of Measurements for Improving Performance and Health. Sports Med. 2024;54:247&#x2013;255. doi: 10.1007/s40279-023-01910-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01910-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10933193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37658967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Z., Liu Y., Hu X., Tang M., Wang L. Validity and Reliability of Inertial Measurement Units on Lower Extremity Kinematics During Running: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. Open. 2022;8:86. doi: 10.1186/s40798-022-00477-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-022-00477-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9237201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35759130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson B.W., Low C.A., Jacobson N., Are&#xe1;n P., Torous J., Allen N.B. Guidelines for Wrist-Worn Consumer Wearable Assessment of Heart Rate in Biobehavioral Research. NPJ Digit. Med. 2020;3:90. doi: 10.1038/s41746-020-0297-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-020-0297-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7320189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32613085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins G.S., Reitsma J.B., Altman D.G., Moons K.G.M. Transparent Reporting of a Multivariable Prediction Model for Individual Prognosis or Diagnosis (TRIPOD): The TRIPOD Statement. BMJ. 2015;350:g7594. doi: 10.1136/bmj.g7594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.g7594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25569120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Cruz Rivera S., Moher D., Calvert M.J., Denniston A.K., Ashrafian H., Beam A.L., Chan A.-W., Collins G.S., Darzi A., et al. Reporting Guidelines for Clinical Trial Reports for Interventions Involving Artificial Intelligence: The CONSORT-AI Extension. BMJ. 2020;370:m3164. doi: 10.1136/bmj.m3164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m3164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7490784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32909959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz Rivera S., Liu X., Chan A.-W., Denniston A.K., Calvert M.J. Guidelines for Clinical Trial Protocols for Interventions Involving Artificial Intelligence: The SPIRIT-AI Extension. BMJ. 2020;370:m3210. doi: 10.1136/bmj.m3210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m3210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7490785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32907797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan M.I., Mitchell T.M. Machine Learning: Trends, Perspectives, and Prospects. Science. 2015;349:255&#x2013;260. doi: 10.1126/science.aaa8415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aaa8415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26185243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy K.P. Machine Learning-A Probabilistic Perspective. MIT Press; Cambridge, UK: 2014. Adaptive Computation and Machine Learning.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camacho D.M., Collins K.M., Powers R.K., Costello J.C., Collins J.J. Next-Generation Machine Learning for Biological Networks. Cell. 2018;173:1581&#x2013;1592. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2018.05.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2018.05.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29887378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeCun Y., Bengio Y., Hinton G. Deep Learning. Nature. 2015;521:436&#x2013;444. doi: 10.1038/nature14539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature14539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26017442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell S., Norvig P. Artificial Intelligence: A Modern Approach. Pearson; Hoboken, NJ, USA: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baltrusaitis T., Ahuja C., Morency L.-P. Multimodal Machine Learning: A Survey and Taxonomy. IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell. 2019;41:423&#x2013;443. doi: 10.1109/TPAMI.2018.2798607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2018.2798607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29994351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammes F., Hagg A., Asteroth A., Link D. Artificial Intelligence in Elite Sports-A Narrative Review of Success Stories and Challenges. Front. Sports Act. Living. 2022;4:861466. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2022.861466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2022.861466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9309390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35899138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali S., Abuhmed T., El-Sappagh S., Muhammad K., Alonso-Moral J.M., Confalonieri R., Guidotti R., Del Ser J., D&#xed;az-Rodr&#xed;guez N., Herrera F. Explainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI): What We Know and What Is Left to Attain Trustworthy Artificial Intelligence. Inf. Fusion. 2023;99:101805. doi: 10.1016/j.inffus.2023.101805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inffus.2023.101805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samek W., Wiegand T., M&#xfc;ller K.-R. Explainable Artificial Intelligence: Understanding, Visualizing and Interpreting Deep Learning Models. arXiv. 2017 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1708.08296.1708.08296</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1708.08296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thuany M., Valero D., Villiger E., Forte P., Weiss K., Nikolaidis P.T., Andrade M.S., Cuk I., Sousa C.V., Knechtle B. A Machine Learning Approach to Finding the Fastest Race Course for Professional Athletes Competing in Ironman&#xae; 70.3 Races between 2004 and 2020. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2023;20:3619. doi: 10.3390/ijerph20043619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20043619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9963404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36834311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Lafaye C., Saubade M., Besson C., Margarit-Taule J.M., Gremeaux V., Liu S.-C. Predicting Hydration Status Using Machine Learning Models from Physiological and Sweat Biomarkers During Endurance Exercise: A Single Case Study. IEEE J. Biomed. Health Inform. 2022;26:4725&#x2013;4732. doi: 10.1109/JBHI.2022.3186150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JBHI.2022.3186150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35749337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeevi D., Korem T., Zmora N., Israeli D., Rothschild D., Weinberger A., Ben-Yacov O., Lador D., Avnit-Sagi T., Lotan-Pompan M., et al. Personalized Nutrition by Prediction of Glycemic Responses. Cell. 2015;163:1079&#x2013;1094. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2015.11.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2015.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26590418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendes-Soares H., Raveh-Sadka T., Azulay S., Edens K., Ben-Shlomo Y., Cohen Y., Ofek T., Bachrach D., Stevens J., Colibaseanu D., et al. Assessment of a Personalized Approach to Predicting Postprandial Glycemic Responses to Food Among Individuals Without Diabetes. JAMA Netw. Open. 2019;2:e188102. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2018.8102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2018.8102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6484621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30735238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach A.F., Alexandersen J., Lundgaard C.B. A Numerical Design Methodology for Optimal Pacing Strategy in the Individual Time Trial Discipline of Cycling. Sports Eng. 2025;28:12. doi: 10.1007/s12283-025-00493-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12283-025-00493-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zignoli A., Biral F. Prediction of Pacing and Cornering Strategies during Cycling Individual Time Trials with Optimal Control. Sports Eng. 2020;23:13. doi: 10.1007/s12283-020-00326-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12283-020-00326-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Dandachi M.-M., Billat V., Palacin F., Vigneron V. Early Detection of the Marathon Wall to Improve Pacing Strategies in Recreational Marathoners. AI. 2025;6:130. doi: 10.3390/ai6060130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ai6060130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason R., Pearson L.T., Barry G., Young F., Lennon O., Godfrey A., Stuart S. Wearables for Running Gait Analysis: A Systematic Review. Sports Med. 2023;53:241&#x2013;268. doi: 10.1007/s40279-022-01760-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01760-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9807497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36242762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimmick H.L., van Rassel C.R., MacInnis M.J., Ferber R. Use of Subject-Specific Models to Detect Fatigue-Related Changes in Running Biomechanics: A Random Forest Approach. Front. Sports Act. Living. 2023;5:1283316. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2023.1283316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2023.1283316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10768007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38186400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson W.R., Mian A., Robinson M.A., Verheul J., Lloyd D.G., Alderson J. Multidimensional Ground Reaction Forces and Moments from Wearable Sensor Accelerations via Deep Learning. IEEE Trans. Biomed. Eng. 2021;68:289&#x2013;297. doi: 10.1109/TBME.2020.3006158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TBME.2020.3006158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32746046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosoli G., Antognoli L., Veroli V., Scalise L. Accuracy and Precision of Wearable Devices for Real-Time Monitoring of Swimming Athletes. Sensors. 2022;22:4726. doi: 10.3390/s22134726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22134726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9269005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35808223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan C., Shu Z., Zhang J., Xue F. Real-Time Prediction for Athletes&#x2019; Psychological States Using BERT-XGBoost: Enhancing Human-Computer Interaction. arXiv. 20242412.05816</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Lin Z., Gu S. A Machine Learning Model the Prediction of Athlete Engagement Based on Cohesion, Passion and Mental Toughness. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:3220. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-87794-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-87794-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11763253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39863787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plews D.J., Laursen P.B., Stanley J., Kilding A.E., Buchheit M. Training Adaptation and Heart Rate Variability in Elite Endurance Athletes: Opening the Door to Effective Monitoring. Sports Med. 2013;43:773&#x2013;781. doi: 10.1007/s40279-013-0071-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-013-0071-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23852425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passfield L., Hopker J.G., Jobson S., Friel D., Zabala M. Knowledge Is Power: Issues of Measuring Training and Performance in Cycling. J. Sports Sci. 2017;35:1426&#x2013;1434. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2016.1215504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2016.1215504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27686573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racinais S., Alonso J.M., Coutts A.J., Flouris A.D., Girard O., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Alonso J., Hausswirth C., Jay O., Lee J.K.W., Mitchell N., et al. Consensus Recommendations on Training and Competing in the Heat. Br. J. Sports Med. 2015;49:1164&#x2013;1173. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2015-094915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-094915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4602249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26069301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nybo L., Rasmussen P., Sawka M.N. Performance in the Heat-Physiological Factors of Importance for Hyperthermia-Induced Fatigue. Compr. Physiol. 2014;4:657&#x2013;689. doi: 10.1002/j.2040-4603.2014.tb00554.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/j.2040-4603.2014.tb00554.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24715563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantzios K., Ioannou L.G., Panagiotaki Z., Ziaka S., P&#xe9;riard J.D., Racinais S., Nybo L., Flouris A.D. Effects of Weather Parameters on Endurance Running Performance: Discipline-Specific Analysis of 1258 Races. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2022;54:153&#x2013;161. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8677617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34652333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry S.E., Valdes A.M., Drew D.A., Asnicar F., Mazidi M., Wolf J., Capdevila J., Hadjigeorgiou G., Davies R., Al Khatib H., et al. Human Postprandial Responses to Food and Potential for Precision Nutrition. Nat. Med. 2020;26:964&#x2013;973. doi: 10.1038/s41591-020-0934-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-020-0934-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8265154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32528151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bermingham K.M., Linenberg I., Polidori L., Asnicar F., Arr&#xe8; A., Wolf J., Badri F., Bernard H., Capdevila J., Bulsiewicz W.J., et al. Effects of a Personalized Nutrition Program on Cardiometabolic Health: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Nat. Med. 2024;30:1888&#x2013;1897. doi: 10.1038/s41591-024-02951-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-024-02951-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11271409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38714898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dash S. Win Your Race Goal: A Generalized Approach to Prediction of Running Performance. Sports Med. Int. Open. 2024;8:a24016234. doi: 10.1055/a-2401-6234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2401-6234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11495242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39439845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson P., D&#xfc;king P., Zinner C., Sperlich B., Hotho A. Smartwatch-Derived Data and Machine Learning Algorithms Estimate Classes of Ratings of Perceived Exertion in Runners: A Pilot Study. Sensors. 2020;20:2637. doi: 10.3390/s20092637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s20092637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7248997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32380738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirscoveanu C.-I., Oliveira A.S. Prediction of Instantaneous Perceived Effort during Outdoor Running Using Accelerometry and Machine Learning. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2024;124:963&#x2013;973. doi: 10.1007/s00421-023-05322-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-023-05322-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10879226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37773522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barsumyan A., Shyla R., Saukkonen A., Soost C., Graw J.A., Burchard R. Quantifying Training Response in Cycling Based on Cardiovascular Drift Using Machine Learning. Front. Artif. Intell. 2025;8:1623384. doi: 10.3389/frai.2025.1623384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frai.2025.1623384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12271085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40687435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang G., Mao X., Zhang Q., Lu A. Fatigue Detection in Running with Inertial Measurement Unit and Machine Learning; Proceedings of the 2022 10th International Conference on Bioinformatics and Computational Biology (ICBCB); Hangzhou, China. 13 May 2022; pp. 85&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang P., Wang C., Chen Y., Wang G., Lu A. Identification of Runner Fatigue Stages Based on Inertial Sensors and Deep Learning. Front. Bioeng. Biotechnol. 2023;11:1302911. doi: 10.3389/fbioe.2023.1302911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2023.1302911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10691589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38047289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radtke T., Crook S., Kaltsakas G., Louvaris Z., Berton D., Urquhart D.S., Kampouras A., Rabinovich R.A., Verges S., Kontopidis D., et al. ERS Statement on Standardisation of Cardiopulmonary Exercise Testing in Chronic Lung Diseases. Eur. Respir. Rev. 2019;28:180101. doi: 10.1183/16000617.0101-2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/16000617.0101-2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9488712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31852745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowler A.-L.M., Whitfield J., Marshall L., Coffey V.G., Burke L.M., Cox G.R. The Use of Continuous Glucose Monitors in Sport: Possible Applications and Considerations. Int. J. Sport Nutr. Exerc. Metab. 2022;33:121&#x2013;132. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2022-0139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2022-0139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36572039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Thoracic Society. American College of Chest Physicians ATS/ACCP Statement on Cardiopulmonary Exercise Testing. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 2003;167:211&#x2013;277. doi: 10.1164/rccm.167.2.211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.167.2.211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12524257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadmus-Bertram L., Gangnon R., Wirkus E.J., Thraen-Borowski K.M., Gorzelitz-Liebhauser J. Accuracy of Heart Rate Monitoring by Some Wrist-Worn Activity Trackers. Ann. Intern. Med. 2017;167:607&#x2013;608. doi: 10.7326/L17-0380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/L17-0380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29049770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boudreaux B.D., Hebert E.P., Hollander D.B., Williams B.M., Cormier C.L., Naquin M.R., Gillan W.W., Gusew E.E., Kraemer R.R. Validity of Wearable Activity Monitors during Cycling and Resistance Exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2018;50:624&#x2013;633. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29189666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberti K.G.M.M., Eckel R.H., Grundy S.M., Zimmet P.Z., Cleeman J.I., Donato K.A., Fruchart J.-C., James W.P.T., Loria C.M., Smith S.C., et al. Harmonizing the Metabolic Syndrome: A Joint Interim Statement of the International Diabetes Federation Task Force on Epidemiology and Prevention; National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute; American Heart Association; World Heart Federation; International Atherosclerosis Society; and International Association for the Study of Obesity. Circulation. 2009;120:1640&#x2013;1645. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.109.192644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.109.192644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19805654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zignoli A., Fornasiero A., Stella F., Pellegrini B., Schena F., Biral F., Laursen P.B. Expert-Level Classification of Ventilatory Thresholds from Cardiopulmonary Exercising Test Data with Recurrent Neural Networks. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 2019;19:1221&#x2013;1229. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2019.1587523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2019.1587523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30880591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zignoli A., Fornasiero A., Rota P., Muollo V., Peyr&#xe9;-Tartaruga L.A., Low D.A., Fontana F.Y., Besson D., P&#xfc;hringer M., Ring-Dimitriou S., et al. Oxynet: A Collective Intelligence That Detects Ventilatory Thresholds in Cardiopulmonary Exercise Tests. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 2022;22:425&#x2013;435. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2020.1866081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2020.1866081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33331795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moser O., Riddell M.C., Eckstein M.L., Adolfsson P., Rabasa-Lhoret R., van den Boom L., Gillard P., N&#xf8;rgaard K., Oliver N.S., Zaharieva D.P., et al. Glucose Management for Exercise Using Continuous Glucose Monitoring (CGM) and Intermittently Scanned CGM (isCGM) Systems in Type 1 Diabetes: Position Statement of the European Association for the Study of Diabetes (EASD) and of the International Society for Pediatric and Adolescent Diabetes (ISPAD) Endorsed by JDRF and Supported by the American Diabetes Association (ADA) Pediatr. Diabetes. 2020;21:1375&#x2013;1393. doi: 10.1111/pedi.13105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pedi.13105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7702152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33047481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheridan D., Jaspers A., Viet Cuong D., Op De Be&#xe9;ck T., Moyna N.M., de Beukelaar T.T., Roantree M. Estimating Oxygen Uptake in Simulated Team Sports Using Machine Learning Models and Wearable Sensor Data: A Pilot Study. PLoS ONE. 2025;20:e0319760. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0319760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0319760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12011253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40258017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsiao C.-T., Tong C., Cot&#xe9; G.L. Machine Learning-Based VO2 Estimation Using a Wearable Multiwavelength Photoplethysmography Device. Biosensors. 2025;15:208. doi: 10.3390/bios15040208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bios15040208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12024819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40277522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R., Duclos M., Foster C., Fry A., Gleeson M., Nieman D., Raglin J., Rietjens G., Steinacker J., Urhausen A., et al. Prevention, Diagnosis, and Treatment of the Overtraining Syndrome: Joint Consensus Statement of the European College of Sport Science and the American College of Sports Medicine. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2013;45:186&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2012.730061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2012.730061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23247672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marotta L., Buurke J.H., van Beijnum B.-J.F., Reenalda J. Towards Machine Learning-Based Detection of Running-Induced Fatigue in Real-World Scenarios: Evaluation of IMU Sensor Configurations to Reduce Intrusiveness. Sensors. 2021;21:3451. doi: 10.3390/s21103451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s21103451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8156769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34063478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller D.J., Lastella M., Scanlan A.T., Bellenger C., Halson S.L., Roach G.D., Sargent C. A Validation Study of the WHOOP Strap against Polysomnography to Assess Sleep. J. Sports Sci. 2020;38:2631&#x2013;2636. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2020.1797448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2020.1797448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32713257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bent B., Goldstein B.A., Kibbe W.A., Dunn J.P. Investigating Sources of Inaccuracy in Wearable Optical Heart Rate Sensors. NPJ Digit. Med. 2020;3:18. doi: 10.1038/s41746-020-0226-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-020-0226-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7010823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32047863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soligard T., Schwellnus M., Alonso J.-M., Bahr R., Clarsen B., Dijkstra H.P., Gabbett T., Gleeson M., H&#xe4;gglund M., Hutchinson M.R., et al. How Much Is Too Much? (Part 1) International Olympic Committee Consensus Statement on Load in Sport and Risk of Injury. Br. J. Sports Med. 2016;50:1030&#x2013;1041. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2016-096581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27535989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutehall S., Pitsiladis Y. Personalized Nutrition for the Enhancement of Elite Athletic Performance. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports. 2025;35:e70044. doi: 10.1111/sms.70044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.70044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11958001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40164953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;ger R., Kerksick C.M., Campbell B.I., Cribb P.J., Wells S.D., Skwiat T.M., Purpura M., Ziegenfuss T.N., Ferrando A.A., Arent S.M., et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition Position Stand: Protein and Exercise. J. Int. Soc. Sports Nutr. 2017;14:20. doi: 10.1186/s12970-017-0177-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-017-0177-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5477153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28642676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake J.M., Neubauer O., Della Gatta P.A., Nosaka K. Muscle Damage and Inflammation during Recovery from Exercise. J. Appl. Physiol. 2017;122:559&#x2013;570. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00971.2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00971.2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28035017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke L.M., Sharma A.P., Heikura I.A., Forbes S.F., Holloway M., McKay A.K.A., Bone J.L., Leckey J.J., Welvaert M., Ross M.L. Crisis of Confidence Averted: Impairment of Exercise Economy and Performance in Elite Race Walkers by Ketogenic Low Carbohydrate, High Fat (LCHF) Diet Is Reproducible. PLoS ONE. 2020;15:e0234027. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0234027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0234027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7272074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32497061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holzer R., Bloch W., Brinkmann C. Continuous Glucose Monitoring in Healthy Adults-Possible Applications in Health Care, Wellness, and Sports. Sensors. 2022;22:2030. doi: 10.3390/s22052030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22052030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8915088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35271177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishihara K., Uchiyama N., Kizaki S., Mori E., Nonaka T., Oneda H. Application of Continuous Glucose Monitoring for Assessment of Individual Carbohydrate Requirement during Ultramarathon Race. Nutrients. 2020;12:1121. doi: 10.3390/nu12041121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12041121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7230511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32316458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Cao Y., Luo Y., Chen G., Vokkarane V., Ma Y. DeepFood: Deep Learning-Based Food Image Recognition for Computer-Aided Dietary Assessment. arXiv. 20161606.05675</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nogueira-Rio N., Varela Vazquez L., Lopez-Santamarina A., Mondragon-Portocarrero A., Karav S., Miranda J.M. Mobile Applications and Artificial Intelligence for Nutrition Education: A Narrative Review. Dietetics. 2024;3:483&#x2013;503. doi: 10.3390/dietetics3040035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/dietetics3040035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeiffer B., Stellingwerff T., Hodgson A.B., Randell R., P&#xf6;ttgen K., Res P., Jeukendrup A.E. Nutritional Intake and Gastrointestinal Problems during Competitive Endurance Events. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2012;44:344&#x2013;351. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31822dc809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31822dc809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21775906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira E.P., Burini R.C., Jeukendrup A. Gastrointestinal Complaints During Exercise: Prevalence, Etiology, and Nutritional Recommendations. Sports Med. 2014;44:79&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1007/s40279-014-0153-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0153-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farhud D.D., Zokaei S. Ethical Issues of Artificial Intelligence in Medicine and Healthcare. Iran. J. Public Health. 2021;50:i&#x2013;v. doi: 10.18502/ijph.v50i11.7600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18502/ijph.v50i11.7600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8826344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35223619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nebeker C., Torous J., Bartlett Ellis R.J. Building the Case for Actionable Ethics in Digital Health Research Supported by Artificial Intelligence. BMC Med. 2019;17:137. doi: 10.1186/s12916-019-1377-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-019-1377-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6636063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31311535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharon T. When Digital Health Meets Digital Capitalism, How Many Common Goods Are at Stake? Big Data Soc. 2018;5:2053951718819032. doi: 10.1177/2053951718819032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2053951718819032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canali S., Schiaffonati V., Aliverti A. Challenges and Recommendations for Wearable Devices in Digital Health: Data Quality, Interoperability, Health Equity, Fairness. PLoS Digit. Health. 2022;1:e0000104. doi: 10.1371/journal.pdig.0000104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pdig.0000104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9931360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36812619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudin C. Stop Explaining Black Box Machine Learning Models for High Stakes Decisions and Use Interpretable Models Instead. Nat. Mach. Intell. 2019;1:206&#x2013;215. doi: 10.1038/s42256-019-0048-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42256-019-0048-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9122117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35603010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunning D., Aha D. DARPA&#x2019;s Explainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI) Program. AI Mag. 2019;40:44&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1609/aimag.v40i2.2850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1609/aimag.v40i2.2850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCradden M.D., Stephenson E.A., Anderson J.A. Clinical Research Underlies Ethical Integration of Healthcare Artificial Intelligence. Nat. Med. 2020;26:1325&#x2013;1326. doi: 10.1038/s41591-020-1035-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-020-1035-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32908273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tropol E. Deep Medicine: How Artificial Intelligence Can Make Healthcare Human Again. Basic Books; New York, NY, USA: 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sjoding M.W., Dickson R.P., Iwashyna T.J., Gay S.E., Valley T.S. Racial Bias in Pulse Oximetry Measurement. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020;383:2477&#x2013;2478. doi: 10.1056/NEJMc2029240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMc2029240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33326721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebru T., Morgenstern J., Vecchione B., Vaughan J.W., Wallach H., Daum&#xe9; H., III, Crawford K. Datasheets for Datasets. arXiv. 2021 doi: 10.1145/3458723.1803.09010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3458723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dastin J. Ethics of Data and Analytics. Auerbach Publications; Boca Raton, FL, USA: 2022. Amazon Scraps Secret AI Recruiting Tool That Showed Bias against Women.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Se&#xe7;kin A.&#xc7;., Ate&#x15f; B., Se&#xe7;kin M. Review on Wearable Technology in Sports: Concepts, Challenges and Opportunities. Appl. Sci. 2023;13:10399. doi: 10.3390/app131810399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app131810399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toner J. Wearable Technology in Elite Sport: A Critical Examination. Routledge; London, UK: 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prainsack B. Logged out: Ownership, Exclusion and Public Value in the Digital Data and Information Commons. Big Data Soc. 2019;6:2053951719829773. doi: 10.1177/2053951719829773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2053951719829773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuboff S. The Age of Surveillance Capitalism: The Fight for a Human Future at the New Frontier of Power. PublicAffairs; New York, NY, USA: 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sujan M., Furniss D., Grundy K., Grundy H., Nelson D., Elliott M., White S., Habli I., Reynolds N. Human Factors Challenges for the Safe Use of Artificial Intelligence in Patient Care. BMJ Health Care Inform. 2019;26:e100081. doi: 10.1136/bmjhci-2019-100081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjhci-2019-100081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7252977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31780459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sommen F., de Groof J. Risks and Rewards of AI Democratization. United Eur. Gastroenterol. J. 2024;12:427&#x2013;428. doi: 10.1002/ueg2.12560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ueg2.12560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11091771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38526950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obermeyer Z., Powers B., Vogeli C., Mullainathan S. Dissecting Racial Bias in an Algorithm Used to Manage the Health of Populations. Science. 2019;366:447&#x2013;453. doi: 10.1126/science.aax2342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aax2342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31649194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zallio M., Ike C.B., Chiv&#x103;ran C. Designing Artificial Intelligence: Exploring Inclusion, Diversity, Equity, Accessibility, and Safety in Human-Centric Emerging Technologies. AI. 2025;6:143. doi: 10.3390/ai6070143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ai6070143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floridi L., Cowls J., Beltrametti M., Chatila R., Chazerand P., Dignum V., Luetge C., Madelin R., Pagallo U., Rossi F., et al. AI4People-An Ethical Framework for a Good AI Society: Opportunities, Risks, Principles, and Recommendations. Minds Mach. 2018;28:689&#x2013;707. doi: 10.1007/s11023-018-9482-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11023-018-9482-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6404626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30930541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheller M.J., Edwards B., Reina G.A., Martin J., Pati S., Kotrotsou A., Milchenko M., Xu W., Marcus D., Colen R.R., et al. Federated Learning in Medicine: Facilitating Multi-Institutional Collaborations without Sharing Patient Data. Sci. Rep. 2020;10:12598. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-69250-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-69250-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7387485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32724046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaswani A., Shazeer N., Parmar N., Uszkoreit J., Jones L., Gomez A.N., Kaiser L., Polosukhin I. Attention Is All You Need. arXiv. 20231706.03762</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan S.J., Yang Q. A Survey on Transfer Learning. IEEE Trans. Knowl. Data Eng. 2010;22:1345&#x2013;1359. doi: 10.1109/TKDE.2009.191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TKDE.2009.191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kairouz P., McMahan H.B., Avent B., Bellet A., Bennis M., Bhagoji A.N., Bonawitz K., Charles Z., Cormode G., Cummings R., et al. Advances and Open Problems in Federated Learning. arXiv. 2021 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1912.04977.1912.04977</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1912.04977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zerveas G., Jayaraman S., Patel D., Bhamidipaty A., Eickhoff C. A Transformer-Based Framework for Multivariate Time Series Representation Learning. arXiv. 2020 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2010.02803.2010.02803</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2010.02803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins G.S., Moons K.G.M., Dhiman P., Riley R.D., Beam A.L., Calster B.V., Ghassemi M., Liu X., Reitsma J.B., van Smeden M., et al. TRIPOD+AI Statement: Updated Guidance for Reporting Clinical Prediction Models That Use Regression or Machine Learning Methods. BMJ. 2024;385:e078378. doi: 10.1136/bmj-2023-078378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2023-078378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11019967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38626948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai Y.-H.H., Bai S., Liang P.P., Kolter J.Z., Morency L.-P., Salakhutdinov R. Multimodal Transformer for Unaligned Multimodal Language Sequences. arXiv. 2019 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1906.00295.1906.00295</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1906.00295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32362720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang P.P., Zadeh A., Morency L.-P. Foundations &amp; Trends in Multimodal Machine Learning: Principles, Challenges, and Open Questions. ACM Comput. Surv. 2024;56:264. doi: 10.1145/3656580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3656580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim B., Ar&#x131;k S.&#xd6;., Loeff N., Pfister T. Temporal Fusion Transformers for Interpretable Multi-Horizon Time Series Forecasting. Int. J. Forecast. 2021;37:1748&#x2013;1764. doi: 10.1016/j.ijforecast.2021.03.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijforecast.2021.03.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonawitz K., Eichner H., Grieskamp W., Huba D., Ingerman A., Ivanov V., Kiddon C., Kone&#x10d;n&#xfd; J., Mazzocchi S., McMahan H.B., et al. Towards Federated Learning at Scale: System Design. arXiv. 2019 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1902.01046.1902.01046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1902.01046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahan H.B., Moore E., Ramage D., Hampson S., Ag&#xfc;era y Arcas B. Communication-Efficient Learning of Deep Networks from Decentralized Data. arXiv. 2023 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1602.05629.1602.05629</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1602.05629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abadi M., Chu A., Goodfellow I., McMahan H.B., Mironov I., Talwar K., Zhang L. Deep Learning with Differential Privacy; Proceedings of the 2016 ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security; Vienna, Austria. 24&#x2013;28 October 2016; pp. 308&#x2013;318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halilaj E., Rajagopal A., Fiterau M., Hicks J.L., Hastie T.J., Delp S.L. Machine Learning in Human Movement Biomechanics: Best Practices, Common Pitfalls, and New Opportunities. J. Biomech. 2018;81:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1016/j.jbiomech.2018.09.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2018.09.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6879187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30279002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seshadri D.R., Li R.T., Voos J.E., Rowbottom J.R., Alfes C.M., Zorman C.A., Drummond C.K. Wearable Sensors for Monitoring the Internal and External Workload of the Athlete. NPJ Digit. Med. 2019;2:71. doi: 10.1038/s41746-019-0149-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-019-0149-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6662809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31372506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bate G.L., Kirk C., Rehman R.Z.U., Guan Y., Yarnall A.J., Del Din S., Lawson R.A. The Role of Wearable Sensors to Monitor Physical Activity and Sleep Patterns in Older Adult Inpatients: A Structured Review. Sensors. 2023;23:4881. doi: 10.3390/s23104881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s23104881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10222486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37430796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gedi A.A., Khalif A.A., Doon M.A.S., Mohamed A.A., Ali I.A., Ahmed B.A. Personalized Gym Recommendation System Using Machine Learning. Int. J. Eng. Trends Technol. 2025;73:249&#x2013;257. doi: 10.14445/22315381/IJETT-V73I4P122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14445/22315381/IJETT-V73I4P122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucher A., Chaudhry B.M., Davis J.W., Lawrence K., Panza E., Baqer M., Feinstein R.T., Fields S.A., Huberty J., Kaplan D.M., et al. How to Design Equitable Digital Health Tools: A Narrative Review of Design Tactics, Case Studies, and Opportunities. PLoS Digit. Health. 2024;3:e0000591. doi: 10.1371/journal.pdig.0000591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pdig.0000591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11340894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39172776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X., Xiao L., Sun Y., Zhang J., Ma T., He L. A Survey of Human-in-the-Loop for Machine Learning. Future Gener. Comput. Syst. 2022;135:364&#x2013;381. doi: 10.1016/j.future.2022.05.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.future.2022.05.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino J.G., de Oliveira Capanema D., de Souza T.V., Serr&#xe3;o J.C., Machado Pereira A.C., Nassis G.P. Current Approaches to the Use of Artificial Intelligence for Injury Risk Assessment and Performance Prediction in Team Sports: A Systematic Review. Sports Med. Open. 2019;5:28. doi: 10.1186/s40798-019-0202-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-019-0202-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6609928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31270636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haase J. Augmenting Coaching with GenAI: Insights into Use, Effectiveness, and Future Potential. arXiv. 2025 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2502.14632.2502.14632</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2502.14632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindsay R., Spittle M. The Adaptable Coach-a Critical Review of the Practical Implications for Traditional and Constraints-Led Approaches in Sport Coaching. Int. J. Sports Sci. Coach. 2024;19:1240&#x2013;1254. doi: 10.1177/17479541241240853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17479541241240853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett T.J. The Training-Injury Prevention Paradox: Should Athletes Be Training Smarter and Harder? Br. J. Sports Med. 2016;50:273&#x2013;280. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2015-095788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4789704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26758673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittelstadt B. Ethics of the Health-Related Internet of Things: A Narrative Review. Ethics Inf. Technol. 2017;19:157&#x2013;175. doi: 10.1007/s10676-017-9426-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10676-017-9426-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashtiani F., Sreedhara V.S.M., Vahidi A., Hutchison R., Mocko G. Optimal Pacing of a Cyclist in a Time Trial Based on Individualized Models of Fatigue and Recovery. arXiv. 2021 doi: 10.1109/TCST.2022.3178930.2007.11393</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCST.2022.3178930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jianjun Q., Isleem H.F., Almoghayer W.J.K., Khishe M. Predictive Athlete Performance Modeling with Machine Learning and Biometric Data Integration. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:16365. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-01438-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-01438-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12065918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40348828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietraszewski P., Terbalyan A., Roczniok R., Maszczyk A., Ornowski K., Manilewska D., Kuli&#x15b; S., Zaj&#x105;c A., Go&#x142;a&#x15b; A. The Role of Artificial Intelligence in Sports Analytics: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Performance Trends. Appl. Sci. 2025;15:7254. doi: 10.3390/app15137254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app15137254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An R. Artificial Intelligence in Health and Sport Sciences: Promise, Progress, and Prudence. J. Sport Health Sci. 2025;14:101054. doi: 10.1016/j.jshs.2025.101054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2025.101054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12221458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40349842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo&#x17e;i&#x107; V. Artifical Intelligence as the Reason and the Solution of Digital Divide. Lang. Educ. Technol. 2023;3:96&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X., Li X., Guo M. Diversifying Configurational Paths for Athlete Data Protection. Sci. Rep. 2024;14:32053. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-83792-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-83792-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11686122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39738453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>