<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41703157</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mechanism and engineering practice of roof stability for secondary gob-side entry retaining in deep mines.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9518</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-39802-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To facilitate the reuse of the gob-side retained entry as a long-term return airway, alleviate mining-excavation pressure, and reduce roadway development costs, this paper proposes a secondary gob-side entry retaining technique. The study examines the movement behavior of overlying strata throughout the entire process of secondary gob-side entry retaining, introduces a roof support concept based on "major and minor structural zones," establishes a mechanical model of the roof structure for secondary retention, derives a design formula for the roadside backfill, analyzes the main factors influencing the stability of the overlying strata structure, and proposes an integrated "four-in-one" surrounding rock control technology for secondary gob-side entry retaining. The results indicate that: (1) The "major structural zone" of the overlying strata stabilizes only after experiencing three mining disturbances. (2) The coordinated load-bearing behavior of the "minor structural zone" in roof support is crucial to surrounding rock stability. A "four-in-one" control strategy is proposed, integrating the roadside packing bodies on both sides, the roof bolting-cable system, floor reinforcement, and internal roadway support to form a stable load-bearing structure. (3) Appropriately reducing the roadway width, the widths of the two packing bodies, and the cantilever length of the main roof on the goaf side can enhance the support capacity of the coal rib during the initial retention stage. This reduces the load on the packing bodies during the secondary gob-side entry retaining stage, thereby alleviating surrounding rock stress. The proposed approach has yielded favorable outcomes in engineering practice, demonstrating both theoretical relevance and practical significance for supporting roadways under similar conditions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Jingke</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Intelligent Manufacturing and Smart Transportation, Suzhou City University, Suzhou, 215104, China. jkwucumt@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jiarui</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Architecture and Civil Engineering, Huaiyin Institute of Technology, Huai'an, 223001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Fuxing</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing China Coal Mine Engineering Co., Ltd., Beijing, 100013, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>51804129</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2019K139</GrantID><Agency>China Postdoctoral Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024SGY017</GrantID><Agency>Suzhou City University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Backfill</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep mine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Roof</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Secondary gob-side entry retaining</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surrounding rock</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41703157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13004903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-39802-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-39802-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ming, C., He, M. C., Wang, J., Liu, J. N. &amp; Coli, M. Control technology of surrounding rock stability based on compensation theory in gob-side entry retaining with composite hard roof. <i>J. Mt. Sci.</i><b>22</b>(03), 1029&#x2013;1047 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11629-024-8780-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, H. Z., Xu, L. &amp; Wen, Z. J. Ground response and failure mechanism of gob-side entry by roof cutting with hard main roof. <i>J Central South Univer</i><b>31</b>(07), 2488&#x2013;2512 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11771-024-5695-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, L. J., Wang, W. &amp; Zhang, G. J. Study on the technology of gob-side entry retaining by roof cutting to release pressure in fully mechanized mining working face with high stress. <i>J Henan Polytech Univ (Nat Sci)</i><b>40</b>(06), 43&#x2013;53 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. Z., Deng, M., Bai, J. B., Yan, S. &amp; Yu, X. Y. Stability control of gob-side entry retained under the gob with close distance coal seams. <i>Int. J. Min. Sci. Technol.</i><b>31</b>(02), 321&#x2013;332 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmst.2020.11.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, H. S. et al. Bearing characteristics of brokenstone columnin goaf of large dip angle coal seam and stability mechanism of gob-side entryretaining. <i>J. China Univ. Min. Technol.</i><b>54</b>(03), 595&#x2013;608 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Liu, P., Jiang, J. &amp; Sun, Z. Y-shaped ventilation air leakage law of working face of gob-side entry retaining by cutting roof to release pressure. <i>J Min Saf Eng</i><b>38</b>(03), 625&#x2013;633 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. F. &amp; Hua, X. Z. Mechanical analysis on the stability of surrounding rock structure of gob-side entry retaining. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>42</b>(09), 2262&#x2013;2269 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y., Yang, Y. G., Yan, S., Hao, S. P. &amp; Cao, Q. J. Study on reinforcement mechanism of filling body in gob-side entry retaining. <i>J Min Saf Eng</i><b>35</b>(06), 1129&#x2013;1134 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kan, J. G., Wu, J. K., Zhang, N. &amp; Liang, D. X. Structure stability analysis and control technology of surrounding rock of the secondary gob-side entry retaining. <i>J Min Saf Eng</i><b>35</b>(05), 877&#x2013;884 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Q., He, M. C. &amp; Yang, J. Study of a no-pillar mining technique with automatically formed gob-side entry retaining for longwall mining in coal mines. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>110</b>, 1&#x2013;8 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2018.07.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, C. L., Zhang, N., Ran, Z., Gao, R. &amp; Yang, H. Q. Superposed disturbance mechanism of sequential overlying strata collapse for gob-side entry retaining and corresponding control strategies. <i>J Central South Univ</i><b>25</b>(09), 2258&#x2013;2271 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11771-018-3911-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. C. et al. Estimation of the REV size and equivalent permeability coefficient of fractured rock masses with an emphasis on comparing the radial and unidirectional flow configurations. <i>Rock Mech. Rock Eng.</i><b>51</b>(05), 1457&#x2013;1471 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-018-1422-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Q. S., Lei, G. F., Peng, X. X., Lu, C. B. &amp; Wei, L. Rheological characteristics of cement grout and its effect on mechanical properties of a rock fracture. <i>Rock Mech. Rock Eng.</i><b>51</b>(02), 613&#x2013;625 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-017-1340-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dou, L. M. &amp; He, H. Study of OX-F-T spatial structure evolution of overlying strata in coal mines. <i>Chin. J. Rock Mech. Eng.</i><b>31</b>(03), 453&#x2013;460 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin, Y. J. et al. Collaborative bearing mechanism of support body-accumulation body along gobfor gob-sideretention gateway. <i>J. China Univ. Min. Technol.</i><b>54</b>(03), 595&#x2013;608 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. Z. et al. Review and development of surrounding rock control technology for gob-side entry retaining in China. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>48</b>(11), 3979&#x2013;4000 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. Z. et al. Mechanical analysis of roof separation within and outside anchorage zone above backfill area of gob-side entry retaining and its engineering application. <i>J Min Saf Eng</i><b>35</b>(05), 893&#x2013;901 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. Z., Wang, W. J., Chen, Y. &amp; Yu, X. Y. Study on stress state of immediate roof above backfill area ingob-side entry retaining and its application. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>42</b>(08), 1960&#x2013;1970 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, X. J., Dong, C. W., Yuan, Z. X., Zhou, N. &amp; Yin, W. Deformation behavior of gob-side filling body of gob-side retaining entry in the deep backfilling workface. <i>J Min Saf Eng</i><b>37</b>(01), 62&#x2013;72 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, G. R. et al. Stress distribution and deformation characteristics of roadside backfill for gob-side entry of fully-mechanized caving in thick coal seam. <i>J Min Saf Eng</i><b>36</b>(06), 1128&#x2013;1136 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, F. R. et al. Study on key parameters of filling gob-side roadway in the thick layer soft rock fault top. <i>J Min Saf Eng</i><b>36</b>(06), 1128&#x2013;1136 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, M. M. et al. Analysis of supporting resistance of reserved pier column for gob-side entry retaining in wide roadway. <i>Rock Soil Mech</i><b>39</b>(11), 4218&#x2013;4225 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, G. J., Zhang, Y., Chang, X. L. &amp; Xin, Y. J. Technology of partition support by cutting-roof pressure relief and constant resistance reinforcement for double-used roadway with deep excavation-induced damage zone. <i>J Min Strata Control Eng</i><b>4</b>(04), 043027 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, C. L., Zhang, N., Ran, Z., Gao, R. &amp; Yang, H. Q. Superposed disturbance mechanism of sequential overlying strata collapse for gob-side entry retaining and corresponding control strategies. <i>J. Cent. South Univ.</i><b>25</b>, 2258&#x2013;2271 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11771-018-3911-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C. et al. Experimental study on the effect of grouting reinforcement on the shear strength of a fractured rock mass. <i>PLoS ONE</i><b>14</b>(08), 1&#x2013;13 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0220643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6690545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31404074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, G.R., Ma, Z.J., Wu, W.D., Bai, J.B., Du, S.W., Bai, J.W., He, L.J. Research on the mechanism of grouped collapse of thick and hard roof for gob-side entry retaining combined backfill in fully mechanized caving face. <i>Journal of China Coal Society</i>, 1&#x2013;20 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, H. S. et al. Bearing characteristics of brokenstone columnin goaf of large dip angle coal seam and stability mechanism of gob-side entryretaining. <i>J. China Univ. Min. Technol.</i><b>54</b>(03), 561&#x2013;576 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. et al. Optimization analysis of layered materials of composite filling body beside gob-side entry retaining. <i>Coal Sci Technol</i><b>52</b>(10), 21&#x2013;32 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, C. Y., Gao, Y. G., Chen, J., Cui, X. M. &amp; Cai, H. B. Surrounding rock stabilization and deformation evolution of gob-side entry retaining in deep colliery with mega-height coal seam extracted. <i>Chin J Undergr Space Enga</i><b>17</b>(03), 897&#x2013;908 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, K. et al. Application of deep borehole blasting to gob-side entry retaining forced roof caving in hard and compound roof deep well. <i>Chin. J. Rock Mech. Eng.</i><b>32</b>(08), 1588&#x2013;1594 (2013).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>