<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41793487</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-3023</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International urogynecology journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int Urogynecol J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effectiveness of Intensive Preoperative Pelvic Floor Muscle Training in Women with Stress Urinary Incontinence Awaiting Surgery: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00192-026-06559-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION AND HYPOTHESIS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We aimed to investigate the effectiveness of intensive preoperative pelvic floor muscle training (I-PPFMT) in women with stress urinary incontinence (SUI) awaiting mid-urethral sling surgery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Ninety women with SUI scheduled for surgery were randomly assigned to an I-PPFMT group (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;46) or a control group (CG) receiving only education (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;44). The intervention group completed 6-week I-PPFMT emphasizing both endurance and strength, whereas the CG received only education about the pelvic floor. All assessments were conducted before and after the intervention. Pelvic floor muscle (PFM) function was evaluated using the Modified Oxford System (MOS) of grading and perineometric measurements, whereas pelvic floor health knowledge was assessed using the Pelvic Floor Health Knowledge Quiz. In addition, pelvic floor symptoms were evaluated using the Global Pelvic Floor Bother Questionnaire and the Incontinence Severity Index (ISI).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The I-PPFMT group showed significant improvements in MOS (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.85) and ISI (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.90) compared with the control group. Pelvic floor health knowledge also increased significantly in the I-PPFMT group (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.038). GPFBQ scores improved in both groups. Importantly, in 43% of participants, the planned surgical procedure was postponed following completion of I-PFMT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">I-PPFMT significantly enhanced PFM strength and symptom severity. Nearly half of the participants postponed their planned surgical procedure, supporting the integration of structured preoperative PFMT into standard clinical practice as a potentially effective, low-risk, and cost-efficient strategy to optimize continence outcomes and reduce immediate surgical demand.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive license to International Urogynecological Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xdc;zelpasaci</LastName><ForeName>Esra</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>G&#xfc;lhane Faculty of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, University of Health Sciences, Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye. uzelpasaciesra@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xd6;zkutlu</LastName><ForeName>&#xd6;zge</ForeName><Initials>&#xd6;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>G&#xfc;lhane Faculty of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, University of Health Sciences, Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demir</LastName><ForeName>Esma</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>G&#xfc;lhane Institute of Health Sciences, Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, University of Health Sciences, Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>D&#xfc;lger</LastName><ForeName>Ay&#x15f;eg&#xfc;l</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>G&#xfc;lhane Institute of Health Sciences, Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, University of Health Sciences, Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xdc;n Yildirim</LastName><ForeName>Necmiye</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>G&#xfc;lhane Faculty of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation, University of Health Sciences, Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xd6;zdemir</LastName><ForeName>&#xd6;zhan</ForeName><Initials>&#xd6;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>G&#xfc;lhane Faculty of Medicine, Obstetrics and Gynecology, University of Health Sciences, Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int Urogynecol J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101567041</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0937-3462</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic floor education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic floor muscle training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Preoperative rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stress urinary incontinence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Women&#x2019;s health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. This randomized controlled trial was conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki and received ethical approval from G&#xfc;lhane Scientific Research Ethics Committee (approval number: 2025/184). The study was prospectively registered at ClinicalTrials.gov (ID: NCT06957795). Conflicts of Interest: None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41793487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-026-06559-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00192-026-06559-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Doumouchtsis SK, de Tayrac R, Lee J, Daly O, Melendez-Munoz J, Lindo FM, et al. An International Continence Society (ICS)/International Urogynecological Association (IUGA) joint report on the terminology for the assessment and management of obstetric pelvic floor disorders. Int Urogynecol J. 2023;34(1):1&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-022-05397-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36443462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orhan C, &#xd6;zg&#xfc;l S, Baran E, &#xdc;zelpasac&#x131; E, Nakip G, &#xc7;inar GN, et al. Cultural adaptation and validation of the Turkish CONTILIFE: a quality of life questionnaire for urinary incontinence. Int Urogynecol J. 2019;30(1):139&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-018-3823-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30460380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf8; K, Berghmans B, M&#xf8;rkved S, Van Kampen M. Evidence-Based Physical Therapy for the Pelvic Floor. 3rd ed. Edinburgh: Elsevier; 2023. p. 202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todhunter-Brown A, Hazelton C, Campbell P, Elders A, Hagen S, McClurg D. Conservative interventions for treating urinary incontinence in women: an overview of Cochrane systematic reviews. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2022;9(9):CD012337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36053030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9437962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nambiar AK, Arlandis S, B&#xf8; K, Cobussen-Boekhorst H, Costantini E, de Hei M, et al. European Association of Urology guidelines on the diagnosis and management of female non-neurogenic lower urinary tract symptoms. I. Diagnostics, overactive bladder, stress urinary incontinence, and mixed urinary incontinence. Eur Urol. 2022;82(1):49&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eururo.2022.01.045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean L, Charette M, Varette K, Brooks K, Harvey M-A, Robert M, et al. Pelvic floor muscle training as an adjunct to a midurethral sling: a single-blind randomised controlled trial. Int Urogynecol J. 2022;33(4):809&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-020-04668-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33660001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung VW, Borello-France D, Newman DK, Richter HE, Lukacz ES, Moalli P, et al. Effect of behavioral and pelvic floor muscle therapy combined with surgery vs surgery alone on incontinence symptoms among women with mixed urinary incontinence: the ESTEEM randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2019;322(11):1066&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2019.12467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31529007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6749544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Itkonen Freitas A-M, Mentula M, Rahkola-Soisalo P, Tulokas S, Mikkola TS. Tension-free vaginal tape surgery versus polyacrylamide hydrogel injection for primary stress urinary incontinence: a randomized clinical trial. J Urol. 2020;203(2):372&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JU.0000000000000517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31479396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nauman K, Stolzle A, Owens L, Frilot CF, Gomelsky A. Impact of preoperative pelvic floor muscle training (pretraining) on urinary storage and emptying symptoms in women undergoing sling surgery. Int Urogynecol J. 2022;33(3):673&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-021-04870-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34106321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tunn R, Baessler K, Kn&#xfc;pfer S, Hampel C. Urinary incontinence and pelvic organ prolapse in women: prevention and treatment. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2023;120(5):71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36647585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10080228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin L, Li M, Pan M. The therapeutic effect of pelvic floor muscle training on stress urinary incontinence following prostatectomy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Transl Androl Urol. 2023;12(7):1155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/tau-23-337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37554527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10406533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szyma&#x144;ski JK, Starzec-Proserpio M, Bartosi&#x144;ska-Raczkiewicz D, Krawczyk A, Kukulski P, Jakiel G. Impact of preoperative pelvic floor muscle function on the success of surgical treatment of pelvic organ prolapse. Int Urogynecol J. 2024;35(1):85&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-023-05653-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37819368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akay E, G&#xfc;ler OM, Bayraktar HK, G&#xfc;l ADU, T&#xfc;rko&#x11f;lu A. Psychometric validity and reliability of the Turkish version of the questionnaire for urinary incontinence diagnosis in women with urinary incontinence. BMC Womens Health. 2025;25(1):197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-025-03730-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40253398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12008939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frawley H, Shelly B, Morin M. Fundamentals of terminology in pelvic floor muscle assessment: a concise reference. Continence. 2025;14:101756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cont.2025.101756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laycock J, Jerwood D. Pelvic floor muscle assessment: the perfect scheme. Physiotherapy. 2001;87(12):631&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0031-9406(05)61108-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf8; K. Pressure measurements during pelvic floor muscle contractions: the effect of different positions of the vaginal measuring device. Neurourol Urodyn. 1992;11(2):107&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1002/nau.1930110205 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nau.1930110205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf8; K, Finckenhagen HB. Vaginal palpation of pelvic floor muscle strength: inter-test reproducibility and comparison between palpation and vaginal squeeze pressure. Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2001;80(10):883&#x2013;883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11580731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmani N, Mohseni-Bandpei MA. Application of perineometer in the assessment of pelvic floor muscle strength and endurance: a reliability study. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2011;15(2):209&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2009.07.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21419362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al&#x2019;Deges W, Toprak &#xc7;elenay &#x15e;. Development of pelvic floor health knowledge quiz: validity and reliability. Turk J Physiother Rehabil. 2021;32(2):122&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21653/tjpr.754949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Do&#x11f;an H, &#xd6;zengin N, Bakar Y, Duran B. Reliability and validity of a Turkish version of the Global Pelvic Floor Bother Questionnaire. Int Urogynecol J. 2016;27(10):1577&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-016-3014-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27037562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazar HU, &#x15e;irin A. A validity and reliability study of the incontinence index. Meandros Med Dent J. 2008;9(3):5&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagen S, Elders A, Stratton S, Sergenson N, Bugge C, Dean S, et al. Effectiveness of pelvic floor muscle training with and without electromyographic biofeedback for urinary incontinence in women: multicentre randomised controlled trial. BMJ 2020; 371:m3719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m3719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33055247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7555069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerlegiz ENA, Akbayrak T, G&#xfc;r&#x15f;en C, Yazici MS, Bolat NM, Akdo&#x11f;an B, et al. Lifestyle recommendations and pelvic floor muscle training with Knack maneuver for post-prostatectomy urinary incontinence: a randomized controlled trial. Support Care Cancer. 2025;33(2):132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39888446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11785613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrier-Noreau G, Le Berre M, Mercier J, Mont-Briant S, Dumoulin C. Group-based pelvic floor muscle training for urinary incontinence in postmenopausal women: tips and tricks for successful practice: ICS 2023 workshop. Continence. 2025;15:101906. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cont.2025.101906 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cont.2025.101906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumoulin C, Cacciari LP, Hay-Smith EJC. Pelvic floor muscle training versus no treatment, or inactive control treatments, for urinary incontinence in women. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2018;10(10):CD005654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30288727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6516955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szyma&#x144;ski JK, Krawczyk A, Starzec-Proserpio M, Raczkiewicz D, Kukulski P, Jakiel G. Can pelvic floor muscle function before surgery determine the outcome of surgical treatment of stress urinary incontinence in women? Neurourol Urodyn. 2024;43(7):1665&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nau.25466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38624023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turkan A, Inci Y, Fazli D. The short-term effects of physical therapy in different intensities of urodynamic stress incontinence. Gynecol Obstet Invest. 2005;59(1):43&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000081133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15459518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf8; K, Hilde G. Does it work in the long term?&#x2014;a systematic review on pelvic floor muscle training for female stress urinary incontinence. Neurourol Urodyn. 2013;32(3):215&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nau.22292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22847318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yak&#x131;t Ye&#x15f;ilyurt S, &#xd6;zengin N, Top&#xe7;uo&#x11f;lu MA. Comparing the efficacy of the Knack maneuver on pelvic floor muscle function and urinary symptoms using different teaching methods: a prospective, nonrandomized study. Int Urogynecol J. 2022;33(10):2895&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-022-05213-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35501571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9060846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodley SJ, Lawrenson P, Boyle R, Cody JD, M&#xf8;rkved S, Kernohan A, et al. Pelvic floor muscle training for preventing and treating urinary and faecal incontinence in antenatal and postnatal women. Cochrane Database System Rev. 2020;5(5):CD007471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32378735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7203602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skaug KL, Engh ME, B&#xf8; K. Pelvic floor muscle training in female functional fitness exercisers: an assessor-blinded randomised controlled trial. Br J Sports Med. 2024;58(9):486&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-107365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38413133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11103308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hay-Smith EJC, Starzec-Proserpio M, Moller B, Aldabe D, Cacciari L, Pitangui ACR, et al. Comparisons of approaches to pelvic floor muscle training for urinary incontinence in women. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2024;12(12):CD009508. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD009508.pub2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD009508.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39704322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11660230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cammu H, Van Nylen M, Blockeel C, Kaufman L, Amy J-J. Who will benefit from pelvic floor muscle training for stress urinary incontinence? Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2004;191(4):1152&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajog.2004.05.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15507935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slack A, Hill A, Jackson S. Is there a role for a specialist physiotherapist in the multi-disciplinary management of women with stress incontinence referred from primary care to a specialist continence clinic? J Obstet Gynaecol. 2008;28(4):410&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01443610802149772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18604676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>