<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41867846</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2692-8205</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>bioRxiv : the preprint server for biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>bioRxiv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Multidimensional Framework for Behavioral Persistence: Dissociable Dimensions of Effort, Endurance, and Sequence Stability in Mice.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2026.03.02.709169</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.64898/2026.03.02.709169</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Behavioral persistence, the maintenance of goal-directed action despite obstacles, is a fundamental adaptive process, yet its scientific study remains fragmented across disciplines with disparate operational definitions. Here, we introduce the Persistence Spectrum (PERCS) framework, a five-dimensional model deconstructing persistence into Perseverance of Effort (P), Strategic Endurance (E), Resistance to Extinction (R), Temporal Consistency (C), and Repetitive Sequence Stability (S). Using programmable operant schedules via the FED3 system, we induced a continuum of persistent food-seeking in mice across four paradigms: Fixed Ratio (FR), Alternating 2&#xd7;2 and 5&#xd7;5, and Random Progressive Ratio (RPR). To objectively identify persistence periods, we developed a session-specific Gaussian mixture model, providing a data-driven alternative to arbitrary frequency thresholds. We found that persistence bouts were fundamentally driven by unrewarded effort, not reward delivery: instantaneous frequency for incorrect pokes significantly exceeded that for correct pokes in FR, 2&#xd7;2, and 5&#xd7;5 (all p &lt; 0.05). This pattern was most pronounced in the high-demand RPR schedule, where high-rate poking continued unabated even after successes, directly challenging reinforcement-centric models and providing strong empirical support for frustration theory. Linear mixed-effects modeling revealed that frequency increased with consecutive unrewarded pokes across all paradigms, with a quadratic (inverted-U) relationship specific to FR and 2&#xd7;2 (p &lt; 0.001), suggesting effort invigoration followed by strategic disengagement in simpler tasks, whereas high-demand schedules maintained linear increases. Notably, the collapse of Sequence Stability (S) in RPR is partly constrained by the task's environmental contingency: random reward rules mathematically restrict stable sequence learning. Aggregate analysis showed total poke counts and unrewarded effort scaled with task difficulty (all p &lt; 2e-16), yet pellet retrieval rates remained stable, indicating goal achievement despite increased challenge. Crucially, PERCS profiles were robust across independent and continuous training histories, demonstrating they reflect stable phenotypes shaped by current contingencies rather than training artifacts. Application of PERCS revealed distinct fingerprints: FR produced near-zero P, E, R, and C but maximal S, characteristic of an efficient habit; 2&#xd7;2 and 5&#xd7;5 elevated P, E, and R while reducing S; and RPR generated highest P and R, lowest S, and marked inter-individual variability. These findings demonstrate that operant schedules dissociably shape distinct persistence dimensions, with unrewarded effort acting as a key motivational trigger, positioning frustrative nonreward as a primary engine of persistent behavior. The PERCS framework provides a unified, quantitative language for characterizing persistent behavior across species and paradigms, offering a powerful tool for linking dimensions to neural circuits and understanding their breakdown in neuropsychiatric disorders.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Tianyu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Zoology and Physiology, University of Wyoming, Laramie, WY 82071.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnston</LastName><ForeName>William R</ForeName><Initials>WR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Zoology and Physiology, University of Wyoming, Laramie, WY 82071.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Christensen</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Zoology and Physiology, University of Wyoming, Laramie, WY 82071.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crouse</LastName><ForeName>Samuel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Zoology and Physiology, University of Wyoming, Laramie, WY 82071.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Qian-Quan</ForeName><Initials>QQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Zoology and Physiology, University of Wyoming, Laramie, WY 82071.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>bioRxiv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101680187</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2692-8205</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41867846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13001402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.64898/2026.03.02.709169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2026.03.02.709169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amsel A. and Roussel J. (1952). &#x201c;Motivational properties of frustration. I. Effect on a running response of the addition of frustration to the motivational complex.&#x201d; J Exp Psychol 43(5): 363&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14946348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aston-Jones G. and Cohen J. D. (2005). &#x201c;An integrative theory of locus coeruleus-norepinephrine function: adaptive gain and optimal performance.&#x201d; Annu Rev Neurosci 28: 403&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16022602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azrin N. H. and Nunn R. G. (1973). &#x201c;Habit-reversal: a method of eliminating nervous habits and tics.&#x201d; Behav Res Ther 11(4): 619&#x2013;628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4777653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barkley R. A. (1997). &#x201c;Attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder, self-regulation, and time: toward a more comprehensive theory.&#x201d; J Dev Behav Pediatr 18(4): 271&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9276836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett I. and Onnela J. P. (2020). &#x201c;Inferring mobility measures from GPS traces with missing data.&#x201d; Biostatistics 21(2): e98&#x2013;e112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7868053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30371736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett J. M., Raineri Tapies M. G. and Shepherd G. M. G. (2020). &#x201c;Manual dexterity of mice during food-handling involves the thumb and a set of fast basic movements.&#x201d; PLoS One 15(1): e0226774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6961851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31940368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumeister R. F., Bratslavsky E., Muraven M. and Tice D. M. (1998). &#x201c;Ego depletion: is the active self a limited resource?&#x201d; J Pers Soc Psychol 74(5): 1252&#x2013;1265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9599441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulos Z. and Terman M. (1980). &#x201c;Food availability and daily biological rhythms.&#x201d; Neurosci Biobehav Rev 4(2): 119&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6106914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradshaw C. M. and Killeen P. R. (2012). &#x201c;A theory of behaviour on progressive ratio schedules, with applications in behavioural pharmacology.&#x201d; Psychopharmacology (Berl) 222(4): 549&#x2013;564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22752382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carcea I., Caraballo N. L., Marlin B. J., Ooyama R., Riceberg J. S., Mendoza Navarro J. M., Opendak M., Diaz V. E., Schuster L., Alvarado Torres M. I., Lethin H., Ramos D., Minder J., Mendoza S. L., Bair-Marshall C. J., Samadjopoulos G. H., Hidema S., Falkner A., Lin D., Mar A., Wadghiri Y. Z., Nishimori K., Kikusui T., Mogi K., Sullivan R. M. and Froemke R. C. (2021). &#x201c;Oxytocin neurons enable social transmission of maternal behaviour.&#x201d; Nature 596(7873): 553&#x2013;557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8387235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34381215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carver C. S. and Scheier M. F. (1982). &#x201c;Control theory: a useful conceptual framework for personality-social, clinical, and health psychology.&#x201d; Psychol Bull 92(1): 111&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7134324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carver C. S. and Scheier M. F. (1998). On the self-regulation of behavior. New York, NY, US, Cambridge University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chevee M., Kim C. J., Crow N., Follman E. G., Leonard M. Z. and Calipari E. S. (2023). &#x201c;Food Restriction Level and Reinforcement Schedule Differentially Influence Behavior during Acquisition and Devaluation Procedures in Mice.&#x201d; eNeuro 10(9).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cronbach L. J. and Meehl P. E. (1955). &#x201c;Construct validity in psychological tests.&#x201d; Psychol Bull 52(4): 281&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13245896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis M., Ressler K., Rothbaum B. O. and Richardson R. (2006). &#x201c;Effects of D-cycloserine on extinction: translation from preclinical to clinical work.&#x201d; Biol Psychiatry 60(4): 369&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16919524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Araujo Salgado I., Li C., Burnett C. J., Rodriguez Gonzalez S., Becker J. J., Horvath A., Earnest T., Kravitz A. V. and Krashes M. J. (2023). &#x201c;Toggling between food-seeking and self-preservation behaviors via hypothalamic response networks.&#x201d; Neuron 111(18): 2899&#x2013;2917 e2896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10528369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37442130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duckworth A. L., Peterson C., Matthews M. D. and Kelly D. R. (2007). &#x201c;Grit: perseverance and passion for long-term goals.&#x201d; J Pers Soc Psychol 92(6): 1087&#x2013;1101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17547490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenberger R. (1992). &#x201c;Learned industriousness.&#x201d; Psychol Rev 99(2): 248&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1594725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floresco S. B., Zhang Y. and Enomoto T. (2009). &#x201c;Neural circuits subserving behavioral flexibility and their relevance to schizophrenia.&#x201d; Behav Brain Res 204(2): 396&#x2013;409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19110006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank E., Kupfer D. J., Thase M. E., Mallinger A. G., Swartz H. A., Fagiolini A. M., Grochocinski V., Houck P., Scott J., Thompson W. and Monk T. (2005). &#x201c;Two-year outcomes for interpersonal and social rhythm therapy in individuals with bipolar I disorder.&#x201d; Arch Gen Psychiatry 62(9): 996&#x2013;1004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16143731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geurts H. M., Corbett B. and Solomon M. (2009). &#x201c;The paradox of cognitive flexibility in autism.&#x201d; Trends Cogn Sci 13(2): 74&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5538880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19138551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goedhoop J., Arbab T. and Willuhn I. (2023). &#x201c;Anticipation of Appetitive Operant Action Induces Sustained Dopamine Release in the Nucleus Accumbens.&#x201d; J Neurosci 43(21): 3922&#x2013;3932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10217991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37185100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goedhoop J. N., van den Boom B. J. G., Robke R., Veen F., Fellinger L., van Elzelingen W., Arbab T. and Willuhn I. (2022). &#x201c;Nucleus accumbens dopamine tracks aversive stimulus duration and prediction but not value or prediction error.&#x201d; Elife 11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goltstein P. M., Reinert S., Glas A., Bonhoeffer T. and Hubener M. (2018). &#x201c;Food and water restriction lead to differential learning behaviors in a head-fixed two-choice visual discrimination task for mice.&#x201d; PLoS One 13(9): e0204066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6136814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30212542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graybiel A. M. (2008). &#x201c;Habits, rituals, and the evaluative brain.&#x201d; Annu Rev Neurosci 31: 359&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18558860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graybiel A. M. and Rauch S. L. (2000). &#x201c;Toward a neurobiology of obsessive-compulsive disorder.&#x201d; Neuron 28(2): 343&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11144344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodos W. (1961). &#x201c;Progressive ratio as a measure of reward strength.&#x201d; Science 134(3483): 943&#x2013;944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13714876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Insel T. R. (2018). &#x201c;Digital phenotyping: a global tool for psychiatry.&#x201d; World Psychiatry 17(3): 276&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6127813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30192103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin X., Tecuapetla F. and Costa R. M. (2014). &#x201c;Basal ganglia subcircuits distinctively encode the parsing and concatenation of action sequences.&#x201d; Nat Neurosci 17(3): 423&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3955116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24464039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killeen P. R., Posadas-Sanchez D., Johansen E. B. and Thrailkill E. A. (2009). &#x201c;Progressive ratio schedules of reinforcement.&#x201d; J Exp Psychol Anim Behav Process 35(1): 35&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2806234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19159161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lejuez C. W., Hopko D. R., Acierno R., Daughters S. B. and Pagoto S. L. (2011). &#x201c;Ten year revision of the brief behavioral activation treatment for depression: revised treatment manual.&#x201d; Behav Modif 35(2): 111&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21324944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lord C., Brugha T. S., Charman T., Cusack J., Dumas G., Frazier T., Jones E. J. H., Jones R. M., Pickles A., State M. W., Taylor J. L. and Veenstra-VanderWeele J. (2020). &#x201c;Autism spectrum disorder.&#x201d; Nat Rev Dis Primers 6(1): 5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8900942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31949163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin R. S. (1991). &#x201c;Apathy: a neuropsychiatric syndrome.&#x201d; J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci 3(3): 243&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1821241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markowitz J. E., Gillis W. F., Jay M., Wood J., Harris R. W., Cieszkowski R., Scott R., Brann D., Koveal D., Kula T., Weinreb C., Osman M. A. M., Pinto S. R., Uchida N., Linderman S. W., Sabatini B. L. and Datta S. R. (2023). &#x201c;Spontaneous behaviour is structured by reinforcement without explicit reward.&#x201d; Nature 614(7946): 108&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9892006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36653449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matikainen-Ankney B. A., Earnest T., Ali M., Casey E., Wang J. G., Sutton A. K., Legaria A. A., Barclay K. M., Murdaugh L. B., Norris M. R., Chang Y. H., Nguyen K. P., Lin E., Reichenbach A., Clarke R. E., Stark R., Conway S. M., Carvalho F., Al-Hasani R., McCall J. G., Creed M. C., Cazares V., Buczynski M. W., Krashes M. J., Andrews Z. B. and Kravitz A. V. (2021). &#x201c;An opensource device for measuring food intake and operant behavior in rodent home-cages.&#x201d; Elife 10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFarland D. J. and Sibly R. M. (1975). &#x201c;The behavioural final common path.&#x201d; Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci 270(907): 265&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">239416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mischel W., Shoda Y. and Rodriguez M. I. (1989). &#x201c;Delay of gratification in children.&#x201d; Science 244(4907): 933&#x2013;938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2658056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevin J. A. and Grace R. C. (2000). &#x201c;Behavioral momentum and the law of effect.&#x201d; Behav Brain Sci 23(1): 73&#x2013;90; discussion 90&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11303339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevin J. A. and Grace R. C. (2000). &#x201c;Preference and resistance to change with constant-duration schedule components.&#x201d; J Exp Anal Behav 74(1): 79&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1284785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10966097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevin J. A. and Grace R. C. (2005). &#x201c;Resistance to extinction in the steady state and in transition.&#x201d; J Exp Psychol Anim Behav Process 31(2): 199&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15839776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onnela J. P. and Rauch S. L. (2016). &#x201c;Harnessing Smartphone-Based Digital Phenotyping to Enhance Behavioral and Mental Health.&#x201d; Neuropsychopharmacology 41(7): 1691&#x2013;1696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4869063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26818126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peca J., Feliciano C., Ting J. T., Wang W., Wells M. F., Venkatraman T. N., Lascola C. D., Fu Z. and Feng G. (2011). &#x201c;Shank3 mutant mice display autistic-like behaviours and striatal dysfunction.&#x201d; Nature 472(7344): 437&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3090611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21423165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podlesnik C. A. and Shahan T. A. (2008). &#x201c;Response-reinforcer relations and resistance to change.&#x201d; Behav Processes 77(1): 109&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17706897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson N. R. and Roberts D. C. (1996). &#x201c;Progressive ratio schedules in drug self-administration studies in rats: a method to evaluate reinforcing efficacy.&#x201d; J Neurosci Methods 66(1): 1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8794935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salamone J. D., Correa M., Farrar A. and Mingote S. M. (2007). &#x201c;Effort-related functions of nucleus accumbens dopamine and associated forebrain circuits.&#x201d; Psychopharmacology (Berl) 191(3): 461&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17225164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandson J. and Albert M. L. (1984). &#x201c;Varieties of perseveration.&#x201d; Neuropsychologia 22(6): 715&#x2013;732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6084826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayar-Atasoy N., Yavuz Y., Laule C., Dong C., Kim H., Rysted J., Flippo K., Davis D., Aklan I., Yilmaz B., Tian L. and Atasoy D. (2024). &#x201c;Opioidergic signaling contributes to food-mediated suppression of AgRP neurons.&#x201d; Cell Rep 43(1): 113630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10865729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38165803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner B. F. (1988). &#x201c;The operant side of behavior therapy.&#x201d; J Behav Ther Exp Psychiatry 19(3): 171&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3069874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Squire L. R. and Zola S. M. (1996). &#x201c;Structure and function of declarative and nondeclarative memory systems.&#x201d; Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 93(24): 13515&#x2013;13522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC33639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8942965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorndike E. L. (1933). &#x201c;A Proof of the Law of Effect.&#x201d; Science 77(1989): 173&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinbergen N. (1972). &#x201c;Functional ethology and the human sciences.&#x201d; Proc R Soc Lond B Biol Sci 182(1069): 385&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4404805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treadway M. T. and Zald D. H. (2011). &#x201c;Reconsidering anhedonia in depression: lessons from translational neuroscience.&#x201d; Neurosci Biobehav Rev 35(3): 537&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3005986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20603146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y. and Sun Q. Q. (2024). &#x201c;A prefrontal motor circuit initiates persistent movement.&#x201d; bioRxiv.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinreb C., Pearl J. E., Lin S., Osman M. A. M., Zhang L., Annapragada S., Conlin E., Hoffmann R., Makowska S., Gillis W. F., Jay M., Ye S., Mathis A., Mathis M. W., Pereira T., Linderman S. W. and Datta S. R. (2024). &#x201c;Keypoint-MoSeq: parsing behavior by linking point tracking to pose dynamics.&#x201d; Nat Methods 21(7): 1329&#x2013;1339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11245396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38997595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiltschko A. B., Johnson M. J., Iurilli G., Peterson R. E., Katon J. M., Pashkovski S. L., Abraira V. E., Adams R. P. and Datta S. R. (2015). &#x201c;Mapping Sub-Second Structure in Mouse Behavior.&#x201d; Neuron 88(6): 1121&#x2013;1135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4708087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26687221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wykes T., Huddy V., Cellard C., McGurk S. R. and Czobor P. (2011). &#x201c;A meta-analysis of cognitive remediation for schizophrenia: methodology and effect sizes.&#x201d; Am J Psychiatry 168(5): 472&#x2013;485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21406461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>