<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41768917</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0971-7196</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>50</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of parasitic diseases : official organ of the Indian Society for Parasitology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Parasit Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Temporal prevalence of cattle trypanosome infection and Tsetse fly density in Zala district, Gofa Zone, Southern Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>53</StartPage><EndPage>61</EndPage><MedlinePgn>53-61</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12639-025-01807-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In Ethiopia, livestock are an integral part of farming systems, and importance sources of high quality protein (meat, milk and eggs) as well as they are contributing to the economic welfare of the people. Bovine trypanosomosis is a parasitic disease causing serious economic impact on livestock productivity and agricultural development. A repeated cross-sectional design was employed to estimate the seasonal prevalence of trypanosome infection and to assess <i>Glossina</i> spp. apparent density in Zala district, Gofa zone. A total of 560 cattle (280 in each season) were examined for trypanosome by using buffy coat technique. For the entomological survey, 80 NGU traps, odour-baited with acetone, were deployed in watering and grazing areas that is where the animals and vector are believed to have frequent contact. The overall prevalence of trypanosome infection in cattle was 7.0% (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;5.1-9.4). The dry and wet season trypanosome infection were 4.3% (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.4-7.4) and 9.6% (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;6.7-13.7), respectively. The prevalence of cattle trypanosome infection was significantly higher during wet season (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.38, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), in black and black-spotted coat color (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.61, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) and poor body conditioned (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.55, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) animals. Both in dry and wet seasons two species of <i>Trypanosoma</i> were circulating in the area: <i>Trypanosoma congolense</i> (87.2%) and <i>Trypanosoma vivax</i> (12.8%). The mean PCV value of infected cattle (20.89&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.04) was significantly lower than in non-infected animals (22.9&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;6.32%). A total of 564 flies were caught, and 56.9% was <i>Glossina</i> spp. and 43.1% was other biting flies. <i>Glossina pallidipes</i> was the only species observed, and moreover, two other genera of biting fly (i.e. <i>Stomoxys</i> spp. and <i>Tabanus</i> spp.). The overall apparent density of <i>Glossina pallidipes</i> was 1.38&#xa0;F/T/D, and it was 1.78&#xa0;F/T/D and 0.99&#xa0;F/T/D, in wet and dry season, respectively. The observed prevalence of trypanosome infection, and <i>Glossina pallidipes</i> apparent density could be a potential threat to animal health and productivity. So, the recorded prevalence was high, and it suggests that the need for the development of strategy for vector and the parasites control.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; Indian Society for Parasitology 2025. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toka</LastName><ForeName>Tone</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zala District Livestock and Fishery Development Office, Gofa Zone, Southern Region Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sheferaw</LastName><ForeName>Desie</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2128-8392</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Hawassa University, P.O. Box 05, Hawassa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04r15fz20</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.192268.6</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0000 8953 2273</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lejebo</LastName><ForeName>Firew</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Arba Minch Animal Health Research Center, Gamo Zone, Southern Region Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hailegebreal</LastName><ForeName>Gizachew</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Hawassa University, P.O. Box 05, Hawassa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04r15fz20</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.192268.6</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0000 8953 2273</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Parasit Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9713059</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0971-7196</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cattle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glossina</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Season</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Trypanosome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Zala district</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interestsThe authors declare that there is no any form competing interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2027</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41768917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12946621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12639-025-01807-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abebe G (2005) Review article: trypanosomosis in Ethiopia. Ethiop J Biol Sci 9:75&#x2013;121. 10.4314/ejbs.v4i1.39017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ejbs.v4i1.39017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abebe G, Malone JB, Thompson AR (2004) Geospatial forecast model for tsetse-transmitted animal trypanosomosis in Ethiopia. SINET Ethiop J Sci 27(1):1&#x2013;8. 10.4314/sinet.v27i1.18215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/sinet.v27i1.18215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abebe R, Gure S, Simon J (2017) Bovine trypanosomosis and vector density in Omo ghibe Tsetse belt, Southern Ethiopia. Acta Trop 167:79&#x2013;85. 10.1016/j.actatropica.2016.12.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actatropica.2016.12.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28007483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemayehu B, Bogale B, Fentahun T, Chanie M (2012) Bovine trypanosomosis: a threat to cattle production in Chena district, South-west Ethiopia. Open J Anim Sci 4(2):287&#x2013;291. 10.4236/ojas.2012.24039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ojas.2012.24039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asresie A, Zemedu L (2015) Contribution of livestock sector in Ethiopian economy: a review. Adv Life Sci Technol 29:79&#x2013;90</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayalew ZA, Manie GF, Kassie M, Mekonnen TM (2021) The economics of trypanosomiasis: empirical evidence on its impacts on livestock production and welfare. AgEcon Search, Research in Agricultural and Applied Economics. International Conference of Agricultural Economists, August 17&#x2013;31, 2021, p 53</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayele T, Ephrem D, Elias K, Tamiru B, Gizaw D, Mebrahtu G, Mebrat E (2012) Prevalence of bovine trypanosomosis and its vector density in Daramalo district, South-Western Ethiopia. J Vet Adv 2(6):266&#x2013;272</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berhe T, Bayleyegn G, Asefa F, Girma S (2015) Prevalence of bovine trypanosomosis and its vector density in tembro district, South-Eastern Ethiopia. J Anim Sci Adv 5(6):1333&#x2013;1343</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5455/jasa.20150616060014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bezabih M, Bisho M (2017) Prevalence of bovine trypanosomosis in Gamo Gofa zone, Ouba Debrestahay district, and Southern Ethiopia. J Vet Med Anim Health 9(9):250&#x2013;254. 10.5897/JVMAH2015.0421</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/JVMAH2015.0421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brightwell R, Dransfield D, Kyorku C, Golder K, Tarimo A, Mungai D (1987) A new trap for <i>Glossina pallidipes</i>. Trop Pest Manag 33(2):151&#x2013;159. 10.1080/09670878709371136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09670878709371136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cecchi G, Mattioli R, Slingenbergh J, De La Rocque S (2008) Land cover and Tsetse fly distributions in sub-Saharan Africa. Med Vet Entomol 22(4):364&#x2013;373. 10.1111/j.1365-2915.2008.00747.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2915.2008.00747.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18785934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constable D, Hinchcliff W, Done H, Gr&#xfc;nberg W (2017) In: Medicine V (ed) A textbook of the diseases of cattle, horses, sheep, pigs, and goats, 11th edn. Elsevier Ltd, St. Louis, MO, pp 2150&#x2013;2156</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CSA (2022) Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia, Ethiopian Statistical Service, Agricultural sample survey, Report on Livestock and livestock characteristics, Statistical Bulletin 594, Volume II, Central Statistical Authority, Addis Ababa, p 219</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degnah E, Fareda B, Bekuma B, Hunde A, Duguma M (2013) Proportion of bovine trypanosomosis in Lalo-Kile district Kelem Wollega zone, oromia regional State, Western Ethiopia. Acta Parasitol Glob 4(2):34&#x2013;40. 10.5829/idosi.apg.2013.4.2.7382</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5829/idosi.apg.2013.4.2.7382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duguma R, Tasew S, Olani A, Damena D, Alemu D, Mulatu T (2015) Spatial distribution of <i>Glossina</i> spp. and <i>Trypanosoma</i> spp. in south-western Ethiopia. Parasites Vectors 8:2&#x2013;10. 10.1186/s13071-015-1041-9
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13071-015-1041-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4544814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26286484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efrem D, Kassa T, Kebede N, Worku T (2023) Seasonal prevalence of bovine trypanosomosis and trypanosome species distribution in Jimma Horo district, oromia regional State, Western Ethiopia. Parasite Epidemiol Control 20:e00280. 10.1016/j.parepi.2022.e00280</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parepi.2022.e00280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9761842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36545242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ephrem A, Geja G (2019) A study on prevalence of trypanosomosis, its risk factors and anemia in cattle of Damot Woyde district, Southern Ethiopia. ARC J Anim Vet Sci 5(4):1&#x2013;18. 10.20431/2455-2518.0504001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20431/2455-2518.0504001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eyasu T, Mekuria S, Sheferaw D (2021) Seasonal prevalence of trypanosomosis, Glossina density and infection along the escarpment of Omo river, Loma district, Southern Ethiopia. Heliyon 7:66&#x2013;67. 10.1016/j.heliyon.e06667</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.e06667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8095118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33997365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fentahun T, Tekeba M (2013) Prevalence of bovine trypanosomosis and distribution of vectors in Hawa Gelan district, oromia region, Ethiopia. J Vet Adv 3(8):238&#x2013;244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5455/jva.20130331025023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuller GK (1978) Distribution of Glossina (Diptera: Glossinidae) in south-western Ethiopia. Bull Ent Res 68:299&#x2013;305. 10.1017/S0007485300007379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0007485300007379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gashururu RS, Githigia SM, Gasana MN, Habimana R, Maingi N, Cecchi G, Paone M, Zhao W, Masiga DK, Gashumba J (2021) An update on the distribution of Glossina (tsetse flies) at the wildlife-human-livestock interface of Akagera National park, Rwanda. Parasites Vectors 14:294. 10.1186/s13071-021-04786-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13071-021-04786-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8173956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34078446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebre T, Kapitano B, Beyene D, Alemu D, Beshir A, Worku Z, Kife T, Selamu A, Debas E, Kalsa A, Asfaw N, Zhao W, Paone M, Cecchi G (2022) The National atlas of Tsetse Fies and African animal trypanosomosis in Ethiopia. Parasites Vectors 15:491. 10.1186/s13071-022-05617-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13071-022-05617-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9798648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36578020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green CH (1988) The effect of color in trap- and screen-orientated responses in <i>Glossina palpalis palpalis</i> (Robineau-Desvoidy) (Diptera: Glossinidae. Bull Entomol Res 78:591&#x2013;604. 10.1017/S0007485300015443</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0007485300015443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leak G (1999) The role in the epidemiology and control of trypanosomosis Tsetse biology and ecology. Wallingford, oxon, OX<sub>10 8</sub>DE, UK. CABI Publishing, p 568</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leak SGA, Ejigu D, Vreysen MJB (2008) Collection of entomological baseline data for Tsetse area-wide integrated pest management programmes Stephen. Joint FAO/IAEA Programme of Nuclear Techniques in Food and Agriculture Vienna, Austria, p 214</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lelisa K, Shimeles S, Bekele J, Sheferaw D (2014) Bovine trypanosomosis and its fly vectors in three selected settlement areas of Hawa-Gelan district, Western Ethiopia. Onderstepoort J Vet Res 81(1):Art715. 10.4102/ojvr.v81i1.715</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4102/ojvr.v81i1.715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25686018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leta S, Alemayehu G, Seyoum Z, Bezie M (2016) Prevalence of bovine trypanosomosis in Ethiopia: a meta-analysis. Parasites Vectors 9:139. 10.1186/s13071-016-1404-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13071-016-1404-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4785740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26965590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer A, Holt HR, Selby R, Guitian J (2016) Past and ongoing tsetse and animal trypanosomiasis control operation in five African countries: a systematic review. PLOS Negl Trop Dis 10(12):e0005247. 10.1371/journal.pntd.0005247</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5222520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28027299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray M, Murray K, McIntyre M (1977) An improved parasitological technique for the diagnosis of African trypanosomiasis. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg 71(4):325&#x2013;326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0035-9203(77)90110-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">563634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngari NN, Gamba DO, Olet PA, Zhao W, Paone M, Cecchi G (2020) Developing a National atlas to support the progressive control of tsetse-transmitted animal trypanosomosis in Kenya. Parasites Vectors 13:286. 10.1186/s13071-020-04156-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13071-020-04156-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7275614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32503681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson J, Butterworth H (1986) A guide to condition scoring of Zebu cattle. International Livestock Centre for Africa, Addis Ababa, pp 1&#x2013;29</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nnko J, Ngonyoka A, Salekwa L, Estes B, Hudson J, Gwakisa S (2017) Seasonal variation of Tsetse fly species abundance and prevalence of trypanosomes in the Maasai steppe, Tanzania. J Vector Ecol 42(1):24&#x2013;33. 10.1111/jvec.12236</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jvec.12236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28504437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock JN (1982) Training manual for tsetse control personnel, vol 1. Tsetse biology, systematics and distribution; techniques, FAO of the United Nation, Rome, p 273</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sergeant E, Perkins N (2015) Epidemiology for field veterinarians. An introduction, CABI, Nosworthy Ways, Wallingford, Oxforshire OX<sub>10</sub><sub>8</sub>DE, pp 116&#x2013;137</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyoum W, Tora E, Kore K, Lejebo F (2022) Seasonal patterns: bovine trypanosomosis, and infection in rift valleys of Gamo zone, Southern Ethiopia. Front Vet Sci 9:805564. 10.3389/fvets.2022.805564</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fvets.2022.805564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8961361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35359685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheferaw D, Birhanu B, Asrade B, Abera M, Tusse T, Fikadu A, Denbarga Y, Gona Z, Regassa A, Moje N, Kussito E, Mekibib B, Asefa T, Woldesenbet Z (2016) Bovine trypanosomosis and Glossina distribution in selected areas of Southern part of rift Valley, Ethiopia. Acta Trop 154:145&#x2013;148. 10.1016/j.actatropica.2015.11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actatropica.2015.11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26581831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sjaastad O, Sand O, Hove K (2020) Physiology os domestic animals, 3rd edn. Scandinavian Veterinary Press, pp 364&#x2013;365. www.scanvetpress.com</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steverding D (2008) The history of African trypanosomiasis. Parasites Vect 1:3. 10.1186/1756-3305-1-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1756-3305-1-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2270819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18275594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadele SK, Ayichew SM (2017) Prevalence and the associated risk factors of bovine trypanosomiasis in Nyangatom pastoral woreda, Southern Nation and nationalities people region (SNNPR), Ethiopia. J Vet Med Anim Health 9(6):105&#x2013;109. 10.5897/JVMAH2017.0560</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/JVMAH2017.0560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse A, Tsegaye B (2010) Bovine trypanosomosis and its vectors in the two villages of Benchi Maji zone: South-Western Ethiopia. Trop Anim Health Prod 42:1757&#x2013;1762. 10.1007/s11250-010-9632-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11250-010-9632-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20577803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor MA, Coop RL, Wall RL (2016) Veterinary parasitology, 4th edn. Wiley, The Atrium, Southern Gate, Chichester, West Sussex, PO19 8SQ, UK, pp 110&#x2013;160 and 393&#x2013;398</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teka W, Terefe D, Wondimu A (2012) Prevalence study of bovine trypanosomosis and Tsetse density in selected villages of arbaminch, Ethiopia. J Vet Med Anim Health 4(3):36&#x2013;41. 10.5897/JVMAH12.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/JVMAH12.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tekile D, Deresa B, Abdurahama M (2014) Proportion of bovine trypanosomosis in Guto Gida district of East Wollega zone, oromia regional State, Ethiopia. Glob J Med Res (G) Vet Sci Vet Med14(2):1&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thrusfield M (2018) Veterinary Epidemiology, 4th edition. Blackwell Science Ltd., London, pp 272&#x2013;293</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uilenberg G (1998) A field guide for the diagnosis, treatment and prevention of African animal trypanosomosis, Adapted from the original edition by Boyt, W.P., FAO of United Nation, Rome, Italy, p 104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vale GA (1982) The trap-orientated behaviour of Tsetse flies (Glossinidae) and other diptera. Bull Ent Res 72:71&#x2013;93. 10.1017/S000748530005029X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S000748530005029X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Bossche P, Rowlands G (2001) The relationship between the parasitological prevalence of Trypanosomal infections in cattle and herd average packed cell volume. Acta Trop 78(2):163&#x2013;170. 10.1016/S0001-706X(00)00182-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0001-706X(00)00182-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11230826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wall R, Shearer D (1997) Veterinary entomology. Arthropod ectoparasites of veterinary importance. Champman and Hall, London, pp 141&#x2013;193</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ZWADO (Zala Woreda agricultural development office) (2023) Annual report of Woreda Agricultural and Development activities, Zala Woreda, Ethiopia</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>