<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41924690</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessment of Functional Capacity and Fatigue Severity in Young Women With Polycystic Ovary Syndrome: A Cross-Sectional Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e104468</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e104468</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e104468</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.104468</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) commonly affects females of reproductive age in India, causing hormone imbalances, irregular menstrual cycles, high testosterone levels, and cysts. It is a chronic illness with no known cure, but medication, lifestyle modifications, and fertility treatments can help in managing some symptoms. In addition to the above irregularities,&#xa0;many physical symptoms, like fatigue and reduced functional capacity (maximal oxygen uptake, or VO<sub>2</sub> max), commonly affect the day-to-day activities of these patients. The degree of impact of PCOS on functional capacity is still underexplored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The objective of the study was to assess the VO<sub>2</sub> max and fatigue level of young females with PCOS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional observational study was conducted in which a total of 37 young females from health science institutions with PCOS aged 18-24 years participated in the study. The Fatigue Severity Scale (FSS) was used to evaluate the fatigue level of females with PCOS. The VO<sub>2</sub> max of the participants was estimated using the Queens College step test&#xa0;(QCST). The Wilcoxon signed rank test and Spearman's rank correlation coefficient were used to analyze the data.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The mean age of the participants was 20.64+1.35 years. The&#xa0;participants'&#xa0;mean VO<sub>2</sub> max was&#xa0;35.25&#xa0;mL/kg/min, which is lower&#xa0;than&#xa0;the&#xa0;typical&#xa0;average&#xa0;of&#xa0;36-45 mL/kg/min.&#xa0;This&#xa0;implies&#xa0;that&#xa0;compared&#xa0;to&#xa0;healthy&#xa0;individuals,&#xa0;females with PCOS had decreased cardio-respiratory fitness (CRF) levels. There was no statistically significant correlation between the duration of PCOS, fatigue, and VO<sub>2&#xa0;</sub>max. The mean fatigue&#xa0;score&#xa0;of&#xa0;39.56&#xa0;indicates&#xa0;that&#xa0;the&#xa0;majority&#xa0;of&#xa0;patients&#xa0;experienced&#xa0;above-average levels of fatigue (p&#xa0;&gt;&#xa0;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">PCOS does not significantly impact VO<sub>2</sub> max in young females, although they showed mildly lower VO<sub>2</sub> max and mild to moderate fatigue levels compared to healthy individuals. Further research is needed to assess the impact of chronic PCOS on these variables.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Kalpesh et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalpesh</LastName><ForeName>Satani</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiorespiratory Physiotherapy, College of Physiotherapy, Sumandeep Vidyapeeth Deemed to Be University, Vadodara, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanghani</LastName><ForeName>Janavi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physiotherapy, Sumandeep Vidyapeeth Deemed to Be University, Vadodara, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Palani G</ForeName><Initials>PG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physiotherapy, Sumandeep Vidyapeeth Deemed to Be University, Vadodara, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiorespiratory fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polycystic ovary syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">queens college step test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vo2 max</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Sumandeep Vidyapeeth Institutional Ethics Committee issued approval SVIEC/ON/phys/BNMPT22/Oct/23/19. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41924690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13036572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.104468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The prevalence of polycystic ovary syndrome in a community sample of Iranian population: Iranian PCOS prevalence study. Tehrani FR, Simbar M, Tohidi M, Hosseinpanah F, Azizi F. Reprod Biol Endocrinol. 2011;9:39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3070632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21435276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of polycystic ovarian syndrome in India: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Bharali MD, Rajendran R, Goswami J, Singal K, Rajendran V. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9826643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36628015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology, pathogenesis, genetics &amp; management of polycystic ovary syndrome in India. Ganie MA, Vasudevan V, Wani IA, Baba MS, Arif T, Rashid A. Indian J Med Res. 2019;150:333&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6902362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31823915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polycystic ovarian syndrome (PCOS): approach to traditional systems, natural and biochemical compounds for its management. Gade R, Dwarampudi LP, Vijayanandhan V, et al. Indian J Biochem Biophys. 2022;59:521&#x2013;527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recommendations from the 2023 international evidence-based guideline for the assessment and management of polycystic ovary syndrome. Teede HJ, Tay CT, Laven JJ, et al. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2023;108:2447&#x2013;2469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10505534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37580314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term metabolic, cardiovascular and neoplastic risks with polycystic ovary syndrome. Cattrall FR, Healy DL. Best Pract Res Clin Obstet Gynaecol. 2004;18:803&#x2013;812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15380148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BMI and polycystic ovary syndrome: demographic trends in weight and health. Mohapatra I, Samantaray SR. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10986768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38567220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adverse effects of selected markers on the metabolic and endocrine profiles of obese women with and without PCOS. Daghestani MH, Daghestani MH, Warsy A, et al. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2021;12:665446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8188979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34122339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polycystic ovary syndrome and reproductive health of women: a curious association. Zehravi M, Maqbool M, Ara I. Int J Adolesc Med Health. 2021;33:333&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33878255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>How to screen and prevent metabolic syndrome in patients of PCOS early: implications from metabolomics. Zhao X, Feng X, Zhao X, et al. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2021;12:659268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8207510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34149613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena I, Kaur AP, Suman S, Abhilasha Abhilasha, Mitra P, Sharma P, Kumar M. Weight Management - Challenges and Opportunities. IntechOpen; 2022. The multiple consequences of obesity; pp. 1&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psychological symptoms and brain activity alterations in women with PCOS and their relation to the reduced quality of life: a narrative review. Pinto J, Cera N, Pignatelli D. J Endocrinol Invest. 2024;47:1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11196322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38485896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polycystic ovary syndrome, diabetes and cardiovascular disease: risks and risk factors. Lakhani K, Prelevic GM, Seifalian AM, Atiomo WU, Hardiman P. J Obstet Gynaecol. 2004;24:613&#x2013;621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16147598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The fatigue severity scale. Application to patients with multiple sclerosis and systemic lupus erythematosus. Krupp LB, LaRocca NG, Muir-Nash J, Steinberg AD. Arch Neurol. 1989;46:1121&#x2013;1123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2803071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psychological distress and fatigue in polycystic ovarian syndrome: a pilot study. Bajpai A, Sharma D. J Hum Reprod Sci. 2025;18:113&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12306717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40740626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Is cardiorespiratory fitness impaired in PCOS women? A review of the literature. Don&#xe0; S, Bacchi E, Moghetti P. J Endocrinol Invest. 2017;40:463&#x2013;469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28028784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardio-metabolic disease and polycystic ovarian syndrome (PCOS): a narrative review. Sangaraju SL, Yepez D, Grandes XA, Talanki Manjunatha R, Habib S. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9203254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35719759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serum testosterone predicts cardiorespiratory fitness impairment in normal-weight women with polycystic ovary syndrome. Bacchi E, Negri C, Di Sarra D, et al. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 2015;83:895&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26173542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health-related criterion-referenced cut-points for cardiorespiratory fitness among youth: a systematic review. Rollo S, Fraser BJ, Seguin N, Sampson M, Lang JJ, Tomkinson GR, Tremblay MS. Sports Med. 2022;52:101&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34468952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graded exercise testing protocols for the determination of VO2max: historical perspectives, progress, and future considerations. Beltz NM, Gibson AL, Janot JM, Kravitz L, Mermier CM, Dalleck LC. J Sports Med (Hindawi Publ Corp) 2016;2016:3968393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5221270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28116349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Queen's college step test and its validity of VO2max: Prediction on young healthy females. Newland A and Nguyen K. https://mavmatrix.uta.edu/kinesiology_studentwork/94/ Kinesiol Stud Res. 2018;94</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A literature review of the effects of PCOS on cardiovascular health. Mundle K, Raza Z. Undergrad Res Nat Clin Sci Technol J. 2021;5:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Validation of the fatigue severity scale in a Swiss cohort. Valko PO, Bassetti CL, Bloch KE, Held U, Baumann CR. Sleep. 2008;31:1601&#x2013;1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2579971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19014080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of physical parameters on Queens College Step Test performance in young adults of Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India: an observational study. Pandya RA, Kaydawala BA, Purohit M, Sheth MS. J Soc Indian Physiother. 2024;8:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Queens College step test calculator. https://www.topendsports.com/testing/tests/step-queens.htm https://www.topendsports.com/testing/tests/step-queens.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Update on PCOS: consequences, challenges, and guiding treatment. Hoeger KM, Dokras A, Piltonen T. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2021;106:0&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33211867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polycystic ovary syndrome, insulin resistance, and obesity: navigating the pathophysiologic labyrinth. Rojas J, Ch&#xe1;vez M, Olivar L, et al. Int J Reprod Med. 2014;2014:719050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4334071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25763405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of continuous and intermittent aerobic physical training on hormonal and metabolic profile, and body composition in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a randomized controlled trial. Ribeiro VB, Kogure GS, Lopes IP, et al. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 2020;93:173&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32286711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiopulmonary impairment in young women with polycystic ovary syndrome. Orio F Jr, Giallauria F, Palomba S, et al. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2006;91:2967&#x2013;2971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16757529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health-related physical fitness in women with polycystic ovary syndrome versus controls: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cirone D, Berbrier DE, Gibbs JC, Usselman CW. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2024;309:17&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36920532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>