<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41578913</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1940-3372</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The plant genome</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Plant Genome</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integrative machine learning approach for identifying genes associated with quantitative traits: A soybean (Glycine max) yield case study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70178</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70178</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/tpg2.70178</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To improve the identification of minor-effect molecular markers and genes associated with quantitative traits, addressing inefficiencies in traditional molecular marker mining and the limited impact of these markers in practical breeding, we analyzed over 15,000 soybean (Glycine max) genotypes across nine maturity groups using an AI-driven genomic approach, uncovering 2513 key genetic markers and 393 genes associated with yield. These included stable determinants unaffected by environmental variability and others with environment-dependent effects. The light gradient boosting machine (LightGBM) model was applied, and model performance was assessed using multiple evaluation metrics across the total datasets by fivefold cross-validation, yielding a mean squared error of 0.0862 and an R<sup>2</sup> of 0.8369, which demonstrates a strong alignment between predicted and observed yield values. To further validate prediction accuracy, a t-test comparing predicted and actual yields produced a T-statistic of 0.5236 with a p-value of 0.60054, indicating no statistically significant difference between the two distributions. These results confirm the reliability and robustness of the LightGBM approach for yield prediction and underscore its potential utility in breeding programs focused on enhancing agricultural productivity. Our maturity group-based analysis revealed region-specific marker distributions, providing refined targets for precision breeding. Three key principles for marker-assisted selection (MAS) in quantitative trait breeding were introduced: marker complementarity, regional specificity, and quantification. Breeding programs should employ comprehensive sets of region-specific markers, while the effectiveness of MAS can be measured based on the number and SHapley Additive exPlanations value of markers utilized. Our approach to assessing marker sensitivity across environments offers valuable perspectives on genotype-by-environment interactions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). The Plant Genome published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Crop Science Society of America.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8448-5540</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Agriculture and Food Science, Florida Agricultural and Mechanical University, Tallahassee, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ouyang</LastName><ForeName>Haoyong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Agriculture and Food Science, Florida Agricultural and Mechanical University, Tallahassee, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Zhengxiao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geography and Environment, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Jiayi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Natural Resources and Environment, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yichan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geosciences, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Zhou</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Agronomy Department, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Chang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5389-0479</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Agronomy Department, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Plant Genome</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101273919</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1940-3372</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005819">Genetic Markers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013025" MajorTopicYN="Y">Glycine max</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="Y">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005819" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Markers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040641" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quantitative Trait Loci</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005838" MajorTopicYN="N">Genotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069600" MajorTopicYN="N">Plant Breeding</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017343" MajorTopicYN="Y">Genes, Plant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019655" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quantitative Trait, Heritable</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Quantitative traits are influenced by complex genetic and environmental interactions, making their improvement a persistent challenge. To enhance breeding efficiency, one effective approach is to achieve accurate phenotype prediction from genome by developing better predictive models and identifying more genes associated with quantitative traits, particularly those with minor effects. Our study applied machine learning to improve the identification of minor&#x2010;effect molecular markers and genes associated with quantitative traits, addressing inefficiencies in traditional molecular marker mining and the limited impact of these markers in practical breeding. Soybean yield is shaped by complex genetic and environmental interactions, requiring advanced tools to pinpoint key genomic regions. This study analyzed diverse soybean genotypes across nine maturity groups and identified chromosome&#x2010;specific markers through maturity zone analysis, enabling region&#x2010;targeted breeding. Using SHapley Additive exPlanations&#x2010;based machine learning, single&#x2010;nucleotide polymorphisms were categorized as positive, negative, or environment&#x2010;dependent contributors to yield. Environmental sensitivity analysis further ranked genes from stable to highly variable, highlighting robust targets for breeding. The study also identified microRNAs as important regulators of yield. These findings offer a valuable resource for molecular breeding and the development of stable, high&#x2010;yield soybean cultivars.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). The Plant Genome published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Crop Science Society of America.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41578913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tpg2.70178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Adeshina, Y. O., Deeds, E. J., &amp; Karanicolas, J. (2020). Machine learning classification can reduce false positives in structure&#x2010;based virtual screening. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 117(31), 18477&#x2013;18488. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2000585117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akond, M., Liu, S., Kantartzi, S. K., Meksem, K., Bellaloui, N., Lightfoot, D. A., Yuan, J., Wang, D., Anderson, J., &amp; Kassem, M. A. (2015). A SNP genetic linkage map based on the &#x2018;Hamilton&#x2019; by &#x2018;Spencer&#x2019; recombinant inbred line population identified QTL for seed isoflavone contents in soybean. Plant Breeding, 134, 580&#x2013;588. https://doi.org/10.1111/pbr.12298</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso, C., Ramos&#x2010;Cruz, D., &amp; Becker, C. (2019). The role of plant epigenetics in biotic interactions. New Phytologist, 221, 731&#x2013;737. https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.15408</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anand, L., &amp; Rodriguez Lopez, C. M. (2022). ChromoMap: An R package for interactive visualization of multi&#x2010;omics data and annotation of chromosomes. BMC Bioinformatics, 23, Article 33. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12859&#x2010;021&#x2010;04556&#x2010;z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayalew, H., Schapaugh, W., Vuong, T., &amp; Nguyen, H. T. (2022). Genome&#x2010;wide association analysis identified consistent QTL for seed yield in a soybean diversity panel tested across multiple environments. The Plant Genome, 15, e20268. https://doi.org/10.1002/tpg2.20268</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandillo, N. B., Jarquin, D., Posadas, L. G., Lorenz, A. J., &amp; Graef, G. L. (2023). Genomic selection performs as effectively as phenotypic selection for increasing seed yield in soybean. The Plant Genome, 16, e20285. https://doi.org/10.1002/tpg2.20285</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batuwita, R., &amp; Palade, V. (2010). Efficient resampling methods for training support vector machines with imbalanced datasets. In The 2010 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN) (pp. 1&#x2013;8). IEEE. https://doi.org/10.1109/IJCNN.2010.5596787</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batuwita, R., &amp; Palade, V. (2013). Class imbalance learning methods for support vector machines. In H. He &amp; Y. Ma (Eds.), Imbalanced learning: Foundations, algorithms, and applications (pp. 83&#x2013;99). Wiley. https://doi.org/10.1002/9781118646106.ch5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamini, Y., &amp; Hochberg, Y. (1995). Controlling the false discovery rate: A practical and powerful approach to multiple testing. Journal of the Royal Statistical Society: Series B (Methodological), 57(1), 289&#x2013;300. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.2517&#x2010;6161.1995.tb02031.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernard, R. L., Cremeens, C., Cooper, R., Collins, F., Krober, O., Athow, K., Laviolette, F., Coble, C., &amp; Nelson, R. (1998). Evaluation of the USDA Soybean Germplasm Collection: Maturity groups 000&#x2010;IV (FC 01.547&#x2010;PI 266.807) (Technical Bulletins 356540). United States Department of Agriculture.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhat, J. A., Adeboye, K. A., Ganie, S. A., Barmukh, R., Hu, D., Varshney, R. K., &amp; Yu, D. (2022). Genome&#x2010;wide association study, haplotype analysis, and genomic prediction reveal the genetic basis of yield&#x2010;related traits in soybean (Glycine max L.). Frontiers in Genetics, 13, 953833. https://doi.org/10.3389/fgene.2022.953833</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobb, J. N., Biswas, P. S., &amp; Platten, J. D. (2019). Back to the future: Revisiting MAS as a tool for modern plant breeding. Theoretical and Applied Genetics, 132, 647&#x2013;667. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00122&#x2010;018&#x2010;3266&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crossa, J. (2012). From genotype x environment interaction to gene x environment interaction. Current Genomics, 13, 225&#x2013;244. https://doi.org/10.2174/138920212800543066</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietterich, T. (1995). Overfitting and under computing in machine learning. ACM Computing Surveys (CSUR), 27(3), 326&#x2013;327. https://doi.org/10.1145/212094.212114</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diniz, W. J. S., Mazzoni, G., Coutinho, L. L., Banerjee, P., Geistlinger, L., Cesar, A. S. M., Bertolini, F., Afonso, J., De Oliveira, P. S. N., Tizioto, P. C., Kadarmideen, H. N., &amp; Regitano, L. C. A. (2019). Detection of co&#x2010;expressed pathway modules associated with mineral concentration and meat quality in nelore cattle. Frontiers in Genetics, 10, 210. https://doi.org/10.3389/fgene.2019.00210</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, R., Albert, P. S., &amp; Schisterman, E. F. (2012). A discussion of gene&#x2010;gene and gene&#x2010;environment interactions and longitudinal genetic analysis of complex traits. Statistics in Medicine, 31, 2565. https://doi.org/10.1002/sim.5495</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto, M. S., Suvorov, A., Jensen, N. O., Clement, M. J., &amp; Bybee, S. M. (2016). Detecting false positive sequence homology: A machine learning approach. BMC Bioinformatics, 17, 1&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12859&#x2010;016&#x2010;0955&#x2010;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gharakhanlou, N. M., &amp; Perez, L. (2024). From data to harvest: Leveraging ensemble machine learning for enhanced crop yield predictions across Canada amidst climate change. Science of the Total Environment, 951, 175764. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.175764</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, H., Xiong, H., Xie, Y., Zhao, L., Gu, J., Zhao, S., Ding, Y., &amp; Liu, L. (2019). Functional mutation allele mining of plant architecture and yield&#x2010;related agronomic traits and characterization of their effects in wheat. BMC Genetics, 20, 1&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12863&#x2010;019&#x2010;0804&#x2010;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajheidari, M., Sunyaev, S., &amp; de Meaux, J. (2024). Are complex traits underpinned by polygenic molecular traits? A reflection on the complexity of gene expression. Plant &amp; Cell Physiology, 66, 444&#x2013;460. https://doi.org/10.1093/pcp/pcae140</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hancock, J., Smith, R., &amp; Johnson, L. (2022). Systematic methods for selecting optimal classification thresholds in machine learning. Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research, 58, 1&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasibuan, L. S., Kusuma, W. A., &amp; Suwamo, W. B. (2014). Identification of single nucleotide polymorphism using support vector machine on imbalanced data. In 2014 International Conference on Advanced Computer Science and Information System (pp. 375&#x2013;379). IEEE. https://doi.org/10.1109/ICACSIS.2014.7065876</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill, J., Peregrine, E., Sprau, G., Cremeens, C., Nelson, R., Orf, J., &amp; Thomas, D. (2005). Evaluation of the USDA soybean germplasm collection: Maturity groups 000&#x2010;IV (PI 507670&#x2010;PI 574486). US Department of Agriculture Technical Bulletin, 1914, 1&#x2013;131. https://www.ars.usda.gov/is/np/SoybeanGermplasm/SoyGerm2005.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill, J., Peregrine, E., Sprau, G., Cremeens, C., Nelson, R., Kenty, M., Kilen, T., &amp; Thomas, D. (2001). Evaluation of the USDA Soybean Germplasm Collection: maturity groups VI&#x2010;VIII (FC 03.659&#x2010;PI 567.235 B). US Department of Agriculture Technical Bulletin, 1894, 1&#x2013;127. https://www.ars.usda.gov/is/np/SoybeanGermplasm/SoyGerm2001.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill, J., Peregrine, E., Sprau, G., Cremeens, C., Nelson, R., Orf, J., &amp; Thomas, D. (2008). Evaluation of the USDA Soybean Germplasm Collection: Maturity Groups 000&#x2010;IV (PI 578371&#x2010;PI 612761). US Department of Agriculture Technical Bulletin, 1919, 1&#x2013;151. https://www.ars.usda.gov/is/np/SoybeanGermplasm/SoyGerm2008-Group4.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holland, J. B. (2004). Implementation of molecular markers for quantitative traits in breeding programs&#x2014;Challenges and opportunities. In Proceedings of the 4th International Crop Science Congress (Vol. 26, pp. 1&#x2013;13). Regional Institute. https://www.ars.usda.gov/ARSUserFiles/60701500/Publications/Holland/Holland4thInt%27lCropSciCong04.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huber, F., Yushchenko, A., Stratmann, B., &amp; Steinhage, V. (2022). Extreme gradient boosting for yield estimation compared with deep learning approaches. Computers and Electronics in Agriculture, 202, 107346. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compag.2022.107346</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyten, D. L., Cannon, S. B., Song, Q., Weeks, N., Fickus, E. W., Shoemaker, R. C., Specht, J. E., Farmer, A. D., May, G. D., &amp; Cregan, P. B. (2010). High&#x2010;throughput SNP discovery through deep resequencing of a reduced representation library to anchor and orient scaffolds in the soybean whole genome sequence. BMC Genomics, 11, 1&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471&#x2010;2164&#x2010;11&#x2010;38</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarqu&#xed;n, D., Kocak, K., Posadas, L., Hyma, K., Jedlicka, J., Graef, G., &amp; Lorenz, A. (2014). Genotyping by sequencing for genomic prediction in a soybean breeding population. BMC Genomics, 15, 1&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471&#x2010;2164&#x2010;15&#x2010;740</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juvik, G. A., Bernard, R. L., Chang, R., &amp; Cavins, J. F. (1989). Evaluation of the USDA wild soybean germplasm collection: maturity groups 000 to IV (PI 65.549 to PI 483.464). https://doi.org/10.22004/ag.econ.337409</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakoulidou, I., Avramidou, E. V., Bar&#xe1;nek, M., Brunel&#x2010;Muguet, S., Farrona, S., Johannes, F., Kaiserli, E., Lieberman&#x2010;Lazarovich, M., Martinelli, F., Mladenov, V., Testillano, P. S., Vassileva, V., &amp; Maury, S. (2021). Epigenetics for crop improvement in times of global change. Biology, 10, 766. https://doi.org/10.3390/biology10080766</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur, H., Pannu, H. S., &amp; Malhi, A. K. (2019). A systematic review on imbalanced data challenges in machine learning: Applications and solutions. ACM Computing Surveys (CSUR), 52(4), 1&#x2013;36. https://doi.org/10.1145/3343440</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke, G., Meng, Q., Finley, T., Wang, T., Chen, W., Ma, W., Ye, Q., &amp; Liu, T.&#x2010;Y. (2017). Lightgbm: A highly efficient gradient boosting decision tree. In Proceedings of the 31st International Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS'17). Curran Associates Inc.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, K.&#x2010;S., Diers, B., Hyten, D., Rouf Mian, M., Shannon, J., &amp; Nelson, R. (2012). Identification of positive yield QTL alleles from exotic soybean germplasm in two backcross populations. Theoretical and Applied Genetics, 125, 1353&#x2013;1369. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00122&#x2010;012&#x2010;1944&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko, D. K., &amp; Brandizzi, F. (2020). Network&#x2010;based approaches for understanding gene regulation and function in plants. The Plant Journal, 104, 302&#x2013;317. https://doi.org/10.1111/tpj.14940</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, S., Stecher, G., Suleski, M., Sanderford, M., Sharma, S., &amp; Tamura, K. (2024). MEGA12: Molecular evolutionary genetic analysis version 12 for adaptive and green computing. Molecular Biology and Evolution, 41, msae263. https://doi.org/10.1093/molbev/msae263</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landress, A. D. (2016). A hybrid approach to reducing the false positive rate in unsupervised machine learning intrusion detection. In SoutheastCon 2016. (pp. 1&#x2013;6). IEEE. https://doi.org/10.1109/SECON.2016.7506647</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S., Cao, Y., Wang, C., Yan, C., Sun, X., Zhang, L., Wang, W., &amp; Song, S. (2023). Genome&#x2010;wide association mapping for yield&#x2010;related traits in soybean (Glycine max) under well&#x2010;watered and drought&#x2010;stressed conditions. Frontiers in Plant Science, 14, 1265574. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2023.1265574</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindemose, S., O'Shea, C., Jensen, M., &amp; Skriver, K. (2013). Structure, function and networks of transcription factors involved in abiotic stress responses. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 14, 5842&#x2013;5878. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms14035842</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linthicum, K. P., Schafer, K. M., &amp; Ribeiro, J. D. (2019). Machine learning in suicide science: Applications and ethics. Behavioral Sciences &amp; the Law, 37(3), 214&#x2013;222. https://doi.org/10.1002/bsl.2392</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, N., Li, M., Hu, X., Ma, Q., Mu, Y., Tan, Z., Xia, Q., Zhang, G., &amp; Nian, H. (2017). Construction of high&#x2010;density genetic map and QTL mapping of yield&#x2010;related and two quality traits in soybean RILs population by RAD&#x2010;sequencing. BMC Genomics, 18, 1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12864&#x2010;017&#x2010;3854&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X., Huang, M., Fan, B., Buckler, E. S., &amp; Zhang, Z. (2016). Iterative usage of fixed and random effect models for powerful and efficient genome&#x2010;wide association studies. PLoS Genetics, 12, e1005767. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pgen.1005767</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long, Y., Zhang, C., &amp; Meng, J. (2008). Challenges for QTL analysis in crops. Journal of Crop Science and Biotechnology, 11, 7&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12892&#x2010;008&#x2010;0008&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg, S. M., Erion, G., Chen, H., DeGrave, A., Prutkin, J. M., Nair, B., Katz, R., Himmelfarb, J., Bansal, N., &amp; Lee, S.&#x2010;I. (2020). From local explanations to global understanding with explainable AI for trees. Nature Machine Intelligence, 2, 56&#x2013;67. https://doi.org/10.1038/s42256&#x2010;019&#x2010;0138&#x2010;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg, S. M., Erion, G. G., &amp; Lee, S.&#x2010;I. (2018). Consistent individualized feature attribution for tree ensembles. arXiv. https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.1802.03888</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manna, M., Thakur, T., Chirom, O., Mandlik, R., Deshmukh, R., &amp; Salvi, P. (2021). Transcription factors as key molecular target to strengthen the drought stress tolerance in plants. Physiologia Plantarum, 172, 847&#x2013;868. https://doi.org/10.1111/ppl.13268</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mather, K. (1941). Variation and selection of polygenic characters. Journal of Genetics, 41, 159&#x2013;193. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF02983019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mickelbart, M. V., Hasegawa, P. M., &amp; Bailey&#x2010;Serres, J. (2015). Genetic mechanisms of abiotic stress tolerance that translate to crop yield stability. Nature Reviews Genetics, 16, 237&#x2013;251. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrg3901</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moraes, D., Wainer, J., &amp; Rocha, A. (2016). Low false positive learning with support vector machines. Journal of Visual Communication and Image Representation, 38, 340&#x2013;350. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jvcir.2016.03.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muqaddasi, Q. H., Reif, J. C., Li, Z., Basnet, B. R., Dreisigacker, S., &amp; R&#xf6;der, M. S. (2017). Genome&#x2010;wide association mapping and genome&#x2010;wide prediction of another extrusion in CIMMYT spring wheat. Euphytica, 213, 73. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10681&#x2010;017&#x2010;1863&#x2010;y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson, R. L., Amdor, P. J., &amp; Orf, J. H. (1987). Evaluation of the USDA soybean germplasm collection: Maturity groups 000 to IV (PI 273.483 to PI 427.107) (Technical Bulletins 157020). United States Department of Agriculture.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng, D. W., Abeysinghe, J. K., &amp; Kamali, M. (2018). Regulating the regulators: The control of transcription factors in plant defense signaling. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 19, 3737. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms19123737</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novakazi, F., Afanasenko, O., Anisimova, A., Platz, G. J., Snowdon, R., Kovaleva, O., Zubkovich, A., &amp; Ordon, F. (2019). Genetic analysis of a worldwide barley collection for resistance to net form of net blotch disease (Pyrenophora teres f. teres). Theoretical and Applied Genetics, 132, 2633&#x2013;2650. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00122&#x2010;019&#x2010;03378&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parganiha, V., &amp; Verma, M. (2024). An effective soil analysis and crop yield prediction based on optimised light GBM in smart agriculture. Journal of Agronomy and Crop Science, 210, e12726. https://doi.org/10.1111/jac.12726</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson, A. H., Lander, E. S., Hewitt, J. D., Peterson, S., Lincoln, S. E., &amp; Tanksley, S. D. (1988). Resolution of quantitative traits into Mendelian factors by using a complete linkage map of restriction fragment length polymorphisms. Nature, 335, 721&#x2013;726. https://doi.org/10.1038/335721a0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peregrine, E., Sprau, G., Cremeens, C., Handly, P., Kilen, T., Smith, J., Thomas, D., Sarins, J. D., &amp; Nelson, R. (2008). Evaluation of the USDA Soybean Germplasm Collection: Maturity Group V (FC 30265&#x2010;PI 612614) and Maturity Groups VI&#x2010;VIII (PI 416758&#x2010;PI 606432B). US Department of Agriculture Technical Bulletin, 1920, 1&#x2013;369. https://www.ars.usda.gov/is/np/SoybeanGermplasm/SoyGerm2008-Group5.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preeti, K. S., &amp; Dhankar, A. (2017). A review on machine learning techniques. International Journal of Advanced Research in Computer Science, 8(3), 778&#x2013;882. https://doi.org/10.26483/ijarcs.v8i3.3096</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price, A. L., Zaitlen, N. A., Reich, D., &amp; Patterson, N. (2010). New approaches to population stratification in genome&#x2010;wide association studies. Nature Reviews Genetics, 11, 459&#x2013;463. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrg2813</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pujar, M., Gangaprasad, S., Govindaraj, M., Gangurde, S. S., Kanatti, A., &amp; Kudapa, H. (2020). Genome&#x2010;wide association study uncovers genomic regions associated with grain iron, zinc and protein content in pearl millet. Scientific Reports, 10, 19473. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;020&#x2010;76230&#x2010;y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resende, R. T., De Resende, M. D. V., Azevedo, C. F., Fonseca E Silva, F., Melo, L. C., Pereira, H. S., Souza, T. L. P. O., Valdisser, P. A. M. R., Brondani, C., &amp; Vianello, R. P. (2018). Genome&#x2010;wide association and regional heritability mapping of plant architecture, lodging and productivity in phaseolus vulgaris. G3 Genes|Genomes|Genetics, 8, 2841&#x2013;2854. https://doi.org/10.1534/g3.118.200493</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saitou, N., &amp; Nei, M. (1987). The neighbor&#x2010;joining method: A new method for reconstructing phylogenetic trees. Molecular Biology and Evolution, 4, 406&#x2013;425. https://doi.org/10.1093/oxfordjournals.molbev.a040454</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sebastian&#x2010;delaCruz, M., Gonzalez&#x2010;Moro, I., Olazagoitia&#x2010;Garmendia, A., Castellanos&#x2010;Rubio, A., &amp; Santin, I. (2021). The role of lncRNAs in gene expression regulation through mRNA stabilization. Non&#x2010;Coding RNA, 7, 3. https://doi.org/10.3390/ncrna7010003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah, I. M., Dar, M. A., Bhat, K. A., Dar, T. A., Ahmad, F., &amp; Ahmad, S. M. (2022). Long non&#x2010;coding RNAs: Biogenesis, mechanism of action and role in different biological and pathological processes. In Recent Advances in Noncoding RNAs. IntechOpen. https://doi.org/10.5772/intechopen.104861</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shook, J. M., Zhang, J., Jones, S. E., Singh, A., Diers, B. W., &amp; Singh, A. K. (2021). Meta&#x2010;GWAS for quantitative trait loci identification in soybean. G3 Genes|Genomes|Genetics, 11, jkab117. https://doi.org/10.1093/g3journal/jkab117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Q., Hyten, D. L., Jia, G., Quigley, C. V., Fickus, E. W., Nelson, R. L., &amp; Cregan, P. B. (2015). Fingerprinting soybean germplasm and its utility in genomic research. G3 Genes|Genomes|Genetics, 5, 1999&#x2013;2006. https://doi.org/10.1534/g3.115.019000</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souche, E. L., Hellemans, B., Van Houdt, J. K. J., Canario, A., Klages, S., Reinhardt, R., &amp; Volckaert, F. A. M. (2007). Mining for single nucleotide polymorphisms in expressed sequence tags of European sea bass. Journal of Integrative Bioinformatics, 4(3), 158&#x2013;167. https://doi.org/10.1515/jib&#x2010;2007&#x2010;73</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Specht, J., Hume, D., &amp; Kumudini, S. (1999). Soybean yield potential&#x2014;A genetic and physiological perspective. Crop Science, 39, 1560&#x2013;1570. https://doi.org/10.2135/cropsci1999.3961560x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Specht, J. E., Diers, B. W., Nelson, R. L., de Toledo, J. F. F., Torrion, J. A., &amp; Grassini, P. (2014). Soybean. Yield Gains in Major US Field Crops, 33, 311&#x2013;355. https://doi.org/10.2135/cssaspecpub33.c12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdisser, P. A. M. R., Pereira, W. J., Almeida Filho, J. E., M&#xfc;ller, B. S. F., Coelho, G. R. C., De Menezes, I. P. P., Vianna, J. P. G., Zucchi, M. I., Lanna, A. C., Coelho, A. S. G., De Oliveira, J. P., Moraes, A. D. C., Brondani, C., &amp; Vianello, R. P. (2017). In&#x2010;depth genome characterization of a Brazilian common bean core collection using DArTseq high&#x2010;density SNP genotyping. BMC Genomics, 18, 423. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12864&#x2010;017&#x2010;3805&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Vuuren, C., van Mens, K., de Beurs, D., Lokkerbol, J., van der Wal, M., Cuijpers, P., &amp; Chinapaw, M. (2021). Comparing machine learning to a rule&#x2010;based approach for predicting suicidal behavior among adolescents: Results from a longitudinal population&#x2010;based survey. Journal of Affective Disorders, 295, 1415&#x2013;1420. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jad.2021.09.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z., Zhu, Y., Liu, Z., Li, H., Tang, X., &amp; Jiang, Y. (2023). Comparative analysis of tissue&#x2010;specific genes in maize based on machine learning models: CNN performs technically best, LightGBM performs biologically soundest. Frontiers in Genetics, 14, 1190887. https://doi.org/10.3389/fgene.2023.1190887</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, C., Mozzoni, L. A., Moseley, D., Hummer, W., Ye, H., Chen, P., Shannon, G., &amp; Nguyen, H. (2020). Genome&#x2010;wide association mapping of flooding tolerance in soybean. Molecular Breeding, 40, 1&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11032&#x2010;019&#x2010;1086&#x2010;0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, X., Ren, C., Joshi, T., Vuong, T., Xu, D., &amp; Nguyen, H. T. (2010). SNP discovery by high&#x2010;throughput sequencing in soybean. BMC Genomics, 11, 1&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471&#x2010;2164&#x2010;11&#x2010;469</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xavier, A., Muir, W. M., &amp; Rainey, K. M. (2016). Assessing predictive properties of genome&#x2010;wide selection in soybeans. G3 Genes|Genomes|Genetics, 6, 2611&#x2013;2616. https://doi.org/10.1534/g3.116.032268</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y., Zhang, X., Li, H., Zheng, H., Zhang, J., Olsen, M. S., Varshney, R. K., Prasanna, B. M., &amp; Qian, Q. (2022). Smart breeding driven by big data, artificial intelligence, and integrated genomic&#x2010;enviromic prediction. Molecular Plant, 15, 1664&#x2013;1695. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molp.2022.09.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying, X. (2019). An overview of overfitting and its solutions. Journal of Physics: Conference Series, 1168, 022022. https://doi.org/10.1088/1742&#x2010;6596/1168/2/022022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, J., Pressoir, G., Briggs, W. H., Vroh Bi, I., Yamasaki, M., Doebley, J. F., Mcmullen, M. D., Gaut, B. S., Nielsen, D. M., Holland, J. B., Kresovich, S., &amp; Buckler, E. S. (2006). A unified mixed&#x2010;model method for association mapping that accounts for multiple levels of relatedness. Nature Genetics, 38, 203&#x2013;208. https://doi.org/10.1038/ng1702</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, J., Xiong, H., Zhu, X., Zhang, H., Li, H., Miao, J., Wang, W., Tang, Z., Zhang, Z., Yao, G., Zhang, Q., Pan, Y., Wang, X., Rashid, M. A. R., Li, J., Gao, Y., Li, Z., Yang, W., Fu, X., &amp; Li, Z. (2017). OsLG3 contributing to rice grain length and yield was mined by Ho&#x2010;LAMap. BMC Biology, 15, Article 28. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12915&#x2010;017&#x2010;0365&#x2010;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, A., Chen, P., Korth, K., Hancock, F., Pereira, A., Brye, K., Wu, C., &amp; Shi, A. (2017). Genome&#x2010;wide association study (GWAS) of salt tolerance in worldwide soybean germplasm lines. Molecular Breeding, 37, Article 30. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11032&#x2010;017&#x2010;0634&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J., Song, Q., Cregan, P. B., &amp; Jiang, G.&#x2010;L. (2016). Genome&#x2010;wide association study, genomic prediction and marker&#x2010;assisted selection for seed weight in soybean (Glycine max). Theoretical and Applied Genetics, 129, 117&#x2013;130. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00122&#x2010;015&#x2010;2614&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M., Liu, S., Wang, Z., Yuan, Y., Zhang, Z., Liang, Q., Yang, X., Duan, Z., Liu, Y., Kong, F., Liu, B., Ren, B. O., &amp; Tian, Z. (2022). Progress in soybean functional genomics over the past decade. Plant Biotechnology Journal, 20, 256&#x2013;282. https://doi.org/10.1111/pbi.13682</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, T., Wu, T., Wang, L., Jiang, B., Zhen, C., Yuan, S., Hou, W., Wu, C., Han, T., &amp; Sun, S. (2019). A combined linkage and GWAS analysis identifies QTLs linked to soybean seed protein and oil content. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 20, 5915. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms20235915</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, W., Yan, Z., &amp; Zhang, L. (2024). A comparative study of 11 non&#x2010;linear regression models highlighting autoencoder, DBN, and SVR, enhanced by SHAP importance analysis in soybean branching prediction. Scientific Reports, 14, 5905. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;024&#x2010;55243&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, X., Xiang, X., Zhang, M., Cao, D., Du, C., Zhang, L., &amp; Hu, J. (2023). Combining GS&#x2010;assisted GWAS and transcriptome analysis to mine candidate genes for nitrogen utilization efficiency in Populus cathayana. BMC Plant Biology, 23(1), Article 182. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12870&#x2010;023&#x2010;04202&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmer, G., Miller, M. J., Steketee, C. J., Jackson, S. A., de Tunes, L. V. M., &amp; Li, Z. (2021). Genetic control and allele variation among soybean maturity groups 000 through IX. The Plant Genome, 14, e20146. https://doi.org/10.1002/tpg2.20146</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuckerkandl, E., &amp; Pauling, L. (1965). Evolutionary divergence and convergence in proteins. In Evolving genes and proteins (pp. 97&#x2013;166). Elsevier. https://doi.org/10.1016/B978&#x2010;1&#x2010;4832&#x2010;2734&#x2010;4.50017&#x2010;6</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>