<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41316790</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0250-3301</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>46</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Huan jing ke xue= Huanjing kexue</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Huan Jing Ke Xue</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[Analysis of Evolution and Influencing Factors of Ecological Security Patterns in Nanchang City Under the Trade-off between Ecosystem Service Supply and Demand].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7316</StartPage><EndPage>7328</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7316-7328</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.13227/j.hjkx.202410013</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Balancing the supply and demand of ecosystem services is an important way to achieve regional sustainable development. Moreover, constructing an ecological security pattern based on this is highly significant for maintaining regional ecological security and promoting human well-being. The ecological security pattern of Nanchang City from 2000 to 2020 was established by integrating ecosystem service supply-demand trade-offs, ecological sensitivity, landscape connectivity, and circuit theory. Its dynamic evolution characteristics were analyzed, and the influencing factors of the ecological security pattern were explored using Geodetector and geographically weighted regression models. The results showed that: &#x2460; The supply-demand trade-off situation of ecosystem services in Nanchang City was spatially heterogeneous. Surplus areas were mainly concentrated in the woodlands and waters in the east and west, while deficit areas existed in the expanding central urban area. &#x2461; The ecological sources were concentrated in the east and west, with relatively consistent spatial patterns, but their areas have decreased slightly. &#x2462; Based on the clustering characteristics of ecological sources, the research region was divided into four major ecological zones: the Poyang Lake Ecological Zone, the Jiaoling-Meiling Mount Ecological Zone, the Jungshan Lake Ecological Zone, and the Gan River Ecological Zone. &#x2463; Between 2000 and 2020, the average length of ecological corridors increased. In the eastern and western parts, there were mainly short corridors, which served as the internal links of the ecological regions. In the central part, the corridors were relatively long, with most of them serving as important corridors connecting the four major ecological regions. Ecological pinch points were mainly distributed in the central and eastern parts, located in the middle of the corridors in a strip-shaped formation. Ecological barrier points were concentrated in the eastern region and showed a decreasing trend. &#x2464; Elevation, NDVI, population density, GDP, and the distance from construction land were the main factors affecting the ecological security pattern in Nanchang City. The study can provide references for Nanchang City to maintain ecological security and protect and restore territorial space.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yi-An</ForeName><Initials>YA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Earth Science, East China University of Technology, Nanchang 330013, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Bao-Qun</ForeName><Initials>BQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Earth Science, East China University of Technology, Nanchang 330013, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Jiang-Long</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Surveying and Geoinformation Engineering, East China University of Technology, Nanchang 330013, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Earth Science, East China University of Technology, Nanchang 330013, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>chi</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China</Country><MedlineTA>Huan Jing Ke Xue</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8405344</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0250-3301</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nanchang City</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ecological security pattern</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">influencing factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spatial and temporal evolution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">trade-offs between ecosystem service supply and demand</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41316790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13227/j.hjkx.202410013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>