<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41616711</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-9800</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>230</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied radiation and isotopes : including data, instrumentation and methods for use in agriculture, industry and medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Radiat Isot</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Application of Self2Self self-supervised denoising framework to airborne gamma-ray spectrometry data.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>112468</StartPage><MedlinePgn>112468</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.apradiso.2026.112468</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0969-8043(26)00052-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Airborne gamma-ray spectrometry(AGRS)data are susceptible to degradation due to factors such as flight altitude variations, constraints on detector volume, and intricate background interferences, which collectively hinder the acquisition of high-quality reference samples in field environments and curtail the performance of conventional denoising techniques. This study investigates the potential feasibility of the Self2Self self-supervised denoising algorithm in this domain. The approach requires only a single noisy image, employing random Bernoulli masks to produce incomplete image variants, thereby forcing an enhanced U-Net architecture to reconstruct the values of masked pixels. Furthermore, it integrates dropout mechanisms for multiple sampling alongside ensemble prediction strategies to alleviate variance and generate high-fidelity denoised outputs. Experiments were conducted utilizing data from the LSS experimental zone in Gansu Province, with evaluations performed via peak signal-to-noise ratio (PSNR), structural similarity index measure (SSIM), and feature peak signal-to-noise ratio (FPSNR) metrics. The outcomes reveal that post-denoising, the PSNR values for thorium (Th), potassium (K), and uranium (U) attained 32.03&#x202f;dB, 30.53&#x202f;dB, and 28.66&#x202f;dB, respectively, accompanied by SSIM values of 0.99, 0.97, and 0.91. Additionally, the FPSNR for the characteristic peaks of each radionuclide exhibited enhancements ranging from 2.43 to 2.60&#x202f;dB, with the uranium series representing a relative improvement of 29.6&#x202f;%. This methodology proficiently preserves spectral peak morphologies and gradient transitions while effectively attenuating stripe artifacts, thereby augmenting overall image quality. The research furnishes novel perspectives for leveraging AGRS in mineral prospecting and environmental surveillance, substantiating the robustness of the Self2Self framework in processing datasets characterized by low count rates and stochastic noise perturbations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Fan</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Key Laboratory of Uranium Resources Exploration-Mining and Nuclear Remote Sensing, East China University of Technology, Nanchang, China; School of Nuclear Science and Engineering, East China University of Technology, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Key Laboratory of Uranium Resources Exploration-Mining and Nuclear Remote Sensing, East China University of Technology, Nanchang, China; School of Nuclear Science and Engineering, East China University of Technology, Nanchang, China. Electronic address: xiongchaollg@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Jiahao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nuclear Science and Engineering, East China University of Technology, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nuclear Science and Engineering, East China University of Technology, Nanchang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xinjie</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Radiation Medicine and Protection (SRMP) of Soochow University, Suzhou, 215123, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Hexi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Key Laboratory of Uranium Resources Exploration-Mining and Nuclear Remote Sensing, East China University of Technology, Nanchang, China; School of Nuclear Science and Engineering, East China University of Technology, Nanchang, China. Electronic address: wujing-7758@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Radiat Isot</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9306253</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0969-8043</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Airborne gamma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Denoising</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-supervised learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self2Self</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">U-net</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41616711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apradiso.2026.112468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0969-8043(26)00052-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>