<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41431142</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-2197</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>113</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of botany</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Bot</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Climate niches structure a regional hybrid zone in Sphagnum (peatmoss, Bryophyta).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70143</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70143</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ajb2.70143</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PREMISE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Hybridization is an important evolutionary process across all groups of embryophyte land plants, but relatively little is known about hybridization and introgression in plants with a dominant gametophyte life cycle stage. This paper focuses on hybridization between four closely related species of the moss genus Sphagnum.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Analyses utilized three types of molecular data: restriction-site-associated DNA sequencing (RADseq), RADseq-like data derived from in silico digestion of genome sequences, and species-specific barcode markers developed previously for this group. Sampling included 582 gametophytes from 79 collecting sites from 27&#xb0; to 56&#xb0;N. A range of analytical methods were employed: phylogeny reconstruction, genetic analyses using the program structure, demographic modeling, and comparative genomics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Gene flow was detected among all pairwise combinations of extant species and between ancestral lineages and those species. Hybridization between S. diabolicum and S. magniae was especially pronounced and plants in a regional zone from North Carolina to New Jersey were genetically admixed. Demographic analyses indicated that this admixture reflects hybridization. Introgressed SNPs were detected across all chromosomes, but introgressed SNPs fixed in genetically pure samples of the two species were concentrated on four autosomes: 2, 7, 14, and 19. Patterns of genomic admixture/introgression were significantly correlated with climate variation across collection sites within the hybrid zone.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The genomic structure of plants in a regional hybrid zone between S. magniae and S. diabolicum was structured by climate adaptation and strengthens the value of this group for learning more about speciation and climate adaptation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Botanical Society of America.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>A Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7344-9955</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and L. E. Anderson Bryophyte Herbarium, Duke University, Durham, 27708, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duffy</LastName><ForeName>Aaron M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0530-6191</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and L. E. Anderson Bryophyte Herbarium, Duke University, Durham, 27708, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aguero</LastName><ForeName>Blanka</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8442-5409</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and L. E. Anderson Bryophyte Herbarium, Duke University, Durham, 27708, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nieto-Lugilde</LastName><ForeName>Marta</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1593-3853</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and L. E. Anderson Bryophyte Herbarium, Duke University, Durham, 27708, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imwattana</LastName><ForeName>Karn</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7347-1741</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Botany, Faculty of Science, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, 10330, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robinson</LastName><ForeName>Sean C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0961-4968</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, SUNY Oneonta, Oneonta, 13820, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schuette</LastName><ForeName>Scott</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7185-6178</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pennsylvania Natural Heritage Program, Western Pennsylvania Conservancy, Pittsburgh, 15222, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilkens</LastName><ForeName>Richard T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2855-7295</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, Salisbury University, Salisbury, 21801, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yavitt</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8292-7824</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Natural Resources, Cornell University, Ithaca, 14853, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weston</LastName><ForeName>David J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4794-9913</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biosciences Division, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, 37830, TN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piatkowski</LastName><ForeName>Bryan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biosciences Division, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, 37831, TN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Granath</LastName><ForeName>Gustaf</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3632-9102</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ecology and Genetics, Evolutionary Biology Centre, Uppsala University, Norbyv&#xe4;gen 18D, SE-752 36, Uppsala, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Bot</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370467</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0002-9122</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006824" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hybridization, Genetic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044003" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sphagnopsida</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010802" MajorTopicYN="N">Phylogeny</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002980" MajorTopicYN="Y">Climate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051456" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Flow</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018745" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome, Plant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020641" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017422" MajorTopicYN="N">Sequence Analysis, DNA</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RADseq</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">climate adaptation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">climate niche</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hybridization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">introgression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peatmoss</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41431142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajb2.70143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Abbott, R. J., N. H. Barton, and J. M. Good. 2016. Genomics of hybridization and its evolutionary consequences. Molecular Ecology 25: 2325&#x2013;2332</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews, A. L. 1912. Notes on North American Sphagnum III. Bryologist 15: 70&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bridel, S. E. 1798. Muscologia recentiorum seu analysis, historia, et descriptio methodica omnium muscorum frondosorum, huscus&#x2010;cognitorum, ad norman Hedwigii, vol. 2, 1&#x2013;224. C. G. Ettingerum, Gotha, Germany; Barrois iuniorem, Paris, France.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell, D. R., A. Faidiga, and G. Trujillo. 2018. Clines in traits compared over two decades in a plant hybrid zone. Annals of Botany 122: 315&#x2013;324</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrell, A. A., T. J. Lawrence, K. G. M. Cabugao, D. L. Carper, D. A. Pelletier, J. H. Lee, S. S. Jawdy, et al. 2022a. Habitat&#x2010;adapted microbial communities mediate Sphagnum peatmoss resilience to warming. New Phytologist 234: 2111&#x2013;2125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrell, A. A., D. Veli&#x10d;kovi&#x107;, T. J. Lawrence, B. P. Bowen, K. B. Louie, D. L. Carper, R. K. Chu, et al. 2022b. Novel metabolic interactions and environmental conditions mediate the boreal peatmoss&#x2013;cyanobacteria mutualism. ISME Journal 16: 1074&#x2013;1085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffy, A., B. Aguero, H. Sten&#xf8;ien, K. l. Flatberg, M. S. Ignatov, K. Hassel, and A. J. Shaw. 2020. Phylogenetic structure in the Sphagnum recurvum complex (Bryophyta: Sphagnaceae) relative to taxonomy and geography. American Journal of Botany 107: 1283&#x2013;1295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eaton, D. A. R., and I. Overcast. 2020. ipyrad: Interactive assembly and analysis of RADseq datasets. Bioinformatics 36: 2592&#x2013;2594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flatberg, K.I., K. Thingsgaard, and S. M. S&#xe5;stad. 2006. Interploidal gene flow and introgression in bryophytes: Sphagnum girgensohnii, Sphagnum russowii, a case of spontaneous neotriploidy. Journal of Bryology 28: 27&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gay, L., P&#x2010;A. Crochet, D. A. Bell, and T. Lenormand. 2008. Comparing clines on molecular and phenotypic traits in hybrid zones: a window on tension zone models. Evolution 62&#x2010;11: 2789&#x2013;2806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goudet J. 2005. hierfstat, a package for R to compute and test variance components and F&#x2010;statistics. Molecular Ecology Notes 5: 184&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutenkunst, R. N., R. D. Hernandez, S. H. Williamson, and C. D. Bustamante. 2009. Inferring the joint demographic history of multiple populations from multidimensional SNP data. PLoS Genetics 5: e1000695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison, R. C., and E. L. Larson. 2016. Heterogeneous genome divergence, differential introgression, and the origin and structure of hybrid zones. Molecular Ecology 25: 2454&#x2013;2466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassel, K., M. O. Kyrkjeeide, N. Yousefi, T. Prest&#xf8;, H. K. Sten&#xf8;ien, A. J. Shaw, and K. I. Flatberg. 2018. Sphagnum divinum (sp. nov.) and S. medium Limpr. and their relationship to S. magellanicum Brid. Journal of Bryology 3: 197&#x2013;222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healey, A. L., B. Piatkowski, J. T. Lovell, A. Sreedasyam, S. B. Carey, S. Mamidi, S. Shu, et al. 2023. Newly identified sex chromosomes in the Sphagnum (peat moss) genome alter carbon sequestration and ecosystem dynamics. Nature Plants 9: 238&#x2013;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hijmans, R. 2022. Geosphere: spherical trigonometry. R package version 1.5&#x2010;18. Website https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=geosphere [accessed 10 November 2024].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill, M. O. 2020. Sphagnum divinum and Sphagnum medium in Britain and Ireland. Field Bryology 123: 10&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoang, D. T., O. Chernomor, A. von Haeseler, B. Q. Minh, and L. S. Vinh. 2018. UFBoot2: Improving the ultrafast bootstrap approximation. Molecular Biology and Evolution 35: 518&#x2013;522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imwattana, K. 2023. Introgression, population structure, and systematics of the Sphagnum capillifolium complex. Ph.D. dissertation, Duke University, Durham, NC, USA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, M. J., G. Granath, T. Teemu, R. Pouliot, H. K. Sten&#xf8;ien, L. Rochefort, H. Rydin, A. J. Shaw. 2014. Evolution of niche preference in Sphagnum peat mosses. Evolution 69: 90&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jombart, T., and I. Ahmed. 2011. adegenet 1.3&#x2010;1: New tools for the analysis of genome&#x2010;wide SNP data. Bioinformatics 27: 3070&#x2013;3071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalyaanamoorthy, S, B. Q. Minh, T. K. F. Wong, A. von Haeseler, and L. S. Jermiin. 2017. ModelFinder: Fast model selection for accurate phylogenetic estimates. Nature Methods 14: 587&#x2013;589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamvar, Z. N., J. F. Tabima, and N. J. Gr&#xfc;nwald. 2014. Poppr: an R package for genetic analysis of populations with clonal, partially clonal, and/or sexual reproduction. PeerJ 2: e281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karger, D. N., O. Conrad, J. B&#xf6;hner, T. Kawohl, H. Kreft, R. W. Soria&#x2010;Auza, N. E. Zimmermann, H. P. Linder, and M. Kessler. 2017. Climatologies at high resolution for the earth's land surface areas. Scientific Data 4: 170122. https://doi.org/10.1038/sdata.2017.122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilner, C. L., A. A. Carrell, D. J. Wieczynski, S. Votzke, K. DeWitt, A. Yammine, A. J. Shaw, et al. 2024. Temperature and CO2 interactively drive shifts in the compositional and functional structure of peatland protist communities. Global Change Biology 30: e17203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyrkjeeide, M. O., K. Hassel, K. I. Flatberg, A. J. Shaw, N. Yousefi, and H. K. Sten&#xf8;ien. 2016. Spatial genetic structure of the abundant and widespread peatmoss Sphagnum magellanicum Brid. PLoS One 11: e0148447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant, V. 1981. Plant speciation. Columbia University Press, NY, NY, USA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leroy, T., J.&#x2010;M. Louvet, C. Lalanne, G. Le Provost, K. Labadie, J.M. Aury, S. Delzon, et al. 2020. Adaptive introgression as a driver of local adaptation to climate in European white oaks. New Phytologist: 226: 1171&#x2013;1182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis, P. O. 2001. A likelihood approach to estimating phylogeny from discrete morphological character data. Systematic Biology 50: 913&#x2013;925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malmer, N. 1962. Studies on mire vegetation in the Archaean area of southwestern Gotaland (south Sweden). I. Vegetation and habitat conditions on the Akhult mire. Opera Botanica 7: 1&#x2013;322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minh, B. Q., H. A. Schmidt, O. Chernomor, D. Schrempf, W. D. Woodhams, A. von Haeseler, and R. Lanfear. 2020. IQ&#x2010;TREE 2: New models and efficient methods for phylogenetic inference in the genomic era. Molecular Biology and Evolution 37: 1530&#x2013;1534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natcheva, R., and N. Cronberg. 2004. What do we know about hybridization among bryophytes in nature? Canadian Journal of Botany 82: 1687&#x2013;1704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overcast, I. 2024. easySFS. Website https://github.com/isaacovercast/easySFS</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parchman, T. L., Z. Gompert, J. Mudge, F. D. Schilkey, C. W. Benkman, and C. A. Buerkle. 2012. Genome&#x2010;wide association genetics of an adaptive trait in lodgepole pine. Molecular Ecology 21: 2991&#x2013;3005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;aloza&#x2010;Bojac&#xe1;, G., J. G. Burleigh, A. Maciel&#x2010;Silva, D. C. Cargill, D. Bell, E. B. Sessa, S. F. McDaniel, et al. 2025. Ancient reticulation, incomplete lineage sorting and the evolution of the pyrenoid at the dawn of hornwort diversification. Annals of Botany 135: 1199&#x2013;1214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piatkowski, B., D. J. Weston, B. Aguero, A. Duffy, K. Imwattana, A. L. Healey, J. Schmutz, and A. J. Shaw. 2023. Divergent selection fuels genomic differentiation between incipient species of Sphagnum (peat moss). Annals of Botany 132: 499&#x2013;512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pritchard, J. K., M. Stephens, and P. Donnelly. 2000. Inference of population structure using multilocus genotype data. Genetics 155: 945&#x2013;959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. 2021. R: a language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna, Austria. Website https://www.R-project.org/ [accessed 22 November 2024].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricca, M., P. Sz&#xf6;v&#xe9;nyi, and A. J. Shaw. 2011. Interploidal hybridization and mating patterns in the Sphagnum subsecundum complex. Molecular Ecology 20: 3202&#x2013;3218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawangproh, W., and N. Cronberg. 2021. Evidence for interspecific hybridization in bryophytes during premolecular and molecular eras. Bryophyte Diversity and Evolution 43: 180&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawangproh, W., L. Heden&#xe4;s, A. S. Lang, B. Hansson, and N. Cronberg. 2020. Gene transfer across species boundaries in bryophytes: evidence from major lifecycle stages in Homalothecium lutescens and H. sericeum. Annals of Botany 125: 565&#x2013;579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartzer, C., and J. Joshi. 2017. Parallel adaptive responses to abiotic but not biotic conditions after cryptic speciation in European peat moss Sphagnum magellanicum Brid. Perspectives in Plant Ecology, Evolution and Systematics 26: 14&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw, A. J., B. E. Carter, B. Aquero, D. P. da Costa, and A. Crowl. 2018. Range change evolution of peat mosses (Sphagnum) within and between climate zones. Global Change Biology 25: 108&#x2010;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw, A. J., A. Duffy, M. Nieto&#x2010;Lugilde, B. Aguero, S. Schuette, S. Robinson, J. Loveland, et al. 2023a. Clonality, local population structure and gametophyte sex ratios in cryptic species of the Sphagnum magellanicum complex. Annals of Botany 132: 77&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw, A. J., M. Nieto&#x2010;Lugilde, B. Aguero, A. M. Duffy, B. T. Piatkowski, J. Jaramillo&#x2010;Chico, S. Robinson, et al. 2023b. Sphagnum diabolicum sp. nov. and S. magniae sp. nov.; morphological variation and taxonomy of the &#x201c;S. magellanicum complex&#x201d;. Bryologist 126: 69&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw, A. J., M. Nieto&#x2010;Lugilde, B. Aguero, A. M. Duffy, S. Robinson, K. Hassel, K. I. Flatberg, et al. 2025. Genetic structure of the Sphagnum magellanicum (Sphagnaceae) complex in Europe. Bryologist 128: 474&#x2013;486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw, A. J., B. T. Piatkowski, A. M. Duffy, B. Aguero, K. Imwattana, M. Nieto&#x2010;Lugilde, A. Healey, et al. 2022. Phylogenomic structure and speciation in an emerging model: the Sphagnum magellanicum complex (Bryophyta). New Phytologist 236: 1497&#x2013;1511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stebbins Jr., G. L. 1950. Variation and evolution in plants. Columbia University Press, NY, NY, USA</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sz&#xf6;v&#xe9;nyi, P., S. Rensing, D. Lang, G. A. Wray, and A. J. Shaw. 2011. Generation&#x2010;biased gene expression in a bryophyte model system. Molecular Biology and Evolution 28: 803&#x2013;812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turetsky, M., D. J. Weston, W. D. Cox, C. Petro, and A. J Shaw. 2025. Sphagnum moss as a challenging but unique eco&#x2010;evolutionary study system. New Phytologist 247: 1608&#x2010;1621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitt, D., and N. G. Slack. 1984. Niche diversification of Sphagnum relative to environmental factors in northern Minnesota peatlands. Canadian Journal of Botany 62: 1409&#x2013;1430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegmann, D., D. Kessner, K. R. Veeramah, R. A. Mathias, D. L. Nicolae, L. R. Yanek, Y. V. Sun, et al. 2011. Recombination rates in admixed individuals identified by ancestry&#x2010;based inference. Nature Genetics 43: 847&#x2013;853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weston, D. J., M. R. Turetsky, M. G. Johnson, G. Granath, Z. Lindo, L. R. Belyea, S. K. Rice, et al. 2018. The Sphagnome Project: enabling ecological and evolutionary insights through a genus&#x2010;level sequencing project. New Phytologist 217: 16&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitney, K.D., K. W. Broman, N. C. Kane, S. M. Hovick, R. A. Randell, and L. H. Rieseberg. 2015. Quantitative trait locus mapping identifies candidate alleles involved in adaptive introgression and range expansion in a wild sunflower. Molecular Ecology 24: 2194&#x2013;2211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, J., P. J. Morris, J. Liu, and J. Holden. 2018. PEATMAP: Refining estimates of global peatland distribution based on a meta&#x2010;analysis. Catena 160: 134&#x2013;140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousefi, N., K. Hassel, K. I. Flatberg, P. Kemppainen, E. Trucchi, A. J. Shaw, M. O. Kyrkjeeide, et al. 2017. Divergent evolution and niche differentiation within the common peatmoss Sphagnum magellanicum. American Journal of Botany 104: 1060&#x2013;1072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, Z. C. 2012. Northern peatland carbon stocks and dynamics: a review. Biogeosciences 9: 4071&#x2013;4085.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>