<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41662700</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1526-7598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Anesthesia and analgesia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Anesth Analg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Addressing Healthcare Provider Well-being in a Conflict Zone: A Mixed-Method Study of Vital Anesthesia Simulation Training Wellbeing.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1213/ANE.0000000000007983</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Burnout among healthcare providers can adversely impact their performance and patient care. Vital Anaesthesia Simulation Training (VAST) Wellbeing is a 1-day course designed to promote personal and professional well-being and to reduce burnout for healthcare providers in low-resource settings. VAST Wellbeing has demonstrated benefits in this context but has never been evaluated in a conflict zone. This study assessed the influence of VAST Wellbeing among healthcare workers practicing in the EMERGENCY-NGO Salam Centre for Cardiac Surgery in Sudan amidst a conflict.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This mixed-methods study was designed to explore participants' experience of VAST Wellbeing offered in Sudan to learn about benefits and challenges to this training in a conflict zone. Our team used in-depth qualitative interviews with purposively selected course participants. Perceived social stigma of receiving mental health support and attitudes toward help seeking for mental health were also quantitatively assessed using the Stigma Scale for Receiving Psychological Help and the General Help-Seeking Questionnaire, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Sixty healthcare providers attended the course; 35 completed quantitative measures, and 12 were interviewed. Stigma for receiving mental health support decreased comparing median [interquartile range {IQR}] precourse to postcourse scores (8.0 [6-9] versus 6.0 [3-8], P =.005). Willingness to seek help in the event of a mental health concern significantly increased when comparing precourse to postcourse scores (3.4 [2.6 to 3.9] versus 4.6 [3.9 to 5.0], P &gt;.001). Three major themes and nine subthemes were identified during qualitative data analysis. Theme 1: The influence of conflict manifested as participants reporting persistent fear and stress and that the workplace was extremely strained. Theme 2: In social context it was noted that the training reduced social stigma, strengthened of a sense of community, and led to subtle changes in the workplace environment. Theme 3: The training contributed to new learning and practices, such as greater recognition of burnout and engaging in personal well-being practices. Acceptance of mindfulness was mixed, albeit with recognition of its positive effects. Despite many contextual challenges, participants reported the course to be needed and relevant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The findings suggest that VAST Wellbeing was pertinent and impactful in a conflict zone. It helped to foster a stronger sense of community, reduce stigma around mental health discussions, increase the acceptability of help-seeking, and encourage participants to adopt strategies for self-care and well-being.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 International Anesthesia Research Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elaibaid</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2275-5108</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Anaesthesia, Galway University Hospital, Galway, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Al Awasi International Training Center, Khartoum, Sudan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lopez-Barreda</LastName><ForeName>Rodrigo A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia, School of Medicine, Pontificia Universidad Cat&#xf3;lica de Chile, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Salam Centre for Cardiac Surgery - Emergency NGO, Khartoum, Sudan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bailey</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan G</ForeName><Initials>JG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia, Pain Management and Perioperative Medicine, Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mossenson</LastName><ForeName>Adam I</ForeName><Initials>AI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1078-2547</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia, Pain Management and Perioperative Medicine, Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia, SJOG Midland Public and Private Hospital, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maio</LastName><ForeName>Elisabetta</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-5021-5850</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Salam Centre for Cardiac Surgery - Emergency NGO, Khartoum, Sudan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Livingston</LastName><ForeName>Patricia</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9893-5116</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia, Pain Management and Perioperative Medicine, Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Anesth Analg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>1310650</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0003-2999</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest, Funding: Please see DISCLOSURES at the end of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41662700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1213/ANE.0000000000007983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00000539-990000000-01657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Maslach C, Leiter MP. Understanding the burnout experience: recent research and its implications for psychiatry. World Psychiatry. 2016;15:103&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanafelt TD, Boone S, Tan L, et al. Burnout and satisfaction with work-life balance among US physicians relative to the general US population. Arch Intern Med. 2017;72:1377&#x2013;1385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhadi M, Msherghi A, Elgzairi M, et al. Burnout syndrome among hospital healthcare workers during the COVID-19 pandemic and civil war: a cross-sectional study. Front Psychiatry. 2020;11:579563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Workneh RS, Tuyishime E, Mumbwe M, Igaga EN, Bould MD. Not a &#x201c;first world problem&#x201d;&#x2014;care of the anesthetist in East and Southern Africa. Paediatr Anaesth. 2021;31:39&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Burn-out an &#x201c;occupational phenomenon&#x201d;: International Classification of Diseases. Accessed March 7, 2025. https://www.who.int/news/item/28-05-2019-burn-out-an-occupational-phenomenon-international-classification-of-diseases</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mossenson AI, Mukwesi C, Elaibaid M, et al. Vital Anaesthesia Simulation Training (VAST): immersive simulation designed for diverse settings. Int J Surg Glob Health. 2021;4:e64&#x2013;e64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mossenson AI, Tuyishime E, Rawson D, et al. Promoting anaesthetisia providers&#x2019; non-technical skills through the Vital Anaesthesia Simulation Training (VAST) course in a low-resource setting. Br J Anaesth. 2020;124:206&#x2013;213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey J, Mossenson A, Whynot S, Nyirigira G, Gower S, Livingston P. A mixed methods cohort study evaluating the impact of a one-day wellbeing course for anesthesia providers working in low-resource settings. Anesth Analg. 2024;139:375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhadi YAM, Ahmed A, Salih EB, Abdelhamed OS, Ahmed MHH, El Dabbah NA. A cross-sectional survey of burnout in a sample of resident physicians in Sudan. PLoS One. 2022;17:e0265098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loskutov O, Markov Y, Maruniak S, Strokan A. Prevalence of professional burnout among anesthesiologists during the war in Ukraine: an observational study. Anesth Analg. 2024;139:e69&#x2013;e70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abed Alah M. Echoes of conflict: the enduring mental health struggle of Gaza&#x2019;s healthcare workers. Confl Health. 2024;18:21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy A, Wirtz A, Black E, Robinson WC. Health impacts of war-related stress on healthcare workers in conflict zones: a systematic review. Global Public Health. 2019;14:1261&#x2013;1275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin A, Abdullah S, ElAbbadi A, et al. Sudan: from a forgotten war to an abandoned healthcare system. BMJ Glob Health. 2024;9:e016406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miccio R, Quattrociocchi M, Valgoi L, et al. Treating children with advanced rheumatic heart disease in sub-saharan africa: the NGO EMERGENCY&#x2019;s project at the salam centre for cardiac surgery in Sudan. Front Pediatr. 2021;9:704729.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portella G, Chatenoud L, Gatti S, et al.; Salam Centre Working Group. Rheumatic valve surgery in Sudan: results in 7,449 patients at the salam centre for cardiac Surgery. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025;85:88&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasileiou K, Barnett J, Thorpe S, Young T. Characterising and justifying sample size sufficiency in interview-based studies: systematic analysis of qualitative health research over a 15-year period. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2018;18:148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mossenson AI, Ocholi D, Gower S, Livingston PL. Skill translation following the vital anesthesia simulation training facilitator course: a qualitative study. Anesth Analg. 2023;137:551&#x2013;558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gower S, Mossenson A, Ndekezi JK, Livingston P. Building global partnerships: a qualitative exploration of in-person training for healthcare simulation educators working in low-resource settings. Simul Healthc. 2025;20:7&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mossenson AI, Bailey JG, Whynot S, Livingston P. Qualities of effective Vital Anaesthesia Simulation Training facilitators delivering simulation-based education in resource-limited settings. Anesth Analg. 2021;133:215&#x2013;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Cathain A, Murphy E, Nicholl J. The quality of mixed methods studies in health services research. J Health Serv Res Policy. 2008;13:92&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Successful Qualitative Research: A Practical Guide for Beginners. Sage; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komiya N, Good GE, Sherrod NB. Emotional openness as a predictor of college students&#x2019; attitudes toward seeking psychological help. J Couns Psychol.. 2000;47:138&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson CJ, Deane FP, Ciarrochi J, Rickwood D. Measuring help-seeking intentions: properties of the general help-seeking questionnaire. Can J Couns Psychother. 2005;39:15&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deane FP, Wilson CJ, Ciarrochi J. Suicidal ideation and help&#x2010;negation: not just hopelessness or prior help. J Clin Psychol. 2001;57:901&#x2013;914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Y, McGrath PJ, Hayden J, Kutcher S. Mental health literacy measures evaluating knowledge, attitudes and help-seeking: a scoping review. BMC Psychiatry. 2015;15:291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grupp F, Moro MR, Nater UM, Skandrani S, Mewes R. &#x2018;Only God can promise healing.&#x2019;: help-seeking intentions and lay beliefs about cures for post-traumatic stress disorder among Sub-Saharan African asylum seekers in Germany. Eur J Psychotraumatol. 2019;10:1684225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwalek M, Pierce K, Straub V. Designing a questionnaire with retrospective pre-post items: format matters. Eval Program Plann. 2024;103:102411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little TD, Chang R, Gorrall BK, et al. The retrospective pretest&#x2013;posttest design redux: on its validity as an alternative to traditional pretest&#x2013;posttest measurement. Int J Behavioral Devel. 2020;44:175&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammarberg K, Kirkman M, De Lacey S. Qualitative research methods: when to use them and how to judge them. Hum Reprod. 2016;31:498&#x2013;501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual Res Psychol. 2006;3:77&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemu W, Kamei T, Aoyama A, Agalu A. Internalised stigma among people with mental illness in Africa: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Psychiatry. 2023;23:383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens GJ, Sharma A, Skeoch K. Help-seeking attitudes and behaviours among humanitarian aid workers. Int J Humanitarian Action. 2022;7:16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta N, Clement S, Marcus E, et al. Evidence for effective interventions to reduce mental health-related stigma and discrimination in the medium and long term: systematic review. Br J Psychiatry. 2015;207:377&#x2013;384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhorakeye L, Biracyaza E. Exploring barriers to mental health services utilization at kabutare district hospital of rwanda: perspectives from patients. Front Psychiatry. 2021;12:591843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pheko MM, Chilisa R, Balogun SK, Kgathi C. Predicting intentions to seek psychological help among botswana university students: the role of behavioral beliefs, attitudes and subjective norms. SAGE Open. 2013;3:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surya M, Jaff D, Stilwell B, Schubert J. The importance of mental well-being for health professionals during complex emergencies: it is time we take it seriously. Glob Health Sci Pract. 2017;5:188&#x2013;196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh PA, Kindred R, Perrins K, et al. Prevalence of complex post-traumatic stress disorder (CPTSD): a systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychiatry Res. 2025;351:116586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa M, Oberholzer-Riss M, Hatz C, Steffen R, Puhan M, Schlagenhauf P. Pre-travel health advice guidelines for humanitarian workers: a systematic review. Travel Med Infect Dis. 2015;13:449&#x2013;465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnhart BJ, Reddy SG, Arnold GK. Remind me again: physician response to web surveys: the effect of email reminders across 11 opinion survey efforts at the american board of internal medicine from 2017 to 2019. Eval Health Prof. 2021;44:245&#x2013;259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham CT, Quan H, Hemmelgarn B, et al. Exploring physician specialist response rates to web-based surveys. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2015;15:32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng-Jia W, Kelly Z, Francisca F-A. Response rates of online surveys in published research: a meta-analysis. Comput Hum Behav Rep. 2022;7:100206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg N. Non-response bias. In: Kempf-Leonard K., ed Encyclopedia of Social Measurement 2. Academic Press; 2010:865&#x2013;873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendra R, Hill A. Rethinking response rates: new evidence of little relationship between survey response rates and nonresponse bias. Eval Rev. 2019;43:307&#x2013;330.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>