<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41547825</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2050-7283</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cultural barriers influencing virtual community of practice: a scopic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>215</StartPage><MedlinePgn>215</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">215</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40359-025-03841-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Connectivism is the philosophy of education for the digital age, making Vygotsky&#x2019;s concept of zone of proximal development (ZPD) more flexible. Stretching it to include learning that lies outside the learner, in social networks and technological tools. It has replaced passive teaching methodologies with more active ones, including student-centered learning, the co-creation of knowledge, and peer review assessment strategies. Subsequently, the virtual communities of practices are considered an important medium for generation and dissemination of soft or tacit knowledge.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The objective of this scopic review was to explore the cultural factors which hamper the growth of a &#x2018;virtual community of practice&#x2019; of any organization.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This scopic review was done using Arksey and O&#x2019; Malley framework. This framework is comprised of following five steps: (1) identification of the research question, (2) identifying pertinent studies, (3) study selection, (4) charting the data, (5) organizing, summarizing, and reporting the results.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS">This research was conducted in ERIC, Pub med, Psycinfo and Cochrane library. A total of 31,000 records were acknowledged. After data characterization of full text articles, four themes emerged from the articles which fulfilled the criteria of inclusion: Individualism vs. collectivism, power distance, in group vs. out group orientation, cultural values and language barrier. Cultural factors like difference in time zone, working in a complex learning environment, missing organized guidance and the social presence of facilitators were also identified as minor aspects impeding the growth of virtual community of practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The research reported five major cultural elements which have influenced the virtual community of practice, that is, collectivism versus individualism, power distance in society language and geographical barriers, cultural values and in group versus out group orientation. Competitiveness and job security related fears are further influential barriers in the knowledge sharing across different cultures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s40359-025-03841-3.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manzoor</LastName><ForeName>Shamaila</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Azad Jammu &amp; Kashmir Medical College, Muzaffarabad, Pakistan. Shamaila1.Manzoor@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Health Sciences, Lahore, Pakistan. Shamaila1.Manzoor@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Atiq</LastName><ForeName>Noor</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>King Edward Medical University, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101627676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-7283</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cultural differences</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Individualism and connectivism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knowledge sharing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Power distance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Virtual community of practice</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable (as manuscript does not involve the use of any animal or human data or tissue). Consent for publication: Not applicable. Conflict of interest: There was no substantial disagreement between the researchers. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41547825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12896104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40359-025-03841-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40359-025-03841-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>1. Mattar J. Constructivism and connectivism in education technology: Active, situated, authentic, experiential, and anchored learning. RIED Rev Iberoam Educ a Distancia. 2018;21(2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>2. Boyraz S, Ocak G. Connectivism: A Literature Review for the New Pathway of Pandemic Driven Education.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dziubaniuk O, Ivanova-Gongne M, Nyholm M. Learning and teaching sustainable business in the digital era: a connectivism theory approach. Int J Educ Technol High Educ. 2023;20(1):1&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41239-023-00390-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10112993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37096023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taha MH, Abdalla ME, Wadi M, Khalafalla H. Curriculum delivery in medical education during an emergency: a guide based on the responses to the COVID-19 pandemic. MedEdPublish. 2020;9:69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15694/mep.2020.000069.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10697579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38058876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardichvili A. Learning and knowledge sharing in virtual communities of practice: motivators, barriers, and enablers. Adv Dev Hum Resour. 2008;10(4):541&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1523422308319536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufman DM. Teaching and learning in medical education: how theory can inform practice. In: Underst Med Educ evidence, theory, Pract. 2018. p. 37&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLoughlin C, Patel KD, O&#x2019;Callaghan T, Reeves S. The use of virtual communities of practice to improve interprofessional collaboration and education: findings from an integrated review. J Interprof Care. 2018;32(2):136&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13561820.2017.1377692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29161155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldie JGS. Connectivism: a knowledge learning theory for the digital age? Med Teach. 2016;38(10):1064&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/0142159X.2016.1173661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27128290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>9. Ghofrani P, Hollister MC. Connectivism as an emerging trend in elearning in large organizations. DETT; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>10. De Jager LJ. Misunderstanding in second language instructional communication. University of Pretoria; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boitshwarelo B. Proposing an integrated research framework for connectivism: utilising theoretical synergies. Int Rev Res Open Distrib Learn. 2011;12(3):161&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>12. &#x17b;emojtel-Piotrowska M, Piotrowski J. Hofstede&#x2019;s cultural dimensions theory. In: Encyclopedia of sexual psychology and behavior. Springer; 2023. p. 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>13. Hall ET, Hall MR. Key concepts: Underlying structures of culture. Int HRM Manag Divers Work. 2001;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Easthope A. Bhabha, hybridity and identity. Text Pract. 1998;12(2):341&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09502369808582312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>15. Kraidy M. The Cultural and Political Economies of Hybrid Media Texts. Hybridity, or Cult Log Glob. 2005;(761):97&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canagarajah AS. Interrogating the &#x201c;native speaker fallacy&#x201d;: Non-linguistic roots, non-pedagogical results. In: Non-native educators in English language teaching. Routledge; 2013. p. 77&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy P, Sharma B, Chaudhary K. Digital literacy: a review of literature. Int J Technoethics. 2020;11(2):65&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/IJT.20200701.oa1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dub&#xe9; L, Bourhis A, Jacob R. Towards a typology of virtual communities of practice. Interdiscip J Inf Knowl Manag. 2006;1:69&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buus N, Nygaard L, Berring LL, Hybholt L, Kamionka SL, Rossen CB, et al. Arksey and O&#x2032;Malley&#x2bc;s consultation exercise in scoping reviews: a critical review. J Adv Nurs. 2022;78(8):2304&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jan.15265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9545832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35451517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rethlefsen ML, Page MJ. PRISMA 2020 and PRISMA-S: common questions on tracking records and the flow diagram. J Med Libr Assoc JMLA. 2022;110(2):253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9014944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35440907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadie SNH. ABC of a scoping review: a simplified JBI scoping review guideline. Educ Med J. 2024. 10.21315/eimj2024.16.2.14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21315/eimj2024.16.2.14</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>22. Hughes SE, Aiyegbusi OL, Lasserson DS, Collis P, Rivera SC, McMullan C, et al. Protocol for a scoping review exploring the use of patient-reported outcomes in adult social care. BMJ Open. 2021;11(4):e045206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8051391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33849854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinmaz H, Lee Y-T, Fanea-Ivanovici M, Baber H. A systematic review on digital literacy. Smart Learn Environ. 2022;9(1):21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40561-022-00204-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9175160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40478098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhagat RS, Kedia BL, Harveston PD, Triandis HC. Cultural variations in the cross-border transfer of organizational knowledge: an integrative framework. Acad Manag Rev. 2002;27(2):204&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/4134352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>25. Ardichvili A, Maurer M, Wentling T. Knowledge Sharing Through Online Communities of Practice: The Impact of Cultural Variations. Online Submiss. 2005;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang CX, Pearce P, Chen G. Not losing our collective face: social identity and Chinese tourists&#x2019; reflections on uncivilised behaviour. Tour Manag. 2019;73:71&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tourman.2019.01.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardichvili A, Maurer M, Li W, Wentling T, Stuedemann R. Cultural influences on knowledge sharing through online communities of practice. J Knowl Manag. 2006;10(1):94&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/13673270610650139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilgino&#x11f;lu E. Knowledge hoarding: a literature review. Manag Sci Lett. 2019;9(1):61&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5267/j.msl.2018.10.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofstede G. Culture&#x2019;s consequences: Comparing values, behaviors, institutions and organizations across nations. Sage publications; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang A, Francesco AM, Kessler E. The relationship between individualism-collectivism, face, and feedback and learning processes in Hong Kong, Singapore, and the United States. J Cross-Cult Psychol. 2003;34(1):72&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0022022102239156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M, Hunter JE, Miyahara A, Horvath A, Bresnahan M, Yoon H. Individual-vs. culture&#x2010;level dimensions of individualism and collectivism: effects on preferred conversational styles. Commun Monogr. 1996;63(1):29&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03637759609376373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drogendijk R, Zander L. Walking the cultural distance: In search of direction beyond friction. In: The past, present and future of international business &amp; management. Emerald Group Publishing Limited; 2010. p. 189&#x2013;212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanisch J, Churchman D. Virtual communities of practice: the communication of knowledge across cultural boundaries. Int J Web Based Communities. 2008;4(4):418&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1504/IJWBC.2008.019548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>34. Vasquez VM. Critical literacy. In: Oxford research encyclopedia of education. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw L, Jazayeri D, Kiegaldie D, Morris M. Virtual communities of practice to improve clinical outcomes in healthcare: protocol for a 10-year scoping review. BMJ Open. 2021;11(7):e046998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-046998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8314687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ndjama JDN. Bridging the Digital Divide in the Access and Usage of Technology Through Digital Literacy in Rural Vocational Schools. In: Institutes of Higher Education (IHE) and Workforce Collaboration for Digital Literacy. IGI Global Scientific Publishing; 2025. p. 91&#x2013;124.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>