<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41776793</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1119-3077</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nigerian journal of clinical practice</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Niger J Clin Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Three-Arm Randomized Trial of Aerobic Training Versus High-Intensity Interval Training on Clinical and Functional Outcomes in Patients with Chronic Neck Pain.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>113</StartPage><EndPage>126</EndPage><MedlinePgn>113-126</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/njcp.njcp_476_25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">High-intensity interval training (HIIT) has become increasingly popular. However, no studies have investigated the effects of HIIT in individuals with neck pain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study compared the effectiveness of 8 weeks of aerobic training (AT) and HIIT as therapeutic interventions for individuals with chronic neck pain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a prospective, randomized-controlled, single-blinded study. Forty-six patients with chronic neck pain were randomized to the AT, HIIT, and control groups. Aerobic (n = 13) exercise (arm ergometer) was at 70% of peak workload. HIIT (n = 15) was at 90% of peak workload. AT or HIIT was applied for 24 training sessions during 8 weeks. Pain intensity, cervical range of motion (CROM), cervical proprioception (joint position error), head posture (craniovertebral angle (CVA)) static endurance and activation of deep cervical flexor muscles (Craniocervical Flexion Test), disability (Neck Disability Index), and emotional state (Beck Depression Index (BDI), Beck Anxiety Index (BAI)) were evaluated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Between-group differences revealed that the AT and HIIT groups exhibited lower pain and disability levels and higher CVA, endurance and activation of the deep cervical flexor muscles, and CROM values compared to the control group. HIIT group showed a significant improvement in BDI score compared to the AT group and control group, and HIIT group showed a significant increase in BAI score compared to AT group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study showed that AT and HIIT were similarly effective on the clinical effects of neck pain and functional disability. Both exercises can potentially be performed in individuals with neck pain according to personal factors.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Nigerian Journal of Clinical Practice.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc7;&#x131;nar</LastName><ForeName>S Ayy&#x131;ld&#x131;z</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Therapy and Rehabilitation, Hacettepe University, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demirel</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Therapy and Rehabilitation, Hacettepe University, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x15e;ahiner</LastName><ForeName>M L</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology and Medical Faculty, Hacettepe University, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xd6;ge</LastName><ForeName>H K</ForeName><Initials>HK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Medical Faculty, Hacettepe University, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bilgin</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Therapy and Rehabilitation, Hacettepe University, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Niger J Clin Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101150032</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019547" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neck Pain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072696" MajorTopicYN="Y">High-Intensity Interval Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016037" MajorTopicYN="N">Single-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016059" MajorTopicYN="N">Range of Motion, Articular</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059350" MajorTopicYN="Y">Chronic Pain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010147" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain Measurement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004185" MajorTopicYN="N">Disability Evaluation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aerobic exercises</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic neck pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high intensity interval training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical therapy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41776793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/njcp.njcp_476_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01253091-202602000-00001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Safiri S, Kolahi A-A, Hoy D, Buchbinder R, Mansournia MA, Bettampadi D, et al. Global, regional, and national burden of neck pain in the general population, 1990&#x2013;2017: Systematic analysis of the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017. Br Med J 2020;368:m791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoy D, March L, Woolf A, Blyth F, Brooks P, Smith E, et al. The global burden of neck pain: Estimates from the Global Burden of Disease 2010 study. Ann Rheum Dis 2014;73:1309&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurwitz EL, Randhawa K, Yu H, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; P, Haldeman S. The global spine care initiative: A summary of the global burden of low back and neck pain studies. Eur Spine J 2018;27:796&#x2013;801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paraskevopoulos E, Koumantakis GA, Papandreou M. A systematic review of the aerobic exercise program variables for patients with non-specific neck pain: Effectiveness and clinical applications. Healthcare 2023;11:339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price J, Rushton A, Tyros V, Heneghan NR. Expert consensus on the important chronic non-specific neck pain motor control and segmental exercise and dosage variables: An international e-Delphi study. PLoS One 2021;16:e0253523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Zoete RM, Armfield NR, McAuley JH, Chen K, Sterling M. Comparative effectiveness of physical exercise interventions for chronic non-specific neck pain: A systematic review with network meta-analysis of 40 randomised controlled trials. Br J Sports Med 2021;55:730&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahid A, Manek N, Nichols M. Quantifying the association between physical activity and cardiovascular disease and diabetes: A systematic review and meta- analysis. J Am Heart Assoc 2016;5:e002495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinckard K, Baskin KK, Stanford KI. Effects of exercise to improve cardiovascular health. Front Cardiovasc Med 2019;6:19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisl&#xf8;ff U, St&#xf8;ylen A, Loennechen JP, Bruvold M, Rognmo &#xd8;, Haram PM, et al. Superior cardiovascular effect of aerobic interval training versus moderate continuous training in heart failure patients: A randomized study. Circulation 2007;115:3086&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel H, Alkhawam H, Madanieh R, Shah N, Kosmas CE, Vittorio TJ. Aerobic vs anaerobic exercise training effects on the cardiovascular system. World J Cardiol 2017;9:134&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atakan MM, Li Y, Ko&#x15f;ar &#x15e;N, Turnag&#xf6;l HH, Yan X. Evidence-based effects of high-intensity interval training on exercise capacity and health: A review with historical perspective. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021;18:7201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weston KS, Wisl&#xf8;ff U, Coombes JS. High-intensity interval training in patients with lifestyle-induced cardiometabolic disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med 2014;48:1227&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jelleyman C, Yates T, O&#x2019;Donovan G, Gray LJ, King JA, Khunti K, et al. The effects of high-intensity interval training on glucose regulation and insulin resistance: A meta-analysis. Obes Rev 2015;16:942&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botta RM, Palermi S, Tarantino D. High-intensity interval training for chronic pain conditions: A narrative review. J Exerc Rehabil 2022;18:10&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatsios PI, Grammatopoulou E, Dimitriadis Z, Koumantakis GA. The effectiveness of manual therapy in the cervical spine and diaphragm, in combination with breathing reeducation exercises, in patients with non-specific chronic neck pain: Protocol for development of outcome measures and a randomized controlled trial. Diagnostics 2022;12:2690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vancampfort D, Van Damme T, Brunner E, McGrath RL, Hemmings L, Eduarda Guimaraes M, et al. Dropout from exercise interventions in adults with fibromyalgia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2024;105:571&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarmento CVM, Liu Z, Smirnova IV, Liu W. Exploring adherence to moderate to high-intensity exercises in patients with fibromyalgia: The role of physiological and psychological factors&#x2014;A narrative literature review. Physiologia 2023;3:472&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakens D. Calculating and reporting effect sizes to facilitate cumulative science: A practical primer for t-tests and ANOVAs. Front Psychol 2013;4:863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen SP, Hooten WM. Advances in the diagnosis and management of neck pain. BMJ 2017;358:j3221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCormack HM, David JDL, Sheather S. Clinical applications of visual analogue scales: A critical review. Psychol Med 1988;18:1007&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Audette I, Dumas JP, C&#xe9;t&#xe9; IN, Serres SJD. Validity and between-day reliability of the cervical range of motion (CROM) device. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 2010;40:318&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy RS, Maiya AG, Rao SK. Effect of dorsal neck muscle fatigue on cervicocephalic kinaesthetic sensibility. Hong Kong Physiother J 2012;30:105&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salahzadeh Z, Maroufi N, Ahmadi A, Behtash H, Razmjoo A, G ohari M, et al. Assessment of forward head posture in females: Observational and photogrammetry methods. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil 2014;27:131&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jull G, Ashaun PO, Falla DL. Clinical assessment of the deep cervical flexor muscles: The craniocervical flexion test. J Manipulative Physiol Ther 2008;31:525&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslan E, Karaduman A, Yakut Y, Aras B, Simsek IE, Yagl&#x131; N. The cultural adaptation, reliability, and validity of neck disability index in patients with neck pain: A Turkish version study. Spine 2008;33:E362&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acar S, Savci S, Keskino&#x11f;lu P, Akdeniz B, &#xd6;zpelit E, Kahraman B&#xd6;, et al. Tampa scale of kinesiophobia for heart Turkish version study: Cross-cultural adaptation, exploratory factor analysis, and reliability. J Pain Res 2016;9:445&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tekinda M, Tekindal MA. Validity and reliability of basic depression scale for Turkey. Med J West Black Sea 2021;5:452&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulusoy M, sahin Nh, Erkmen H. Turkish version of the beck anxiety inventory: Psychometric properties. J Cogn Psychother 1998;12:163&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher A, Dar G, Carel R. Effectiveness of combined aerobic exercise and neck-specific exercise compared to neck specific exercise alone on work ability in neck pain patients: A secondary analysis of data from a randomized controlled trial. Arch Occup Environ Health 2021;94:1739&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuenca-Mart&#xed;nez F, Sempere-Rubio N, Varangot-Reille C, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Carnero J, Suso-Mart&#xed; L, Alba-Quesada P, et al. Effects of high-intensity interval training (HIIT) on patients with musculoskeletal disorders: A systematic review and meta-analysis with a meta-regression and mapping report. Diagnostics 2022;12:2532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Q, Zhanga N, Zhang R, Yuanc Y. Network meta-analysis of the effect of exercise therapy on chronic neck pain. Med Nov Technol Devices 2025;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naugle KM, Fillingim RB, Riley JL. A meta-analytic review of the hypoalgesic effects of exercise. J Pain 2012;13:1139&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith BE, Hendrick P, Bateman M, Holden S, Littlewood C, Smith TO, et al. Musculoskeletal pain and exercise&#x2014;challenging existing paradigms and introducing new. Br J Sports Med 2019;53:14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Leary TJ, Collett J, Howells K, Morris MG. High but not moderate-intensity endurance training increases pain tolerance: A randomised trial. Eur J Appl Physiol 2017;117:2201&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakansson S., Jones M.D., Ristov M., Marcos L., Clark T., Ram A., et al. Intensity-dependent effects of aerobic training on pressure pain threshold in overweight men: A randomized trial. Eur J Pain 2018;22:1813&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mijwel S, Backman M, Bolam KA, Olofsson E, Norrbom J, Bergh J, et al. Highly favorable physiological responses to concurrent resistance and high-intensity interval training during chemotherapy: The OptiTrain breast cancer trial. Breast Cancer Res Treat 2018;169:93&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams SC, DeLorey DS, Davenport MH, Stickland MK, Fairey AS, North S, et al. Effects of high-intensity aerobic interval training on cardiovascular disease risk in testicular cancer survivors: A phase 2 randomized controlled trial. Cancer 2017;123:4057&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalafi M, Symonds ME. The impact of high-intensity interval training on inflammatory markers in metabolic disorders: A meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports 2020;30:2020&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steckling FM, Farinha JB, Figueiredo FDC, Santos DLD, Bresciani G, Kretzmann NA, et al. High-intensity interval training improves inflammatory and adipokine profiles in po&#xfb06;menopausal women with metabolic syndrome. Arch Physiol Biochem 2018;125:85&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanaki M, Khosravi M, Khoshdooni-Farahani A, Dadashi A, Heydari MF, Delfan M, et al. High-intensity interval training reversed high-fat diet&#x2013;induced M1-macrophage polarization in rat adipose tissue via inhibition of NOTCH signaling. J Inamm Res 2020;13:165&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeVon HA, Piano MR, Rosenfeld AG, Hoppensteadt DA. The association of pain with protein inflammatory biomarkers. A review of the literature. Nurs Res 2014;63:51&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDowall A, Skeppholm M, Robinson Y, Olerud C. Validation of the visual analog scale in the cervical spine. J Neurosurg Spine 2018;28:227&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud NF, Hassan KA, Abdelmajeed SF, Moustafa IM, Silva AG. The relationship between forward head posture and neck pain: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med 2019;12:562&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim E-K, Kim JS. Correlation between rounded shoulder posture, neck disability indices, and degree of forward head posture. J Phys Ther Sci 2016;28:2929&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd El-Azeim AS, Mahmoud AG, Mohamed MT, El-Khateeb YS. Impact of adding scapular stabilization to postural correctional exercises on symptomatic forward head posture: A randomized controlled trial. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 2022;58:757&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heydari Z, Sheikhhoseini R, Shahrbanian S, Piri H. Establishing minimal clinically important difference for effectiveness of corrective exercises on craniovertebral and shoulder angles among students with forward head posture: A clinical trial study. BMC Pediatr 2022;22:230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghamkhar L, Kahlaee AH. Is forward head posture relevant to cervical muscles performance and neck pain? A case control study. Braz J Phys Ther 2019;23:346&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shyama S, Nagaraj S. Effect of stabilization exercises on craniovertebral angle and cervical range of motion among visual display users with forward head posture. Bull Rehabil Med 2023;22:48&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subbarayalu AV, Ameer MA. Relationships among head posture, pain intensity, disability and deep cervical flexor muscle performance in subjects with postural neck pain. J Taibah Univ Med Sci 2017;12:541&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falla DL, Jull GA, Hodges PW. Feedforward activity of the cervical flexor muscles during voluntary arm movements is delayed in chronic neck pain. Exp Brain Res 2007;157:43&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishida H, Suehiro T, Kurozumi C, Ono K, Ando S, Watanabe S. Correlation between neck slope angle and deep cervical flexor muscle thickness in healthy participants. J Bodyw Mov Ther 2015;19:717&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romeo A, Baccini M, Carreras G, Sagripanti M, Ruggeri M, Mauro Di Bari M. Reliability, validity, and responsiveness of the craniocervical flexion test in people who are asymptomatic and patients with nonspecific neck pain: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Phys Ther 2022;102:pzac054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark NC, R&#xf6;ijezon U, Treleaven J. Proprioception in musculoskeletal rehabilitation. Part 2: Clinical assessment and intervention. Man Ther 2015;20:378&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vries Jd, Ischebeck BK, Voogt LP, van der Geest JN, Janssen M, Frens MA, Kleinrensinke GJ. Joint position sense error in people with neck pain: A systematic review. Man Ther 2015;20:736&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy RS, Maiya A, Rao SK. Proprioceptive reposition errors in subjects with cervical spondylosis. Int J Health Sci Res 2012;1:65&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyd-Clark LC, Briggs CA, Galea MP. Muscle spindle distribution, morphology, and density in longus colli and multifidus muscles of the cervical spine. Spine 2002;27:694&#x2013;701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proske U, Wise AK, Gregory JE. The role of muscle receptors in the detection of movements. Prog Neurobiol 2000;60:85&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong M-S, Lee H-Y, Ryu Y-U, Lee M-Y. Effects of craniocervical flexion exercise on upper-limb postural stability during a goal-directed pointing task. J Phys Ther Sci 2015;27:2005&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong MS, Lee HY, Lee MY. Correlation between head posture and proprioceptive function in the cervical region. J Phys Ther Sci 2016;28:857&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin G, Zhao X, Wangc W, Wilkinson T. The relationship between forward head posture, postural control and gait: A systematic review. Gait Posture 2022;98:316&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DH, Kim CJ, Son SM. Neck pain in adults with forward head posture: Effects of craniovertebral angle and cervical range of motion. Osong Public Health Res Perspect 2018;9:309&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Queka J, Pua YH, Clark RA, Bryant AL. Effects of thoracic kyphosis and forward head posture on cervical range of motion in older adults. Man Ther 2013;18:65&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo WG, An DH. The relationship between the active cervical range of motion and changes in head and neck posture after continuous VDT work. Ind Health 2009;47:183&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher A, Carel RS, Tzipi K, Esther H, Dar G. The effectiveness of an aerobic exercise training on patients with neck pain during a short- and long-term follow-up: A prospective double-blind randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil 2020;34:617&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanpied PR, Gross AR, Elliott JM, Devaney LL, Clewley D, Walton DM, et al. Neck pain: Revision 2017. Clinical practice guidelines linked to the international classification of functioning, disability and health from the orthopaedic section of the American physical therapy association. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 2017;47:A1&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vernon H. The neck disability index: State-of-the-art, 1991&#x2013;2008. J Manipulative Physiol Ther 2008;31:491&#x2013;502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira-Souza AISd, Kempe M, Grimmelsmann S, Tavares LF, Castro-Carletti EMD, Andrade AV, et al. The effectiveness of aerobic exercise on pain and disability in individuals with neck pain: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Exp Physiol 2024. doi: 10.1113/EP091884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bougar MR, Veiskarami HA, Khodarahimi S, Izadpanah A, Sadeghi M, Nazari N. Effectiveness of three physical treatments on pain perception and emotional state in males with chronic joint pain. J Clin Psychol Med Settings 2022;29:785&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDermid JC, Walton DM, Avery S, Blanchard A, Etruw E, Mcalpine C, Goldsmith CH. Measurement properties of the neck disability index: A systematic review. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 2009;39:400&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucibelloa KM, Paoluccia EM, Grahamb JD, Heisz JJ. A randomized control trial investigating high-intensity interval training and mental health: A novel non-responder phenotype related to anxiety in young. Men Health Phys Activity 2020;18:100327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masson SC, Tejani AM. Minimum clinically important differences identified for commonly used depression rating scales. J Clin Epidemiol 2013;66:805&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>