<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41794319</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-6424</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>397</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental pollution (Barking, Essex : 1987)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Pollut</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Distribution and bioaccumulation characteristics of emerging and legacy per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS) in a typical subtropical estuary-bay-offshore ecosystem.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>127931</StartPage><MedlinePgn>127931</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.envpol.2026.127931</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0269-7491(26)00301-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As replacements for legacy per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS), perfluoroalkyl ether carboxylic and sulfonic acids (PFECAs) are increasingly applied and consequently detected in diverse environmental matrices. Yet, their occurrence and environmental behaviors in subtropical estuary-bay systems remain poorly documented. Here, we conducted a comprehensive investigation of 14 PFECAs and 22 legacy PFAS in surface seawater (N&#xa0;=&#xa0;77), sediments (N&#xa0;=&#xa0;29) and biota (N&#xa0;=&#xa0;173) across a representative subtropical estuary-bay-offshore continuum. Overall, legacy PFAS dominated in seawater and biota, whereas sediments contained comparable levels of emerging and legacy PFAS owing to the elevated abundance of hexafluoropropylene oxide dimer acid (HFPO-DA). Concentrations of &#x2211;PFAS ranged from 1.74 to 30.91&#xa0;ng/L in seawater and 0.52 to 7.08&#xa0;ng/g dw in sediments, indicating a relatively low contamination status compared with other Chinese coastal bays. Partitioning behavior differed substantially between chemical classes: the Kd values of hexafluoropropylene oxide derivatives (HFPOs) displayed carbon-number relationships distinct from those of perfluoroalkyl carboxylic acids (PFCAs). In biota, &#x2211;PFAS concentrations varied from 2.22 to 65.61&#xa0;ng/g dw, with perfluoro-(3,5-dioxahexanoic) acid (PFO2HxA) showing clear bioaccumulation and biomagnification potential. Notably, the relationships between bioconcentration factors of PFECAs and carbon chain length/ether oxygen content diverged from trends previously reported for Laizhou Bay, underscoring region-specific bioaccumulation behaviors. The results suggested that local residents were unlikely to experience significant exposure to PFOA or PFOS through seafood consumption. However, potential health risks associated with PFECAs remain uncertain, emphasizing the need for further evaluation of their toxicological effects.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Mi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Key Laboratory of Coastal Zone Environmental Processes and Ecological Security, Yantai Institute of Coastal Zone Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Yantai, 264003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>Riquan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pinglu Canal and Beibu Gulf Coastal Ecosystem Observation and Research Station of Guangxi, Guangxi Key Laboratory of Marine Environmental Change and Disaster in Beibu Gulf, College of Marine Sciences, Beibu Gulf University, Qinzhou, 535011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dou</LastName><ForeName>Wenke</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Key Laboratory of Coastal Zone Environmental Processes and Ecological Security, Yantai Institute of Coastal Zone Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Yantai, 264003, China; University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, 100049, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Key Laboratory of Coastal Zone Environmental Processes and Ecological Security, Yantai Institute of Coastal Zone Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Yantai, 264003, China; University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, 100049, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Fengfeng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Environmental Health Impact Assessment of Emerging Contaminants, Ministry of Ecology and Environment, School of Environmental Science and Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, 200240, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Yitao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Environmental Health Impact Assessment of Emerging Contaminants, Ministry of Ecology and Environment, School of Environmental Science and Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, 200240, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Jianhui</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Key Laboratory of Coastal Zone Environmental Processes and Ecological Security, Yantai Institute of Coastal Zone Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Yantai, 264003, China; Pinglu Canal and Beibu Gulf Coastal Ecosystem Observation and Research Station of Guangxi, Guangxi Key Laboratory of Marine Environmental Change and Disaster in Beibu Gulf, College of Marine Sciences, Beibu Gulf University, Qinzhou, 535011, China. Electronic address: jhtang@yic.ac.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Pollut</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804476</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0269-7491</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bioaccumulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PFESAs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Partitioning behavior</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Subtropical bay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Trophic transfer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41794319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envpol.2026.127931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0269-7491(26)00301-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>