<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41888680</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2334</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC infectious diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence and determinants of hepatitis B virus infection among youth in southern-central Ethiopia: a community-based cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12879-026-13185-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Hepatitis B virus (HBV) is a major global public health problem that affects approximately 2&#xa0;billion people worldwide. In Ethiopia, there is limited information on the community-wide spread of HBV, especially among youth. This gap in community-wide data hinders a thorough understanding of HBV transmission dynamics and effective public health interventions tailored to youth populations in southern-central Ethiopia. Therefore, this study aimed to determine the prevalence of HBV infection and associated factors among youth ages 15 to 29 years in southern-central Ethiopia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A community-based cross-sectional study was conducted from March to April 2022. A multistage cluster sampling technique was employed to select 692 study participants. Data on exposure variables were collected via a standardized questionnaire. A rapid diagnostic test with immunochromatographic strips was used to screen for HBV infection. A binary logistic regression model was fitted to identify independent predictors of HBV infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The overall prevalence of HBV was 6.8% [95% confidence (CI): 5.1-8.9] out of 692 youth tested for the HBV surface antigen. The prevalence varies among kebeles (Ethiopia's smallest administrative unit), ranging from 2.2% in Borer Kebele to 9.7% in Jeju Kebele. Over 80% of the participants demonstrated poor knowledge about HBV. Only 6 (0.9%) of the study participants had received HBV vaccination. A history of dental extraction [adjusted odds ratio (AOR): 2.82; 95% CI: 1.05, 7.60], history of hospitalization (AOR: 3.17; 95% CI: 1.26, 7.97), history of having close contact with a person who has jaundice (AOR: 3.57; 95% CI: 1.24, 10.24), and having multiple sexual partners in the past 12 months (AOR: 8.81; 95% CI: 3.84, 20.21) were significantly associated with HBV infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The study showed that the prevalence of HBV infection among the youth population was at the upper end of the intermediate endemicity range according to the World Health Organization classification and varied across study kebeles. We also found a low vaccination history for HBV. Tooth extraction, hospitalization, contact with jaundiced individuals, and having multiple sexual partners significantly increased HBV infection. Infection prevention in dental clinics and hospitals; behavioral change education on risky sexual behaviors; expanding services for screening, and treatment; and emphasizing the urgent catch-up vaccination campaigns for youth are crucial to reduce HBV transmission.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Not applicable.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Joffe</LastName><ForeName>Zeleke Tadesse</ForeName><Initials>ZT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Hawassa University, Hawassa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsegaw</LastName><ForeName>Desalegn</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Hawassa University, Hawassa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fentahun</LastName><ForeName>Selam</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Hawassa University, Hawassa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Darge</LastName><ForeName>Samuel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central Ethiopia Regional State Health Bureau, Worabe, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alemu</LastName><ForeName>Tsegaye</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Hawassa University, Hawassa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Solomon</LastName><ForeName>Tarekegn</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Hawassa University, Hawassa, Ethiopia. tarekegn2solomon@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2334</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gurage zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HBV infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Southern-central Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Youth</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was reviewed and approved by the Institutional Review Board (IRB) of Hawassa University at the College of Medicine and Health Sciences under the reference number of Ref No. IRB/067/14 and signed by the chairperson of Mr. Dawit Jember on 16/02/2022. The study was conducted in accordance with Helsinki declaration and according to the ethical review guideline of Ethiopia. The support letter was taken from the Hawassa University, School of Public Health and the Regional Health Bureau. Written informed consent was obtained from each participant before data collection after receiving full information about the study. The written assent of parents/guardians was obtained from youth under 18 years of age. The interviews were conducted in a private place. A standard information sheet was used to describe the study&#x2019;s objectives via the participants&#x2019; language. The study participants were made aware that their participation was completely voluntary and that they might leave the study at any time. They were also informed that all data obtained from them would be kept confidential. Counseling was provided on how to accept test results, whether they are favorable or unfavorable. Information on the need to receive the HBV vaccine and avoid risk factors was provided to those who received negative test results. Individuals who tested positive for HBV received information, counseling, and referrals to neighboring hospitals for follow-up and better care. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41888680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-026-13185-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12879-026-13185-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Margolis HS, Alter MJ, Hadler SC. Viral hepatitis. In: Evans AS, Kaslow RA, editors. Viral Infections of Humans: Epidemiology and Control. 4th ed. New York: Plenum Publishing Corporation; 1997. pp. 363&#x2013;418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lok ASF. Chronic hepatitis B. N Engl J Med. 2002;346(22):1682&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson NP, Easterbrook PJ, McMahon BJ. Epidemiology of Hepatitis B Virus Infection and Impact of Vaccination on Disease. Clin Liver Dis. 2016;20(4):607&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Global Progress Report on HIV, Viral hepatitis and sexually transmitted infections. World Health Organization: Geneva, Switzerland; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Hepatitis. [cited 2023 September 22]. Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/hepatitis-b.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hepatitis [Internet]. WHO | Regional Office for Africa. [cited 2023 Feb 22]. Available from: https://www.afro.who.int/health-topics/hepatitis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsega E. Epidemiology, prevention and treatment of viral hepatitis with emphasis on new developments. Ethiop Med J. 2000;38:131&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan M, Bhadoria AS, Cui F, Tan A, Van Holten J, Easterbrook P, et al. Estimating the proportion of people with chronic hepatitis B virus infection eligible for hepatitis B antiviral treatment worldwide: a systematic review and meta-analysis. lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;6(2):106&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonderup MW, Spearman CW. Global disparities in hepatitis B elimination-a focus on Africa. Viruses. 2022;14(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Introduction of hepatitis B vaccine into childhood immunization services. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2001. WHO/V&amp;B/01.31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethiopia National Strategy for Prevention and Control of Viral Hepatitis. 2016&#x2013;2020 | Coalition for Global Hepatitis Elimination. [cited 2023 Fe 28]. Available from: https://www.globalhep.org/evidence-base/ethiopia-national-strategy-prevention-and-control-viral-hepatitis-2016-2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfa T, Hawulte B, Tolera A, Abate D. Hepatitis B virus infection and associated risk factors among medical students in eastern Ethiopia. PLoS ONE. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gedefie A, Seid A, Molla Fenta G, Tilahun M, Shibabaw A, Ali A. Hepatitis B and C virus infections and associated factors among HIV-positive and HIV-negative tuberculosis patients in public health facilities, Northeast Ethiopia: A comparative cross-sectional study. SAGE open Med. 2023;11:20503121231166642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfu MA, Habtemariam TT, Belay NB. Risk factors associated with Hepatitis B virus infection among pregnant women attending public hospitals in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. PLoS ONE. 2023;18(4):e0284646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belyhun Y, Maier M, Mulu A, Diro E, Liebert UG. Hepatitis viruses in Ethiopia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Infect Dis. 2016;16(1):761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woldegiorgis AE, Erku W, Medhin G, Berhe N, Legesse M. Community-based sero-prevalence of hepatitis B and C infections in South Omo Zone, Southern Ethiopia. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(12):e0226890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumalo A, Teklu T, Demisse T, Anjulo A. Undiagnosed Seroprevalence of Hepatitis B and C Virus Infections in the Community of Wolaita Zone, Southern Ethiopia. Hepatic medicine: Evid Res. 2022;14:111&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FMOH. Ethiopia National Expanded Program on Immunization: Comprehensive multi-year plan (2021&#x2013;2025). Addis Ababa Federal Ministry of Health; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia, Ministry of Youth Sports and Culture. Ethiopia National Youth Policy. Addis Ababa. 2004. https://www.tea4africa.org/pdf/Ethiopian-National-Youth-Policy.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Central Statistical Agency (CSA) [Ethiopia] and ICF. Ethiopia Demographic and Health Survey 2016. Addis Ababa: CSA and ICF. 2016. https://dhsprogram.com/pubs/pdf/FR328/FR328.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meheus A. Teenagers&#x2019; lifestyle and the risk of exposure to hepatitis B virus. Vaccine. 2000;18(Suppl 1):S26&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meheus A. Risk of hepatitis B in adolescence and young adulthood. Vaccine. 1995;13(Suppl 1):S31&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abera B, Adem Y, Yimer M, Mulu W, Zenebe Y, Mekonnen Z. Community seroprevalence of hepatitis B, C and human immunodeficiency virus in adult population in gojjam zones, northwest Ethiopia. Virol J. 2017;14(1):21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belay AS, Abateneh DD, Yehualashet SS, Kebede KM. Hepatitis B Virus Infection and Associated Factors Among Adults in Southwest Ethiopia: Community-Based Cross-Sectional Study. Int J Gen Med. 2020;13:323&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Federal Demographic Republic of Ethiopia Central Statistical Agency. Population Projection of Ethiopia for All Regions. At Wereda Level from 2014&#x2013;2017. Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 2013. Available at: http://www.statsethiopia.gov.et/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Population-Projection-At-Wereda-Level-from-2014-2017.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jargalsaikhan G, Eichner M, Boldbaatar D, Bat-Ulzii P, Lkhagva-Ochir O, Oidovsambuu O, et al. Sensitivity and specificity of commercially available rapid diagnostic tests for viral hepatitis B and C screening in serum samples. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(7):e0235036.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global regional, national burden of hepatitis B. 1990&#x2013;2019: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019. lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;7(9):796&#x2013;829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kafeero HM, Ndagire D, Ocama P, Kudamba A, Walusansa A, Sendagire H. Prevalence and predictors of hepatitis B virus (HBV) infection in east Africa: evidence from a systematic review and meta-analysis of epidemiological studies published from 2005 to 2020. Archives of public health&#x2009;=&#x2009;Archives belges de sante publique. 2021;79(1):167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Men P, Xiao Y, Gao P, Lv M, Yuan Q, et al. Hepatitis B infection in the general population of China: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Infect Dis. 2019;19(1):811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elzouki NA, Smeo MN, Sammud M, Elahmer O, Daw M, Furarah A, et al. Prevalence of hepatitis B and C virus infections and their related risk factors in Libya: a national seroepidemiological survey. East Mediterr Health J. 2013;19(7):589&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scaraveli NG, Passos AM, Voigt AR, Livramento A, Tonial G, Treitinger A, et al. Seroprevalence of hepatitis B and hepatitis C markers in adolescents in Southern Brazil. Cadernos de saude publica. 2011;27(4):753&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beykaso G, Mulu A, Giday M, Berhe N, Selamu M, Mihret A, et al. Burden and Transmission Risks of Viral Hepatitis in Southern Ethiopia: Evidence Needed for Prevention and Control Measures. Risk Manage Healthc policy. 2021;14:4843&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochola E, Ocama P, Orach CG, Nankinga ZK, Kalyango JN, McFarland W, et al. High burden of hepatitis B infection in Northern Uganda: results of a population-based survey. BMC Public Health. 2013;13:727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humayed SMA. The risk of acquiring hepatitis B and C viral infections following tooth extraction in Al Farsha area, south-western Saudi Arabia. Saudi J Dent Res. 2016;7(2):127&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahboobi N, Agha-Hosseini F, Safari S, Lavanchy D, Alavian SM. Hepatitis B virus infection in dentistry: a forgotten topic. J Viral Hepatitis. 2010;17(5):307&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oosthuysen J, Potgieter E, Fossey A. Compliance with infection prevention and control in oral health-care facilities: a global perspective. Int Dent J. 2014;64(6):297&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekete G, Mulualem Belay G, Kassa SF. Prevalence of Primary Tooth Extraction and Its Associated Factors Among Under-Five-Year-Old Children in Debre Tabor Town, North-Central Ethiopia: Community-Based Cross-Sectional Study. Int J Gen Med. 2023;16:837&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bancha B, Kinfe AA, Chanko KP, Workie SB, Tadese T. Prevalence of hepatitis B viruses and associated factors among pregnant women attending antenatal clinics in public hospitals of Wolaita Zone, South Ethiopia. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(5):e0232653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weldebrhan D, Berhe H, Tesfay Y. Risk Factors for Hepatitis B Virus Infection in North Ethiopia: A Case-Control Study. Hepatic medicine: Evid Res. 2023;15:79&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asemahagn MA. Epidemiology of hepatitis B and C virus infections among patients who booked for surgical procedures at Felegehiwot referral hospital, Northwest Ethiopia. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(6):e0234822.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taye M, Daka D, Amsalu A, Hussen S. Magnitude of hepatitis B and C virus infections and associated factors among patients scheduled for surgery at Hawassa University comprehensive specialized Hospital, Hawassa City, southern Ethiopia. BMC Res Notes. 2019;12(1):412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassaw B, Abera N, Legesse T, Workineh A, Ambaw G. Sero-prevalence and associated factors of hepatitis B virus among pregnant women in Hawassa city public hospitals, Southern Ethiopia: Cross-sectional study design. SAGE open Med. 2022;10:20503121221140778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fite RO, Kooti W, Azeze GA, Tesfaye B, Hagisso SN. Seroprevalence and factors associated with hepatitis B virus infection in blood donors in Ethiopia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Virol. 2020;165(5):1039&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafiq M, Nadeem M, Sattar Z, Khan SM, Faheem SM, Ahsan I, et al. Identification of risk factors for hepatitis B and C in Peshawar, Pakistan. HIV AIDS (Auckl). 2015;7:223&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Global Hepatitis Report 2017. Geneva: World Health Organization. Licence: CC BY-NC-SA 3.0 IGO, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazzal Z, Sobuh I. Risk factors of hepatitis B transmission in northern Palestine: a case - control study. BMC Res Notes. 2014;7:190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed H, Eshetie A, Melese D. Prevalence of hepatitis B virus and associated risk factors among adults patients at Dessie referral and Kemise general hospitals in northeastern Ethiopia. Health Sci Rep. 2022;5(3):e659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemu AA, Zeleke LB, Aynalem BY, Kassa GM. Hepatitis B Virus Infection and Its Determinants among Pregnant Women in Ethiopia: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Infect Dis Obstet Gynecol. 2020;2020:9418475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awili HO, Gitao GC, Muchemi GM. Seroprevalence and Risk Factors for Hepatitis B Virus Infection in Adolescent Blood Donors within Selected Counties of Western Kenya. Biomed Res Int. 2020;2020:8578172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aderibigbe SA, Akinola D, Ameen HA, Olubiyi SK, Alatishe-Muhammed B, Osagbemi GK. Risk exposure to hepatitis B infection among senior secondary school students in a Metropolitan City of North-central Nigeria. Ethiop J Health Dev. 2016;30(2).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>