<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41798526</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence and Lifestyle Correlates of Premenstrual Syndrome and Its Severity Among Female University Students in Yemen: A Cross-Sectional Study of Dietary Habits and Qat Use.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e102968</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e102968</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e102968</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.102968</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Premenstrual syndrome (PMS) is a significant public health challenge that adversely affects the quality of life and academic performance of young women. While lifestyle factors are implicated in its etiology, evidence from populations experiencing protracted conflict and resource limitations is critically lacking. This study investigates the exploratory prevalence, symptom patterns, and modifiable lifestyle correlates of PMS severity among female university students in Yemen. Materials and methods In this cross-sectional study, 175 female students aged 15 to 25 from a university in Ibb, Yemen, were recruited between March and September 2024 via convenience sampling. Participants completed a validated Arabic-language questionnaire assessing demographic characteristics, lifestyle behaviors (including the culturally specific use of Qat), and the severity of 22 PMS symptoms using the Arabic Premenstrual Syndrome Scale. Moderate-to-severe PMS was classified using adapted diagnostic criteria from the Arabic Premenstrual Symptoms Screening Tool. The primary outcome was the total PMS severity score. Data were analyzed using bivariate tests and hierarchical multiple linear regression to identify associated factors while adjusting for demographic confounders (age and college level). The sample size provided sufficient power for regression analysis but was underpowered for high-precision prevalence estimation. Results The exploratory prevalence of moderate-to-severe PMS was 41.1% (n = 72). Psychological symptoms represented the most burdensome domain, with depressed mood (84.6%), anxiety (81.7%), and irritability (78.9%) being the most prevalent. In multivariable analysis, four modifiable factors were independently associated with higher PMS severity: overweight/obese status (&#x3b2; = 4.85, p = 0.008), rural residence (&#x3b2; = 3.78, p = 0.013), high fast-food consumption (&#x3b2; = 5.10, p = 0.004), and Qat chewing (&#x3b2; = 2.95, p = 0.015). Exploratory analysis revealed a significant interaction between overweight/obese status and fast-food intake (p = 0.018), indicating a synergistic association with symptom severity. The full model explained 40.1% of the variance in PMS severity. Conclusions This study reveals a high burden of PMS symptoms strongly linked to modifiable lifestyle and anthropometric factors among students in a conflict zone. The identification of Qat chewing and fast-food intake as key correlates underscores the importance of context-specific health behaviors. Although causal inference is limited by the cross-sectional design, these findings highlight a critical opportunity for nonpharmacological public health promotion, such as nutritional counseling and weight management programs, to potentially mitigate morbidity and improve the well-being of young women in humanitarian settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Alsharif et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alsharif</LastName><ForeName>Afaf</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Jiblah University for Medical and Health Sciences, Ibb, YEM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Qadasi</LastName><ForeName>Rofida</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, College of Midwifery, Jiblah University for Medical and Health Sciences, Ibb, YEM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alrefaey</LastName><ForeName>Rofaida</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, College of Midwifery, Jiblah University for Medical and Health Sciences, Ibb, YEM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alshahary</LastName><ForeName>Dinar</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, College of Midwifery, Jiblah University for Medical and Health Sciences, Ibb, YEM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Tahary</LastName><ForeName>Awsan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, College of Midwifery, Jiblah University for Medical and Health Sciences, Ibb, YEM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Roida</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, College of Midwifery, Jiblah University for Medical and Health Sciences, Ibb, YEM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aldoies</LastName><ForeName>A'ala'a</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, College of Midwifery, Jiblah University for Medical and Health Sciences, Ibb, YEM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">conflict and health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lifestyle medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutritional epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">premenstrual syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qat chewing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">university students</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">women&#x2019;s health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Research Ethics Committee of Jiblah University issued approval 29, dated March 1, 2024. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41798526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12965376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.102968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The phenomenology of premenstrual syndrome in female medical students: a cross sectional study. Balaha MH, Amr MA, Saleh Al Moghannum M, Saab Al Muhaidab N. Pan Afr Med J. 2010;5:4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2984319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21120003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premenstrual syndrome, prevalence, management and impact in quality of life of women residing in Al Qunfudhah, Saudi Arabia. Alrizqi RA, Alomari AS, Alsahabi RI, Alshehri RM, Alamri SS, Ahmed AM. J Adv Trends Med Res. 2025;2:566&#x2013;572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of premenstrual syndrome and its associated factors in Africa: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Andualem F, Melkam M, Takelle GM, et al. Front Psychiatry. 2024;15:1338304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10865226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38356911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of premenstrual tension syndrome on academic performance among female university students from the United Arab Emirates: a cross-sectional study. Omara EI, Salama RA, Tadross TM, Ahmed SK, Mohamed MG, Dewan SM, Islam MR. Health Sci Rep. 2024;7:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11464558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39391676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of premenstrual syndrome and its associations with dietary and other lifestyle factors among university female students in Dubai: a cross-sectional study. Al Sabbah H, Al Mutawa N, Assaf EA. Womens Health (Lond) 2024;20:17455057241260026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11143812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38819884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietary, psychological and lifestyle factors associated with premenstrual symptoms. AlQuaiz A, Albugami M, Kazi A, Alshobaili F, Habib F, Gold EB. Int J Womens Health. 2022;14:1709&#x2013;1722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9766474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36561605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Life style factors associated with premenstrual syndrome among El-Minia University Students, Egypt. Seedhom AE, Mohammed ES, Mahfouz EM. Int Scholar Res Notice. 2013;2013:617123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of premenstrual syndrome and its association with psychosocial and lifestyle variables: a cross-sectional study from Palestine. Abu Alwafa R, Badrasawi M, Haj Hamad R. BMC Womens Health. 2021;21:233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8178841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34090416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premenstrual syndrome, associated symptoms and evidence - based nursing management: a comparative study between rural Menoufia Governorate (Egypt) and Hodidha Governorate (Yemen) Gamal AM, Shahin MA. Am J Nurs Sci. 2015;4:84&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premenstrual syndrome is associated with dietary and lifestyle behaviors among university students: a cross-sectional study from Sharjah, UAE. Hashim MS, Obaideen AA, Jahrami HA, et al. Nutrients. 2019;11:1939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6723319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31426498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appropriate body-mass index for Asian populations and its implications for policy and intervention strategies. Lancet. 2004;363:157&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14726171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reliability and validity of the International Physical Activity Questionnaire (IPAQ) Hallal PC, Victora CG. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15076800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Validity of the International Physical Activity Questionnaire Short Form (IPAQ-SF): a systematic review. Lee PH, Macfarlane DJ, Lam TH, Stewart SM. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2011;8:115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3214824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22018588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Investigation of the frequency of premenstrual syndrome and its effect on quality of life in women aged 18-45 years working in Adana City Training and Research Hospital. Koca ZK, &#xc7;abuk A&#x130;, Yayla ME. J Eur Med Sci. 2024;5:14&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The experience and severity of premenstrual syndrome among a Saudi sample using a newly developed Arabic language scale. Algahtani H, Jahrami H. https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Twana-Rahim/publication/274746711_Which_Is_the_Optimal_Depression_Rating_Scale_to_Identify_DSM-IV_Depression_in_Schizophrenia_A_Diagnostic_Validity_Comparison_of_Five_Mood_Scales/links/572c574c08aef5d48d334361/Which-Is-the-Optimal-Depression-Rating-Scale-to-Identify-DSM-IV-Depression-in-Schizophrenia-A-Diagnostic-Validity-Comparison-of-Five-Mood-Scales.pdf#page=38 Arab J Psych. 2014;25:33&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premenstrual dysphoric disorder in Arab women: validation and cultural adaptation of the Arabic version of the premenstrual screening tool. Mahfoud Z, Emam R, Anchassi D, et al. Women Health. 2019;59:631&#x2013;645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30475684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The premenstrual symptoms screening tool (PSST) for clinicians. Steiner M, Macdougall M, Brown E. Arch Womens Ment Health. 2003;6:203&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12920618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moderate to severe premenstrual syndrome and contributing factors among university students in Palestine. Nazzal Z, Hasan N, Al-Sukhon M. https://staff.najah.edu/en/publications/10683/ J Commun Med. 2015;1:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence, impacts and medical managements of premenstrual syndrome among female students: cross-sectional study in College of Health Sciences, Mekelle University, Mekelle, northern Ethiopia. Tolossa FW, Bekele ML. BMC Womens Health. 2014;14:52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3994244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24678964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The prevalence, risk factors and lifestyle patterns of Jordanian females with premenstrual syndrome: a cross-sectional study. Ababneh MA, Alkhalil M, Rababa'h A. Future Sci OA. 2023;9:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10518813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37752914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of premenstrual syndrome (PMS) among female biomedical students in Kabul, Afghanistan: a cross-sectional study. Tawakoli MF, Abed A, Sakhi R. Int J Womens Health. 2025;17:1911&#x2013;1922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12235441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40630160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association between premenstrual syndrome and eating disturbance in college students: a cross-sectional study. Yoshinari Y, Morino S, Shinohara Y, et al. BMC Womens Health. 2024;24:330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11157793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38849887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premenstrual syndrome and its association with exposure to political violence, human insecurity, and well-being: a cross-sectional study among Palestinian adolescent refugees. Wakabayashi N, Sarhan MB, Fujiya R, Sugiyama D, Fuse R, Hammoudeh W, Ghandour R. Reprod Health. 2025;22:243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12659531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41310671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical, psychological, and behavioral symptoms of premenstrual syndrome in relation to body size and shape. Tutkuviene J, Gervickaite S, Sveikataite M, Stulgyte G, Rugelyte J, Simkunaite-Rizgeliene R, Ramasauskaite D. Am J Hum Biol. 2025;37:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12621079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41243766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Relationships between premenstrual syndrome (PMS) and diet composition, dietary patterns and eating behaviors. Oboza P, Ogarek N, W&#xf3;jtowicz M, Rhaiem TB, Olszanecka-Glinianowicz M, Koce&#x142;ak P. Nutrients. 2024;16:1911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11206370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38931266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of premenstrual syndrome in Pakistani women. Shershah S, Morrison JJ, Jafarey S. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1861351/ J Pak Med Assoc. 1991;41:101&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1861351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical activity and menstrual health symptoms and characteristics: a systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. Buchanan-Smith LI, Pang AH, Yeshitila NK, Parsons EN, Blodgett JM. J Womens Health (Larchmt) 2025;34:1535&#x2013;1547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40766994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of exercise on premenstrual symptoms: a systematic review. Yesildere Saglam H, Orsal O. Complement Ther Med. 2020;48:102272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31987230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of physical activity on premenstrual syndrome: a systematic review. Ayyub S, Agrawal M, Sharma V, Aravind A. Ann Neurosci. 2025;32:315&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11647822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39691311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association between smoking and premenstrual syndrome: a meta-analysis. Choi SH, Hamidovic A. Front Psychiatry. 2020;11:575526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7725748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33324253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smoking prevalence, attitudes and associated factors among students in health-related Departments of Community College in rural Yemen. Nasser AM, Salah BA, Regassa LT, Alhakimy AA, Zhang X. Tob Induc Dis. 2018;16:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6659497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31516430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobacco use and khat chewing among adolescents in Yemen: a large-scale school-based cross-sectional study. Al-Maweri SA, Alhajj MN, Al-Soneidar WA, et al. BMC Public Health. 2024;24:2406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11375828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39232711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The potential adverse effects of habitual use of Catha edulis (khat) Al-Habori M. Expert Opin Drug Saf. 2005;4:1145&#x2013;1154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16255671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effects of khat (Catha edulis) use on the genitourinary system: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ahmed F, Alnadhari I, Ghabisha S, et al. J Ethn Subst Abuse. 2024:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39092911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effects of khat use during pregnancy on perinatal and maternal outcomes: a meta-analysis. Yitayih Y, Vanderplasschen W, Vandewalle S, Rita VD, Gilbert L. Arch Womens Ment Health. 2023;26:11&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36689029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of chewing Khat leaves on human mood. Hassan NA, Gunaid AA, El-Khally FM, Murray-Lyon IM. https://research.ajman.ac.ae/en/publications/the-effect-of-chewing-khat-leaves-on-human-mood-2/ Saudi Med J. 2002;23:850&#x2013;853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12174239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The relationship between premenstrual dysphoric symptoms, perceived stress, and sleep quality among nursing students: a cross-sectional study. Innab A, Alenezi A, Khaled A, Dewan M, Mostafa M. Healthcare (Basel) 2025;13:2862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12652963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41302248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khat dependency and psychophysical symptoms among chewers in Jazan Region, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. El-Setouhy M, Alsanosy RM, Alsharqi A, Ismail AA. Biomed Res Int. 2016;2016:2642506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4789047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27022605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>