<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41598063</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of Wire Arc Additive Manufacturing Parameters on the Morphology, Microstructure, and Hardness of DSS2209 Single-Bead Deposited Layers.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">353</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma19020353</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study systematically investigates the effects of key process parameters in wire arc additive manufacturing (WAAM) on the surface morphology, geometric dimensions, microstructure, and microhardness of single-bead single-layer deposits fabricated from 2209 duplex stainless steel. Using a controlled variable approach, the influences of wire feed speed, travel speed, oscillation pattern, oscillation frequency, and oscillation amplitude on the deposition quality were examined. Experimental results indicate that wire feed speed and travel speed significantly affect the bead width, height, and fusion zone morphology, with optimal ranges identified as 4.5-6.5 m/min and 5-6 mm/s, respectively. Among the oscillation patterns, sinusoidal and figure-eight trajectories resulted in uniform deposition distribution and a refined microstructure, whereas the circular pattern led to fish-scale surface features and coarse grains. The optimal oscillation frequency and amplitude were determined to be 4 Hz and 4 mm, respectively, under which the deposits exhibited high surface quality, no defects other than the depression in the arc extinction zone, and the microhardness remains stable in the range of 280-290 HV. Comprehensive analysis indicates that investigating the influence of these process parameters on the morphology, microstructure, and hardness of DSS2209 single-bead deposits can effectively enhance the overall performance of WAAM-fabricated 2209 duplex stainless steel components, thereby providing a reliable foundation for subsequent multi-layer and multi-bead deposition.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Construction Hydraulic Robots of Anhui Higher Education Institutes, Tongling University, Tongling 244061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Metallurgical Engineering, Anhui University of Technology, Ma'anshan 243002, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Liang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Metallurgical Engineering, Anhui University of Technology, Ma'anshan 243002, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Long</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2756-1460</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Construction Hydraulic Robots of Anhui Higher Education Institutes, Tongling University, Tongling 244061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Metallurgical Engineering, Anhui University of Technology, Ma'anshan 243002, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Feihong</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Metallurgical Engineering, Anhui University of Technology, Ma'anshan 243002, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Dongsheng</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8794-1190</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Construction Hydraulic Robots of Anhui Higher Education Institutes, Tongling University, Tongling 244061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Youwen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Construction Hydraulic Robots of Anhui Higher Education Institutes, Tongling University, Tongling 244061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">2209 duplex stainless steel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hardness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microstructure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">process parameters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">single-bead deposition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surface morphology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wire arc additive manufacturing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>We declare that the authors have no conflicts of interest publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41598063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12843230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma19020353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma19020353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang D., Liu L., Tang J., Liu Y., Wei C., Weng Z., Shao J., Tan H., Zhou W., Neirinck B., et al. Recent advances on additive manufacturing of heterogeneous/gradient metallic materials via laser powder bed fusion. Int. J. Extreme Manuf. 2025;7:062007. doi: 10.1088/2631-7990/adf69e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2631-7990/adf69e</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X., Liu J., Yang Y., Bai J., Shuai C., Buhagiar J., Ning X. Laser powder bed fusion of biodegradable magnesium alloys: Process, microstructure and properties. Int. J. Extreme Manuf. 2024;7:022007. doi: 10.1088/2631-7990/ad967e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2631-7990/ad967e</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rui Z., Liu J., Shi Y., Wang D. Additive Manufacturing Method of lattice structure based on material manufacturing performance driven: Using machine learning to optimize manufacturing process. Addit. Manuf. Front. 2025:200258. doi: 10.1016/j.amf.2025.200258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amf.2025.200258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei H., Huang Y., Xiao Y., Liu F., Zhan J., Li H., Zeng J., Yang Y., Song C. Enhancing comprehensive properties of Zr&#x2013;2.5Nb fabricated via laser powder bed fusion through post-processing for medical implants. Addit. Manuf. Front. 2025:200291. doi: 10.1016/j.amf.2025.200291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amf.2025.200291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treutler K., Wesling V. The current state of research of wire arc additive manufacturing (WAAM): A review. Appl. Sci. 2021;11:8619. doi: 10.3390/app11188619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app11188619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah A., Aliyev R., Zeidler H., Krinke S. A review of the recent developments and challenges in wire arc additive manufacturing (WAAM) process. J. Manuf. Mater. Process. 2023;7:97. doi: 10.3390/jmmp7030097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jmmp7030097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill S.G., Jr. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Georgia Southern University; Statesboro, GA, USA: 2025. Pulsed Arc Additive Manufacturing of a Functionally Graded ER2209 Duplex Stainless Steel and HSLA-100 Structure: Morphology, Characterization, and Mechanical Performance; p. 2957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin W., Zhang C., Jin S., Tian Y., Wellmann D., Liu W. Wire arc additive manufacturing of stainless steels: A review. Appl. Sci. 2020;10:1563. doi: 10.3390/app10051563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app10051563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberini M., Astarita A., Campatelli G., Scippa A., Montevecchi F., Venturini G., Durante M., Squillace A. Selection of optimal process parameters for wire arc additive manufacturing. Procedia CIRP. 2017;62:470&#x2013;474. doi: 10.1016/j.procir.2016.06.124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procir.2016.06.124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omiyale B.O., Olugbade T.O., Abioye T.E., Farayibi P.K. Wire arc additive manufacturing of aluminium alloys for aerospace and automotive applications: A review. Mater. Sci. Technol. 2022;38:391&#x2013;408. doi: 10.1080/02670836.2022.2045549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02670836.2022.2045549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S.R., Khanna P. Wire arc additive manufacturing (WAAM): A new process to shape engineering materials. Mater. Today Proc. 2021;44:118&#x2013;128. doi: 10.1016/j.matpr.2020.08.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2020.08.030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pant H., Arora A., Gopakumar G.S., Chadha U., Saeidi A., Patterson A.E. Applications of wire arc additive manufacturing (WAAM) for aerospace component manufacturing. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2023;127:4995&#x2013;5011. doi: 10.1007/s00170-023-11623-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-023-11623-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling C., Li Q., Zhang Z., Yang Y., Zhou W., Chen W., Dong Z., Pan C., Shuai C. Influence of heat treatment on microstructure, mechanical and corrosion behavior of WE43 alloy fabricated by laser-beam powder bed fusion. Int. J. Extreme Manuf. 2023;6:015001. doi: 10.1088/2631-7990/acfad5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2631-7990/acfad5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosli N.A., Alkahari M.R., bin Abdollah M.F., Maidin S., Ramli F.R., Herawan S.G. Review on effect of heat input for wire arc additive manufacturing process. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2021;11:2127&#x2013;2145. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2021.02.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2021.02.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerv&#xe5;g M., S&#xf8;rensen C., Robertstad A., Br&#xf8;nstad B.M., Nyhus B., Eriksson M., Aune R., Ren X., Akselsen O.M., Bunaziv I. Additive manufacturing with superduplex stainless steel wire by CMT process. Metals. 2020;10:272. doi: 10.3390/met10020272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met10020272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini V.A., H&#xf6;gstr&#xf6;m M., Hurtig K., Valiente Bermejo M.A., Stridh L.E., Karlsson L. Wire-arc additive manufacturing of a duplex stainless steel: Thermal cycle analysis and microstructure characterization. Weld. World. 2019;63:975&#x2013;987. doi: 10.1007/s40194-019-00735-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40194-019-00735-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senthil T.S., Babu S.R., Puviyarasan M., Dhinakaran V. Mechanical and microstructural characterization of functionally graded Inconel 825-SS316L fabricated using wire arc additive manufacturing. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2021;15:661&#x2013;669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghaffari M., Nemani A.V., Shakerin S., Mohammadi M., Nasiri A. Grain refinement and strengthening of PH 13-8Mo martensitic stainless steel through TiC/TiB2 inoculation during wire arc additive manufacturing. Materialia. 2023;28:101721. doi: 10.1016/j.mtla.2023.101721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtla.2023.101721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang B., Liu M., Xu Y., Liu J., Chang Y., Wang P., Zhang L., Jiang L. Mechanical properties, microstructure, and theoretical modeling of CMT-WAAM 2209 duplex stainless steel. J. Constr. Steel Res. 2025;235:109892. doi: 10.1016/j.jcsr.2025.109892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcsr.2025.109892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang D., Kim N., Lee H. Effect of aging on the corrosion resistance of 2209 duplex stainless steel weldments. Met. Mater. Int. 2019;25:740&#x2013;750. doi: 10.1007/s12540-019-00247-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12540-019-00247-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma J., Taiwade R.V. Effect of welding processes and conditions on the microstructure, mechanical properties and corrosion resistance of duplex stainless steel weldments&#x2014;A review. J. Manuf. Process. 2017;25:134&#x2013;152. doi: 10.1016/j.jmapro.2016.11.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2016.11.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hachemi H., Azzaz M., Djeghlal M.E. Influence of temperature and chloride concentration on passivation mechanism and corrosion of a DSS2209 welded joint. J. Mater. Eng. Perform. 2016;25:4292&#x2013;4302. doi: 10.1007/s11665-016-2262-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11665-016-2262-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagasai B.P., Dwivedy M., Malarvizhi S., Balasubramanian V., Ramaswamy A., Snehalatha P., Vegesna N. Study on properties and microstructure of wire arc additive manufactured 2209 duplex stainless steel. Metallogr. Microstruct. Anal. 2024;13:519&#x2013;531. doi: 10.1007/s13632-024-01089-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13632-024-01089-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Peng K., Chen X. Duplex stainless steel 2209 with excellent properties deposited by plasma arc additive manufacturing without post heat-treatment: Favorable phase ratio and no &#x3c3;-phase. Arch. Civ. Mech. Eng. 2024;24:175. doi: 10.1007/s43452-024-00907-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43452-024-00907-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu K., Hua X., Shen C., Ding Y., Xin J., Mou G., Reddy K.M. Effect of variable polarity during cold metal transfer on microstructure and mechanical properties of directed energy deposition-arc built 2209 duplex stainless steel. Addit. Manuf. 2023;75:103750. doi: 10.1016/j.addma.2023.103750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addma.2023.103750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C.J., Liu T.G., Zhu P., Lu Y.H., Shoji T.J.M.S. Study on microstructure and tensile properties of 316L stainless steel fabricated by CMT wire and arc additive manufacturing. Mater. Sci. Eng. A. 2020;796:140006. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2020.140006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2020.140006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Cheng F., Wu S. Improvement of pitting corrosion resistance of wire arc additive manufactured duplex stainless steel through post-manufacturing heat-treatment. Mater. Charact. 2021;171:110743. doi: 10.1016/j.matchar.2020.110743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2020.110743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y., Lin X., Kang N., Huang W., Wang Z. Mechanical properties and precipitation behavior of the heat-treated wire + arc additively manufactured 2219 aluminum alloy. Mater. Charact. 2021;171:110735. doi: 10.1016/j.matchar.2020.110735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2020.110735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Y., Zhang H., Wang G., Wang H. Investigation of mechanical properties for hybrid deposition and micro rolling of bainite steel. J. Mater. Process. Technol. 2017;250:220&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu J., Wang X., Bai J., Ding J., Williams S., Zhai Y., Liu K. Deformation microstructures and strengthening mechanisms for the wire+arc additively manufactured Al-Mg4.5Mn alloy with inter-layer rolling. Mater. Sci. Eng. A. 2018;712:292&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Zhou Q., Wang K., Peng Y., Ding J., Kong J., Williams S. Study on microstructure and tensile properties of high nitrogen Cr-Mn steel processed by CMT wire and arc additive manufacturing. Mater. Des. 2019;166:107611. doi: 10.1016/j.matdes.2019.107611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2019.107611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao X., Waddell C., Hamilton C., Xiao H. Quality prediction and control in wire arc additive manufacturing via novel machine learning framework. Micromachines. 2022;13:137. doi: 10.3390/mi13010137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/mi13010137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8778228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35056302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X., Wang Y., Song H., Huang J., Zhang H., Chen X., Chen H., Li R. Effect of auxiliary longitudinal magnetic field on overlapping deposition of wire arc additive manufacturing. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2023;125:1383&#x2013;1401. doi: 10.1007/s00170-022-10609-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-022-10609-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P., Zhang H., Zhu H., Li Q., Feng M. Wire-arc additive manufacturing of AZ31 magnesium alloy fabricated by cold metal transfer heat source: Processing, microstructure, and mechanical behavior. J. Mater. Process. Technol. 2021;288:116895. doi: 10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2020.116895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2020.116895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xi W., Song B., Zhao Y., Yu T., Wang J. Geometry and dilution rate analysis and prediction of laser cladding. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2019;103:4695&#x2013;4702. doi: 10.1007/s00170-019-03932-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-019-03932-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>