<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41458837</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Drug-Induced Bullous Pemphigoid Triggered by Immune Checkpoint Inhibitor Opdualag in an Elderly Patient With Recurrent Metastatic Melanoma: A Case Report and Treatment Course With Dupilumab.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e97838</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e97838</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e97838</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.97838</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Bullous pemphigoid (BP) is an autoimmune subepidermal blistering disorder most commonly affecting elderly individuals and may be triggered by medications, including immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICIs). We present the case of an 81-year-old male with a history of recurrent metastatic melanoma previously treated with nivolumab and relatlimab (Opdualag), who developed a persistent pruritic eruption following initiation of dual PD-1/LAG-3 blockade. Despite discontinuation of immunotherapy six months before dermatologic evaluation and use of multiple topical corticosteroids and oral antihistamines, symptoms persisted. A punch biopsy and direct immunofluorescence demonstrated linear IgG and C3 deposition along the basement membrane zone, consistent with BP. On initial dermatologic examination, urticarial pink plaques involved approximately 50% of the body surface area, with lesions affecting the left medial inferior chest and epigastric region. Treatment with subcutaneous dupilumab was initiated alongside clobetasol 0.05% ointment. At follow-up, the patient reported persistent activity, receiving intramuscular triamcinolone acetonide and adjunctive therapies, including hydroxyzine, hydrocortisone 2.5% cream (for groin), and triamcinolone 0.1% ointment. By the second week of treatment, new plaques continued to appear daily without subjective improvement. Objective scoring with the Bullous Pemphigoid Disease Area Index was not obtained. This case illustrates the diagnostic and therapeutic challenges in managing ICI-induced BP and highlights the early course of dupilumab therapy, which had not yet produced clinical improvement at the time of last follow-up. Continued therapy was planned, and no adverse effects were reported.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Moreno et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moreno</LastName><ForeName>Brian A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dermatology, Lake Erie College of Osteopathic Medicine, Bradenton, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lutwak</LastName><ForeName>Moises</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dermatology, Larkin Community Hospital, South Miami, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lutwak</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dermatology, Larkin Community Hospital, South Miami, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kerdel</LastName><ForeName>Francisco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dermatology, Florida Academic Dermatology Center, Coral Gables, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">academic dermatology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bullous pemphigoid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical dermatology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complex medical dermatology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dermatology oncology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dermatology training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">general dermatology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immune checkpoint inhibitors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical dermatology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skin disease/dermatology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41458837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12741989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.97838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Association of bullous pemphigoid with immune checkpoint inhibitor therapy in patients with cancer: a systematic review. Asdourian MS, Shah N, Jacoby TV, Reynolds KL, Chen ST. JAMA Dermatol. 2022;158:933&#x2013;941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35612829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A retrospective, single-institution experience of bullous pemphigoid as an adverse effect of immune checkpoint inhibitors. Shalata W, Weissmann S, Itzhaki Gabay S, et al. Cancers (Basel) 2022;14:5451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9656349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36358869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The latest option: nivolumab and relatlimab in advanced melanoma. Albrecht LJ, Livingstone E, Zimmer L, Schadendorf D. Curr Oncol Rep. 2023;25:647&#x2013;657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10164023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37004702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autoimmune bullous skin disorders with immune checkpoint inhibitors targeting PD-1 and PD-L1. Naidoo J, Schindler K, Querfeld C, et al. Cancer Immunol Res. 2016;4:383&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5241697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26928461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Second-line therapies for steroid-refractory immune-related adverse events in patients treated with immune checkpoint inhibitors. Ruf T, Kramer R, Forschner A, et al. Eur J Cancer. 2024;203:114028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38652976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A case report of steroid-refractory bullous pemphigoid induced by immune checkpoint inhibitor therapy. Guan S, Zhang L, Zhang J, Song W, Zhong D. Front Immunol. 2022;13:1068978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9845947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36685586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of immune-related cutaneous adverse events with dupilumab. Kuo AM, Gu S, Stoll J, et al. J Immunother Cancer. 2023;11:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10255229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37270183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupilumab for bullous pemphigoid related to immune checkpoint inhibitors: a retrospective case series. Nykaza I, Moy A, Dusza SW, et al. Oncologist. 2025;30:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12404300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40638215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Case report: dupilumab therapy for immune checkpoint inhibitor-induced bullous pemphigoid enables dual immunotherapy initiation in progressive malignant melanoma. Gr&#xfc;ninger J, Lehr S, Meiss F, Rafei D, Schauer F. Front Oncol. 2025;15:1613552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12507624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41079106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of dupilumab in moderate-to-severe bullous pemphigoid. Zhang Y, Xu Q, Chen L, et al. Front Immunol. 2021;12:738907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8552038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34721404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Case report: dupilumab for the treatment of bullous pemphigoid. Wang M, Wang J, Shi B. Dermatol Ther. 2022;35:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35478478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nine cases of refractory bullous pemphigoid treated with dupilumab and literature review. Liang J, Abulikemu K, Maolidan Maolidan, et al. Int Immunopharmacol. 2023;116:109788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36731156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Real-world evaluation of the effectiveness and safety of dupilumab in bullous pemphigoid: an ambispective multicentre case series. Planella-Fontanillas N, Bosch-Amate X, Jim&#xe9;nez Ant&#xf3;n A, et al. Br J Dermatol. 2025;192:501&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39418120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupilumab as a novel therapy for bullous pemphigoid: a multicenter case series. Abdat R, Waldman RA, de Bedout V, et al. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2020;83:46&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32179082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effective response to high-frequency and prolonged dupilumab therapy in severe refractory bullous pemphigoid: a case study. Jiang X, Chen L, Zhu Y, Zhan S, Jin N, Cheng H. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2025;21:2503521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12520100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41063533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>