<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41900751</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An RSM-Based Investigation on the Process-Performance Correlation and Microstructural Evolution of Friction Stir Welded 7055 Al/2195 Al-Li Dissimilar T-Joints.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1260</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma19061260</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Friction stir welding (FSW) is a key technology for manufacturing T-shaped thin-walled structures and avoiding fusion welding defects. However, the quantitative relationship between its process parameters and the microstructure properties of the joint remains unclear. To address this, this study established regression models via response surface methodology (RSM) relating rotational speed (<i>w</i>), welding speed (<i>v</i>), and plunge depth (<i>h</i>) to the mechanical properties of T-joints. The optimal process parameters (400 rpm, 60 mm/min, 0.21 mm) were determined, under which the ultimate tensile strength (UTS) and weld nugget hardness (WNH) of the joint reached 74.1% (377 MPa) and 94.4% (153 Hv) of the base materials (BM) respectively, with <i>v</i> showing the most significant influence on joint mechanical properties. Microstructural observations revealed that from the BM to the stirring zone (SZ), the grains underwent a continuous evolution from coarsening, partial recrystallization to complete dynamic recrystallization (DRX). In the SZ, due to severe plastic deformation and high heat input, the continuous dynamic recrystallization (CDRX) was the dominant mechanism, and the grain was significantly refined. The heat input in the thermomechanical affected zone (TMAZ) is relatively low, mainly geometric dynamic recrystallization (GDRX). DRX-driven grain refinement was the primary strengthening factor in the joint, with hardness closely related to grain size. However, thermal cycling induced softening in the heat-affected zone (HAZ) and promoted the precipitation of brittle compounds such as Al<sub>3</sub>Mg<sub>2</sub> and MgZn<sub>2</sub>, which caused crack initiation exhibiting intergranular brittle fracture. Subsequently, under stress drive, it extends to SZ, mainly characterized by ductile fracture.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Binbin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sichuan Province Engineering Technology Research Center of General Aircraft Maintenance, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, 46 Nanchang Road, Guanghan 618307, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Aviation Engineering, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, 46 Nanchang Road, Guanghan 618307, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Yanjie</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sichuan Province Engineering Technology Research Center of General Aircraft Maintenance, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, 46 Nanchang Road, Guanghan 618307, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuo</LastName><ForeName>Duquan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5053-0400</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sichuan Province Engineering Technology Research Center of General Aircraft Maintenance, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, 46 Nanchang Road, Guanghan 618307, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Aviation Engineering, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, 46 Nanchang Road, Guanghan 618307, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Nannan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-1039-2867</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Luoyang College, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, Luoyang 471000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yuanxiu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sichuan Province Engineering Technology Research Center of General Aircraft Maintenance, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, 46 Nanchang Road, Guanghan 618307, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Haoran</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sichuan Province Engineering Technology Research Center of General Aircraft Maintenance, Civil Aviation Flight University of China, 46 Nanchang Road, Guanghan 618307, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Chong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9764-853X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Engineering, University of Tokyo, 7-3-1 Hongo, Bunkyo-ku, Tokyo 113-8656, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>NO. 24CAFUC07002, and NO. 25CAFUC04018</GrantID><Agency>the Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. GAMRC2023ZD03</GrantID><Agency>the Sichuan Province Engineering Technology Research Center of General Aircraft Maintenance</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>NO. 2025JDRC0020</GrantID><Agency>the Sichuan Science and Technology Program</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">T-joints</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dynamic recrystallization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">friction stir welding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mechanical properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microstructure evolution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">response surface methodology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41900751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13028133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma19061260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma19061260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang W., Yuan S., Qiao K., Wang K., Zhang S., Peng P., Zhang T., Peng H., Wu B., Yang J. Microstructure and nanomechanical behavior of friction stir welded joint of 7055 aluminum alloy. J. Manuf. Process. 2021;61:311&#x2013;321. doi: 10.1016/j.jmapro.2020.11.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2020.11.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Z., Jiang Y., Xu J., Yu L., Zhang H. Effects of Sc microalloying on mechanical properties and corrosion resistance of FSW joints of spray formed 7055 aluminum alloy. Mater. Charact. 2025;220:114633. doi: 10.1016/j.matchar.2024.114633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2024.114633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun G., Sun W., Zhou L., Luo S., Zhang Z., Liu D., Wu H. Microstructure, mechanical and fracture properties of friction stir welded 2195 Al-Li alloy joints. Chin. J. Aeronaut. 2024;37:345&#x2013;361. doi: 10.1016/j.cja.2023.10.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cja.2023.10.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feistauer E., Bergmann L., dos Santos J. Effect of reverse material flow on the microstructure and performance of friction stir welded T-joints of an Al-Mg alloy. Mater. Sci. Eng. A. 2018;731:454&#x2013;464. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2018.06.056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2018.06.056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu Y., Yang X., Xu J., Li J., Xiang S., Chen Z., Sanders R.E. Enhanced mechanical property and corrosion resistance of alloy 5182 FSW joints by Sc and Zr alloying. Mater. Charact. 2022;194:112412. doi: 10.1016/j.matchar.2022.112412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2022.112412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang J., Shi L., Wu C., Liu X., Zhao Y. Improving bonding strength of medium-thick Al-Cu dissimilar joint by a novel splat cooling assisted double side friction stir welding. Mater. Charact. 2024;211:113878. doi: 10.1016/j.matchar.2024.113878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2024.113878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel M.M., Badheka V.J. A review on friction stir welding (FSW) process for dissimilar aluminium to steel metal systems. Weld. Int. 2024;38:91&#x2013;115. doi: 10.1080/09507116.2023.2291064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09507116.2023.2291064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoyos E., Serna M.C. Basic Tool Design Guidelines for Friction Stir Welding of Aluminum Alloys. Metals. 2021;11:2042. doi: 10.3390/met11122042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met11122042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R., Tang W., Tian C., Yang X. Improving the microstructure and mechanical properties of 2A14-T4 aluminum alloy thick T-joints via stationary tool shoulder friction stir butt welding. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2024;130:635&#x2013;648. doi: 10.1007/s00170-023-12752-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-023-12752-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W., Li S., Nan Y., Bai X., Li W. Study on microstructure and corrosion behavior of T-joints of 2A12 and 2A97 aluminum alloys by FSW. Mater. Today Commun. 2024;41:110368. doi: 10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.110368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.110368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z.L., Wang B.B., Zhang Z., Xue P., Liu F.C., Ni D.R., Xiao B.L., Ma Z.Y. A feasible operational parameter window for enhancement of welding speed in friction stir welding of 2195-T8 Al&#x2013;Li alloy. Sci. Technol. Weld. Join. 2023;28:679&#x2013;688. doi: 10.1080/13621718.2023.2202039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13621718.2023.2202039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noh S., Ando M., Tanigawa H., Fujii H., Kimura A. Friction stir welding of F82H steel for fusion applications. J. Nucl. Mater. 2016;478:1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.jnucmat.2016.05.028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnucmat.2016.05.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vidakis N., Petousis M., David C., Sagris D., Mountakis N., Moutsopoulou A. The impact of process parameters and pin-to-shoulder ratio in FSW of polycarbonate: Welding forces and critical quality indicators. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2024;130:5457&#x2013;5477. doi: 10.1007/s00170-024-13033-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-024-13033-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao S., Zhou L., Zhang X., Zhang J., Li G., Zhao H. Microstructure and properties of friction stir welded joints for 6061-T6/7075-T6 dissimilar aluminum alloy. Trans. China Weld. Inst. 2022;43:35&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Gao Y., Zhang Q., Zhao H. Microstructure and mechanical properties of friction stir welded joint of 2A14-T4 aluminum alloy thick plate. Trans. China Weld. Inst. 2022;43:20&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;evik B., Ozcatalbas Y., G&#xfc;len&#xe7; B. Effect of welding speed on the mechanical properties and weld defects of 7075 Al alloy joined by FSW. Kovove Mater. 2016;54:241&#x2013;247. doi: 10.4149/km_2016_3_241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4149/km_2016_3_241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabraeili R., Jafarian H.R., Khajeh R., Park N., Kim Y., Heidarzadeh A., Eivani A.R. Effect of FSW process parameters on microstructure and mechanical properties of the dissimilar AA2024 Al alloy and 304 stainless steel joints. Mater. Sci. Eng. A. 2021;814:140981. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2021.140981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2021.140981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y., Li W., Liu X., Gao F., Yu Y., Vairis A. Evolution of microstructure, texture and mechanical properties of special friction stir welded T-joints for an &#x3b1; titanium alloy. Mater. Charact. 2021;177:111152. doi: 10.1016/j.matchar.2021.111152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2021.111152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zareie O., Mousavizade S.M., Ezatpour H.R., Zareie H., Farmanbar N. Effect of plunging depth and dwelling time on microstructure and mechanical properties of 6061 aluminum alloy welded by protrusion friction stir spot welding. Weld. World. 2020;64:785&#x2013;805. doi: 10.1007/s40194-020-00884-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40194-020-00884-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasath V.M.M., Kumar S.D., Raffic N.M. Effects of multi-objective optimization of friction stir welding process parameter on mechanical and ballistic properties of AA5754 aluminum alloy. J. Adhes. Sci. Technol. 2025;39:879&#x2013;909. doi: 10.1080/01694243.2024.2432392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01694243.2024.2432392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchouicha M., Mazari M., Slimane A., Hadji H., Bouchouicha B. Exploring parameter effects on friction stir welding (FSW): Experimental study and optimization analysis of 5052 aluminum alloy. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2025;138:1023&#x2013;1037. doi: 10.1007/s00170-025-15583-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-025-15583-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen K., Liu Y., Zeng G., Wang Z., Ge M., Li K. Parameter-mechanical properties regression model and fine grain strengthening phenomenon of Mg-9Al-Zn magnesium alloy weldments prepared by FSW. Int. J. Press. Vessel. Pip. 2025;214:105460. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpvp.2025.105460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpvp.2025.105460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakache H.E., Belattar A., May A., Merazga C., Chergui T., Lahmar H., Mokdad A. Optimization approach using L16 Taguchi design to improve FSW parameters for AA2017-T4 weld joints. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2025;138:4793&#x2013;4811. doi: 10.1007/s00170-025-15831-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-025-15831-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muchhadiya A., Kumar A., Kumari S., Saxena K.K., Bandhu D., Vora J., Reddy V.P. Optimization of friction stir welding process parameters for HDPE sheets using satisfaction function approach. Indian J. Eng. Mater. Sci. 2024;31:58&#x2013;66. doi: 10.56042/ijems.v31i1.561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.56042/ijems.v31i1.561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelhady S.S., Elbadawi R.E., Zoalfakar S.H. Multi-objective optimization of FSW variables on joint properties of AA5754 aluminum alloy using Taguchi approach and grey relational analysis. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2024;130:4235&#x2013;4250. doi: 10.1007/s00170-024-12969-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-024-12969-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dugar Y., Singh N., Kumar A., Vinayagamurthy G., Shanmuganatan S.P., Manjunath M. Microstructural studies and parametric optimization of dissimilar friction stir welds. Weld. Int. 2023;37:206&#x2013;225. doi: 10.1080/09507116.2023.2211283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09507116.2023.2211283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vahdati M., Moradi M., Shamsborhan M. Modeling and Optimization of the Yield Strength and Tensile Strength of Al7075 Butt Joint Produced by FSW and SFSW Using RSM and Desirability Function Method. Trans. Indian Inst. Met. 2020;73:2587&#x2013;2600. doi: 10.1007/s12666-020-02075-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12666-020-02075-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar J.P., Raj A., Kulandaivel A., Kumar L., V M., Ravichandran M., Rout I., Prasath S. Experimental analysis and RSM-based optimization of friction stir welding joints made of the alloys AA6101 and C11000. Mater. Res. Express. 2023;10:056512. doi: 10.1088/2053-1591/acd23d.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2053-1591/acd23d</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Y., Zuo D., Xu T., Ma G., Feng S., Fu H., Cao Z., Li W. Microstructure Characterization and Mechanical Properties of Dissimilar Al/Al-Li Alloy T-Joints Welded by Friction Stir Welding. Machines. 2025;13:852. doi: 10.3390/machines13090852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/machines13090852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sriram D., Rao V., Vijayakumar S., Peyyala A., Sri M.N.S., Rao N.S., Cheepurupalli N., Subbiah R. Microstructure, mechanical properties of dissimilar friction stir welded AA6063/AA5052 alloys, and optimization of process parameters using Box Behnken-TOPSIS approach. Met. Mater. 2024;62:363&#x2013;375. doi: 10.31577/km.2024.6.363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31577/km.2024.6.363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan R., Jayadeep U.B., Rajankutty M. Experimental and numerical investigation of process force evolution in Ultra-High Rotational Speed Micro FSW. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2023;130:2523&#x2013;2545. doi: 10.1007/s00170-023-12871-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-023-12871-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y., Meng X., Zhang Y., Cao J., Feng J. Micro friction stir welding of ultra-thin Al-6061 sheets. J. Mech. Work. Technol. 2017;250:313&#x2013;319. doi: 10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2017.07.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2017.07.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye T., Han Y., Zuo D., Fu H., Feng S., Gao C., Li W. Research on Creep Deformation of Dissimilar FSWed T-Joints Under Different Ultrasonic Vibration Modes: Experiment, Constitutive Model, and Simulation Verification. Materials. 2025;18:2275. doi: 10.3390/ma18102275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18102275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12112799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40429012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crushan R., Varthanan P.A. Optimization of dissimilar AA5052-H32 and AA5083-H111 aluminium FSW joints with scandium interfacial layer. Mater. Manuf. Process. 2023;38:1372&#x2013;1384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mothilal M., Kumar A. Optimization of friction stir welding process parameter in the joining of AA7075-T6/AA5083-O dissimilar aluminum alloy using response surface methodology. Int. J. Press. Vessel. Pip. 2024;211:105282. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpvp.2024.105282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpvp.2024.105282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P., Zhao S.-D., Zhang C.-W., Zang S.-L., Chen Z., Fei L.-Y., Wang Y.-F., Jiang H., Li F., Zhou H. Bonding mode and mechanical properties of keyhole-free friction stir rivet welded aluminum alloy joints. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2022;18:185&#x2013;199. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2022.02.097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2022.02.097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuk S., Shim S.H., Jeong M., Lee D., Lee K., Kim S.H., Lee S.Y., Han J.H. Micro/nanostructure evolution and deformation mechanisms in friction-stir-welded 7075 Al alloy: A comparative analysis of weld zones. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2025;36:5193&#x2013;5210. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2025.04.161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2025.04.161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L., Huang W., Ruan M., Chen Z. Effects of temperatures on microstructure evolution and deformation behavior of Fe&#x2013;32Ni by in-situ EBSD. Mater. Sci. Eng. A. 2023;875:145097. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2023.145097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2023.145097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long S.-L., Pan S.-S., Yang M., Luo X.-L., Ling M., Gui Q., Yi Y.-L. Effects of stirring friction on the microstructure, texture and mechanical properties of 7055 aluminum alloy. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2024;33:5413&#x2013;5424. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.10.102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.10.102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C.-Q., Deng J., Wang S.-X., Liu L.-L. A physical-based constitutive model to describe the strain-hardening and dynamic recovery behaviors of 5754 aluminum alloy. Mater. Sci. Eng. A. 2017;699:106&#x2013;113. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2017.04.086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2017.04.086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu H., Zhen L., Zhang B., Yang L., Chen J. Microstructure characterization of 7050 aluminum alloy during dynamic recrystallization and dynamic recovery. Mater. Charact. 2008;59:1185&#x2013;1189. doi: 10.1016/j.matchar.2007.09.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2007.09.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galiyev A., Kaibyshev R., Gottstein G. Correlation of plastic deformation and dynamic recrystallization in magnesium alloy ZK60. Acta Mater. 2001;49:1199&#x2013;1207. doi: 10.1016/S1359-6454(01)00020-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1359-6454(01)00020-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNelley T., Swaminathan S., Su J. Recrystallization mechanisms during friction stir welding/processing of aluminum alloys. Scr. Mater. 2008;58:349&#x2013;354. doi: 10.1016/j.scriptamat.2007.09.064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scriptamat.2007.09.064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X., Lu Y., Ning M., Zhou X., Chen J. Tailoring microstructural evolution and fracture damage behavior of a Mg&#x2013;Y&#x2013;Zn alloy during hot tensile deformation. Mater. Sci. Eng. A. 2023;871:144857. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2023.144857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2023.144857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prangnell P., Heason C. Grain structure formation during friction stir welding observed by the &#x2018;stop action technique&#x2019;. Acta Mater. 2005;53:3179&#x2013;3319. doi: 10.1016/j.actamat.2005.03.044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actamat.2005.03.044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo D.Q., Cao Z.Q., Cao Y.J., Huo L.B., Li W.Y. Thermal fields in dissimilar 7055 Al and 2197 Al-Li alloy FSW T-joints: Numerical simulation and experimental verification. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2019;103:3495&#x2013;3512. doi: 10.1007/s00170-019-03465-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-019-03465-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu X., Luan Y., Qiao J., Yang B., Zhang W., Liang S.Y. Optimization of process parameters in friction stir welding of 2219 aluminum alloy thick plate. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2023;129:4201&#x2013;4215. doi: 10.1007/s00170-023-12577-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-023-12577-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su J.-Q., Nelson T.W., Sterling C.J. Microstructure evolution during FSW/FSP of high strength aluminum alloys. Mater. Sci. Eng. A. 2005;405:277&#x2013;286. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2005.06.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2005.06.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P., Chen W., Chen J., Chen Z., Tang Y., Liu G., Huang B., Zhang Z. Microstructure Evolution and Mechanical Properties of Friction Stir Welded Al&#x2013;Cu&#x2013;Li Alloy. Acta Met. Sin. (Engl. Lett.) 2024;37:855&#x2013;871. doi: 10.1007/s40195-024-01674-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40195-024-01674-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q., Wang W., Peng P., Zhang T., Han P., Guan X.-H., Wang Z., Qiao K., Cai J., Wang K.-S. Microstructure evolution and strengthening mechanism of friction stir welded joint of 20 mm-thick AZ31 magnesium alloy. Trans. Nonferrous Met. Soc. China. 2023;33:3295&#x2013;3308. doi: 10.1016/S1003-6326(23)66334-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1003-6326(23)66334-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;am G., Mistikoglu S. Recent Developments in Friction Stir Welding of Al-alloys. J. Mater. Eng. Perform. 2014;23:1936&#x2013;1953. doi: 10.1007/s11665-014-0968-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11665-014-0968-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Liu Z., Ji S., Yue Y., Dong Z., Chen C. Active-passive radial-additive friction stir repairing of mechanical hole out of dimension tolerance of AZ31 magnesium alloy. J. Magnes. Alloys. 2023;11:3186&#x2013;3199. doi: 10.1016/j.jma.2021.12.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jma.2021.12.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu P., Li W., Vairis A., Chen D. Cyclic deformation behavior of friction-stir-welded dissimilar AA5083-to-AA2024 joints: Effect of microstructure and loading history. Mater. Sci. Eng. A. 2019;744:145&#x2013;153. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2018.12.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2018.12.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>