<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41233444</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integrated spherical phase change modules in concrete roofs enhance thermal performance in hot climates.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>39845</StartPage><MedlinePgn>39845</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">39845</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-23490-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Rising energy demand for building cooling exacerbates the environmental challenges associated with energy consumption. Incorporating phase change materials (PCMs) into building envelopes, particularly sun&#x2011;exposed roofs, can substantially reduce energy use. This study examines the thermal&#x2011;storage efficiency of metallic, spherical PCM modules embedded within a reinforced concrete roof, designed for hot&#x2011;climate conditions. The roof is divided into four distinct thermal zones: Zone&#x2011;1 (conventional concrete), Zone&#x2011;2 (empty spherical modules), and Zones 3-4 (modules filled with organic PCMs, organic mixture, 35&#xa0;&#xb0;C (OM35) and organic mixture, 37&#xa0;&#xb0;C (OM37)). Important thermal performance metrics, such as temperature distribution, heat flux, thermal load, time lag, decrement factor, key response index, and carbon emissions savings, are evaluated. Integrating spherical PCM modules led to significant improvements. These include an average reduction in indoor surface temperature of 10.2&#xa0;&#xb0;C, a decrease in cooling load of upto 69%, and a reduced decrement factor. In addition, OM35 showed a higher key response index and enhanced thermal performance than OM37. The findings demonstrate the practical viability of spherical PCM&#x2011;integrated roofs as a passive&#x2011;cooling strategy for buildings in hot climates.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huluka</LastName><ForeName>Abdin Bedada</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Ambo University, Ambo, Ethiopia. abdin.bedada@ambou.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muthulingam</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology Ropar, Rupnagar, 140 001, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cooling load</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy savings</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PCM-integrated roof</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Phase change materials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spherical PCM module</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Zone approach</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41233444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12615621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-23490-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-23490-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>International Energy Agency, The Future of Cooling&#x2013;Opportunities for energy efficient air conditioning, (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, M., Ibrahim, M. &amp; Saeed, T. Space cooling achievement by using lower electricity in hot months through introducing PCM-enhanced buildings. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>53</b>, 104506 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena, R., Rakshit, D., Kaushik, S.C. Review on PCM application for cooling load reduction in Indian buildings. in <i>Solar Energy: Systems, Challenges, and Opportunities</i> (Eds Tyagi, H., Chakraborty, P.R., Powar, S., Agarwal, A.K.) pp. 247&#x2013;275 (Springer Singapore, Singapore, 2020)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alnuaimi, A. N. &amp; Natarajan, S. The energy cost of cold thermal discomfort in the global south. <i>Buildings</i><b>10</b>(5), 93 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings10050093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chanda, P. R. &amp; Biswas, A. Carving a niche in building energy using modern vernacular house with passive wall materials&#x2013;A multi-criteria decision-making framework. <i>Energy</i><b>312</b>, 133539 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2024.133539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osibodu, S. J., Adeyinka, A. M. &amp; Mbelu, O. V. Phase change material integration in concrete for thermal energy storage: techniques and applications in sustainable building. <i>Sustain. Energy Res.</i><b>11</b>(1), 45 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40807-024-00138-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghamari, M. et al. Advancing sustainable building through passive cooling with phase change materials, a comprehensive literature review. <i>Energy Build.</i><b>312</b>, 114164 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enbuild.2024.114164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail, A., Wang, J., Salami, B. A., Oyedele, L. O. &amp; Otukogbe, G. K. Microencapsulated phase change materials for enhanced thermal energy storage performance in construction materials: A critical review. <i>Construct. Build. Mater.</i><b>401</b>, 132877 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacios, A. et al. A perspective on Phase change material encapsulation: Guidance for encapsulation design methodology from low to high-temperature thermal energy storage applications. <i>J. Energy Storage</i><b>72</b>, 108597 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2023.108597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivanathan, A. et al. Phase change materials for building construction: An overview of nano-/micro-encapsulation. <i>Nanotechnol. Rev.</i><b>9</b>(1), 896&#x2013;921 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/ntrev-2020-0067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez-Rodriguez, M., Alonso-Martinez, M., Suarez-Ramon, I. &amp; Garcia-Nieto, P. J. Numerical model for determining the effective heat capacity of macroencapsulated PCM for building applications. <i>Appl. Ther. Eng.</i><b>242</b>, 122478 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2024.122478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maier, M., Salazar, B., Unluer, C., Taylor, H. K. &amp; Ostertag, C. P. Thermal and mechanical performance of a novel 3D printed macro-encapsulation method for phase change materials. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>43</b>, 103124 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, E. et al. Experimental study of the thermal protection performance of the high reflectivity-phase change material (PCM) roof in summer. <i>Build. Environ.</i><b>164</b>, 106381 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.buildenv.2019.106381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y. K., Kim, M. Y., Chung, M. H. &amp; Park, J. C. PCM cool roof systems for mitigating urban heat island - an experimental and numerical analysis. <i>Energy Build.</i><b>205</b>, 109537 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enbuild.2019.109537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, J. et al. Thermal performance evaluation and optimal design of building roof with outer-layer shape-stabilized PCM. <i>Renew. Energy</i><b>145</b>, 2538&#x2013;2549 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2019.08.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xam&#xe1;n, J. et al. Thermal performance analysis of a roof with a PCM-layer under Mexican weather conditions. <i>Renew. Energy</i><b>149</b>, 773&#x2013;785 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2019.12.084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H., Li, J., Xi, C., Chen, W. &amp; Kong, X. Experimental and numerical study on the thermal performance of ventilated roof composed with multiple phase change material (VR-MPCM). <i>Energy Convers. Manage.</i><b>213</b>, 112836 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2020.112836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triano-Ju&#xe1;rez, J., Macias-Melo, E. V., Hern&#xe1;ndez-P&#xe9;rez, I., Aguilar-Castro, K. M. &amp; Xam&#xe1;n, J. Thermal behavior of a phase change material in a building roof with and without reflective coating in a warm humid zone. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>32</b>, 101648 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Yasiri, Q. &amp; Szab&#xf3;, M. Case study on the optimal thickness of phase change material incorporated composite roof under hot climate conditions. <i>Case Stud. Construct. Mater.</i><b>14</b>, e00522 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, P., Liu, Z., Xi, S., Zhang, Y. &amp; Zhang, L. Experiment and numerical simulation of an adaptive building roof combining variable transparency shape-stabilized PCM. <i>Energy Build.</i><b>263</b>, 112030 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enbuild.2022.112030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baskar, I. &amp; Chellapandian, M. Experimental and finite element analysis on the developed real-time form stable PCM based roof system for thermal energy storage applications. <i>Energy Build.</i><b>276</b>, 112514 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enbuild.2022.112514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, L. et al. Experiment verification and simulation optimization of phase change material cool roof in summer&#x2013;A case study of Chongqing China. <i>Energy</i><b>293</b>, 130613 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2024.130613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, H. et al. Experimental study of a novel Radiative cooling-Dual phase change material roof under hot summer and warm winter climate. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>95</b>, 110309 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.110309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godoy-Rangel, C., Rivera-Solorio, C. I. &amp; Gij&#xf3;n-Rivera, M. Thermal and energy performance assessment of naturally ventilated roofs with phase change material. <i>Energy Build.</i><b>319</b>, 114517 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enbuild.2024.114517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lingfan, S., Lin, G. &amp; Hongbo, C. Improved energy-saving performance of a small office building using coupled phase change materials and thermochromic (PCM/TC) roof system. <i>J. Energy Storage</i><b>100</b>, 113561 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2024.113561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contreras-Aguilar, J. A., Gij&#xf3;n-Rivera, M., Rivera-Solorio, C. I. &amp; Noh-Pat, F. Thermo-economic assessment of a double-layer phase-change material in building roofs in a semi-arid climate. <i>Ther. Sci. Eng. Progress</i><b>57</b>, 103093 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tsep.2024.103093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abass, P. J. &amp; Muthulingam, S. Thermal energy storage performance of biaxial voided RCC roof slab integrated with macroencapsulated PCM for passive cooling of buildings. <i>J. Energy Storage.</i><b>88</b>, 111478 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2024.111478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaffar Abass, P., Muthulingam, S. Comprehensive assessment of PCM integrated roof for passive building design: A study in energo-economics. <i>Energy Build</i>. 317 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulkarni, K. S., Singh, G. &amp; Premi, R. A detailed investigation on thermal performance and energy savings of cool roof systems for composite climates of India. <i>Advances in Building Energy Research</i><b>18</b>(5), 453&#x2013;474 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17512549.2024.2374553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tariku, F., Shang, Y. &amp; Molleti, S. Thermal performance of flat roof insulation materials: A review of temperature, moisture and aging effects. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>76</b>, 107142 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.107142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://www.meteoblue.com/en/weather/historyclimate/climatemodelled/ropar_ india_1257951 (Last accessed April 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abass, P. J. &amp; Muthulingam, S. Selection and thermophysical assessment of phase change materials (PCMs) for space cooling applications in buildings. <i>Numer. Heat Transfer Part A-Appl.</i><b>86</b>(8), 2423&#x2013;2445 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10407782.2023.2292183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z., Shi, G., Wang, S., Fang, X. &amp; Liu, X. Thermal energy storage cement mortar containing n-octadecane/expanded graphite composite phase change material. <i>Renew. Energy</i><b>50</b>, 670&#x2013;675 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2012.08.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sari, A. &amp; Kaygusuz, K. Thermal performance of a eutectic mixture of lauric and stearic acids as PCM encapsulated in the annulus of two concentric pipes. <i>Sol. Energy</i><b>72</b>(6), 493&#x2013;504 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0038-092X(02)00026-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitts, J.W. Final report on corrosion of aluminum embedded in concrete, U.S. Department of Commerce, National Bureau of Standards (1967).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathore, P. K. S., Shukla, S. K. &amp; Gupta, N. K. Yearly analysis of peak temperature, thermal amplitude, time lag and decrement factor of a building envelope in tropical climate. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>31</b>, 101459 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Yasiri, Q. &amp; Szab&#xf3;, M. Thermal performance of concrete bricks based phase change material encapsulated by various aluminium containers: An experimental study under Iraqi hot climate conditions. <i>J. Energy Storage</i><b>40</b>, 102710 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2021.102710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares, N. et al. Validation of different numerical models with benchmark experiments for modelling microencapsulated-PCM-based applications for buildings. <i>Int. J. Ther. Sci.</i><b>159</b>, 106565 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2020.106565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukai, J., Kanou, M., Kodama, Y. &amp; Miyatake, O. Thermal conductivity enhancement of energy storage media using carbon fibers. <i>Energy Convers. Manage.</i><b>41</b>(14), 1543&#x2013;1556 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0196-8904(99)00166-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrer, G., Sol&#xe9;, A., Barreneche, C., Martorell, I. &amp; Cabeza, L. F. Corrosion of metal containers for use in PCM energy storage. <i>Renew. Energy</i><b>76</b>, 465&#x2013;469 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2014.11.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, G. &amp; Han, Y. Numerical simulation on thermal characteristics of supercooled salt hydrate PCM for energy storage: Multiphase model. <i>Appl. Therm. Eng.</i><b>125</b>, 145&#x2013;152 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2017.07.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zayed, M. E. et al. Recent progress in phase change materials storage containers: Geometries, design considerations and heat transfer improvement methods. <i>J. Energy Storage</i><b>30</b>, 101341 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2020.101341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanmuganathan, R., Sekar, M., Praveenkumar, T. R., Pugazhendhi, A. &amp; Brindhadevi, K. Experimental investigation and numerical analysis of energy efficiency building using phase changing material coupled with reflective coating. <i>Int. J. Energy Res.</i><b>45</b>(12), 17279&#x2013;17290 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/er.5783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radha, S., Rao, B. N. Flexural behavior of reinforced concrete biaxial voided square slabs. <i>Aci Struct. J. 117</i>(5) (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena, R., Rakshit, D. &amp; Kaushik, S. C. Experimental assessment of Phase Change Material (PCM) embedded bricks for passive conditioning in buildings. <i>Renew. Energy</i><b>149</b>, 587&#x2013;599 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2019.12.081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, D. H. W., Lau, C. C. S. &amp; Lam, J. C. Standard skies classification using common climatic parameters. <i>J. Sol.Energy Eng.</i><b>126</b>(3), 957&#x2013;964 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.1740776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, S. et al. Experimental study on the influence of PCM container height on heat transfer characteristics under constant heat flux condition. <i>Appl. Therm. Eng.</i><b>172</b>, 115159 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2020.115159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shokouhmand, H. &amp; Kamkari, B. Experimental investigation on melting heat transfer characteristics of lauric acid in a rectangular thermal storage unit. <i>Exp. Thermal Fluid Sci.</i><b>50</b>, 201&#x2013;212 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.expthermflusci.2013.06.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzaei, P. A. &amp; Haghighat, F. Modeling of phase change materials for applications in whole building simulation. <i>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</i><b>16</b>(7), 5355&#x2013;5362 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2012.04.053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitagawa, H., Asawa, T. &amp; Hirayama, Y. Optimum window-opening control for naturally ventilated buildings with phase change materials in the hot and humid climate of Indonesia. <i>Build. Environ.</i><b>245</b>, 110898 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.buildenv.2023.110898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurt, H. The usage of air gap in the composite wall for energy saving and air pollution. <i>Environ. Prog. Sustain. Energy</i><b>30</b>(3), 450&#x2013;458 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ep.10486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhamare, D. K., Rathod, M. K., Banerjee, J. &amp; Ar&#x131;c&#x131;, M. Investigation of the effect of air layer thickness on the thermal performance of the PCM integrated roof. <i>Buildings</i><b>13</b>(2), 488 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings13020488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dlimi, M. et al. Energy performance and thickness optimization of hemp wool insulation and air cavity layers integrated in Moroccan building walls&#x2019;. <i>Sustain. Prod. Consump.</i><b>20</b>, 273&#x2013;288 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.spc.2019.07.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ar&#x131;c&#x131;, M., Bilgin, F., Ni&#x17e;eti&#x107;, S. &amp; Karabay, H. PCM integrated to external building walls: An optimization study on maximum activation of latent heat. <i>Appl. Therm. Eng.</i><b>165</b>, 114560 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2019.114560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhamare, D. K., Rathod, M. K. &amp; Banerjee, J. Proposal of a unique index for selection of optimum phase change material for effective thermal performance of a building envelope. <i>Sol. Energy</i><b>218</b>, 129&#x2013;141 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2021.02.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psomopoulos, C. S., Skoula, I., Karras, C., Chatzimpiros, A. &amp; Chionidis, M. Electricity savings and CO<sub>2</sub> emissions reduction in buildings sector: How important the network losses are in the calculation?. <i>Energy</i><b>35</b>(1), 485&#x2013;490 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2009.10.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhawan, S., Puram, r. CO<sub>2</sub> baseline database for the Indian power sector, Central Electricity Authority, Ministry of Power, Government on India, New Delhi, India, (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das, B. et al. Effect of the absorber surface roughness on the performance of a solar air collector: An experimental investigation. <i>Renew. Energy</i><b>152</b>, 567&#x2013;578 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2020.01.056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chanda, P.R., Biswas, A. Exploring window-to-wall ratios for an energy-efficient vernacular architecture under various climatic conditions: An MCDM, simulation and experimental based framework. Arab. J. Sci. Eng. 1&#x2013;25 (2025).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>