<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41841058</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Actinomycetoma Due to Nocardia brasiliensis: Recognition in Primary Care.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103509</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103509</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103509</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103509</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Mycetoma is a chronic, progressively destructive subcutaneous infection caused by aerobic filamentous bacteria (actinomycetoma) or true fungi (eumycetoma). It represents one of the most neglected tropical diseases, disproportionately affecting vulnerable populations in resource-limited rural settings. In Latin America, actinomycetoma predominates, most commonly caused by <i>Nocardia brasiliensis</i>. Delayed diagnosis is frequent due to its indolent course and limited awareness at the primary care level, often resulting in severe deformity, disability, or amputation. We report the case of a 43-year-old agricultural worker from rural Bolivia who presented with a two-year history of progressive, painless swelling of the right foot and ankle, associated with multiple draining sinus tracts extruding whitish grains. Based on the classic clinical triad and epidemiological context, mycetoma was suspected in the primary care setting. Direct microscopic examination supported actinomycetoma, and empirical antibiotic therapy was initiated. Culture later confirmed <i>Nocardia brasiliensis</i>. Histopathology demonstrated a basophilic grain surrounded by suppurative and granulomatous inflammation. This report underscores the critical role of primary care physicians in the early clinical recognition of mycetoma using basic diagnostic tools, particularly in endemic and underserved regions. Prompt identification and timely referral of actinomycetoma can substantially reduce morbidity, prevent irreversible tissue damage, and improve functional outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Mart&#xed;nez-Ortega et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;nez-Ortega</LastName><ForeName>Jes&#xfa;s Iv&#xe1;n</ForeName><Initials>JI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Histology, Autonomous University of Nuevo Leon, Monterrey, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dermatology, Dermatology Institute of Jalisco, Zapopan, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dermatology Service, General Zone Hospital 11, Mexican Institute of Social Security, Piedras Negras, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosas-Lezama</LastName><ForeName>Frida Itzel</ForeName><Initials>FI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, General Zone Hospital, Mexican Institute of Social Security, Merida, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Macias Quiroga</LastName><ForeName>Alejandra Nicole</ForeName><Initials>AN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dermatology Department, Hospital Obrero No 1, La Paz, BOL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">actinomycetoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic subcutaneous infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic delay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">family medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">latin america</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neglected tropical diseases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nocardia brasiliensis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">primary care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rural health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tropical medicine</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41841058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12989037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mycetoma: a clinical dilemma in resource limited settings. Emmanuel P, Dumre SP, John S, Karbwang J, Hirayama K. Ann Clin Microbiol Antimicrob. 2018;17:35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6085652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30097030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mycetoma: reviewing a neglected disease. Verma P, Jha A. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2019;44:123&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29808607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mycetoma and the environment. Fahal AH, Bakhiet SM. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2023;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10653480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37971968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mycetoma: the spectrum of clinical presentation. Fahal AH, Suliman SH, Hay R. Trop Med Infect Dis. 2018;3:14&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6161195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30274493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global sociodemographic, clinical, and epidemiological profiling of patients with mycetoma: a systematic review. Salah ME, Fearon Scales ML, Habib K, et al. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2025;19:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12617881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40811735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neglected endemic mycoses. Queiroz-Telles F, Fahal AH, Falci DR, Caceres DH, Chiller T, Pasqualotto AC. Lancet Infect Dis. 2017;17:0&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28774696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Disseminated cutaneous Mycobacterium chelonae infection in an immunocompetent patient. Martinez-Ortega JI, Perez-Hernandez FJ Sr, Rodriguez-Castellanos MA, Martinez-Jaramillo E, Guillermo-Herrera JC. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10484636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37692700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An immune-based therapeutical approach in an elderly patient with fixed cutaneous sporotrichosis. Mart&#xed;nez-Ortega JI, Franco-Gonzalez S, Ramirez Cibrian AG. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10901695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38425596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dermatological fungal neglected tropical diseases. Santos DWCL, Azevedo C, Queiroz-Telles F. Curr Fungal Infect Rep. 2025;19:6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12416368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40927623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical features of mycetoma and the appropriate treatment options. Agarwal P, Jagati A, Rathod SP, Kalra K, Patel S, Chaudhari M. Res Rep Trop Med. 2021;12:173&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8275212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34267575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mycetoma management: therapeutic challenges and the role of pharmacovigilance. Hussein SM, Saeed AA, Fahal AH. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2025;19:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12007666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39977423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>