<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41322328</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2950-4708</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of conservative dentistry and endodontics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Conserv Dent Endod</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative evaluation of compressive strength and antimicrobial activity of mineral trioxide aggregate incorporated with gold nanoparticles: An experimental <i>in vitro</i> study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1145</StartPage><EndPage>1150</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1145-1150</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/JCDE.JCDE_568_25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To determine the mechanical and biological enhancements of mineral trioxide aggregate (MTA) by evaluating the effect of incorporation of gold nanoparticles (AuNps) on the compressive strength and antimicrobial properties of MTA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTINGS AND DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This is an <i>in vitro</i> study to test the properties of MTA after the addition of AuNps. Two main groups were considered: (1) Group 1: MTA and (2) Group 2: MTA + AuNp for the testing of compressive strength and antimicrobial activity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUBJECTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">For the testing of compressive strength, both the groups with 7 samples each were subject to compressive load at day 1 and day 7 using Universal Testing Machine; considering a total sample size of 28 for testing the compressive strength. Antimicrobial activity of both the groups was evaluated against <i>Streptococcus mutans</i> through disk diffusion test using 7 agar plates. Prediffusion of the plates was done followed by incubation for 24 h followed by evaluation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STATISTICAL ANALYSIS USED" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Comparison of compressive strength was done using an independent sample <i>t</i>-test. Comparison of the mean zone of inhibition (ZOI) was done using ANOVA with <i>post hoc</i> Tukey's test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The mean compressive strength was significantly higher for Group 2 than Group 1 at day 7. There was no significant difference in the mean compressive strength between day 1 and 7 in MTA and MTA + AuNP, respectively. Group 2 showed a significantly greater mean ZOI in comparison to Group 1.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Addition of AuNps led to a significant improvement in the performance of MTA in the context of compressive strength and antimicrobial efficacy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Journal of Conservative Dentistry and Endodontics.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jagtap</LastName><ForeName>Manali Ajay</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Conservative Dentistry, Aesthetics and Endodontics, Manubhai Patel Dental College, Hospital and Research Centre, Vadodara, Gujarat, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arora</LastName><ForeName>Ankit Ved</ForeName><Initials>AV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Conservative Dentistry, Aesthetics and Endodontics, Manubhai Patel Dental College, Hospital and Research Centre, Vadodara, Gujarat, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kapoor</LastName><ForeName>Sonali Vinod</ForeName><Initials>SV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Conservative Dentistry, Aesthetics and Endodontics, Manubhai Patel Dental College, Hospital and Research Centre, Vadodara, Gujarat, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agrawal</LastName><ForeName>Urvashi Omprakash</ForeName><Initials>UO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Conservative Dentistry, Aesthetics and Endodontics, Manubhai Patel Dental College, Hospital and Research Centre, Vadodara, Gujarat, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Conserv Dent Endod</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918697474706676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2950-4708</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Compressive strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Streptococcus mutans</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gold nanoparticles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mineral trioxide aggregate</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41322328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12659899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/JCDE.JCDE_568_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JCDE-28-1145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Torabinejad M, Watson TF, Pitt Ford TR. Sealing ability of a mineral trioxide aggregate when used as a root end filling material. J Endod. 1993;19:591&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8151252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parirokh M, Torabinejad M. Mineral trioxide aggregate: A comprehensive literature review--Part III: Clinical applications, drawbacks, and mechanism of action. J Endod. 2010;36:400&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20171353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbari M, Zebarjad SM, Nategh B, Rouhani A. Effect of nano silica on setting time and physical properties of mineral trioxide aggregate. J Endod. 2013;39:1448&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24139272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torabinejad M, Hong CU, McDonald F, Pitt Ford TR. Physical and chemical properties of a new root-end filling material. J Endod. 1995;21:349&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7499973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunam D, Bode Y, Narra PM, Krishna CH, Reddy SN, Venkateshwarlu M. Comparative evaluation of apical microleakage of mineral trioxide aggregate, Biodentine, and Bio-C Repair as root-end filling materials using dye extraction method: An in vitro study. J Conserv Dent Endod. 2024;27:1305&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11823578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39959012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashwini Ts, Hosmani N, Patil CR, Yalgi VS. Role of mineral trioxide aggregate in management of external root resorption. J Conserv Dent. 2013;16:579&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3842733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24347899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobankara FK, Altin&#xf6;z HC, Ergani O, Kav K, Belli S. In vitro antibacterial activities of root-canal sealers by using two different methods. J Endod. 2004;30:57&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14760911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dammaschke T, Gerth HU, Z&#xfc;chner H, Sch&#xe4;fer E. Chemical and physical surface and bulk material characterization of white ProRoot MTA and two Portland cements. Dent Mater. 2005;21:731&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15935463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meraji N, Bolhari B, Sefideh MR, Niavarzi S. Prevention of tooth discoloration due to calcium-silicate cements: A review. Dental Hypotheses. 2019;10:4&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karunakaran S, Praveen N, Selvandran KE, Leburu A, Madhuram K, Kumar AR. Effectiveness of mineral trioxide aggregate and its modifications in inducing dentin bridge formation during pulp capping: A systematic review. J Conserv Dent Endod. 2025;28:222&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12007749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40256699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed MS, Saeed MG, Hasan NH. Immunohistochemical study of mixing mineral trioxide aggregate with hyaluronic acid as a pulp-capping agent in dog teeth. J Conserv Dent Endod. 2024;27:485&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11205164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38939541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravana KR, Vijayalakshmi R. Nanotechnology in dentistry. Indian J Dent Res. 2006;17:62&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17051869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozak ST, Ozkan P. Nanotechnology and dentistry. Eur J Dent. 2013;7:145&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3571524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23408486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansoori GA. Principles of nanotechnology:molecular-based study of condensed matter in small systems. 1st ed. Singapore: World Scientific; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rieth M. Nano-engineering in Science and Technology: An Introduction to the World of Nano-design. 1st ed. Singapore: World Scientific; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abiodun-Solanke I, Ajayi D, Arigbede A. Nanotechnology and its application in dentistry. Ann Med Health Sci Res. 2014;4:S171&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4212373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25364585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>She WJ, Zhang FQ. Comparison of the antibacterial activity on oral pathogens among six types of nano-silver base inorganic antibacterial agents. Shanghai Kou Qiang Yi Xue. 2003;12:356&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14966611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrestha A, Shi Z, Neoh KG, Kishen A. Nanoparticulates for antibiofilm treatment and effect of aging on its antibacterial activity. J Endod. 2010;36:1030&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20478460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sondi I, Salopek-Sondi B. Silver nanoparticles as antimicrobial agent: A case study on E. coli as a model for gram-negative bacteria. J Colloid Interface Sci. 2004;275:177&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15158396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan Zarrabi M, Javidi M, Naderinasab M, Gharechahi M. Comparative evaluation of antimicrobial activity of three cements: New endodontic cement (NEC), mineral trioxide aggregate (MTA) and Portland. J Oral Sci. 2009;51:437&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19776512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razmi H, Aminsobhani M, Bolhari B, Shamshirgar F, Shahsavan S, Shamshiri AR. Calcium enriched mixture and mineral trioxide aggregate activities against Enterococcus faecalis in presence of dentin. Iran Endod J. 2013;8:191&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3808680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24171028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asgary S, Kamrani FA. Antibacterial effects of five different root canal sealing materials. J Oral Sci. 2008;50:469&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19106476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esteki P, Jahromi MZ, Tahmourespour A. In vitro antimicrobial activity of mineral trioxide aggregate, Biodentine and calcium-enriched mixture cement against Enterococcus faecalis, Streptococcus mutans, and Candida albicans using the agar diffusion technique. Dent Res J (Isfahan) 2021;18:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8122692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34084290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basturk FB, Nekoofar MH, G&#xfc;nday M, Dummer PM. The effect of various mixing and placement techniques on the compressive strength of mineral trioxide aggregate. J Endod. 2013;39:111&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23228268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunne NJ, Orr JF, Mushipe MT, Eveleigh RJ. The relationship between porosity and fatigue characteristics of bone cements. Biomaterials. 2003;24:239&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12419624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bichile ML, Mahaparale R, Mattigatti S, Wahane KD, Raut SV. Push-out bond strength of mineral trioxide aggregate with addition of titanium dioxide, silver, and silicon dioxide nanoparticles: An in vitro comparative study. J Conserv Dent. 2022;25:541&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9733541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36506620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres MR, Slate AJ, Ryder SF, Akram M, Iruzubieta CJC, Whitehead KA. Ionic gold demonstrates antimicrobial activity against Pseudomonas aeruginosa strains due to cellular ultrastructure damage. Arch Microbiol. 2021;203:3015&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8289768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathiyaraj S, Suriyakala G, Dhanesh Gandhi A, Babujanarthanam R, Almaary KS, Chen TW, et al. Biosynthesis, characterization, and antibacterial activity of gold nanoparticles. J Infect Public Health. 2021;14:1842&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34690096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salesa B, Ferr&#xfa;s-Manzano P, Tu&#xf1;&#xf3;n-Molina A, Cano-Vicent A, Assis M, Andr&#xe9;s J, et al. Study of biological properties of gold nanoparticles: Low toxicity, no proliferative activity, no ability to induce cell gene expression and no antiviral activity. Chem Biol Interact. 2023;382:110646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37506996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>