<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41408615</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6874</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC women's health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Womens Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Determinants of access to maternal healthcare services among women in the Wolaita Zone, Southern Ethiopia: an unmatched case&#x2012;control study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>599</StartPage><MedlinePgn>599</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">599</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12905-025-04105-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Maternal mortality is a significant public health problem, particularly in sub-Saharan Africa, including Ethiopia. However, evidence on the determinants of access to maternal healthcare services is inadequate in Ethiopia. Therefore, this study aimed to identify the determinants of access to maternal healthcare services among women in southern Ethiopia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We conducted a community-based unmatched case&#x2012;control study between April 15 and May 15, 2023. A sample size of 360 (120 cases and 240 controls) was selected using a systematic random sampling technique. The collected data were entered into EpiData software and exported to SPSS software version 25. The profiles of the participants were explored using descriptive analysis. Binary logistic regressions and multivariate analysis were used.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Access to maternal healthcare services was greater among women who perceived a <i>need</i> for maternity healthcare (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;7.96 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.49&#x2013;18.21)), who were <i>able to seek</i> maternity healthcare (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;6.08 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.12&#x2013;15.68)), who were <i>able to reach</i> maternity healthcare (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.46 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.89&#x2013;10.52)), who were <i>able to pay</i> for maternity healthcare (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.41 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.54&#x2013;7.56)), and who perceived maternal healthcare services as <i>approachable</i> (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.89 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.32&#x2013;6.37)) and had greater access to maternal healthcare services than their counterparts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Health sector administrators at the Woreda and Zonal levels better to work on maternal healthcare services advocacy, improving women&#x2019;s economic capacity, and empowering them in decision making.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12905-025-04105-3.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hidoto</LastName><ForeName>Kassahun Tafesse</ForeName><Initials>KT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, College of Health Sciences and Medicine, Wolaita Sodo University, Wolaita Sodo, Addis Ababa, Southern Ethiopia Regional State, Ethiopia. kassahun_tafesse@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gidebo</LastName><ForeName>Kassa Daka</ForeName><Initials>KD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, College of Health Sciences and Medicine, Wolaita Sodo University, Wolaita Sodo, Addis Ababa, Southern Ethiopia Regional State, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koyra</LastName><ForeName>Mengistu Meskele</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, College of Health Sciences and Medicine, Wolaita Sodo University, Wolaita Sodo, Addis Ababa, Southern Ethiopia Regional State, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dom&#xed;nguez</LastName><ForeName>Maria Luisa Guillen</ForeName><Initials>MLG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Preventive Medicine and Public Health, Food Science, Toxicology, and Legal Medicine, University of Valencia, Valencia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Womens Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088690</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6874</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval and consent to participate: We conducted the study in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki for research ethics. The authors obtained ethical approval from the Wolaita Sodo University Institutional Review Board on February 23/2023 with reference number SGS/256/23. We obtained written permission from the Wolaita Zone Health Department to conduct the study. We also obtained verbal informed consent from each of the study participants. We collected the data anonymously to maintain the confidentiality of the respondents&#x2019; responses. Conflict of interest: The authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41408615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12709740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-025-04105-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12905-025-04105-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jacobs B, Ir P, Bigdeli M, Annear PL, Van Damme W. Addressing access barriers to health services: an analytical framework for selecting appropriate interventions in low-income Asian countries. Health Policy Plann. 2011;27(4):288&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapol/czr038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21565939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berhan Y, Berhan A, Commentary. Reasons for persistently high maternal and perinatal mortalities in ethiopia: part III-Perspective of the three delays model. Ethiop J Health Sci. 2014;24(0 Suppl):137&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ejhs.v24i0.12S</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4249213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25489188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. World Health Organization (WHO). World Health Report 2005: Make Every Mother and Child Count. WHO report. 2005;2005(Geneva).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ICF, EPHIEEa. Ethiopia mini demographic and health survey 2019:. Key indicators Rockville. Maryland, USA: EPHI and ICF; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getnet Bayih Endalew LAGATG. Intention to use Maternity Waiting Home among Pregnant Women in Jimma District, Southwest Ethiopia. Global Journals Inc (USA). 2016;16 (6).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UN-DESA. Sustainable development goal 3: ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages,2017. Sustainable Dev Knowl Platf. 2017.&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health FDRoEMo. Policy and practice information for action Better Information Better Decision Better Health. EFDR Q Health Bull. 2013;5(1).&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levesque JF, Harris MF, Russell G. Patient-centred access to health care: conceptualising access at the interface of health systems and populations. Int J Equity Health. 2013;12:18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1475-9276-12-18</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3610159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23496984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell SM, Roland MO, Buetow SA. Defining quality of care. Social Science &amp; Medicine (1982). 2000;51(11):1611-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11072882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell O. Access to health care in developing countries: breaking down demand side barriers. Cadernos De Saude Publica. 2007;23(12):2820&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0102-311X2007001200003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18157324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penchansky R, Thomas JW. The concept of access: definition and relationship to consumer satisfaction. Med Care. 1981;19(2):127&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005650-198102000-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7206846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters DH, Garg A, Bloom G, Walker DG, Brieger WR, Rahman MH. Poverty and access to health care in developing countries. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2008;1136:161&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1196/annals.1425.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17954679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stekelenburg J, Jager BE, Kolk PR, Westen EH, van der Kwaal A, Wolffers IN. editor. Health care seeking behaviour and utilisation of traditional healers health services in Kalabo District, Zambia . Health Policy. 2005; 71(1):67-87. 10.1016/j.healthpol.2004.05.008. PPMID: 1556 3994.&#xa0;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15563994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts C, Zimmerman C. Violence against women: global scope and magnitude. Lancet (London England). 2002;359(9313):1232&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(02)08221-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11955557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ensor T, Cooper SL. Overcoming barriers to health service access: influencing the demand side. Health Policy Plann. 2004;19 2:69&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapol/czh009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14982885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekonnen , Y ared, and Asnakech Mekonnen. Utilization of maternal health care services in Ethiopia . Calverton, Maryland, USA: ORC Macro.&#xa0;2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurji JGL, Gebrethadik LA, Wordofa MA , Sudhaker M, Asefa Y, Kiros G, Mamo A, Bergen N, Asfaw S, Bedru KH, Labonte R, Taljaard M, Kulkarni M. Factors associated with maternity waiting home use among women in Jimma Zone, Ethiopia: a multilevel cross-sectional analysis. BMJ Open. 2019;9(8):e028210. 10.1136/bmjopen-2018. PMID: 31467047; PMCID: PMC6720516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6720516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31467047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson AK, Abdalla S, Serenska A, Demeke B, Darmstadt GL. Association between maternity waiting home stay and obstetric outcomes in Yetebon, Ethiopia: a mixed-methods observational cohort study. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2021;21(1) :482. 10.1186/s2884-021-03913-3. PMID: 34217232; PMCID: PMC8254337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8254337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34217232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JB, Collison AH, Richardson D, Kwofie G, Senah KA, Tinkorang EK. The maternity waiting home concept: the Nsawam, Ghana experience. The Accra Team. Int J Gynecol Obstet. 1997;59 Suppl 2:S165-72. 10.1016/s0020-7292(97)00162-8. PMID:9389628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9389628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiruneh G, Taye B, Karim A, Betemariam W, Fessecha N, Wereta T, Lemango E. Maternity waiting homes in rural health centers of ethiop: the situation, women&#x2019;s experiences and challenges. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry EG, Semrau K, Hamer DH, Vian T, Nambao M, Mataka K, et al. The influence of quality maternity waiting homes on utilization of facilities for delivery in rural Zambia. Reproductive Health. 2017;14(1):68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12978-017-0328-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5450262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28558800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott NA, Vian T, Kaiser JL, Ngoma T, Mataka K, Henry EG, et al. Listening to the community: using formative research to strengthen maternity waiting homes in Zambia. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(3):e0194535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0194535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5854412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29543884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agency CCS. ICPS-Population-Projection-2007-2037-produced. 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akter S, Rich JL, Davies K, Inder KJ. Access to maternal healthcare services among Indigenous women in the Chittagong hill Tracts, bangladesh: A cross-sectional study. BMJ Open. 2019;9(10) e033224. 10.1136/bmjopen-2019-033224. PMID: 31662407; PMCID PMC6830644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6830644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31662407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Workineh GHD. Factors affecting utilization of postnatal care service in Amhara region, Jabitena District, Ethiopia. Sci J Public Health. 2014;2:169&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11648/j.sjph.20140203.15</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hordofa MAS, Berhanu M, Lemiso H. Postnatal care service utilization and associated factors among women in Dembecha district, Northwest Ethiopia. Sci J Public Health. 2015;3:689&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebede KM, Mihrete KM. Factors influencing women&#x2019;s access to the maternity waiting home in rural Southwest Ethiopia: a qualitative exploration. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2020;20(1):296. 10.1186/s12884-020-02988-8. PMID; 32408875; PMCID : MPC7226938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7226938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32408875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dadi LS, Berhane M, Ahmed Y, et al. Maternal and newborn health services utilization in Jimma Zone, Southwest Ethiopia: a community based cross-sectional study. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2019;19:178.&#xa0;10.1186/s12884-019-2335-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6530050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31113407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teshome D, Abera M, Nigatu M (2022). Maternity waiting home Utilization and associated factors among women who gave birth in the Digelu and Tijo district of the Arsi Zone, Oromia, Ethiopia. Reprod Syst Sex Disord. 11:326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peteros Y. , Assegid S, Shaweno T, Markos M. Utilization of pregnant Women waiting area and associated factors among mothers at Damboya district Kembata Tembaro zone Southern Ethiopia. Pan Afr Med J. 2023;46:89. 10.11604/pamj.2023.46.89.33071. PMID; 38314233; PMCID: PMC10837281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10837281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38314233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiwanuka SN, Ekirapa EK, Peterson S, Okui O, Rahman MH, Peters D, et al. Access to and utilisation of health services for the poor in uganda: a systematic review of available evidence. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg. 2008;102(11):1067&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trstmh.2008.04.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18565559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyei-Nimakoh M, Carolan-Olah M, McCann TV. Access barriers to obstetric care at health facilities in sub-Saharan Africa&#x2014;a systematic review. Syst Reviews. 2017;6(1):110. 10.1186/s13643-017-0503-x. PMID: 28587676; PMCID: PMC5461715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5461715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28587676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geleto A, Chojenta C, Musa A, Loxton D. Barriers to access and utilization of emergency obstetric care at health facilities in sub-Saharan africa: a systematic review of literature. Syst Rev. 2018;7 (1):183. 10.1186/s13643-018-0842-2. PMID: 3024808; PMCID: PMC6234634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6234634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30424808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cu A, Meister S, Lefebvre B, Ridde V. Assessing healthcare access using the levesque&#x2019;s conceptual framework- a scoping review. Int J Equity Health. 2021;20(1):116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12939-021-01416-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8103766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33962627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mramba L, Nassir FA, Ondieki C, Kimanga D. Reasons for low utilization of a maternity waiting home in rural Kenya. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2010;108(2):152&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijgo.2009.08.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19892347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiferaw BB, Modiba LM. Why do women not use skilled birth attendance service? An explorative qualitative study in North West Ethiopia. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2020;20(1):633. 10.1186/s12884-020-03312-0. PMID; 33076867; PMCID: PMC7574439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7574439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33076867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah R, Rehfuess EA, Maskey MK, Fischer R, Bhandari PB, Delius M. Factors affecting institutional delivery in rural Chitwan district of Nepal: a community-based cross-sectional study. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2015;15:27. 10.1186/s12884-015-0454-y. PMID: 25884164; PMCID: PMC4339648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4339648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25884164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iftikhar ul Husnain M, Rashid M, Shakoor U. Decision-making for birth location among women in pakistan: evidence from National survey. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2018;18(1):226. 10.1186/s12884-018-1844-8. PMID: 29898695; PMCID: PMC6000961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6000961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29898695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birmeta KDY, Woldeyohannes D. Determinants of maternal health care utilization in Holeta town, central Ethiopia. BMC Health Serv Res. 2013;13(1):256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6963-13-256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3710264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23822155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klootwijk L, Chirwa AE, Kabaghe AN, van Vugt M. Challenges affecting prompt access to adequate uncomplicated malaria case management in children in rural primary health facilities in Chikhwawa Malawi. BMC Health Ser v Res. 2019;19(1):735. 10.1186/s12913-019-4544-9. PMID: 31640676; PMCID: PMC 6805512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6805512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31640676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corscadden L, Levesque JF, Lewis V, Breton M, Sutherland K, Weenink JW, et al. Barriers to accessing primary health care: comparing Australian experiences internationally. Aust J Prim Health. 2017;23(3):223&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/PY16093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27927280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyathi L, Tugli AK, Tshitangano TG, Mpofu M. Investigating the accessibility factors that influence antenatal care services utilisation in Mangwe district, Zimbabwe. Afr J Prim Health Care Family Med. 2017;9(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5506496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28697619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. M. Factors and perceptions that influence women to use a Maternal Waiting Home (MWH) in Ifakara, Tanzania. 2013. (unpublished thesis)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obola TD, Leimengo TY, Herut BM (2022). Intention to use maternity waiting home and determinant factors among pregnant women in Misrak Badewacho District, Hadiya Zone, southern Ethiopia: A cross sectional study. Reprod Syst Sex disord. 11:322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahab R, Sakellariou D. Barriers to accessing maternal care in low income countries in Africa: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(12):4292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7344902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32560132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jowett M. Safe motherhood interventions in low-income countries: an economic justification and evidence of cost effectiveness. Health Policy Plann. 2000;53:201&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10996067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nigussie AA, Emiru AA, Demilew YM, Mersha EA. Factors associated with knowledge on obstetric danger signs among women who gave birth within 1 year in Bahir Dar City administration, North West, Ethiopia. BMC Res Notes. 2019;12 (1):177. 10.1186/s13104-019-4212-5. PMID: 30917864; PMCID: PMC6437945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6437945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30917864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekie M, Taklual W. Delivery place preference and its associated factors among women who deliver in the last 12 months in Simada district of Amhara Region, Northwest Ethiopia: a community based cross sectional study. BMC Res Notes. 2019;12(1):114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6397443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30823885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebreyesus H, Mamo A, Teweldemedhin M, Gidey B, Hdush Z, Birhanu Z. Experiences of homeless women on maternity health service utilization and associated challenge in Aksum town, Northern Ethiopia. BMC Health Serv Res. 2019;19 (1):359. 10.1186/s12913-019-4201-3. PMID: 31170981; PMCID: PMC6554879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6554879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31170981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>