<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41180263</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2628-5452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Analytical science advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Anal Sci Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Phosphorus Fractionation and Soil Properties across Smallholder Land Uses in the South Ethiopia Regional State.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70053</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70053</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e70053</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ansa.70053</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Soil fertility decline and land degradation pose significant challenges to agricultural production and food security for smallholder farmers in South Ethiopia. The widespread deficiency and limited plant availability of phosphorus (P), often locked in less available forms despite its presence. This study aimed to examine P fractionation characteristics across different land uses, encompassing home gardens, forage land, grazing land, cropland, and woodlot in Wolaita Zone, South Ethiopia regional state. Soil samples were collected from two depths (0-20&#xa0;cm and 20-40&#xa0;cm) and analyzed for physicochemical properties and P fractions using the modified Hedley sequential method. The result indicated that the home gardens exhibited the highest pH, soil organic carbon (SOC), total nitrogen (TN), available phosphorus (AP), exchangeable bases (Ca, K, Na), and cation exchange capacity (CEC) across both soil depths. These higher values are attributed to intensive management, continuous organic amendment application, and diverse plant species. The analysis of soil P fractions revealed that home gardens had the highest labile P, while cropland showed higher NaOH-Pi and residual P. The Corg:Po ratio indicated the highest values in grazing lands, suggesting potential P immobilization, and the lowest in croplands, potentially favouring mineralization. Total inorganic P (TPi) was highest in home gardens, supporting enhanced mineralization, whereas total organic P (TPo) showed significant variation influenced by management. The soil pH, SOC, TN, AP, Ca<sup>+2</sup>, and K<sup>+</sup> were positively significant with the various P fractions, while exchangeable acidity showed an inverse relationship. Thus, home gardens demonstrated enhanced P availability and better soil fertility. The findings indicate the critical need for site-specific nutrient management strategies to optimize phosphorus use efficiency, improve soil health, and enhance agricultural sustainability in South Ethiopia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Analytical Science Advances published by Wiley&#x2010;VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lulu</LastName><ForeName>Mekdes</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Agriculture Department of Plant Science Wachemo University Hossana Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Anal Sci Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918334986206676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2628-5452</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">P availability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">home garden</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sequential extraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">soil fertility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">soil organic carbon</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41180263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12578600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ansa.70053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ANSA70053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gashu Adam A. and Wenedem Agegnehu A., &#x201c;Challenges of Smallholder Farming in Ethiopia and Opportunities by Adopting Climate&#x2010;Smart Agriculture,&#x201d; Agriculture 11, no. 3 (2021): 192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lelago A., Mamo T., and Abegaz A., &#x201c;Review on Challenges to Soil Fertility in Ethiopia,&#x201d; Global Scientific Journal 9, no. 3 (2021): 1923&#x2013;1930.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retta A., Gebrehiwot S., Abera S., and Tolosa T., &#x201c;The Dynamics Between Soil Erosion, Nutrient Variability, Land Use, Topography, and Implications for Food Security in Southern Ethiopia,&#x201d; Cogent Food &amp; Agriculture 10, no. 1 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melkamu Ho S., &#x201c;Using Ethio&#x2010;SIS Fertility Maps In Southern Ethiopia,&#x201d; Research Journal of Agricultural Sciences 15, no. 2 (2024): 118&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayenew M., Mamo T., and Abegaz A., &#x201c;Forms and Distribution of Phosphorus in Selected Soils of Northwestern Ethiopia,&#x201d; Journal of Soil Science and Environmental Management 9, no. 4 (2018): 84&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiflu A., Beyene S., and Jeff S., &#x201c;Fractionation and Availability of Phosphorus in Acid Soils of Hagereselam, Southern Ethiopia Under Different Rates of Lime,&#x201d; Chemical and Biological Technologies in Agriculture 4 (2017): 21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asaye Z., Kim D.&#x2010;G., Yimer F., et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effects of Combined Application of Compost and Mineral Fertilizer on Soil Carbon and Nutrient Content, Yield, and Agronomic Nitrogen Use Efficiency in Maize&#x2010;Potato Cropping Systems in Southern Ethiopia,&#x201d; Land 11, no. 6 (2022): 1&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maharjan S., Maranguit D., and Buol S., &#x201c;Phosphorus Fractions and Their Availability in Different Land Use Systems in the Mid&#x2010;Hills of Nepal,&#x201d; Journal of Nepal Agricultural Research Council 4, no. 1 (2018): 1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiessen H. and Moir J. O. (1993). Characterization of Available P by Sequential Extraction. In Carter M. R. (Ed.), &#x201c;Soil Sampling and Methods of Analysis&#x201d;. (Lewis Publishers, 1993): 75&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed M., Mamo T., and Abegaz A., &#x201c;Phosphorus Fractions and Their Relationship with Soil Properties in Some Selected Soils of Ethiopia,&#x201d; Journal of Soil Science and Environmental Management 9, no. 3 (2018): 57&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maranguit D., Guillaume T., and Kuzyakov Y., &#x201c;Land&#x2010;Use Change Affects Phosphorus Fractions in Highly Weathered Tropical Soils,&#x201d; Catena 149 (2017): 385&#x2013;393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chopra S. H. and Kanwar J. S., Analytical Agricultural Chemistry (Kalyani Publisher, Ludhiana, 1976).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen S. R., Cole C. V., Watanabe F. S., and Dean L. A., &#x201c;Estimation of Available Phosphorus in Soils by Extraction with Sodium Carbonate,&#x201d; USDA Circular 939 (1954): 1&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson M. L., Soil Chemical Analysis (Prentice Hall, 1958).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walkley A. and Black I. A., &#x201c;An Examination of the Degtjareff Method for Determining Soil Organic Matter and a Proposed Modification of The Chromic Acid Titration Method,&#x201d; Soil Science 37 (1934): 29&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman H., &#x201c;Cation Exchange Capacity,&#x201d; Methods of Soil Analysis Part 2: Chemical and Microbiological Properties (1965).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowell D. L., Soil Science: Methods &amp; Applications (Longman Scientific &amp; Technical, 1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedley M. J., Stewart J. W. B., and Chauhan B. S., &#x201c;Changes in Inorganic and Organic Soil Phosphorus Fractions Induced by Cultivation Practices and by Laboratory Incubations,&#x201d; Soil Science Society of America Journal 46, no. 5 (1982): 970&#x2013;976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy J. and Riley J. P., &#x201c;A modified Single Solution Method for the Determination of Phosphate in Natural Waters,&#x201d; Analytica Chimica Acta 27 (1962): 31&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SAS (Statistical Analysis System) Institute, SAS/STAT User's Guide , SAS Institute, Inc., 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lal R., &#x201c;Soil Carbon Sequestration to Mitigate Climate Change,&#x201d; Geoderma 123, no. 1&#x2010;2 (2004): 1&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Heide C. M. J., van Mansfeld M. J. M., and Hazeu G. W., &#x201c;Abandoned Cropland: Opportunity for Nature Conservation or Challenge for Regional Economic Development?&#x201d; European Planning Studies 18, no. 9 (2010): 1475&#x2013;1494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Li S., Li X., Wang Y., and West T. O., &#x201c;The Contribution of Agricultural Land to Carbon Sequestration in China: A Review and Synthesis,&#x201d; Global Change Biology 24, no. 1 (2018): 18&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez M. A., Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;P&#xe9;rez J. A., Arriaga J. D., and Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;Oliva F., &#x201c;Effects of Management on Soil Carbon, Nitrogen, and Microbial Biomass in Home Gardens of a Tropical Dry Forest,&#x201d; Agroforestry Systems 91, no. 1 (2017): 89&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Agriculture Organization . (2020). Soil Organic Carbon: A Critical Component of Soils and Food Security. Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimsen J., Smith J., and Jones A., &#x201c;Nutrient Cycling in Home Gardens: Implications for Soil Health,&#x201d; Agricultural Systems 178 (2020): 102871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson G. P. and Vitousek P. M., &#x201c;Nitrogen in Agriculture: Balancing the Costs of Fertilizer with Ecological Consequences,&#x201d; Nature Reports 34 (2009): 97&#x2013;125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;ere&#xf1;a D., Gichangi A., Kimetu J., Abreu D. L. C., and Reyes H., &#x201c;Nutrient Flows and Balances in Smallholder Farming Systems of the Western Highlands of Kenya: Impacts of Crop&#x2010;livestock Integration and Soil Amendments,&#x201d; Geoderma 395 (2021): 115082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharpley A. N., McDowell R. W., and Kleinman P. J. A., &#x201c;Optimizing Phosphorus Management in Agricultural Systems: A Review,&#x201d; Agricultural Systems 118 (2013): 1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretty J., Morison J., and Hine R., &#x201c;Sustainable Agriculture and the Environment in the UK,&#x201d; Environmental Science &amp; Policy 8, no. 5 (2005): 60&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W. and He Y., &#x201c;Fertilizer and Soil Management Practices That Improve Fertility and Sustainable Crop Production,&#x201d; Agronomy Journal 111, no. 5 (2019): 2330&#x2013;2345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sims J. T., &#x201c;Soil Properties and Sustainability,&#x201d; Sustainable Agriculture Reviews 28 (2017): 123&#x2013;145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez P. A., Properties and Management of Soils in the Tropics, 2nd ed. (Cambridge, UK: Cambridge University Press, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tekalign S. and Yared A., &#x201c;Effects of Integrated Soil Fertility Management Practices on Soil Physicochemical Properties and Yield of Wheat in Endegagn District, Gurage Zone, Southern Ethiopia,&#x201d; Journal of Soil Science and Environmental Management 8, no. 3 (2017): 56&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebede S. and Gebreselassie S., &#x201c;Modeling Soil Loss and Identifying Priority Areas for Soil Conservation Planning in Fincha'a Watershed, Horo Guduru Wollega Zone, Ethiopia,&#x201d; International Soil and Water Conservation Research 6, no. 3 (2018): 209&#x2013;221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marschner P., Marschner's Mineral Nutrition of Higher Plants. 3rd ed. (Academic Press, 2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negash M. and Dechassa N., &#x201c;Influence of Traditional Farming Practices on Soil Fertility Status in the Highlands of Ethiopia,&#x201d; World Journal of Agricultural Sciences 9, no. 6 (2013): 469&#x2013;478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lal R., &#x201c;Restoring Soil Quality for a Better Environment,&#x201d; Soil Science Society of America Journal 79, no. 6 (2015): 1841&#x2013;1850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mengel K. and Kirkby E. A., Principles of Plant Nutrition. 5th ed. (Kluwer Academic Publishers, 2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havlin J. L., Tisdale S. L., Nelson W. L., and Beaton J. D., Soil Fertility and Fertilizers: An Introduction to Nutrient Management. 8th ed. (Pearson, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad D., Hafeez F., Alharby H. F., et al., &#x201c;Changes in Land Use Systems Alter the Phosphorus Nutrition and Associated Soil Fertility Status,&#x201d; Polish Journal of Environmental Studies 29, no. 6 (2020): 3975&#x2013;3982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng S., Zhang J., He J., Wang S., Sun Y., and Wei R., &#x201c;Response of Soil Phosphorus Fractions to Land Use Change in the Subalpine Ecosystems of Southwest China,&#x201d; Ecological Indicators 144 (2022): 109432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melese A., Gebrekidan H., Yli&#x2010;Halla M., and Yitaferu B., &#x201c;Phosphorus Status, Inorganic Phosphorus Forms, and Other Physicochemical Properties of Acid Soils of Farta District, Northwestern Highlands of Ethiopia,&#x201d; Applied and Environmental Soil Science (2015), 10.1155/2015/748390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2015/748390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y. S., &#x201c;Responses of Root Architecture Development to Low Phosphorus Availability: A Review,&#x201d; Annals of Botany 112, no. 3 (2023): 391&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3698383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23267006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonfa D., Kitila G., and Tufa M., &#x201c;Effects of Different Land Use Types on Selected Soil Physicochemical Properties at Laga Gur&#x2010;Micro Watershed, Central Highland of Ethiopia,&#x201d; Journal of Agriculture, Food and Natural Resources 3, no. 1 (2025): 6&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed W., Jing H., Kaillou L., et al., &#x201c;Changes in Phosphorus Fractions Associated With Soil Chemical Properties Under Long&#x2010;term Organic and Inorganic Fertilization in Paddy Soils of Southern China,&#x201d; PLoS One 14, no. 5 (2019): e0216881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6510419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31075143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lulu M., Lemma B., and Melese A., &#x201c;Soil Organic Carbon and Nutrients in Smallholding Land Uses in Southern,&#x201d; Journal of Plant Nutrition and Soil Science 183 (2020): 69&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharyya P., Chakrabarti K., Chakraborty A., and Nayak D. C., &#x201c;Effect of Municipal Solid Waste Compost on Phosphorous Content of Rice Straw and Grain Under Submerged Condition,&#x201d; Archive of Agronomy and Soil Science 51, no. 4 (2005): 363&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatiboni L. C., Brunetto G., Rheinheimer D. S., and Kamisnki J. (2013). Fracionamento Qu&#xed;mico e Formas de F&#xf3;sforo no Solo: Uso e Limita&#xe7;&#xf5;es. In Ara&#xfa;jo A. P. &amp; Alves B. J. R. (Eds.), &#x201c;T&#xf3;picos em Ci&#xea;ncia Do Solo&#x201d;. (Sociedade Brasileira De Ci&#xea;ncia Do Solo, 2013): 141&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menzies N. W., &#x201c;Phosphorus in soils,&#x201d; Soil fertility manual. Queensland Department of Primary Industries and Fisheries (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chimdi A., Martti E., and Kari Y., &#x201c;Sequential Fractionation Patterns of Soil Phosphorus Collected from Different Land Use Systems of Dire Inchini District, West Shawa Zone, Ethiopia,&#x201d; American Eurasian Journal of Science Research 9, no. 3 (2014): 51&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Desta G., Mengistu K., and Kebede M., &#x201c;Linking Soil Quality Indicators to Phosphorus Availability Across Different Land Management Systems in the Ethiopian Highlands,&#x201d; <i>Land Degradation &amp; Development</i> (2024): pp&#x2013;pp. <i>X</i>(Y).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tellen V. and Yerokun O., &#x201c;Influence of Long&#x2010;Term Land Use Changes on Soil Phosphorus Fractions in Tropical Ecosystems,&#x201d; Soil Use and Management 40, no. 1 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady N. C. and Weil R. R., The Nature and Properties of Soils. 15th ed. (Pearson Education, Inc, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Li Q., and Zhang W., &#x201c;Interactions Between Soil Organic Carbon, Nitrogen, and Phosphorus Cycling: A Review,&#x201d; Journal of Environmental Quality 52, no. 1 (2023): 35&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng L., Liu Y., and Chen R., &#x201c;Effects of Agricultural Management Practices on Soil Phosphorus Forms and Availability: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Agricultural Ecosystems &amp; Environment 358 (2023): 108711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebede M. and Desta G., &#x201c;Soil Phosphorus Fractions and Their Relationship with Soil Physicochemical Properties Under Contrasting Land Uses in Southern Ethiopia,&#x201d; Environmental Science and Pollution Research 30, no. 35 (2023): 84482&#x2013;84496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mengistu K. and Desta G., &#x201c;Assessment of Soil Phosphorus Pools and Their Influencing Factors in Different Land Use Types of Ethiopia,&#x201d; Nutrient Cycling in Agroecosystems 128, no. 2 (2024): 227&#x2013;244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tekalign S. and Desta G., &#x201c;Organic Matter Dynamics and Nutrient Stoichiometry in Relation to Phosphorus Cycling in Tropical Soils,&#x201d; Geoderma Regional (2024): 39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abate E. and Desta G., &#x201c;Impact of Land Use Change on Soil Properties and Nutrient Dynamics in Agricultural Landscapes of Ethiopia,&#x201d; Journal of Soil Science and Environmental Management 15, no. 2 (2024): 37&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>