<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41760765</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-5373</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>240</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>British dental journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br Dent J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The influence of oral health on sports performance: an interdisciplinary perspective.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>277</StartPage><EndPage>283</EndPage><MedlinePgn>277-283</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41415-025-9348-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sports performance is a multifactorial concept determined by the interplay of physical, technical, tactical, and psychological factors. While its measurement is straightforward in metrical sports (e.g., athletics or swimming), it is more complex in team or aesthetic disciplines. In recent years, the role of oral health has gained attention as a potentially modifiable factor influencing athletic performance. This paper provides a comprehensive overview of how sports performance is defined and measured - particularly in explosive and endurance sports - and explores the impact of oral health on performance outcomes. Evidence from systematic reviews and observational studies shows consistent associations between poor oral health (e.g., periodontal disease, caries, malocclusion) and reduced objective performance metrics such as V&#x307;O<sub>2</sub> max, power output, speed, and agility, as well as self-reported reductions in training capacity and competitive performance. Potential mechanisms include systemic inflammation, impaired nutrition, altered microbiomes, psychological burden, and altered sensorimotor control. These pathways highlight the relevance of oral health in both recovery and performance optimisation. Future research in sports dentistry should adopt an interdisciplinary approach, using validated outcome measures, clearly defined athlete populations, and co-produced study designs involving athletes and support teams to enhance relevance and generalisability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hollander</LastName><ForeName>Karsten</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Interdisciplinary Exercise Science and Sports Medicine, MSH Medical School Hamburg, Germany. karsten.hollander@medicalschool-hamburg.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eshkol-Yogev</LastName><ForeName>Inbar</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Periodontology, Eastman Dental Institute, UCL, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zech</LastName><ForeName>Astrid</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Movement Science and Exercise Physiology, University of Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buti</LastName><ForeName>Jacopo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Periodontology, Eastman Dental Institute, UCL, London, UK; Centre for Oral Health and Performance, Eastman Dental Institute, UCL, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Needleman</LastName><ForeName>Ian</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Periodontology, Eastman Dental Institute, UCL, London, UK; Centre for Oral Health and Performance, Eastman Dental Institute, UCL, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br Dent J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7513219</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0007-0610</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009909" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oral Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Ethics declaration. The authors declare no conflicts of interest. KH is Editor for the German Journal of Sports Medicine and Associate Editor for BMJ Open Sports and Exercise Medicine. KH is the head team physician of the German Athletics Federation (DLV). IN leads the UCL Centre for Oral Health and Performance, is a Faculty member for the International Olympic Committee Diploma in Sports Medicine and is a Scientific Advisor to the German Athletics Federation (DLV). Guest Editor, Ian Needleman, was not involved in the peer review process of this manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41760765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12948669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41415-025-9348-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41415-025-9348-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>T M, O'Donoghue P, de Eira Sampaio A J. <i>Routledge Handbook of Sports Performance Analysis</i>. London: Routledge, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay A K A, Stellingwerff T, Smith E S <i>et al</i>. Defining training and performance caliber: a participant classification framework. <i>Int J Sports Physiol Perform</i> 2022; <b>17:</b> 317&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34965513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edouard P, Iatropoulos S, Velebova K <i>et al</i>. National medical teams during European Athletics championships from 2009 to 2024: composition, gender distribution, and influence on team performance. <i>Sports Med Open</i> 2025; DOI:10.1186/s40798-025-00864-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12081799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40372657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns A, Collins D. Interdisciplinary practice in performance sport: A scoping review of evidence of collaboration. <i>Eur J Sport Sci</i> 2023; <b>23:</b> 1877&#x2013;1891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37042174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U M. What does a sports dentist do all day. <i>Br Dent J</i> 2025; <b>240; 04:</b> 263-270</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41760763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher J, Ashley P, Needleman I. Oral health screening for sport. <i>Br Dent J</i> 2025; <b>240; 04:</b> 223-227</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12948672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41760757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher J, Ashley P, Needleman I. Implementation of a behavioural change intervention to enhance oral health behaviours in elite athletes: a feasibility study. <i>BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med</i> 2020; DOI: 10.1136/bmjsem-2020-000759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7304795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32577302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes D C, Ellefsen S, Baar K. Adaptations to endurance and strength training. <i>Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med</i> 2018; DOI: 10.1101/cshperspect.a029769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5983157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28490537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Close G L, Hamilton D L, Philp A <i>et al</i>. New strategies in sport nutrition to increase exercise performance. <i>Free Radic Biol Med</i> 2016; <b>98:</b> 144&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26855422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausswirth C, Mujika I, physique Indsedl&#xe9;. Recovery for performance in sport: Human Kinetics 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Kempe M, Brink M <i>et al</i>. Effectiveness of recovery strategies after training and competition in endurance athletes: an umbrella review. <i>Sports Med Open</i> 2024; <b>10:</b> 55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11098991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38753045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Halson S, Burke L M <i>et al</i>. An integrated multifactorial approach to periodization for optimal performance in individual and team sports. <i>Int J Sports Physiol Perform</i> 2018; <b>13:</b> 538&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29848161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasper K. Sports training principles. <i>Curr Sports Med Rep</i> 2019; <b>18:</b> 95&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30969230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raglin J S. Psychological factors in sport performance: the Mental Health Model revisited. <i>Sports Med</i> 2001; <b>31:</b> 875&#x2013;890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11665914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iso-Ahola S E. Intrapersonal and interpersonal factors in athletic performance. <i>Scand J Med Sci Sports</i> 1995; <b>5:</b> 191&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7552764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopp A, Jekauc D. The influence of emotional intelligence on performance in competitive sports: a meta-analytical investigation. <i>Sports</i> 2018; DOI: 10.3390/sports6040175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6316207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30551649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabzevari F, Samadi H, Ayatizadeh F <i>et al</i>. Effectiveness of mindfulness-acceptance-commitment based approach for rumination, cognitive Flexibility and sports performance of elite players of beach soccer: a randomized controlled trial with 2-months follow-up. <i>Clin Pract Epidemiol Ment Health</i> 2023;DOI: 10.2174/17450179-v19-e230419-2022-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10487324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37916212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu T W, Chang C F. Biomechanics of human movement and its clinical applications. <i>Kaohsiung J Med Sci</i> 2012; <b>28:</b> 13&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11922132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22301008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiriev B.<i>A Scoring Tables of Athletics, 2025 Revised Edition</i>. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viru A, Viru M. Nature of training effects. <i>In</i> William E. Garrett D T K (eds) <i>Exercise and Sport Science</i>. Philadelphia: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilins, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley J A, Hargreaves M, Joyner M J <i>et al</i>. Integrative biology of exercise. <i>Cell</i> 2014; <b>159:</b> 738&#x2013;749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25417152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. <i>ACSM's Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription</i>. Baltimore: Wolters Kluwer Health, 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23851406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noakes T D, Myburgh K H, Schall R. Peak treadmill running velocity during the VO<sub>2</sub> max test predicts running performance. <i>J Sports Sci</i> 1990; <b>8:</b> 35&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2359150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayorga-Vega D, Aguilar-Soto P, Viciana J. Criterion-related validity of the 20-m shuttle run test for estimating cardiorespiratory fitness: a meta-analysis. <i>J Sports Sci Med</i> 2015; <b>14:</b> 536&#x2013;547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4541117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26336340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawes J. <i>Developing Agility and Quickness</i>. Illinois: Human Kinetics, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J. <i>NSCA's Guide to Program Design</i>. Illinois: Human Kinetics, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira R O, Frazao D R, Ferreira M K M <i>et al</i>. Periodontal disease and sports performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>Res Sports Med</i> 2024; <b>32:</b> 767&#x2013;786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37497651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramantoro T, Hariyani N, Setyowati D <i>et al</i>. The impact of oral health on physical fitness: a systematic review. <i>Heliyon</i> 2020; DOI: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2020.e03774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7182722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32346633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashley P, Di Iorio A, Cole E <i>et al</i>. Oral health of elite athletes and association with performance: a systematic review. <i>Br J Sports Med</i> 2015; <b>49:</b> 14&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4316843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25388551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merle C L, Richter L, Challakh N <i>et al</i>. Associations of blood and performance parameters with signs of periodontal inflammation in young elite athletes-an explorative study. <i>J Clin Med</i> 2022; DOI: 10.3390/jcm11175161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9457155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36079091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yapici H, Ero&#x11e; Lu O, Ayan S <i>et al</i>. The relation between performance and oral health in male athletes. <i>Eur Res J</i> 2019; <b>5:</b> 1007&#x2013;1013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hooren B, Souren T, Bongers B C. Accuracy of respiratory gas variables, substrate, and energy use from 15 CPET systems during simulated and human exercise. <i>Scand J Med Sci Sports</i> 2024; DOI: 10.1111/sms.14490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37697640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faude O, Kindermann W, Meyer T. Lactate threshold concepts: how valid are they? <i>Sports Med</i> 2009; <b>39:</b> 469&#x2013;490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19453206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels J T. A physiologist's view of running economy. <i>Med Sci Sports Exerc</i> 1985; <b>17:</b> 332&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3894870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwalm L C, Fohrmann D, Schaffarczyk M <i>et al</i>. Habituation does not change running economy in advanced footwear technology. <i>Int J Sports Physiol Perform</i> 2024; DOI: 10.1123/ijspp.2024-0136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39187239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones A M, Vanhatalo A. The &#x2018;Critical Power' Concept: applications to sports performance with a focus on intermittent high-Intensity Exercise. <i>Sports Med</i> 2017; <b>47:</b> 65&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5371646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28332113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper K H. A means of assessing maximal oxygen intake. Correlation between field treadmill <i>test. JAMA</i> 1968; <b>203:</b> 201&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5694044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McArdle W D, Katch F I, Pechar G S <i>et al</i>. Reliability and interrelationships between maximal oxygen intake, physical work capacity and step-test scores in college women. <i>Med Sci Sports</i> 1972; <b>4:</b> 182&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4648576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangsbo J, Iaia F M, Krustrup P. The Yo-Yo intermittent recovery test: a useful tool for evaluation of physical performance in intermittent sports. <i>Sports Med</i> 2008; <b>38:</b> 37&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18081366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferradans L, Moreira A, Coto N P <i>et al</i>. Does oral hygiene influence salivary pH, lactate, and IL-1&#x3b2; of basketball players during intense exercise? <i>Int J Odontostomat</i> 2020; <b>14:</b> 617&#x2013;622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laursen P B, Shing C M, Peake J M <i>et al</i>. Interval training program optimization in highly trained endurance cyclists. <i>Med Sci Sports Exerc</i> 2002; <b>34:</b> 1801&#x2013;1807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12439086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe9;ger L A, Lambert J. A maximal multistage 20-m shuttle run test to predict VO<sub>2</sub> max. <i>Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol</i> 1982; <b>49:</b> 1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7201922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haugen T, Buchheit M. Sprint running performance monitoring: methodological and practical considerations. <i>Sports Med</i> 2016; <b>46:</b> 641&#x2013;656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26660758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovic G, Dizdar D, Jukic I <i>et al</i>. Reliability and factorial validity of squat and countermovement jump tests. <i>J Strength Cond Res</i> 2004; <b>18:</b> 551&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15320660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hori N, Newton R U, Kawamori N <i>et al</i>. Reliability of performance measurements derived from ground reaction force data during countermovement jump and the influence of sampling frequency. <i>J Strength Cond Res</i> 2009; <b>23:</b> 874&#x2013;882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19387390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buti J, Ronca F, Burgess P W <i>et al</i>. Association between periodontitis and physical fitness in law enforcement workers. <i>Clin Oral Investig</i> 2025; <b>29:</b> 99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11782456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39884984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin-Jimenez N, Perez-Bey A, Cruz-Leon C <i>et al</i>. Criterion-related validity and reliability of the standing long jump test in adults: The Adult-Fit project. <i>Eur J Sport Sci</i> 2024; <b>24:</b> 1379&#x2013;1392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11369318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39167610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega F B, Lesko&#x161;ek B, Blagus R <i>et al</i>. European fitness landscape for children and adolescents: updated reference values, fitness maps and country rankings based on nearly 8 million test results from 34 countries gathered by the FitBack network. <i>Br J Sports Med</i> 2023; <b>57:</b> 299&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9985767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36623866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zech A, Venter R, de Villiers J E <i>et al</i>. Motor skills of children and adolescents are influenced by growing up barefoot or shod. <i>Front Pediatr</i> 2018; <b>6:</b> 115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5996942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29922637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-Or O. The Wingate anaerobic test. An update on methodology, reliability and validity. <i>Sports Med</i> 1987; <b>4:</b> 381&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3324256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamamc&#x131;lar O, Kocahan T, Ak&#x131;no&#x11f;lu B <i>et al</i>. Effect of dental caries and the consequential variation in blood parameters on the anaerobic performance of rowing athletes. <i>Med J Islamic World Acad Sci</i> 2019; <b>27:</b> 55&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamorro C, Armijo-Olivo S, De la Fuente C <i>et al</i>. Absolute reliability and concurrent validity of hand held dynamometry and isokinetic dynamometry in the hip, knee and ankle joint: systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>Open Med</i> 2017; <b>12:</b> 359&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5651404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29071305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin J-B, Samozino P. Interpreting power-force-velocity profiles for individualized and specific training. <i>Int J Sports Physiol Perform</i> 2016; <b>11:</b> 267&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26694658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azodo C C, Osazuwa O. Dental conditions among competitive university athletes in Nigeria. <i>Odontostomatol Trop</i> 2013; <b>36:</b> 34&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23781684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera R R, Zanin L, Ambrosano G M <i>et al</i>. Orofacial trauma in Brazilian basketball players and level of information concerning trauma and mouthguards. <i>Dent Traumatol</i> 2011; <b>27:</b> 208&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21496201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher J, Ashley P, Petrie A <i>et al</i>. Oral health and performance impacts in elite and professional athletes. <i>Community Dent Oral Epidemiol</i> 2018; <b>46:</b> 563&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29938820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan K, Qadir A, Trakman G <i>et al</i>. Sports and energy drink consumption, oral health problems and performance impact among elite Athletes. <i>Nutrients</i> 2022; DOI: 10.3390/nu14235089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9738880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36501119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kragt L, Moen M H, Van Den Hoogenband C R <i>et al</i>. Oral health among Dutch elite athletes prior to Rio 2016. <i>Phys Sportsmed</i> 2019; <b>47:</b> 182&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30408425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Needleman I, Ashley P, Meehan L <i>et al</i>. Poor oral health including active caries in 187 UK professional male football players: clinical dental examination performed by dentists. <i>Br J Sports Med</i> 2016; <b>50:</b> 41&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26527674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Needleman I, Ashley P, Petrie A <i>et al</i>. Oral health and impact on performance of athletes participating in the London 2012 Olympic Games: a cross-sectional study. <i>Br J Sports Med</i> 2013; <b>47:</b> 1054&#x2013;1058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3812828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24068332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locker D, Quinonez C. To what extent do oral disorders compromise the quality of life? <i>Community Dent Oral Epidemiol</i> 2011; <b>39:</b> 3&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21114518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slade G D, Spencer A J. Development and evaluation of the oral health Impact profile. <i>Community Dent Health</i> 1994; <b>11:</b> 3&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8193981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adulyanon S, Vourapukjaru J, Sheiham A. Oral impacts affecting daily performance in a low dental disease Thai population. <i>Community Dent Oral Epidemiol</i> 1996; <b>24:</b> 385&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9007354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papapanou P N, Sanz M, Buduneli N <i>et al</i>. Periodontitis: consensus report of workgroup 2 of the 2017 World workshop on the classification of periodontal and peri-Implant diseases and conditions. <i>J Periodontol</i> 2018; <b>89(Suppl1):</b> 173&#x2013;182..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29926951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Aiuto F, Parkar M, Andreou G <i>et al</i>. Periodontitis and systemic inflammation: control of the local infection is associated with a reduction in serum inflammatory markers. <i>J Dent Res</i> 2004; <b>83:</b> 156&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14742655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebersole J L, Machen R L, Steffen M J <i>et al</i>. Systemic acute-phase reactants, C-reactive protein and haptoglobin, in adult periodontitis. <i>Clin Exp Immunol</i> 1997; <b>107:</b> 347&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1904587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9030874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loos B G, Craandijk J, Hoek F J <i>et al</i>. Elevation of systemic markers related to cardiovascular diseases in the peripheral blood of periodontitis patients. <i>J Periodontol</i> 2000; <b>71:</b> 1528&#x2013;1534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11063384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson T C, Clarkson J E, Worthington H V <i>et al</i>. Treatment of periodontitis for glycaemic control in people with diabetes mellitus. <i>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</i> 2022; DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD004714.pub4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9009294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35420698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanderVeen B N, Fix D K, Montalvo R N <i>et al</i>. The regulation of skeletal muscle fatigability and mitochondrial function by chronically elevated interleukin-6. <i>Exp Physiol</i> 2019; <b>104:</b> 385&#x2013;397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6750733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30576589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rayavarapu S, Coley W, Kinder T B <i>et al</i>. Idiopathic inflammatory myopathies: pathogenic mechanisms of muscle weakness. <i>Skelet Muscle</i> 2013; <b>3:</b> 13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3681571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23758833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamer M, Molloy G J. Association of C-reactive protein and muscle strength in the English longitudinal study of ageing. <i>Age</i> 2009; <b>31:</b> 171&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2734243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19466582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edouard P, Reurink G, Mackey A L <i>et al</i>. Traumatic muscle injury. <i>Nat Rev Dis Primers</i> 2023; <b>9:</b> 56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37857686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karshikoff B, Sundelin T, Lasselin J. Role of inflammation in human fatigue: relevance of multidimensional assessments and potential neuronal mechanisms. <i>Front Immunol</i> 2017; <b>8:</b> 21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5247454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28163706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang I, Arthur R A, Zhao L <i>et al</i>. The oral microbiome and inflammation in mild cognitive impairment. <i>Exp Gerontol</i> 2021; <b>147:</b> 111273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33556534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinetz E, Bocharova N. Inflammation in Elite Athletes: A Review of Novel Factors, the Role of Microbiome, and Treatments for Performance Longevity. <i>Cureus</i> 2024; DOI: 10.7759/cureus.72720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11606592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39618672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padilha C S, Von Ah Morano A E, Kruger K <i>et al</i>. The growing field of immunometabolism and exercise: Key findings in the last 5 years. <i>J Cell Physiol</i> 2022; <b>237:</b> 4001&#x2013;4020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36052887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr A E, Jager R, Carpenter K C <i>et al</i>. The athletic gut microbiota. <i>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</i> 2020; <b>17:</b> 24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7218537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheiman J, Luber J M, Chavkin T A <i>et al</i>. Meta-omics analysis of elite athletes identifies a performance-enhancing microbe that functions via lactate metabolism. <i>Nat Med</i> 2019; <b>25:</b> 1104&#x2013;1109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7368972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31235964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minty M, Canceill T, Le S <i>et al</i>. Oral health and microbiota status in professional rugby players: case-control study. <i>J Dent</i> 2018; <b>79:</b> 53&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30292825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryan N S, Burleigh M C, Easton C. The oral microbiome, nitric oxide and exercise performance. <i>Nitric Oxide</i> 2022; 125-<b>126:</b> 23&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35636654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da D, Zhao Q, Zhang H <i>et al</i>. Oral microbiome in older adults with mild cognitive impairment. <i>J Oral Microbiol</i> 2023; <b>15:</b> 2173544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9897770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36742284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adnan D, Engen P A, Villanueva M <i>et al</i>. Oral microbiome brain axis and cognitive performance in older adults. <i>Npj Dement</i> 2025;DOI: 10.1038/s44400-025-00004-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanhatalo A, L'Heureux J E, Kelly J <i>et al</i>. Network analysis of nitrate-sensitive oral microbiome reveals interactions with cognitive function and cardiovascular health across dietary interventions. <i>Redox Biol</i> 2021; <b>41:</b> 101933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7970425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33721836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas D T, Erdman K A, Burke L M. American College of Sports Medicine Joint Position Statement. Nutrition and Athletic Performance. <i>Med Sci Sports Exerc</i> 2016; <b>48:</b> 543&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26891166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke L M, Hawley J A. Swifter, higher, stronger: What's on the menu? <i>Science</i> 2018; <b>362:</b> 781&#x2013;787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30442803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durham J, Touger-Decker R, Nixdorf D R <i>et al</i>. Oro-facial pain and nutrition: a forgotten relationship? <i>J Oral Rehabil</i> 2015; <b>42:</b> 75&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25201161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulze A, Busse M. Sports Diet and Oral Health in Athletes: A Comprehensive Review. <i>Medicina</i> 2024; DOI: 10.3390/medicina60020319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10890155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38399605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur P, Singh S, Mathur A <i>et al</i>. Impact of dental disorders and its influence on self esteem levels among adolescents. <i>J Clin Diagn Res</i> 2017; DOI: 10.7860/JCDR/2017/23362.9515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5449896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28571250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkan A, Cakmak O, Yilmaz S <i>et al</i>. Relationship Between psychological factors and oral health status and behaviours. <i>Oral Health Prev Dent</i> 2015; <b>13:</b> 331&#x2013;339/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25197739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerrits M M, van Oppen P, Leone S S <i>et al</i>. Pain, not chronic disease, is associated with the recurrence of depressive and anxiety disorders. <i>BMC Psychiatry</i> 2014; <b>14:</b> 187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4090396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24965597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayabekir M, Tuncer M. Effect of teeth clenching on handgrip force in adult men: role of periodontal mechanoreceptors. <i>Acta Neurol Belg</i> 2023; <b>123:</b> 1945&#x2013;1956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37351827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nota A, Tecco S, Ehsani S <i>et al</i>. Postural stability in subjects with temporomandibular disorders and healthy controls: A comparative assessment. <i>J Electromyogr Kinesiol</i> 2017; <b>37:</b> 21&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28865312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leroux E, Leroux S, Maton F <i>et al</i>. Influence of dental occlusion on the athletic performance of young elite rowers: a pilot study. <i>Clinics</i> 2018; DOI: 10.6061/clinics/2017/e453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6238821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30517283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>