<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41703116</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Simulation of deformation characteristics of irregular rock specimens with different mining face lengths.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9463</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-38575-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The roof caving characteristics of the mining face significantly influence gas migration in old goafs, underground tunnel excavation, and the stability of surface structures. The mining length and the width of the retained coal pillar are crucial parameters affecting roof deformation and caving. By fabricating irregular-shaped specimen with varying mining lengths, conducting uniaxial compression tests, collecting defor-mation data using acoustic emission and VIC monitoring systems, and performing numerical simulations with ABAQUS, the mechanical properties and deformation characteristics of these irregular-shaped specimen were re-vealed. The findings indicate that: (1) Under uniaxial compression, the peak stresses of specimens with mining lengths of 50&#xa0;mm, 60&#xa0;mm, 70&#xa0;mm, and 80&#xa0;mm were 14.166, 9.738, 7.160, and 6.524&#xa0;MPa, respectively. As the mining length increased, the peak stress of the specimens gradually decreased, with the rate of decrease slowing down. (2) The ring count and cumulative ring count of acoustic emissions exhibited distinct stage characteristics under uniaxial compression. The cumulative ring count decreased with increasing mining length of the irregular-shaped specimen, indicating a reduction in the internal damage area. (3) The ABAQUS numerical simulation results demonstrate that an increase in vertical loading stress leads to the gradual expansion of the plastic zone. When the proportion of the plastic zone is similar, the stress decreases with increasing mining length, suggesting that a longer mining length reduces the bearing capacity. Additionally, there is a linear decrease in both peak strength and the proportion of the plastic zone. The research findings can serve as a reference for studies on the failure mode and mechanical properties of roof caving in mining faces.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yubo</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Energy Science and Engineering, Henan Polytechnic University, Jiaozuo, 454003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Energy Science and Engineering, Henan Polytechnic University, Jiaozuo, 454003, China. liuxiao@hpu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of CBM Resources and Reservoir Formation Process, Ministry of Education, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221116, China. liuxiao@hpu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Shaoren</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Energy Science and Engineering, Henan Polytechnic University, Jiaozuo, 454003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Haixiao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Energy Science and Engineering, Henan Polytechnic University, Jiaozuo, 454003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Jiawei</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Energy Science and Engineering, Henan Polytechnic University, Jiaozuo, 454003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ni</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoming</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Energy Science and Engineering, Henan Polytechnic University, Jiaozuo, 454003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>51974108</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>232102320231</GrantID><Agency>Henan Provincial Science and Technology Research Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Different mining length</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Irregular-shaped specimen</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanical properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Numerical simulation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41703116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13004835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-38575-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-38575-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xie, P. et al. Three-dimensional fracture migration evolution law of overburden rock in steeply dipping working face. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i> 1&#x2013;14 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, X. &amp; Mao, X. Influence of repeated mining of close distance coal seams on slope stability. <i>J. XI&#x2019;AN Univ. Sci. Technol.</i><b>39</b>, 34&#x2013;42 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, E. Research on layout technology of extra-thick coal seam roadway influenced by concentrated stress of close coal columns concentrated. <i>Jinneng Hold. Sci. Technol.</i> 47&#x2013;50 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue, M. &amp; Guo, K. Optimization research on size of narrow coal pillar of Gob-side entry driving in deep shaft Impact-tendency coal seam. <i>Coal Technol.</i><b>44</b>, 81&#x2013;85 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. Structure form and evolution characteristics of collapsed roof in Goaf. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>46</b>, 3771&#x2013;3780 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X. Influence of working face mining height on stability of roadway coal pillars. <i>Energy Energy Conserv.</i> 287&#x2013;291 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, H. &amp; Wang, Y. Research on determination of Gob-side entry of Close-distance Extra-thick coal seam under coal pillars. <i>Coal Technol.</i><b>42</b>, 91&#x2013;95 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H. Research on influence of deep coal seam mining width on stability of coal pillars. <i>Coal Sec. Technol. Magazine</i>. <b>45</b>, 105&#x2013;108 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, K., Teng, T., Yang, Y., Li, Z. &amp; Ding, H. Numerical simulation study on stress field and plastic zone evolution of deep coal seam overburden under different mining heights. <i>Min. Technol.</i><b>24</b>, 41&#x2013;45 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W., Wang, S., Liu, H., Jiang, T. &amp; Ren, M. The space and time characteristics of the cover stress re-establishment of the fractured rock mass in the Goaf after coal mining. <i>J. Min. Saf. Eng.</i><b>34</b>, 127&#x2013;133 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Q. Influence factors analysis of residual pillar in Goaf and its evaluation methods. <i>Saf. Coal Mines</i>. <b>48</b>, 128&#x2013;131 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M. et al. Study of the compatible deformation and stability of the system of super Thick strata and coal pillars. <i>Chin. J. Rock Mechan. Eng.</i><b>36</b>, 326&#x2013;334 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, Z., Li, J., He, F. &amp; Zhang, S. Stability study and field observation of coal pillar between Goaf and unmined top-coal caving face. <i>J. Min. Sci. Technol.</i><b>2</b>, 371&#x2013;378 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, T., You, S., Pei, F. &amp; Bai, X. Instability mechanism and control technology of coal pillar bumps under hard roof. <i>J. Min. Saf. Eng.</i><b>34</b>, 54&#x2013;59 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, S., Cao, Y. &amp; Jiang, H. Research on catastrophe instability mechanism of section coal pillars in block mining. <i>J. Min. Saf. Eng.</i><b>31</b>, 907&#x2013;913 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, L. Optimized study on coal pillar width of fully-mechanized coal face in medium thick seam with shallow depth. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i> 17&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, A. Study on width optimization of sectional coal pillar in Ping Shuo 3 underground mine. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>40</b>, 45&#x2013;48 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, J. et al. Research on rational width of section coal-pillar in large mining height of shallow coal seam. <i>Coal Technol.</i><b>35</b>, 1&#x2013;3 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, T., Zhao, X. &amp; Song, Y. On reasonable width of section coal pillar in Thick coal working face. <i>Miner. Eng. Res.</i> 35&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv, H., Cheng, Z. &amp; Liu F.Study on the mechanism of a new fully mechanical mining method for extremely Thick coal seam. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>142</b> (3), 104788 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2021.104788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv, H. et al. Stress, displacement, and crack evolution of top-coal layers in high-intensity repeated mining with extra-thick coal seam. <i>Comput. Part. Mech.</i><b>12</b> (5), 2879&#x2013;2893 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40571-025-00959-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, A., Shao, G., Su, J., Liu, J. &amp; Sun, Y. Uniaxial compression test and numerical simulation for alternatively soft and hard interbedded rock mass. <i>J. Hohai University(Natural Sciences)</i>. <b>46</b>, 533&#x2013;538 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, G. et al. Physical simulation of deformation and failure mechanism of soft and hard interbedded salt rocks. <i>Chin. J. Rock Mechan. Eng.</i><b>31</b>, 1813&#x2013;1820 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, Z. Study on the influence of roof and floor strength and pillar width to height ratio on coal pillar type rock burst. (Liaoning Technical University, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. et al. Roof failure mechanism of gob-side entry retaining by roof cutting and pressure releasing and its control technology. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>45</b>, 80&#x2013;84 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, Z., Chen, G. &amp; Qin, Q. Effects of combination mode on mechanical properties and rock burst tendency of the coal-rock combinations. <i>J. XI&#x2019;an Univ. Sci. Technol.</i><b>37</b>, 655&#x2013;661 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, G. et al. Mechanical properties and failure mechanism of combined bodies with different coal-rock ratios and combinations. <i>J. Min. Strata Control Eng.</i><b>3</b>, 84&#x2013;94 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, G., Zhang, S., Li, T., Zhang, G. &amp; Lv, P. Influence of properties and proportion of coal-rock combined body on the law of mechanical properties. <i>J. Liaoning Tech. Univ. (Natl. Sci.)</i><b>40</b>, 198&#x2013;205</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, P. et al. Coal thickness effect on mechanics and energy characteristics of coal-rock combination model. <i>J. Min. Saf. Eng.</i><b>37</b>, 1067&#x2013;1076 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, X., Liu, J., Xing, Y., Wang, Q. &amp; Xu, Q. Influences of section coal pillar size to overlying strata migration. <i>Coal Eng.</i> 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv, H. et al. Study on mechanical characteristics and failure modes of coal&#x2013;mudstone combined body with prefabricated crack. <i>Mathematics</i><b>10</b> (2), 177 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math10020177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv, H. et al. Study on hydraulic fracturing prevention and control of rock burst in roof of deep extra-thick coal seam roadway group. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>(1) (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11603062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39604398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong, Y. et al. The comprehensive identification of roof risk in a fully mechanized working face using the cloud model. <i>Mathematics</i><b>9</b> (17): 2072 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang, Y. et al. Study on failure characteristics and control technology of roadway surrounding rock under repeated mining in close-distance coal seam. <i>Mathematics</i><b>10</b> (13), 2166 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math10132166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L. et al. Comprehensive identification of surface subsidence evaluation grades of mines in Southwest China. <i>Mathematics</i><b>10</b> (15), 2664 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math10152664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Compiled by Dou Lin ming et al et al. <i>Rock Burst Prevention and Control Technology [M]</i> (China University of Mining and Technology, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Q. et al. Study on stress and fracture evolution of sectional hydraulic fracturing of coal seam roof. <i>J. China Univ. Min. Technol.</i><b>52</b>, 1084&#x2013;1095 (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>