<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41859764</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-4984</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental science and ecotechnology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Sci Ecotechnol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Plant-level carbon accounting of China's pulp and paper industry via multimodal fusion.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100682</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100682</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100682</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ese.2026.100682</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Plant-scale industrial carbon accounting is critical for developing targeted emission-reduction policies. However, most assessments of carbon-intensive sectors rely on aggregate statistics, which obscure significant heterogeneity among individual plants. China's pulp and paper industry (PPI), the largest globally, encompasses diverse production processes, raw material inputs, and emission sources. Existing accounting frameworks rely on statistical data and average emission factors within poorly defined system boundaries, which prevents differentiation at the individual plant level. Here, we propose a multimodal data fusion framework that integrates high-resolution remote-sensing imagery with plant textual data to capture structural and operational characteristics undetectable by any single data modality. Applied to 720 pulping and papermaking plants across China, the framework achieves R<sup>2</sup> values of up to 0.96 across five plant types and estimates total sectoral carbon emissions at 163.6 million tonnes of CO<sub>2</sub> in 2022, with pronounced regional disparities concentrated in eastern coastal provinces. Analysis of functional-zone contributions further reveals that wastewater treatment areas are a consistent cross-category emission driver, and that just 5% of high-emission plants account for approximately 43% of sectoral emissions-a skewed structure that demands differentiated regulatory intervention. Incorporating regional solar radiation data, rooftop photovoltaic deployment is projected to reduce annual PPI emissions by up to 10.3%, with primary-fiber pulp plants offering the greatest mitigation leverage. Beyond China's PPI, this scalable, data-driven approach provides a transferable blueprint for granular, plant-level carbon accounting in other heterogeneous heavy industries.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Song</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Advanced Papermaking and Paper-Based Materials, South China University of Technology, Guangzhou, 510640, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qi</LastName><ForeName>Huaqing</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Advanced Papermaking and Paper-Based Materials, South China University of Technology, Guangzhou, 510640, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zifei</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Advanced Papermaking and Paper-Based Materials, South China University of Technology, Guangzhou, 510640, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoyu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, South China University of Technology, Guangzhou, 510640, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Yulin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Advanced Papermaking and Paper-Based Materials, South China University of Technology, Guangzhou, 510640, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Man</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Advanced Papermaking and Paper-Based Materials, South China University of Technology, Guangzhou, 510640, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Sci Ecotechnol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918453988906676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-4984</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon accounting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon reduction potential</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multimodal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Plant-scale</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulp and paper industry</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41859764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12997205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ese.2026.100682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-4984(26)00027-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>China Paper Association  . China Paper Association, Beijing; 2019. China Paper Industry Sustainable Development White Paper.http://www.chinappi.org/reps/20190226104141217819.html (in Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S., Yu K., Yu Y. Industrial transformation for synergistic carbon and pollutant reduction in China: using environmentally extended multi-regional input-output model and multi-objective optimization. Energy. 2025;318 doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2025.134830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2025.134830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Ewijk S., Stegemann J.A., Ekins P. Limited climate benefits of global recycling of pulp and paper. Nat. Sustain. 2021;4(2):180&#x2013;187. doi: 10.1038/s41893-020-00624-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41893-020-00624-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai M., Sun M., Chen B., Shi L., Jin M., Man Y., Liang Z., de Almeida C.M.V.B., Li J., Zhang P., Chiu A.S.F., Xu M., Yu H., Meng J., Wang Y. Country-specific net-zero strategies of the pulp and paper industry. Nature. 2024;626(7998):327&#x2013;334. doi: 10.1038/s41586-023-06962-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-023-06962-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38109939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Q.L., Zhao H.L., Wei G.X., Zhu Y.W., Li T., Xu M., Guo X., Shi H.Z., Lian Y., Liu H.Q. Sustainable papermaking in China: assessing provincial economic and environmental performance of pulping technologies. ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2024;12(11):4517&#x2013;4529. doi: 10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei T., Guan D., Shan Y., Zheng B., Liang X., Meng J., Zhang Q., Tao S. Adaptive CO2 emissions mitigation strategies of global oil refineries in all age groups. One Earth. 2021;4(8):1114&#x2013;1126. doi: 10.1016/j.oneear.2021.07.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oneear.2021.07.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stangl J., Borsos A., Diem C., Reisch T., Thurner S. Firm-level supply chains to minimize unemployment and economic losses in rapid decarbonization scenarios. Nat. Sustain. 2024;7(5):581&#x2013;589. doi: 10.1038/s41893-024-01321-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41893-024-01321-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao Q., Kuang X. A study on the implementation of corporate carbon emission accounting in the production process. Pol. J. Environ. Stud. 2024;33(3):2941&#x2013;2957. doi: 10.15244/pjoes/175300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15244/pjoes/175300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Man Y., Yan Y., Wang X., Ren J., Xiong Q., He Z. Overestimated carbon emission of the pulp and paper industry in China. Energy. 2023;273 doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2023.127279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.127279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Z., Hong M., Zheng H., Wang J., Xiong Q., Man Y. Towards low-carbon papermaking wastewater treatment process based on kriging surrogate predictive model. J. Clean. Prod. 2023;425 doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.139039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.139039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu W., Tang Q., Xue W., Shi X., Zhao D., Liu Z., Liu X., Jiang C., Yan G., Wang J. Quantifying china's iron and steel industry's CO2 emissions and environmental health burdens: a pathway to sustainable transformation. Environ. Sci. Ecotechnol. 2024;20 doi: 10.1016/j.ese.2023.100367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ese.2023.100367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11361861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39221075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Li X., Chen L., Wang M. Global primary aluminum smelters' CO2 mitigation potential and targeted carbon-neutral pathways. J. Clean. Prod. 2024;474 doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.143628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.143628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi H., Wang Z., Hu S., He Z., Han Y., Man Y. Multiscale life-cycle carbon emission analysis for papermaking industry of China: evolution triggered by the waste import ban. ACS Sustainable Chem. Eng. 2025;13(28):11128&#x2013;11142. doi: 10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c00355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.5c00355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Man Y., Li J., Hong M., Han Y. Energy transition for the low-carbon pulp and paper industry in China. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2020;131 doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2020.109998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2020.109998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spreafico C., Landi D., Russo D. A new method of patent analysis to support prospective life cycle assessment of eco-design solutions. Sustain. Prod. Consum. 2023;38:241&#x2013;251. doi: 10.1016/j.spc.2023.04.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.spc.2023.04.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marujo E.C., Rodrigues G.G., Covatti A.A. Procedures to combine estimators of greenhouse gases emission factors. Carbon Bal. Manag. 2024;19(1):4. doi: 10.1186/s13021-024-00250-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13021-024-00250-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11342513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38315265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu Q., Guo J., Li N., Qi J., Xu M. Mitigating grand challenges in life cycle inventory modeling through the applications of large language models. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2024;58(44):19595&#x2013;19603. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.4c07634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.4c07634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39431580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Lam K.M., Wang Q. CoF-Net: a progressive coarse-to-fine framework for object detection in remote-sensing imagery. IEEE T. Geosci. Remote. 2023;61 doi: 10.1109/TGRS.2022.3233881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TGRS.2022.3233881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawanis H.S.N., Ilyas R.A., Jalil R., Ibrahim R., Majid R.A., Ab Hamid N.H. Insights into lignocellulosic fibre feedstock and its impact on pulp and paper manufacturing: a comprehensive review sustain. Mater. Technol. 2024;40 doi: 10.1016/j.susmat.2024.e00922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.susmat.2024.e00922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S., Ma J., Jiang F. Monitoring street-level improper dumpsites via a multi-modal and LLM-based framework. Resour. Conserv. Recycl. 2025;218 doi: 10.1016/j.resconrec.2025.108227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2025.108227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y., Zhang F., Gao Y., Tu W., Duarte F., Ratti C., Guo D., Liu Y. Comprehensive urban space representation with varying numbers of street-level images. Comput. Environ. Urban Syst. 2023;106 doi: 10.1016/j.compenvurbsys.2023.102043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compenvurbsys.2023.102043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao R., Tu W., Yang C., Li Q., Liu J., Zhu J., Zhang Q., Li Q., Qiu G. Deep learning-based remote and social sensing data fusion for urban region function recognition. ISPRS J. Photogramm. 2020;163:82&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2020.02.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2020.02.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyo F.H., Nastasi B., Astiaso Garcia D. Decarbonization pathways for the pulp and paper industry: a comprehensive review. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2025;223 doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2025.116070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2025.116070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y.H., Wu J.H., Liu T.Y. Bottom-up analysis of energy conservation and carbon dioxide mitigation potentials by extended marginal abatement cost curves for pulp and paper industry. Energy Strategy Rev. 2022;42 doi: 10.1016/j.esr.2022.100893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.esr.2022.100893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinese Academy of Environmental Planning (CAEP) &amp; Institute for Carbon Neutrality, Tsinghua University . Energy Foundation China; 2025. Outlook on Industrial low-carbon Technologies Toward China's Carbon Neutrality Goal. (in Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng H., Zhang D., Yu H., Man Y., Wang Y. Assessing life-cycle GHG emissions of recycled paper products under imported solid waste ban in China: a case study. Sci. Total Environ. 2023;891 doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.164407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.164407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37244615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai C., Fan K., Cai Q., Ye Q., Wu X. Low carbon and cost-effective pathways for specialty paper production in China. Sustain. Prod. Consum. 2023;39:556&#x2013;568. doi: 10.1016/j.spc.2023.05.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.spc.2023.05.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagues W.J., Jameel H., Sanchez D.L., Park S. Prospects for bioenergy with carbon capture &amp; storage (BECCS) in the United States pulp and paper industry. Energy Environ. Sci. 2020;13(8):2243&#x2013;2261. doi: 10.1039/D0EE01107J.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D0EE01107J</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Man Y., Han Y., Li J., Hong M., Zheng W. Life cycle energy consumption analysis and green manufacture evolution for the papermaking industry in China. Green Chem. 2019;21(5):1011&#x2013;1020. doi: 10.1039/c8gc03604g.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c8gc03604g</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gailani A., Cooper S., Allen S., Pimm A., Taylor P., Gross R. Assessing the potential of decarbonization options for industrial sectors. Joule. 2024;8(3):576&#x2013;603. doi: 10.1016/j.joule.2024.01.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2024.01.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;hringer C., Garc&#xed;a-Muros X., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Eguino M. Who bears the burden of greening electricity? Energy Econ. 2022;105 doi: 10.1016/j.eneco.2021.105705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eneco.2021.105705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Chen X., Li W., Peng R., Ji J., Su X., Luo C. Energy, economic, emissions analysis of semi-flexible crystalline silicon photovoltaic system integrated with factory building roofs based on actual electricity load and cost conditions. Energy Build. 2025;330 doi: 10.1016/j.enbuild.2025.115358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enbuild.2025.115358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao D., Hou Y., Zhi Y., Wei Z., Mao J., Kong W., Zheng S., Peng B., Yang X. Multi-objective optimization of urban industrial building rooftop PV-Storage systems: integrating dynamic degradation and lifecycle carbon footprint. Sustain. Cities Soc. 2025;130 doi: 10.1016/j.scs.2025.106615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2025.106615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Z., Liu C., Wang Y., Wang X., Man Y. Optimal operation of wind-solar-thermal collaborative power system considering carbon trading and energy storage. Appl. Energy. 2023;352 doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2023.121993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2023.121993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipi&#xe4;inen S., Apajalahti E.L., Vakkilainen E. Decarbonization prospects for the European pulp and paper industry: different development pathways and needed actions. Energies. 2023;16(2):746. doi: 10.3390/en16020746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en16020746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweetapple C., Fu G., Butler D. Identifying sensitive sources and key control handles for the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions from wastewater treatment. Water Res. 2014;62:249&#x2013;259. doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2014.06.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2014.06.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24960125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China . China Planning Press; Beijing: 2015. Code for Design of Pulp and Papermaking Plant (GB 51092&#x2013;2015) (in Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>China Paper Association . China Light Industry Press; Beijing: 2022. China Paper Industry Yearbook 2022. (in Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji A., Xue X., Wang Y., Luo X., Xue W. An integrated approach to automatic pixel-level crack detection and quantification of asphalt pavement. Autom. ConStruct. 2020;114 doi: 10.1016/j.autcon.2020.103176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autcon.2020.103176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Long R., Chen H., Wu M., Ma W., Li Q. Topic-sentiment analysis of citizen environmental complaints in China: using a Stacking-BERT model. J. Environ. Manag. 2024;371 doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.123112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.123112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39476670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P., Yu P., Huang L., Zhang Y. An integrated technical, economic, and environmental framework for evaluating the rooftop photovoltaic potential of old residential buildings. J. Environ. Manag. 2022;317 doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2022.115296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2022.115296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35644676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P., Zhang S., Pu Y., Cao S., Zhang Y. Estimation of photovoltaic power generation potential in 2020 and 2030 using land resource changes: an empirical study from China. Energy. 2021;219 doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2020.119611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2020.119611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IPCC . Cambridge University Press; 2014. IPCC Climate Change 2014: Mitigation of Climate Change. Working Group III Contribution to AR5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kucherenko S., Tarantola S., Annoni P. Estimation of global sensitivity indices for models with dependent variables. Comput. Phys. Commun. 2012;183(4):937&#x2013;946. doi: 10.1016/j.cpc.2011.12.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpc.2011.12.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>