<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41593692</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1741-7015</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of aerobic or resistance exercise on sleep and cancer-related fatigue in patients with breast cancer during or after neoadjuvant chemotherapy: a 3-arm randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">114</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12916-026-04669-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The aim of this secondary analysis of the BENEFIT randomized controlled trial was to investigate the effects of aerobic training (AT) or resistance training (RT) during neoadjuvant chemotherapy (NACT) on sleep and cancer-related fatigue (CRF), compared to a waitlist control group (WCG) that performed RT after surgery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In the BENEFIT study, 184 patients with breast cancer with scheduled NACT (mean age&#x2009;=&#x2009;50&#xa0;years, standard deviation&#x2009;=&#x2009;11) were randomized to AT (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;62), RT (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;62), or WCG (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;60). While the AT and RT groups trained during NACT (two supervised and one home-based session weekly), the WCG completed the same training as the RT group but only after breast surgery. Self-reported sleep quality (Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index) and CRF (EORTC QLQ-FA12) were collected before NACT (T0), after 9&#xa0;weeks (T1), after NACT and before surgery (T2), 6&#xa0;months after surgery (T3), and 12&#xa0;months after surgery (T4). At T0, T2, and T3, sleep was additionally objectively measured by actigraphy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Longitudinal analyses of covariance examining changes from baseline suggested no clear difference of AT and RT compared to the WCG regarding sleep and CRF parameters post-intervention (T2). In contrast, at T3 the WCG, which exercised between T2 and T3, showed more favorable mean values compared to the AT group in total CRF (adjusted mean difference (AMD):&#x2009;-&#x2009;10.53, 95% CI [-&#x2009;19.63,&#x2009;-&#x2009;1.42]) and physical CRF (AMD:&#x2009;-&#x2009;14.28 [-&#x2009;26.02,&#x2009;-&#x2009;2.54] on 0-100 scale), and a tendency toward lower scores in self-reported global sleep quality (AMD:&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.24 [-&#x2009;0.48, 0.01] on log-transformed scale). Moderation analyses further suggested that group differences in total CRF at T3 in favor of the WCG were more pronounced among participants with at least mild emotional distress at baseline. There were no clear differences between groups in objective sleep parameters at T2 or T3, or regarding self-reported sleep or fatigue endpoints at T4.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The findings suggest that exercise interventions in the post-NACT phase may be more effective than during NACT for managing fatigue, while providing limited benefits for sleep.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The BENEFIT study has been registered at ClincialTrials.gov (NCT02999074).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haussmann</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Physical Activity, Cancer Prevention and Survivorship, German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) and National Center for Tumor Diseases (NCT) Heidelberg, a partnership between DKFZ and University Medical Center Heidelberg, Im Neuenheimer Feld 581, Heidelberg, 69120, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Health Care Research and Rehabilitation Research, Institute of Medical Biometry and Statistics, Faculty of Medicine, Medical Center, University of Freiburg, Hugstetter Str. 49, Freiburg, 79106, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schmidt</LastName><ForeName>Martina E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Physical Activity, Cancer Prevention and Survivorship, German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) and National Center for Tumor Diseases (NCT) Heidelberg, a partnership between DKFZ and University Medical Center Heidelberg, Im Neuenheimer Feld 581, Heidelberg, 69120, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goldschmidt</LastName><ForeName>Siri</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Physical Activity, Cancer Prevention and Survivorship, German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) and National Center for Tumor Diseases (NCT) Heidelberg, a partnership between DKFZ and University Medical Center Heidelberg, Im Neuenheimer Feld 581, Heidelberg, 69120, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hiensch</LastName><ForeName>Anouk E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht University, P.O. Box 85500, Utrecht, GA, 3508, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wiskemann</LastName><ForeName>Joachim</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, University Clinic Heidelberg and National Center for Tumor Diseases (NCT) Heidelberg, a partnership between DKFZ and University Medical Center Heidelberg, Im Neuenheimer Feld 460, Heidelberg, 69120, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steindorf</LastName><ForeName>Karen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Physical Activity, Cancer Prevention and Survivorship, German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) and National Center for Tumor Diseases (NCT) Heidelberg, a partnership between DKFZ and University Medical Center Heidelberg, Im Neuenheimer Feld 581, Heidelberg, 69120, Germany. k.steindorf@dkfz-heidelberg.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT02999074</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101190723</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1741-7015</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001943" MajorTopicYN="Y">Breast Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020360" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neoadjuvant Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000089943" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep Quality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endurance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Insomnia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oncology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient-reported outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: All procedures performed in this study involving human participants were in accordance with the ethical standards of the institutional and/or national research committee and with the 1964 Declaration of Helsinki and its later amendments or comparable ethical standards. The study was approved by the Ethics Committee of the Medical Faculty of the University of Heidelberg (reference number: S-678/2015). All participants provided written informed consent prior to study enrollment. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41593692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12924517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-026-04669-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12916-026-04669-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bray F, Laversanne M, Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, Soerjomataram I, et al. Global cancer statistics 2022: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2024;74(3):229&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38572751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferlay J, Ervik M, Lam F, Laversanne M, Colombet M, Mery L, et al. Cancer Today. In: Global Cancer Observatory. International Agency for Research on Cancer; 2024. https://gco.iarc.who.int/today. Accessed 12 Apr 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers C, Cobb AN, Lloren JIC, Chaudhary LN, Johnson MK, Huang CC, et al. National trends in neoadjuvant chemotherapy utilization in patients with early-stage node-negative triple-negative breast cancer: the impact of the CREATE-X trial. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2024;203(2):317&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10872271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37864105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early Breast Cancer Trialists' Collaborative Group (EBCTCG). Long-term outcomes for neoadjuvant versus adjuvant chemotherapy in early breast cancer: meta-analysis of individual patient data from ten randomised trials. Lancet Oncol. 2018;19(1):27&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5757427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29242041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korde LA, Somerfield MR, Carey LA, Crews JR, Denduluri N, Hwang ES, et al. Neoadjuvant chemotherapy, endocrine therapy, and targeted therapy for breast cancer: ASCO guideline. J Clin Oncol. 2021;39(13):1485&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8274745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33507815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng WH, Teo RH, Cheng LJ, Lau Y, Lau ST. Global prevalence of sleep disturbances among breast cancer survivors: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sleep Health. 2023;9(5):704&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37453906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y, He B, Jiang M, Yang Y, Wang C, Huang C, et al. Prevalence and risk factors of cancer-related fatigue: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Nurs Stud. 2020;111:103707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32920423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stapleton SJ, Holden J, Epstein J, Wilkie DJ. A systematic review of the symptom distress scale in advanced cancer studies. Cancer Nurs. 2016;39(4):E9&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4744575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26252436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imran M, Al-Wassia R, Alkhayyat SS, Baig M, Al-Saati BA. Assessment of quality of life (QoL) in breast cancer patients by using EORTC QLQ-C30 and BR-23 questionnaires: a tertiary care center survey in the western region of Saudi Arabia. PLoS One. 2019;14(7):e0219093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6620008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31291302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bean HR, Diggens J, Ftanou M, Weihs KL, Stanton AL, Wiley JF. Insomnia and fatigue symptom trajectories in breast cancer: a longitudinal cohort study. Behav Sleep Med. 2021;19(6):814&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33470847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox RS, Ancoli-Israel S, Roesch SC, Merz EL, Mills SD, Wells KJ, et al. Sleep disturbance and cancer-related fatigue symptom cluster in breast cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy. Support Care Cancer. 2020;28(2):845&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6959513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31161437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelzer F, Tr&#xf6;ger W, Reif M, Sch&#xf6;nberg S, Martin DD, M&#xfc;ller C, et al. Fatigue and quality of life during neoadjuvant chemotherapy of early breast cancer: a prospective multicenter cohort study. Breast Cancer. 2024;31(1):124&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10764505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37966690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konieczny M, Sawicka J, G&#x105;ska I, Kaczmar E, Babu&#x15b;ka-Roczniak M, B&#x105;dziul D. Health-related quality of life and disease acceptance among women with breast cancer pre- and post-neoadjuvant chemotherapy. Cancers (Basel). 2025;17(3):497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11816349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39941864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros Torres D, Jorge Koifman R, da Silva Santos S. Impact on fatigue of different types of physical exercise during adjuvant chemotherapy and radiotherapy in breast cancer: systematic review and meta-analysis. Support Care Cancer. 2022;30(6):4651&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35064331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernard P, Savard J, Steindorf K, Sweegers MG, Courneya KS, Newton RU, et al. Effects and moderators of exercise on sleep in adults with cancer: individual patient data and aggregated meta-analyses. J Psychosom Res. 2019;124:109746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31443811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell KL, Winters-Stone KM, Wiskemann J, May AM, Schwartz AL, Courneya KS, et al. Exercise guidelines for cancer survivors: consensus statement from international multidisciplinary roundtable. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(11):2375&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8576825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31626055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturgeon KM, Smith AM, Federici EH, Kodali N, Kessler R, Wyluda E, et al. Feasibility of a tailored home-based exercise intervention during neoadjuvant chemotherapy in breast cancer patients. BMC Sports Science, Medicine and Rehabilitation. 2022;14(1):31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8874298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornsby WE, Douglas PS, West MJ, Kenjale AA, Lane AR, Schwitzer ER, et al. Safety and efficacy of aerobic training in operable breast cancer patients receiving neoadjuvant chemotherapy: a phase II randomized trial. Acta Oncol. 2014;53(1):65&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23957716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brahmbhatt P, Look Hong NJ, Sriskandarajah A, Alavi N, Selvadurai S, Berger-Richardson D, et al. A feasibility randomized controlled trial of prehabilitation during neoadjuvant chemotherapy for women with breast cancer: a mixed methods study. Ann Surg Oncol. 2024;31(4):2261&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38219003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee K, Norris MK, Wang E, Dieli-Conwright CM. Effect of high-intensity interval training on patient-reported outcomes and physical function in women with breast cancer receiving anthracycline-based chemotherapy. Support Care Cancer. 2021;29(11):6863&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34018031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakano J, Hashizume K, Fukushima T, Ueno K, Matsuura E, Ikio Y, et al. Effects of aerobic and resistance exercises on physical symptoms in cancer patients: a meta-analysis. Integr Cancer Ther. 2018;17(4):1048&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6247562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30352523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michael CM, Lehrer EJ, Schmitz KH, Zaorsky NG. Prehabilitation exercise therapy for cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cancer Med. 2021;10(13):4195&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8267161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34110101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt ME, Goldschmidt S, Kreutz C, M&#xfc;ller J, Schneeweiss A, May AM, et al. Effects of aerobic or resistance exercise during neoadjuvant chemotherapy on tumor response and therapy completion in women with breast cancer: the randomized controlled BENEFIT trial. J Sport Health Sci. 2025;14:101064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12395146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40447136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldschmidt S, Schmidt ME, Rosenberger F, Wiskemann J, Steindorf K. Patterns and influencing factors of exercise attendance of breast cancer patients during neoadjuvant chemotherapy. Support Care Cancer. 2024;32(1):79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10764381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38170301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams N. The Borg rating of perceived exertion (RPE) scale. Occup Med (Lond). 2017;67(5):404&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldschmidt S, Schmidt ME, Rosenberger F, Wiskemann J, Steindorf K. Maintenance of aerobic or resistance training after an exercise intervention among breast cancer patients after neoadjuvant chemotherapy. J Phys Act Health. 2024;21(1):11&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37917983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF, 3rd TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989;28(2):193&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2748771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck SL, Schwartz AL, Towsley G, Dudley W, Barsevick A. Psychometric evaluation of the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index in cancer patients. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2004;27(2):140&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15157038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontes F, Gon&#xe7;alves M, Maia S, Pereira S, Severo M, Lunet N. Reliability and validity of the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index in breast cancer patients. Support Care Cancer. 2017;25(10):3059&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28455545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kripke DF, Mullaney DJ, Messin S, Wyborney VG. Wrist actigraphic measures of sleep and rhythms. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1978;44(5):674&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">77772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ActiGraph. How did ActiGraph develop the automatic sleep-detection algorithm used in CentrePoint to estimate in-bed and out-of-bed times? In: ActiGraph Support Knowledge Base. ActiGraph; 2020. https://actigraphcorp.my.site.com/support/s/article/How-did-ActiGraph-develop-the-automatic-sleep-detection-algorithm-used-in-CentrePoint-to-estimate-in-bed-and-out-of-bed-times. Accessed 16 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tudor-Locke C, Barreira TV, Schuna JM Jr., Mire EF, Katzmarzyk PT. Fully automated waist-worn accelerometer algorithm for detecting children&#x2019;s sleep-period time separate from 24-h physical activity or sedentary behaviors. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2014;39(1):53&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24383507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreutz C, M&#xfc;ller J, Schmidt ME, Steindorf K. Comparison of subjectively and objectively assessed sleep problems in breast cancer patients starting neoadjuvant chemotherapy. Support Care Cancer. 2021;29(2):1015&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7767899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32556623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaus A, M&#xfc;ller S. Measuring fatigue of cancer patients in the German-speaking region: development of the Fatigue Assessment Questionnaire. Pflege. 2001;14(3):161&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12385268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weis J, Tomaszewski KA, Hammerlid E, Ignacio Arraras J, Conroy T, Lanceley A, et al. International Psychometric Validation of an EORTC Quality of Life Module Measuring Cancer Related Fatigue (EORTC QLQ-FA12). J Natl Cancer Inst. 2017;109(5):djw273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28376231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weis J, Wirtz MA, Tomaszewski KA, Hammerlid E, Arraras JI, Conroy T, et al. Sensitivity to change of the EORTC quality of life module measuring cancer-related fatigue (EORTC QlQ-Fa12): results from the international psychometric validation. Psychooncology. 2019;28(8):1753&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31225669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EORTC Data Center. EORTC QLQ-C30 Scoring Manual. In: European Organisation for Research and Treatment of Cancer. 2001. https://www.eortc.org/app/uploads/sites/2/2018/02/SCmanual.pdf. Accessed 19 Jun 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;we B, Wahl I, Rose M, Spitzer C, Glaesmer H, Wingenfeld K, et al. A 4-item measure of depression and anxiety: validation and standardization of the Patient Health Questionnaire-4 (PHQ-4) in the general population. J Affect Disord. 2010;122(1&#x2013;2):86&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19616305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinz A, Weis J, Br&#xe4;hler E, Mehnert A. Fatigue in the general population: German normative values of the EORTC QLQ-FA12. Qual Life Res. 2018;27(10):2681&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29909484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Buuren S, Groothuis-Oudshoorn K. Mice: multivariate imputation by chained equations in R. J Stat Softw. 2011;45(3):1&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little RJA, Rubin DB. Statistical analysis with missing data. 3rd ed. Hoboken: John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreutz C, Schmidt ME, Steindorf K. Effects of physical and mind-body exercise on sleep problems during and after breast cancer treatment: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2019;176(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30955185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo-Schimmel A, Kober KM, Paul SM, Cooper BA, Harris C, Shin J, et al. Sleep disturbance is associated with perturbations in immune-inflammatory pathways in oncology outpatients undergoing chemotherapy. Sleep Med. 2023;101:305&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11200329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36470166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez D, Medino-Mu&#xf1;oz J, Romero-El&#xed;as M, Garc&#xed;a-Foncillas J, Ruiz-Casado A. Biological mechanisms of cancer-related fatigue in breast cancer survivors after treatment: a scoping review. J Cancer Surviv. 2025;19:414&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37930591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courneya KS, Segal RJ, Gelmon K, Mackey JR, Friedenreich CM, Yasui Y, et al. Predictors of adherence to different types and doses of supervised exercise during breast cancer chemotherapy. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2014;11:85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4110703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24997476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund LW, Ammitzb&#xf8;ll G, Hansen DG, Andersen EAW, Dalton SO. Adherence to a long-term progressive resistance training program, combining supervised and home-based exercise for breast cancer patients during adjuvant treatment. Acta Oncol. 2019;58(5):650&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30698050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Waart H, Buffart LM, Stuiver MM, van Harten WH, Sonke GS, Aaronson NK. Adherence to and satisfaction with low-intensity physical activity and supervised moderate-high intensity exercise during chemotherapy for breast cancer. Support Care Cancer. 2020;28(5):2115&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31396745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mijwel S, Backman M, Bolam KA, Jervaeus A, Sundberg CJ, Margolin S, et al. Adding high-intensity interval training to conventional training modalities: optimizing health-related outcomes during chemotherapy for breast cancer: the OptiTrain randomized controlled trial. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2018;168(1):79&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5847033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29139007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bland KA, Neil-Sztramko SE, Kirkham AA, Bonsignore A, Van Patten CL, McKenzie DC, et al. Predictors of attendance to an oncologist-referred exercise program for women with breast cancer. Support Care Cancer. 2018;26(9):3297&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29651596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt ME, Wiskemann J, Armbrust P, Schneeweiss A, Ulrich CM, Steindorf K. Effects of resistance exercise on fatigue and quality of life in breast cancer patients undergoing adjuvant chemotherapy: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Cancer. 2015;137(2):471&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25484317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browall M, Mijwel S, Rundqvist H, Wengstr&#xf6;m Y. Physical activity during and after adjuvant treatment for breast cancer: an integrative review of women&#x2019;s experiences. Integr Cancer Ther. 2018;17(1):16&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5950941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28008778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzoni AS, Carlsson M, Berntsen S, Nordin K, Demmelmaier I. Finding my own motivation" - a mixed methods study of exercise and behaviour change support during oncological treatment. Int J Behav Med. 2019;26(5):499&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6785591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31441015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Vulpen JK, Sweegers MG, Peeters PHM, Courneya KS, Newton RU, Aaronson NK, et al. Moderators of exercise effects on cancer-related fatigue: a meta-analysis of individual patient data. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52(2):303&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6962544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31524827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deutsche Krebsgesellschaft e.V., Deutsche Krebshilfe. Interdisziplin&#xe4;re S3-Leitlinie f&#xfc;r die Fr&#xfc;herkennung, Diagnostik, Therapie und Nachsorge des Mammakarzinoms. In: Arbeitsgemeinschaft der Wissenschaftlichen Medizinischen Fachgesellschaften (AWMF). 2021. https://register.awmf.org/assets/guidelines/032-045OLl_S3_Mammakarzinom_2021-07.pdf. Accessed 5 Jul 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oun R, Moussa YE, Wheate NJ. The side effects of platinum-based chemotherapy drugs: a review for chemists. Dalton Trans. 2018;47(19):6645&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29632935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Minckwitz G, Huang CS, Mano MS, Loibl S, Mamounas EP, Untch M, et al. Trastuzumab emtansine for residual invasive HER2-positive breast cancer. N Engl J Med. 2019;380(7):617&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30516102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan AR, Im SA, Mattar A, Colomer R, Stroyakovskii D, Nowecki Z, et al. Fixed-dose combination of pertuzumab and trastuzumab for subcutaneous injection plus chemotherapy in HER2-positive early breast cancer (FeDeriCa): a randomised, open-label, multicentre, non-inferiority, phase 3 study. Lancet Oncol. 2021;22(1):85&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33357420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Schoot GGF, Ormel HL, Westerink NL, May AM, Elias SG, Hummel YM, et al. Optimal timing of a physical exercise intervention to improve cardiorespiratory fitness: during or after chemotherapy. JACC CardioOncol. 2022;4(4):491&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9700259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36444224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou R, Chen Z, Zhang S, Wang Y, Zhang C, Lv Y, et al. Effects of exercise on cancer-related fatigue in breast cancer patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Life. 2024;14(8):1011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11355832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39202753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musoro JZ, Coens C, Sprangers MAG, Brandberg Y, Groenvold M, Flechtner HH, et al. Minimally important differences for interpreting EORTC QLQ-C30 change scores over time: a synthesis across 21 clinical trials involving nine different cancer types. Eur J Cancer. 2023;188:171&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37257278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Vulpen JK, Peeters PH, Velthuis MJ, van der Wall E, May AM. Effects of physical exercise during adjuvant breast cancer treatment on physical and psychosocial dimensions of cancer-related fatigue: a meta-analysis. Maturitas. 2016;85:104&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26857888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belloni S, Arrigoni C, Arcidiacono MA, Baroni I, Conte G, Dellafiore F, et al. A systematic review of systematic reviews and pooled meta-analysis on psychosocial interventions for improving cancer-related fatigue. Semin Oncol Nurs. 2023;39(3):151354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36379818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo UG, Berton A, De Salvatore S, Piergentili I, Casciani E, Faldetta A, et al. Minimal clinically important difference and patient acceptable symptom state for the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index in patients who underwent rotator cuff tear repair. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(16):8666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8391581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34444415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers LQ, Courneya KS, Oster RA, Anton PM, Robbs RS, Forero A, et al. Physical Activity and Sleep Quality in Breast Cancer Survivors: A Randomized Trial. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49(10):2009&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5600650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28538261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalter J, Buffart LM, Korstjens I, van Weert E, Brug J, de Verdonck- Leeuw IM, et al. Moderators of the effects of group-based physical exercise on cancer survivors&#x2019; quality of life. Support Care Cancer. 2015;23(9):2623&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4519631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25680762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzoni AS, Helgesen Bj&#xf8;rke AC, Stenling A, B&#xf6;rjeson S, Sj&#xf6;vall K, Berntsen S, et al. The role of long-term physical activity in relation to cancer-related health outcomes: a 12-month follow-up of the Phys-Can RCT. Integr Cancer Ther. 2023;22:15347354231178869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10331773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37358262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>