<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41361020</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1567-2387</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of molecular histology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Mol Histol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Modulation of placental inflammation by Azadirachta indica in rat models of diabetes-induced maternal and fetal complications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9</StartPage><MedlinePgn>9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10735-025-10658-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Maternal diabetes mellitus (MDM) is associated with an increased risk of fetal and placental malformations compared with normal pregnancies. The leaf extract of Azadirachta indica (neem) has been employed as a bioactive agent with proven antidiabetic potential. Beyond its hypoglycemic effects, neem extract has been reported to reduce inflammatory markers, ameliorate insulin resistance, and enhance blood circulation. In the present study, pregnant female rats were allocated into four experimental groups: (I) control (C), (II) neem-treated (N), (III) type 2 diabetes mellitus-induced (D), and (IV) diabetic pregnant rats treated with neem extract (D&#x2009;+&#x2009;N). Diabetic dams exhibited marked elevations in serum glucose, insulin, and lipid profile parameters. Moreover, a significant increase in IFN-&#x3b3; and IFN-&#x3b3;/IL-10 ratio, accompanied by a significant reduction in IL-10 levels, was recorded in comparison with controls. Treatment of diabetic dams with neem extract resulted in significant improvements in maternal body weight, reproductive performance, and fetal morphology relative to untreated diabetic rats. Histopathological examination of placental tissues revealed that neem supplementation normalized the decidual layer, increased its thickness, and enhanced the structure of the junctional zone (JZ) and labyrinth zone (LZ) compared to diabetic controls. In conclusion, administration of Azadirachta indica leaf extract demonstrated protective effects against diabetes-induced alterations in pregnancy. It improved maternal metabolic and inflammatory profiles, enhanced reproductive outcomes, and preserved the histological integrity of placental tissues in diabetic rats.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature B.V.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abou-El-Naga</LastName><ForeName>Amoura M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6369-5909</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zoology Department, Faculty of Science, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El Ghaweet</LastName><ForeName>Heba Atef</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4310-7564</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zoology Department, Faculty of Science, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdeen</LastName><ForeName>Sherif Helmy</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zoology Department, Faculty of Science, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Sheikhe</LastName><ForeName>Zeinab Sobh</ForeName><Initials>ZS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zoology Department, Faculty of Science, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Halim Mansour</LastName><ForeName>Hend Abd</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6044-7312</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zoology and Entomology Department, Faculty of Science, Al-Azhar University, Nasr City, Cairo, Egypt. hendmansour.sci.g@azhar.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Mol Histol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101193653</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1567-2379</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010936">Plant Extracts</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001786">Blood Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D031601" MajorTopicYN="Y">Azadirachta</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010936" MajorTopicYN="Y">Plant Extracts</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010920" MajorTopicYN="Y">Placenta</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003921" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Experimental</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="Y">Inflammation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001786" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Glucose</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Azadirachta indica</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fetal malformation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">INF-&#x3b3;/IL-10 ratio</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Maternal diabetes mellitus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neem</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Placenta</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Ethics Committee of the Laboratory Animals of the Faculty of Science, Mansoura University (serial No. Sci-Z-M-2020-80). The experiment adhered to the National Institutes of Health's guidelines outlined in their publication (NIH Publication No. 85-23, revised 1996) regarding the care and utilization of laboratory animals. Consent to publish: Not applicable</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41361020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10735-025-10658-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10735-025-10658-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abd El-Kareem MS, Rabbih MAEF, Selim ETM, Elsherbiny EAEM, El-Khateeb AY (2016) Application of GC/EIMS in combination with semi-empirical calculations for identification and investigation of some volatile components in Basil essential oil. Int J Anal Mass Spectrom Chromatogr 4(1):14&#x2013;25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ijamsc.2016.41002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou-El-Naga AM, Mansour HAEH, El-Sawi MR, El-Dein MA, Tag YM, Ghanem RA, Shawki MA (2025) Restorative effects of momordica Charantia extract on cerebellar GFAP and NGF expression in pregnant diabetic rats and their offspring. PLoS ONE 20(4):e0321022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40184394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11970674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0321022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aires MB, Dos Santos ACV (2015) Effects of maternal diabetes on trophoblast cells. World J Diabetes 6:338</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25789116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4239/wjd.v6.i2.338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allain CC, Poon LS, Chan CS, Richmond W, FU P C (1974) Enzymatic determination of total serum cholesterol. Clin Chem 20:470&#x2013;475</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4818200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/clinchem/20.4.470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzohairy MA (2016) Therapeutics role of Azadirachta indica (Neem) and their active constituents in diseases prevention and treatment. Evidence-Based Complement Altern Med 2016:1&#x2013;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/7382506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andlib N, Sajad M, Thakur SC (2024) Association of diabetes mellitus with risk of reproductive impairment in females: A comprehensive review. Acta Histochem 126(5&#x2013;7):152173</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39004007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.acthis.2024.152173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atwa A, Sobhy N, Latif A K M A, Bakry S (2025) Mitigation of cyclophosphamide-induced premature ovarian insufficiency in rats through bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells and placental extract therapy: a comprehensive evaluation. Beni-Suef Univ J Basic Appl Sci 14(1):15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43088-025-00604-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bitzur R, Cohen H, Kamari Y, Shaish A, Harats D (2009) Triglycerides and HDL cholesterol: stars or second leads in diabetes? Diabetes Care 32:373&#x2013;377</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc09-S343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;sa-eipper C, Leonard JR, Putcha G, Zheng TS, Flavell RA, Rakic P, Kuida K, Roth KA (2001) DNA damage-induced neural precursor cell apoptosis requires p53 and caspase 9 but neither Bax nor caspase 3. Development 128:137&#x2013;146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11092819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/dev.128.1.137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dallaqua B, Saito FH, Rodrigues T, Calderon IMP, Rudge MVC, Herrera E, Damasceno DC (2012a) Treatment with Azadirachta indica in diabetic pregnant rats: negative effects on maternal outcome. J Ethnopharmacol 143:805&#x2013;811</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22921950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2012.07.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dallaqua B, Saito FH, Rodrigues T, Calderon IMP, Rudge MVC, Herrera E, Damasceno DC (2012b) Treatment with Azadirachta indica in diabetic pregnant rats: negative effects on maternal outcome. J Ethnopharmacol 143(3):805&#x2013;811</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22921950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2012.07.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damasceno D, Volpato G, Calderon I D M P, Aguilar R, Rudge MC (2004) Effect of bauhinia forficata extract in diabetic pregnant rats: maternal repercussions. Phytomedicine 11:196&#x2013;201</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15070172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1078/0944-7113-00348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damasceno DC, Silva HP, Vaz GF, Vasques-silva FA, Calderon IMP, Rudge MVC, Campos KE, Volpato GT (2013) Diabetic rats exercised prior to and during pregnancy: maternal reproductive outcome, biochemical profile, and frequency of fetal anomalies. Reproductive Sci 20:730&#x2013;738</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1933719112461186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damasceno DC, Netto A, Iessi I, Gallego F, Corvino S, Dallaqua B, Sinzato Y, Bueno A, Calderon IDM, Rudge MVC (2014) Streptozotocin-induced diabetes models: pathophysiological mechanisms and fetal outcomes. Biomed Res Int 2014:1&#x2013;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2014/819065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das AR, Mostofa M, Hoque ME, Das S, Sarkar AK (2010) Comparative efficacy of Neem (Azadirachta Indica) and Metformin hydrochloride (comet<sup>&#xae;</sup>) in streptozotocin induced diabetes melitus in rats. Bangladesh J Veterinary Med 8(1):75&#x2013;80</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3329/bjvm.v8i1.8353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimeji I, Kayode A, Ikponmwosa A (2022) Role of in-utero Neem leaf (Azadirachta indica) supplemented diet on some hematological parameters and glucose storage in offspring of Wistar rats. Int J Curr Res Physiol Pharmacol 2022:1&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eid FA, Shoman HH, Abu Elnaga NA, Abed El-Halim H (2014) Effect of Olive leaf extract on the kidney of pregnant diabetic rats and their fetuses. Int J Adv Res 2(11):740&#x2013;776</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Beltagy AEFB, Abou El-Naga AM, El-Habibi ESM, Shams S E S, M (2020) Ameliorative role of Neem (Azadiracta indica) leaves ethanolic extract on testicular injury of neonatally diabetic rats induced by streptozotocin. Egypt J Basic Appl Sci 7(1):210&#x2013;225</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-nabarawy SK (2014) Oxidative damage in embryo and placenta of Streptozotocin-induced diabetic rats. Egypt J Hosp Med 31:1&#x2013;10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elnahas SM, Mansour HA, El-Sawi MR, Abou-El-Naga AM (2024) Therapeutic effect of momordica Charantia on cardiomyopathy in a diabetic maternal rat model. J Experimental Zool Part A: Ecol Integr Physiol 341(9):977&#x2013;990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jez.2854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farias PS, Dos Santos Souza K, Mar&#xe7;al AC, Fioretto ET, Aires MB (2014) Altered placental morphology and VEGF expression in diabetic rats. 2014:285&#x2013;290</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasoulakis Z, Koutras A, Antsaklis P, Theodora M, Valsamaki A, Daskalakis G, Kontomanolis EN (2023) Intrauterine growth restriction due to gestational diabetes: from pathophysiology to diagnosis and management. Medicina 59(6):1139</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37374343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10305438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/medicina59061139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fassati P, Prencipe L (1982) Triglycerides enzymetic colorimetric method. Clin Chem 28:2077&#x2013;2081</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedewald WT, Levy RI, Fredrickson DS (1972) Estimation of the concentration of low-density lipoprotein cholesterol in plasma, without use of the preparative ultracentrifuge. Clin Chem 18:499&#x2013;502</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4337382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/clinchem/18.6.499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gad ES, Aldossary SA, El-Ansary MR, Abd El-Galil MM, Abd-El-Hamid AH, El-Ansary AR, Hassan NF (2025) Cilostazol counteracts mitochondrial dysfunction in hepatic encephalopathy rat model: Insights into the role of cAMP/AMPK/SIRT1/PINK-1/parkin hub and p-CREB/BDNF/TrkB neuroprotective trajectory. European Journal of Pharmacology 987: 177194</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallego FQ, Barco VS, Sinzato YK, Paula VG, de Souza MR, da Cruz LL, Damasceno DC (2024) Effect of transgenerational diabetes via maternal lineage in female rats. Heliyon 10(10)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garris DR (1988) Effects of diabetes on uterine condition, decidualization, vascularization, and corpus luteum function in the pseudopregnant rat. Endocrinology 122:665&#x2013;672</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3276500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/endo-122-2-665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H, Zhang Q, Li R, Seshadri VD (2023) Nigericin abrogates maternal and embryonic oxidative stress in the Streptozotocin-Induced diabetic pregnant rats. Appl Biochem Biotechnol 195(2):801&#x2013;815</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36190644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12010-022-04100-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutierrez RMP, G&#xf3;mez Y G Y, Guzman MD (2011) Attenuation of nonenzymatic glycation, hyperglycemia, and hyperlipidemia in streptozotocin-induced diabetic rats by chloroform leaf extract of Azadirachta indica. Pharmacognosy Magazine 7:254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21969798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3173902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0973-1296.84243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammad R, Abdel Wahab MA, Farouk N, Zakaria MY, Eldosoky MA, Elmadbouly AA, Abd Elghany, R A E (2023) Non-classical monocytes frequency and serum vitamin D3 levels are linked to diabetic foot ulcer associated with peripheral artery disease. J Diabetes Invest 14(10):1192&#x2013;1201</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdi.14048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han HK, Choi EY (2023) Effects of taraxacum Mongolicum extract on blood glucose levels and lipid profiles in Streptozotocin-Induced diabetic rats. Korean J Food Nutr 36(1):50&#x2013;57</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayat M (1989) Principles and techniques of electron microscopy, biological applications, vol 453. Macmillan, New York, pp 229&#x2013;230</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-349-09857-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyman L, Houri-haddad Y, Heyman SN, Ginsburg I, Gleitman Y, Feuerstein O (2017) Combined antioxidant effects of Neem extract, bacteria, red blood cells and lysozyme: possible relation to periodontal disease. BMC Complement Altern Med 17:399</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28797303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5553582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12906-017-1900-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussein HA, El-Garhy IM, Sedek AEM (2021) Ultrasonographic measurement of placental thickness as a predictor of fetal birth weight. Al-Azhar Med J 50(1):407&#x2013;418</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/amj.2021.139733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiss AC, Lima PH, Sinzato YK, Takaku M, Takeno MA, Rudge MV, Damasceno DC (2009) Animal models for clinical and gestational diabetes: maternal and fetal outcomes. Diabetol Metab Syndr 1:21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19840387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2770456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1758-5996-1-21</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koul A, Mohan V, Bharati S (2014) Azadirachta indica mitigates DMBA-induced hepatotoxicity: a biochemical and radiometric study. J B B 51(1):37&#x2013;45</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar VS, Navaratnam V (2013) Neem (Azadirachta indica): prehistory to contemporary medicinal uses to humankind. Asian Pac J Trop Biomed 3:505&#x2013;514</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23835719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3695574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2221-1691(13)60105-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ku&#x17a;micki M, Szamatowicz J, Kretowski A, Ku&#x107; P, Kretowski M, Wawrusiewicz N, Okruszko A, Leroith D, G&#xf3;rska M (2006) Evaluation of adiponectin and TNFalpha genes expression in women with gestational diabetes. Preliminary results. Ginekologia Polska 77:930&#x2013;936</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17373119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Liu H, Shang L (2023) Tert-butylhydroquinone mitigates renal dysfunction in pregnant diabetic rats via Attenuation of oxidative stress and modulation of the iNOs/NFkB/TNF alpha signalling Pathway. Endocrine, metabolic &amp; immune Disorders-Drug targets (Formerly current drug targets-Immune. Endocr Metabolic Disorders) 23(5):633&#x2013;646</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li QR, Xu HY, Ma RT, Ma YY, Chen MJ (2024) Targeting autophagy: A promising therapeutic strategy for diabetes mellitus and diabetic nephropathy. Diabetes Therapy 2:1&#x2013;30</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malekifard F, Delirezh N, Hobbenaghi R, Malekinejad H (2015) Immunotherapeutic effects of Pentoxifylline in type 1 diabetic mice and its role in the response of T-helper lymphocytes. Iran J Basic Med Sci 18:247</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25945237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4414990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCalla GA, Brown PD (2024) Suitability of the Neonatal Streptozotocin Diabetes Model and Folklore Therapeutic use of Low-Dose Neem Leaf Extract to Treat Hyperglycemia Associated with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus. Tropical Journal of Natural Product Research 2024; 8(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mccalla G, Parshad O, Brown P, Gardner M (2016) Beta cell regenerating potential of Azadirachta indica (Neem) extract in diabetic rats. West Indian Med J 65:13&#x2013;17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Q, Shao L, Luo X, Mu Y, Xu W, Gao C, Gao L, Liu J, Cui Y (2015) Ultrastructure of placenta of gravidas with gestational diabetes mellitus. Obstet Gynecol Int (1): 283124</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathy Mongy E, El-Arab Ali El-Arab N, Kamal Ramadan S, Yousef El-Saeed B M (2017) Effects of adipose tissue mesenchymal stem cell therapy on diabetic rats. Al-Azhar Med J 46(1):193&#x2013;210</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12816/0035548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray R, Kaplan A (1984) Clin chem the CV Mosby Co. St Louis Tor Princet 4:1261&#x2013;1266</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Offor C (2015) Comparative anti-diabetic effects of the ethanol leaf-extracts of Vernonia amygdalina and Azadirachta indica in albino rats. Int J Curr Microbiol App Sci 4(1):201&#x2013;209</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okada M, Matsui H, Ito Y, Fujiwara A, Inano K (1998) Low-density lipoprotein cholesterol can be chemically measured: a new superior method. J Lab Clin Med 132:195&#x2013;201</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9735925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-2143(98)90168-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ornoy A, Becker M, Weinstein-Fudim L, Ergaz Z (2021) Diabetes during pregnancy: A maternal disease complicating the course of pregnancy with long-term deleterious effects on the offspring. A clinical review. Int J Mol Sci 22:2965</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33803995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7999044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22062965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patry M, Teinturier R, Goehrig D, Zetu C, Ripoche D, Kim IS, Hennino A (2015) &#x3b2;ig-h3 represses T-cell activation in type 1 diabetes. Diabetes 64(12):4212&#x2013;4219</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26470788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db15-0638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Ramirez CA, Nakano H, Law RC, Matulionis N, Thompson J, Pfeiffer A, Christofk HR (2024) Atlas of fetal metabolism during mid-to-late gestation and diabetic pregnancy. Cell 187(1):204&#x2013;215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38070508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2023.11.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietro L, Daher S, Rudge MVC, Calderon I D M P, Damasceno DC, Sinzato YK, Bandeira C, Bevilacqua E (2010) Vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) and VEGF-receptor expression in placenta of hyperglycemic pregnant women. Placenta 31:770&#x2013;780</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20674013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.placenta.2010.07.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinheiro MS, Rodrigues LS, Sneto L, Moraes-Souza RQ, Soares TS, Americo MF, Campos KE, Damasceno DC, Volpato GT (2017) Effect of bauhinia holophylla treatment in Streptozotocin-induced diabetic rats. An Acad Bras Cienc 89:263&#x2013;272</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28225851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/0001-3765201720160050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasineni K, Bellamkonda R, Singareddy SR, Desireddy S (2010) Antihyperglycemic activity of catharanthus roseus leaf powder in streptozotocin-induced diabetic rats. Pharmacognosy Res 2:195</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21808566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3141314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0974-8490.65523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reece EA, Ma XD, Zhao Z, Wu YK, Dhanasekaran D (2005) Aberrant patterns of cellular communication in diabetes-induced embryopathy in rats: II, apoptotic pathways. Am J Obstet Gynecol 192:967&#x2013;972</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15746699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajog.2004.10.592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossouw M, Nel HJ, Cooke GS, Van Helden PD, Hoal EG (2003) Association between tuberculosis and a polymorphic NF&#x3ba;B binding site in the interferon &#x3b3; gene. Lancet 361:1871&#x2013;1872</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12788577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(03)13491-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito FH, Damasceno DC, Kempinas WG, Morceli G, Sinzato YK, Taylor KN, Rudge MV (2010) Repercussions of mild diabetes on pregnancy in Wistar rats and on the fetal development. Diabetology &amp; metabolic syndrome 2010; 2: 26</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleh MN, Hassan SA, Mahmoud FY, Shenouda MB (2017) The effect of maternal-induced diabetes on postnatal development of the paraventricular and ventromedial hypothalamic nuclei in albino rats: a histological, immunohistochemical, and morphometric study. J Curr Med Res Pract 2:47</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/JCMRP.JCMRP_34_16</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah NS, Wang MC, Freaney PM, Perak AM, Carnethon MR, Kandula NR, Gunderson EP, Bullard KM, Grobman WA, O&#x2019;Brien MJ (2021) Trends in gestational diabetes at first live birth by race and ethnicity in the US, 2011&#x2013;2019. J A M A 326:660&#x2013;669</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34402831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8371572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2021.7217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharp AN, Heazell AE, Crocker IP, Mor G (2010) Placental apoptosis in health and disease. Am J Reprod Immunol 64:159&#x2013;169</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20367628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3025811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0897.2010.00837.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinzato Y, Damasceno DC, Laufer-Amorim R, Rodrigues M, Oshiiwa M, Taylor K, Rudge MVC (2011) Plasma concentrations and placental immunostaining of interleukin-10 and tumornecrosis factor-&#x3b1; as predictors of alterations in the embryo-fetal organism and the placental development of diabetic rats. Braz J Med Biol Res 44:206&#x2013;211</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21344139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0100-879X2011007500015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinzato YK, Volpato GT, Iessi IL, Bueno A, Calderon IDMP, Rudge MVC, Damasceno DC (2012) Neonatally induced mild diabetes in rats and its effect on maternal, placental, and fetal parameters. Experimental Diabetes Res 2012:1&#x2013;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2012/108163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spyratos F (1993) DNA content and cell cycle analysis by flow cytometry in clinical samples: application in breast cancer. Biol Cell 78:69&#x2013;72</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7693120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0248-4900(93)90116-V</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunarwidhi AL, Sudarsono S, Nugroho AE (2014) Hypoglycemic effect of combination of Azadirachta indica A. Juss. And Gynura procumbens (Lour.) Merr. Ethanolic extracts standardized by Rutin And Quercetin in alloxan-induced hyperglycemic rats. Adv Pharm Bull 4:613&#x2013;618</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25671197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung N, Salazar Garc&#xed;a MD, Dambaeva S, Beaman KD, Gilman Sachs A, Kwak Kim J (2016) Gonadotropin releasing hormone analogues lead to pro inflammatory changes in T lymphocytes. Am J Reprod Immunol 76(1):50&#x2013;58</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27293115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aji.12522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatke P, Desai S, Gabhe S (2014) Isolation of Quercetin-3-O-&#x3b2;-D-Glucoside from Azadirachta indica. Am J Phytomedicine Clin Ther 2:870&#x2013;876</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thoh M, Kumar P, Nagarajaram HA, Manna SK (2010) Azadirachtin interacts with the tumor necrosis factor (TNF) binding domain of its receptors and inhibits TNF-induced biological responses. J Biol Chem 285(8):5888&#x2013;5895</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20018848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M109.065847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinker SC, Gilboa SM, Moore CA, Waller DK, Simeone RM, Kim SY, Jamieson DJ, Botto LD, Reefhuis J, Study NBDP (2020) Specific birth defects in pregnancies of women with diabetes: National birth defects prevention Study, 1997&#x2013;2011. Am J Obstet Gynecol 222:171&#x2013;176</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajog.2019.08.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umar SZ, Osibemhe M, Ganiyu AI (2024) Antidiabetic potential of Azadirachta indica aqueous leaves extract on Streptozotocin-Induced diabetic Wistar rats. Bulletins Nat Appl Sci 1(2):129&#x2013;137</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vambergue A, Fajardy I (2011) Consequences of gestational and pregestational diabetes on placental function and birth weight. World J Diabetes 2:196</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22087356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3215769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4239/wjd.v2.i11.196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergallo C, Panzarini E, Dini L (2019) High performance liquid chromatographic profiling of antioxidant and antidiabetic flavonoids purified from Azadirachta indica (neem) leaf ethanolic extract. Pure Appl Chem 91(10):1631&#x2013;1640</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/pac-2018-1221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volpato GT, Damasceno DC, Sinzato YK, Ribeiro VM, Rudge MVC, Calderon, I M P (2012) Oxidative stress status and placental implications in diabetic rats undergoing swimming exercise after embryonic implantation. Reproductive Sci 22:602&#x2013;608</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1933719114556485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousef Yousef Ghaly A, Maged Abd El-aal H, Mahmoud Awad A, Ali Faheem Abdo A (2023) ) evaluation of fetal cardiac function by fetal echocardiography in pregnant diabetic patients. Al-Azhar Med J 52(2):555&#x2013;570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/amj.2023.291648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>