<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41238072</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1552-6259</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Annals of thoracic surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Thorac Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>One-Year Results of Novel Aortic Arch Hybrid Prosthesis for Repair of Acute DeBakey Type I Dissection With Malperfusion: PERSEVERE Study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0003-4975(25)01111-7</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.athoracsur.2025.10.036</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">High rates of major adverse events and negative aortic remodeling are common after hemiarch repair for acute DeBakey type I aortic dissection. The ProspEctive, Single ARm, Multi-center Clinical InveStigation to EValuatE the Safety and Effectiveness of AMDS in the TREatment of Acute DeBakey Type I Dissection (PERSEVERE; NCT05174767) study evaluated 1-year outcomes with the AMDS Hybrid Prosthesis i(Artivion, Inc) n patients with malperfusion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">PERSEVERE is a prospective, single arm study. Primary end point events of mortality, new disabling stroke, new renal failure requiring dialysis, myocardial infarction, and rate of distal anastomotic new entry (DANE) tears were assessed through 1 year. Reoperation, aortic patency, and changes in aortic remodeling, including total aortic growth, true lumen expansion, and false lumen thrombosis, were also reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of 93 enrolled patients, 63 (68%) completed 1-year follow-up, and 56 patients had a computed tomographic angiogram. Through 1 year, 19 (20%) patients died, 11 (12%) had new disabling strokes, 19 (20%) required dialysis, and 2 (2%) had a myocardial infarction; most events Occurred within 30 days. DANE was not documented in any postoperative computed tomographic angiograms. Freedom from unanticipated aortic reoperations and occlusion in the arch was 96% (89 of 93) and 100% (91 of 91), respectively. Freedom from total aortic growth at 1 year was 100% in zone 1, 98.2% in zone 2, and 73.2% in zone 3. In zones 1 to 3, true lumen expansion occurred in 96%, 94%, and 70% of patients, respectively. In zones 1 to 3, false lumen thrombosis occurred in 91%, 92%, and 88% of patients, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The 1-year outcomes with the AMDS Hybrid Prosthesis are encouraging, with lower than observed mortality, limited primary events after 30 days, and the absence of DANE. There is evidence of positive aortic remodeling. Follow-up is ongoing.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025. Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Szeto</LastName><ForeName>Wilson Y</ForeName><Initials>WY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiovascular Surgery, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Electronic address: wilson.szeto@pennmedicine.upenn.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fukuhara</LastName><ForeName>Shinichi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiac Surgery, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fleischman</LastName><ForeName>Fernando</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>USC Cardiac and Vascular Institute, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sultan</LastName><ForeName>Ibrahim</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiac Surgery, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brinkman</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiac Surgery Specialists, Thoracic Aortic Clinic, The Heart Hospital Baylor Plano, Plano, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arnaoutakis</LastName><ForeName>George</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiovascular and Thoracic Surgery, Dell Medical School, University of Texas at Austin, Austin, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takayama</LastName><ForeName>Hiroo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiac, Thoracic, and Vascular Surgery, Columbia University, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eudailey</LastName><ForeName>Kyle</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiothoracic Surgery, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jassar</LastName><ForeName>Arminder</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiac Surgery, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moon</LastName><ForeName>Michael C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiac Surgery, Department of Surgery, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>PERSEVERE Investigators</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Thorac Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>15030100R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0003-4975</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Disclosures All authors are PERSEVERE site investigators and/or have consulting agreements related to their duties as Steering Committee members. Wilson Y. Szeto reports a relationship with Abbott Cardiovascular that includes: consulting or advisory and speaking and lecture fees; with Artivion, Inc that includes: consulting or advisory and speaking and lecture fees; with Edwards Lifesciences that includes: consulting or advisory and speaking and lecture fees; with Medtronic that includes: consulting or advisory and speaking and lecture fees; and with Terumo Aortic that includes: consulting or advisory and speaking and lecture fees. Shinichi Fukuhara reports a relationship with Artivion, Inc that includes: consulting or advisory and speaking and lecture fees; with Edwards Lifesciences that includes: consulting or advisory and speaking and lecture fees; with Medtronic that includes: consulting or advisory and speaking and lecture fees; and with Terumo Aortic that includes: consulting or advisory and speaking and lecture fees. Fernando Fleischman reports a relationship with W.L. Gore &amp; Associates that includes: consulting or advisory; with Artivion, Inc that includes: consulting or advisory; with Terumo Aortic that includes: consulting or advisory; with Edwards Lifesciences that includes: consulting or advisory; and with Cook Medical that includes: consulting or advisory. Ibrahim Sultan reports a relationship with Abbott that includes: consulting or advisory; with Artivion, Inc that includes: consulting or advisory; with AtriCure that includes: consulting or advisory; with Medtronic that includes: consulting or advisory; with Edwards Lifesciences that includes: consulting or advisory; with Terumo Aortic that includes: consulting or advisory; and with W.L. Gore &amp; Associates that includes: consulting or advisory. William Brinkman reports a relationship with W.L. Gore &amp; Associates that includes: consulting or advisory and speaking and lecture fees; with Terumo Aortic that includes: consulting or advisory and speaking and lecture fees; and with Artivion, Inc that includes: consulting or advisory and speaking and lecture fees. George Arnaoutakis reports a relationship with Medtronic that includes: consulting or advisory; with Artivion, Inc that includes: consulting or advisory; with Terumo Aortic that includes: consulting or advisory; and with Abbott that includes: consulting or advisory. Hiroo Takayama reports a relationship with Artivion, Inc that includes: consulting or advisory; and with Edwards Lifesciences that includes: consulting or advisory. Kyle Eudailey reports a relationship with Artivion, Inc that includes: consulting or advisory; with Terumo Aortic that includes: consulting or advisory and speaking and lecture fees; with Medtronic that includes: speaking and lecture fees; with Edwards Lifesciences that includes: speaking and lecture fees; and with Japan Lifeline Co that includes: consulting or advisory. Arminder Jassar reports a relationship with Terumo Aortic that includes: consulting or advisory; and with Artivion, Inc that includes: consulting or advisory. Michael C. Moon reports a relationship with Artivion, Inc that includes: consulting or advisory; with Edwards Lifesciences that includes: consulting or advisory; with AtriCure Inc that includes: consulting or advisory; and with Corcym SRL that includes: consulting or advisory.</CoiStatement><InvestigatorList><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frederick</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Atrium Health Sanger Heart &amp; Vascular Institute Kenilworth, Charlotte, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moon</LastName><ForeName>Marc</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baylor St. Luke's Medical Center, Houston, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vargo</LastName><ForeName>Patrick</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery Cleveland Clinic Foundation, Cleveland, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leshnower</LastName><ForeName>Bradley</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emory Heart &amp; Vascular Center Atlanta, Georgia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheema</LastName><ForeName>Mohiuddin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hartford Hospital, Hartford, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramlawi</LastName><ForeName>Basel</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lankenau Medical Center, Wynnewood, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DeRose</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Montefiore Einstein, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Hamamsy</LastName><ForeName>Ismail</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeigler</LastName><ForeName>Sanford</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical University of South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brinster</LastName><ForeName>Derek</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lenox Hill Hospital, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malaisrie</LastName><ForeName>Chris</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northwestern School of Medicine, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhamidipati</LastName><ForeName>Castigliano</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oregon Health and Science University, Portland, Oregon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watkins</LastName><ForeName>Amelia Claire</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stanford University, Stanford, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeng</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Florida College of Medicine, Gainesville, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reece</LastName><ForeName>Brett T</ForeName><Initials>BT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Colorado School of Medicine, Aurora, Colorado.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grimm</LastName><ForeName>Joshua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kachroo</LastName><ForeName>Puja</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Washington University, St Louis, Missouri.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Investigator></InvestigatorList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41238072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.athoracsur.2025.10.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0003-4975(25)01111-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>