<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41540208</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1084</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European radiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur Radiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimizing prostate cancer treatment with MR-guided focused ultrasound: the role of expanded ablation-to-lesion volume ratio.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00330-025-12217-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine which treatment parameters optimize focal therapy for intermediate-risk prostate cancer by balancing oncologic control with healthy tissue preservation, in a phase 2b multicenter trial of MRI-guided Focused Ultrasound (MRgFUS). Additionally, to assess the relationship of ablation volume relative to lesion volume with oncologic outcomes, urinary, and erectile function.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this retrospective interpretation of prospectively acquired data, the non-perfused volume (NPV) of prostate tissue encompassing the MRI-visible lesion volume defined the ablation-volume-to-lesion-volume ratio (ALVR). Oncologic efficacy was assessed as the absence of clinically significant (GGG&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;2) cancer in the treatment zone at 24-month biopsy. Associations between ALVR and outcomes were assessed using Student's t-tests. Baseline characteristics were compared using Kruskal-Wallis tests.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Eighty-nine men (mean age,&#xa0;63 years&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;7) had MRI-visible lesions with a volume of 0.47&#x2009;mL (IQR: 0.20-0.95), with a surrounding NPV of 6.9&#x2009;mL (IQR: 5.2-10.4). Men achieving oncologic efficacy had twice the ALVR compared to those with recurrence at the treatment site (17 vs 8, mean difference 8.8, 95% CI: 2.1, 16, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.013). Increasing NPV relative to total prostate volume did not improve oncologic outcomes. Baseline characteristics did not significantly differ between men with and without GGG&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;2 at 24-month biopsy. ALVR did not differ in men with new erectile dysfunction (mean difference in ALVR: 2.1, 95% CI: -12, 16, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.8) or urinary symptoms (mean difference in ALVR 4.0, 95% CI: -21, 29, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.71).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In patients with intermediate-risk prostate cancer, higher ALVR was associated with superior 2-year oncologic outcomes without increased risk of urinary or erectile dysfunction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="KEY POINTS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Question What treatment parameters optimize focal therapy for prostate cancer by balancing healthy tissue preservation with favorable oncologic outcomes? Findings Patients without residual cancer at 24-month biopsy had twice the ALVR of those with recurrence, with no adverse impact on erectile or urinary function. Clinical relevance While fixed intra-prostatic margins (e.g., 5&#x2009;mm or 10&#x2009;mm) are commonly prescribed in focal therapy, this study highlights the importance of scaling the ALVR in the treatment plan to achieve sufficient oncologic coverage.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to European Society of Radiology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bitton</LastName><ForeName>Rachelle R</ForeName><Initials>RR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2824-8978</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, USA. rbitton@stanford.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vertosick</LastName><ForeName>Emily</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Memorial Sloan Cancer Center, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khandwala</LastName><ForeName>Yash</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Korol</LastName><ForeName>Gena</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Insightec Inc, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vickers</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Memorial Sloan Cancer Center, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ehdaie</LastName><ForeName>Behfar</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Memorial Sloan Cancer Center, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sonn</LastName><ForeName>Geoffrey</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghanouni</LastName><ForeName>Pejman</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P30-CA008748</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P30-CA008748</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur Radiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9114774</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0938-7994</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Eur Radiol. 2026 Jan 16. doi: 10.1007/s00330-025-12245-1.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">41543566</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ablation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Focal therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Focused ultrasound (MR-guided)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High intensity focused ultrasound</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prostate cancer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Compliance with ethical standards. Guarantor: The scientific guarantor of this publication is Pejman Ghanouni, MD, PhD. Conflict of interest: The author G.K. of this manuscript declares relationships with the following companies: Author G.K. is a former employee of Insightec Inc. The remaining authors of this manuscript declare no relationships with any companies, whose products or services may be related to the subject matter of the article. Statistics and biometry: Emily Vertosick and Andrew Vickers kindly provided statistical advice for this manuscript. Two of the authors have significant statistical expertise. Informed consent: Only if the study is on human subjects: written informed consent was obtained from all subjects (patients) in this study. Ethical approval: Institutional Review Board approval was obtained. Study subjects or cohorts overlap: Some study subjects or cohorts have been previously reported in Ehdaie et al [5]. This study examined the cohort of 89 (of the 101 men treated in the parent trial) who had 24-month follow-up biopsy results in the treated area. While the parent trial reported on oncologic outcomes, the focus of this study was to evaluate the effect of expanded ablation margins around the MRI-visible tumor on oncologic and functional outcomes. The parent trial was published in The Lancet Oncology (NCT01657942). Methodology: Retrospective Observational Multicenter study</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41540208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-025-12217-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00330-025-12217-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hopstaken JS, Bomers JGR, Sedelaar MJP, Valerio M, F&#xfc;tterer JJ, Rovers MM (2022) An updated systematic review on focal therapy in localized prostate cancer: What has changed over the past 5 years? Eur Urol 81:5&#x2013;33</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eururo.2021.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34489140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed HU, Dickinson L, Charman S et al (2015) Focal ablation targeted to the index lesion in multifocal localised prostate cancer: a prospective development study. Eur Urol 68:927&#x2013;36</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eururo.2015.01.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25682339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valerio M, Ahmed HU, Emberton M et al (2014) The role of focal therapy in the management of localised prostate cancer: a systematic review. Eur Urol 66:732&#x2013;51</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eururo.2013.05.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23769825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4179888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy D, Peters M, Shah TT et al (2022) Cancer control outcomes following focal therapy using high-intensity focused ultrasound in 1379 men with nonmetastatic prostate cancer: a multi-institute 15-year experience. Eur Urol 81:407&#x2013;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eururo.2022.01.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35123819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehdaie B, Tempany CM, Holland F et al (2022) MRI-guided focused ultrasound focal therapy for patients with intermediate-risk prostate cancer: a phase 2b, multicentre study. Lancet Oncol 23:910&#x2013;918</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(22)00251-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35714666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9400094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghai S, Finelli A, Corr K et al (2024) MRI-guided focused ultrasound focal therapy for intermediate-risk prostate cancer: final results from a 2-year phase II clinical trial. Radiology 310:e231473</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.231473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38441092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stabile A, Orczyk C, Hosking-Jervis F et al (2019) Medium-term oncological outcomes in a large cohort of men treated with either focal or hemi-ablation using high-intensity focused ultrasonography for primary localized prostate cancer. BJU Int 124:431&#x2013;40</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bju.14710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30753756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eldred-Evans D, Tam H, Smith APT, Winkler M, Ahmed HU (2020) Use of imaging to optimise prostate cancer tumour volume assessment for focal therapy planning. Curr Urol Rep 21:38</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11934-020-00987-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32803471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7429546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslim EJ, Law YXT, Fook-Chong SMC et al (2021) Defining prostate cancer size and treatment margin for focal therapy: does intralesional heterogeneity impact the performance of multiparametric MRI? BJU Int 128:178&#x2013;186</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brisbane WG, Priester AM, Ballon J et al (2022) Targeted prostate biopsy: umbra, penumbra, and value of perilesional sampling. Eur Urol 82:303&#x2013;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eururo.2022.01.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35115177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackwell J, Kra&#x15b;ny MJ, O&#x2019;Brien A et al (2022) Proton resonance frequency shift thermometry: a review of modern clinical practices. J Magn Reson Imaging 55:389&#x2013;403</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmri.27446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33217099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barry MJ, Fowler FJ, O&#x2019;leary MP et al (2017) The American Urological Association symptom index for benign prostatic hyperplasia. J Urol. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.juro.2016.10.071</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen RC, Riley A, Wagner G, Osterloh IH, Kirkpatrick J, Mishra A (1997) The international index of erectile function (IIEF): a multidimensional scale for assessment of erectile dysfunction. Urology 49:822&#x2013;30</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0090-4295(97)00238-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9187685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham H, Averick M, Bryan J (2019) Welcome to the Tidyverse. J Open Source Softw 4:1686</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>RR Team (2014) R: a language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sjoberg DD, Whiting K, Curry M, Lavery J, Larmarange J (2021) Reproducible summary tables with the gtsummary package. R J 13:570&#x2013;80</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priester A, Natarajan S, Khoshnoodi P et al (2017) Magnetic resonance imaging underestimation of prostate cancer geometry: use of patient specific molds to correlate images with whole mount pathology. J Urol 197:320&#x2013;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.juro.2016.07.084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27484386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Nobin J, Rosenkrantz AB, Villers A et al (2015) Image guided focal therapy for magnetic resonance imaging visible prostate cancer: defining a 3-dimensional treatment margin based on magnetic resonance imaging histology co-registration analysis. J Urol 194:364&#x2013;70</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.juro.2015.02.080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25711199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4726648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anwar M, Westphalen AC, Jung AJ et al (2014) Role of endorectal MR imaging and MR spectroscopic imaging in defining treatable intraprostatic tumor foci in prostate cancer: Quantitative analysis of imaging contour compared to whole-mount histopathology. Radiother Oncol 110:303&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radonc.2013.12.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24444524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3969841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tay KJ, Cheng CWS, Lau WKO, Khoo J, Thng CH, Kwek JW (2017) Focal therapy for prostate cancer with in-bore MR-guided focused ultrasound: two-year follow-up of a phase I trial&#x2014;complications and functional outcomes. Radiology 285:620&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2017161650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28654336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priester A, Fan RE, Shubert J et al (2023) Prediction and mapping of intraprostatic tumor extent with artificial intelligence. Eur Urol Open Sci 54:20&#x2013;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euros.2023.05.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37545845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10403686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bitton RR, Shao W, Chodakeiwitz Y et al (2024) Intraprocedural diffusion-weighted imaging for predicting ablation zone during MRI-guided focused ultrasound of prostate cancer. Radiol Imaging Cancer 6:e240009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/rycan.240009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39212524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11449221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brisbane WG, Priester AM, Nguyen AV, Topoozian M et al (2024) Focal therapy of prostate cancer: use of artificial intelligence to define tumour volume and predict treatment outcomes. BJUI Compass 6:e456</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bco2.456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39877558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11771490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overduin CG, Jenniskens SFM, Sedelaar JPM, Bomers JGR, F&#xfc;tterer JJ (2017) Percutaneous MR-guided focal cryoablation for recurrent prostate cancer following radiation therapy: retrospective analysis of iceball margins and outcomes. Eur Radiol 27:4828&#x2013;36</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-017-4833-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28409355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5635095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>