<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41390751</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1601-5223</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>163</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Hereditas</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Hereditas</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>LINC01980 promotes the malignant progression of lung squamous carcinoma by targeting miR-204-3p.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>13</StartPage><MedlinePgn>13</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">13</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s41065-025-00617-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Lung squamous cell carcinoma (LUSC) is a prevalent and aggressive subtype of lung cancer. Although LINC01980 has been implicated in the development of several cancers, its specific mechanisms in LUSC remain unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Through GEO database analysis, LINC01980 was identified as aberrantly expressed in LUSC. Using LncBook 2.0, we predicted a target relationship between LINC01980 and miR-204-3p. Validation was performed using dual luciferase reporter assay and RNA pull-down experiments. An analysis of LUSC clinical samples and TCGA data revealed differential expressions of LINC01980 and miR-204-3p. The expression levels of these two molecules were quantified by RT-qPCR in both patient tissues and cell lines. To measure cell proliferation, the CCK-8 assay was applied. Apoptosis was evaluated via flow cytometry, whereas cell migration and invasion were investigated using the Transwell assay. Gene knockdown experiments demonstrated that LINC01980 influences malignant phenotypes in vitro by regulating miR-204-3p.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">LINC01980 was abundantly expressed in LUSC tissues and cell lines and significantly enhanced malignant activities including proliferation, migration, and invasion. Furthermore, LINC01980 promotes tumor progression by suppressing miR-204-3p expression. Rescue experiments confirmed that the depletion of miR-204-3p reverses the tumor-suppressive effects caused by LINC01980 knockdown, indicating that the oncogenic function of LINC01980 is dependent on its negative regulation of miR-204-3p.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">LINC01980 drives LUSC invasiveness by targeting miR-204-3p, providing new insights into its tumor-promoting role and underlying mechanisms.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Man</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrative Oncology, Tianjin Key Laboratory of Cancer Prevention and Therapy, Tianjin Medical University Cancer Institute &amp; Hospital, National Clinical Research Center for Cancer, Tianjin's Clinical Research Center for Cancer, 300060, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrative Oncology, Tianjin Cancer Hospital Airport Hospital, 300000, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Weiwei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Jingxi Medical District of The PLA General Hospital, Beijing, 100043, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Zhansheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrative Oncology, Tianjin Key Laboratory of Cancer Prevention and Therapy, Tianjin Medical University Cancer Institute &amp; Hospital, National Clinical Research Center for Cancer, Tianjin's Clinical Research Center for Cancer, 300060, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Zhanyu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrative Oncology, Tianjin Key Laboratory of Cancer Prevention and Therapy, Tianjin Medical University Cancer Institute &amp; Hospital, National Clinical Research Center for Cancer, Tianjin's Clinical Research Center for Cancer, 300060, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Zhuchen</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrative Oncology, Tianjin Key Laboratory of Cancer Prevention and Therapy, Tianjin Medical University Cancer Institute &amp; Hospital, National Clinical Research Center for Cancer, Tianjin's Clinical Research Center for Cancer, 300060, Tianjin, China. pozhuas7@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrative Oncology, Tianjin Cancer Hospital Airport Hospital, 300000, Tianjin, China. pozhuas7@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrative Oncology, Tianjin Key Laboratory of Cancer Prevention and Therapy, Department of Integrative Oncology, Tianjin Medical University Cancer Institute &amp; Hospital, National Clinical Research Center for Cancer, Tianjin's Clinical Research Center for Cancer, Tianjin Cancer Hospital Airport Hospital, No.99, Dongwu Road, Dongli Airport Economic Zone, Tianjin, 300000, China. pozhuas7@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Lujun</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Tianjin Key Laboratory of Cancer Prevention and Therapy, Tianjin Medical University Cancer Institute &amp; Hospital, National Clinical Research Center for Cancer, Huanhu West Road, North of the Gymnasium, Hexi District, Tianjin, 300060, China. zhaolujunzlj@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. 2022BWKQ026</GrantID><Agency>The Science and Technology Program of Tianjin Binhai New Area Health Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. STLKY0040</GrantID><Agency>The Beijing Baiqiu'en Public Welfare Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Hereditas</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0374654</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0018-0661</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical data</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LINC01980</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LUSC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Malignant biological behavior</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MiR-204-3p</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The authors state that they have obtained Tianjin Cancer Hospital Airport Hospital review board approval or have followed the principles outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki for all human or animal experimental investigations. In addition, for investigations involving human subjects, informed consent has been obtained from the participants involved. Consent for publication: Not Applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41390751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12822309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41065-025-00617-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s41065-025-00617-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pan L, Wang X, Yang L, Zhao L, Zhai L, Xu J, et al. Proteomic and phosphoproteomic maps of lung squamous cell carcinoma from Chinese patients. Front Oncol. 2020;10:963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2020.00963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7308564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32612956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao J, Wu Z, Huang R, Li J, Xu T, Gao Y, et al. Primary lung squamous cell carcinoma with intestinal metastasis: A case report and literature review. Clin Respir J. 2024;18(8):e13817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/crj.13817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11310267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39118303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R, Zhang X, Yang H, Lin Y, Wen Y, Zhao D, et al. Ferroptosis-related LncRNAs signature to predict the survival and immune evasion for lung squamous cell carcinoma. Front Genet. 2022;13:968601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fgene.2022.968601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9459014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36092894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Zhou X, Li L, Han Z. Long noncoding MAGI2-AS3 suppresses several cellular processes of lung squamous cell carcinoma cells by regulating miR-374a/b-5p/CADM2 axis. Cancer Manage Res. 2020;12:289&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CMAR.S232595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6972594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32021443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao K, Si Y, Sun L, Meng X, PortNet. Achieving lightweight architecture and high accuracy in lung cancer cell classification. Heliyon. 2025;11(3):e41850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2025.e41850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11808607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39931476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Liu X, Li J, Zhou H, Carr MJ, Zhang Z, et al. Long noncoding rnas: novel regulators of virus-host interactions. Rev Med Virol. 2019;29(4):e2046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rmv.2046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7169114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31016795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu L, Chen D, Song J. LncRNA SNHG16 promotes non-small cell lung cancer development through regulating EphA2 expression by sponging miR-520a-3p. Thorac Cancer. 2020;11(3):603&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1759-7714.13304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7049505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31953899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M, Feng X, Liu C, Huang Y, Su L, Li X, et al. Diagnostic value of exosome-derived LncRNA PITPNA-AS1 in lung cancer. Front Immunol. 2025;16:1539557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2025.1539557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12058797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40342419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu H, Chen C, Chen F, Sun N. LINC00152 knockdown suppresses tumorigenesis in non-small cell lung cancer via sponging miR-16-5p. J Thorac Disease. 2022;14(3):614&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/jtd-22-59</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8987817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35399229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Liu X, Wu X, Fang H, Shi J, Jiang W. Clinical significance and biological function of PRKCQ-AS1/miR-582-3p expression in LUAD. Hereditas. 2025;162(1):116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41065-025-00482-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12211715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40597380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Z, Zhang R, Zhang X, Sun Y, Liu P, Francoeur N, et al. LINE-1 promotes tumorigenicity and exacerbates tumor progression via stimulating metabolism reprogramming in non-small cell lung cancer. Mol Cancer. 2022;21(1):147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12943-022-01618-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9288060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35842613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Su Y, Fu X, Xiao J, Qin G, Yu M, et al. Evaluation of the prognostic value of long noncoding RNAs in lung squamous cell carcinoma. J Oncol. 2022;2022:9273628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8776467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35069738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suetsugu T, Koshizuka K, Seki N, Mizuno K, Okato A, Arai T, et al. Downregulation of matrix metalloproteinase 14 by the antitumor miRNA, miR-150-5p, inhibits the aggressiveness of lung squamous cell carcinoma cells. Int J Oncol. 2018;52(3):913&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29286099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andonegui-Elguera SD, Zamora-Fuentes JM, Espinal-Enr&#xed;quez J, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Lemus E. Loss of long distance Co-Expression in lung cancer. Front Genet. 2021;12:625741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fgene.2021.625741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7987938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33777098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X, Lin Q, Liu F, Yang F, Mao J, Chen X. LncRNA TMPO-AS1 facilitates the proliferation and metastasis of NSCLC cells by up-regulating ERBB2 via sponging miR-204-3p. Int J ImmunoPathol Pharmacol. 2020;34:2058738420958947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2058738420958947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7520928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32969763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, Shang Y, Shi S, He Y, Shi W, Wang M, et al. Combination of arsenic trioxide and apatinib synergistically inhibits small cell lung cancer by down-regulating VEGFR2/mTOR and Akt/c-Myc signaling pathway via GRB10. Hereditas. 2024;161(1):29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41065-024-00330-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11367874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39223679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng G, Zeng L, Wang Y, Cao Z, Zeng X, Xue Z, et al. Correlation between gut microbiota characteristics and non-small cell lung cancer based on macrogenomics sequencing. Hereditas. 2024;161(1):26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41065-024-00328-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11348753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39192352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Y, Wu Y, Zhang M, Zhu Y, Su X, Kong W, et al. Identification of prognosis-related LncRNAs and cell validation in lung squamous cell carcinoma based on TCGA data. Front Oncol. 2023;13:1240868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2023.1240868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10642190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37965447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Lin M, Zhang M, Wang Z, Lin H, Yu Y, et al. Advanced glycation end products&#x2019; receptor DNA methylation associated with immune infiltration and prognosis of lung adenocarcinoma and lung squamous cell carcinoma. Genet Res. 2023;2023:7129325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/7129325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10368508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37497166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang G, Zhang J, Gong L, Liu D, Wang X, Chen Y, et al. Specific lung squamous cell carcinoma Prognosis-Subtype distinctions based on DNA methylation patterns. Med Sci Monitor: Int Med J Experimental Clin Res. 2021;27:e929524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7942209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33661858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao S, Gong H, Liang W. Characterization of platelet-related genes and constructing signature combined with immune-related genes for predicting outcomes and immunotherapy response in lung squamous cell carcinoma. Aging. 2023;15(14):6969&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/aging.204886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10415560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37477536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Du B, Lu QJ, Fan XW, Tang K, Yang L, et al. miR-541 suppresses proliferation and invasion of squamous cell lung carcinoma cell lines via directly targeting high-mobility group AT-hook 2. Cancer Med. 2018;7(6):2581&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cam4.1491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6010725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29659195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Wang X, Cheng XK, Zong YY, He RQ, Chen G, et al. Clinical significance and effect of LncRNA BBOX1-AS1 on the proliferation and migration of lung squamous cell carcinoma. Oncol Lett. 2022;23(1):17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ol.2021.13135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8607367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34820016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Zhao Q, Tang Z. LncRNA RP11-116G8.5 promotes the progression of lung squamous cell carcinoma through sponging miR-3150b-3p/miR-6870-5p to upregulate PHF12/FOXP4. Pathol Res Pract. 2021;226:153566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prp.2021.153566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34500373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Liang Y, Wu Y, Chen X, Wang K, Li J, et al. Upregulation of a novel LncRNA LINC01980 promotes tumor growth of esophageal squamous cell carcinoma. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2019;513(1):73&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2019.03.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30935686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao S, Li P, Zhou G. Long noncoding RNAs in the prediction of survival of patients with digestive cancers. Turkish J Gastroenterology: Official J Turkish Soc Gastroenterol. 2023;34(1):19&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5152/tjg.2022.22017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9984979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36445051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, Peng P, He L, Gao X. Identification of Lnc RNAs related to prognosis of patients with colorectal cancer. Technol Cancer Res Treat. 2020;19:1533033820962120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1533033820962120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7607722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33111631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Li K, Li X. Knockdown of LncRNA LINC00958 inhibits the proliferation and migration of NSCLC cells by MiR-204-3p/KIF2A axis. Cell Transplant. 2021;30:9636897211025500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/09636897211025500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8287403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34269081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S, Liu T, Sun Y, Liang X. The long noncoding RNA LINC00483 promotes lung adenocarcinoma progression by sponging miR-204-3p. Cell Mol Biol Lett. 2019;24:70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s11658-019-0192-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6916218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31889958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng C, Zhao Y, Li Y, Zhang T, Ma Y, Liu Y. LncRNA MALAT1 promotes lung cancer proliferation and gefitinib resistance by acting as a miR-200a sponge. Arch Bronconeumol. 2019;55(12):627&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arbres.2019.03.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31133357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>