<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41310928</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-5065</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Jan-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Women's health (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Womens Health (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lived experience of unsafe abortion among commercial sex workers in Gedeo Zone, Southern Ethiopia: A phenomenological qualitative study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>17455057251400238</StartPage><MedlinePgn>17455057251400238</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">17455057251400238</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/17455057251400238</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Unsafe abortion is a significant cause of maternal morbidity and mortality in low- and middle-income countries. Female sex workers in Ethiopia are exposed to unwanted and unplanned pregnancy and subsequent abortion. In the absence of access to quality abortion care services, the chances of experiencing unsafe abortion are high. However, limited evidence is available on female sex workers' experience with abortion services and their exposure to unsafe abortion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To explore the lived experiences of female sex workers who underwent unsafe abortion in Gedeo Zone, Southern Ethiopia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study was conducted among female sex workers in Gedeo Zone, Southern Ethiopia, from April to June 2024. The study was employed among female sex workers who had a history of unsafe abortion in the past 2&#x2009;years. Both establishment-based and street-based female sex workers were selected using the snowball sampling method. Face-to-face in-depth interviews were conducted with participants in locations of their preference to ensure privacy. Data saturation was achieved after interviewing 18 participants. The collected data were transcribed verbatim, translated into English, and analyzed thematically using the Open Code 4.03 software. Trustworthiness was ensured throughout the data analysis process.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">A qualitative study with a phenomenological design was employed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The findings of this study revealed that poor knowledge of safe abortion services and poor socioeconomic status are the main causes for seeking unsafe abortion services by commercial sex workers. Unsafe pregnancy terminations were mainly experienced using commercial medications from private pharmacies and using traditional practices through herbal and mechanical techniques. Sex workers resorted to traditional methods and self-induced medication abortions, leading to adverse health, psychosocial, and economic consequences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The study highlights the poor information literacy and limited access to abortion services for sex workers, leading to unsafe practices and subsequent physical and psychological suffering. Therefore, stakeholders should collaborate to increase female sex workers' knowledge and access to safe abortion services.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Getnet</LastName><ForeName>Addisu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9771-3167</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Health Sciences and Medicine, Dilla University, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gashaw</LastName><ForeName>Anteneh</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-8396-2186</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Health Sciences and Medicine, Dilla University, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abebe</LastName><ForeName>Mesfin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9340-0091</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Health Sciences and Medicine, Dilla University, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gebrehanna</LastName><ForeName>Ewenat</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, St. Paul Hospital Millennium Medical College, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Womens Health (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101271249</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1745-5057</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060386" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sex Workers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000028" MajorTopicYN="Y">Abortion, Induced</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006297" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Services Accessibility</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Abortion, Illegal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007407" MajorTopicYN="N">Interviews as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007722" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">female sex workers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lived experience</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">unsafe abortion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of conflicting interestsThe authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41310928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12660650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17455057251400238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bearak J, Popinchalk A, Ganatra B, et al. Unintended pregnancy and abortion by income, region, and the legal status of abortion: estimates from a comprehensive model for 1990&#x2013;2019. Lancet Glob Health 2020; 8(9): e1152&#x2013;e1161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32710833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
WHO. Abortion, https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/abortion (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Chandra-Mouli DV.
Safe abortion care; Training course in adolescent sexual and reproductive health 2022 for WHO Eastern Mediterranean Region, Geneva, https://www.gfmer.ch/SRH-Course-2022/adolescent-health/safe-abortion-2022.htm (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Maternal mortality: evidence brief. World Health Organization, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Trends in maternal mortality 2000 to 2017: estimates by who, UNICEF, UNFPA, World Bank Group and the United Nations Population Division. World Health Organization, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PRB. Abortion facts and figures. PRB, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khezri M, Shokoohi M, Karamouzian M, et al. Induced abortion and associated factors among female sex workers in Iran. Eur J Contracept Reprod Health Care 2020; 25(6): 434&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32938240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khezri M, Tavakoli F, Schwartz S, et al. Global epidemiology of abortion among female sex workers: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression. Ann Epidemiol 2023; 85: 13&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37356778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleeve A, Phrasisombath K, Sychareun V, et al. Attitudes and experiences regarding induced abortion among female sex workers, Savannakhet Province, Laos. Sex Reprod Healthc 2014; 5(3): 137&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25200975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradi G, Gouya MM, Ezzati Amini E, et al. Intentional abortion and its associated factors among female sex workers in Iran: results from national bio-behavioral surveillance-2020. PLoS One 2022; 17(8): e0273732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9423624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36037196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tolu LB, Hurisa T, Abas F, et al. Effect of covid-19 pandemic on safe abortion and contraceptive services and mitigation measures: a case study from a tertiary facility in Ethiopia. Ethiop J Reprod Health 2020; 12(3): 51&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bautista CT, Mej&#xed;a A, Leal L, et al. Prevalence of lifetime abortion and methods of contraception among female sex workers in Bogota, Colombia. Contraception 2008; 77(3): 209&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18279693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chareka S, Crankshaw TL, Zambezi P. Economic and social dimensions influencing safety of induced abortions amongst young women who sell sex in Zimbabwe. Sex Reprod Health Matters 2021; 29(1): 121&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8009027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33576331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalubega JM, Omona K. Lived experiences of women who underwent induced abortion: a qualitative study of Rakai District, Uganda. Int J Health 2021; 8(1): 1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra S, Rath SK. Unsafe abortion: combating the silent menace. Indian J Obstet Gynecol Res 2021; 8(2): 146&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zar&#x119;ba K, Herman K, Ko&#x142;b-Sielecka E, et al. Abortion in countries with restrictive abortion laws &#x2013; possible directions and solutions from the perspective of Poland. Healthcare 2021; 9(11): 1594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8618220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34828639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau JT, Mui LW, Tsui H, et al. Prevalence of induced abortion and associated factors among Chinese female sex workers in Hong Kong. J Sex Marital Ther 2007; 33(1): 19&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17162485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willis B, Church K, Perttu E, et al. The preventable burden of mortality from unsafe abortion among female sex workers: a community knowledge approach survey among peer networks in eight countries. Sex Reprod Health Matters 2023; 31(1): 2250618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10506426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37712508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health &#x2013; Ethiopia. Technical and procedural guideline for abortion care services in Ethiopia. Ministry of Health &#x2013; Ethiopia, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodama Y. New role of cooperatives in Ethiopia: the case of Ethiopian coffee farmers cooperatives. African Study Monographs; 2007; 35: 87&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Consolidated Criteria for Reporting Qualitative Research (COREQ): a 32-item checklist for interviews and focus groups, https://www.equator-network.org/reporting-guidelines/coreq/ (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebni JY, Irandoost SF, Dehghan AA, et al. Exploring the reasons for women to engage in sex work in Tehran, Iran: a qualitative study. Heliyon 2021; 7(12): e08512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8649730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34926855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qayyum S, Iqbal MMA, Akhtar A, et al. Causes and decision of women&#x2019;s involvement into prostitution and its consequences in Punjab, Pakistan. Acad Res Int 2013; 4(5): 398&#x2013;411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abideen Aderinto A, Ima Samuel E. Adolescents at risk: a qualitative study of adolescent sex workers in Ibadan. S Afr Rev Sociol 2008; 39(1): 38&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saggurti N, Sabarwal S, Verma RK, et al. Harsh realities: reasons for women&#x2019;s involvement in sex work in India. J AIDS HIV Res 2011; 3(9): 172&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClarty LM, Bhattacharjee P, Blanchard JF, et al. Circumstances, experiences and processes surrounding women&#x2019;s entry into sex work in India. Cult Health Sex 2014; 16(2): 149&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24236895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jie W, Xiaolan Z, Ciyong L, et al. A qualitative exploration of barriers to condom use among female sex workers in China. PLoS One 2012; 7(10): e46786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3466319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23056452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magalh&#xe3;es RdLB, Sousa LRM, Gir E, et al. Factors associated to inconsistent condom use among sex workers. Rev Lat Am Enfermagem 2019; 27: e3226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6896796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31826167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi Gharehghani MA, Khosravi B, Irandoost SF, et al. Barriers to condom use among female sex workers in Tehran, Iran: a qualitative study. Int J Womens Health 2020; 12: 681&#x2013;689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7468524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32943942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochako R, Okal J, Kimetu S, et al. Female sex workers experiences of using contraceptive methods: a qualitative study in Kenya. BMC Womens Health 2018; 18: 1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6011601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29925361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sibanda E, Shapiro A, Mathers B, et al. Values and preferences of contraceptive methods: a mixed-methods study among sex workers from diverse settings. Sex Reprod Health Matters 2021; 29(1): 314&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8118510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33949283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X-D, Kennedy E, Temmerman M, et al. High rates of abortion and low levels of contraceptive use among adolescent female sex workers in Kunming, China: a cross-sectional analysis. Eur J Contracept Reprod Health Care 2014; 19(5): 368&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24981306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faini D, Munseri P, Bakari M, et al. &#x201c;I did not plan to have a baby. This is the outcome of our work&#x201d;: a qualitative study exploring unintended pregnancy among female sex workers. BMC Womens Health 2020; 20: 1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7709442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33261591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masvawure TB, Mantell JE, Tocco JU, et al. Intentional and unintentional condom breakage and slippage in the sexual interactions of female and male sex workers and clients in Mombasa, Kenya. AIDS Behav 2018; 22: 637&#x2013;648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5820152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28975484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradburn CK, Wanje G, Pfeiffer J, et al. Risky business: condom failures as experienced by female sex workers in Mombasa, Kenya. Cult Health Sex 2017; 19(3): 395&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5590372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27581997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weldegebreal R, Melaku YA, Alemayehu M, et al. Unintended pregnancy among female sex workers in Mekelle City, Northern Ethiopia: a cross-sectional study. BMC Public Health 2015; 15: 1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4320639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25636515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenthal D, Oanh TTK. Listening to female sex workers in Vietnam: influences on safe-sex practices with clients and partners. Sex Health 2006; 3(1): 21&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16607971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karki R. Sexual violence and consequences of unintended pregnancy among the street based sex workers in Nepal. J Dev Adm Stud 2017; 25(1&#x2013;2): 62&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yam EA, Kidanu A, Burnett-Zieman B, et al. Pregnancy experiences of female sex workers in Adama City, Ethiopia: complexity of partner relationships and pregnancy intentions. Stud Fam Plann 2017; 48(2): 107&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5516190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28263396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bukenya JN, Wanyenze RK, Barrett G, et al. Contraceptive use, prevalence and predictors of pregnancy planning among female sex workers in Uganda: a cross sectional study. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth 2019; 19: 1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6454679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30961542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers C, Sapkota S, Paudel R, et al. Medical abortion in Nepal: a qualitative study on women&#x2019;s experiences at safe abortion services and pharmacies. Reprod Health 2019; 16: 1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6632190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31307474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufa M, Wegayehu Y, Tilahun M, et al. The reasons for unsafe abortion among reproductive-age women in the West Shewa Zone, Oromia, Ethiopia. A qualitative study. Millenn J Health 2023; 2(1): 1378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getahun GK, Kidane M, Fekade W, et al. Exploring the reasons for unsafe abortion among women in the reproductive age group in Western Ethiopia. Clin Epidemiol Glob Health 2023; 22: 101301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atakro CA, Addo SB, Aboagye JS, et al. Contributing factors to unsafe abortion practices among women of reproductive age at selected district hospitals in the Ashanti Region of Ghana. BMC Womens Health 2019; 19(1): 1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6500035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31053129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shewale S, Sahay S. Barriers and facilitators for access and utilization of reproductive and sexual health services among female sex workers in urban and rural Maharashtra, India. Front Public Health 2022; 10: 1030914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9772989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36568800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birhanu A. The interface between abortion practice and community response in Amhara Region, North Eastern Ethiopia, 2017: a cross-sectional study. Int J Biomed Res 2023; 2(4): 1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehy G, Dozier JL, Mickler AK, et al. Regional and residential disparities in knowledge of abortion legality and availability of facility-based abortion services in Ethiopia. Contracept X 2021; 3: 100066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8267565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34278291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madeiro AP, Diniz D. Induced abortion among Brazilian female sex workers: a qualitative study. Cien Saude Colet 2015; 20: 587&#x2013;593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25715152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayaweera RT, Ngui FM, Hall KS, et al. Women&#x2019;s experiences with unplanned pregnancy and abortion in Kenya: a qualitative study. PLoS One 2018; 13(1): e0191412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5784933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29370220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallely LM, Homiehombo P, Kelly-Hanku A, et al. Unsafe abortion requiring hospital admission in the Eastern Highlands of Papua New Guinea &#x2013; a descriptive study of women&#x2019;s and health care workers&#x2019; experiences. Reprod Health 2015; 12: 1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4409713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25889957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambir K, Kim C, Necastro KA, et al. Self-administered versus provider-administered medical abortion. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2020; 3(3): CD013181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7062143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32150279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Who recommendations on self-care interventions: self-management of medical abortion. World Health Organization, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin W, Fazari AB, Elmusharaf K. A qualitative study exploring women&#x2019;s experiences of unsafe abortion in Sudan. Open J Soc Sci 2017; 5(3): 149&#x2013;158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luchters S, Bosire W, Feng A, et al. &#x201c;A baby was an added burden&#x201d;: predictors and consequences of unintended pregnancies for female sex workers in Mombasa, Kenya: a mixed-methods study. PLoS One 2016; 11(9): e0162871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5045288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27689699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong WT, Low WY, Wong YL, et al. Exploring pregnancy termination experiences and needs among Malaysian women: a qualitative study. BMC Public Health 2012; 12: 1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3505743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22950371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chekol BM, Dijkerman S, Muluye S, et al. Community-based intervention improves abortion knowledge and reduces abortion stigma among women in Oromia, Ethiopia: a quasi-experimental mixed methods evaluation. BMC Womens Health 2022; 22(1): 463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9677673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36404318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuentes L, Baum S, Keefe-Oates B, et al. Texas women&#x2019;s decisions and experiences regarding self-managed abortion. BMC Womens Health 2020; 20: 1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6945569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31906937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>