<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41728421</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative Evaluation of the Effect of Custom-Made Anatomic Healing Abutment on Papilla Morphology and Gingival Aesthetics With That of Conventional Type of Healing Abutment: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e101909</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e101909</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e101909</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.101909</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Gingival aesthetics has become inevitable in the overall success of implant-supported restorations. The interdental papilla plays a crucial role in attaining optimal aesthetics during the restoration of anterior edentulous regions with implants. The use of customized healing abutments helps to shape and condition the gingival tissue during the healing phase, thereby preserving its natural contours for the subsequent prosthetic stage.&#xa0; Objectives The primary objective is to compare the papillary morphology adjacent to implant restorations using the papilla index after the use of custom-made and conventional healing abutments at permanent crown insertion and at six months. The secondary objective is to compare the emergence profile aesthetics using the pink esthetic score (PES) at the same time points for both types of healing abutments. Methodology The study was designed as a randomized parallel group trial with an allocation ratio of 1:1. Patients who visited the Prosthodontic Department of Government Dental College, Thiruvananthapuram, for implant-retained restoration in the maxillary central incisor region were recruited for the study. Implants were placed in a delayed loading protocol. A total of 20 participants were selected for the study. The control group (n=10) included patients treated with conventional healing abutments, while the test group (n=10) consisted of patients who received customized healing abutments. After six months of healing, conventional healing abutments were placed at second-stage surgery for group I, whereas customized healing abutments were used for group II. Outcome variables, papilla index scores (PIS), and PES&#xa0;were evaluated and compared at the time of insertion of permanent restoration and after six months. Results The distribution of mean papilla index between group I and group II at insertion showed that there is a statistically significant improvement in both mesial and distal PIS for group II (2.00&#xb1;0.00) when compared to group I (1.40&#xb1;0.52). PES&#xa0;were compared between the two groups at the time of insertion of the final crown. The mean PES for the customized group was (11.40&#xb1;0.52) while that of the conventional group was only (10.40&#xb1;0.52) (P value &lt;0.05). The PES&#xa0;of Group I and Group II were compared after six months of crown insertion. Mean PES for the customized group (12.40&#xb1;0.52) when compared to the conventional group (11.40&#xb1;0.52) was higher, and the difference was statistically significant. (P value &lt;0.05) .Statistical analysis was done using Mann-Whitney U test. Interpretation and conclusion&#xa0; This study concludes that customized healing abutments help in procuring a better emergence profile and aesthetics of the restoration. It also restores the optimum contour and papillary size at a faster rate than the conventional healing abutment. Clinical significance The study is unique in that it compares the effect of customized healing abutment on gingival aesthetics and papillary morphology with that of conventional healing abutment in a delayed implant loading protocol.&#xa0;In delayed loading protocols, customized healing abutments are critical tools in guiding the healing of peri-implant soft tissues. They provide superior aesthetic outcomes, especially in the anterior aesthetic zone, by promoting natural-looking gingival architecture.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Surendran et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Surendran</LastName><ForeName>Deepthi V</ForeName><Initials>DV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prosthodontics, Government Dental College, Thiruvananthapuram, Thiruvananthapuram, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ravichandran</LastName><ForeName>Rajagopal</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prosthodontics, Government Dental College, Thiruvananthapuram, Thiruvananthapuram, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karunakaran</LastName><ForeName>Harshakumar</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prosthodontics, Government Dental College, Thiruvananthapuram, Thiruvananthapuram, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healing abutment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">implant aesthetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">papilla index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pink aesthetic score</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prosthodontics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Institute Ethics Committee, Government Dental college, Thiruvanathapuram issued approval IEC/C/81-A/2011/DCT. Decision of IEC/IRB- Recommended. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41728421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12919510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.101909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Soft tissue dimensional change using customized titanium healing abutment in immediate implant placement in posterior teeth. Lertwongpaisan T, Amornsettachai P, Panyayong W, Suphangul S. BMC Oral Health. 2023;23:384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10262413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37308877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Systematic review of peri-implant conditions and aesthetic outcomes of customized versus conventional healing abutments. Ruhstorfer M, G&#xfc;th JF, Stimmelmayr M, Waltenberger L, Schubert O, Graf T. Int J Implant Dent. 2024;10:61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11635071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39661263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peri-implant papilla reconstruction: realities and limitations. Pradeep AR, Karthikeyan BV. J Periodontol. 2006;77:534&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16512769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soft tissue preservation and crestal bone loss around single-tooth implants. Sunitha RV, Ramakrishnan T, Kumar S, Emmadi P. J Oral Implantol. 2008;34:223&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18780568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Criteria for success of osseointegrated endosseous implants. Smith DE, Zarb GA. J Prosthet Dent. 1989;62:567&#x2013;572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2691661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The esthetic dental implant: letting restoration be the guide. Garber DA. J Am Dent Assoc. 1995;126:319&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7897100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Single implant-supported restorations in the anterior maxilla. Carri&#xf3;n JB, Barbosa IR. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15839591. Int J Periodontics Restorative Dent. 2005;25:149&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15839591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esthetic problems in the anterior maxilla. Sullivan D, Kay H, Schwarz M, Gelb D. https://openurl.ebsco.com/EPDB%3Agcd%3A10%3A9854618/detailv2?sid=ebsco%3Aplink%3Ascholar&amp;id=ebsco%3Agcd%3A82120713&amp;crl=c&amp;link_origin=scholar.google.com Int J Oral Maxillofac Implants. 1994;9:64&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flap technique for periodontal bone implants. Papilla preservation technique. Takei HH, Han TJ, Carranza FA Jr, Kenney EB, Lekovic V. J Periodontol. 1985;56:204&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3889270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interproximal papillae reconstruction in maxillary implants. Nemcovsky CE, Moses O, Artzi Z. J Periodontol. 2000;71:308&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10711622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An incision design to promote a gingival base for the creation of interdental implant papillae. Flanagan D. J Oral Implantol. 2002;28:25&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12498460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A new implant design for optimal esthetics and retention of interproximal papillae. Gadhia MH, Holt RL. Implant Dent. 2003;12:164&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12861885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strategies for management of single-tooth extraction sites in aesthetic implant therapy. Sclar AG. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2004;62:90&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15332186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A modified implant healing abutment to optimize soft tissue contours: a case report. Pow EH, McMillan AS. Implant Dent. 2004;13:297&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15591990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Managing the soft tissue margin: the key to implant aesthetics. Lazzara RJ. https://europepmc.org/article/med/8219171 PPAD. 1993;1:81&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8219171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Customized emergence profile in the implant crown--a new technique. Bain CA, Weisgold AS. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9161136/ Compend Contin Educ Dent. 1997;18:41&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9161136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early healing of immediate implants connected with two types of healing abutments: a prospective cohort study. Hu C, Lin W, Gong T, Zuo Y, Qu Y, Man Y. Implant Dent. 2018;27:646&#x2013;652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30119070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regeneration of gingival papillae after single-implant treatment. Jemt T. International Journal of Periodontics &amp; Restorative Dentistry. 1997;17:326&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9497723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of soft tissue around single-tooth implant crowns: the pink esthetic score. F&#xfc;rhauser R, Florescu D, Benesch T, Haas R, Mailath G, Watzek G. Clin Oral Implants Res. 2005;16:639&#x2013;644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16307569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The simplified oral hygiene index.  [
Aug;
2017 
];Greene JG, Vermillion JR. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9497723/ The Journal of the American Dental Association. 1964 68:7&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14076341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Improving aesthetics of implant-supported restorations. Touati B. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9002895/ Pract Periodontics Aesthet Dent. 1995;7:81&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9002895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Implant-supported single tooth replacement in the aesthetic region: a complex challenge. Grunder U, Spielman HP, Gaberth&#xfc;el T. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9242145/ Pract Periodontics Aesthet Dent. 1996;8:835-42, quiz 844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9242145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Periimplant tissue management: optimal timing for an aesthetic result. H&#xfc;rzeler MB, Weng D. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9242146/ Pract Periodontics Aesthet Dent. 1996;8:857&#x2013;869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9242146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prosthetic soft tissue management in esthetic implant restorations, part II: post-surgical considerations and impression techniques. A narrative review. Atri F, Nokar K. Clin Exp Dent Res. 2025;11:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11872796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40025681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Predictability of soft tissue form around single-tooth implant restorations. Priest G. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12617365/ Int J Periodontics Restorative Dent. 2003;23:19&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12617365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical and radiographic evaluation of the papilla level adjacent to single&#x2010;tooth dental implants. A retrospective study in the maxillary anterior region. Choquet V, Hermans M, Adriaenssens P, Daelemans P, Tarnow DP, Malevez C. https://doi.org/10.1902/jop.2001.72.10.1364. Journal of periodontology. 2001;72:1364&#x2013;1371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11699478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of customized and prefabricated healing abutments on peri-implant soft tissue and bone in immediate implant sites: a randomized controlled trial. Chokaree P, Poovarodom P, Chaijareenont P, Rungsiyakull P. J Clin Med. 2024;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10856257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38337580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The mucosal attachment at different abutments. An experimental study in dogs. Abrahamsson I, Berglundh T, Glantz PO, Lindhe J. J Clin Periodontol. 1998;25:721&#x2013;727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9763327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>