<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41160382</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-2614</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical monitoring and computing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Monit Comput</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of the change in carotid corrected flow time and stroke volume variation for assessing volume responsiveness in general anesthesia patients: a prospective, observational study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10877-025-01375-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Accurately identifying surgical patients who will have an increase in stroke volume following fluid administration remains challenging when utilizing noninvasive bedside methods. This study aims to compare the value of using ultrasound to measure changes in corrected carotid artery flow time (&#x394;FTc) with that of using invasive measurements of stroke volume variation (&#x394;SVV) for assessing volume responsiveness in patients under general anesthesia and mechanical ventilation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 91 patients undergoing elective abdominal surgery under general anesthesia were enrolled in this prospective observational study. Under general anesthesia and mechanical ventilation, the &#x394;FTc was measured using noninvasive bedside ultrasound, and the &#x394;SVV was measured using invasive hemodynamic monitoring, both before and after fluid administration. Fluid responders were defined as an increase in stroke volume of &#x2265;&#x2009;10% after the fluid challenge.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 47 (54.0%) patients were fluid responders. The &#x394;FTc was 14.5&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;8.3 ms for responders and 5.7&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.9 ms for non-responders, while the &#x394;SVV was 3.3&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.4% for responders and 1.7&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.7% for non-responders. The areas under the receiver operating characteristic curves for &#x394;FTc and &#x394;SVV were 0.85 (95% CI 0.77-0.92; P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) and 0.84 (95% CI 0.75-0.93; P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), respectively. The optimal cutoff values were 7.03 ms for &#x394;FTc (sensitivity 91.5%, specificity 69.8%) and 2.85% for &#x394;SVV (sensitivity 95.6%, specificity 72.6%). A narrower gray zone for &#x394;FTc, ranging from 7 ms to 12 ms and covering 27 patients, was observed compared with that for &#x394;SVV, which ranged from 1% to 3% and covered 41 patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Both the &#x394;FTc and &#x394;SVV reliably assessed fluid responsiveness in patients undergoing general anesthesia and mechanical ventilation. Noninvasive bedside ultrasound measurement of &#x394;FTc can serve as an accurate assessment parameter, reflecting the presence of volume responsiveness following rapid fluid administration and showing greater clinical applicability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">www.chictr.org.cn (ChiCTR2500101114); registered 21 April 2025.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yongyong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, National Regional Medical Center, Binhai Campus of the First Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical University, No. 999, Huashan Rd, 350212, Fuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The First Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical University, No. 20 Chazhong Rd, 350005, Fuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine, 900 Hospital of the Joint Logistic Support Force/Fuzong Clinical Medical College of Fujian Medical University, No. 156, West 2nd Ring Rd, 350025, Fuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Chenlong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, National Regional Medical Center, Binhai Campus of the First Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical University, No. 999, Huashan Rd, 350212, Fuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The First Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical University, No. 20 Chazhong Rd, 350005, Fuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Zhongmou</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, National Regional Medical Center, Binhai Campus of the First Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical University, No. 999, Huashan Rd, 350212, Fuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The First Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical University, No. 20 Chazhong Rd, 350005, Fuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Huanghui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Laboratory of Anesthesiology and Brain Functional Modulation Clinical Research Center for Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine, Translational Research Institute of Brain and Brain-Like Intelligence, Department of Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine, School of Medicine, Shanghai Fourth People's Hospital, Tongji University, No. 1279, Sanmen Rd, 200434, Shanghai, China. mzkwhh@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Guozhong</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Laboratory of Anesthesiology and Brain Functional Modulation Clinical Research Center for Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine, Translational Research Institute of Brain and Brain-Like Intelligence, Department of Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine, School of Medicine, Shanghai Fourth People's Hospital, Tongji University, No. 1279, Sanmen Rd, 200434, Shanghai, China. cgzssq2000@sina.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, National Regional Medical Center, Binhai Campus of the First Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical University, No. 999, Huashan Rd, 350212, Fuzhou, China. 165552215@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The First Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical University, No. 20 Chazhong Rd, 350005, Fuzhou, China. 165552215@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2022QH1079</GrantID><Agency>Startup Fund for Scientific Research of Fujian Medical University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>sykyqd04801</GrantID><Agency>Scientific Research Project of Shanghai Fourth People's Hospital</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Monit Comput</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9806357</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1387-1307</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Corrected carotid artery flow time</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fluid therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">General anesthesia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stroke volume</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Volume responsiveness</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical approval: This study was approved by the ethics committee of the First Affiliated Hospital of Fujian Medical University (approval number: [2025]647; date of approval: March 15, 2025) and registered in the Chinese Clinical Trial Register (ChiCTR2500101114; registered 21 April 2025). Consent to participate: Informed consent was obtained from all individual participants included in the study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41160382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10877-025-01375-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10877-025-01375-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abd E, Aziz MA, Grass F, Calini G, Lovely JK, Jacob AK, Behm KT, D&#x2019;Angelo AD, Shawki SF, Mathis KL, Larson DW. Intraoperative fluid management a modifiable risk factor for surgical Quality - Improving standardized practice. Ann Surg. 2022;275:891&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1097/sla.0000000000005384 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/sla.0000000000005384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messina A, Robba C, Calabr&#xf2; L, Zambelli D, Iannuzzi F, Molinari E, et al. Association between perioperative fluid administration and postoperative outcomes: a 20-year systematic review and a meta-analysis of randomized goal-directed trials in major visceral/noncardiac surgery. Crit Care. 2021;25:43. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13054-021-03464-1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-021-03464-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33522953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7849093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cihoric M, Kehlet H, H&#xf8;jlund J, Lauritsen ML, Kanstrup K, Foss NB. Perioperative changes in fluid distribution and haemodynamics in acute high-risk abdominal surgery. Crit Care. 2023;27:20. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13054-023-04309-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-023-04309-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36647120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9841944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Waal EEC, Frank M, Scheeren TWL, Kaufmann T, de Korte-de Boer D, Cox B, van Kuijk SMJ, Montenij LM, Buhre W. Perioperative goal-directed therapy in high-risk abdominal surgery. A multicenter randomized controlled superiority trial. J Clin Anesth. 2021;75:110506. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinane.2021.110506 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinane.2021.110506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34536718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheeren TW, Wiesenack C, Gerlach H, Marx G. Goal-directed intraoperative fluid therapy guided by stroke volume and its variation in high-risk surgical patients: a prospective randomized multicentre study. J Clin Monit Comput. 2013;27:225&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10877-013-9461-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10877-013-9461-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23558909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willars C, Dada A, Hughes T, Green D. Functional haemodynamic monitoring: the value of SVV as measured by the LiDCORapid&#x2122; in predicting fluid responsiveness in high risk vascular surgical patients. Int J Surg. 2012;10:148&#x2013;52. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijsu.2012.02.003 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijsu.2012.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22330275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarro LH, Bloomstone JA, Auler JO Jr., Cannesson M, Rocca GD, Gan TJ, et al. Perioperative fluid therapy: a statement from the international fluid optimization group. Perioper Med (Lond). 2015;4:3. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13741-015-0014-z .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley CA, Ma C, Hollon MM. Perioperative point of care ultrasound for hemodynamic assessment: a narrative review. Semin Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2023;27:208&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1177/10892532231165088 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10892532231165088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36943777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vall&#xe9;e F, Fourcade O, De Soyres O, Angles O, Sanchez-Verlaan P, Pillard F, et al. Stroke output variations calculated by esophageal doppler is a reliable predictor of fluid response. Intensive Care Med. 2005;31:1388&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00134-005-2768-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-005-2768-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16132887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou K, Ran S, Guo Y, Ye H. Carotid artery ultrasound for assessing fluid responsiveness in patients undergoing mechanical ventilation with low tidal volume and preserved spontaneous breathing. Shock. 2024;61:360&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1097/shk.0000000000002288 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/shk.0000000000002288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38117132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen J, Dai S, Tao X, Chen X, Xu L. Corrected flow time and respirophasic variation in blood flow peak velocity of radial artery predict fluid responsiveness in gynecological surgical patients with mechanical ventilation. BMC Anesthesiol. 2022;22:299. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12871-022-01837-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12871-022-01837-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36123625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9484168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Liu Z, Fang J, Xie Y, Zhang M, Yang J. Correlation of carotid corrected flow time and respirophasic variation in blood flow peak velocity with stroke volume variation in elderly patients under general anaesthesia. BMC Anesthesiol. 2022. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12871-022-01792-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12871-022-01792-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36550437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9773574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung S, Kim J, Na S, Nam WS, Kim DH. Ability of carotid corrected flow time to predict fluid responsiveness in patients mechanically ventilated using low tidal volume after surgery. J Clin Med. 2021. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm10122676 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm10122676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35011948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8745675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monnet X, Shi R, Teboul JL. Prediction of fluid responsiveness. What&#x2019;s new? Ann Intensive Care. 2022;12:46. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13613-022-01022-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13613-022-01022-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35633423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9148319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaves RCF, Barbas CSV, Queiroz VNF, Serpa Neto A, Deliberato RO, Pereira AJ, Timenetsky KT, Silva J&#xfa;nior JM, Takaoka F, de Backer D, et al. Assessment of fluid responsiveness using pulse pressure variation, stroke volume variation, plethysmographic variability index, central venous pressure, and inferior Vena Cava variation in patients undergoing mechanical ventilation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Crit Care. 2024;28:289. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13054-024-05078-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-024-05078-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39217370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11366151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossein-Nejad H, Banaie M, Davarani SS, Mohammadinejad P. Assessment of corrected flow time in carotid artery via point-of-care ultrasonography: reference values and the influential factors. J Crit Care. 2017;40:46&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcrc.2017.03.009 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcrc.2017.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28324786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossein-Nejad H, Mohammadinejad P, Lessan-Pezeshki M, Davarani SS, Banaie M. Carotid artery corrected flow time measurement via bedside ultrasonography in monitoring volume status. J Crit Care. 2015;30:1199&#x2013;203. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcrc.2015.08.014 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcrc.2015.08.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26410681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biais M, Ehrmann S, Mari A, Conte B, Mahjoub Y, Desebbe O, et al. Clinical relevance of pulse pressure variations for predicting fluid responsiveness in mechanically ventilated intensive care unit patients: the grey zone approach. Crit Care. 2014;18:587. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13054-014-0587-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-014-0587-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25658489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4240833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanca D, Schwarz EC, Olgers TJ, Ter Avest E, Azizi N, Bouma HR, Maaten T, J.C. Intra-and inter-observer variability of point of care ultrasound measurements to evaluate hemodynamic parameters in healthy volunteers. Ultrasound J. 2023;15:22. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13089-023-00322-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13089-023-00322-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37145390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10163179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monnet X, Teboul JL. Passive leg raising. Intensive Care Med. 2008;34:659&#x2013;63. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00134-008-0994-y .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-008-0994-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18214429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coeckelenbergh S, Zaouter C, Alexander B, Cannesson M, Rinehart J, Duranteau J, et al. Automated systems for perioperative goal-directed hemodynamic therapy. J Anesth. 2020;34:104&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00540-019-02683-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00540-019-02683-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31555916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arslan-Carlon V, Tan KS, Dalbagni G, Pedoto AC, Herr HW, Bochner BH, et al. Goal-directed versus standard fluid therapy to decrease ileus after open radical cystectomy: a prospective randomized controlled trial. Anesthesiology. 2020;133:293&#x2013;303. https://doi.org/10.1097/aln.0000000000003367 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/aln.0000000000003367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32472804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marik PE, Monnet X, Teboul JL. Hemodynamic parameters to guide fluid therapy. Ann Intensive Care. 2011. https://doi.org/10.1186/2110-5820-1-1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2110-5820-1-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21906348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3224476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahidi Delshad E, Sanadgol H, Bakhshandeh H, Saberian M, Alavi SM. Fluid balance has effects on the length of hospital stay after coronary artery bypass grafting surgery. Iran J Kidney Dis. 2020;14:36&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32156840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrianello S, Marchegiani G, Bannone E, Masini G, Malleo G, Montemezzi GL, et al. Clinical implications of intraoperative fluid therapy in pancreatic surgery. J Gastrointest Surg. 2018;22:2072&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11605-018-3887-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11605-018-3887-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30066067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Backer D, Fagnoul D. Intensive care ultrasound: VI. Fluid responsiveness and shock assessment. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2014;11:129&#x2013;36. https://doi.org/10.1513/AnnalsATS.201309-320OT .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1513/AnnalsATS.201309-320OT</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24460447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaptein MJ, Kaptein EM. Inferior vena cava collapsibility index: clinical validation and application for assessment of relative intravascular volume. Adv Chronic Kidney Dis. 2021;28:218&#x2013;26. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.ackd.2021.02.003 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ackd.2021.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34906306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandeville JC, Colebourn CL. Can transthoracic echocardiography be used to predict fluid responsiveness in the critically ill patient? A systematic review. Crit Care Res Pract. 2012;2012:513480. https://doi.org/10.1155/2012/513480 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2012/513480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22400109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3286892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chytra I, Pradl R, Bosman R, Peln&#xe1;r P, Kasal E, Zidkov&#xe1; A. Esophageal doppler-guided fluid management decreases blood lactate levels in multiple-trauma patients: a randomized controlled trial. Crit Care. 2007;11:R24. https://doi.org/10.1186/cc5703 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/cc5703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17313691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2151901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monnet X, Rienzo M, Osman D, Anguel N, Richard C, Pinsky MR, et al. Esophageal doppler monitoring predicts fluid responsiveness in critically ill ventilated patients. Intensive Care Med. 2005;31(9):1195&#x2013;201. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00134-005-2731-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-005-2731-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16059723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris J, Jones C. Is there still a role for the oesophageal doppler in cardiac output monitoring? Br J Hosp Med (Lond). 2021;82:1&#x2013;2. https://doi.org/10.12968/hmed.2020.0690 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12968/hmed.2020.0690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34431353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blehar DJ, Glazier S, Gaspari RJ. Correlation of corrected flow time in the carotid artery with changes in intravascular volume status. J Crit Care. 2014;29:486&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcrc.2014.03.025 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcrc.2014.03.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24930363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DH, Shin S, Kim N, Choi T, Choi SH, Choi YS. Carotid ultrasound measurements for assessing fluid responsiveness in spontaneously breathing patients: corrected flow time and respirophasic variation in blood flow peak velocity. Br J Anaesth. 2018;121:541&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bja.2017.12.047 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bja.2017.12.047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30115251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenny JS, Barjaktarevic I, Mackenzie DC, Eibl AM, Parrotta M, Long BF, Eibl JK. Diagnostic characteristics of 11 formulae for calculating corrected flow time as measured by a wearable doppler patch. Intensive Care Med Exp. 2020;8:54. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40635-020-00339-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40635-020-00339-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32940808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7498524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenny JS, Barjaktarevic I, Eibl AM, Parrotta M, Long BF, Elfarnawany M, et al. Temporal concordance between pulse contour analysis, bioreactance and carotid doppler during rapid preload changes. PLoS ONE. 2022;17:e0265711. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0265711 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0265711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35320307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8942202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Arrigo S, Dell&#x2019;Anna AM, Sandroni C, Messina A, Cacciola S, Pacini C, et al. Can carotid artery doppler variations induced by the end-expiratory occlusion maneuver predict fluid responsiveness in septic shock patients? Crit Care. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13054-023-04422-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-023-04422-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37076861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10116770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipszyc AC, Walker SCD, Beech AP, Wilding H, Akhlaghi H. Predicting fluid responsiveness using carotid ultrasound in mechanically ventilated patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of diagnostic test accuracy studies. Anesth Analg. 2024;138:1174&#x2013;86. https://doi.org/10.1213/ane.0000000000006820 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1213/ane.0000000000006820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38289868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Chen W, Cheng H, Liu C, Yao W, Ding F, et al. Value of corrected flow time in common carotid artery in predicting volume responsiveness under mechanical ventilation. Shock. 2022;58:28&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.1097/shk.0000000000001959 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/shk.0000000000001959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35904148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9415202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>