<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41806297</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1614-7499</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental science and pollution research international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Sci Pollut Res Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tracking the fate of organophosphate esters: from occurrence to risk in the lower Yangtze River water.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11356-026-37567-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The lower Yangtze River basin represents a significant zone for the production, utilization, and emission of organophosphate esters (OPEs). This study examined the occurrence, concentration levels, and spatial distribution of eight commonly found OPEs in the lower Yangtze River water during 2022-2024, while assessing associated ecological and health risks. Five target OPEs maintained high detection frequencies throughout the three-year period. Chlorinated OPEs dominated the OPE profile in surface waters. Spatially, elevated concentrations were observed along the Nanjing-Shanghai river reach. The severe drought in 2022 contributed to comparatively lower overall OPE concentrations. A notable surge in TCEP levels occurred in September 2023, likely attributable to atmospheric wet deposition and industrial wastewater discharges. Data from newly added sampling points near the middle reaches in 2024 indicate lower OPE concentrations. Correlation analysis, principal component analysis, and hierarchical cluster analysis indicated that tris(2-chloroethyl) phosphate (TCEP), tris(1-chloro-2-propyl) phosphate (TCIPP), and tris(1,3-dichloro-2-propyl) phosphate (TDCIPP) primarily originated from inadequately treated sewage and industrial effluents, while tri-n-butyl phosphate (TnBP) and triphenyl phosphate (TPhP) showed strong associations with vehicular emissions, maritime transport discharges, and industrial operations. Ecological risk assessment identified TCEP as requiring particular attention, and health risk evaluation indicated negligible health concerns from OPEs in drinking water sources throughout lower reaches of the Yangtze River.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Yangtze River Water Environment, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Pollution Control and Ecological Security, Shanghai, 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Wenxuan</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Qingdao Ecological Environment Bureau Jiaozhou Branch, Qingdao, 266300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Wanyu</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Yangtze River Water Environment, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Pollution Control and Ecological Security, Shanghai, 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Ge</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shimadzu China Co. Ltd (Shanghai Branch), Shanghai, 200233, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Jiajun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Yangtze River Water Environment, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Pollution Control and Ecological Security, Shanghai, 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Yao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Yangtze River Water Environment, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Pollution Control and Ecological Security, Shanghai, 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Zhiliang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Yangtze River Water Environment, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Pollution Control and Ecological Security, Shanghai, 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Yangtze River Water Environment, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Pollution Control and Ecological Security, Shanghai, 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qiu</LastName><ForeName>Yanling</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3002-7557</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Yangtze River Water Environment, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, 200092, China. ylqiu@tongji.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Pollution Control and Ecological Security, Shanghai, 200092, China. ylqiu@tongji.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2021YFC3200801</GrantID><Agency>the National Key Research and Development Project of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 2022-4-ZD-06</GrantID><Agency>Central University Basic Research Fund of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Sci Pollut Res Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9441769</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0944-1344</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ecological risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Organophosphate esters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Source apportionment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spatial distribution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Yangtze River</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval: This is not applicable. Consent to participate: This is not applicable. Consent to publish: This is not applicable. Competing interests: The authors have no relevant financial or non-financial interests to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41806297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-026-37567-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11356-026-37567-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bollmann UE, M&#xf6;ler A, Xie ZY, Ebinghaus R, Einax JW (2012) Occurrence and fate of organophosphorus flame retardants and plasticizers in coastal and marine surface waters. Water Res 46:531&#x2013;538. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2011.11.028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2011.11.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bondarenko S, Gan JY, Haver DL, Kabashima JN (2004) Persistence of selected organophosphate and carbamate insecticides in waters from a coastal watershed. Environ Toxicol Chem 23:2649&#x2013;2654. https://doi.org/10.1897/03-436</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1897/03-436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao M, Guo C-S, Zhang H, Liu S-Q, Chen M, Lu J-P, Hou S, You X-J, Xu J (2023) Occurrence distribution and risk assessment of organophosphate esters in a typical area of the estuary in the Yellow River Basin. Huan Jing Ke Xue= Huanjing Kexue 44:1378&#x2013;1386. https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202204164</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13227/j.hjkx.202204164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen ZK, An CJ, Elektorowicz M, Tian XL (2022) Sources, behaviors, transformations, and environmental risks of organophosphate esters in the coastal environment: A review. Mar Pollut Bull 180. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.marpolbul.2022.113779</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cristale J, Katsoyiannis A, Sweetman AJ, Jones KC, Lacorte S (2013) Occurrence and risk assessment of organophosphorus and brominated flame retardants in the River Aire (UK). Environ Pollut 179:194&#x2013;200. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2013.04.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envpol.2013.04.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cristale J, Dantas RF, De Luca A, Sans C, Esplugas S, Lacorte S (2017) Role of oxygen and DOM in sunlight induced photodegradation of organophosphorous flame retardants in river water. J Hazard Mater 323:242&#x2013;249. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2016.05.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2016.05.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du BB, Zhang Y, Chen H, Shen MJ, Zhou W, Zeng LX (2019) Development and validation of a liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry method for the simultaneous determination of 17 traditional and emerging aryl organophosphate esters in indoor dust. J Chromatogr A 1603:199&#x2013;207. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chroma.2019.06.045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chroma.2019.06.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Chemicals Bureau (2003) Technical Guidance Document on Risk Assessment Part &#x2161;. Office for Official Publications of the European Communities, Luxembourg</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan QY, Huang S, Guo JX, Xie Y, Chen M, Chen YF, Qi WX, Liu HJ, Jia ZY, Hu HX, Qu JH (2024) Spatiotemporal distribution and transport flux of organophosphate esters in the sediment of the Yangtze River. J Hazard Mater 477. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.135312</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang H, Yang LF, Yan M, Fan YA, Zhu JP, Ji LZ (2023) Research progress in cardiotoxicity of organophosphate esters. Front Pharmacol 14. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2023.1264515</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu J, Fu KH, Chen Y, Li XM, Ye T, Gao K, Pan WX, Zhang AQ, Fu JJ (2021) Long-range transport, trophic transfer, and ecological risks of organophosphate esters in remote areas. Environ Sci Technol 55:10192&#x2013;10209. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.0c08822</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.0c08822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao XZ, Huang P, Huang QH, Rao KF, Lu ZB, Xu YP, Gabrielsen GW, Hallanger I, Ma M, Wang ZJ (2019) Organophosphorus flame retardants and persistent, bioaccumulative, and toxic contaminants in Arctic seawaters: on-board passive sampling coupled with target and non-target analysis. Environ Pollut 253:1&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2019.06.094</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envpol.2019.06.094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou R, Xu YP, Wang ZJ (2016) Review of OPFRs in animals and humans: absorption, bioaccumulation, metabolism, and internal exposure research. Chemosphere 153:78&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2016.03.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2016.03.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu WX, Gao P, Wang L, Hu JY (2023) Endocrine disrupting toxicity of aryl organophosphate esters and mode of action. Crit Rev Environ Sci Technol 53:1&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10.1080/10643389.2022.2050147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10643389.2022.2050147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang JA, Ye LJ, Fang ML, Su GY (2022) Industrial production of organophosphate flame retardants (OPFRs): big knowledge gaps need to be filled? Bull Environ Contam Toxicol 108:809&#x2013;818. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00128-021-03454-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00128-021-03454-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang JA, Li JH, Meng WK, Su GY (2024) A critical review on organophosphate esters in drinking water: Analysis, occurrence, sources, and human health risk assessment. Sci Total Environ 913. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.169663</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang K, Fei J, Zhang Z, Kong R, Li M, Zhang Y, Liu C (2023) Exposure to environmentally relevant concentrations of TnBP results in tissue-specific bio-accumulation and inhibits growth of silver carp (Hypophthalmichthys molitrix). Chemosphere 334:138972. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2023.138972</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2023.138972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang MY, Zeng LJ, Wang C, Zhou X, Peng Y, Shi CL, Wang SS, Li Y, Barcel&#xf3; D, Li H (2025) A comprehensive and quantitative comparison of organophosphate esters: characteristics, applications, environmental occurrence, toxicity, and health risks. Crit Rev Environ Sci Technol 55:310&#x2013;333. https://doi.org/10.1080/10643389.2024.2406587</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10643389.2024.2406587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim UJ, Oh JK, Kannan K (2017) Occurrence, removal, and environmental emission of organophosphate flame retardants/plasticizers in a wastewater treatment plant in New York State. Environ Sci Technol 51:7872&#x2013;7880. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.7b02035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.7b02035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D, Zhang Q, Chen JQ, Zhang SH, Song NH, Xu HZ, Guo RX (2020a) Characterization and health risk assessment of organophosphate esters in indoor dust from urban and rural domestic house and college dormitory in Nanjing, China. Environ Sci Pollut Res 27:36826&#x2013;36837. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-020-09494-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-020-09494-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D, Zhang S-H, Zhang Q, Wang B, Pu Y-Q, Zhao X, Li H, Song N-H, Guo R-X (2020b) Occurrence and risk assessment of organophosphate esters in source water of the Nanjing section of the Yangtze River. Huan Jing Ke Xue= Huanjing Kexue 41:205&#x2013;212. https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.201907149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13227/j.hjkx.201907149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D, Zhong Y, Zhu XF, Wang HL, Yang WQ, Deng YR, Huang WL, Peng PA (2021) Reductive degradation of chlorinated organophosphate esters by nanoscale zerovalent iron/cetyltrimethylammonium bromide composites: reactivity, mechanism and new pathways. Water Res. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2020.116447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2020.116447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li SL, Wan YJ, Wang Y, He ZY, Xu SQ, Xia W (2022) Occurrence, spatial variation, seasonal difference, and ecological risk assessment of organophosphate esters in the Yangtze River, China: From the upper to lower reaches. Sci Total Environ 851. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.158021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li WT, Yuan Y, Wang SL, Liu XY (2023) Occurrence, spatiotemporal variation, and ecological risks of organophosphate esters in the water and sediment of the middle and lower streams of the Yellow River and its important tributaries. J Hazard Mater 443. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2022.130153</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian MS, Lin CY, Wu TT, Xin M, Gu X, Lu S, Cao YX, Wang BD, Ouyang W, Liu XT, He MC (2021) Occurrence, spatiotemporal distribution, and ecological risks of organophosphate esters in the water of the Yellow River to the Laizhou Bay, Bohai Sea. Sci Total Environ. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.147528</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.147528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv JP, Guo CS, Luo Y, Liu Y, Deng YH, Sun SW, Xu J (2022) Spatial distribution, receptor modelling and risk assessment of organophosphate esters in surface water from the largest freshwater lake in China. Ecotoxicol Environ Saf 238. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoenv.2022.113618</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma W-X, Yu Y-L, Chang J-J, Qiu Y-L, Zhang H, Zhu Z-L, Wang R (2024) Occurrence characteristics and health risk assessment of organophosphate esters in tap water of Shanghai. Huan Jing Ke Xue= Huanjing Kexue 45:6096&#x2013;6103. https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202310198</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13227/j.hjkx.202310198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma YX, Vojta S, Becanova J, Habtemichael AZ, Adelman DA, Muir D, Lohmann R (2021) Spatial distribution and air-water exchange of organophosphate esters in the lower Great Lakes*. Environ Pollut. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2021.117349</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envpol.2021.117349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Environmental Protection (2016a) Chinese Population Exposure Parameters Handbook (Children&#x2019;s Volume: 0-5 years). China Environment Press, Beijing</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Environmental Protection (2016b) Chinese Population Exposure Parameters Handbook (Children&#x2019;s Volume: 6-17 years). China Environment Press, Beijing</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Environmental Protection (2016c) Handbook of Chinese Population Exposure Parameters (Adult Volume). China Environment Press, Beijing</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pantelaki I, Voutsa D (2021) Organophosphate esters in inland and coastal waters in northern Greece. Sci Total Environ 800. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.149544</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao Y, Feng CL, Jin XW, Yan ZF, Feng WY, Wang Y, Bai YC (2024) Concentration levels and ecological risk assessment of typical organophosphate esters in representative surface waters of a megacity. Environ Res 251. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.118614</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt N, Castro-Jim&#xe9;nez J, Fauvelle V, Ourgaud M, Semp&#xe9;r&#xe9; R (2020) Occurrence of organic plastic additives in surface waters of the Rhone River (France). Environ Pollut 257. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2019.113637</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi YF, Zhang Y, Du YM, Kong DG, Wu QH, Hong YG, Wang Y, Tam NFY, Leung JYS (2020) Occurrence, composition and biological risk of organophosphate esters (OPEs) in water of the Pearl River Estuary, South China. Environ Sci Pollut Res 27:14852&#x2013;14862. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-020-08001-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-020-08001-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slotkin TA, Skavicus S, Stapleton HM, Seidler FJ (2017) Brominated and organophosphate flame retardants target different neurodevelopmental stages, characterized with embryonic neural stem cells and neuronotypic PC12 cells. Toxicology 390:32&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tox.2017.08.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tox.2017.08.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xfc;hring R, Diamond ML, Bernstein S, Adams JK, Schuster JK, Fernie K, Elliott K, Stern G, Jantunen LM (2021) Organophosphate esters in the Canadian Arctic Ocean. Environ Sci Technol 55:304&#x2013;312. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.0c04422</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.0c04422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>USEPA Exposure Factors Handbook, Washington DC</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Veen I, de Boer J (2012) Phosphorus flame retardants: properties, production, environmental occurrence, toxicity and analysis. Chemosphere 88:1119&#x2013;1153. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2012.03.067</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2012.03.067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M-H (2023) Source analysis of heavy metals in typical farmland soils based on PCA-APCS-MLR and geostatistics. Huan Jing Ke Xue= Huanjing Kexue 44:3509&#x2013;3519. https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202208002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13227/j.hjkx.202208002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Zhu QQ, Yan XT, Wang YW, Liao CY, Jiang GB (2020) A review of organophosphate flame retardants and plasticizers in the environment: Analysis, occurrence and risk assessment. Sci Total Environ 731. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2020.139071</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Sun HW, Zhu HK, Yao YM, Chen H, Ren C, Wu FC, Kannan K (2018) Occurrence and distribution of organophosphate flame retardants (OPFRs) in soil and outdoor settled dust from a multi-waste recycling area in China. Sci Total Environ 625:1056&#x2013;1064. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.01.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.01.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YL, Li XX, Chen SJ, Yang J, Fang B, Chen H, Yao YM, Sun HW (2024) Structure-dependent distribution, metabolism, and toxicity effects of alkyl organophosphate esters in lettuce (Lactuca sativa L.). Environ Sci Technol 58:17441&#x2013;17453. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c05523</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.4c05523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei GL, Li DQ, Zhuo MN, Liao YS, Xie ZY, Guo TL, Li JJ, Zhang SY, Liang ZQ (2015) Organophosphorus flame retardants and plasticizers: sources, occurrence, toxicity and human exposure. Environ Pollut 196:29&#x2013;46. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2014.09.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envpol.2014.09.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing LQ, Tao M, Zhang Q, Kong M, Sun J, Jia SY, Liu CH (2020) Occurrence, spatial distribution and risk assessment of organophosphate esters in surface water from the lower Yangtze River Basin. Sci Total Environ 734. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2020.139380</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing RG, Zhang P, Zheng N, Ji H, Shi R, Ge LK, Ma HR (2023) Organophosphate esters in the seawater of the Bohai Sea: Environmental occurrence, sources and ecological risks. Mar Pollut Bull 191. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.marpolbul.2023.114883</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Zhang BA, Hu QP, Liu Y, Shang T, Zeng XY, Yu ZQ (2021) Occurrence and spatio-seasonal distribution of organophosphate tri- and di-esters in surface water from Dongting Lake and their potential biological risk. Environ Pollut 282. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2021.117031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Liu P, Li M (2020) Tri-n-butyl phosphate induced earthworm intestinal damage by influencing nutrient absorption and energy homeostasis of intestinal epithelial cells. J Hazard Mater 398. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2020.122850</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Wei L, Wang R, Zhao GH, Yang SY, Cheng HF, Wu HL, Huang QH (2025) Uncovering the partitioning, transport flux and socioeconomic factors of organophosphate esters in an urban estuary of eastern China. Environ Pollut 373. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2025.126132</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao C, Yang HP, Li Y (2021) A review on organophosphate flame retardants in the environment: Occurrence, accumulation, metabolism and toxicity. Sci Total Environ 795. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.148837</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin X, Li X, Zhu D, Wang H, Li X, Yue S, Li A (2024) Residue characteristics,spatiotemporal distribution and ecotoxicological risk assessment of organochlorine pesticides and organophosphorus pesticides in surface water in northwest Tai Lake Basin. Acta Sci Circumstantiae 44:283&#x2013;298</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Jiang J, Xiang M, Dong C, Yu Y (2023) Derivation of oral reference dose for triphenyl phosphate using Bayesian benchmark dose modeling system. Environ Sci Technol 46:227&#x2013;236</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Lu L, Zhu WJ, Yang B, Lu DL, Dan SF, Zhang SF (2021a) Organophosphorus flame retardants (OPFRs) in the seawater and sediments of the Qinzhou Bay, Northern Beibu Gulf: Occurrence, distribution, and ecological risks. Mar Pollut Bull 168. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.marpolbul.2021.112368</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang SW, Yang C, Liu MY, Zhao WY, Li YX, Meng XZ, Cai MH (2021b) Occurrence of organophosphate esters in surface water and sediment in drinking water source of Xiangjiang River, China. Sci Total Environ. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.146734</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.146734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W-P, Zhang Z-F, Guo C-S, Lu J-P, Deng Y-H, Zhang H, Xu J (2021c) Pollution characteristics and risk assessment of organophosphate esters in rivers and water body around Taihu Lake. Huan Jing Ke Xue= Huanjing Kexue 42:1801&#x2013;1810. https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202008266</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13227/j.hjkx.202008266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang ZY, Shao HY, Wu MH, Zhang JY, Li DY, Li JS, Wang HY, Shi WY, Xu G (2019) Occurrence, distribution, and potential sources of organophosphate esters in urban and rural surface water in Shanghai, China. Arch Environ Contam Toxicol 77:115&#x2013;126. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00244-019-00633-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00244-019-00633-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J-L, Lu H-J, Lu J-P, Yang J-T, Luo Y, Cao M, Sun S-W, Guo C-S, Xu J (2023) Pollution level and risk assessment of OPEs in typical river basins of China. Huan Jing Ke Xue= Huanjing Kexue 44:6700&#x2013;6709. https://doi.org/10.13227/j.hjkx.202210293</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13227/j.hjkx.202210293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou LF, Wang XL, Zhang X, Liu LL, Liang JL, Zhao XL, Wu FC (2025) Besides traditional organophosphate esters: The ecological risks of emerging organophosphate esters in the Yangtze River basin cannot be ignored. Environ Pollut 367. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2024.125585</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu HK, Al-Bazi MM, Kumosani TA, Kannan K (2020) Occurrence and profiles of organophosphate esters in infant clothing and raw textiles collected from the United States. Environ Sci Technol Lett 7:415&#x2013;420. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.estlett.0c00221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.estlett.0c00221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>