<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41182878</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Plyometric and Ballistic Training Have Similar Effects on Young Amateur Male Wrestlers' Athletic Performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>98</StartPage><EndPage>105</EndPage><MedlinePgn>98-105</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005260</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Haghighi, AH, Shandiz, HH, Kakhak, SAH, Shahrabadi, H, Coswig, V, and Gentil, P. Plyometric and ballistic training have similar effects on young amateur male wrestlers' athletic performance. J Strength Cond Res 40(1): 98-105, 2026-This was a quasi-experimental study with a pretest and post-test design aimed at investigating the effects of resistance-plyometric training (RPT) compared with resistance-ballistic training (RBT) on the athletic performance of young amateur male wrestlers. Twenty wrestlers aged 16-18 years were randomly divided into RPT and RBT groups. The experimental groups participated in 3 sessions per week of the RPT or RBT program for 6 weeks in addition to their wrestling training routine during the preseason period. Before and after the intervention, the subjects were assessed for bench press strength, leg press strength, bench press endurance, leg press endurance, t test agility, 3-kg medicine ball throwing performance, Sargent jump performance, and specific wrestling tasks (flying mare, duck under, and rear throw). The results showed that both the RPT and RBT programs improved physical fitness (except for medicine ball throwing, which did not improve in RBT) and specific task performance (flying mare, duck under, and rear throw) with p &lt; 0.05. There were no differences between the RPT and RBT programs in any of the physical fitness indicators or specific task performances ( p &gt; 0.05). Considering that no significant difference was observed between the 2 types of training, young amateur male wrestlers could benefit from both RPT and RBT programs to improve their physical fitness and performance on specific tasks.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haghighi</LastName><ForeName>Amir Hossein</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Sports Sciences, Hakim Sabzevari University, Sabzevar, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shandiz</LastName><ForeName>Hamidreza Hosseinzadeh</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Sports Sciences, Hakim Sabzevari University, Sabzevar, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kakhak</LastName><ForeName>Seyed Alireza Hosseini</ForeName><Initials>SAH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad and Hakim Sabzevari University, Mashhad and Sabzevar, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahrabadi</LastName><ForeName>Hadi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Sports Sciences, Hakim Sabzevari University, Sabzevar, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coswig</LastName><ForeName>Victor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education, Federal University of Ceara, Fortaleza, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gentil</LastName><ForeName>Paulo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education and Dance, Federal University of Goias, Goiania, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014952" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wrestling</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059385" MajorTopicYN="Y">Plyometric Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">plyometrics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength and conditioning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41182878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Barbas I, Fatouros IG, Douroudos II, et al. Physiological and performance adaptations of elite Greco-Roman wrestlers during a one-day tournament. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 1421&#x2013;1436, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess KE, Connick MJ, Graham-Smith P, Pearson SJ. Plyometric vs. isometric training influences on tendon properties and muscle output. J Strength Cond Res 21: 986&#x2013;989, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaabene H, Negra Y, Bouguezzi R, et al. Physical and physiological attributes of wrestlers: An update. J Strength Cond Res 31: 1411&#x2013;1442, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandler PT, Greig M, Comfort P, McMahon JJ. Variability of plyometric and ballistic exercise technique maintains jump performance. J Strength Cond Res 32: 1571&#x2013;1582, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. (2nd ed.). New Jersey: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates Mahwah, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McGuigan MR, Newton RU. Adaptations in athletic performance after ballistic power versus strength training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 42: 1582&#x2013;1598, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cvetkovi&#x107; &#x10c;., Mari&#x107; J, Mareli&#x107; N. Technical efficiency of wrestlers in relation to some anthropometric and motor variables. Kinesiology 37: 74&#x2013;83, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies G, Riemann BL, Manske R. Current concepts of plyometric exercise. Int J Sports Phys Ther 10: 760&#x2013;786, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lemos Muller CH, Ramis TR, Ribeiro JL. Effects of low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction on the perceived exertion, muscular resistance and endurance in healthy young adults. Sport Sci Health 15: 503&#x2013;510, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Amiridis IG. Plyometric exercises: Optimizing the transfer of training gains to sport performance. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 51: 117&#x2013;127, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faigenbaum AD, Lloyd RS, MacDonald J, Myer GD. Citius, Altius, Fortius: Beneficial effects of resistance training for young athletes: Narrative review. Br J Sports Med 50: 3&#x2013;7, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faigenbaum AD, McFarland JE, Keiper FB, et al. Effects of a short-term plyometric and resistance training program on fitness performance in boys age 12 to 15 years. J Sports Sci Med 6: 519&#x2013;525, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathi A, Hammami R, Moran J, Borji R, Sahli S, Rebai H. Effect of a 16-week combined strength and plyometric training program followed by a detraining period on athletic performance in pubertal volleyball players. J Strength Cond Res 33: 2117&#x2013;2127, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferley DD, Scholten S, Vukovich MD. Combined sprint interval, plyometric, and strength training in adolescent soccer players: Effects on measures of speed, strength, power, change of direction, and anaerobic capacity. J Strength Cond Res 34: 957&#x2013;968, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Four&#xe9; A, Nordez A, Cornu C. Plyometric training effects on Achilles tendon stiffness and dissipative properties. J App Physiol 109: 849&#x2013;854, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritz CO, Morris PE, Richler JJ. Effect size estimates: Current use, calculations, and interpretation. J Exp Psychol Gen 141: 2&#x2013;18, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Pallar&#xe9;s J, L&#xf3;pez-Gull&#xf3;n JM, Muriel X, D&#xed;az A, Izquierdo M. Physical fitness factors to predict male Olympic wrestling performance. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 1747&#x2013;1758, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Bottaro M. Effects of training attendance on muscle strength of young men after 11 weeks of resistance training. Asian J Sports Med 4: 101&#x2013;106, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gierczuk D, Sadowski J. Fitness profiles of successful and less successful Greco-Roman and freestyle wrestlers. J Phys Edu Sport 21: 3541&#x2013;3546, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustiniani A, Battaglia G, Messina G, et al. Transcranial alternating current stimulation (tACS) does not affect sports people's explosive power: A pilot study. Front Hum Neurosci 15: 640609, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granacher U, Lesinski M, B&#xfc;sch D, et al. Effects of resistance training in youth athletes on muscular fitness and athletic performance: A conceptual model for long-term athlete development. Front Physiol 7: 164, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granacher U, Muehlbauer T, Doerflinger B, Strohmeier R, Gollhofer A. Promoting strength and balance in adolescents during physical education: Effects of a short-term resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 25: 940&#x2013;949, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haghighi AH, Hosseini SB, Askari R, Shahrabadi H, Ramirez-Campillo R. Effects of plyometric compared to high-intensity interval training on youth female basketball player's athletic performance. Sport Sci Health 20: 1&#x2013;10, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haghighi AH, Zaferanieh A, Hosseini-Kakhak SA, et al. Effects of power and ballistic training on table tennis players' electromyography changes. Int J Environ Res Publ Health 18: 7735, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman BW, Raiteri BJ, Connick MJ, Beckman EM, Macaro A, Kelly VG, James LP. Altered countermovement jump force profile and muscle-tendon unit kinematics following combined ballistic training. Scand J Med Sci Sports 32:1464-1476, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karagianni K, Donti O, Katsikas C, Bogdanis GC. Effects of supplementary strength-power training on neuromuscular performance in young female athletes. Sports (Basel) 8: 104, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitamura K, Roschel H, Loturco I, et al. Strength and power training improve skill performance in volleyball players. Motriz: Revista de Educa&#xe7;&#xe3;o F&#xed;sica 26: e10200034, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropractic Med 15: 155&#x2013;163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Gall F, Carling C, Reilly T, Vandewalle H, Church J, Rochcongar P. Incidence of injuries in elite French youth soccer players: A 10-season study. Am J Sports Med 34: 928&#x2013;938, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf8;ken J, Solstad TEJ, Stien N, Andersen V, Saeterbakken AH. Effects of bouncing the barbell in bench press on throwing velocity and strength among handball players. PLoS One 16: e0260297, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, Ratamess NA, Hoffman JR, Faigenbaum AD, Kang J, Chilakos A. The effects of combined ballistic and heavy resistance training on maximal lower- and upper-body strength in recreationally trained men. J Strength Cond Res 22: 132&#x2013;139, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marques V, Coswig V, Viana R, et al. Physical fitness and anthropometric measures of young Brazilian judo and wrestling athletes and its relations to cardiorespiratory fitness. Sports (Basel) 7: 38, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mc Dermott EJ, Balshaw TG, Brooke-Wavell K, Maden-Wilkinson TM, Folland JP. The effect of a prior eccentric lowering phase on concentric neuromechanics during multiple joint resistance exercise in older adults. Scand J Med Sci Sports 33: 2009&#x2013;2024, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEvoy K, Newton R. Baseball throwing speed and base running speed: The effects of ballistic resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 12: 216&#x2013;2221, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mersmann F, Bohm S, Schroll A, Boeth H, Duda G, Arampatzis A. Evidence of imbalanced adaptation between muscle and tendon in adolescent athletes. Scand J Med Sci Sports 24: e283&#x2013;e289, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mersmann F, Bohm S, Schroll A, Boeth H, Duda GN, Arampatzis A. Muscle and tendon adaptation in adolescent athletes: A longitudinal study. Scand J Med Sci Sports 27: 75&#x2013;82, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mersmann F, Bohm S, Schroll A, Marzilger R, Arampatzis A. Athletic training affects the uniformity of muscle and tendon adaptation during adolescence. J Appl Physiol 121: 893&#x2013;899, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narimani M, Esmaeilzadeh S, Pesola AJ, Haapala EA, Heidari B, Azevedo LB. Allometrically scaled explosive strength, but not static strength or maximal oxygen uptake is associated with better central processing time in young males. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 60: 947&#x2013;956, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojeda-Aravena A, Herrera-Valenzuela T, Vald&#xe9;s-Badilla P, B&#xe1;ez-San Mart&#xed;n E, Thapa RK, Ramirez-Campillo R. A systematic review with meta-analysis on the effects of plyometric-jump training on the physical fitness of combat sport athletes. Sports (Basel) 11: 33, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauole K, Madole K, Garhammer J, Lacourse M, Rozenek R. Reliability and validity of the T-Test as a measure of agility, leg power, and leg speed in college-aged men and women. J Strength Cond Res 14: 443&#x2013;450, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peitz M, Behringer M, Granacher U. A systematic review on the effects of resistance and plyometric training on physical fitness in youth- what do comparative studies tell us? PLoS One 13: e0205525, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Gomez J, Olmedillas H, Delgado-Guerra S, et al. Effects of weight lifting training combined with plyometric exercises on physical fitness, body composition, and knee extension velocity during kicking in football. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 33: 501&#x2013;510, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrov R. Olympic Wrestling Throughout the Millennia. International Amateur Wrestling Federation, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, &#xc1;lvarez C, Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, et al. Methodological characteristics and future directions for plyometric jump training research: A scoping review. Sports Med 48: 1059&#x2013;1081, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Castillo D, Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Moran J, de Villarreal ES, Lloyd RS. Effects of plyometric jump training on jump and sprint performance in young male soccer players: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 50: 2125&#x2013;2143, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Garc&#xed;a-de-Alcaraz A, Chaabene H, Moran J, Negra Y, Granacher U. Effects of plyometric jump training on physical fitness in amateur and professional volleyball: A meta-analysis. Front Physiol 12: 636140, 2021a.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Garc&#xed;a-de-Alcaraz A, Chaabene H, Moran J, Negra Y, Granacher U. Effects of plyometric jump training on physical fitness in amateur and professional volleyball: A meta-analysis. Front Physiol 12: 636140, 2021b.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, Moran J, Chaabene H, Negra Y, Scanlan AT. The effects of plyometric jump training on physical fitness attributes in basketball players: A meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci 11: 656&#x2013;670, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Gentil P, Negra Y, Grgic J, Girard O. Effects of plyometric jump training on repeated sprint ability in athletes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 51: 2165&#x2013;2179, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Hansen EA, Raastad T. Strength training affects tendon cross-sectional area and freely chosen cadence differently in noncyclists and well-trained cyclists. J Strength Cond Res 26: 158&#x2013;166, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sholeh KK, Farshad T. The construction and validation of a test of wrestling skill. Res J Fish Hydrobiol 10: 188&#x2013;194, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sole S, Ram&#xed;rez-Campillo R, Andrade DC, Sanchez-Sanchez J. Plyometric jump training effects on the physical fitness of individual-sport athletes: A systematic review with meta-analysis. PeerJ 9: e11004, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi R. Plyometrics: Power training for judo: Plyometric training with medicine balls. Natl Strength Cond Assoc J 14: 66&#x2013;71, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weir JP. Quantifying test-retest reliability using the intraclass correlation coefficient and the SEM. J Strength Cond Res 19: 231&#x2013;240, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weldon A, Duncan MJ, Turner A, Lockie RG, Loturco I. Practices of strength and conditioning coaches in professional sports: A systematic review. Biol Sport 39: 715&#x2013;726, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaferanieh A, Haghighi AH, Kakhak SAH, Maleki A, C&#xe8; E, Esposito F. Effect of ballistic and power training on performance adaptations of &#xe9;lite table tennis players. Sport Sci Health 17: 181&#x2013;190, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaras N, Spengos K, Methenitis S, et al. Effects of strength vs. ballistic-power training on throwing performance. J Sports Sci Med 12: 130&#x2013;137, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zghal F, Colson SS, Blain G, Behm DG, Granacher U, Chaouachi A. Combined resistance and plyometric training is more effective than plyometric training alone for improving physical fitness of pubertal soccer players. Front Physiol 10: 1026, 2019.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>