<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41673030</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2052-4463</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific data</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Data</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Glacier Inventory Dataset of the Qilian Mountains for the Period 2018-2019.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">419</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41597-026-06782-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The Qilian Mountains are located in the arid region of northwestern China and represent a vital ecological functional zone in this area. Glaciers in the Qilian Mountains, as the primary source of freshwater, play a crucial role in regulating the regional water cycle, maintaining ecological balance, and supporting socio-economic activities across the region. Against the backdrop of global warming, glaciers in this region have exhibited a clear trend of retreat. However, the glacier inventory data from China's First and Second National Glacier Inventories are relatively outdated and no longer accurately reflect the current state of glacier changes in the area. This study utilized high-resolution satellite imagery from 2018-2019, including data from the Gaofen series (Gaofen-1, Gaofen-2, and Gaofen-6), Ziyuan-3, and Landsat 8, as primary data sources. Glacier boundaries were delineated through visual interpretation, and relevant attributes were supplemented based on the GLIMS (Global Land Ice Measurements from Space) coding scheme. The final product is the Glacier Inventory Dataset of the Qilian Mountains for the period 2018-2019. The results show that a total of 2797 modern glaciers are distributed across the Qilian Mountains, with a combined area of 1489.53&#x2009;km&#xb2;. This dataset provides valuable support for studies related to glacier change and associated environmental processes in the Qilian Mountain region.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qin</LastName><ForeName>Xiang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Qilianshan Observation and Research Station of Cryosphere and Ecologic Environment, State Key Laboratory of Cryospheric Science and Frozen Soil Engineering, Northwest Institute of Eco- Environment and Resources, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Lanzhou, 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, 100049, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Renjun</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Qilianshan Observation and Research Station of Cryosphere and Ecologic Environment, State Key Laboratory of Cryospheric Science and Frozen Soil Engineering, Northwest Institute of Eco- Environment and Resources, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Lanzhou, 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, 100049, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yushuo</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1518-4829</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Qilianshan Observation and Research Station of Cryosphere and Ecologic Environment, State Key Laboratory of Cryospheric Science and Frozen Soil Engineering, Northwest Institute of Eco- Environment and Resources, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Lanzhou, 730000, China. yushuo_liu@lzb.ac.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jinlong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Remote Sensing of Gansu Province, Heihe Remote Sensing Experimental Research Station, Northwest Institute of Eco-Environment and Resources, Chinese Academy of Sciences, 730000, Lanzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Western China's Environmental Systems (Ministry of Education), College of Earth and Environmental Sciences, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gansu Natural Resources Satellite Application Technology Center, Lanzhou, 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Data</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101640192</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-4463</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41673030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13004958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41597-026-06782-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41597-026-06782-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yang, M. <i>et al</i>. The Tibetan Plateau cryosphere: Observations and model simulations for current status and recent changes. <i>Earth-Science Reviews</i><b>190</b>, 353&#x2013;369 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.earscirev.2018.12.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levermann, A. <i>et al</i>. Potential climatic transitions with profound impact on Europe: Review of the current state of six &#x2018;tipping elements of the climate system&#x2019;. <i>Climatic Change</i><b>110</b>, 845&#x2013;878 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10584-011-0126-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stocker, T. F., Qin, D. &amp; Plattner, G. K. Observations: Cryosphere. Climate Change 2013: The Physical Science Basis. Contribution of Working Group I to the Fifth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, D. <i>et al</i>. Cryospheric science: research framework and disciplinary system. <i>National Science Review</i><b>5</b>(2), 255&#x2013;268 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nsr/nwx108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boy, M. <i>et al</i>. Interactions between the atmosphere, cryosphere, and ecosystems at northern high latitudes. <i>Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics</i><b>19</b>(3), 2015&#x2013;2061 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/acp-19-2015-2019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S. <i>et al</i>. Changes in the global cryosphere and their impacts: A review and new perspective. <i>Sciences in Cold and Arid Regions</i><b>12</b>(6), 343&#x2013;354 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeBeer, C. M., Sharp, M. &amp; Schuster-Wallace, C. Glaciers and ice sheets. <i>World</i><b>215</b>(705,739), 1565 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barry, R. G. The cryosphere&#x2013;past, present, and future: a review of the frozen water resources of the world. <i>Polar Geography</i><b>34</b>(4), 219&#x2013;227 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1088937X.2011.638146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad, S. &amp; Thapa, A. Improved MODIS TERRA/AQUA composite Snow and glacier (RGI6. 0) data for High Mountain Asia (2002&#x2013;2018). <i>PANGAEA</i> (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, B. <i>et al</i>. Changes in the supply and demand potentials of China&#x2019;s glacier water resources in the 21st century: Spatiotemporal mismatches and combined effects. <i>Advances in Climate Change Research</i><b>14</b>(5), 746&#x2013;757 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.accre.2023.09.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, T. <i>et al</i>. The imbalance of the Asian water tower. <i>Nature Reviews Earth &amp; Environment</i><b>3</b>(10), 618&#x2013;632 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43017-022-00299-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodge, S. M. <i>et al</i>. Climate variations and changes in mass of three glaciers in western North America. <i>Journal of Climate</i><b>11</b>(9), 2161&#x2013;2179 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1175/1520-0442(1998)011&lt;2161:CVACIM&gt;2.0.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baolin, L., Yichi, Z. &amp; Chenghu, Z. Remote sensing detection of glacier changes in Tianshan Mountains for the past 40 years. <i>Journal of Geographical sciences</i><b>14</b>, 296&#x2013;302 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02837410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen, L. A. <i>et al</i>. Integrated research on mountain glaciers: current status, priorities and future prospects. <i>Geomorphology</i><b>103</b>(2), 158&#x2013;171 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geomorph.2008.04.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolch, T. <i>et al</i>. A glacier inventory for the western Nyainqentanglha Range and the Nam Co Basin, Tibet, and glacier changes 1976&#x2013;2009. <i>The Cryosphere</i><b>4</b>(3), 419&#x2013;433 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/tc-4-419-2010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon, T. Saying goodbye to glaciers. <i>Science</i><b>356</b>(6338), 580&#x2013;581 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aam9625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28495713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehecq, A. <i>et al</i>. Twenty-first century glacier slowdown driven by mass loss in High Mountain Asia. <i>Nature Geoscience</i><b>12</b>(1), 22&#x2013;27 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41561-018-0271-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansson, P. <i>et al</i>. The concept of glacier storage: a review. <i>Journal of Hydrology</i><b>282</b>(1-4), 116&#x2013;129 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-1694(03)00258-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorg, A. <i>et al</i>. Climate change impacts on glaciers and runoff in Tien Shan (Central Asia). <i>Nature Climate Change</i><b>2</b>(10), 725&#x2013;731 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nclimate1592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, J. <i>et al</i>. Assessment of runoff generation capacity and total runoff contribution for different landscapes in alpine and permafrost watershed. <i>Catena</i><b>249</b>, 108643 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.catena.2024.108643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, Y. <i>et al</i>. Snowmelt risk telecouplings for irrigated agriculture. <i>Nature Climate Change</i><b>12</b>(11), 1007&#x2013;1015 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41558-022-01509-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, L. <i>et al</i>. Changes in characteristics of climate extremes from 1961 to 2017 in Qilian Mountain area, northwestern China. <i>Environmental Earth Sciences</i><b>81</b>(6), 177 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-022-10297-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai, B. <i>et al</i>. Changing characteristics of ecosystem and water storage under the background of warming and humidification in the Qilian Mountains, China. <i>Science of the Total Environment</i><b>893</b>, 164959 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.164959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37331391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, M. <i>et al</i>. Glacier changes in the Qilian Mountains in the past half-century: Based on the revised First and Second Chinese Glacier Inventory. <i>Journal of Geographical Sciences</i><b>28</b>, 206&#x2013;220 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11442-018-1468-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, M. <i>et al</i>. What induces the spatiotemporal variability of glacier mass balance across the Qilian Mountains. <i>Climate Dynamics</i><b>59</b>(11), 3555&#x2013;3577 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00382-022-06283-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian, H., Yang, T. &amp; Liu, Q. Climate change and glacier area shrinkage in the Qilian mountains, China, from 1956 to 2010. <i>Annals of Glaciology</i><b>55</b>(66), 187&#x2013;197 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3189/2014AoG66A045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, L. &amp; Li, X. Dataset of the first glacier inventory in China. <i>Cold and Arid Regions Science Data Center at Lanzhou</i> (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, W. <i>et al</i>. The second Chinese glacier inventory: data, methods and results. <i>Journal of Glaciology</i><b>61</b>(226), 357&#x2013;372 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3189/2015JoG14J209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad, S. &amp; Thapa, A. An improved Terra&#x2013;Aqua MODIS snow cover and Randolph Glacier Inventory 6.0 combined product (MOYDGL06*) for high-mountain Asia between 2002 and 2018. <i>Earth System Science Data</i><b>12</b>(1), 345&#x2013;356 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/essd-12-345-2020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad, S. &amp; Thapa, A. Daily Terra&#x2013;Aqua MODIS cloud-free snow and Randolph Glacier Inventory 6.0 combined product (M* D10A1GL06) for high-mountain Asia between 2002 and 2019. <i>Earth System Science Data</i><b>13</b>(2), 767&#x2013;776 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/essd-13-767-2021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu, X. <i>et al</i>. Glacier extraction based on high-spatial-resolution remote-sensing images using a deep-learning approach with attention mechanism. <i>The Cryosphere</i><b>16</b>(10), 4273&#x2013;4289 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/tc-16-4273-2022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rott, H. &amp; Paul, F. Satellite Remote Sensing of Glaciers and Ice Sheets. Glaciers and Ice Sheets in the Climate System: The Karthaus Summer School Lecture Notes 327-348 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller, F., Caflisch, T. &amp; M&#xfc;ller, G. Instructions for compilation and assemblage of data for a World Glacier Inventory. Zurich: Department of Geography, Swiss Federal Institute of Technology (ETH) (1977).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, J. C. &amp; Sampson, R. J. <i>Statistics and data analysis in geology</i>. New York: Wiley (1986).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. Glacier inventory data of Qilian Mountains in 2018/2019. <i>National Tibetan Plateau / Third Pole Environment Data Center</i>, 10.11888/Cryos.tpdc.302479 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita, K., Sakai, A., Nuimura, T., Yamaguchi, S. &amp; Sharma, R. R. Recent changes in Imja Glacial Lake and its damming moraine in the Nepal Himalayarevealed by <i>in situ</i> surveys and multi-temporal ASTER imagery. <i>Environmental Research Letters</i><b>4</b>(4), 045205 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-9326/4/4/045205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. <i>et al</i>. Quantitative analysis of Arctic ice flow acceleration with increasing temperature. <i>Acta Oceanologica Sinica</i><b>40</b>(1), 22&#x2013;32 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13131-021-1718-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul, F. <i>et al</i>. Recommendations for the compilation of glacier inventory data from digital sources. <i>Annals of Glaciology</i><b>50</b>(53), 119&#x2013;126 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3189/172756410790595778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>