<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41461049</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1603</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neurophysiology : official publication of the American Electroencephalographic Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neurophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>American Clinical Neurophysiology Society Technical Standards for Performing Intraoperative Electrocorticography.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>101</StartPage><EndPage>109</EndPage><MedlinePgn>101-109</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WNP.0000000000001233</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">These consensus guidelines by the American Clinical Neurophysiology Society (ACNS) describe best practices for performing intraoperative Electrocorticography (ioECoG) using subdural or depth electrodes for adult and pediatric population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A group of ACNS members was convened to develop technical standards for performing ioECoG. PubMed searches were performed to identify pertinent peer-reviewed literature. Sections were assigned to individual authors based on expertise. Consensus was achieved during subsequent group discussions to develop evidence-based recommendations to the extent possible.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECOMMENDATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Communication between the neurosurgical and the neurophysiology teams is essential in verifying and documenting the location of the contacts. Most authors recommend ioECoG recordings of at least 5 and up to 30 minutes in duration to allow for sufficient observation of interictal activity. The anesthesia should be adjusted to allow continuous EEG activity and to minimize the effect on the ioECoG recording during general anesthesia or awake surgery. The surgical procedure and technical report should separate ioECoG recordings to define the irritative zone from ioECoG findings during functional mapping. The neurophysiology physician's physical presence in the operating room is required in the definition of the services.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These consensus guidelines by the ACNS describe best practices for performing intraoperative ECoG based on published literature and expert consensus.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 by the American Clinical Neurophysiology Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schuele</LastName><ForeName>Stephan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northwestern University, Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Husain</LastName><ForeName>Aatif</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Duke University, Durham, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tatum</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mayo Clinic College of Medicine &amp; Health Science, Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gavvala</LastName><ForeName>Jay</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UTHealth Houston, Texas Medical Center Houston, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Selioutski</LastName><ForeName>Olga</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sinha</LastName><ForeName>Saurabh R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Pennsylvania Perelman School of Medicine, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Inati</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NINDS, National Institute of Health, Bethesda, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jacobs</LastName><ForeName>Julia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gloss</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Charleston Area Medical Center, Charleston, West Virginia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alkawadri</LastName><ForeName>Rafeed</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nordli</LastName><ForeName>Doug</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Chicago Medicine, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Templer</LastName><ForeName>Jessica</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northwestern University, Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keller</LastName><ForeName>Crystal</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Duke University, Durham, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nuwer</LastName><ForeName>Marc</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCLA Medical Center, Los Angeles, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017065">Practice Guideline</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neurophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8506708</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0736-0258</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069280" MajorTopicYN="Y">Electrocorticography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064795" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intraoperative Neurophysiological Monitoring</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012955" MajorTopicYN="N">Societies, Medical</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurophysiology</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004569" MajorTopicYN="N">Electroencephalography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Awake mapping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intraoperative electrocorticography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Technical standards</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ioECoG</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41461049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNP.0000000000001233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004691-990000000-00286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nuwer MR, Schuele SU. Electrocorticography. In: Schomer DL, Lopes da Silva F, eds. Niedermeyer&#x2019;s Electroencephalopgraphy. 7th ed. Oxford University Press; 2018:Chapter 30:771&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo J, Wang Z, van't Klooster MA, et al. Seizure outcome after intraoperative electrocorticography-tailored epilepsy surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurology 2024;102:e209430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel K, Pek V, Shlobin NA, et al. Clinical utility of intraoperative electrocorticography for epilepsy surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Epilepsia 2023;64:253&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warsi NM, Mohammad AH, Zhang F, et al. Electrocorticography-guided resection enhances postoperative seizure freedom in low-grade tumor-associated epilepsy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Review. Neurosurgery 2023;92:18&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha SR, Sullivan L, Sabau D, et al. American clinical neurophysiology society guideline 1: minimum technical requirements for performing clinical electroencephalography. J Clin Neurophysiol 2016;33:303&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metting van Rijn AC, Peper A, Grimbergen CA. High-quality recording of bioelectric events. Part 2. Low-noise, low-power multichannel amplifier design. Med Biol Eng Comput 1991;29:433&#x2013;440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess RC. Electrical safety. Handb Clin Neurol 2019;160:67&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worrell GA, Stead M, Cascino G. Electrocorticography. In: Nuwer MR, ed. Handbook of clinical neurophysiology: intraoperative monitoring of human function. Amsterdam, Elsevier; 2008:141&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St Louis EK, Frey LC. Electroencephalography (EEG). An introductory text and atlas of normal and abnormal findings in adults, children and infants. American Epilepsy Society; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American clinical neurophysiology S. Guideline twelve: guidelines for long-term monitoring for epilepsy. J Clin Neurophysiol 2008;25:170&#x2013;180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metting van Rijn AC, Peper A, Grimbergen CA. High-quality recording of bioelectric events. Part 1. Interference reduction, theory and practice. Med Biol Eng Comput 1990;28:389&#x2013;397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AF, Bolger DJ. The neurophysiological bases of EEG and EEG measurement: a review for the rest of us. Psychophysiology 2014;51:1061&#x2013;1071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha SR, Keller CM. Epilepsy surgery and brain mapping. In: Husain AM, ed. A practical approach to neurophyhsiologic intraoperative monitoring. 2nd ed. New York: Demos Medical; 2015:287&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blatt DR, Roper SN, Friedman WA. Invasive monitoring of limbic epilepsy using stereotactic depth and subdural strip electrodes: surgical technique. Surg Neurol 1997;48:74&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widdess-Walsh P, Jeha L, Nair D, Kotagal P, Bingaman W, Najm I. Subdural electrode analysis in focal cortical dysplasia: predictors of surgical outcome. Neurology 2007;69:660&#x2013;667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatum WO, Dionisio JB, Vale FL. Subdural electrodes in focal epilepsy surgery at a typical academic epilepsy center. J Clin Neurophysiol 2015;32:139&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatum WO, McKay JH, ReFaey K, et al. Detection of after-discharges during intraoperative functional brain mapping in awake brain tumor surgery using a novel high-density circular grid. Clin Neurophysiol 2020;131:828&#x2013;835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekelis K, Radwan TA, Desai A, et al. Subdural interhemispheric grid electrodes for intracranial epilepsy monitoring: feasibility, safety, and utility: clinical article. J Neurosurg 2012;117:1182&#x2013;1188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavvala J, Zafar M, Sinha SR, Kalamangalam G, Schuele S. Stereotactic EEG practices: a survey of United States tertiary referral epilepsy centers. J Clin Neurophysiol 2020; 39:474&#x2013;480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritaccio AL, Brunner P, Schalk G. Electrical stimulation mapping of the brain: basic principles and emerging alternatives. J Clin Neurophysiol 2018;35:86&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schijns OE, Hoogland G, Kubben PL, Koehler PJ. The start and development of epilepsy surgery in Europe: a historical review. Neurosurg Rev 2015;38:447&#x2013;461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widmann G, Schullian P, Ortler M, Bale R. Frameless stereotactic targeting devices: technical features, targeting errors and clinical results. Int J Med Robot 2012;8:1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta AD, Labar D, Dean A, et al. Frameless stereotactic placement of depth electrodes in epilepsy surgery. J Neurosurg 2005;102:1040&#x2013;1045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grewal SS, Alvi MA, Perkins WJ, et al. Reassessing the impact of intraoperative electrocorticography on postoperative outcome of patients undergoing standard temporal lobectomy for MRI-negative temporal lobe epilepsy. J Neurosurg 2019;132:605&#x2013;614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takayama Y, Ikegaya N, Iijima K, et al. Single-institutional experience of chronic intracranial electroencephalography based on the combined usage of subdural and depth electrodes. Brain Sci 2021;11:307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halford JJ, Sabau D, Drislane FW, Tsuchida TN, Sinha SR. American clinical neurophysiology society guideline 4: recording clinical EEG on digital media. Neurodiagn J 2016;56:261&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritaccio A, Boatman-Reich D, Brunner P, et al. Proceedings of the second international workshop on advances in electrocorticography. Epilepsy Behav 2011;22:641&#x2013;650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagerlund TD, Gross RA. DC-EEG recording: a paradigm shift in seizure localization? Neurology 2003;60:1062&#x2013;1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frauscher B, Bartolomei F, Kobayashi K, et al. High-frequency oscillations: the state of clinical research. Epilepsia 2017;58:1316&#x2013;1329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arya R, Mangano FT, Horn PS, Holland KD, Rose DF, Glauser TA. Adverse events related to extraoperative invasive EEG monitoring with subdural grid electrodes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Epilepsia 2013;54:828&#x2013;839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullin JP, Shriver M, Alomar S, et al. Is SEEG safe? A systematic review and meta-analysis of stereo-electroencephalography-related complications. Epilepsia 2016;57:386&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abecassis ZA, Ayer AB, Templer JW, Yerneni K, Murthy NK, Tate MC. Analysis of risk factors and clinical sequelae of direct electrical cortical stimulation-induced seizures and afterdischarges in patients undergoing awake mapping. J Neurosurg 2020;134:1610&#x2013;1617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natalini D, Ganau M, Rosenkranz R, et al. Comparison of the asleep-awake-asleep technique and monitored anesthesia care during awake craniotomy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurosurg Anesthesiol 2022;34:e1-e13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aghajanian S, Naeimi A, Mohammadifard F, et al. Efficacy and safety of anesthetic agents in awake craniotomy using monitored anesthesia care protocol: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurosurg Rev 2025;48:57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokkinos V, Zaher N, Antony A, Bagi&#x107; A, Mark Richardson R, Urban A. The intracranial correlate of the 14&amp;6/sec positive spikes normal scalp EEG variant. Clin Neurophysiol 2019;130:1570&#x2013;1580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLachlan RS, Luba N. Cortical location of benign paroxysmal rhythms in the electrocorticogram. Can J Neurol Sci 2002;29:154&#x2013;158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filho AP, Cukiert A, Diambra L. Peri-ictal complexity loss as determined by approximate entroph analysis in the electrocortigram obtained by chronic subdural recordings in patients with refractory temporal lobe epilepsy. J Epilepsy Clin Neurophysiol 2006;12:191&#x2013;199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagasawa T, Juhasz C, Rothermel R, Hoechstetter K, Sood S, Asano E. Spontaneous and visually driven high-frequency oscillations in the occipital cortex: intracranial recording in epileptic patients. Hum Brain Mapp 2012;33:569&#x2013;583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melani F, Zelmann R, Mari F, Gotman J. Continuous high frequency activity: a peculiar SEEG pattern related to specific brain regions. Clin Neurophysiol 2013;124:1507&#x2013;1516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmini A, Gambardella A, Andermann F, et al. Intrinsic epileptogenicity of human dysplastic cortex as suggested by corticography and surgical results. Ann Neurol 1995;37:476&#x2013;487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez IS, Loddenkemper T. Electrocorticography for seizure foci mapping in epilepsy surgery. J Clin Neurophysiol 2013;30:554&#x2013;570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xf6;ppel G, Dorfer C, Samueli S, et al. Single stage epilepsy surgery in children and adolescents with focal cortical dysplasia type II-prognostic value of the intraoperative electrocorticogram. Clin Neurophysiol 2019;130:20&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T, Hakimian S, Schwartz TH. Intraoperative ElectroCorticoGraphy (ECog): indications, techniques, and utility in epilepsy surgery. Epileptic Disord 2014;16:271&#x2013;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alarcon G, Garcia Seoane JJ, Binnie CD, et al. Origin and propagation of interictal discharges in the acute electrocorticogram. Implications for pathophysiology and surgical treatment of temporal lobe epilepsy. Brain 1997;120:2259&#x2013;2282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asano E, Muzik O, Shah A, et al. Quantitative interictal subdural EEG analyses in children with neocortical epilepsy. Epilepsia 2003;44:425&#x2013;434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmini A, Paglioli E. The irritative zone and seizure onset zone in acute ECOG: the quest for relevant epileptogenic tissue. In: Lhatoo SD, Kahane P, Luders HO, eds. Invasive studies of the human epileptic brain: principles and practice. 1st ed. Oxford University Press; 2018:120&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu JY, Sankar R, Lerner JT, Matsumoto JH, Vinters HV, Mathern GW. Removing interictal fast ripples on electrocorticography linked with seizure freedom in children. Neurology 2010;75:1686&#x2013;1694.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs J, Wu JY, Perucca P, et al. Removing high-frequency oscillations: a prospective multicenter study on seizure outcome. Neurology 2018;91:e1040-e1052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zijlmans M, Worrell GA, D&#xfc;mpelmann M, et al. How to record high-frequency oscillations in epilepsy: a practical guideline. Epilepsia 2017;58:1305&#x2013;1315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zijlmans M, Huiskamp GM, Cremer OL, Ferrier CH, van Huffelen AC, Leijten FS. Epileptic high-frequency oscillations in intraoperative electrocorticography: the effect of propofol. Epilepsia 2012;53:1799&#x2013;1809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chui J, Manninen P, Valiante T, Venkatraghavan L. The anesthetic considerations of intraoperative electrocorticography during epilepsy surgery. Anesth Analg 2013;117:479&#x2013;486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacar BayramA, Yan Q, Isitan C, Rao S, Spencer DD, Alkawadri R. Effect of anesthesia on electrocorticography for localization of epileptic focus: literature review and future directions. Epilepsy Behav 2021;118:107902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon MV, Nuwer MR, Szel&#xe9;nyi A. Electroencephalography, electrocorticography, and cortical stimulation techniques. Handb Clin Neurol 2022;186:11&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire G, El-Beheiry H, Manninen P, Lozano A, Wennberg R. Activation of electrocorticographic activity with remifentanil and alfentanil during neurosurgical excision of epileptogenic focus. Br J Anaesth 2003;91:651&#x2013;655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun D, van't Klooster MA, Ringeling EM, et al. Pausing propofol during neurosurgery to record intraoperative electrocorticography is feasible; 10 years of clinical experience. Clin Neurophysiol 2024;167:84&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaitanya G, Arivazhagan A, Sinha S, et al. Dexmedetomidine anesthesia enhances spike generation during intra-operative electrocorticography: a promising adjunct for epilepsy surgery. Epilepsy Res 2015;109:65&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs J, LeVan P, Chander R, Hall J, Dubeau F, Gotman J. Interictal high-frequency oscillations (80-500 hz) are an indicator of seizure onset areas independent of spikes in the human epileptic brain. Epilepsia 2008;49:1893&#x2013;1907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van't Klooster MA, van Klink NE, Leijten FS, et al. Residual fast ripples in the intraoperative corticogram predict epilepsy surgery outcome. Neurology 2015;85:120&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain SA, Mathern GW, Sankar R, Wu JY. Prospective and &#x201c;live&#x201d; fast ripple detection and localization in the operating room: impact on epilepsy surgery outcomes in children. Epilepsy Res 2016;127:344&#x2013;351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe9;nar CG, Chauvi&#xe8;re L, Bartolomei F, Wendling F. Pitfalls of high-pass filtering for detecting epileptic oscillations: a technical note on &#x201c;false&#x201d; ripples. Clin Neurophysiol 2010;121:301&#x2013;310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedele T, van 't Klooster M, Burnos S, et al. Automatic detection of high frequency oscillations during epilepsy surgery predicts seizure outcome. Clin Neurophysiol 2016;127:3066&#x2013;3074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss SA, Berry B, Chervoneva I, et al. Visually validated semi-automatic high-frequency oscillation detection aides the delineation of epileptogenic regions during intra-operative electrocorticography. Clin Neurophysiol 2018;129:2089&#x2013;2098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amiri M, Lina JM, Pizzo F, Gotman J. High frequency oscillations and spikes: separating real HFOs from false oscillations. Clin Neurophysiol 2016;127:187&#x2013;196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sartorius CJ, Berger MS. Rapid termination of intraoperative stimulation-evoked seizures with application of cold Ringer's lactate to the cortex. Technical note. J Neurosurg 1998;88:349&#x2013;351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano SG, Eldredge EA, Wang FK, et al. The effect of propofol on intraoperative electrocorticography and cortical stimulation during awake craniotomies in children. Paediatric Anaesth 2000;10:29&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skucas AP, Artru AA. Anesthetic complications of awake craniotomies for epilepsy surgery. Anesth Analgesia 2006;102:882&#x2013;887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosain S, Nagarajan L, Fraser R, Van Poznak A, Labar D. Effects of nitrous oxide on electrocorticography during epilepsy surgery. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol 1997;102:340&#x2013;342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cascino GD. Pharmacological activation. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol Suppl 1998;48:70&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endo T, Sato K, Shamoto H, Yoshimoto T. Effects of sevoflurane on electrocorticography in patients with intractable temporal lobe epilepsy. J Neurosurg Anesthesiol 2002;14:59&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesko R, Benova B, Jezdik P, et al. The clinical utility of intraoperative electrocorticography in pediatric epilepsy surgical strategy and planning. J Neurosurg Pediatr 2020;26:533&#x2013;542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty A, Pardeshi S, Shah VM, Kulkarni A. Anesthesia considerations in epilepsy surgery. Int J Surg 2016;36:454&#x2013;459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal S, Kim AJ, Berg AT, et al. Seizure outcomes in children following electrocorticography-guided single-stage surgical resection. Pediatr Neurol 2017;71:35&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shewmon A. Electroencephalography as a localizing tool. Neurosurg Clin N Am 1995;6:481&#x2013;490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinner DS, L&#xfc;ders H, Lesser RP, Morris HH. Cortical generators of somatosensory evoked potentials to median nerve stimulation. Neurology 1987;37:1141&#x2013;1145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arya R, Baumer FM, Chauvel P, et al. American clinical neurophysiology society technical standards for electrical stimulation with intracranial electrodes for functional brain mapping and seizure induction. J Clin Neurophysiol 2025;42:190&#x2013;200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nossek E, Matot I, Shahar T, et al. Intraoperative seizures during awake craniotomy: incidence and consequences: analysis of 477 patients. Neurosurgery 2013;73:135&#x2013;140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penfield WB, Boldrey E. Somatic motor and sensory representation in the cerebral cortex of man as studied by electric stimulation. Brain 1937;60:389&#x2013;443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taniguchi M, Cedzich C, Schramm J. Modification of cortical stimulation for motor evoked potentials under general anesthesia: technical description. Neurosurgery 1993;32:219&#x2013;226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selner AN, Stone JL. Somatosensory- and motor-evoked potentials in surgery of eloquent cortex under general anesthesia: advantages and limitations. In: Byrne RW, ed. Functional mapping of the cerebral cortex: safe surgery in eloquent cortex. Springer; 2016:115&#x2013;140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair DR, Burgess R, McIntyre CC, L&#xfc;ders H. Chronic subdural electrodes in the management of epilepsy. Clin Neurophysiol 2008;119:11&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blume WT, Jones DC, Pathak P. Properties of after-discharges from cortical electrical stimulation in focal epilepsies. Clin Neurophysiol 2004;115:982&#x2013;989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandonnet E, Winkler PA, Duffau H. Direct electrical stimulation as an input gate into brain functional networks: principles, advantages and limitations. Acta Neurochirurgica 2010;152:185&#x2013;193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celix JM, Silbergeld DL. Intraoperative cortical mapping techniques and limitations. In: Byrne RW, ed. Functional mapping of the cerebral cortex: safe surgery in eloquent brain. Springer; 2016:63&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pouratian N, Cannestra AF, Bookheimer SY, Martin NA, Toga AW. Variability of intraoperative electrocortical stimulation mapping parameters across and within individuals. J Neurosurg 2004;101:458&#x2013;466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez JR, Ahn-Ewing J, Emerson R, et al. Guidelines for qualifications of neurodiagnostic personnel: a joint position statement of the American Clinical Neurophysiology Society, the American Association of Neuromuscular &amp; Electrodiagnostic Medicine, the American Society of Neurophysiological Monitoring, and ASET-the Neurodiagnostic Society. J Clin Neurophysiol 2023;40:271&#x2013;285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Care Financing A. Physician Supervision of Diagnostic Tests. DHHA HCFA program memorandum carriers. 2001;Transmittal B-01-28:April 18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AMA. Current procedural terminology (CPT). American Medical Association, Chicago, IL. 2021.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>