<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41390481</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2072-1315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>45</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of health, population, and nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Health Popul Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Determinants of healthcare access among women aged 15-49 years in tanzania: a population-based cross-sectional survey.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23</StartPage><MedlinePgn>23</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s41043-025-01188-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Globally, access to healthcare among women of reproductive age is among top most health agenda. In line with the endeavor, the government of Tanzania strive to ensure healthcare is accessible to every community member particularly women of reproductive age (15-49 years). However, there are limited scientific evidence on the proportion of women aged 15-49 who can access and the determinants of healthcare services in Tanzania. This study intended to fill the gap.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In this study, we analysed secondary information of a weighted sample 15,254 women aged 15-49 years collected using cross-sectional design during the 2022 Tanzania Demographic and Health Survey(TDHS). The binary dependent variable was healthcare access status and independent variables were women's social demographical characteristics. Descriptive analysis and multivariable modified Poisson regression analysis were performed. The p-value&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 at 95% was set to determine the significant determinant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The proportion of women with access to healthcare in Tanzania, stand at 50.2%. After controlling for other covariates, the modified Poisson regression showed that women with secondary and higher education level (Adjusted Prevalence Ratio (APR);1.21,95%CI:1.12,1.30), women who are covered by health insurance (APR;1.18,95%CI:1.11,1.26), belonging to richest households (APR;1.62,95%CI:1.45,1.80), residing in southern zone (APR;1.32,95%CI:1.22,1.42) and women living in union (APR;1.10,95%C:1.05,1.16); had higher prevalence ratio of healthcare access compared to their counter parts. "Conversely, negative determinants of healthcare access included being aged 35-49 years (APR; 0.92; 95% CI: 0.88, 0.97), living in households with 5-6 members, and residing in rural areas (APR; 0.78; 95% CI: 0.73, 0.83). These groups had a lower prevalence of healthcare access compared to their counterparts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Only half of Tanzanian women of reproductive age had adequate healthcare access. Its positive determinants included having secondary and above education level, being covered by health insurance, belonging to richest households, residing in southern and coast zones and living in union. Negative determinants included residing in rural, coming from poor households and having no formal education. As a motive toward universal health coverage in Tanzania, the government should design targeted health interventions focusing on poor women in rural areas with low levels of education to improve the healthcare access for all.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luoga</LastName><ForeName>Pankras</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Development Studies, School of Public Health and Social Sciences, Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences, Box 65001, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. luoga.pankras1@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kagaigai</LastName><ForeName>Alphoncina</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Development Studies, School of Public Health and Social Sciences, Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences, Box 65001, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anaeli</LastName><ForeName>Amani</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Development Studies, School of Public Health and Social Sciences, Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences, Box 65001, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tungu</LastName><ForeName>Malale</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Development Studies, School of Public Health and Social Sciences, Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences, Box 65001, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adam</LastName><ForeName>Jovinary</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Development Studies, School of Public Health and Social Sciences, Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences, Box 65001, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Osborne</LastName><ForeName>Augustus</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, School of Environmental Sciences, Njala University, PMB, Freetown, Sierra Leone.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Bangladesh</Country><MedlineTA>J Health Popul Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100959228</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1606-0997</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013636" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Tanzania</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006297" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Services Accessibility</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012959" MajorTopicYN="N">Socioeconomic Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012424" MajorTopicYN="N">Rural Population</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004522" MajorTopicYN="N">Educational Status</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006306" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Surveys</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DHS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthcare access</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reproductive age</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tanzania</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Women</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study used secondary data hence this study did not require another ethical clearance. Consent for publication: This manuscript does not contain any individual data so consent for publication is not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41390481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12821192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41043-025-01188-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s41043-025-01188-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baten A, Biswas RK, Kendal E, Bhowmik J. Utilization of maternal healthcare services in low &#x2013; and middle &#x2013; income countries: a systematic review and meta &#x2013; analysis. Syst Rev [Internet]. 2025; Available from: 10.1186/s13643-025-02832-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12004674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40241227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaddeus S, Maine D. Too far to walk: maternal mortality in context. Sm Sci Med Elsevier Sci Ltd. 1994;38(8):1091&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8042057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sylla B, Ismaila O, Diallo G25 Years of Digital Health Toward Universal Health Coverage in Low- and Middle-Income Countries: Rapid Systematic ReviewJ Med Internet Res 2025;27:e59042. 10.2196/59042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12163355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40440696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira N, Filha DS, Li J, Howard PAP, Quayyum Z, Kibuchi E et al. The economics of healthcare access: a scoping review on the economic impact of healthcare access for vulnerable urban populations in low &#x2013; and middle &#x2013; income countries. 2022;1&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9805259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36585704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terefe B, Workneh BS, Zeleke GA, Mekonen EG, Zegeye AF, Aemro A et al. Uncovering women&#x2019;s healthcare access challenges in low- and middle-income countries using mixed effects modelling approach: Insights for achieving the Sustainable Development Goals. PLoS One [Internet]. 2025;20(1):1&#x2013;21. Available from: 10.1371/journal.pone.0314309</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11737728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39820848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yihune Teshale M, Bante A, Gedefaw Belete A, Crutzen R, Spigt M, Stutterheim SE. Barriers and facilitators to maternal healthcare in East Africa: a systematic review and qualitative synthesis of perspectives from women, their families, healthcare providers, and key stakeholders. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth [Internet]. 2025;25(1). Available from: 10.1186/s12884-025-07225-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11792318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39901111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osborne A, James PB, Bangura C. Determinants of poor access to health care among women of reproductive age in Sierra Leone: a cross-sectional study. BMC Health Serv Res [Internet]. 2025;25(1). Available from: 10.1186/s12913-025-12363-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11800412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39910623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penchansky R, Thomas WJ. The Concept of Access: Denifition and Relationship to Consumer Satisfaction. Med Care [Internet]. 1981;XIX(2):127&#x2013;40. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7206846/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7206846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minyihun A, Tessema ZT. Determinants of access to health care among women in East African countries: a multilevel analysis of recent demographic and health surveys from 2008 to 2017. Risk Manag Healthc Policy. 2020;13:1803&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/RMHP.S263132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7533273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33061713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The United Republic of Tanzania. 2012 Population and Housing Census: Population Distribution by Administrative Areas. 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health (MoH) [Tanzania Mainland], Ministry of Health (MoH) [Zanzibar], National Bureau of Statistics (NBS), Office of the Chief Government Statistician (OCGS), and ICF. 2022. Tanzania Demographic and Health Survey and Malaria Indicator Survey. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croft TN, Allen CK, Zachary BW et al. 2023. Guide to DHS Statistics. Rockville, Maryland, USA: ICFCroft, Trevor N., Allen, Courtney K., Zachary, Blake W. 2023. Guide to DHS Statistics. Rockville, Maryland UI. Guide to DHS Statistics DHS-8. Demogr Heal Surv Progr. 20AD;7(version 2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anaeli A, Alphoncina K, Luoga P, Nyamhanga T, Tungu M. The role of health insurance on healthcare utilisation among women in Tanzania: insights from Tanzania demographic and health survey. Arch Public Health. 2025;83(176):1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12225034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40611298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luoga P, Mahiti GR, Kapinga O, Herzon B, Mwaisengela SM, Hokororo JC et al. Socioeconomic and geographical disparities in disability distribution among Tanzanian population: insights from the 2022 demographic and health survey and malaria indicator survey. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12257763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40660121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bintabara D, Nakamura K, Seino K. Improving access to healthcare for women in Tanzania by addressing socioeconomic determinants and health insurance: a population-based cross-sectional survey. BMJ Open. 2018;8(9):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2018-023013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6144413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30209158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamirat KS, Tessema ZT, Kebede FB. Factors associated with the perceived barriers of health care access among reproductive-age women in Ethiopia: a secondary data analysis of 2016 Ethiopian demographic and health survey. BMC Health Serv Res. 2020;20(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-020-05485-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7382096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32711517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maitanmi BT, Adelaja AA, Okunola DR, Maitanmi JO, Tola YO, Akingbade O. Association between socioeconomic status and the utilization of maternal health services in Nigeria. Iran J Nurs Midwifery Res. 2023;28(5):514&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijnmr.ijnmr_61_22</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10588924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37869684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaya S, Bishwajit G, Ekholuenetale M, Shah V. Awareness and utilization of community clinic services among women in rural areas in Bangladesh: a cross-sectional study. PLoS One. 2017;12(10):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0187303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5659786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29077754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowou RK, Atanuriba GA, Adzigbli LA, Balame SK, Tahidu I, Aggrey-Korsah J, et al. Determinants of health insurance coverage among women in Mauritania: a multilevel analysis. BMC Public Health. 2024;24(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-024-17691-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10797733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38243212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tungu M, Luoga P, Anaeli A, Nyamhanga T. Correlates associated with health insurance on cervical cancer screening in Tanzania: a comparison between the insured and uninsured women using demographic and health survey 2022. BMC Health Serv Res. 2024. 10.1186/s12913-024-11989-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-024-11989-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11607916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39614270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muremyi R, Haughton D, Niragire F, Kabano I. A cross-sectional analysis of the impact of health insurance on the use of health care in Rwanda. Heliyon. 2023;9(6):e17086. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e17086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e17086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10361221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37484315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merga BT, Raru TB, Deressa A, Regassa LD, Gamachu M, Negash B, et al. The effect of health insurance coverage on antenatal care utilizations in Ethiopia: evidence from national survey. Frontiers in Health Services. 2023;3:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frhs.2023.1101164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10587574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37869683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahiti GR, Adam J, Luoga P. Prevalence and determinants of cervical cancer screening among women aged 15&#x2013;49 years in Tanzania: analysis of demographic and health survey 2022. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12100887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40410900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konje ET, Tito M, Magoma N, Hatfield J, Kuhn S, Sauve RS, et al. Missed opportunities in antenatal care for improving the health of pregnant women and newborns in Geita district, Northwest Tanzania. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2018;18(1):1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-018-2014-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6173847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30290769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowes S. Matrilineal Kinship and Spousal Cooperation: Evidence from the Matrilineal Belt *. 2019;(December).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kongela SM. This document is discoverable and free to researchers across the Globe due to the work of agecon Search. Help ensure our sustainability. Gender equality in ownership of agricultural land in rural Tanzania. Does Matrilineal Tenure System Matter ?; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musa A, Chojenta C, Geleto A, Loxton D. The associations between intimate partner violence and maternal health care service utilization: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Womens Health. 2019;19(1):1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-019-0735-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6390526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30808353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozawa S, Grewal S, Bridges JFP. Household size and the decision to purchase health insurance in cambodia: results of a discrete-choice experiment with scale adjustment. Appl Health Econ Health Policy. 2016;14(2):195&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40258-016-0222-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4791455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26860280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapologwe NA, Marwa B, Marwa H, Kebby A, Kengia JT, Ruhago G. From pilot to national roll-out of the improved Community Health Fund (iCHF) in Tanzania: lessons learnt and way forward. 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11556162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39533367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Embrey M, Mbwasi R, Shekalaghe E, Liana J, Kimatta S, Ignace G, et al. National Health Insurance Fund &#x2019; s relationship to retail drug outlets&#x202f;: a Tanzania case study. J Pharm Policy Pract. 2021(1). 10.1186/s40545-021-00303-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7888141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33593420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saurman E. Improving access: modifying Penchansky and Thomas &#x2019; s Theory of Access. 2015;0(0):1&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26377728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>