<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41502624</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>48</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Phytochemical Profiling, Molecular Docking, ADMET Analysis of <i>Zingiber Officinale</i> Peel Extract for the Biogenic Synthesis of ZnO and Fe-Doped ZnO Nanoparticles with Antibacterial and Photocatalytic Potential.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>59849</StartPage><EndPage>59871</EndPage><MedlinePgn>59849-59871</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.5c09902</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Industrial dye effluents are the predominant source of water pollution, while the increasing prevalence of bacterial infections poses a serious public health threat. Nanoparticles offer promising avenues for addressing these challenges. Therefore, this study sought to synthesize ZnO (ZNP) and Fe-doped ZnO (F-ZNP) nanoparticles using <i>Zingiber officinale</i> peel extract and investigate their antimicrobial and photocatalytic potential, along with molecular insights into the antibacterial activity of phytochemicals through in silico studies. Phytochemical profiling of the <i>Z. officinale</i> peel extract was performed using gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC-MS). The physicochemical characteristics of the biogenic ZNP and F-ZNP were analyzed using X-ray diffraction (XRD), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), UV-visible (UV-vis) spectroscopy, and thermogravimetric and differential thermal (TG/DT) analyses. <i>In silico</i> analysis of phytochemicals was performed to assess their interactions with bacterial proteins (GyrB and FabH) and to predict their pharmacokinetic properties. XRD analysis confirmed the hexagonal wurtzite structure with a mean crystallite size of 31.92 nm for ZNP and 23.49 nm for F-ZNP. SEM micrographs revealed a flake-like morphology with an average particle size of 47 and 35 nm for ZNP and F-ZNP, respectively. UV-vis spectroscopy revealed absorption edges at 363 and 369 nm, with corresponding band gaps of 3.15 and 3.10 eV for ZNP and F-ZNP, respectively. TG/DT thermographs demonstrated excellent thermal stability, with minimal weight loss of only 2.70% for ZNP and 5.21% for F-ZNP up to 800 &#xb0;C. The dynamic light scattering technique revealed hydrodynamic diameters of &#x223c;433 nm (ZNP) and &#x223c;422 nm (F-ZNP) with minor aggregation. Zeta potentials of +7.27 mV (ZNP) and +17.44 mV (F-ZNP) indicated low and improved colloidal stability, respectively, demonstrating enhanced dispersibility upon Fe doping. The biogenic ZNP exhibited a moderate methylene blue degradation rate of 56.24%, while F-ZNP resulted in an outstanding photocatalytic degradation rate of 91.39% within 120 min. Moreover, F-ZNP demonstrated excellent photocatalytic reusability, maintaining a high performance (&#x223c;78%) even after three cycles. The biogenic ZNP and F-ZNP exhibited substantial antibacterial activity against both Gram-positive and Gram-negative bacterial strains, showing a zone of inhibition of 10 to 16 mm. These results were corroborated by favorable binding affinity with bacterial proteins -7.2 to -5.0 kcal/mol), and the bioactive molecules were safe based on ADMET analysis. Moreover, both ZNP and F-ZNP exhibited excellent biocompatibility with hemolysis percentages remaining below 2% across all tested concentrations (25-400 &#x3bc;g/mL). Notably, F-ZNP demonstrated slightly enhanced hemocompatibility compared to ZNP. Therefore, our findings suggest a facile and sustainable route to synthesize ZNP and F-ZNP using the ginger peel extract, focusing on their safe application in antibacterial therapy and wastewater treatment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Molla</LastName><ForeName>Anik</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-5488-905X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Glass &amp; Ceramic Engineering, Rajshahi University of Engineering &amp; Technology, Rajshahi 6204, Bangladesh.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">166216</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akhter</LastName><ForeName>Hajara</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5046-7635</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Industrial Microbiology Research Division, BCSIR Chattogram Laboratories, Bangladesh Council of Scientific and Industrial Research (BCSIR), Chattogram 4220, Bangladesh.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">130051</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical and Toxicological Research Institute (BTRI), Bangladesh Council of Scientific and Industrial Research (BCSIR), Dhaka 1205, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rafi</LastName><ForeName>Ehasanul Islam</ForeName><Initials>EI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-0096-4291</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Industrial and Production Engineering, Bangladesh University of Engineering &amp; Technology, Dhaka 1000, Bangladesh.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">61750</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Islam</LastName><ForeName>Ariful</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4599-0111</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Professor Joarder DNA and Chromosome Research Laboratory, Department of Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology, University of Rajshahi, Rajshahi 6205, Bangladesh.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">118869</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lipy</LastName><ForeName>Evena Parvin</ForeName><Initials>EP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical and Toxicological Research Institute (BTRI), Bangladesh Council of Scientific and Industrial Research (BCSIR), Dhaka 1205, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miah</LastName><ForeName>Md Abdus Satter</ForeName><Initials>MAS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical and Toxicological Research Institute (BTRI), Bangladesh Council of Scientific and Industrial Research (BCSIR), Dhaka 1205, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Islam</LastName><ForeName>Saiful</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Industrial Microbiology Research Division, BCSIR Chattogram Laboratories, Bangladesh Council of Scientific and Industrial Research (BCSIR), Chattogram 4220, Bangladesh.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">130051</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41502624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12772413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c09902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dihom H. R., Al-Shaibani M. M., Mohamed R. M. S. R., Al-Gheethi A. A., Sharma A., Khamidun M. H. B.. Photocatalytic Degradation of Disperse Azo Dyes in Textile Wastewater Using Green Zinc Oxide Nanoparticles Synthesized in Plant Extract: A Critical Review. J. Water Process Eng. 2022;47:102705. doi: 10.1016/j.jwpe.2022.102705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jwpe.2022.102705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Khawaga A. M., Elsayed M. A., Gobara M., Suliman A. A., Hashem A. H., Zaher A. A., Mohsen M., Salem S. S.. Green Synthesized ZnO Nanoparticles by Saccharomyces Cerevisiae and Their Antibacterial Activity and Photocatalytic Degradation. Biomass Convers. Biorefinery. 2025;15(2):2673&#x2013;2684. doi: 10.1007/s13399-023-04827-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13399-023-04827-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalayc&#x131;o&#x11f;lu Z., &#xd6;zu&#x11f;ur Uysal B., PekcanErim O. F. B., Erim F. B.. Efficient Photocatalytic Degradation of Methylene Blue Dye from Aqueous Solution with Cerium Oxide Nanoparticles and Graphene Oxide-Doped Polyacrylamide. ACS Omega. 2023;8(14):13004&#x2013;13015. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.3c00198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c00198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10099124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37065069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Q., Li Y., He W., Chen T., Liu N., Ma L., Qiu Z., Shang Z., Wang Z.. A Polyene Macrolide Targeting Phospholipids in the Fungal Cell Membrane. Nature. 2025;640:743&#x2013;751. doi: 10.1038/s41586-025-08678-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-025-08678-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12003179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40108452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhter H., Ritu S. S., Siddique S., Chowdhury F., Chowdhury R. T., Akhter S., Hakim M.. In Silico Molecular Docking and ADMET Prediction of Biogenic Zinc Oxide Nanoparticles: Characterization, and in Vitro Antimicrobial and Photocatalytic Activity. RSC Adv. 2024;14(49):36209&#x2013;36225. doi: 10.1039/D4RA06890D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D4RA06890D</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11555492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39534048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitra P., Dutta D., Das S., Basu T., Pramanik A., Patra A.. Antibacterial and Photocatalytic Properties of ZnO-9-Aminoacridine Hydrochloride Hydrate Drug Nanoconjugates. ACS Omega. 2018;3(7):7962&#x2013;7970. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.8b00568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.8b00568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6072247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30087929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoudho K. N., Uddin S., Rumon M. M. H., Shakil M. S.. Influence of Physicochemical Properties of Iron Oxide Nanoparticles on Their Antibacterial Activity. ACS Omega. 2024;9(31):33303&#x2013;33334. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.4c02822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.4c02822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11308002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39130596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbadawy H. A., Elhusseiny A. F., Hussein S. M., Sadik W. A.. Sustainable and Energy-Efficient Photocatalytic Degradation of Textile Dye Assisted by Ecofriendly Synthesized Silver Nanoparticles. Sci. Rep. 2023;13(1):2302. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-29507-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-29507-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9911601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36759696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ta Q. T. H., Cho E., Sreedhar A., Noh J.-S.. Mixed-Dimensional, Three-Level Hierarchical Nanostructures of Silver and Zinc Oxide for Fast Photocatalytic Degradation of Multiple Dyes. J. Catal. 2019;371:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.jcat.2019.01.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcat.2019.01.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis D. V., Jayakumar M. N., Ahmad H., Gokhale T.. Antimicrobial Activity of Biogenic Metal Oxide Nanoparticles and Their Synergistic Effect on Clinical Pathogens. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2023;24(12):9998. doi: 10.3390/ijms24129998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms24129998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10298676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37373146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang M., Chen J.-H., Xu X.-L., Yang P.-H., Hildebrand H. F.. Antibacterial Activities of Inorganic Agents on Six Bacteria Associated with Oral Infections by Two Susceptibility Tests. Int. J. Antimicrob. Agents. 2006;27(6):513&#x2013;517. doi: 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2006.01.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2006.01.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16713190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautam S., Agrawal H., Thakur M., Akbari A., Sharda H., Kaur R., Amini M.. Metal Oxides and Metal Organic Frameworks for the Photocatalytic Degradation: A Review. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2020;8(3):103726. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2020.103726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2020.103726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong C. B., Ng L. Y., Mohammad A. W.. A Review of ZnO Nanoparticles as Solar Photocatalysts: Synthesis, Mechanisms and Applications. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2018;81:536&#x2013;551. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2017.08.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2017.08.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Rawashdeh N. A. F., Allabadi O., Aljarrah M. T.. Photocatalytic Activity of Graphene Oxide/Zinc Oxide Nanocomposites with Embedded Metal Nanoparticles for the Degradation of Organic Dyes. ACS Omega. 2020;5(43):28046&#x2013;28055. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.0c03608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.0c03608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7643185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33163787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amrute V., Supin K. K., Supin K. K., Vasundhara M., Chanda A.. Observation of Excellent Photocatalytic and Antibacterial Activity of Ag Doped ZnO Nanoparticles. RSC Adv. 2024;14(45):32786&#x2013;32801. doi: 10.1039/d4ra05197a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d4ra05197a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11483781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39429934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oprea O., Andronescu E., Ficai D., Ficai A., Oktar F., Yetmez M.. ZnO Applications and Challenges. Curr. Org. Chem. 2014;18(2):192&#x2013;203. doi: 10.2174/13852728113176660143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/13852728113176660143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam F., Shohag S., Uddin M. J., Islam M. R., Nafady M. H., Akter A., Mitra S., Roy A., Emran T. B., Cavalu S.. Exploring the Journey of Zinc Oxide Nanoparticles (ZnO-NPs) toward Biomedical Applications. Materials. 2022;15(6):2160. doi: 10.3390/ma15062160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15062160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8951444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35329610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J., Huang Y., Zhu S., Abbes N., Jing X., Zhang L.. A Review of the Green Synthesis of ZnO Nanoparticles Using Plant Extracts and Their Prospects for Application in Antibacterial Textiles. J. Eng. Fiber. Fabr. 2021;16:15589250211046242. doi: 10.1177/15589250211046242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15589250211046242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gnanamozhi P., Monamary A., Jereil S. D., Pauline J. E., Ratnam J. A. O., Ganeshkumar A., Pandiyan V., Alothman A. A., Alshgari R. A., Govindasamy M.. Effective Photocatalytic Degradation of Methylene Blue (MB) and Reactive Red 120 (RR120) Using Al Substituted ZnO Nanoparticles. Surf. Interfaces. 2023;41:103203. doi: 10.1016/j.surfin.2023.103203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surfin.2023.103203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muktaridha O., Adlim M., Suhendrayatna S., Ismail I.. Progress of 3d Metal-Doped Zinc Oxide Nanoparticles and the Photocatalytic Properties. Arab. J. Chem. 2021;14(6):103175. doi: 10.1016/j.arabjc.2021.103175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arabjc.2021.103175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chai H.-Y., Lam S.-M., Sin J.-C.. Green Synthesis of Magnetic Fe-Doped ZnO Nanoparticles via Hibiscus Rosa-Sinensis Leaf Extracts for Boosted Photocatalytic, Antibacterial and Antifungal Activities. Mater. Lett. 2019;242:103&#x2013;106. doi: 10.1016/j.matlet.2019.01.116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matlet.2019.01.116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh P., Kumar R., Singh R. K.. Progress on Transition Metal-Doped ZnO Nanoparticles and Its Application. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2019;58(37):17130&#x2013;17163. doi: 10.1021/acs.iecr.9b01561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.iecr.9b01561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddahi P., Shahtahmasebi N., Kompany A., Mashreghi M., Safaee S., Roozban F.. Effect of Doping on Structural and Optical Properties of ZnO Nanoparticles: Study of Antibacterial Properties. Mater. Sci. 2014;32:130&#x2013;135. doi: 10.2478/s13536-013-0181-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/s13536-013-0181-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandhi V., Ganesan R., Abdulrahman Syedahamed H. H., Thaiyan M.. Effect of Cobalt Doping on Structural, Optical, and Magnetic Properties of ZnO Nanoparticles Synthesized by Coprecipitation Method. J. Phys. Chem. C. 2014;118(18):9715&#x2013;9725. doi: 10.1021/jp411848t.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp411848t</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying S., Guan Z., Ofoegbu P. C., Clubb P., Rico C., He F., Hong J.. Green Synthesis of Nanoparticles: Current Developments and Limitations. Environ. Technol. Innov. 2022;26:102336. doi: 10.1016/j.eti.2022.102336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eti.2022.102336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuel M. S., Ravikumar M., John J A., Selvarajan E., Patel H., Chander P. S., Soundarya J., Vuppala S., Balaji R., Chandrasekar N.. A Review on Green Synthesis of Nanoparticles and Their Diverse Biomedical and Environmental Applications. Catalysts. 2022;12(5):459. doi: 10.3390/catal12050459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/catal12050459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayaram S., Razafindralambo H., Sun Y.-Z., Vasantharaj S., Ghafarifarsani H., Hoseinifar S. H., Raeeszadeh M.. Applications of Green Synthesized Metal Nanoparticles a Review. Biol. Trace Elem. Res. 2024;202(1):360&#x2013;386. doi: 10.1007/s12011-023-03645-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12011-023-03645-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10097525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37046039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alharbi N. S., Alsubhi N. S., Felimban A. I.. Green Synthesis of Silver Nanoparticles Using Medicinal Plants: Characterization and Application. J. Radiat. Res. Appl. Sci. 2022;15(3):109&#x2013;124. doi: 10.1016/j.jrras.2022.06.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jrras.2022.06.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M., Ikram M., Ijaz M., Ul-Hamid A., Avais M., Anjum A. A.. Green Synthesis and Evaluation of N-Type ZnO Nanoparticles Doped with Plant Extract for Use as Alternative Antibacterials. Appl. Nanosci. 2020;10:3787&#x2013;3803. doi: 10.1007/s13204-020-01451-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13204-020-01451-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav A., Kumar H., Kumar P., Rani G., Maken S.. Syzygium Cumini Leaf Extract Mediated Green Synthesis of ZnO Nanoparticles: A Sustained Release for Anticancer, Antimicrobial, Antioxidant, and Anti-Corrosive Applications. J. Mol. Struct. 2025;1325:141017. doi: 10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.141017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.141017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yizengaw D. E., Godie E. M., Manayia A. H.. Green Synthesis and Characterization of ZnO Nanoparticles Using Justicia Schemperiana Leaf Extract and Its Antibacterial and Antioxidant Activity. Inorg. Chem. Commun. 2025;174:114071. doi: 10.1016/j.inoche.2025.114071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inoche.2025.114071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haque M. J., Bellah M. M., Hassan M. R., Rahman S.. Synthesis of ZnO Nanoparticles by Two Different Methods &amp; Comparison of Their Structural, Antibacterial, Photocatalytic and Optical Properties. Nano Express. 2020;1(1):010007. doi: 10.1088/2632-959X/ab7a43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2632-959X/ab7a43</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasiljevic Z., Vunduk J., Bartolic D., Miskovic G., Ognjanovic M., Tadic N. B., Nikolic M. V.. An Eco-Friendly Approach to ZnO NP Synthesis Using Citrus Reticulata Blanco Peel/Extract: Characterization and Antibacterial and Photocatalytic Activity. ACS Appl. Bio Mater. 2024;7(5):3014&#x2013;3032. doi: 10.1021/acsabm.4c00079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsabm.4c00079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38597359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirubakaran D., Wahid J. B. A., Karmegam N., Jeevika R., Sellapillai L., Rajkumar M., SenthilKumar K. J.. A Comprehensive Review on the Green Synthesis of Nanoparticles: Advancements in Biomedical and Environmental Applications. Biomed. Mater. Devices. 2025;4:388&#x2013;413. doi: 10.1007/s44174-025-00295-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44174-025-00295-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman M. A., Hossain M. S., Hossain M. T., Ahmed S.. Morphological Effect of Green and Chemically Synthesized Nano-ZnO for Evaluation of Antimicrobial and Photo-Catalytic Activity. J. Mol. Struct. 2025;1334:141822. doi: 10.1016/j.molstruc.2025.141822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molstruc.2025.141822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayustaningwarno F., Anjani G., Ayu A. M., Fogliano V.. A Critical Review of Ginger&#x2019;s (Zingiber Officinale) Antioxidant, Anti-Inflammatory, and Immunomodulatory Activities. Front. Nutr. 2024;11(June):1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2024.1364836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2024.1364836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11187345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38903613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Radadi N. S., Faisal S., Alotaibi A., Ullah R., Hussain T., Rizwan M., Zaman N., Iqbal M., Iqbal A., Ali Z.. Zingiber Officinale Driven Bioproduction of ZnO Nanoparticles and Their Anti-Inflammatory, Anti-Diabetic, Anti-Alzheimer, Anti-Oxidant, and Anti-Microbial Applications. Inorg. Chem. Commun. 2022;140:109274. doi: 10.1016/j.inoche.2022.109274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inoche.2022.109274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebede Urge S., Tiruneh Dibaba S., Belay Gemta A.. Green Synthesis Method of ZnO Nanoparticles Using Extracts of Zingiber Officinale and Garlic Bulb (Allium Sativum) and Their Synergetic Effect for Antibacterial Activities. J. Nanomater. 2023;2023(1):1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1155/2023/7036247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/7036247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takele E., Feyisa Bogale R., Shumi G., Kenasa G.. Green Synthesis, Characterization, and Antibacterial Activity of CuO/ZnO Nanocomposite Using Zingiber Officinale Rhizome Extract. J. Chem. 2023;2023(1):1&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1155/2023/3481389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/3481389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhaddad R., Abualsoud B. M., Al-Deeb I., Nsairat H.. Green Synthesized Zingiber Officinale-ZnO Nanoparticles: Anticancer Efficacy against 3D Breast Cancer Model. Futur. Sci. OA. 2024;10(1):2419806. doi: 10.1080/20565623.2024.2419806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/20565623.2024.2419806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11572278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39539163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullah, Hussain T., Faisal S., Rizwan M., Almostafa M. M., Younis N. S., Yahya G.. Zingiber Officinale Rhizome Extracts Mediated Ni Nanoparticles and Its Promising Biomedical and Environmental Applications. BMC Complement. Med. Ther. 2023;23(1):349. doi: 10.1186/s12906-023-04182-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12906-023-04182-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10546789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37789322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MuthuKathija M., Badhusha M. S. M., Rama V.. Green Synthesis of Zinc Oxide Nanoparticles Using Pisonia Alba Leaf Extract and Its Antibacterial Activity. Appl. Surf. Sci. Adv. 2023;15:100400. doi: 10.1016/j.apsadv.2023.100400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsadv.2023.100400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faisal S., Jan H., Shah S. A., Shah S., Khan A., Akbar M. T., Rizwan M., Jan F., Wajidullah, Akhtar N., Khattak A., Syed S.. Green Synthesis of Zinc Oxide (ZnO) Nanoparticles Using Aqueous Fruit Extracts of Myristica Fragrans: Their Characterizations and Biological and Environmental Applications. ACS Omega. 2021;6(14):9709&#x2013;9722. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.1c00310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.1c00310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8047667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33869951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mie R., Samsudin M. W., Din L. B., Ahmad A., Ibrahim N., Adnan S. N. A.. Synthesis of Silver Nanoparticles with Antibacterial Activity Using the Lichen Parmotrema Praesorediosum. Int. J. Nanomed. 2013:121&#x2013;127. doi: 10.2147/IJN.S52306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJN.S52306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3872223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24379670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiranmayee M., Rajesh N., Vidya Vani M., Khadri H., Mohammed A., Chinni S. V., Ramachawolran G., Riazunnisa K., Moussa A. Y.. Green Synthesis of Piper Nigrum Copper-Based Nanoparticles: In Silico Study and ADMET Analysis to Assess Their Antioxidant, Antibacterial, and Cytotoxic Effects. Front. Chem. 2023;11:1218588. doi: 10.3389/fchem.2023.1218588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fchem.2023.1218588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10509375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37736256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ongtanasup T., Kamdenlek P., Manaspon C., Eawsakul K.. Green-Synthesized Silver Nanoparticles from Zingiber Officinale Extract: Antioxidant Potential, Biocompatibility, Anti-LOX Properties, and in Silico Analysis. BMC Complement. Med. Ther. 2024;24(1):84. doi: 10.1186/s12906-024-04381-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12906-024-04381-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10863109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38350963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullahi A., Khairulmazmi A., Yasmeen S., Ismail I. S., Norhayu A., Sulaiman M. R., Ahmed O. H., Ismail M. R.. Phytochemical Profiling and Antimicrobial Activity of Ginger (Zingiber Officinale) Essential Oils against Important Phytopathogens. Arab. J. Chem. 2020;13(11):8012&#x2013;8025. doi: 10.1016/j.arabjc.2020.09.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arabjc.2020.09.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S., Zhang L., Yu M., Luo D., Chen S., Liu W., Zhang Y., Zhang L., Zhao T.. Essential Oils of Zingiber Officinale: Chemical Composition, in Vivo Alleviation Effects on TPA Induced Ear Swelling in Mice and in Vitro Bioactivities. Front. Nutr. 2022;9:1043175. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2022.1043175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2022.1043175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9639606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36352904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiki Y. L., Tolesa L. D., Tiwikrama A. H., Chala T. F.. Ginger (Zingiber Officinale)-Mediated Green Synthesis of Silver-Doped Tin Oxide Nanoparticles and Evaluation of Its Antimicrobial Activity. ACS omega. 2024;9(10):11443&#x2013;11452. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.3c07855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c07855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10938312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38496979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuadra J. G., Scalschi L., Vicedo B., Guc M., Izquierdo-Roca V., Porcar S., Fraga D., Carda J. B.. ZnO/Ag Nanocomposites with Enhanced Antimicrobial Activity. Appl. Sci. 2022;12(10):5023. doi: 10.3390/app12105023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app12105023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roguai S., Djelloul A. S.. Microstructural and Photocatalytic Degradation of Methylene Blue of Zinc Oxide and Fe-Doped ZnO Nanoparticles Prepared by Simple Coprecipitation Method. Solid State Commun. 2021;334&#x2013;335:114362. doi: 10.1016/J.SSC.2021.114362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.SSC.2021.114362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleem S., Jameel M. H., Akhtar N., Nazir N., Ali A., Zaman A., Rehman A., Butt S., Sultana F., Mushtaq M., Zeng J. H., Amami M., Althubeiti K.. Modification in Structural, Optical, Morphological, and Electrical Properties of Zinc Oxide (ZnO) Nanoparticles (NPs) by Metal (Ni, Co) Dopants for Electronic Device Applications. Arab. J. Chem. 2022;15(1):103518. doi: 10.1016/j.arabjc.2021.103518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arabjc.2021.103518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam M. A., Ahmed S., Bishwas R. K., Mostofa S., Jahan S. A.. X-Ray Crystallographic Diffraction Study by Whole Powder Pattern Fitting (WPPF) Method: Refinement of Crystalline Nanostructure Polymorphs TiO2. South African J. Chem. Eng. 2025;51(January):68&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1016/j.sajce.2024.10.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sajce.2024.10.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chauhan A., Verma R., Kumari S., Sharma A., Shandilya P., Li X., Batoo K. M., Imran A., Kulshrestha S., Kumar R.. Photocatalytic Dye Degradation and Antimicrobial Activities of Pure and Ag-Doped ZnO Using Cannabis Sativa Leaf Extract. Sci. Rep. 2020;10(1):1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-64419-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-64419-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7217889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliannezhadi M., Mirsanaee S. Z., Jamali M., Shariatmadar Tehrani F.. The Physical Properties and Photocatalytic Activities of Green Synthesized ZnO Nanostructures Using Different Ginger Extract Concentrations. Sci. Rep. 2024;14(1):1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-52455-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-52455-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10807023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38263199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Algarni T. S., Abduh N. A. Y., Aouissi A., Al Kahtani A.. Photodegradation of Methyl Orange under Solar Irradiation on Fe-Doped ZnO Nanoparticles Synthesized Using Wild Olive Leaf Extract. Green Process. Synth. 2022;11(1):895&#x2013;906. doi: 10.1515/gps-2022-0077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/gps-2022-0077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahai A., Kumar Y., Agarwal V., Olive-M&#xe9;ndez S. F., Goswami N.. Doping Concentration Driven Morphological Evolution of Fe Doped ZnO Nanostructures. J. Appl. Phys. 2014;116(16):164315. doi: 10.1063/1.4900721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.4900721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan M. M., Khan W., Azam A., Naqvi A. H.. Effect of Size Reduction on Structural and Optical Properties of ZnO Matrix Due to Successive Doping of Fe Ions. J. Lumin. 2014;145:160&#x2013;166. doi: 10.1016/j.jlumin.2013.06.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jlumin.2013.06.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezazadeh N. H., Buazar F., Matroodi S.. Synergistic Effects of Combinatorial Chitosan and Polyphenol Biomolecules on Enhanced Antibacterial Activity of Biofunctionalaized Silver Nanoparticles. Sci. Rep. 2020;10(1):1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-76726-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-76726-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7665213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33184403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbar Jan F., Wajidullah, Ullah R., Ullah N., Salman, Usman M.. Exploring the Environmental and Potential Therapeutic Applications of Myrtus Communis L. Assisted Synthesized Zinc Oxide (ZnO) and Iron Doped Zinc Oxide (Fe-ZnO) Nanoparticles. J. Saudi Chem. Soc. 2021;25(7):101278. doi: 10.1016/j.jscs.2021.101278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jscs.2021.101278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagadevan S., Vennila S., Lett J. A., Marlinda A. R., Hamizi N. A. B., Johan M. R.. Tailoring the Structural, Morphological, Optical, Thermal and Dielectric Characteristics of ZnO Nanoparticles Using Starch as a Capping Agent. Results Phys. 2019;15(July):102543. doi: 10.1016/j.rinp.2019.102543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rinp.2019.102543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldeen T. S., Ahmed Mohamed H. E., Maaza M.. ZnO Nanoparticles Prepared via a Green Synthesis Approach: Physical Properties, Photocatalytic and Antibacterial Activity. J. Phys. Chem. Solids. 2022;160:110313. doi: 10.1016/j.jpcs.2021.110313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpcs.2021.110313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabbi M. A., Akter R., Khatun M. H., Ahmed F., Kadri H. J., Maitra B., Uddin Rasel M. Z., Al-Amin M., Kabir S. R., Habib M. R.. Extraction of Wood Vinegar from Bagasse and Its Application as Bio-Reducer to Produce Stable Silver Nanoparticles with Enhanced Antibacterial Activity. Heliyon. 2024;10(24):e40976. doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e40976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e40976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11667609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39720026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan Z. H., Zhang L. D. S.. Synthesis, characterization and photocatalytic activity of ZnFe2O4/TiO2 nanocomposite. J. Mater. Chem. 2001;11(4):1265&#x2013;1268. doi: 10.1039/b006994i.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/b006994i</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjithkumar B., Ranjith Kumar E., Ramalingam H. B., Rahale C. S., Mahmoud M. H. H., Binyaseen A. M., Keshk A. A., El-Metwaly N. M.. Bio-Ingredients Assisted Synthesis of Fe Doped Zinc Oxide Nanostructures: Study on Structural, Optical, Morphological and Thermal Properties. Ceram. Int. 2021;47(24):35378&#x2013;35383. doi: 10.1016/j.ceramint.2021.08.321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2021.08.321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddique M. N., Ali T., Ahmed A., Tripathi P.. Enhanced Electrical and Thermal Properties of Pure and Ni Substituted ZnO Nanoparticles. Nano-Struct. Nano-Objects. 2018;16:156&#x2013;166. doi: 10.1016/j.nanoso.2018.06.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoso.2018.06.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S., Mukherjee S., Kr Singh R., Chatterjee S., Ghosh A. K.. Structural and Optical Properties of Sol-Gel Derived Nanocrystalline Fe-Doped ZnO. J. Appl. Phys. 2011;110(10):103508. doi: 10.1063/1.3658221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.3658221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Gattorno G., Santiago-Jacinto P., Rendon-V&#xe1;zquez L., N&#xe9;meth J., D&#xe9;k&#xe1;ny I., D&#xed;az D.. Novel Synthesis Pathway of ZnO Nanoparticles from the Spontaneous Hydrolysis of Zinc Carboxylate Salts. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2003;107(46):12597&#x2013;12604. doi: 10.1021/jp035788x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp035788x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldalbahi A., Alterary S., Ali Abdullrahman Almoghim R., Awad M. A., Aldosari N. S., Fahad Alghannam S., Nasser Alabdan A., Alharbi S., Ali Mohammed Alateeq B., Abdulrahman Al Mohsen A., Alkathiri M. A., Abdulrahman Alrashed R.. Greener Synthesis of Zinc Oxide Nanoparticles: Characterization and Multifaceted Applications. Molecules. 2020;25(18):4198. doi: 10.3390/molecules25184198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules25184198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7571220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32937751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohd Yusof H., Abdul Rahman N. A., Mohamad R., Zaidan U. H., Samsudin A. A.. Biosynthesis of Zinc Oxide Nanoparticles by Cell-Biomass and Supernatant of Lactobacillus Plantarum TA4 and Its Antibacterial and Biocompatibility Properties. Sci. Rep. 2020;10(1):1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-76402-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-76402-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7673015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33204003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammed A., Asere T. G., Diriba T. F.. Photocatalytic and Antimicrobial Properties of ZnO and Mg-Doped ZnO Nanoparticles Synthesized Using Lupinus Albus Leaf Extract. ACS Omega. 2024;9(2):2480&#x2013;2490. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.3c07093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c07093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10795139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38250416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancuso A., Sacco O., Mottola S., Pragliola S., Moretta A., Vaiano V., De Marco I.. Synthesis of Fe-Doped ZnO by Supercritical Antisolvent Precipitation for the Degradation of Azo Dyes under Visible Light. Inorg. Chim. Acta. 2023;549(January):121407. doi: 10.1016/j.ica.2023.121407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ica.2023.121407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Zhong Q., Guo W., Zhang W., Ya Y., Xia Y.. Novel Platycladus Orientalis&#x2013;Shaped Fe-Doped ZnO Hierarchical Nanoflower Decorated with Ag Nanoparticles for Photocatalytic Application. J. Alloys Compd. 2021;880:160501. doi: 10.1016/j.jallcom.2021.160501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2021.160501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadeem M. S., Munawar T., Mukhtar F., Naveed ur Rahman M., Riaz M., Iqbal F.. Enhancement in the Photocatalytic and Antimicrobial Properties of ZnO Nanoparticles by Structural Variations and Energy Bandgap Tuning through Fe and Co Co-Doping. Ceram. Int. 2021;47(8):11109&#x2013;11121. doi: 10.1016/j.ceramint.2020.12.234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2020.12.234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bawazeer T. M., Alsoufi M. S., Shkir M., Al-Shehri B. M., Hamdy M. S.. Excellent Improvement in Photocatalytic Nature of ZnO Nanoparticles via Fe Doping Content. Inorg. Chem. Commun. 2021;130:108668. doi: 10.1016/j.inoche.2021.108668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inoche.2021.108668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karthik K. V., Raghu A. V., Reddy K. R., Ravishankar R., Sangeeta M., Shetti N. P., Reddy C. V.. Green Synthesis of Cu-Doped ZnO Nanoparticles and Its Application for the Photocatalytic Degradation of Hazardous Organic Pollutants. Chemosphere. 2022;287(P2):132081. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2021.132081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2021.132081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34500333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradeev raj K., Sadaiyandi K., Kennedy A., Sagadevan S., Chowdhury Z. Z., Johan M. R. B., Aziz F. A., Rafique R. F., Thamiz Selvi R., Rathina bala R.. Influence of Mg Doping on ZnO Nanoparticles for Enhanced Photocatalytic Evaluation and Antibacterial Analysis. Nanoscale Res. Lett. 2018;13:229. doi: 10.1186/s11671-018-2643-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s11671-018-2643-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6081874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30076473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Moyeen A., Mahmud R. M., Mazumder D. D., Ghosh S., Datta O., Molla A., Begum M. E.. Investigation of Structural, Optical, Antibacterial, and Dielectric Properties of Sol-Gel and Biosynthesized TiO2 Nanoparticles. Heliyon. 2024;10:e40776. doi: 10.1186/s11671-018-2643-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s11671-018-2643-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11665395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39717598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasiljevic Z. Z., Dojcinovic M. P., Vujancevic J. D., Jankovic-Castvan I., Ognjanovic M., Tadic N. B., Stojadinovic S., Brankovic G. O., Nikolic M. V.. Photocatalytic Degradation of Methylene Blue under Natural Sunlight Using Iron Titanate Nanoparticles Prepared by a Modified Sol-Gel Method: Methylene Blue Degradation with Fe2TiO5. Roy. Soc. Open Sci. 2020;7(9):200708. doi: 10.1098/rsos.200708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rsos.200708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7540765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33047033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radha B., Rathi R., Lalithambika K. C., Thayumanavan A., Ravichandran K., Sriram S.. Effect of Fe Doping on the Photocatalytic Activity of ZnO Nanoparticles: Experimental and Theoretical Investigations. J. Mater. Sci. Mater. Electron. 2018;29(16):13474&#x2013;13482. doi: 10.1007/s10854-018-9472-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10854-018-9472-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zong Y., Li Z., Wang X., Ma J., Men Y.. Synthesis and High Photocatalytic Activity of Eu-Doped ZnO Nanoparticles. Ceram. Int. 2014;40(7):10375&#x2013;10382. doi: 10.1016/j.ceramint.2014.02.123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2014.02.123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendes C. R., Dilarri G., Forsan C. F., Sapata V., Lopes P. R. M., de Moraes P. B., Montagnolli R. N., Ferreira H., Bidoia E. D., Bidoia E. D.. Antibacterial Action and Target Mechanisms of Zinc Oxide Nanoparticles against Bacterial Pathogens. Sci. Rep. 2022;12(1):2658. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-06657-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-06657-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8850488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35173244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salman M., Sharma P., Kumar M., Ethayathulla A. S., Kaur P.. Targeting Novel Sites in DNA Gyrase for Development of Anti-Microbials. Brief. Funct. Genomics. 2023;22(2):180&#x2013;194. doi: 10.1093/bfgp/elac029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bfgp/elac029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36064602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu X. Y., Tang J., Zhang Z., Ding K.. Bacterial -Ketoacyl-Acyl Carrier Protein Synthase III (FabH) as a Target for Novel Antibacterial Agents Design. Curr. Med. Chem. 2015;22(5):651&#x2013;667. doi: 10.2174/0929867322666141212115236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/0929867322666141212115236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25515508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alarfaj A. A., Hirad A. H., Ravindran B., Narasimhamoorthi S. P.. Evaluation of Anti-Microbial Activity and Molecular Docking of Green Synthesized Copper Oxide Nanoparticle from Aegle Marmelos Leaf Extract. J. Drug Del. Sci. Technol. 2023;87:104851. doi: 10.1016/j.jddst.2023.104851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jddst.2023.104851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oselusi S. O., Christoffels A., Egieyeh S. A.. Cheminformatic Characterization of Natural Antimicrobial Products for the Development of New Lead Compounds. Molecules. 2021;26(13):3970. doi: 10.3390/molecules26133970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules26133970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8271829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34209681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sympli H. D.. Estimation of Drug-Likeness Properties of GC MS Separated Bioactive Compounds in Rare Medicinal Pleione Maculata Using Molecular Docking Technique and SwissADME in Silico Tools. Netw. Model. Anal. Heal. Informat. Bioinf. 2021;10:14&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1007/s13721-020-00276-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13721-020-00276-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7903411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33643765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bultum L. E., Tolossa G. B., Kim G., Kwon O., Lee D.. In Silico Activity and ADMET Profiling of Phytochemicals from Ethiopian Indigenous Aloes Using Pharmacophore Models. Sci. Rep. 2022;12(1):22221. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-26446-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-26446-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9789083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36564437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipinski C. A.. Lead-and Drug-like Compounds: The Rule-of-Five Revolution. Drug Discov. today Technol. 2004;1(4):337&#x2013;341. doi: 10.1016/j.ddtec.2004.11.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ddtec.2004.11.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24981612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maximo da Silva M., Comin M., Santos Duarte T., Foglio M. A., De Carvalho J. E., do Carmo Vieira M., Nazari Formagio A., Synthesis A. S.. Synthesis, Antiproliferative Activity and Molecular Properties Predictions of Galloyl Derivatives. Molecules. 2015;20(4):5360&#x2013;5373. doi: 10.3390/molecules20045360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules20045360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6272127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25816079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadat Razavi Z., Sina Alizadeh S., Sadat Razavi F., Souri M., Soltani M.. Advancing Neurological Disorders Therapies: Organic Nanoparticles as a Key to Blood-Brain Barrier Penetration. Int. J. Pharm. 2025;670:125186. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpharm.2025.125186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2025.125186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39788400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Chen Z., Li A., Liu R., Yang H., Xia X.. The Phytochemical Potential for Brain Disease Therapy and the Possible Nanodelivery Solutions for Brain Access. Front. Oncol. 2022;12:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.3389/fonc.2022.936054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2022.936054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9259986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35814371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daina A., Michielin O., Zoete V.. SwissADME: A Free Web Tool to Evaluate Pharmacokinetics, Drug-Likeness and Medicinal Chemistry Friendliness of Small Molecules. Sci. Rep. 2017;7:1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1038/srep42717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep42717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5335600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28256516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmeliegy M., Vourvahis M., Guo C., Wang D. D.. Effect of P-Glycoprotein (P-Gp) Inducers on Exposure of P-Gp Substrates: Review of Clinical Drug&#x2013;Drug Interaction Studies. Clin. Pharmacokinet. 2020;59(6):699&#x2013;714. doi: 10.1007/s40262-020-00867-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40262-020-00867-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7292822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32052379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen T. T. L., Duong V. A., Maeng H. J.. Pharmaceutical Formulations with P-Glycoprotein Inhibitory Effect as Promising Approaches for Enhancing Oral Drug Absorption and Bioavailability. Pharmaceutics. 2021;13(7):1103&#x2013;1148. doi: 10.3390/pharmaceutics13071103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics13071103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8309061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34371794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao M., Ma J., Li M., Zhang Y., Jiang B., Zhao X., Huai C., Shen L., Zhang N., He L., Qin S.. Cytochrome P450 Enzymes and Drug Metabolism in Humans. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2021;22(23):12808&#x2013;12816. doi: 10.3390/ijms222312808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms222312808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8657965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34884615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teo Y. L., Ho H. K., Chan A.. Metabolism-Related Pharmacokinetic Drug-Drug Interactions with Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitors: Current Understanding, Challenges and Recommendations. Br. J. Clin. Pharmacol. 2015;79(2):241&#x2013;253. doi: 10.1111/bcp.12496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bcp.12496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4309630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25125025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arici M., &#xd6;zhan G.. CYP2C9, CYPC19 and CYP2D6 Gene Profiles and Gene Susceptibility to Drug Response and Toxicity in Turkish Population. Saudi Pharm. J. 2017;25(3):376&#x2013;380. doi: 10.1016/j.jsps.2016.09.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsps.2016.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5357098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28344492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pu L., Naderi M., Liu T., Wu H.-C., Mukhopadhyay S., Brylinski M.. EToxPred: A Machine Learning-Based Approach to Estimate the Toxicity of Drug Candidates. BMC Pharmacol. Toxicol. 2019;20(1):1&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1186/s40360-018-0282-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40360-018-0282-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6325674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30621790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H. M., Yu M. S., Kazmi S. R., Oh S. Y., Rhee K. H., Bae M. A., Lee B. H., Shin D. S., Oh K. S., Ceong H., Lee D., Na D.. Computational Determination of HERG-Related Cardiotoxicity of Drug Candidates. BMC Bioinf. 2019;20(S10):250. doi: 10.1186/s12859-019-2814-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12859-019-2814-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6538553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31138104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>