<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41484846</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2318</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC geriatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Geriatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development and validation of predicting hospital mortality of acute ischemic stroke patients over 80 years in ICU: a retrospective study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>154</StartPage><MedlinePgn>154</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">154</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12877-025-06821-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Elderly patients have different risk profiles and stroke features compared to younger individuals. However, there is a paucity of data on acute ischemic stroke (AIS) in very old subjects, and insufficient data has been published about prognostication in this population. This study aimed to design a nomogram for predicting hospital mortality of AIS patients over 80 years old in intensive care units (ICU) and to establish clear risk strata via the gray zone approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In this retrospective cohort study, the baseline data and in-hospital prognosis of patients with stroke from the Medical Information Mart for Intensive Care-IV database were retrieved. Patient outcomes were dichotomized into survival and non-survival based on 28-day prognosis. Independent predictors identified through univariate and multivariable logistic regression were used to construct the nomogram. Model performance was evaluated in the validation set using AUC, calibration curves, and decision curve analysis (DCA). The gray zone approach categorized patients into three risk groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Initially, 929 eligible patients with AIS were identified, and 224 (24.1%) achieved the endpoint event. The multivariable analysis revealed that Male, White, APS-III, GCS, glucose and Mechanical ventilation were independent predictors for AIS, which were incorporated into a nomogram. The model demonstrated strong performance in the validation set, with an area under the curve (AUC) of 0.814. The gray zone approach effectively stratified patients into three distinct risk categories with significantly different mortality rates: low-risk (Total points&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;105), medium-risk (105&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;Total points&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;129), and high-risk (Total points&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;129). This stratification was further validated by significant Kaplan-Meier survival differences (log-rank <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) and a clear dose-response relationship across risk groups (HR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.99 per category, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). The current study demonstrated that, within the gray zone, male sex and a higher GCS score were associated with survival.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">In conclusion, the nomogram and its associated risk strata offer a practical tool that directly informs prognosis and clinical decision-making for AIS patients over 80 in the ICU.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12877-025-06821-9.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Lishan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, School of Public Health, (Guangdong Provincial Key Laboratory of Tropical Disease Research), Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, 510515, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yimin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nanfang Hospital, Southern Medical University, Guangzhou North Avenue 1838#, Guangzhou, 510515, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuro International Collaboration (NIC), Foshan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pitton Rissardo</LastName><ForeName>Jamir</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Department, Cooper University Hospital, Camden, NJ, 08103, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mofatteh</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Dentistry and Biomedical Sciences, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast, Northern Ireland, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fornari Caprara</LastName><ForeName>Ana Leticia</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology Department, Cooper University Hospital, Camden, NJ, 08103, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Qibei</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nanfang Hospital, Southern Medical University, Guangzhou North Avenue 1838#, Guangzhou, 510515, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Yihua</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Nanfang Hospital, Southern Medical University, Guangzhou North Avenue 1838#, Guangzhou, 510515, China. simey@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>An</LastName><ForeName>Shengli</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, School of Public Health, (Guangdong Provincial Key Laboratory of Tropical Disease Research), Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, 510515, China. hsasl@smu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2022A1515012152</GrantID><Agency>Guangdong Basic and Applied Research Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Geriatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968548</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2318</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elderly</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gray zone approach</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">In-hospital mortality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MIMIC-IV</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stroke</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki (as revised in 2013). The collection of patient information and creation of the MIMIC-IV was reviewed by the Institutional Review Board at the Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, which abandoned informed consent and approved the data-sharing initiative. As the MIMIC-IV database desensitized patient information, the requirement for informed consent of patients is not essential. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41484846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12870360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-025-06821-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12877-025-06821-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Olindo S, Cabre P, Deschamps R, Chatot-Henry C, Rene-Corail P, Fournerie P, et al. Acute stroke in the very elderly: epidemiological features, stroke subtypes, management, and outcome in Martinique, French West Indies. Stroke. 2003;34(7):1593&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.STR.0000077924.71088.02</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12829873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toyoda K, Yoshimura S, Nakai M, Koga M, Sasahara Y, Sonoda K, et al. Twenty-year change in severity and outcome of ischemic and hemorrhagic strokes. JAMA Neurol. 2022;79(1):61&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2021.4346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8649912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34870689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candelario-Jalil E, Paul S. Impact of aging and comorbidities on ischemic stroke outcomes in preclinical animal models: a translational perspective. Exp Neurol. 2021;335:113494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.expneurol.2020.113494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7874968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33035516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy-O&#x2019;Reilly M, McCullough LD. Age and sex are critical factors in ischemic stroke pathology. Endocrinology. 2018;159(8):3120&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/en.2018-00465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6963709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30010821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Lin Y, Po HL. Comparison of the risk factor profile, stroke subtypes, and outcomes between stroke patients aged 65 years or younger and elderly stroke patients: a hospital-based study. Int J Gerontol. 2013;7(4):205&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijge.2012.11.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonarow GC, Reeves MJ, Zhao X, Olson DM, Smith EE, Saver JL, Schwamm LH. Age-related differences in characteristics, performance measures, treatment trends, and outcomes in patients with ischemic stroke. Circulation. 2010;121(7):879&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.109.892497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20142445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu W, Pitton RJ, Nguyen TN, Mofatteh M, Wei H, Liebeskind DS, Yang S, Li W, Pan W, Zhou S, et al. Effect of atrial fibrillation on outcomes in patients with anterior circulation occlusion stroke receiving endovascular therapy. FRONT AGING NEUROSCI. 2023;15:1160265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2023.1160265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10311510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37396665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saposnik G, Cote R, Phillips S, Gubitz G, Bayer N, Minuk J, Black S. Stroke outcome in those over 80: a multicenter cohort study across Canada. Stroke. 2008;39(8):2310&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.107.511402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18556583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogura T, Nakano M, Izawa Y, Nakamura M, Fujizuka K, Lefor AT. Analysis of risk classification for massive transfusion in severe trauma using the Gray zone approach. Am J Emerg Med. 2015;33(9):1146&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajem.2015.05.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26032662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson A, Bulgarelli L, Shen L, Gayles A, Shammout A, Horng S, et al. MIMIC-IV, a freely accessible electronic health record dataset. Sci Data. 2023;10(1):1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41597-022-01899-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9810617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36596836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberger AL, Amaral LA, Glass L, Hausdorff JM, Ivanov PC, Mark RG, Mietus JE, Moody GB, Peng CK, Stanley HE. PhysioBank, PhysioToolkit, and physionet: components of a new research resource for complex physiologic signals. Circulation. 2000;101(23):E215&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.101.23.e215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10851218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer M, Deutschman CS, Seymour CW, Shankar-Hari M, Annane D, Bauer M, et al. The third international consensus definitions for sepsis and septic shock (Sepsis-3). JAMA. 2016;315(8):801&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2016.0287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4968574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26903338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambden S, Laterre PF, Levy MM, Francois B. The SOFA score-development, utility and challenges of accurate assessment in clinical trials. Crit Care. 2019;23(1):374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-019-2663-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6880479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31775846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson AE, Kramer AA, Clifford GD. A new severity of illness scale using a subset of acute physiology and chronic health evaluation data elements shows comparable predictive accuracy. Crit Care Med. 2013;41(7):1711&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0b013e31828a24fe</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23660729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Gall JR, Lemeshow S, Saulnier F. A new simplified acute physiology score (SAPS II) based on a European/North American multicenter study. JAMA-J Am Med Assoc. 1993;270(24):2957&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.1993.03510240069035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8254858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sternbach GL. The Glasgow coma scale. J Emerg Med. 2000;19(1):67&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0736-4679(00)00182-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10863122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Zhang L, Ge S, He W, Zeng M. Prognosis predictive value of the Oxford acute severity of illness score for sepsis: a retrospective cohort study. PeerJ. 2019;7:e7083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.7083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6563807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31218129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgerald M, Saville BR, Lewis RJ. Decision curve analysis. JAMA J Am Med Assoc. 2015;313(4):409&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2015.37</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25626037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Liu X, Hu M, Mao Z, Zhou Y, Peng J, et al. A simple nomogram for predicting hospital mortality of patients over 80 years in ICU: an international multicenter retrospective study. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2023;78(7):1227&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glad124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37162208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XD, Li MM. A novel nomogram to predict mortality in patients with stroke: a survival analysis based on the MIMIC-III clinical database. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak. 2022;22(1):92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12911-022-01836-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8988376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35387672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robba C, Giardiello D, Almondo C, Asehnoune K, Badenes R, Cinotti R, et al. Ventilation practices in acute brain injured patients and association with outcomes: the VENTIBRAIN multicenter observational study. Intensive Care Med. 2025;51(2):318&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-025-07808-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11903615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39992441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan S, Ma J. The value of five scoring systems in predicting the prognosis of patients with sepsis-associated acute respiratory failure. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):4760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-55257-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10899590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38413621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mkubwa JJ, Bedada AG, Esterhuizen TM. Traumatic brain injury: association between the Glasgow coma scale score and intensive care unit mortality. South Afr J Crit Car 2022, 38(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9448257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36101711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piironen K, Putaala J, Rosso C, Samson Y. Glucose and acute stroke: evidence for an interlude. Stroke. 2012;43(3):898&#x2013;902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.111.631218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22343652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu D, Tang Y, Zhang Q. Admission hyperglycemia predicts long-term mortality in critically ill patients with subarachnoid hemorrhage: a retrospective analysis of the MIMIC-III database. Front Neurol. 2021;12:678998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2021.678998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8525327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34675863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jhou HJ, Chen PH, Yang LY, Chang SH, Lee CH. Plasma anion gap and risk of in-hospital mortality in patients with acute ischemic stroke: analysis from the MIMIC-IV database. J Pers Med. 2021. 10.3390/jpm11101004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jpm11101004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8541378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34683145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai W, Xu J, Wu X, Chen Z, Zeng L, Song X, et al. Association between triglyceride-glucose index and all-cause mortality in critically ill patients with ischemic stroke: analysis of the MIMIC-IV database. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2023;22(1):138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-023-01864-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10262584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37312120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Li Z, Yin X. Triglyceride-glucose index: a novel evaluation tool for all-cause mortality in critically ill hemorrhagic stroke patients-a retrospective analysis of the MIMIC-IV database. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2024;23(1):100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-024-02193-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10949583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38500198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X, Liang J, Hao W, Zhou J, Gao Y, Gong X, et al. Prognostic value of inflammatory markers for in-hospital mortality in intensive care patients with acute ischemic stroke: a retrospective observational study based on MIMIC-IV. Front Neurol. 2023;14:1174711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2023.1174711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10285211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37360337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YR, Yang LY, Lee CH, Chang SH, Chen PH, Jhou HJ. Is thrombocytopenia an in-hospital mortality risk factor among patients with acute ischemic stroke? A propensity score-matched analysis from the MIMIC-IV database. J Clin Med. 2023. 10.3390/jcm12020580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12020580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9861395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36675509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin Z, Liao N, Lu X, Duan X, Zhou Q, Ge L. Relationship between the hemoglobin-to-red cell distribution width ratio and all-cause mortality in ischemic stroke patients with atrial fibrillation: an analysis from the MIMIC-IV database. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2022;18:341&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NDT.S350588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8865868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35221686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CS, Chen PH, Chang SH, Lee CH, Yang LY, Chen YC, et al. Atrial fibrillation is not an independent determinant of mortality among critically ill acute ischemic stroke patients: a propensity score-matched analysis from the MIMIC-IV database. Front Neurol. 2021;12:730244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2021.730244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8801535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35111120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rissardo J, Caprara ALF. Impact of age on the outcomes of atrial fibrillation-related stroke. Heart Mind. 2024;8:132&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/hm.HM-D-23-00050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J, Chervak LM, Siegler JE, Li Z, Mofatteh M, Galecio-Castillo M, et al. Postinterventional petechial hemorrhage associated with poor functional outcome after successful recanalization following endovascular therapy. Neurosurgery. 2024. 10.1227/neu.0000000000003098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1227/neu.0000000000003098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38984821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Nguyen TN, Mofatteh M, Abdalkader M, Wellington J, Yan Z, et al. Association of early increase in body temperature with symptomatic intracranial hemorrhage and unfavorable outcome following endovascular therapy in patients with large vessel occlusion stroke. J Integr Neurosci. 2022;21(6):156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31083/j.jin2106156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36424759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>