<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41930066</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical Outcomes Following Dual-Frequency Noninvasive Monopolar Radiofrequency Treatment for Facial Laxity and Lower Face Lifting: A Prospective Multicenter Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e104546</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e104546</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e104546</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.104546</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Introduction Facial aging is a common dermatological and plastic surgical concern. As&#xa0;patients today wish to avoid surgical intervention, noninvasive monopolar radiofrequency (NMRF) can be a useful tool to address this concern, but results have varied by target depth. A dual-frequency NMRF system (6.78 MHz and 2 MHz) is designed to support depth-dependent tissue heating across dermal and subdermal planes. This study aimed to evaluate short-term clinical outcomes and safety in a prospective multicenter trial. Methods Thirty-nine subjects at four clinical sites completed the study. The protocol allowed up to three treatments spaced four weeks apart; however, all subjects completed the study after two sessions. Treatments were delivered at three different depths (shallow, middle, and deep), as indicated by the target condition and facial anatomical zone. Standardized clinical photography was taken at baseline, 30- and 90-day timepoints. A five-point Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale (GAIS) was assessed by the principal investigators at the 30- and 90-day assessments, and patients subjectively scored their satisfaction using a study-specific patient satisfaction score (PSS; six-point scale). GAIS results were evaluated for statistical significance; satisfaction was summarized descriptively with exact 95% CIs. Any adverse events were documented. Results A total of 39 subjects received two treatment sessions. Clinician-scored GAIS achieved three or above&#xa0;by 84.6% (33/39; 95% CI, 69.5-94.1) of subjects at 30-day and 92.3% (36/39; 95% CI, 79.1-98.4) of subjects at 90-day timepoints (p=0.0293 and 0.0008, respectively). Patient satisfaction was also high, scoring of four or above&#xa0;for 79.5% of participants at 30-day (31/39; 95% CI, 64.5-89.2%) and 84.6% at 90-day (33/39; 95% CI, 70.3-92.8%). There were no long-lasting adverse events. Conclusion Dual-frequency NMRF, applied with depth-dependent settings in this study, was associated with significant short-term improvement and high satisfaction at 30 and 90 days, with no persistent adverse events. These findings support further evaluation of this noninvasive RF approach for facial aging.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Weiss et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiss</LastName><ForeName>Robert A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dermatology, Maryland Laser, Skin, and Vein Institute, Baltimore, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jordan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dermatology, Laser and Skin - Dermatology, Devon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DiBernardo</LastName><ForeName>Barry</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Plastic Surgery, New Jersey Plastic Surgery, Montclair, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhatia</LastName><ForeName>Ashish C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dermatology, Oak Dermatology, Naperville, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adverse events</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dual-frequency radiofrequency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">facial laxity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">global aesthetic improvement scale</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lower face lifting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">monopolar radiofrequency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">noninvasive monopolar radiofrequency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">noninvasive skin tightening</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient satisfaction score</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prospective multicenter study</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Allendale Investigational Review Board (AIRB) issued approval LMP24001. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: Cynosure Lutronic Inc. (Goyang, South Korea) provided the investigational device and consumables and provided a modest research grant to the sites. The sponsor had no role in the conduct of the study or preparation of the manuscript. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41930066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13040610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.104546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The anatomy of the aging face: volume loss and changes in 3-dimensional topography. Coleman SR, Grover R. Aesthet Surg J. 2006;26:0&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19338976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Defining skin aging and its risk factors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Wong QY, Chew FT. Sci Rep. 2021;11:22075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8586245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34764376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Objective analysis of age-related changes in the superficial musculoaponeurotic system in Japanese females using computed tomography. Okuda I, Abe K, Yoshioka N, Komemushi T, Jinzaki M, Ohjimi H. Aesthet Surg J Open Forum. 2023;5:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10270653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37333712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The facial aging process from the "inside out". Swift A, Liew S, Weinkle S, Garcia JK, Silberberg MB. Aesthet Surg J. 2021;41:1107&#x2013;1119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8438644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33325497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Energy-based skin rejuvenation: a review of mechanisms and thermal effects. Jia X, Feng Y. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2025;24:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11837243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39485034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thermage: the nonablative radiofrequency for rejuvenation. Sukal SA, Geronemus RG. Clin Dermatol. 2008;26:602&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18940540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The use of radiofrequency in aesthetic surgery. Dayan E, Burns AJ, Rohrich RJ, Theodorou S. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2020;8:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7489578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32983755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical efficacy and safety evaluation of a monopolar radiofrequency device with a new vibration handpiece for the treatment of facial skin laxity: a 10-month experience with 64 patients. Edwards AF, Massaki AB, Fabi S, Goldman M. Dermatol Surg. 2013;39:104&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23153312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prospective clinical trial of the latest generation of noninvasive monopolar radiofrequency for the treatment of facial and upper neck skin laxity. Angra K, Alhaddad M, Boen M, Lipp MB, Kollipara R, Hoss E, Goldman MP. Dermatol Surg. 2021;47:762&#x2013;766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33899795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unipolar versus bipolar radiofrequency treatment of rhytides and laxity using a mobile painless delivery method. Alexiades-Armenakas M, Dover JS, Arndt KA. Lasers Surg Med. 2008;40:446&#x2013;453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18727024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joule heating.  [
Feb;
2026 
]. 2022. https://www.britannica.com/science/Joules-law https://www.britannica.com/science/Joules-law</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adverse events after noninvasive radiofrequency treatment for cosmetic uses. Chung YJ, Lee JH. Med Lasers. 2015;4:16&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The validity and practicality of sun-reactive skin types I through VI. Fitzpatrick TB. Arch Dermatol. 1988;124:869&#x2013;871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3377516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The efficacy and safety of combining cross-linked hyaluronic acid filler VYC-12L and energy-based devices for facial skin quality improvement in Asians. Oku M, Oku K. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2025;24:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12509472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41065147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical importance of changes in chronic pain intensity measured on an 11-point numerical pain rating scale. Farrar JT, Young JP Jr, LaMoreaux L, Werth JL, Poole RM. Pain. 2001;94:149&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11690728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The R Project for Statistical Computing.  [
Feb;
2026 
]. 2025. https://www.R-project.org/ https://www.R-project.org/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term efficacy and safety of a novel monopolar radiofrequency device for skin tightening: a prospective randomized controlled study. Wang Z, Li L, Zhang X, Li Z, Yan Y. Lasers Surg Med. 2025;57:259&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39957006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of the clinical safety and efficacy of a noninvasive dual-frequency monopolar radiofrequency device in the treatment of facial photoaging sequelae in Republic of Korea: a clinical study. Hwang JK. Med Lasers. 2025;14:23&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thermal dose requirement for tissue effect: experimental and clinical findings. Dewhirst MW, Viglianti BL, Lora-Michiels M, Hoopes PJ, Hanson M. Proc SPIE Int Soc Opt Eng. 2003;4954:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4188373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25301982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exploring thermal dynamics in wound healing: the impact of temperature and microenvironment. Huang J, Fan C, Ma Y, Huang G. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol. 2024;17:1251&#x2013;1258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11144001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38827629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Expression and function of heat shock protein 47: a collagen-specific molecular chaperone in the endoplasmic reticulum. Nagata K. Matrix Biol. 1998;16:379&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9524358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Computational modeling and histologic analysis of 6.78- and 2-MHz monopolar radiofrequency-induced thermal reactions. Ko K, Ryu HG, Park J, Kim W, Kim S, Ko J, Cho SB. http://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC12662868/ Lasers Med Sci. 2025;40:501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12662868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41315066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monopolar radiofrequency for dermal temperature regulation and remodeling: a porcine model study. Park C, Hong J, Ryu HG, et al. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2024;23:3955&#x2013;3960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11626309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39049551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of dual-frequency noninvasive monopolar radiofrequency in skin tightening: histological evidence. Hong J, Ryu HG, Park C, Park J, Kim K, Lee KM, Chun SI. Skin Res Technol. 2024;30:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11180671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38881041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>