<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41746126</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-445X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Coupling between global brain blood oxygen level-dependent activity and cerebrospinal fluid dynamics in young endurance athletes.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/EP093289</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) contributes to brain waste clearance through its coupling with cerebral haemodynamics. Aerobic exercise promotes brain health, but its influence on brain waste clearance remains unclear. This study examined the coupling between CSF and cerebral haemodynamics in endurance athletes. Fifteen young male endurance athletes were compared with 16 age-matched sedentary male controls. Resting-state functional magnetic resonance imaging was used to obtain brain global blood oxygen level-dependent (gBOLD) and CSF inflow signals. The gBOLD-CSF coupling was estimated using cross-correlation function and transfer function analyses in time and frequency domains, respectively. The magnitude of gBOLD and CSF oscillations was also quantified by power spectral density. The cross-correlation-derived gBOLD-CSF coupling was similar between athletes and sedentary controls (-0.30&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.26&#xa0;vs. -0.33&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.22, P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.753). Power spectral density of the CSF inflow signal was significantly greater in athletes (2.83 [2.19, 3.47] z<sup>2</sup>/Hz) than sedentary individuals (1.84 [1.22, 2.46] z<sup>2</sup>/Hz, P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.030), whereas that of the gBOLD signal did not differ between groups. Although transfer function gain did not show a statistically significant group difference, a moderate effect size was observed (1.50 [-0.36, 3.36] vs. 1.24 [-0.06, 2.55], P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.051, effect size: 0.523). Transfer function phase and coherence were comparable between groups. Significant frequency dependence was observed for gBOLD power spectral density as well as transfer function gain, phase and coherence across groups. Endurance athletes demonstrated greater CSF fluctuation compared with sedentary individuals. Our findings suggest that endurance training may be linked to changes in CSF dynamics.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Experimental Physiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoshi</LastName><ForeName>Daisuke</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0786-8809</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Informatics and Interaction Research Institute, National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology, Tsukuba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Sciences, Japan Institute of Sports Sciences, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fukuie</LastName><ForeName>Marina</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Informatics and Interaction Research Institute, National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology, Tsukuba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asahara</LastName><ForeName>Ryota</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0861-0861</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrated Research Center for Self-Care Technology, National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology, Tsukuba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Medical Research Institute, National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology, Tsukuba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomoto</LastName><ForeName>Tsubasa</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5936-0332</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Informatics and Interaction Research Institute, National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology, Tsukuba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrated Research Center for Self-Care Technology, National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology, Tsukuba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Exercise and Environmental Medicine, Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital Dallas, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>David C</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Gruss Magnetic Resonance Research Center, Albert Einstein College of Medicine, Bronx, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Rong</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Exercise and Environmental Medicine, Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital Dallas, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ohyama-Byun</LastName><ForeName>Keigo</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health and Sports Sciences, University of Tsukuba, Tsukuba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maeda</LastName><ForeName>Seiji</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health and Sports Sciences, University of Tsukuba, Tsukuba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Physiology, School of Sport Sciences, Waseda University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sugawara</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2603-0692</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Informatics and Interaction Research Institute, National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology, Tsukuba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrated Research Center for Self-Care Technology, National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology, Tsukuba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Exercise and Environmental Medicine, Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital Dallas, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health and Sports Sciences, University of Tsukuba, Tsukuba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tarumi</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7061-8867</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Informatics and Interaction Research Institute, National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology, Tsukuba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrated Research Center for Self-Care Technology, National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology, Tsukuba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Exercise and Environmental Medicine, Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital Dallas, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health and Sports Sciences, University of Tsukuba, Tsukuba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>24KJ2216</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>23K24748</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>25K21803</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Advanced Research Initiative for Human High Performance (ARIHHP), University of Tsukuba</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Descente and Ishimoto Memorial Foundation for the Promotion of Sports Science</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9002940</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0958-0670</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain waste clearance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cerebral haemodynamics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cerebrospinal fluid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endurance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glymphatic system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resting&#x2010;state functional magnetic resonance imaging</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41746126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP093289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ainsworth, B. E., Haskell, W. L., Herrmann, S. D., Meckes, N., Bassett, D. R., Jr., Tudor&#x2010;Locke, C., Greer, J. L., Vezina, J., Whitt&#x2010;Glover, M. C., &amp; Leon, A. S. (2011). 2011 Compendium of Physical Activities: A second update of codes and MET values. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 43(8), 1575&#x2013;1581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akselrod, S., Gordon, D., Ubel, F. A., Shannon, D. C., Berger, A. C., &amp; Cohen, R. J. (1981). Power spectrum analysis of heart rate fluctuation: A quantitative probe of beat&#x2010;to&#x2010;beat cardiovascular control. Science, 213(4504), 220&#x2013;222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubert, A. E., Seps, B., &amp; Beckers, F. (2003). Heart rate variability in athletes. Sports Medicine, 33(12), 889&#x2013;919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benveniste, H., Liu, X., Koundal, S., Sanggaard, S., Lee, H., &amp; Wardlaw, J. (2019). The glymphatic system and waste clearance with brain aging: A review. Gerontology, 65(2), 106&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birn, R. M., Diamond, J. B., Smith, M. A., &amp; Bandettini, P. A. (2006). Separating respiratory&#x2010;variation&#x2010;related fluctuations from neuronal&#x2010;activity&#x2010;related fluctuations in fMRI. NeuroImage, 31(4), 1536&#x2013;1548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswal, B., Yetkin, F. Z., Haughton, V. M., &amp; Hyde, J. S. (1995). Functional connectivity in the motor cortex of resting human brain using echo&#x2010;planar MRI. Magnetic Resonance in Medicine, 34(4), 537&#x2013;541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boland, B., Yu, W. H., Corti, O., Mollereau, B., Henriques, A., Bezard, E., Pastores, G. M., Rubinsztein, D. C., Nixon, R. A., Duchen, M. R., Mallucci, G. R., Kroemer, G., Levine, B., Eskelinen, E. L., Mochel, F., Spedding, M., Louis, C., Martin, O. R., &amp; Millan, M. J. (2018). Promoting the clearance of neurotoxic proteins in neurodegenerative disorders of ageing. Nature Reviews. Drug Discovery, 17(9), 660&#x2013;688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolt, T., Wang, S., Nomi, J. S., Setton, R., Gold, B. P., deB Frederick, B., Yeo, B. T. T., Chen, J. J., Picchioni, D., Duyn, J. H., Spreng, R. N., Keilholz, S. D., Uddin, L. Q., &amp; Chang, C. (2025). Autonomic physiological coupling of the global fMRI signal. Nature Neuroscience, 28(6), 1327&#x2013;1335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg, G. (1990). Psychophysical scaling with applications in physical work and the perception of exertion. Scandinavian Journal of Work, Environment &amp; Health, 16, (Suppl 1), 55&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, C., &amp; Glover, G. H. (2009). Relationship between respiration, end&#x2010;tidal CO2, and BOLD signals in resting&#x2010;state fMRI. Neuroimage, 47(4), 1381&#x2013;1393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, C., Metzger, C. D., Glover, G. H., Duyn, J. H., Heinze, H. J., &amp; Walter, M. (2013). Association between heart rate variability and fluctuations in resting&#x2010;state functional connectivity. NeuroImage, 68, 93&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desikan, R. S., S&#xe9;gonne, F., Fischl, B., Quinn, B. T., Dickerson, B. C., Blacker, D., Buckner, R. L., Dale, A. M., Maguire, R. P., Hyman, B. T., Albert, M. S., &amp; Killiany, R. J. (2006). An automated labeling system for subdividing the human cerebral cortex on MRI scans into gyral based regions of interest. NeuroImage, 31(3), 968&#x2013;980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon, E. M., Kamath, M. V., McCartney, N., &amp; Fallen, E. L. (1992). Neural regulation of heart rate variability in endurance athletes and sedentary controls. Cardiovascular Research, 26(7), 713&#x2013;719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischl, B. (2012). FreeSurfer. NeuroImage, 62(2), 774&#x2013;781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuie, M., Yamabe, T., Kimura, R., Zhu, D. C., Ohyama&#x2010;Byun, K., Maeda, S., Sugawara, J., &amp; Tarumi, T. (2024). Ascending aortic impedance in young endurance athletes: A time&#x2010;resolved phase&#x2010;contrast MRI study. Journal of Applied Physiology, 136(3), 555&#x2013;566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fultz, N. E., Bonmassar, G., Setsompop, K., Stickgold, R. A., Rosen, B. R., Polimeni, J. R., &amp; Lewis, L. D. (2019). Coupled electrophysiological, hemodynamic, and cerebrospinal fluid oscillations in human sleep. Science, 366(6465), 628&#x2013;631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xe4;ssler, B., Thielmann, B., B&#xf6;ckelmann, I., &amp; H&#xf6;kelmann, A. (2021). Effects of different exercise interventions on heart rate variability and cardiovascular health factors in older adults: A systematic review. European Review of Aging and Physical Activity, 18(1), 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graves, R. S., Mahnken, J. D., Perea, R. D., Billinger, S. A., &amp; Vidoni, E. D. (2015). Modeling Percentile Rank of Cardiorespiratory Fitness Across the Lifespan. Cardiopulmonary Physical Therapy Journal, 26(4), 108&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, Y., Sainburg, L. E., Kuang, S., Han, F., Williams, J. W., Liu, Y., Zhang, N., Zhang, X., Leopold, D. A., &amp; Liu, X. (2021). Brain Activity Fluctuations Propagate as Waves Traversing the Cortical Hierarchy. Cerebral Cortex, 31(9), 3986&#x2013;4005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, F., Chen, J., Belkin&#x2010;Rosen, A., Gu, Y., Luo, L., Buxton, O. M., &amp; Liu, X. (2021). Reduced coupling between cerebrospinal fluid flow and global brain activity is linked to Alzheimer disease&#x2010;related pathology. PloS Biology, 19(6), e3001233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, F., Lee, J., Chen, X., Ziontz, J., Ward, T., Landau, S. M., Baker, S. L., Harrison, T. M., &amp; Jagust, W. J. (2024). Global brain activity and its coupling with cerebrospinal fluid flow is related to tau pathology. Alzheimer's &amp; Dementia, 20(12), 8541&#x2013;8555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, F., Liu, X., Mailman, R. B., Huang, X., &amp; Liu, X. (2023). Resting&#x2010;state global brain activity affects early &#x3b2;&#x2010;amyloid accumulation in default mode network. Nature Communications, 14(1), 7788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, F., Liu, X., Yang, Y., &amp; Liu, X. (2024). Sex&#x2010;specific age&#x2010;related differences in cerebrospinal fluid clearance assessed by resting&#x2010;state functional magnetic resonance imaging. NeuroImage, 302, 120905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, X. F., Liu, D. X., Zhang, Q., Liang, F. Y., Dai, G. Y., Zeng, J. S., Pei, Z., Xu, G. Q., &amp; Lan, Y. (2017). Voluntary exercise promotes glymphatic clearance of amyloid beta and reduces the activation of astrocytes and microglia in aged mice. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 10, 144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedden, T., Oh, H., Younger, A. P., &amp; Patel, T. A. (2013). Meta&#x2010;analysis of amyloid&#x2010;cognition relations in cognitively normal older adults. Neurology, 80(14), 1341&#x2013;1348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoopes, A., Mora, J. S., Dalca, A. V., Fischl, B., &amp; Hoffmann, M. (2022). SynthStrip: Skull&#x2010;stripping for any brain image. NeuroImage, 260, 119474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson, M., Bannister, P., Brady, M., &amp; Smith, S. (2002). Improved optimization for the robust and accurate linear registration and motion correction of brain images. NeuroImage, 17(2), 825&#x2013;841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kipnis, J., Benveniste, H., Eichmann, A., Thomas, J. L., Reich, D. S., Lewis, L. D., Tsai, L. H., Drieu, A., Bakker, E., Kelley, D. H., Lundgaard, I., Mestre, H., Zott, B., Eide, P. K., van Osch, M. J. P., van Veluw, S. J., Iliff, J., Yang, A. C., Santambrogio, L., &#x2026; Nedergaard, M. (2025). Resolving the mysteries of brain clearance and immune surveillance. Neuron, 113(23), 3908&#x2013;3923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiviniemi, V. (2008). Endogenous brain fluctuations and diagnostic imaging. Human Brain Mapping, 29(7), 810&#x2013;817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiviniemi, V., Wang, X., Korhonen, V., Kein&#xe4;nen, T., Tuovinen, T., Autio, J., LeVan, P., Keilholz, S., Zang, Y. F., Hennig, J., &amp; Nedergaard, M. (2016). Ultra&#x2010;fast magnetic resonance encephalography of physiological brain activity&#x2014;Glymphatic pulsation mechanisms? Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow and Metabolism, 36(6), 1033&#x2013;1045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X., Leopold, D. A., &amp; Yang, Y. (2021). Single&#x2010;neuron firing cascades underlie global spontaneous brain events. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 118(47), e2105395118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mestre, H., Tithof, J., Du, T., Song, W., Peng, W., Sweeney, A. M., Olveda, G., Thomas, J. H., Nedergaard, M., &amp; Kelley, D. H. (2018). Flow of cerebrospinal fluid is driven by arterial pulsations and is reduced in hypertension. Nature Communications, 9(1), 4878.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Napadow, V., Dhond, R., Conti, G., Makris, N., Brown, E. N., &amp; Barbieri, R. (2008). Brain correlates of autonomic modulation: Combining heart rate variability with fMRI. NeuroImage, 42(1), 169&#x2013;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols, T. E., Das, S., Eickhoff, S. B., Evans, A. C., Glatard, T., Hanke, M., Kriegeskorte, N., Milham, M. P., Poldrack, R. A., Poline, J. B., Proal, E., Thirion, B., Van Essen, D. C., White, T., &amp; Yeo, B. T. (2017). Best practices in data analysis and sharing in neuroimaging using MRI. Nature Neuroscience, 20(3), 299&#x2013;303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedergaard, M., &amp; Goldman, S. A. (2020). Glymphatic failure as a final common pathway to dementia. Science, 370(6512), 50&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, W., Fukuie, M., Hoshi, D., Mori, S., Tomoto, T., Sugawara, J., &amp; Tarumi, T. (2024). Dynamic cerebral autoregulation during repeated handgrip exercise: Comparisons with spontaneous rest and sit&#x2010;stand maneuvers. Journal of Applied Physiology, 137(3), 718&#x2013;727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raichle, M. E., &amp; Gusnard, D. A. (2002). Appraising the brain's energy budget. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 99(16), 10237&#x2013;10239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen, M. K., Mestre, H., &amp; Nedergaard, M. (2022). Fluid transport in the brain. Physiological Reviews, 102(2), 1025&#x2013;1151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shmueli, K., van Gelderen, P., de Zwart, J. A., Horovitz, S. G., Fukunaga, M., Jansma, J. M., &amp; Duyn, J. H. (2007). Low&#x2010;frequency fluctuations in the cardiac rate as a source of variance in the resting&#x2010;state fMRI BOLD signal. NeuroImage, 38(2), 306&#x2013;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, S. M., Jenkinson, M., Woolrich, M. W., Beckmann, C. F., Behrens, T. E., Johansen&#x2010;Berg, H., Bannister, P. R., De Luca, M., Drobnjak, I., Flitney, D. E., Niazy, R. K., Saunders, J., Vickers, J., Zhang, Y., De Stefano, N., Brady, J. M., &amp; Matthews, P. M. (2004). Advances in functional and structural MR image analysis and implementation as FSL. Neuroimage, 23, (Suppl 1), S208&#x2013;S219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takayama, F., Aoyagi, A., Shimazu, W., &amp; Nabekura, Y. (2017). Effects of marathon running on aerobic fitness and performance in recreational runners one week after a race. Journal of Sports Medicine, 2017, 9402386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarasoff&#x2010;Conway, J. M., Carare, R. O., Osorio, R. S., Glodzik, L., Butler, T., Fieremans, E., Axel, L., Rusinek, H., Nicholson, C., Zlokovic, B. V., Frangione, B., Blennow, K., M&#xe9;nard, J., Zetterberg, H., Wisniewski, T., &amp; de Leon, M. J. (2016). Clearance systems in the brain&#x2013;implications for Alzheimer diseaser. Nature reviews Neurology, 12(4), 248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarumi, T., Fukuie, M., Yamabe, T., Kimura, R., Zhu, D. C., Ohyama&#x2010;Byun, K., Maeda, S., &amp; Sugawara, J. (2022). Microstructural organization of the corpus callosum in young endurance athletes: A global tractography study. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 16, 1042426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarumi, T., Tomoto, T., Sugawara, J., &amp; Zhang, R. (2025). Aerobic exercise training for the aging brain: Effective dosing and vascular mechanism. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews, 53(1), 31&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarumi, T., Won, J., Tomoto, T., Scheel, N., Zhu, D. C., Ashley, J., Rodrigue, K. M., Kennedy, K. M., Park, D. C., &amp; Zhang, R. (2025). Effects of aerobic exercise and cardiorespiratory fitness on white matter free water fraction in older adults: A 1&#x2010;year randomized controlled trial. Geroscience. Advance online publication. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11357&#x2010;025&#x2010;01709&#x2010;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarumi, T., Yamabe, T., Fukuie, M., Kimura, R., Zhu, D. C., Ohyama&#x2010;Byun, K., Maeda, S., &amp; Sugawara, J. (2021). Proximal aortic compliance in young male endurance athletes: An MRI study. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 53(3), 543&#x2013;550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarumi, T., Yamabe, T., Fukuie, M., Zhu, D. C., Zhang, R., Ogoh, S., &amp; Sugawara, J. (2021). Brain blood and cerebrospinal fluid flow dynamics during rhythmic handgrip exercise in young healthy men and women. The Journal of Physiology, 599(6), 1799&#x2013;1813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Holstein&#x2010;Rathlou, S., Petersen, N. C., &amp; Nedergaard, M. (2018). Voluntary running enhances glymphatic influx in awake behaving, young mice. Neuroscience Letters, 662, 253&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, M., He, Y., Sejnowski, T. J., &amp; Yu, X. (2018). Brain&#x2010;state dependent astrocytic Ca2+ signals are coupled to both positive and negative BOLD&#x2010;fMRI signals. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 115(7), E1647&#x2013;E1656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, S. D., Setzer, B., Fultz, N. E., Valdiviezo, Z., Tacugue, N., Diamandis, Z., &amp; Lewis, L. D. (2023). Neural activity induced by sensory stimulation can drive large&#x2010;scale cerebrospinal fluid flow during wakefulness in humans. PloS Biology, 21(3), e3002035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, L., Kang, H., Xu, Q., Chen, M. J., Liao, Y., Thiyagarajan, M., O'Donnell, J., Christensen, D. J., Nicholson, C., Iliff, J. J., Takano, T., Deane, R., &amp; Nedergaard, M. (2013). Sleep drives metabolite clearance from the adult brain. Science, 342(6156), 373&#x2013;377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing, C. Y., Tarumi, T., Liu, J., Zhang, Y., Turner, M., Riley, J., Tinajero, C. D., Yuan, L. J., &amp; Zhang, R. (2017). Distribution of cardiac output to the brain across the adult lifespan. Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow and Metabolism, 37(8), 2848&#x2013;2856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo, R. E., Kim, J. H., Moon, H. Y., Park, J. Y., Cheon, S., Shin, H. S., Han, D., Kim, Y., Park, S. H., &amp; Choi, S. H. (2025). Long&#x2010;term physical exercise facilitates putative glymphatic and meningeal lymphatic vessel flow in humans. Nature Communications, 16(1), 3360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, R., Zuckerman, J. H., Giller, C. A., &amp; Levine, B. D. (1998). Transfer function analysis of dynamic cerebral autoregulation in humans. American Journal of Physiology, 274(1 Pt 2), H233&#x2013;H241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Brady, M., &amp; Smith, S. (2001). Segmentation of brain MR images through a hidden Markov random field model and the expectation&#x2010;maximization algorithm. IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, 20(1), 45&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, D. C., Tarumi, T., Khan, M. A., &amp; Zhang, R. (2015). Vascular coupling in resting&#x2010;state fMRI: Evidence from multiple modalities. Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow and Metabolism, 35(12), 1910&#x2013;1920.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>