<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41735403</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Apical bud manipulation and integrated nutrient management enhance yield and profitability of cabbage (Brassica oleracea var. capitata L.) in Northwestern Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10391</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-41149-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cabbage (Brassica oleracea var. capitata L.) is an important vegetable crop in Ethiopia, yet its productivity remains low due to poor soil fertility and suboptimal agronomic practices. This study assessed how integrating nutrient management with apical bud manipulation influences cabbage growth, yield, and profitability in northwestern Ethiopia. A field experiment was conducted during the 2021/2022 season at two locations in East Gojjam Zone, Ethiopia, using a randomized complete block design in a 3&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;4 factorial arrangement with three bud levels (one, two, and three) and four farmyard manure (FYM) rates (0, 2.5, 5, and 7.5 t ha<sup>-&#x2009;1</sup>). Growth, yield, and quality traits were recorded and statistically analyzed. Significant interactions occurred between bud retention and FYM rates for all traits. The two-bud&#x2009;+&#x2009;5 t ha<sup>-&#x2009;1</sup> FYM treatment produced the highest marketable yield (41.8 t ha<sup>-&#x2009;1</sup>), total yield (43.1 t ha<sup>-&#x2009;1</sup>), and medium head size (31.8 t ha<sup>-&#x2009;1</sup>). Total yields at 2.5 and 7.5 t ha<sup>-&#x2009;1</sup> FYM were consistently lower across bud levels, with two buds yielding moderately at both rates, whereas one- and three-bud treatments resulted in further reductions reinforcing the superiority of the two-bud&#x2009;+&#x2009;5 t ha<sup>-&#x2009;1</sup> FYM combination. This treatment also generated the highest net return (1917.59 USD ha<sup>-&#x2009;1</sup>). Integrating moderate organic nutrient inputs with proper bud management improves cabbage yield and profitability. The application of 5 t ha&#x207b;&#xb9; FYM with two-bud retention is recommended for sustainable cabbage production in northwestern Ethiopia and comparable agro-ecologies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gelaye</LastName><ForeName>Yohannes</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6772-0198</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Agriculture and Natural Resources, Debre Markos University, P.O. Box 269, Amhara, Ethiopia. yohanes_gelaye@dmu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005308">Fertilizers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012987">Soil</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008372">Manure</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001937" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brassica</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000383" MajorTopicYN="Y">Agriculture</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000191" MajorTopicYN="N">economics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005308" MajorTopicYN="N">Fertilizers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000078622" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nutrients</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069599" MajorTopicYN="Y">Crop Production</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000191" MajorTopicYN="N">economics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018556" MajorTopicYN="N">Crops, Agricultural</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012987" MajorTopicYN="N">Soil</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008372" MajorTopicYN="N">Manure</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cabbage phenology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Head size distribution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Organic manure fertilizer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical approval: Field experiments were conducted with consent from landowners and Debre Markos University authorities, in compliance with ethical and institutional standards.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41735403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13031807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-41149-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-41149-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Singh, S. et al. Characterization and genetic analysis of OguCMS and doubled haploid based large genetic arsenal of Indian cauliflowers (<i>Brassica oleracea var. botrytis</i> L.) for morphological, reproductive and seed yield traits revealed their breeding potential. <i>Genet. Resour. Crop Evol.</i><b>68</b>, 1603&#x2013;1623. 10.1007/s10722-020-01090-4 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10722-020-01090-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallmann, E. et al. The nutritive value of organic and conventional white cabbage (<i>Brassica Oleracea L. Var. Capitata</i>) and anti-apoptotic activity in gastric adenocarcinoma cells of Sauerkraut juice produced therof. <i>J. Agric. Food Chem.</i><b>65</b>, 8171&#x2013;8183. 10.1021/acs.jafc.7b01078 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jafc.7b01078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28838245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mpumi, N., Machunda, R. S., Mtei, K. M. &amp; Ndakidemi, P. A. Selected insect pests of economic importance to Brassica oleracea, their control strategies and the potential threat to environmental pollution in Africa. <i>Sustainability</i><b>12</b>, 3824. 10.3390/su12093824 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su12093824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lounsbury, N. P., Warren, N. D., Wolfe, S. D. &amp; Smith, R. G. Investigating tarps to facilitate organic no-till cabbage production with high-residue cover crops. <i>Renew. Agric. Food Syst.</i><b>35</b>, 227&#x2013;233. 10.1017/S1742170518000509 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1742170518000509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelaye, Y. A systematic review on effects of nitrogen fertilizer levels on cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea var. capitata</i> L.) production in Ethiopia. <i>ScientificWorldJournal</i><b>2024</b>, 6086730. 10.1155/2024/6086730 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11074857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38715843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, D. K. Y. &amp; Thesis Effect of temperature and photoperiod on broccoli development, yield and quality in south-east Queensland. Ph.D. School of Land and Food, The University of Queensland, Australia (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha, C. et al. Response of cabbage to soil test-based fertilization coupled with different levels of drip irrigation in an inceptisol. <i>Irrig. Sci.</i><b>2021</b>, 1&#x2013;15. 10.1007/s00271-021-00761-z (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemayehu, Y. A., Asfaw, S. L. &amp; Terfie, T. A. Reusing urine and coffee processing wastewater as a nutrient source: effect on soil characteristics at optimum cabbage yield. <i>Environ. Technol. Innov.</i><b>23</b>, 101571. 10.1016/j.eti.2021.101571 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eti.2021.101571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray, L. R. et al. Brassica oleracea var. capitata f. alba: a review on its botany, traditional uses, phytochemistry and pharmacological activities. <i>Mini Rev. Med. Chem.</i><b>21</b>, 2399&#x2013;2417. 10.2174/1389557521666210111150036 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1389557521666210111150036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33430729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asomah, S., Anankware, J. P. &amp; Adjei, R. R. Impact of organic and inorganic fertilizers on the growth and yield of cabbage in Ghana. <i>Int. J. Hortic. Sci.</i><b>27</b>, 46&#x2013;49. 10.31421/ijhs/27/2021/8923 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31421/ijhs/27/2021/8923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherka, T. D. &amp; Shiferie, A. S. Intertemporal climate dynamics and trends in head cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea</i> L.) production in Ethiopia. <i>Discover Sustain.</i><b>6</b>, 715. 10.1007/s43621-025-01593-z (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43621-025-01593-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alula, M. &amp; Tesfaye, A. Survey and management of cabbage aphid (<i>Brevicoryne brassicae</i> L.) on cabbage using botanical extracts under irrigation condition at Dera District, North West, Ethiopia. <i>Stechnolock Plant. Biol. Res.</i><b>1</b> (1), 1&#x2013;23 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atnafu, D. Overview of different rate of nitrogen application on growth and yield components of head cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea. capitata</i> L.) in Ethiopia. <i>Am. J. Life Sci.</i><b>8</b>, 196&#x2013;200 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aleminew, &#xc0;. &amp; Alemayehu, M. Soil fertility depletion and its management options under crop production perspectives in Ethiopia. <i>Agric. Rev.</i><b>41</b>, 91&#x2013;105. 10.18805/ag.R-136 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18805/ag.R-136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yayeh, S. G., Alemayehu, M., Haileslassie, A. &amp; Dessalegn, Y. Assessment of small holder farmers garlic (<i>Allium sativum</i> L.) production practices under irrigated farming system in the Highlands of Ethiopia. <i>Afr. J. Agric. Res.</i><b>17</b>, 1172&#x2013;1179. 10.5897/AJAR2019.14033 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/AJAR2019.14033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chikowo, R., Zingore, S., Snapp, S. &amp; Johnston, A. Farm typologies, soil fertility variability and nutrient management in smallholder farming in Sub-Saharan Africa. <i>Nutr. Cycl. Agrosyst.</i><b>100</b>, 1&#x2013;18 (2014). https://izlik.org/JA43KX37NW</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10705-014-9632-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozai, T. et al. Toward commercial production of head vegetables in plant factories with artificial lighting. <i>Plant Factory Basics Appl. Adv.</i><b>2022</b>, 417&#x2013;34. 10.1016/B978-0-323-85152-7.00019-7 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arias, T., Niederhuth, C., McSteen, P. &amp; Pires, J. C. The molecular basis of Kale domestication: transcription profiling of leaves and meristems provides new insights into the evolution of a Brassica oleracea vegetative morphotype.<i> bioRxiv</i>10.3389/fpls.2021.637115 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7973465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33747016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar&#x142;&#xf3;g, P., Hlisnikovsk&#xfd;, L. &amp; Kunzov&#xe1;, E. Effect of digestate on soil organic carbon and plant-available nutrient content compared to cattle slurry and mineral fertilization. <i>Agronomy</i><b>10</b>, 379. 10.3390/agronomy10030379 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy10030379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, C. et al. Effects of organic and bacterial fertilizer application on cabbage characteristic and rhizosphere soil microorganisms. <i>Plant. Stress</i>. <b>18</b>, 101008. 10.1016/j.stress.2025.101008 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.stress.2025.101008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordey, T., Schwarz, D., Kenyon, L., Manickam, R. &amp; Huat, J. Tapping the potential of grafting to improve the performance of vegetable cropping systems in sub-Saharan Africa. A review. <i>Agron. Sustain. Dev.</i><b>40</b>, 1&#x2013;18. 10.1007/s13593-020-00628-1 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13593-020-00628-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferede, S., Yirga, C., Kehaliew, A., Agegnehu, G. &amp; Alemu, T. Farming systems characterization and analysis in east gojjam zone: implications for research and development (R&amp;D) Interventions. Research Report No.&#x202f;127. Ethiopian Institute of Agricultur Research (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LACK, H. W. The representation of plants. In <i>A Cultural History of Plants in the Nineteenth Century</i> (ed. Mabberley, D. J.) 171&#x2013;195 (Bloomsbury Academic, 2022). 10.5040/9781474207010.ch-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, M. et al. Effects of organic manure application with chemical fertilizers on nutrient absorption and yield of rice in Hunan of Southern China. <i>Agric. Sci. China</i>. <b>7</b>, 1245&#x2013;1252. 10.1016/S1671-2927(08)60171-6 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1671-2927(08)60171-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akinmutimi, A. &amp; Amaechi, C. Comparative effects of poultry manure, piggery manure and npk fertilizer on the growth, yield and nutrient content of okra (<i>Abelmoschus esculentus</i>). <i>Int. J. Curr. Res. Rev.</i><b>7</b>, 1 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeshiwas, Y. Effect of different rate of nitrogen fertilizer on the growth and yield of cabbage (<i>Brassica oleraceae</i> L.) at Debre Markos, North West Ethiopia. <i>Afr. J. Plant Sci.</i><b>11</b>, 276&#x2013;281 (2017). https://academicjournals.org/journal/AJPS/article-full-text/2C9AFA764748</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/AJPS2015.1330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warnock, D. F. &amp; Lash, H. Pinching impacts cut Poinsettia stem quality and profit potential. <i>HortScience</i><b>40</b>, 1123A. 10.21273/HORTSCI.40.4.1123A (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seble, G. B. Effects of integrated fertilizer application on soil properties and yield of maize (<i>Zea mays</i> L.) on Nitisols in Pawe District, Northwestern Ethiopia. <i>J. Agric. Environ. Sci.</i><b>9</b>(1), 13&#x2013;32. 10.4314/jaes.v9i1.2 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DV, P., Krishnamurthy, R. &amp; Naveen, D. Long-term effect of integrated nutrient management on soil nutrient status, content and uptake by finger millet crop in a typic kandiustalf of eastern dry zone of Karnataka. <i>Commun. Soil Sci. Plant Anal.</i><b>51</b>, 161&#x2013;174. 10.1080/00103624.2019.1695829 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00103624.2019.1695829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Site, A. H. M. &amp; Dar, B. <i>Amhara National Regional State Bureau of Agriculture. Bahir Dar</i> (Amhara National Regional State Bureau of Agriculture, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Program, C. E., Maize, I. &amp; Center, W. I. <i>From Agronomic Data to Farmer Recommendations: An Economics Training Manual</i> (CIMMYT, 1988). http://hdl.handle.net/10883/3842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoyos, M. Did the trade liberalization of the 1990s really boost economic growth? a critical replication of Estevadeordal and Taylor (2013). <i>Empir. Econ.</i><b>63</b>, 525&#x2013;548. 10.1007/s00181-021-02139-8 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidane, D. Assessment of production practices and effect of NP fertilizer rate on head yield and yield components of head cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea var. capitata</i> L.) under irrigation conditions in Lay Armacheho District, Amhara Region, Ethiopia. M.Sc. Thesis, College of Agriculture and Environmental Sciences, Bahir Dar University, Bahir Dar, Ethiopia (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelaye, Y. &amp; Tadele, E. Agronomic productivity and organic fertilizer rates on growth and yield performance of cabbage (Brassica oleracea var. capitata L.) in Northwestern Ethiopia. <i>ScientificWorldJournal</i><b>2022</b>, 2108401. 10.1155/2022/2108401 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9203243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35720159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belay, A. F. &amp; Gashaw, B. Evaluation of levels of nps fertilizer on head cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea var. capitata</i> L.) production during the two main growing seasons in Chiha district, Ethiopia. <i>Int. J. Agric. Nat. Sci.</i><b>16</b>, 231&#x2013;242 (2023). https://zenodo.org/records/10203781</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haque, K. et al. Yield and nutritional quality of cabbage as affected by nitrogen and phosphorus fertilization. <i>Bangladesh J. Sci. Ind. Res.</i><b>41</b>, 41&#x2013;46 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3329/bjsir.v41i1.267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, G. et al. Brassica coenospecies: a rich reservoir for genetic resistance to leaf spot caused by Alternaria brassicae. <i>Euphytica</i><b>125</b>, 411&#x2013;417 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1016050631673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahirwar, C. S. &amp; Nath, R. Organic Broccoli farming: a step towards doubling farmers&#x2019; income. <i>Biotica Res. Today</i>. <b>2</b>, 47&#x2013;50 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelalem, A., Tekalign, T. &amp; Nigussie, D. Response of potato (<i>Solanum tuberosum</i> L.) to different rates of nitrogen and phosphorus fertilization on vertisols at Debre Berhan, in the central highlands of Ethiopia. <i>Afr. J. Plant Sci.</i><b>3</b>, 016&#x2013;24 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahoo, B. B., Nayak, B. S., Mohanty, S. K. &amp; Khanda, C. Significance of bio-fertilizer incorporation with customized organic manures to reduce inorganic nutrients on growth dynamics, bulb yield and economics of Onion (<i>Allium cepa</i> L.) under the western undulating zone of Odisha. <i>Vegetos</i><b>2022</b>, 1&#x2013;12 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milon, A. R., Chang, S. W. &amp; Ravindran, B. Biochar amended compost maturity evaluation using commercial vegetable crops seedlings through phytotoxicity germination bioassay. <i>J. King Saud Univ.&#x2013;Sci.</i><b>34</b>, 101770 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jksus.2021.101770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayasurya, P., Chatterjee, S., Biswas, A., Viswanath, M. &amp; Roy, A. Low cost protected structures for off&#x2013;season vegetable production: a review. <i>Pharma Innov. J.</i><b>10</b> (7S), 778&#x2013;783 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeyabaskaran, K., Shirgure, P., Pandey, V., Srivastava, A. &amp; Uma, S. Fertigation in horticulture: a guarantee to economized quality production. <i>Indian J. Fertilis.</i><b>17</b> (4), 364&#x2013;383 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>inigaddara, G. <i>Plant and Animal Based Fertilizers and Pesticides</i> (Rajarata University of Sri Lanka, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, P., Abler, D., Lin, G., Sher, A. &amp; Quan, Q. Substituting organic fertilizer for chemical fertilizer: evidence from apple growers in China. <i>Land</i><b>10</b>, 858 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/land10080858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umar, W. et al. Nitrogen and phosphorus use efficiency in agroecosystems. <i>Resourc. Use Efficiency Agric.</i><b>2020</b>, 213&#x2013;257 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angmo, P., Dolma, T., Namgail, D., Chaurasia, O. &amp; Stobdan, T. Growing cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea var capitata</i> L.) in cold winter under passive solar greenhouse in trans-Himalayan Ladakh Region (2020). https://publicationsdrdo.in/index.php/dlsj/article/view/15817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhamala, N. et al. Effect of integrated management of fym and urea in cabbage grown on clay loam soil, Dang, Nepal. <i>J. Clean. WAS (JCleanWAS)</i>. <b>4</b>, 32&#x2013;35. 10.26480/jcleanwas.01.2020.32.35 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26480/jcleanwas.01.2020.32.35</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaitov, B. et al. Impact of organic manure on growth, nutrient content and yield of chilli pepper under various temperature environments. <i>Int. J. Environ. Res. Public. Health</i><b>2019</b>, 16. 10.3390/ijerph16173031 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6747139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31438592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siswanti, D. U. &amp; Riesty, O. S. Effects of biofertilizer and manure application on growth rate and chlorophyll content of spinach (<i>Amaranthus tricolor</i> L.) under salinity stress condition. In <i>BIO Web of Conferences: EDP Sciences</i> 05003 (2021). 10.1051/bioconf/20213305003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Q., Song, M., Kou, L., Li, Q. &amp; Wang, H. Contrasting effects of nitrogen and phosphorus additions on nitrogen competition between coniferous and broadleaf seedlings. <i>Sci. Total Environ.</i><b>861</b>, 160661. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.160661 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.160661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36473665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chintagunta, A. D., Kumar, S. J., Krishna, M., Addanki, M. &amp; Kumar, N. Studies on bioconversion of agri-waste to biomanure. <i>Indian J. Ecol.</i><b>47</b>, 116&#x2013;121 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi, K., Heidari, G., Khalesro, S. &amp; Sohrabi, Y. Soil management, microorganisms and organic matter interactions: a review. <i>Afr. J. Biotechnol.</i><b>10</b>, 19840&#x2013;19849 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sindesi, O. A. Water and nutrient retention under Swiss chard (<i>Beta vulgaris var. cicla</i>) and cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea var. capitata</i> L.) cultivated in soil amended with zeolite (Master&#x2019;s thesis). Cape Peninsula University of Technology 1-119 (2020). http://hdl.handle.net/20.500.11838/3133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue, L. et al. Heterotic prediction of hybrid performance based on genome-wide SNP markers and the phenotype of parental inbred lines in heading Chinese cabbage (<i>Brassica rapa</i> L. ssp. pekinensis). <i>Sci. Hort.</i><b>296</b>, 110907 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2022.110907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sindhu, V., Chatterjee, R. &amp; Mishra, S. Response of different organic nutrient management schedules on productivity, head quality, nutrient uptake and economics of organic cabbage. <i>Vegetable Sci.</i><b>48</b>, 56&#x2013;61 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.61180/vegsci.2021.v48.i1.07</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamid, B. et al. Bacterial plant biostimulants: a sustainable way towards improving growth, productivity, and health of crops. <i>Sustainability</i><b>13</b>, 2856 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su13052856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim, S. L., Wu, T. Y., Lim, P. N. &amp; Shak, K. P. Y. The use of vermicompost in organic farming: overview, effects on soil and economics. <i>J. Sci. Food. Agric.</i><b>95</b>, 1143&#x2013;1156 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jsfa.6849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25130895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua, W. et al. Manure application increased crop yields by promoting nitrogen use efficiency in the soils of 40-year soybean-maize rotation. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>10</b>, 14882. 10.1038/s41598-020-71932-9 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-71932-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32913265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad, H. et al. A paradigm shift towards beneficial microbes enhancing the efficiency of organic and inorganic nitrogen sources for a sustainable environment. <i>Land</i><b>12</b>, 680 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheoran, S. et al. Long-term application of FYM and fertilizer N improve soil fertility and enzyme activity in 51st wheat cycle under pearl millet-wheat. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 21695 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-72076-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11408662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39289455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. et al. Long-term combined application of organic and inorganic fertilizers increases crop yield sustainability by improving soil fertility in maize&#x2013;wheat cropping systems. <i>J. Integr. Agric.</i><b>24</b>, 290&#x2013;305 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, X. et al. Effects of continuous cropping and application of bio-organic fertilizer on photosynthetic performance, dry matter accumulation and distribution of sugar beet. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 1512 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11717948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39789070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadeem Shah, M. et al. Organic fertilizer sources improve the yield and quality attributes of maize (<i>Zea mays</i> L.) hybrids by improving soil properties and nutrient uptake under drought stress. <i>J. King Saud Univ. - Sci.</i><b>35</b>, 102570 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jksus.2023.102570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begum, N. et al. Role of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi in plant growth regulation: implications in abiotic stress tolerance. <i>Front. Plant Sci.</i><b>10</b>, 2019. 10.3389/fpls.2019.01068 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6761482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31608075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fei-Baffoe, B., Amo-Asare, J., Sulemana, A. &amp; Miezah, K. Levels of lead, copper, and zinc in cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea sp</i>.) and Lettuce (<i>Lactuca sativa sp</i>.) grown on soil amended with sewage sludge. <i>J. Environ. Public Health</i>10.1155/2021/8386218 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8032524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33868411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas, C. L., Acquah, G. E., Whitmore, A. P., McGrath, S. P. &amp; Haefele, S. M. The effect of different organic fertilizers on yield and soil and crop nutrient concentrations. <i>Agronomy</i><b>9</b>, 776 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy9120776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkar, D. et al. Optimizing nutrient use efficiency, productivity, energetics, and economics of red cabbage following mineral fertilization and biopriming with compatible rhizosphere microbes. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>11</b>, 1&#x2013;14 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-95092-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8333308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34344947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacjan Mar&#x161;i&#x107;, N. et al. Nitrogen and sulphur fertilisation for marketable yields of cabbage (Brassica oleracea L. var. Capitata), leaf nitrate and glucosinolates and nitrogen losses studied in a field experiment in Central Slovenia. <i>Plants</i><b>10</b>, 1304 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants10071304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8309008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34199139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Li, J., Zhou, D., Song, J. &amp; Gao, J. Nitrogen uptake and distribution in different Chinese cabbage genotypes under low nitrogen stress. <i>Int. J. Mol. Sci.</i><b>23</b>, 1573 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23031573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8836141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35163497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Z. et al. Effects of nutrient deficiency on crop yield and soil nutrients under winter wheat&#x2013;summer maize rotation system in the North China Plain. <i>Agronomy</i><b>14</b>, 2690 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy14112690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, N. et al. Micronutrients and their effects on Horticultural crop quality, productivity and sustainability. <i>Sci. Hort.</i><b>323</b>, 112512 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2023.112512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dotaniya, M. et al. Determining application rates of FYM and pressmud to improve soil health properties in salt degraded soils. <i>PloS one</i>. <b>20</b>, e0317463 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0317463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11785300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39888961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzouk, S. H., Kwaslema, D. R., Omar, M. M. &amp; Mohamed, S. H. Harnessing the power of soil microbes: their dual impact in integrated nutrient management and mediating climate stress for sustainable rice crop production a systematic review. <i>Heliyon</i><b>11</b>, e41158 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e41158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11699367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39758363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babla, M. et al. Value-added products as soil conditioners for sustainable agriculture. <i>Resourc. Conserv. Recycl.</i><b>178</b>, 106079 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saba, M., Abo-Elyousr, K. A. &amp; AL-Solaimani, S. G. Organic production of cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea</i> L.) for agricultural sustainability and healthy nutrition: an overview. <i>J. Appl. Nat. Sci.</i><b>2025</b>, 17. 10.31018/jans.v17i1.6335 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhakar, M. et al. Effect of organic farming practices on yield and quality of cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea var. capitata</i> L.). <i>Int. J. Curr. Microbiol. App Sci.</i><b>9</b>, 615&#x2013;620 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20546/ijcmas.2020.907.069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matisic, M., Dugan, I. &amp; Bogunovic, I. Challenges in sustainable agriculture&#x2014;the role of organic amendments. <i>Agriculture</i><b>14</b>, 643 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture14040643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulla, M. et al. Effects of long-term application of farmyard manure on soil hydro-thermal properties in semi-arid region of Northern India. <i>Commun. Soil Sci. Plant Anal.</i><b>56</b>, 1978&#x2013;1994 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00103624.2025.2488401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, R. C. &amp; Banik, P. Vermicompost and fertilizer application: Effect on productivity and profitability of baby corn (<i>Zea Mays</i> L.) and soil health. <i>Compost Sci. Utiliz.</i><b>22</b>, 83&#x2013;92 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1065657X.2014.895456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raina, S. A., Bhat, R. A., Qadri, H. &amp; Dutta, A. Values of biofertilizers for sustainable management in agricultural industries. <i>Bioremed. Biotechnol.</i><b>2</b>, 121&#x2013;37 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ananda, A., Devi, A., Barik, S., Konthoujam, J. &amp; Bairwa, M. Effect of growth, physiological aspects and yield of cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea</i> L. cv Rareball) in Knol khol and broad bean intercropping system under Imphal West condition. <i>Int. J. Curr. Microbiol. App Sci.</i><b>7</b>, 1111&#x2013;1117 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20546/ijcmas.2018.710.122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, B., Chaubey, T., Upadhyay, D., Jha, A. &amp; Pandey, S. Morphological characterization for DUS testing of cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea var. capitata</i> L.) cultivars. <i>Progressive Hortic.</i><b>44</b>, 32&#x2013;36 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur, P. &amp; Singh, S. Evaluation of cytoplasmic male sterile (CMS) progenies and maintainer lines for yield and horticultural traits in cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea var. capitata</i> L). <i>SABRAO J. Breed. Genet.</i><b>47</b>, 29&#x2013;39 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. et al. Multifaceted ability of organic fertilizers to improve crop productivity and abiotic stress tolerance: review and perspectives. <i>Agronomy</i><b>14</b>, 1141 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy14061141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouda, B. A. &amp; Mahadeen, A. Y. Effect of fertilizers on growth, yield, yield components, quality and certain nutrient contents in broccoli (<i>Brassica olearacea</i> L). <i>Int. J. Agric. Biol.</i><b>10</b>, 627&#x2013;632 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teshome, S. &amp; Amide, A. Response of head cabbage (<i>Brassica olearacea</i> L.) yield to application of different rates of inorganic nitrogen and phosphorus fertilizers at bore, Southern Ethiopia. <i>Am. J. BioScience</i>. <b>5</b>, 18&#x2013;28 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackah, M. A. Mineral nitrogen and salicylic acid rates and their effects on yield, quality and Alternaria blight incidence in cabbage (MPhil thesis). University of Cape Coast (2021). http://hdl.handle.net/123456789/6457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko&#x142;ota, E. &amp; Chohura, P. Control of head size and nutritional value of cabbage by plant population and nitrogen fertilization. <i>Acta Scient. Polonorum Hortorum Cultus</i>. <b>14</b>, 75&#x2013;85 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva, A. L. B. R., Candian, J. S., Zotarelli, L., Coolong, T. &amp; Christensen, C. Nitrogen fertilizer management and cultivar selection for cabbage production in the southeastern United States. <i>HortTechnology</i><b>30</b>, 685&#x2013;691 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21273/HORTTECH04690-20</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J., Li, J., Lv, K. &amp; He, D. Impacts of fertilization regimes on cabbage growth based on the CROPGRO model. <i>HortScience</i><b>60</b>, 715&#x2013;723 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21273/HORTSCI18060-24</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munhuweyi, K., Opara, U. L. &amp; Sigge, G. Postharvest losses of cabbages from retail to consumer and the socio-economic and environmental impacts. <i>Br. Food J.</i><b>118</b>, 286&#x2013;300 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/BFJ-08-2014-0280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, J-M. et al. Current status of vegetable grafting: diffusion, grafting techniques, automation. <i>Sci. Hort.</i><b>127</b>, 93&#x2013;105 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2010.08.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kudama, G., Tolera, T. &amp; Gebeyehu, L. Good farm practices and improved processing technology of enset for sustainable hunger solution in Ethiopia. <i>J. Innov. Entrepreneurship</i>. <b>11</b>, 1&#x2013;20 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13731-022-00210-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabor, G. et al. Effects of spacing on yield and head characteristics of cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea var. capitata</i> L.) in two agro-ecologies of Ethiopia. <i>Afr. J. Agric. Res.</i><b>18</b>, 322&#x2013;329 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/AJAR2022.15993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse, T., Dechassa, N., Bayu, W. &amp; Gebeyehu, S. Effects of farmyard manure and inorganic fertilizer application on soil physico-chemical properties and nutrient balance in rain-fed lowland rice ecosystem. <i>Am. J. Plant. Sci.</i><b>4</b>, 309&#x2013;316 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ajps.2013.42041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhamala, N. et al. Effect of integrated management of fym and urea in cabbage grown on clay loam soil, dang, Nepal. <i>J. Clean. WAS</i>. <b>4</b>, 32&#x2013;35 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26480/jcleanwas.01.2020.32.35</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frossard, E., Bucher, M., M&#xe4;chler, F., Mozafar, A. &amp; Hurrell, R. Potential for increasing the content and bioavailability of Fe, Zn and Ca in plants for human nutrition. <i>J. Sci. Food. Agric.</i><b>80</b>, 861&#x2013;879 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1097-0010(20000515)80:7&lt;861::AID-JSFA601&gt;3.0.CO;2-P</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olaniyi, J. &amp; Ojetayo, A. Effect of fertilizer types on the growth and yield of two cabbage varieties. <i>J. Anim. Plant. Sci.</i><b>12</b>, 1573&#x2013;1582 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bir, M. Effects of organic manures on growth and yield of cabbage. <i>J. Agric. Food Environ.</i><b>3</b>, 2708&#x2013;5694 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha, C. et al. Response of cabbage to soil test-based fertilization coupled with different levels of drip irrigation in an inceptisol. <i>Irrig. Sci.</i><b>40</b>, 239&#x2013;253 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00271-021-00761-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue, L. et al. Genetic dissection of heterotic loci associated with plant weight by Graded pool-seq in heading Chinese cabbage (<i>Brassica rapa</i> L). <i>Planta</i><b>255</b>, 1&#x2013;16. 10.1007/s00425-022-03880-9 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00425-022-03880-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35575830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>