<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41918758</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2516-0230</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nanoscale advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nanoscale Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Multifunctional PAA- and PEG-modified Co<sub>3</sub>V<sub>2</sub>O<sub>8</sub> nanoparticles for enhanced RhB degradation, OER activity, and antibacterial activity: experimental validation and computational insight.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/d5na01130b</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Developing earth-abundant, cost-effective, sustainable and efficient multifunctional catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), catalytic dye degradation, and antibacterial activity is extremely challenging. Herein, a novel ternary heterogeneous catalyst, polyacrylic acid/polyethylene glycol-cobalt vanadate nanoparticles (PAA/PEG-Co<sub>3</sub>V<sub>2</sub>O<sub>8</sub> NPs), was synthesized using a co-precipitation method. This study reported the multifunctionality of PAA/PEG-Co<sub>3</sub>V<sub>2</sub>O<sub>8</sub> in degrading RhB, enhancing OER activity, and inhibiting multiple drug-resistant <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> (MDR <i>S. aureus</i>), with molecular docking analysis providing insights into binding interactions. The samples were comprehensively analyzed using an array of analytical techniques, including XRD, SAED, FTIR spectroscopy, UV-Vis spectroscopy, TEM, HRTEM, and EDS. The electrochemical activity of the prepared material was evaluated by linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS). The optimized sample exhibited a maximum degradation of 96.34% in an acidic medium within 10 minutes and demonstrated minimal overpotentials of 270, 299, and 362 mV at 30, 50, and 100 mA cm<sup>-2</sup>, respectively. The lowest Tafel slope and charge-transfer resistance indicated the superior OER performance. The optimized material showed a maximum inhibition zone of 8.25 &#xb1; 0.93 mm against MDR <i>S. aureus</i>. The bactericidal action of PAA/PEG-Co<sub>3</sub>V<sub>2</sub>O<sub>8</sub> NPs was further elucidated through molecular docking, which substantiated their role in the inhibition of topoisomerase II DNA gyrase and dihydrofolate reductase (DHFR) in <i>S. aureus</i>. These findings demonstrate the role of PAA and PEG in improving the overall activity of Co<sub>3</sub>V<sub>2</sub>O<sub>8</sub>, yielding a pathway for fabricating an efficient, cost-effective, and sustainable material for environmental remediation and water-splitting applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>This journal is &#xa9; The Royal Society of Chemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Munir</LastName><ForeName>Arbab</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics, Government College University, Faisalabad Pakpattan Road Sahiwal Punjab 57000 Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imran</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Research Center for Hydrogen Technologies and Carbon Management (IRC-HTCM), King Fahd University of Petroleum &amp; Minerals Dhahran 31261 Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahzadi</LastName><ForeName>Iram</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Pharmacy, University of Management and Technology Lahore 54770 Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haider</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2876-3996</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences, Faculty of Veterinary and Animal Sciences, Muhammad Nawaz Shareef, University of Agriculture Multan 66000 Punjab Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mateen</LastName><ForeName>Zernab</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Solar Cell Applications Research Lab, Department of Physics, Government College University Lahore Lahore 54000 Punjab Pakistan dr.muhammadikram@gcu.edu.pk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ul-Hamid</LastName><ForeName>Anwar</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0259-301X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Core Research Facilities, King Fahd University of Petroleum &amp; Minerals Dhahran 31261 Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Albassami</LastName><ForeName>Norah A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemistry Department, Faculty of Science, King Khalid University P. O. Box 9004 Abha 61413 Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ikram</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7741-789X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Solar Cell Applications Research Lab, Department of Physics, Government College University Lahore Lahore 54000 Punjab Pakistan dr.muhammadikram@gcu.edu.pk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nanoscale Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101738708</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2516-0230</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41918758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13033997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d5na01130b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">d5na01130b</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kumari H. Sonia S. Ranga R. Chahal S. Devi S. Sharma S. Kumar S. Kumar P. Kumar S. A review on photocatalysis used for wastewater treatment: dye degradation. Water, Air, Soil Pollut. 2023;234:349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10212744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37275322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge M. Zhu N. Zhao Y. Li J. Liu L. Sunlight-assisted degradation of dye pollutants in Ag3PO4 suspension. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2012;51:5167&#x2013;5173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L. Zhang B. Zhang Y. He Y. Huang L. Tan S. Cai X. Simultaneous removal of cationic and anionic dyes from environmental water using montmorillonite-pillared graphene oxide. J. Chem. Eng. Data. 2015;60:1270&#x2013;1278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasnat M. Siddiquey I. Nuruddin A. Comparative photocatalytic studies of degradation of a cationic and an anionic dye. Dyes Pigm. 2005;66:185&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue Y. Hou K. Chen J. Cheng W. Wu Q. Han J. Jiang J. Ag/AgBr/AgVO3 photocatalyst-embedded polyacrylonitrile/polyamide/chitosan nanofiltration membrane for integrated filtration and degradation of RhB. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2022;14:24708&#x2013;24719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35594189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H. Park S. H. Park Y.-K. Kim B. H. Kim S.-J. Jung S.-C. Rapid destruction of the rhodamine B using TiO2 photocatalyst in the liquid phase plasma. Chem. Cent. J. 2013;7:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3847586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24041151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centi G. Ciambelli P. Perathoner S. Russo P. Environmental catalysis: trends and outlook. Catal. Today. 2002;75:3&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyun S. Ahilan V. Kim H. Shanmugam S. The influence of Co3V2O8 morphology on the oxygen evolution reaction activity and stability. Electrochem. Commun. 2016;63:44&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Shafie M. Hydrogen production by water electrolysis technologies: A review. Results Eng. 2023;20:101426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M. A. Zhao H. Zou W. Chen Z. Cao W. Fang J. Xu J. Zhang L. Zhang J. Recent progresses in electrocatalysts for water electrolysis. Electrochem. Energy Rev. 2018;1:483&#x2013;530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu K. Lyu C. Cheng J. Guo Z. Li H. Zhu X. Lau W. M. Zheng J. Modulating electronic structure by etching strategy to construct NiSe2/Ni0. 85Se heterostructure for urea-assisted hydrogen evolution reaction. Small. 2024;20:2304390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37845029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawar S. A. Talekar S. V. Sawant P. D. Patole S. P. Yadav H. M. Gunjakar J. L. 2D-1D Self-Assembly of Water Delaminated Co-Fe-LDH Nanosheets and CNTs via Exfoliation-Restacking Approach for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction. Small. 2025:e06554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40911771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z. Duan X. Wei W. Wang S. Ni B.-J. Iridium-based nanomaterials for electrochemical water splitting. Nano Energy. 2020;78:105270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maia N. L. De Barros M. De Oliveira L. L. Cardoso S. A. Dos Santos M. H. Pieri F. A. Ramalho T. C. Da Cunha E. F. Moreira M. A. Synergism of plant compound with traditional antimicrobials against Streptococcus spp. isolated from bovine mastitis. Front. Microbiol. 2018;9:1203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5998740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29928266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haider A. Ijaz M. Ali S. Haider J. Imran M. Majeed H. Shahzadi I. Ali M. M. Khan J. A. Ikram M. Green synthesized phytochemically (Zingiber officinale and Allium sativum) reduced nickel oxide nanoparticles confirmed bactericidal and catalytic potential. Nanoscale Res. Lett. 2020;15:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7052104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32124107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girma A. Tamir D. Prevalence of bovine mastitis and its associated risk factors among dairy cows in Ethiopia during 2005&#x2013;2022: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Vet. Med. Int. 2022;2022:7775197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9509276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36164492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Q. Qin W. Chu J.-F. Novel Co3(1&#x2013;x) Fe3x V2O8 Nanoparticles as Highly Active and Noble-Metal-Free Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction. Energy Fuels. 2020;34:15019&#x2013;15025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng Y. Li Y. Yu D. Meng Y. N. Wu Y. Zhao X. Liu X. The Microwave-Assisted Hydrothermal Synthesis of CoV2O6 and Co3V2O8 with Morphology Tuning by pH Adjustments for Supercapacitor Applications. ChemistrySelect. 2019;4:956&#x2013;962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang G. Cui H. Yang G. Wang C. Self-assembly of Co3V2O8 multilayered nanosheets: controllable synthesis, excellent Li-storage properties, and investigation of electrochemical mechanism. ACS Nano. 2014;8:4474&#x2013;4487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24684444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y. Liu Y. Du X. Han R. Ding Y. Hexagonal assembly of Co3V2O8 nanoparticles acting as an efficient catalyst for visible light-driven water oxidation. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2014;2:19308&#x2013;19314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajid M. M. Amin N. Shad N. A. Javed Y. Zhang Z. Hydrothermal fabrication of monoclinic bismuth vanadate (m-BiVO4) nanoparticles for photocatalytic degradation of toxic organic dyes. Mater. Sci. Eng., B. 2019;242:83&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T. Zhao L. He Y. Cai J. Luo M. Lin J. Synthesis of g-C3N4/SmVO4 composite photocatalyst with improved visible light photocatalytic activities in RhB degradation. Appl. Catal., B. 2013;129:255&#x2013;263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X. Hu C. Preparation and visible-light photocatalytic activity of Ag3VO4 powders. J. Solid State Chem. 2007;180:725&#x2013;732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simo A. Drah M. Sibuyi N. Nkosi M. Meyer M. Maaza M. Hydrothermal synthesis of cobalt-doped vanadium oxides: Antimicrobial activity study. Ceram. Int. 2018;44:7716&#x2013;7722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghiyasiyan-Arani M. Masjedi-Arani M. Size controllable synthesis of cobalt vanadate nanostructures with enhanced photocatalytic activity for the degradation of organic dyes. J. Mol. Catal. A: Chem. 2016;425:31&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeidi S. S. Sanati P. Rezaei G. Vaseghi B. Synthesis and improving antibacterial effectiveness of Ag/Co3V2O8 nanocomposites by graphene oxide for biomedical applications. Mater. Sci. Eng., B. 2024;306:117457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi F. Rahimi-Nasrabadi M. Daneshmehr M. Eghbali-Arani M. Synthesis, characterization, and investigation of magnetic, photocatalytic and antibacterial properties of TbVO 4 nanoparticles. J. Mater. Sci.: Mater. Electron. 2017;28:14362&#x2013;14368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anandan M. Dinesh S. Krishnakumar N. Balamurugan K. Improved photocatalytic properties and anti-bacterial activity of size reduced ZnO nanoparticles via PEG-assisted precipitation route. J. Mater. Sci.: Mater. Electron. 2016;27:12517&#x2013;12526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang H. Jo E.-H. Jang H. D. Kim T.-O. Synthesis of PEG-modified TiO2&#x2013;InVO4 nanoparticles via combustion method and photocatalytic degradation of methylene blue. Mater. Lett. 2013;92:202&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradi S. Vossoughi M. Feilizadeh M. Zakeri S. M. E. Mohammadi M. M. Rashtchian D. Yoosefi Booshehri A. Photocatalytic degradation of dibenzothiophene using La/PEG-modified TiO 2 under visible light irradiation. Res. Chem. Intermed. 2015;41:4151&#x2013;4167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhag S. Tordera D. Deydier T. Lu J. LiU X. Khranovskyy V. Hultman L. Willander M. Jonsson M. Nur O. Low-temperature growth of polyethylene glycol-doped BiZn2VO6 nanocompounds with enhanced photoelectrochemical properties. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2017;5:1112&#x2013;1119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kausar A. Poly (acrylic acid) nanocomposites: Design of advanced materials. J. Plast. Film Sheeting. 2021;37:409&#x2013;428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y. Li Y. Zhang Y. Mu C. Zhou J. Zhang W. Shi B. Nonswelling silica&#x2013;poly (acrylic acid) composite for efficient and simultaneous removal of cationic dye, heavy metal, and surfactant-stabilized emulsion from wastewater. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2020;59:3383&#x2013;3393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhosale M. Morankar P. J. Lee Y. Seo H. Jeon C.-W. Electropolymerized PAA as a Functional Matrix for CeO2-NiO Hybrid Electrocatalysts for Efficient Water Oxidation. Polymers. 2025;17:2631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12526815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41096274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panneerselvam P. Singh C. Jayaraj S. K. Doulassiramane T. Padmanaban R. Samal A. K. Mohan S. Jadhav A. H. Unveiling the impact of oxygen vacancies in engineered bimetallic oxides for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction: insights from experimental and theoretical approaches. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2024;12:19149&#x2013;19167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaik M. R. Kuniyil M. Khan M. Ahmad N. Al-Warthan A. Siddiqui M. R. H. Adil S. F. Modified polyacrylic acid-zinc composites: Synthesis, characterization and biological activity. Molecules. 2016;21:292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6273445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26938511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urooj I. Noor M. Shah W. A. Arfan M. Wahab M. A. Abdala A. Sohail M. Solid-State Engineered Fe-CoMoO4 with a Defect-Rich Structure: Trimetallic Synergy for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction. Energy Fuels. 2025;39(36):17651&#x2013;17660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergey D. H., Bergey's Manual of Determinative Bacteriology, Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, 1994</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer A. Kirby W. Sherris J. C. Turck M. Antibiotic susceptibility testing by a standardized single disk method. Am. J. Clin. Pathol. 1966;45:493&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5325707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adzitey F. Yussif S. Ayamga R. Zuberu S. Addy F. Adu-Bonsu G. Huda N. Kobun R. Antimicrobial susceptibility and molecular characterization of Escherichia coli recovered from milk and related samples. Microorganisms. 2022;10:1335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9320388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35889054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis I. and James S., Performance Standards for Antimicrobial Susceptibility Testing, 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwalokun B. Ogunledun A. Ogbolu D. Bamiro S. Jimi-Omojola J. In vitro antimicrobial properties of aqueous garlic extract against multidrug-resistant bacteria and Candida species from Nigeria. J. Med. Food. 2004;7:327&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15383227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rayam P. Polkam N. Kuntala N. Banothu V. Anantaraju H. S. Perumal Y. Balasubramanian S. Anireddy J. S. Design and synthesis of oxaprozin-1, 3, 4-oxadiazole hybrids as potential anticancer and antibacterial agents. J. Heterocycl. Chem. 2020;57:1071&#x2013;1082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazzaro F. Caliendo G. Arnesi G. Veronesi A. Sarzi P. Fratianni F. Comparative content of some bioactive compounds in two varieties of Capsicum annuum L. sweet pepper and evaluation of their antimicrobial and mutagenic activities. J. Food Biochem. 2009;33:852&#x2013;868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahzadi I. Islam M. Saeed H. Haider A. Shahzadi A. Haider J. Ahmed N. Ul-Hamid A. Nabgan W. Ikram M. Formation of biocompatible MgO/cellulose grafted hydrogel for efficient bactericidal and controlled release of doxorubicin. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2022;220:1277&#x2013;1286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36030978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bax B. D. Chan P. F. Eggleston D. S. Fosberry A. Gentry D. R. Gorrec F. Giordano I. Hann M. M. Hennessy A. Hibbs M. Type IIA topoisomerase inhibition by a new class of antibacterial agents. Nature. 2010;466:935&#x2013;940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20686482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oefner C. Parisi S. Schulz H. Lociuro S. Dale G. E. Inhibitory properties and X-ray crystallographic study of the binding of AR-101, AR-102 and iclaprim in ternary complexes with NADPH and dihydrofolate reductase from Staphylococcus aureus. Acta Crystallogr., Sect. D: Biol. Crystallogr. 2009;65:751&#x2013;757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low W. H. Siong C. W. Chia C. H. Lim S. S. Khiew P. S. A facile synthesis of graphene/Co3V2O8 nanocomposites and their enhanced charge storage performance in electrochemical capacitors. J. Sci.: Adv. Mater. Devices. 2019;4:515&#x2013;523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad M. B. Tay M. Y. Shameli K. Hussein M. Z. Lim J. J. Green synthesis and characterization of silver/chitosan/polyethylene glycol nanocomposites without any reducing agent. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2011;12:4872&#x2013;4884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3179138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21954331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik R. L. Narsaiah T. B. Justin P. Kumar A. N. Somashekar M. Raghavendra N. Ravikumar C. Khan A. A. Santosh M. Hydrothermally synthesized cobalt vanadate nanoparticles for photocatalytic degradation of Fast Orange Red dye and supercapacitor applications. Mater. Sci. Eng., B. 2023;298:116861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik L. R., Justin P. and Narsaiah T. B., Controllable synthesis of cobalt vanadate nanostructure materials for direct methanol fuel cell applications, Proceedings of the International Conference on Advances in Chemical Engineering (AdChE), 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L. Chang S. Lu X. Han T. Jin R. Zhao T. Fang D. Xie M. Wang M. Yi J. Vapor phosphorus-coated cobalt vanadate as a high-performance anode for a lithium-ion battery. J. Solid State Electrochem. 2022;26:917&#x2013;927.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik R. L. Narsaiah T. B. Justin P. Hydrothermal synthesis and characterization of cobalt vanadate nanoparticles for supercapacitor applications. Mater. Today: Proc. 2023 doi: 10.1016/j.matpr.2023.05.725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2023.05.725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali A. M. Ghazwani N. A. Algarni H. Ismail A. A. Synthesis of ZnO&#x2013;SnO2 nanocomposites: impact of polyethylene glycol on morphological, luminescence and photocatalytic properties. Res. Chem. Intermed. 2019;45:3089&#x2013;3106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jose A. Sunaja Devi K. R. Pinheiro D. Lakshmi Narayana S. Electrochemical synthesis, photodegradation and antibacterial properties of PEG capped zinc oxide nanoparticles. J. Photochem. Photobiol., B. 2018;187:25&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30096540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skrabania K. Miasnikova A. Bivigou-Koumba A. M. Zehm D. Laschewsky A. Examining the UV-vis absorption of RAFT chain transfer agents and their use for polymer analysis. Polym. Chem. 2011;2:2074&#x2013;2083.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arasi S. E. Ranjithkumar R. Devendran P. Krishnakumar M. Arivarasan A. Studies on electrochemical mechanism of nanostructured cobalt vanadate electrode material for pseudocapacitors. J. Energy Storage. 2021;41:102986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali R. N. Naz H. Li J. Zhu X. Liu P. Xiang B. Band gap engineering of transition metal (Ni/Co) codoped in zinc oxide (ZnO) nanoparticles. J. Alloys Compd. 2018;744:90&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imran M. Haider A. Shahzadi I. Moeen S. Ul-Hamid A. Nabgan W. Shahzadi A. Alshahrani T. Ikram M. Polyvinylpyrrolidone and chitosan-coated magnetite (Fe3O4) nanoparticles for catalytic and antimicrobial activity with molecular docking analysis. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2023;11:110088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui H.-J. Huang H.-Z. Yuan B. Fu M.-L. Decolorization of RhB dye by manganese oxides: effect of crystal type and solution pH. Geochem. Trans. 2015;16:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4514904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26213493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan T. S. Thomas M. Natarajan K. Bajaj H. C. Tayade R. J. Study on UV-LED/TiO2 process for degradation of Rhodamine B dye. Chem. Eng. J. 2011;169:126&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laouini A. Bouafia A. Laouini S. E. Mohammed H. A. Tedjani M. L. Alharthi F. Abdullah J. A. A. Boosted Antioxidant and Photocatalytic Power: Reusable PEG-Coated Iron Oxide Nanocomposites for Effective Cephalexin and BCB Dye Degradation. J. Cluster Sci. 2024:1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamal F. Ikram M. Haider A. Ul-Hamid A. Ijaz M. Nabgan W. Haider J. Shahzadi I. Facile synthesis of silver and polyacrylic acid doped magnesium oxide nanostructure for photocatalytic dye degradation and bactericidal behavior. Appl. Nanosci. 2022;12:2409&#x2013;2419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alobaid A. Wang C. Adomaitis R. A. Mechanism and Kinetics of HER and OER on NiFe LDH Films in an Alkaline Electrolyte. J. Electrochem. Soc. 2018;165:J3395&#x2013;J3404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseinkhani P. Zand A. Imani S. Rezayi M. Rezaei Zarchi S. Determining the antibacterial effect of ZnO nanoparticle against the pathogenic bacterium, Shigella dysenteriae (type 1) Int. J. Nano Dimens. 2011;1:279&#x2013;285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed B. Solanki B. Zaidi A. Khan M. S. Musarrat J. Bacterial toxicity of biomimetic green zinc oxide nanoantibiotic: insights into ZnONP uptake and nanocolloid&#x2013;bacteria interface. Toxicol. Res. 2019;8:246&#x2013;261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6417486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30997024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali K. Ahmed B. Ansari S. M. Saquib Q. Al-Khedhairy A. A. Dwivedi S. Alshaeri M. Khan M. S. Musarrat J. Comparative in situ ROS mediated killing of bacteria with bulk analogue, Eucalyptus leaf extract (ELE)-capped and bare surface copper oxide nanoparticles. Mater. Sci. Eng., C. 2019;100:747&#x2013;758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30948112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dizaj S. M. Lotfipour F. Barzegar-Jalali M. Zarrintan M. H. Adibkia K. Antimicrobial activity of the metals and metal oxide nanoparticles. Mater. Sci. Eng., C. 2014;44:278&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25280707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayanetti M. Thambiliyagodage C. Liyanaarachchi H. Ekanayake G. Mendis A. Usgodaarachchi L. In vitro influence of PEG functionalized ZnO&#x2013;CuO nanocomposites on bacterial growth. Sci. Rep. 2024;14:1293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10788344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38221550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahzad H. Imran M. Haider A. Naz S. Umar E. Ul-Hamid A. Nabgan W. Algaradah M. M. Fouda A. M. Haider J. Catalytic and antimicrobial properties of Ag and polyacrylic acid doped SrO nanocomposites; molecular docking analysis. J. Photochem. Photobiol., A. 2023;444:114970.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>