<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41516602</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative Analysis of the Spatiotemporal Evolution Patterns of Acoustic Emission Source Localization Under True Triaxial Loading and Loading-Unloading Conditions in Sandstone.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">167</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26010167</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Microseismic/acoustic emission (AE) monitoring enables real-time, non-destructive observation of deformation and failure processes in rock during loading and unloading. Accordingly, this study designed two experimental schemes-sandstone loading and unloading-to comparatively investigate the spatiotemporal evolution characteristics of AE during sandstone failure under these distinct stress paths. Based on AE waveform time-frequency parameters and AE source location results obtained during testing, the failure evolution patterns of rock under both loading paths were analyzed. The results demonstrate that: (1) In both loading and load-unloading experiments, rock failure exhibited a distinct four-stage characteristic. Under pure loading conditions, failure concentrated near the point of catastrophic rupture, whereas unloading triggered premature rock fracturing, with a more pronounced AE response observed during the unloading phase. (2) For both loading paths, the dominant frequencies of AE waveforms were concentrated within the 0-200 kHz range. A distinct low-frequency (0-100 kHz), high-amplitude zone emerged prominently during Stage 4 in both cases. (3) AE source locations under load-unloading conditions revealed that during Stage 3-characterized by vertical loading combined with lateral unloading in the minimum principal stress direction-tensile failure cracks nucleated within the rock. Subsequently, during Stage 4 of the loading phase, these cracks propagated and coalesced, ultimately forming a macroscopic fracture surface on the sandstone specimen. (4) The AE source location results under pure loading failure conditions indicate that under uniaxial vertical loading, compression-shear failure fractures begin to develop within the rock mass during Stage 3. With continued loading in Stage 4, these shear fractures propagate through to the specimen surface, forming a through-going shear fracture plane.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Peng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China-South Africa Joint Research Center for Development and Utilization on Mineral Resources, BGRIMM Technology Group, Beijing 100160, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Shibo</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China-South Africa Joint Research Center for Development and Utilization on Mineral Resources, BGRIMM Technology Group, Beijing 100160, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China-South Africa Joint Research Center for Development and Utilization on Mineral Resources, BGRIMM Technology Group, Beijing 100160, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhixiu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China-South Africa Joint Research Center for Development and Utilization on Mineral Resources, BGRIMM Technology Group, Beijing 100160, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Nan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2028-4138</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mines, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Fine Exploration and Intelligent Development of Coal Resources, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024YFC2909500</GrantID><Agency>The State Key Research Development Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024YFC2909504</GrantID><Agency>The State Key Research Development Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>04-2368</GrantID><Agency>Youth Science and Technology Innovation Fund of BGRIMM Technology Group</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52504086</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acoustic emission source localization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">loading-unloading</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">time-frequency conversion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">true triaxial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">waveform parameters</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41516602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12787773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26010167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26010167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yin D., Chen S., Ge Y., Liu R. Mechanical properties of rock&#x2013;coal bi-material samples with different lithologies under uniaxial loading. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2020;10:322&#x2013;338. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2020.12.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2020.12.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Ye D., Yang P., Wu C. Study on Impact Tendency of Coal and Rock Mass Based on Different Stress Paths. Adv. Civ. Eng. 2020;2020:8883537. doi: 10.1155/2020/8883537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/8883537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu J., Yin G., Zhang D., Gao H., Li B., Li M. True triaxial strength and failure characteristics of cubic coal and sandstone under different loading paths. Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. 2020;135:104439. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmms.2020.104439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2020.104439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J., Wang E., Zhou R. Real-time measuring and warning of surrounding rock dynamic deformation and failure in deep roadway based on machine vision method. Measurement. 2020;149:107028. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2019.107028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2019.107028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Z., Zhang D., Fang Q., Dui G., Tai Q., Sun F. Analysis of the interaction between tunnel support and surrounding rock considering pre-reinforcement. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2021;115:104074. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2021.104074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2021.104074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H., Sun Q., Feng G., Li S., Xiao Y. In-situ observations of damage-fracture evolution in surrounding rock upon unloading in 2400-m-deep tunnels. Int. J. Min. Sci. Technol. 2023;33:437&#x2013;446. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmst.2022.11.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmst.2022.11.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu R. Stability of surrounding rock in broken zone of the tunnel in rich water and mountains. Desalination Water Treat. 2023;290:170&#x2013;176. doi: 10.5004/dwt.2023.29419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5004/dwt.2023.29419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu H., Xia C., Xu C., Wang C., Zhao H., Maruvanchery V., Li G. Precursory characteristics of coal-rock failure using acoustic emission and computed tomography under uniaxial monotonic and cyclic compression. Measurement. 2025;247:116844. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2025.116844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2025.116844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X., Liu X., Wang X., Liu Y., Xie H., Du P. Acoustic Emission Characteristics of Coal Failure Under Triaxial Loading and Unloading Disturbance. Rock Mech. Rock Eng. 2022;56:1043&#x2013;1061. doi: 10.1007/s00603-022-03104-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-022-03104-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pu Y., Chen J., Apel D., Shang X. Real-Time Identification of Rock Failure Stages Using Deep Learning: A Case Study of Acoustic Emission Analysis in Rock Engineering. Rock Mech. Rock Eng. 2025;58:5531&#x2013;5547. doi: 10.1007/s00603-025-04423-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-025-04423-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombero C., Comina C., Vinciguerra S., Benson P. Microseismicity of an Unstable Rock Mass: From Field Monitoring to Laboratory Testing. J. Geophys. Res. Solid Earth. 2018;15:4210. doi: 10.1002/2017JB014612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/2017JB014612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng G., Li L., Zhu W., Yang T., Tang C., Zheng Y., Wang Y. Microseismic Investigation of Mining-Induced Brittle Fault Activation in a Chinese Coal Mine. Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. 2019;123:104096. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmms.2019.104096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2019.104096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Hu Q., Yu M., Li X., Hu J., Yang H. Acoustic Emission Monitoring Technology for Coal and Gas Outburst. Energy Sci. Eng. 2019;15:2990. doi: 10.1002/ese3.289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ese3.289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He M., Wang Q. Rock Dynamics in Deep Mining. Int. J. Min. Sci. Technol. 2023;33:1065&#x2013;1082. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmst.2023.07.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmst.2023.07.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Liu X., Wang X., Zhou X., Xie H., Cai D., Gu P. Stress-Induced AE Varying Characteristics in Distinct Lithologies Subjected to Uniaxial Compression. Eng. Fract. Mech. 2023;286:109226. doi: 10.1016/j.engfracmech.2023.109266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfracmech.2023.109266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He M., Miao J., Feng J. Rock Burst Process of Limestone and its Acoustic Emission Characteristics under True-Triaxial Unloading Conditions. Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. 2010;47:286&#x2013;298. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmms.2009.09.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2009.09.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren F., Gao Z., Ma K., Yang S. Rockburst probability early warning method based on integrated infrared temperature and acoustic emission parameters. Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. 2025;189:106097. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmms.2025.106097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2025.106097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Y., Wang E., Li Z., Liu X., Huang T., Yao J. Comprehensive Early Warning Method of Microseismic, Acoustic Emission and Electromagnetic Radiation Signals of Rock Burst Based on Deep Learning. Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. 2023;170:105519. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmms.2023.105519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2023.105519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin M., Gao C., Xia Y., Zhang D., Liu X., Liang X. Rock Burst Initiation and Precursors in a Model Specimen Based on Acoustic Emission and Infrared Monitoring. Arab. J. Geosci. 2022;15:333. doi: 10.1007/s12517-021-09423-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-021-09423-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma K., Xie H., Ren F., Chang Y. Rockburst Early-Warning Method Based on Time Series Prediction of Multiple Acoustic Emission Parameters. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2024;153:106060. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2024.106060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2024.106060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong L., Zhang Y., Ma J. Micro-Crack Mechanism in the Fracture Evolution of Saturated Granite and Enlightenment to the Precursors of Instability. Sensors. 2020;20:4595. doi: 10.3390/s20164595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s20164595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7472113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32824347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi Y.-C., Chung B., Jung D. A Proposed Algorithm Based on Variance to Effectively Estimate Crack Source Localization in Solids. Sensors. 2024;24:6092. doi: 10.3390/s24186092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24186092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11436135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39338836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Zhao C., Huang Y., Lyu G. Ground Pressure Control Measures and Microseismic Verification During the Recovery Process of Residual Ore Bodies. Appl. Sci. 2025;15:11467. doi: 10.3390/app152111467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app152111467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou C., Li X., Chen Y., Li W., Liu K., Dong L., Sun D. Optimization and Numerical Verification of Microseismic Monitoring Sensor Network in Underground Mining: A Case Study. Mathematics. 2024;12:3500. doi: 10.3390/math12223500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math12223500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li N., Fang L., Huang B., Chen P., Cai C., Zhang Y., Liu X., Li Z., Wen Y., Qin Y. Characteristics of Acoustic Emission Waveforms Induced by Hydraulic Fracturing of Coal under True Triaxial Stress in a Laboratory-Scale Experiment. Minerals. 2022;12:104. doi: 10.3390/min12010104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min12010104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma T., Tang C., Tang S., Kuang L., Yu Q., Kong D., Zhu X. Rockburst Mechanism and Prediction Based on Microseismic Monitoring. Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. 2018;110:177&#x2013;188. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmms.2018.07.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2018.07.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang N.E., Shen Z., Long S.R., Wu M.C., Shih H.H., Zheng Q., Yen N.-C., Tung C.C., Liu H.H. The empirical mode decomposition and the Hilbert spectrum for nonlinear and non-stationary time series analysis. Proc. R. Soc. Lond. Ser. A Math. Phys. Eng. Sci. 1998;454:903&#x2013;995. doi: 10.1098/rspa.1998.0193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rspa.1998.0193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres M.E., Colominas M.A., Schlotthauer G., Flandrin P. A complete ensemble empirical mode decomposition with adaptive noise; Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP); Prague, Czech Republic. 22&#x2013;27 May 2011; pp. 4144&#x2013;4147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li N., Sun W., Huang B., Chen D., Zhang S., Yan M. Acoustic Emission Source Location Monitoring of Laboratory-Scale Hydraulic Fracturing of Coal Under True Triaxial Stress. Nat. Resour. Res. 2021;30:2297&#x2013;2315. doi: 10.1007/s11053-021-09821-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11053-021-09821-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antoni J. Fourier analysis and spectral estimation. Mech. Syst. Signal Process. 2017;89:2&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1016/j.ymssp.2016.07.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymssp.2016.07.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo T., Zhang T., Lim E., L&#xf3;pez-Ben&#xed;tez M., Ma F., Yu L. A Review of Wavelet Analysis and Its Applications: Challenges and Opportunities. IEEE Access. 2022;10:58869&#x2013;58903. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3179517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3179517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Method for Primary Calibration of Acoustic Emission Sensor. ASTM International; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2021.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>