<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41111175</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1542-233X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Eye &amp; contact lens</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eye Contact Lens</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigation of Epithelial Remodeling After Accelerated Epi-Off Cross-linking in Pediatric Keratoconus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>544</StartPage><EndPage>552</EndPage><MedlinePgn>544-552</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/ICL.0000000000001232</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine the factors that may affect pediatric epithelial remodeling after accelerated epi-off cross-linking (A-CXL) by examining the changes in epithelial thickness (ET) maps in pediatric keratoconus patients at the 1-year follow-up.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Seventy-one eyes of 53 patients (mean age 14.89&#xb1;1.89 years) were included. Before A-CXL, the MS-39 anterior segment optical coherence tomography images were examined 3, 6, and 12 months after corneal cross-linking (CXL).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Significant flattening was observed in Kmax and Ksteep values at 6 and 12 months after A-CXL ( P &lt;0.05). No significant change was noted in mean ET, except for the 6 to 8 mm inferonasal area ( P &gt;0.05). When max-min ET differences were examined in each region of the corneal ET map, significant improvement was detected in the central 6 mm area, in the 2 to 4 mm inferior-temporal (IT) zone, and in the 4 to 6 mm area in the IT and inferior (I) zones ( P &lt;0.05). The change in max-min ET differences in the central 6 mm area before A-CXL and at 12 months after CXL was significantly correlated with the change in corrected distance visual acuity values, corneal keratometry, corneal astigmatism, and stromal thickness parameters ( P &lt;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A-CXL is an effective treatment for preventing the progression of pediatric keratoconus and for normalizing ET changes by promoting epithelial remodeling. Epithelial remodeling may have an impact on the improvement in visual acuity after A-CXL by providing a smooth optical surface.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Contact Lens Association of Ophthalmologists.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Y&#x131;ld&#x131;r&#x131;m Erdal</LastName><ForeName>B&#xfc;&#x15f;ra Dilara</ForeName><Initials>BD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Ankara Etlik City Hospital, Ankara, Turkey .</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kazanc&#x131;</LastName><ForeName>Burcu</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Eye Contact Lens</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101160941</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1542-2321</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003432">Cross-Linking Reagents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017319">Photosensitizing Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>TLM2976OFR</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012256">Riboflavin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9007-34-5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003094">Collagen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007640" MajorTopicYN="Y">Keratoconus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003432" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cross-Linking Reagents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019573" MajorTopicYN="Y">Epithelium, Corneal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D041623" MajorTopicYN="N">Tomography, Optical Coherence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017319" MajorTopicYN="N">Photosensitizing Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012256" MajorTopicYN="N">Riboflavin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003094" MajorTopicYN="N">Collagen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014792" MajorTopicYN="N">Visual Acuity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019781" MajorTopicYN="N">Corneal Topography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010778" MajorTopicYN="Y">Photochemotherapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014466" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultraviolet Rays</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003319" MajorTopicYN="N">Corneal Stroma</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Accelerated epi-off cross-linking</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epithelial remodeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epithelial thickness map</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pediatric keratoconus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Placido combined anterior segment optical coherence tomography</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41111175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ICL.0000000000001232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00140068-990000000-00328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rabinowitz YS.Keratoconus. Sur Ophthalmol 1998;42:297&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafezi F, Kling S, Hafezi NL, et al. Corneal cross-linking. Prog Retin Eye Res 2025;104:101322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anitha V, Vanathi M, Raghavan A, et al. Pediatric keratoconus - Current perspectives and clinical challenges. Indian J Ophthalmol 2021;69:214&#x2013;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal R, Jain P, Arora R. Complications of corneal collagen cross-linking. Indian J Ophthalmol 2022;70:1466&#x2013;1474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eraslan M, Toker E, Cerman E, et al. Efficacy of epithelium-off and epithelium-on corneal collagen cross-linking in pediatric keratoconus. Eye Contact Lens 2017;43:155&#x2013;161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Lu Y, Du K, et al. Comparison of efficacy and safety between standard, accelerated epithelium-off and transepithelial corneal collagen cross-linking in pediatric keratoconus: A meta-analysis. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022;9:787167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinstein DZ, Archer TJ, Gobbe M. Corneal epithelial thickness profile in the diagnosis of keratoconus. J Refract Surg 2009;25:604&#x2013;610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinstein DZ, Gobbe M, Archer TJ, et al. Epithelial, stromal, and total corneal thickness in keratoconus: Three-dimensional display with artemis very-high frequency digital ultrasound. J Refract Surg 2010;26:259&#x2013;271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha KM, Perez-Straziota CE, Stulting RD, et al. Epithelial and stromal remodeling after corneal collagen cross-linking evaluated by spectral-domain OCT. J Refract Surg 2014;30:122&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atia R, Jouve L, Sandali O, et al. Early epithelial remodeling after standard and iontophoresis-assisted corneal cross-linking as evaluated by spectral-domain optical coherence tomography. J Refract Surg 2018;34:551&#x2013;558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lautert J, Doshi D, Price FW, et al. Corneal epithelial remodeling after standard epithelium-off corneal cross-linking in keratoconic eyes. J Refract Surg 2018;34:408&#x2013;412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haberman ID, Lang PZ, Broncano AF, et al. Epithelial remodeling after corneal cross-linking using higher fluence and accelerated treatment time. J Cataract Refract Surg 2018;44:306&#x2013;312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Sun L, Chen Y, et al. One-year outcomes of pachymetry and epithelium thicknesses after accelerated (45 mW/cm(2)) transepithelial corneal collagen cross-linking for keratoconus patients. Sci Rep 2016;6:32692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian M, Jian W, Zhang X, et al. Three-year follow-up of accelerated transepithelial corneal cross-linking for progressive paediatric keratoconus. Br J Ophthalmol 2020;104:1608&#x2013;1612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padmanabhan P, Rachapalle Reddi S, Rajagopal R, et al. Corneal collagen cross-linking for keratoconus in pediatric patients-long-term results. Cornea 2017;36:138&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Einan-Lifshitz A, Achiron A, Hed S, et al. Three-year follow-up of accelerated versus standard corneal cross-linking in paediatric keratoconus. Eye (Lond) 2023;37:1219&#x2013;1224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal M, Gad A, Kotb A, et al. Analysis of the outcomes of three different cross-linking protocols for treatment of paediatric keratoconus: A multicentre randomized controlled trial. Acta Ophthalmol 2024;102:e105&#x2013;e116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fard AM, Reynolds AL, Lillvis JH, et al. Corneal collagen cross-linking in pediatric keratoconus with three protocols: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J AAPOS 2020;24:331&#x2013;336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kesim C, &#xd6;zt&#xfc;rkmen C, &#x15e;ahin A. Astigmatic vectorial analysis in pediatric keratoconus after unilateral cross-linking treatment. Cornea 2022;41:272&#x2013;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eissa SA, Yassin A. Prospective, randomized contralateral eye study of accelerated and conventional corneal cross-linking in pediatric keratoconus. Int Ophthalmol 2019;39:971&#x2013;979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarac O, Caglayan M, Uysal BS, et al. Accelerated versus standard corneal collagen cross-linking in pediatric keratoconus patients: 24 months follow-up results. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2018;41:442&#x2013;447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U&#xe7;akhan &#xd6;, Celik Buyuktepe T, Yavuz Z, et al. Pediatric versus adult corneal collagen cross-linking: Long-term visual, refractive, tomographic and aberrometric outcomes. Curr Eye Res 2021;46:14&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grewal DS, Brar GS, Jain R, et al. Corneal collagen crosslinking using riboflavin and ultraviolet-A light for keratoconus. One-year analysis using scheimpflug imaging. J Cataract Refract Surg 2009;35:425&#x2013;432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Wei S, Zhang Y, et al. Posterior corneal elevation changes and characteristic analysis 1 year after corneal collagen cross-linking for keratoconus. Int Ophthalmol 2022;42:1457&#x2013;1468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schallhorn JM, Tang M, Li Y, et al. Distinguishing between contact lens warpage and ectasia: Usefulness of optical coherence tomography epithelial thickness mapping. J Cataract Refract Surg 2017;43:60&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abtahi MA, Beheshtnejad AH, Latifi G, et al. Corneal epithelial thickness mapping: A major review. J Ophthalmol 2024;2024:6674747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pircher N, Schwarzhans F, Holzer S, et al. Distinguishing keratoconic eyes and healthy eyes using ultrahigh-resolution optical coherence tomography-based corneal epithelium thickness mapping. Am J Ophthalmol 2018;189:47&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang XL, Wang Y, Luo BG, et al. Corneal epithelial thickness analysis of forme fruste keratoconus with optical coherence tomography. Int J Ophthalmol 2021;14:89&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy A, Georgeon C, Knoeri J, et al. Corneal epithelial thickness mapping in the diagnosis of ocular surface disorders involving the corneal epithelium: A comparative study. Cornea 2022;41:1353&#x2013;1361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caporossi A, Mazzotta C, Baiocchi S, et al. Age-related long-term functional results after riboflavin UV A corneal cross-linking. J Ophthalmol 2011;2011:608041&#x2013;608046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soeters N, Van Der Valk R, Tahzib NG. Corneal cross-linking for treatment of progressive keratoconus in various age groups. J Refract Surg 2014;30:454&#x2013;460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mencucci R, Marini M, Paladini I, et al. Effects of riboflavin/UVA corneal cross-linking on keratocytes and collagen fibres in human cornea. Clin Exp Ophthalmol 2010;38:49&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mencucci R, Paladini I, Sarchielli E, et al. Transepithelial riboflavin/ultraviolet. A corneal cross-linking in keratoconus: Morphologic studies on human corneas. Am J Ophthalmol 2013;156:874&#x2013;884.e1.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>