<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41069734</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2311-7710</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of advanced veterinary and animal research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Adv Vet Anim Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Socio-epidemiological study of bovine brucellosis: Seasonal cattle migration in Myanmar.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>350</StartPage><EndPage>360</EndPage><MedlinePgn>350-360</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5455/javar.2025.l903</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Animal migration can spread different diseases from farm to farm without being noticed. Despite bovine brucellosis being endemic in Myanmar, seroprevalence and risk related to farmers' behaviors and cattle migration remain unclear. Thus, understanding brucellosis in seasonal cattle migration is essential to avoid negative economic and public health outcomes. As seasonal cattle movement is done to satisfy local environmental limits, Brucellosis is predisposed in cattle herds of the Central Dry Zone of the country.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In this study, farmer characteristics and seasonal cattle movement practices were investigated for bovine brucellosis prevalence in three Central Myanmar regions from July to August 2022. Blood samples were taken for the Rose Bengal Plate Test to detect brucellosis prevalence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Seasonal migratory farmers had a lower education level, more family members, more cattle heads, and higher income from cattle raising. Influences on disease knowledge included frequent veterinary access (7.02%) and limited disease control training (17.39%). Young farmers with low educational level (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.01), more family members (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.01), less farming experience (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.01), fewer cattle (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.01), cow abortion cases (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.01), farming practices from veterinary access (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.01), and longer migratory distances to grazing pastures (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.01) have higher possibilities to get prevalence of bovine brucellosis at farm level.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study found that farmers' characteristics, migratory practices, migration distance, and abortion history influence Brucellosis prevalence at the farm level. Migratory farmers need farmer collaboration and veterinary training to learn effective farming practices. Access to veterinary services and farmer awareness campaigns about livestock migration risks are essential.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hlaing</LastName><ForeName>Su Su</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6399-4143</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Animal and Veterinary Sciences and Agriculture, Obihiro University of Agriculture and Veterinary Medicine, Obihiro, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kono</LastName><ForeName>Hiroichi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5660-3148</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agro-Environmental Science, Obihiro University of Agriculture and Veterinary Medicine, Obihiro, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Bangladesh</Country><MedlineTA>J Adv Vet Anim Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101647585</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2311-7710</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bovine brucellosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cattle migration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myanmar</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">farmers&#x2019; characteristics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>No conflicts of interest are disclosed by the authors.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41069734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12506768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5455/javar.2025.l903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JAVAR-12-2-350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Myanmar SSP Working Paper 41. MAPSA, Washington, DC, USA.: 2023.. MAPSA (Myanmar Agriculture Policy Support Activity) Myanmar&#x2019;s livestock sector: An overview of production and consumption in 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belton B, Fang P. Livestock, capture fisheries, and aquaculture in Myanmar: Status and recent trends. Int Food Policy Res Inst. 2022;20:135940. https://doi.org/10.2499/p15738coll2.135940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaimba GK, Njehia BK, Njehia BK, Guliye AY. Effects of cattle rustling and household characteristics on migration decisions and herd size amongst pastoralists in Baringo District, Kenya. Pastoralism. 2011;1(1):18. https://doi.org/10.1186/2041-7136-1-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemmons EA, Alfson KJ, Dutton JW. 3rd Transboundary animal diseases, an overview of 17 diseases with potential for global spread and serious consequences. Animals. 2021;11(7):2039. https://doi.org/10.3390/ani11072039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8300273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34359167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruget AS, Rossi G, Pepler PT, Beaun&#xe9;e G, Banks CJ, Enright J, et al. Multi-species temporal network of livestock movements for disease spread. Appl Netw Sci. 2021;6:15. https://doi.org/10.1007/s41109-021-00354-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khurana SK, Sehrawat A, Tiwari R, Prasad M, Gulati B, Shabbir MZ, et al. Bovine brucellosis a comprehensive review. Vet Q. 2021;41(1):61&#x2013;88. https://doi.org/10.1080/01652176.2020.1868616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33353489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman MT, Sobur MA, Islam MS, Ievy S, Hossain MJ, El Zowalaty ME, et al. Zoonotic diseases: Etiology, impact, and control. Microorganisms. 2020;8(9):1405. https://doi.org/10.3390/microorganisms8091405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7563794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32932606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias RM, East IJ. Cattle movement patterns in Australia: an analysis of the NLIS database 2008&#x2013;2012. Aust Vet J. 2015;93:394&#x2013;403. https://doi.org/10.1111/avj.12377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26503533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyetola WD, Diallo K, Kreppel K, Kone PS, Schelling E, Bonfoh B, et al. Factors influencing the transborder transmission of brucellosis in cattle between c&#xf4;te d&#x2019;ivoire and mali: evidence from literature and current key stakeholders. Front Vet Sci. 2021;8:630580. https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2021.630580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7987678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33778036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Win H, Kasemsuwan S, Myint HT, Ekgatat M, Phimpraphai W. Prevalence and risk factors of brucellosis and dairy farmers KAP in 2 townships, Myanmar. Vet Integr Sci. 2023;21(2):439&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.12982/VIS.2023.031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herridge DF, Win MM, New KMM, Kyu KL, Win SS, Shwe T, et al. The cropping systems of the Central Dry Zone of Myanmar: Productivity constraints and possible solutions, Agric Syst. 2019;169:31&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.agsy.2018.12.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IWMI (International Water Management Institute) Improving water management in Myanmar&#x2019;s Dry Zone for food security, livelihoods and health. Colombo, Sri Lanka: 2015. p. 52. http://www.iwmi.cgiar.org/Publications/Other/Reports/PDF/improving-water-management-in myanmars-dry-zone-for-food-security-livelihoods-and-health.pdf (Accessed 15 December 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MOALI (Ministry of Agriculture, Livestock and Irrigation) Myanmar agriculture at a glance department of planning. Ministry of Agriculture, Livestock and Irrigation; 2016. p. 166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MOPF (Ministry of Planning and Finance) [Internet] Report of National Livestock baseline survey 2018. Myanmar Census of Agriculture; 2020. https://www.mopf.gov.mm/sites/default/files/upload_pdf/2020/08/National_Livestock_Baseline_Survey_2018_Report.PDF (Accessed 24 March 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giovambattista G, Moe KK, Polat M, Borjigin L, Hein ST, Moe HH. Characterization of bovine MHC DRB3 diversity in global cattle breeds, with a focus on cattle in Myanmar. BMC Genet. 2020;21:95. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12863-020-00905-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7460757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32867670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekiri AB, Kilonzo C, Bird BH, VanWormer E, Wolking DJ, Smith WA, et al. Utility of the rose bengal test as a point-of-care test for human brucellosis in endemic African settings: a systematic review. J Trop Med. 2020;2020:1&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1155/2020/6586182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7519193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33014074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins RA. Precision Farming Information Sources Used by Cotton Farmers. 2009. https://trace.tennessee.edu/utk_gradthes/532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillespie JM, Davis CG, Rahelizatovo NC. Factors influencing the adoption of breeding technologies in U.S. Hog Production. J Agric Appl Econ. 2004;36(1):35&#x2013;47. https://doi.org/10.1017/S1074070800021842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madjid A. Epidemiology of brucellosis in smallholder cattle herds in South Sulawesi, Indonesia. Copenhagen, Denmark: Proceedings of the 5th international symposium on veterinary epidemiology and economics (published as ActaVeterinaria Scandinavica Supplementum 84) 1988..</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jittapalapong S, Inpankaew T, Sangwaranond A, Phasuk C, Pinyopanuwat N, Chimnoi W, et al. Current status of brucellosis in dairy cows of Chiang Rai Province, Thailand. Kasetsart J. 2008;42:67&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anka MS, Hassan L, Khairani-Bejo S, Zainal MA, Mohamad RB, Salleh A, et al. A case-control study of risk factors for bovine brucellosis seropositivity in Peninsular Malaysia. PLoS One. 2014;9(9):e108673. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0108673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4181650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25265020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogugua AJ, Akinseye VO, Cadmus EO, Jolaoluwa Awosanya EA, Alabi PI, Idowu OS, et al. Prevalence and risk factors associated with bovine brucellosis in herds under extensive production system in southwestern Nigeria. Trop Anim Health Prod. 2018;50(7):1573&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11250-018-1597-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29680957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doss CR, McPeak GJ. Are household decisions cooperative? Evidence on pastoral migration and milk sales from northern Kenya. Economic Growth Centre, Yale University, Centre Discussion. :906. http://www.econ.yale.edu/growth_pdf/cdp906.pdf.2005 (Accessed 22 October 2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmelin NB. Competing gender norms and social practice in Himalayan farm management. World Dev. 2019;122:85&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.worlddev.2019.05.018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghafeer MH, Aldhukair EF, Alzahrani AH, Alsaedi AS, Almutairi ON, Aloliky AA, et al. Assessment of knowledge, attitude, and practice related to brucellosis among livestock farmers and meat handlers in Saudi Arabia. Front Vet Sci. 2024;11:1410330. https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2024.1410330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11229521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38978632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Majali AM, Talafha AQ, Ababneh MM, Ababneh MM. Seroprevalence and risk factors for bovine brucellosis in Jordan. J Vet Sci. 2009;10(1):61&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.4142/jvs.2009.10.1.61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2801095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19255525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shome R, Natesan K, Kalleshamurthy T, Yadav C, Sahay S, Skariah S, et al. Management of bovine brucellosis in organized dairy herds through the identification of risk factors: A cross-sectional study from Karnataka, India. Vet World. 2023;16(5):1122&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.14202/vetworld.2023.1122-1130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10420698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37576779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito MM, Turku S, Lehrfield L, Shoman A. The impact of human activities on zoonotic infection transmissions. Animals. 2023;13(10):1646. https://doi.org/10.3390/ani13101646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10215220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37238075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robi DT, Urge B, Bogale A, Aleme M, Temteme S. Herd and animal level seroprevalence and associated risk factors of bovine brucellosis in different agro-ecologies of southwest Ethiopia. Heliyon. 2023;9(6):e16852. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e16852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10250804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37303577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asakura S, Makingi G, Kazwala R, Makita K. Herd-level risk factors associated with Brucella sero-positivity in cattle, and perception and behaviours on the disease control among agro-pastoralists in Tanzania. Acta Trop. 2018;187:99&#x2013;107. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actatropica.2018.07.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30009764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekwem D, Morrison TA, Reeve R, Enright J, Buza J, Shirima G, et al. Livestock movement informs the risk of disease spread in traditional production systems in East Africa. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):16375. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-95706-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8361167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34385539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hlaing S, Kubota S, Makita K, Win Y, Myint H, Kono H. Association of farmers&#x2019; knowledge, attitude and practices with bovine brucel-losis seroprevalence in Myanmar. Anim Biosci. 2024;37(3):547&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.5713/ab.23.0273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10915188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38291750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kothalawala KAC, Makita K, Kothalawala H, Jiffry AM, Kubota S, Kono H. Association of farmers&#x2019; socio-economics with bovine brucellosis epidemiology in the dry zone of Sri Lanka. Prev Vet Med. 2017;147:117&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.prevetmed.2017.08.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29254709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adugna AE, Agga GE, Zewde G. Sero-epidemiological survey of bovine brucellosis under a traditional production system in western Ethiopia. Rev Sci Tech. 2013;32(3):765&#x2013;75. https://doi.org/10.20506/rst.32.2.2218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24761729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagamiko FD, Muma JB, Karimuribo ED, Mwanza AM, Sindato C, Hang&#x2019;Ombe BM. Sero-prevalence of bovine brucellosis and associated risk factors in mbeya region, Southern highlands of Tanzania. Acta Trop. 2018;178:169&#x2013;75. https://doi.org/10.1101/688705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29191516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derdour SY, Hafsi F, Azzag N, Tennah S, Laamari A, China B, et al. Prevalence of the main infectious causes of abortion in dairy cattle in Algeria. J Vet Res. 2017;61:337&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.1515/jvetres-2017-0044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5894425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29978092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asmare K, Regassa F, Robertson LJ, Martin AD, Skjerve E. Reproductive disorders in relation to Neospora caninum, Brucella spp. and bovine viral diarrhoea virus serostatus in breeding and dairy farms of central and southern Ethiopia. Epidemiol Infect. 2013;141(8):1772&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0950268812002191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9151610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23034138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fereig RM, Mazeed AM, Alharbi AS, Abdelraheem MZ, Omar MA, Almuzaini AM, et al. Seroprevalence of antibodies to Brucella spp. and Neospora caninum in cattle from delta region of Egypt: Correlation of seropositivity with abortion history. Immuno. 2024;4(4):374&#x2013;84. https://doi.org/10.3390/immuno4040024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adabi M, Khazaiee S, Sadeghi-Nasab A, Alamian S, Arabestani MR, Valiei Z, et al. Brucellosis in livestock: First study on seroepidemiology, risk factors, and preventive strategies to manage the disease in Famenin, Iran. Vet World. 2022;15(8):2102&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.14202/vetworld.2022.2102-2110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9615486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36313852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemayehu G, Mamo G, Alemu B, Desta H, Tadesse B, Benti T, et al. Causes and flock level risk factors of sheep and goat abortion in three agroecology zones in Ethiopia. Front Vet Sci. 2021;8:615310. https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2021.615310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7878554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33585619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>