<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41136460</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Oxygen-depleted and ferruginous seawater composition imprinted in Early Cretaceous Fe-rich Al-glauconites in marginal marine deposits.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>37208</StartPage><MedlinePgn>37208</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">37208</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-21056-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The composition of marine authigenic iron silicates bears subtle evidence of paleo-oceanographic and paleoclimatic conditions. This study focuses on the compositionally unique glauconite within the Early Cretaceous Pariwar and Habur formations in the Jaisalmer Basin and discusses its implications. The Al-glauconite is enriched in TFe<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> (&gt;&#x2009;18&#xa0;wt%), and is considered as Fe-rich Al-glauconite. The X-ray diffraction parameters, the micro-texture, and the K<sub>2</sub>O content reveal an evolved to highly evolved structure of the glauconite. It is abundant in shallow subtidal and tidal- and wave-influenced shoreface facies, and it forms either by the alteration of fecal pellets or as bioclast infillings. Micropaleontological and ichnological proxies confirm the glauconitization in an oxygen-depleted, shallow marine depositional setting. Small-sized (&lt;&#x2009;1&#xa0;cm) fodinichnial, pascichnial, domichnial, and repichnial traces, and agglutinated foraminifera (Bathysiphon) corroborate the oxygen-depleted seawater. The landward expansion of the oxygen minimum zone, leading to oxygen depletion in coastal settings, facilitates the glauconitization in a marginal marine setting. Kaolinite and Fe-Al-smectite react in the presence of excess Fe, forming Fe-rich Al-glauconite on the seafloor. Therefore, the compositionally unique glauconite reflects atypical seawater chemistry with increased elemental influx of Al, Fe, and Mg related to intense continental weathering, kaolinite substrate, and mobilization of Fe<sup>2+</sup> in oxygen-depleted seawater.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chakraborty</LastName><ForeName>Arpita</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Earth Sciences, Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, Powai, Mumbai, 400076, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Srivastava</LastName><ForeName>Ayush</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Earth Sciences, Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, Powai, Mumbai, 400076, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Brijesh</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Earth Sciences, Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, Powai, Mumbai, 400076, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Punekar</LastName><ForeName>Jahnavi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Earth Sciences, Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, Powai, Mumbai, 400076, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dasgupta</LastName><ForeName>Sudipta</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Earth Sciences, Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, Powai, Mumbai, 400076, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chakrabarty</LastName><ForeName>Snehasis</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>KDMIPE, Oil and Natural Gas Corporation Ltd., Dehradun, 248195, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Banerjee</LastName><ForeName>Santanu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Earth Sciences, Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, Powai, Mumbai, 400076, India. santanu@iitb.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>PMRF ID: 1302641</GrantID><Agency>Prime Ministers Research Fellowship, India</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>DO/2021-COGE002-015</GrantID><Agency>Centre of Oil Gas and Energy, IIT Bombay</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>DO/2021-COGE002-015</GrantID><Agency>Centre of Oil Gas and Energy, IIT Bombay</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>DO/2021-COGE002-015</GrantID><Agency>Centre of Oil Gas and Energy, IIT Bombay</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>DO/2021-COGE002-015</GrantID><Agency>Centre of Oil Gas and Energy, IIT Bombay</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>DO/2021-COGE002-015</GrantID><Agency>Centre of Oil Gas and Energy, IIT Bombay,</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SR/FST/ES-II/2019/63</GrantID><Agency>Department of Science and Technology, Ministry of Science and Technology, India</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Agglutinated foraminifera</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fe-rich Al-glauconite</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ichnology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Marginal marine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen depletion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sequence stratigraphy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41136460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12552670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-21056-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-21056-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation> Odin, G. S. &amp; Matter, A. De glauconiarum origine. <i>Sedimentology</i><b>28</b>, 611&#x2013;641 (1981).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-3091.1981.tb01925.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee, S. &amp; Bansal, U. Vilas Thorat, A. A review on palaeogeographic implications and Temporal variation in glaucony composition. <i>J. Palaeogeography</i>. <b>5</b>, 43&#x2013;71 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jop.2015.12.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee, S., Chattoraj, S. L., Saraswati, P. K., Dasgupta, S. &amp; Sarkar, U. Substrate control on formation and maturation of glauconites in the middle eocene Harudi Formation, Western Kutch, India. <i>Mar. Pet. Geol.</i><b>30</b>, 144&#x2013;160 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2011.10.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee, S., Mondal, S., Chakraborty, P. P. &amp; Meena, S. S. Distinctive compositional characteristics and evolutionary trend of precambrian glaucony: example from Bhalukona Formation, Chhattisgarh basin, India. <i>Precambrian Res.</i><b>271</b>, 33&#x2013;48 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.precamres.2015.09.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldermann, A., Warr, L. N., Grathoff, G. H. &amp; Dietzel, M. The rate and mechanism of deep-sea glauconite formation at the Ivory Coast&#x2013;Ghana marginal ridge. <i>Clays Clay Miner.</i><b>61</b> (3), 258&#x2013;276 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1346/CCMN.2013.0610307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldermann, A. et al. Exploring reverse silicate weathering across geological time: a review. <i>Clay Miner.</i><b>60</b> (1), 1&#x2013;27 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1180/clm.2024.27</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudmin, M. et al. Roasting-leaching experiments on glauconitic rocks of Bakchar ironstone deposit (Western Siberia) for evaluation their fertilizer potential. <i>Appl. Clay Sci.</i><b>162</b>, 121&#x2013;128 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2018.05.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal, U., B&#xf6;ning, P. &amp; Wilmsen, M. Enhanced chemical weathering of the continents promoted fast late cretaceous nearshore glaucony formation: implications from the Danubian cretaceous Group, Germany. <i>J. Geol. Soc.</i><b>180</b> (2), 2022&#x2013;2098 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1144/jgs2022-098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilmsen, M., Bansal, U., Metzner, N. &amp; B&#xf6;ning, P. Geochemical and depositional environment of an upper cretaceous greensand giant (M&#xfc;nsterland cretaceous Basin, Germany). <i>Chem. Geol.</i><b>661</b>, 122&#x2013;168 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemgeo.2024.122168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee, S., Choudhury, T. R., Saraswati, P. K. &amp; Khanolkar, S. The formation of authigenic deposits during paleogene warm Climatic intervals: a review. <i>J. Palaeogeography</i>. <b>9</b>, 1&#x2013;27 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42501-020-00076-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury, T. R., Banerjee, S., Khanolkar, S., Saraswati, P. K. &amp; Meena, S. S. Glauconite authigenesis during the onset of the Paleocene-Eocene thermal maximum: A case study from the Khuiala formation in Jaisalmer Basin, India. <i>Palaeogeogr., Palaeoclimatol. Palaeoecol.</i><b>571</b>, 110388 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.palaeo.2021.110388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldermann, A. et al. Impact of green clay authigenesis on element sequestration in marine settings. <i>Nat. Commun.</i><b>13</b> (1), 1527 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-29223-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8940969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35318333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeder, S. W., Hitchon, B. &amp; Levinson, A. A. Hydrogeochemistry of the surface waters of the Mackenzie river drainage basin, Canada&#x2014;I. Factors controlling inorganic composition. <i>Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta</i>. <b>36</b> (8), 825&#x2013;865 (1972).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0016-7037(72)90053-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Albani, A., Meunier, A. &amp; F&#xfc;rsich, F. Unusual occurrence of glauconite in a shallow lagoonal environment (Lower Cretaceous, Northern Aquitaine Basin, SW France). <i>Terra Nova</i>. <b>17</b> (6), 537&#x2013;544 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-3121.2005.00646.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chafetz, H. S. &amp; Reid, A. Syndepositional shallow-water precipitation of glauconitic minerals. <i>Sed. Geol.</i><b>136</b> (1&#x2013;2), 29&#x2013;42 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0037-0738(00)00082-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, D. et al. Formation of shallow-water glaucony in weakly oxygenated precambrian ocean: an example from the mesoproterozoic Tieling formation in North China. <i>Precambrian Res.</i><b>294</b>, 214&#x2013;229 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.precamres.2017.03.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldermann, A. et al. The role of Fe on the formation and diagenesis of interstratified glauconite-smectite and illite-smectite: A case study of upper cretaceous shallow-water carbonates. <i>Chem. Geol.</i><b>453</b>, 21&#x2013;34 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemgeo.2017.02.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg-Madsen, V. High-alumina glaucony from the middle cambrian of &#xd6;land and Bornholm, Southern Baltoscandia. <i>J. Sediment. Res.</i><b>53</b> (3), 875&#x2013;893 (1983).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, N. P. Mesozoic lithostratigraphy of the Jaisalmer basin, Rajasthan. <i>J. Palaeontol. Soc. India</i>. <b>51</b> (2), 1&#x2013;25 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0971102320060201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai, J., Singh, A. &amp; Pandey, D. K. Early to middle Albian age calcareous nannofossils from Pariwar formation of Jaisalmer Basin, Rajasthan, Western India and their significance. <i>Curr. Sci.</i><b>105</b>, 1604&#x2013;1611 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, R., Aggarwal, N., Das, N., Pandey, B. &amp; Kumar, K. Palaeoenvironmental reconstruction based on palynofacies analysis of the early to middle jurassic of the lathi Formation, Jaisalmer Basin, India. <i>J. Palaeontol. Soc. India</i>. <b>67</b> (2), 262&#x2013;273 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0971102320220202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma, S. K., Chakrabarty, S., Gorai, D. &amp; Microfacies Depositional Environment and Origin of low resistivity sandstone in Lower Cretaceous Pariwar Formation, Jaisalmer Basin, India. <i>SPG</i> (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishna, J. An overview of the mesozoic stratigraphy of Kachchh and Jaisalmer basins. <i>J. Palaeontol. Soc. India</i>. <b>32</b>, 136&#x2013;149 (1987).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0971102319870114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey, D. et al. A review of the Lower-lowermost upper jurassic facies and stratigraphy of the Jaisalmer Basin, Western Rajasthan, India. <i>Volumina Jurassica</i>. <b>10</b> (1), 61&#x2013;82 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey, R., Aswal, M. L., Shah, L. &amp; Mahanti, S. A note on sand geometry and Paleo-environmental analysis of lower Goru and Pariwar sands, Jaisalmer Basin, India. <i>Indian Near Surf. Geophys. Conf. Exhib.</i><b>1</b>, 1&#x2013;13 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dar, Q. et al. Depositional facies and reservoir characteristics of the early cretaceous lower Goru Formation, lower indus basin pakistan: integration of petrographic and gamma-ray log analysis. <i>Petroleum</i><b>9</b> (3), 331&#x2013;341 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petlm.2021.09.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal, J., Singh, N. P., Canon, A. &amp; Ernst, M. Sur l age et les affinities Gondwanicnnes de microfaunes (Foraminifercs et ostracodes) malgaches, Indicnncs Ct Chillicnnes Au Sommet du Jurassique et Ala base du Crtacc. <i>Acad. Sci. Paris</i>. <b>271</b>, 24&#x2013;27 (1970).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal, J. &amp; Singh, N. P. Cretaceous biostratigraphy of Jaisalmer subsurface, Rajasthan. <i>India VIIIth Colloq. Ind. Micropal Strat</i> 22&#x2013;23 (1980).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasgupta, S. K. Revision of the Mesozoic-Tertiary stratigraphy of the Jaisalmer basin, Rajasthan. <i>Indian J. Earth Sci.</i><b>2</b> (1), 77&#x2013;94 (1975).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das, N., Kumar, R., Pandey, B., Kumar, K. &amp; Bhattacharya, D. Record of plant fossils from freshly discovered succession of the Pariwar Formation, Jaisalmer Basin, Western India. <i>Hist. Biol.</i><b>33</b> (12), 3281&#x2013;3290 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08912963.2020.1861611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spath, L. F. Revision of jurassic cephalopods from Kutch. <i>Palaeontologica Indica New. Series</i><b>2</b>, I&#x2013;VI (1933).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loeblich, A. R. Jr &amp; Tappan, H. <i>Foraminiferal Genera and their Classification</i> (Springer, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaminski, M. A. &amp; Gradstein, F. M. <i>Atlas of Paleogene cosmopolitan deep-water agglutinated foraminifera</i>. (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Setoyama, E., Kaminski, M. A. &amp; Tyszka, J. Late Cretaceous&#x2013;Paleogene foraminiferal morphogroups as palaeoenvironmental tracers of the rifted Labrador margin, Northern proto-Atlantic. <i>Grzybowski Foundation Special Publication</i>. <b>22</b>, 179&#x2013;220 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James, U. P. Description of new species of fossils and remarks on some others, from the lower and upper silurian rocks of Ohio. <i>Paleontologist</i><b>3</b>, 17&#x2013;24 (1879).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrenberg, K. Erg&#xa8; anzende bemerkungen Zu Den Seinerzeit Aus dem Mioz&#xa8; an von Burgschleinitz beschriebenen Gangkernen und Bauten Dekapoder Krebse. <i>PalZ</i><b>23</b>, 354&#x2013;359 (1944).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF03160443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson, H. A. Contributions to the study of the errant annelides of the older palaeozoic rocks. <i>Proc. Royal Soc. Lond.</i><b>21</b>, 288&#x2013;290 (1873).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rspl.1872.0061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haldeman, S. S. A monograph of the Limniades, and other freshwater bivalve shells of the apparently new animals in different classes, and names and characters of the subgenera in paludina and anculosa. <i>J. Dobson Philadelphia</i><b>3</b>, 3 (1840).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salter, J. W. On annelide burrows and surface markings from the cambrian rocks of the Longmynd. <i>Q. J. Geol. Soc.</i><b>13</b>, 199&#x2013;207 (1857).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1144/GSL.JGS.1857.013.01-02.29</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zenker, J. C. <i>Historisch-topographisches Taschenbuch von Jena und seiner Umgebung. Friedrich Frommann.</i> (1836).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmid, E. E. <i>Der Muschelkalk des &#xf6;stlichen Th&#xfc;ringen. Fromann.</i> (1876).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heer, O. <i>Die Urwelt der Schweiz</i>. (1865).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heer, O. <i>Flora fossilis Helvetiae</i>. (1877).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sternberg, K. M. V. Versuch einer geognostisch-botanischen darstellung der flora der Vorwelt, band II, hefte 5 und 6 attempt to a geognostic-botanical representation of the flora of the ancient world. <i>J. Spurny Prague</i>. <b>II</b> (5/6), 94 (1833).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hitchcock, E. <i>Ichnology of New England; a report on the sandstone of the Connecticut Valley, especially its footmarks.</i> 1&#x2013;220 (1858).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasiotis, S. T. &amp; Mitchell, C. E. A comparison of crayfish burrow morphologies: triassic and holocene fossil, paleo-and neo&#x2010;ichnological evidence, and the identification of their burrowing signatures. <i>Ichnos: Int. J. Plant. Anim.</i><b>2</b> (4), 291&#x2013;314 (1993).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10420949309380104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duringer, P. et al. New termite trace fossils: Galleries, nests and fungus combs from the Chad basin of Africa (Upper Miocene&#x2013;Lower Pliocene). <i>Palaeogeogr., Palaeoclimatol. Palaeoecol.</i><b>251</b> (3&#x2013;4), 323&#x2013;353 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.palaeo.2007.03.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkar, S., Banerjee, S., Chakraborty, S. &amp; Bose, P. K. Shelf storm flow dynamics: insight from the mesoproterozoic Rampur Shale, central India. <i>Sed. Geol.</i><b>147</b> (1&#x2013;2), 89&#x2013;104 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0037-0738(01)00189-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poyatos-Mor&#xe9;, M. et al. Sharp-based, mixed carbonate&#x2013;siliciclastic shallow-marine deposits (upper Miocene, Betic Cordillera, Spain): the record of ancient transgressive shelf ridges? <i>Sed. Geol.</i><b>429</b>, 106077 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sedgeo.2021.106077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buatois, L. A. &amp; Mangano, M. G. <i>Ichnology: Organism Substrate Interactions in Space and time</i> (Cambridge University Press, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knaust, D. <i>Atlas of Trace Fossils in Well Core: appearance, Taxonomy and Interpretation</i> (Springer, 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der-Adams, C. Estuaries of the past and present: A biofacies perspective. <i>Sed. Geol.</i><b>190</b> (1&#x2013;4), 289&#x2013;298 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sedgeo.2006.05.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray, J. W., Alve, E. &amp; Jones, B. W. A new look at modern agglutinated benthic foraminiferal morphogroups: their value in palaeoecological interpretation. <i>Palaeogeogr., Palaeoclimatol. Palaeoecol.</i><b>309</b> (3&#x2013;4), 229&#x2013;241 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.palaeo.2011.06.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sprong, J. et al. Characterization of the latest Danian event by means of benthic foraminiferal assemblages along a depth transect at the Southern Tethyan margin (Nile Basin, Egypt). <i>Mar. Micropaleontol.</i><b>86</b>, 15&#x2013;31 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marmicro.2012.01.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haig, D. W. Ammobaculites (Foraminifera): living fossils in Southern Western Australian estuaries. <i>J. R. Soc. West. Aust.</i><b>103</b>, 57&#x2013;77 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraswati, P. K. <i>Foraminiferal micropaleontology for understanding Earth&#x2019;s history</i> (Elsevier, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, R. W. <i>Foraminifera and their Applications</i> (Cambridge University Press, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anan, H. S. Representatives of some diagnostic agglutinated foraminiferal genera of the subclass monothalamana (Bathysiphon, Orbulinelloides, Repmanina, Miliammina, Agglutinella, Dentostomenia, Ammomassilina, Psammolingulina) in the Tethys. <i>Geol. Behav. (GBR)</i>. <b>5</b> (2), 53&#x2013;58 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26480/gbr.02.2021.53.58</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Mowbray, T. &amp; Visser, M. J. Reactivation surfaces in subtidal channel deposits, Oosterschelde, Southwest Netherlands. <i>J. Sediment. Res.</i><b>54</b> (3), 811&#x2013;824 (1984).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nio, S. D. &amp; Yang, C. S. Sea-level fluctuations and the geometric variability of tide-dominated sandbodies. <i>Sed. Geol.</i><b>70</b>, 161&#x2013;193 (1991).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0037-0738(91)90140-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi, K. Morphologic and hydrodynamic controls on the occurrence of tidal bundles in an open-coast macrotidal environment, Northern Gyeonggi Bay, West Coast of Korea. <i>Sed. Geol.</i><b>339</b>, 68&#x2013;82 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sedgeo.2016.04.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bose, P. K. &amp; Chakraborty, P. P. Marine to fluvial transition: proterozoic upper Rewa sandstone, Maihar, India. <i>Sed. Geol.</i><b>89</b>, 285&#x2013;302 (1994).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0037-0738(94)90098-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olariu, C., Steel, R. J., Dalrymple, R. W. &amp; Gingras, M. K. Tidal dunes versus tidal bars: the sedimentological and architectural characteristics of compound dunes in a tidal seaway, the lower Baronia sandstone (Lower Eocene), ager Basin, Spain. <i>Sed. Geol.</i><b>279</b>, 134&#x2013;155 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sedgeo.2012.07.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasiotis, S. T. Continental ichnology: Fundamental processes and controls on trace fossil distribution. In: Miller III, W. (Ed.), <i>Trace Fossils</i> 268&#x2013;284 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das, M., Dasgupta, S., Singh, S., Klunk, M. A. &amp; D&#x2019;souza, R. The <i>Camborygma </i>ichnofacies in a high-resolution sequence-stratigraphic framework for the eocene palustrine-alluvial depositional interval of the Kutch Basin, India. <i>J. Palaeo.</i><b>14</b> (1), 141&#x2013;156 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jop.2024.12.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zecchin, M. &amp; Catuneanu, O. High-resolution sequence stratigraphy of clastic shelves I: units and bounding surfaces. <i>Mar. Pet. Geol.</i><b>39</b> (1), 1&#x2013;25 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2012.08.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava, A., Dasgupta, S. &amp; Singh, S. Lower-order transgressive&#x2013;regressive cycles within a higher-order transgression at the basin margin: an aberrant intercalation of palaeosol and biostromal ichnofabrics from the early miocene Kutch Basin, India. <i>J. Palaeogeography</i>. <b>13</b> (4), 906&#x2013;923 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jop.2024.08.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alekseeva, T. V., Malyshev, V. V. &amp; Alekseev, A. O. Paleosols as markers of stratigraphic unconformities in the upper Visean rocks of the Mstikhino Section, Kaluga oblast: Geochemistry, Mineralogy, and biogenic structures. <i>Stratigr. Geol. Correl.</i><b>30</b> (6), 475&#x2013;497 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1134/S086959382206003X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundgren, B. Studier ofver Fossilforande Losa block. <i>Geol. Stock Forh</i>. <b>13</b>, 111&#x2013;121 (1891).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/11035899109446863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahmer, G. Lebensspuren Aus dem Taunusquarzit und Den siegener schichten (Unterdevon). <i>Preussischen Geologischen Landesanstalt Zu Berlin Jahrbuch</i>. <b>57</b>, 523&#x2013;539 (1937).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe4;gdefrau, K. &#xdc;ber einige Bohrg&#xe4;nge Aus dem unteren muschelkalk von Jena. <i>Pal&#xe4;ontologische Z.</i><b>14</b>, 150&#x2013;160 (1932).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF03041628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey, R. W., Howard, J. D. &amp; Pryor, W. A. <i>Ophiomorpha</i>: its morphologic, taxonomic, and environmental significance. <i>Palaeogeogr. Palaeoclimatol. Palaeoecol.</i><b>23</b>, 199&#x2013;229 (1978).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0031-0182(78)90094-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knaust, D. The ichnogenus <i>Ophiomorpha</i>: taxonomy and environmental distribution. <i>Earth Sci. Rev.</i><b>261</b>, 104988 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.earscirev.2024.104988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knaust, D. <i>Balanoglossites</i>-burrowed firmgrounds&#x2013;the most common ichnofabric on earth? <i>Earth Sci. Rev.</i><b>220</b>, 103747 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.earscirev.2021.103747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty, P. P. &amp; Bailwal, R. Architecture of a tide-influenced, wave dominated shallow-marine deposit from a paleoproterozoic rift setting: example from the Badalgarh Formation, Bayana basin, Rajasthan, Northwest India. <i>J. Earth Syst. Sci.</i><b>130</b>, 1&#x2013;22 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12040-021-01558-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luan, X., Sproat, C. D., Jin, J. &amp; Zhan, R. Depositional environments, hematite&#x2013;chamosite differentiation and origins of middle ordovician iron ooids in the upper Yangtze region, South China. <i>Sedimentology</i><b>71</b> (7), 2210&#x2013;2247 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sed.13213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mount, J. F. Mixing of siliciclastic and carbonate sediments in shallow shelf environments. <i>Geology</i><b>12</b> (7), 432&#x2013;435 (1984).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1130/0091-7613(1984)12&lt;432:MOSACS&gt;2.0.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkar, S. et al. Siliciclastic&#x2013;carbonate mixing modes in the river-mouth bar palaeogeography of the upper cretaceous Garudamangalam sandstone (Ariyalur, India). <i>J. Palaeogeography</i>. <b>3</b> (3), 233&#x2013;256 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore, D. M. &amp; Reynolds, R. J. <i>X-ray Diffraction and the Identification and Analysis of Clay Minerals.</i> (1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee, S., Farouk, S., Nagm, E., Choudhury, T. R. &amp; Meena, S. S. High mg-glauconite in the Campanian Duwi formation of Abu Tartur plateau, Egypt and its implications. <i>J. Afr. Earth Sc.</i><b>156</b>, 12&#x2013;25 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jafrearsci.2019.05.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson, G. R. &amp; Hower, J. The mineralogy of glauconite. <i>Clays Clay Miner.</i><b>23</b> (4), 289&#x2013;300 (1975).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1346/CCMN.1975.0230405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Quir&#xf3;s, A. et al. Glaucony authigenesis, maturity and alteration in the Weddell sea: an indicator of paleoenvironmental conditions before the onset of antarctic glaciation. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>9</b> (1), 13580 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-50107-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6753099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31537907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudmin, M., Banerjee, S., Mazurov, A., Makarov, B. &amp; Martemyanov, D. Economic potential of glauconitic rocks in Bakchar deposit (SE Western Siberia) for alternate potash fertilizer. <i>Appl. Clay Sci.</i><b>150</b>, 225&#x2013;233 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2017.09.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porrenga, D. H. Non-marine glauconitic illite in the lower oligocene of Aardebrug, Belgium. <i>Clay Miner.</i><b>7</b> (4), 421&#x2013;430 (1968).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1180/claymin.1968.007.4.05</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal, U., Pande, K., Banerjee, S., Nagendra, R. &amp; Jagadeesan, K. C. The timing of oceanic anoxic events in the cretaceous succession of cauvery basin: constraints from <sup>40</sup>Ar/<sup>39</sup>Ar ages of glauconite in the Karai shale formation. <i>Geol. J.</i><b>54</b> (1), 308&#x2013;315 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/gj.3177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly, J. C. &amp; Webb, J. A. The genesis of glaucony in the Oligo&#x2013;Miocene Torquay Group, southeastern australia: petrographic and geochemical evidence. <i>Sed. Geol.</i><b>125</b> (1&#x2013;2), 99&#x2013;114 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0037-0738(98)00149-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tribovillard. et al. Syndepositional glauconite as a paleoenvironmental proxy-the lower cenomanian chalk of cap blanc Nez (N-France). <i>Chem. Geol.</i><b>584</b>, 120508 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tribovillard et al. The contrasting origins of glauconite in the shallow marine environment highlight this mineral as a marker of paleoenvironmental conditions. <i>Comptes Rendus G&#xe9;oscience</i>. <b>355</b> (S2), 1&#x2013;16 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal, S., Banerjee, S., Sarkar, S., Mondal, I. &amp; Choudhury, T. R. Origin and sequence stratigraphic implications of high-alumina glauconite within the lower Quartzite, Vindhyan supergroup. <i>Mar. Pet. Geol.</i><b>112</b>, 104040 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2019.104040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal, S., Choudhury, T. R., Das, A., Sarkar, S. &amp; Banerjee, S. Shallow marine Glauconitization during the proterozoic in response to intrabasinal tectonics: A study from the proterozoic lower Bhander Sandstone, central India. <i>Precambrian Res.</i><b>372</b>, 106596 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.precamres.2022.106596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed, I. Q. et al. The influence of depositional conditions on chemical and mineralogical composition of glauconite: case study from the late cretaceous Dokan basin in Kurdistan region of Iraq. <i>Appl. Clay Sci.</i><b>263</b>, 107639 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2024.107639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burst, J. F. Mineral heterogeneity in glauconite pellets. American mineralogist. <i>J. Earth Planet. Mater.</i><b>43</b> (5&#x2013;6), 481&#x2013;497 (1958).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odin, G. S. &amp; Fr&#xf6;hlich, F. Glaucony from the kerguelen plateau (Southern Indian Ocean). <i>Developments Sedimentology</i>. <b>45</b>, 277&#x2013;294 (1988).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0070-4571(08)70068-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odin, G. S. &amp; Fullagar, P. D. Geological significance of the glaucony facies. <i>Developments Sedimentology</i>. <b>45</b>, 295&#x2013;332 (1988).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0070-4571(08)70069-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courbe, C., Velde, B. &amp; Meunier, A. Weathering of glauconites: reversal of the Glauconitization process in a soil profile in Western France. <i>Clay Minerals</i>. <b>16</b> (3), 231&#x2013;243 (1981).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1180/claymin.1981.016.3.02</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ireland, B. J., Curtis, C. D. &amp; Whiteman, J. A. Compositional variation within some glauconites and illites and implications for their stability and origins. <i>Sedimentology</i><b>30</b> (6), 769&#x2013;786 (1983).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-3091.1983.tb00710.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jach, R. &amp; Starzec, K. Glaucony from the condensed Lower-Middle jurassic deposits of the Kri&#x17e;na Unit, Western Tatra Mountains, Poland. <i>Ann. Soc. Geol. Pol.</i><b>73</b>, 183&#x2013;192 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longu&#xe9;p&#xe9;e, H. &amp; Cousineau, P. A. Constraints on the genesis of Ferrian illite and aluminum-rich glauconite: potential impact on sedimentology and isotopic studies. <i>Can. Mineral.</i><b>44</b> (4), 967&#x2013;980 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2113/gscanmin.44.4.967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velde, B. The chemical evolution of glauconite pellets as seen by microprobe determinations. <i>Mineralogical Magazine</i>. <b>40</b>, 753&#x2013;760 (1976).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1180/minmag.1976.040.315.09</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velde, B. <i>Clay Minerals: A Physico-Chemical Explanation of their Occurrence</i> (Elsevier, 1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isson, T. T. &amp; Planavsky, N. J. Reverse weathering as a long-term stabilizer of marine pH and planetary climate. <i>Nature</i><b>560</b> (7719), 471&#x2013;475 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-018-0408-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30089907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury, T. R., Khanolkar, S. &amp; Banerjee, S. Glauconite authigenesis during the warm Climatic events of paleogene: case studies from shallow marine sections of Western India. <i>Glob. Planet Change</i>. <b>214</b>, 103857 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gloplacha.2022.103857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal, U., Banerjee, S., Pande, K., Arora, A. &amp; Meena, S. S. The distinctive compositional evolution of glauconite in the cretaceous Ukra hill member (Kutch basin, India) and its implications. <i>Mar. Pet. Geol.</i><b>82</b>, 97&#x2013;117 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2017.01.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal, U., Banerjee, S., Ruidas, D. K. &amp; Pande, K. Origin and geochemical characterization of the glauconites in the upper cretaceous Lameta Formation, Narmada Basin, central India. <i>J. Palaeogeography</i>. <b>7</b> (2), 99&#x2013;116 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jop.2017.12.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekdale, A. A. &amp; Mason, T. R. Characteristic trace-fossil associations in oxygen-poor sedimentary environments. <i>Geology</i><b>16</b> (8), 720&#x2013;723 (1988).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1130/0091-7613(1988)016&lt;0720:CTFAIO&gt;2.3.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moffitt, S. E. et al. Paleoceanographic insights on recent oxygen minimum zone expansion: lessons for modern oceanography. <i>PloS One</i>. <b>10</b> (1), 0115246 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0115246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4309540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25629508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xf6;nfeld, J. et al. Records of past mid-depth ventilation: cretaceous ocean anoxic event 2 vs. Recent oxygen minimum zones. <i>Biogeosciences</i><b>12</b> (4), 1169&#x2013;1189 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/bg-12-1169-2015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, J. C. et al. Do phytoplankton require oxygen to survive? A hypothesis and model synthesis from oxygen minimum zones. <i>Limnol. Oceanogr.</i><b>68</b> (7), 1417&#x2013;1437 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/lno.12367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xf6;llmi, K. B. Early cretaceous life, climate and anoxia. <i>Cretac. Res.</i><b>35</b>, 230&#x2013;257 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cretres.2011.12.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlanger, S. O. &amp; Jenkyns, H. Cretaceous oceanic anoxic events: causes and consequences. <i>Geologie En Mijnbouw</i><b>55</b>(3&#x2013;4), 179&#x2013;184 (1976).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metzner, N., Wilmsen, M. &amp; B&#xf6;ning, P. Greensand formation, siliceous Earth deposition and coastal metal drawdown in the Danubian cretaceous basin (Bavaria, Germany). <i>Mar. Pet. Geol.</i><b>170</b>, 107067 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2024.107067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Z. et al. Enhanced terrigenous organic matter input and productivity on the Western margin of the Western Pacific warm pool during the quaternary sea-level lowstands: forcing mechanisms and implications for the global carbon cycle. <i>Q. Sci. Rev.</i><b>232</b>, 106211 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.quascirev.2020.106211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, A. M. &amp; Goldring, R. Description and analysis of bioturbation and ichnofabric. <i>J. Geol. Soc.</i><b>150</b> (1), 141&#x2013;148 (1993).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1144/gsjgs.150.1.0141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>