<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41909411</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Vitamin B12 Deficiency Presenting as Pseudothrombotic Microangiopathy and Intestinal Pseudo-Obstruction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e104246</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e104246</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e104246</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.104246</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Vitamin B12 deficiency is a common and reversible cause of megaloblastic anemia, but in severe cases, it may mimic thrombotic microangiopathy (TMA), a presentation known as pseudothrombotic microangiopathy (pseudo-TMA). This rare entity is frequently underrecognized and may lead to inappropriate therapies if not promptly identified. We report the case of a 62-year-old man who presented with abdominal pain, distension, and constipation, initially raising concern for intestinal obstruction or malignancy. Laboratory evaluation revealed macrocytic anemia, thrombocytopenia, elevated lactate dehydrogenase, and indirect hyperbilirubinemia. Further assessment demonstrated a low reticulocyte count, absence of significant schistocytosis, markedly reduced vitamin B12 levels, and elevated ferritin. Autoimmune testing confirmed pernicious anemia as the underlying etiology. Treatment with intramuscular hydroxocobalamin resulted in complete clinical and hematologic recovery. This case demonstrates the value of recognizing pseudo-TMA and considering vitamin B12 deficiency in patients with TMA-like features and unexplained gastrointestinal symptoms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Salcedo Elguea et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salcedo Elguea</LastName><ForeName>Erandy A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Institute for Social Security and Services for State Workers General Hospital, Juarez City, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barrio Rivera</LastName><ForeName>Humberto</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surgery, Mexican Social Security Institute Hospital of Zone Number 35, Juarez City, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garcia Chavez</LastName><ForeName>Pablo A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hematology, Institute for Social Security and Services for State Workers General Hospital, Juarez City, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ineffective erythropoiesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intestinal pseudo-obstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">megaloblastic anemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pernicious anemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vitamin b12 deficiency anemia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41909411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13030109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.104246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Vitamin B12 deficiency. Stabler SP. N Engl J Med. 2013;368:2041&#x2013;2042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23697526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobalamin deficiency presenting with thrombotic microangiopathy (TMA) features: a systematic review. Tran PN, Tran MH. Transfus Apher Sci. 2018;57:102&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29454538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemolysis and schistocytosis in the emergency department: consider pseudothrombotic microangiopathy related to vitamin B12 deficiency. No&#xeb;l N, Maign&#xe9; G, Tertian G, et al. QJM. 2013;106:1017&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23842487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pseudo-thrombotic microangiopathy related to cobalamin deficiency. Andr&#xe8;s E, Affenberger S, Federici L, Korganow AS. Am J Med. 2006;119:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17145235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura. Joly BS, Coppo P, Veyradier A. Blood. 2017;129:2836&#x2013;2846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28416507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severe vitamin B12 deficiency mimicking microangiopathic hemolytic anemia. Hassouneh R, Shen S, Lee O, Hart RA, Rhea LP, Fadden P. J Hematol. 2021;10:202&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8425804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34527117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin B12 deficiency and metabolism-mediated thrombotic microangiopathy (MM-TMA) Sabry W, Elemary M, Burnouf T, Seghatchian J, Goubran H. Transfus Apher Sci. 2020;59:102717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31902683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Current hematological findings in cobalamin deficiency. A study of 201 consecutive patients with documented cobalamin deficiency. Andr&#xe8;s E, Affenberger S, Zimmer J, et al. Clin Lab Haematol. 2006;28:50&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16430460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The pathophysiology of elevated vitamin B12 in clinical practice. Andr&#xe8;s E, Serraj K, Zhu J, Vermorken AJ. QJM. 2013;106:505&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23447660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffbrand AV, Higgs DR, Keeling DM, Mehta AB. Postgraduate Haematology. Hoboken, NJ: Wiley Blackwell; 2016. Megaloblastic anemia; pp. 53&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Is vitamin B12 deficiency a risk factor for gastroparesis in patients with type 2 diabetes? Ahmed SS, El-Hafez HA, Mohsen M, El-Baiomy AA, Elkhamisy ET, El-Eshmawy MM. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2023;15:33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9976380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36855172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitamin B(12) deficiency presenting as intestinal pseudo-obstruction in short bowel syndrome: a case report. Morotti F, Terruzzi J, Cavalleri L, Betalli P, D'Antiga L, Norsa L. Nutrition. 2023;106:111895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36435090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Life-threatening pseudo-thrombotic microangiopathy caused by severe vitamin B12 deficiency. Abuhelwa Z, Khan T, Daas R, Ghazaleh S, Assaly R. Am J Med Case Rep. 2021;9:532&#x2013;534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consensus on the standardization of terminology in thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura and related thrombotic microangiopathies. Scully M, Cataland S, Coppo P, et al. J Thromb Haemost. 2017;15:312&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27868334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thrombotic microangiopathy with irreversible renal function in a CKD patient following COVID-19: case report. Qin Y, Yang X, Zhao W, Li Y, Bai Y, Wang L. Front Med (Lausanne) 2025;12:1484385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12488711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41048967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AGA Clinical Practice Update on the diagnosis and management of atrophic gastritis: expert review. Shah SC, Piazuelo MB, Kuipers EJ, Li D. Gastroenterology. 2021;161:1325&#x2013;1332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8740554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>