<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41674114</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-445X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>111</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Skeletal muscle myosin heavy chain fragmentation following exercise may be linked to post-exercise inflammation and remodelling.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2123</StartPage><EndPage>2134</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2123-2134</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/EP093340</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The purpose of this exploratory investigation was to determine if acute post-exercise skeletal muscle myosin heavy chain fragmentation (MyHC<sub>frag</sub>) coincides with alterations in molecular chaperones and proteolytic enzymes, select markers of mammalian target of rapamycin complex 1 (mTORC1) signalling, and/or specific gene expression signatures. Untrained males (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;10, 23&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;2&#xa0;years) and females (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;10, 23&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;3&#xa0;years) completed a bout of combined endurance and resistance exercise. Vastus lateralis muscle biopsies were taken before, 3&#xa0;h and 24&#xa0;h post-exercise. Tissue was fractioned into myofibrillar (MF) and sarcoplasmic protein (SF) fractions for protein analysis. Differential RNA expression (DE) from those who experienced high and low MyHC<sub>frag</sub> post-exercise was also analysed via bulk RNA-sequencing. MyHC<sub>frag</sub> increased 24&#xa0;h post-exercise, albeit only four of 20 chaperone and proteolytic markers were concomitantly altered and none significantly correlated with 24&#xa0;h post-exercise MyHC<sub>frag</sub>. Given these null findings, we explored six participants who experienced the most post-exercise MyHC<sub>frag</sub> versus six who experienced the least MyHC<sub>frag</sub> with the intent of examining if post-exercise gene signatures or signalling differed. Although mTORC1 signalling markers were similar, 799 DE transcripts were identified 24&#xa0;h post-exercise. Pathway analysis on DE differences indicated that nine of the top 10 pathways enriched in high-MyHC<sub>frag</sub> participants were related to inflammation. High MyHC<sub>frag</sub> participants also presented an upregulation in extracellular matrix remodelling genes at the 24&#xa0;h post-exercise time point. Though we lack immunohistochemical data, these findings suggest that post-exercise MyHC<sub>frag</sub> is associated with an upregulation in an inflammatory and remodelling signature, and longer-term studies are needed to determine if these acute outcomes align with unique adaptive responses.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Experimental Physiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tiede</LastName><ForeName>Dakota R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Nutrabolt Applied and Molecular Sciences Laboratory, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bittencourt</LastName><ForeName>Diego</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-9953-5872</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Federal University, University of S&#xe3;o Carlos, S&#xe3;o Carlos, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Michel</LastName><ForeName>J Max</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9894-3856</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Nutrabolt Applied and Molecular Sciences Laboratory, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Plotkin</LastName><ForeName>Daniel L</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Nutrabolt Applied and Molecular Sciences Laboratory, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mattingly</LastName><ForeName>Madison L</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Nutrabolt Applied and Molecular Sciences Laboratory, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anglin</LastName><ForeName>Derick A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Nutrabolt Applied and Molecular Sciences Laboratory, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vann</LastName><ForeName>Christopher G</ForeName><Initials>CG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9072-4488</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Duke Molecular Physiology Institute, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Graham</LastName><ForeName>Zachary A</ForeName><Initials>ZA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Healthspan, Resilience, and Performance Research, Florida Institute for Human and Machine Cognition, Pensacola, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Exercise Medicine, The University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Broderick</LastName><ForeName>Timothy J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Healthspan, Resilience, and Performance Research, Florida Institute for Human and Machine Cognition, Pensacola, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Exercise Medicine, The University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bamman</LastName><ForeName>Marcas M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Healthspan, Resilience, and Performance Research, Florida Institute for Human and Machine Cognition, Pensacola, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Exercise Medicine, The University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Michael D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7359-5362</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Nutrabolt Applied and Molecular Sciences Laboratory, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>N000141613159</GrantID><Agency>Office of Naval Research</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9002940</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0958-0670</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.6.4.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018995">Myosin Heavy Chains</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.11.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000076222">Mechanistic Target of Rapamycin Complex 1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018995" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myosin Heavy Chains</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="Y">Inflammation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076222" MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanistic Target of Rapamycin Complex 1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fragmentation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myosin heavy chain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41674114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP093340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Acquarone, D., Bertero, A., Brancaccio, M., &amp; Sorge, M. (2025). Chaperone proteins: The rising players in muscle atrophy. Journal of Cachexia, Sarcopenia and Muscle, 16(1), e13659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelidis, C. E., Lazaridis, I., &amp; Pagoulatos, G. N. (1999). Aggregation of hsp70 and hsc70 in vivo is distinct and temperature&#x2010;dependent and their chaperone function is directly related to non&#x2010;aggregated forms. European Journal of Biochemistry, 259(1&#x2013;2), 505&#x2013;512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman, M. M., Roberts, B. M., &amp; Adams, G. R. (2018). Molecular regulation of exercise&#x2010;induced muscle fiber hypertrophy. Cold Spring Harbor perspectives in medicine, 8(6), a029751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, T. C., Chen, H. L., Lin, M. J., Wu, C. J., &amp; Nosaka, K. (2010). Potent protective effect conferred by four bouts of low&#x2010;intensity eccentric exercise. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 42(5), 1004&#x2013;1012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lemos Muller, C. H., Schroeder, H. T., Farinha, J. B., Lopez, P., Reischak&#x2010;Oliveira, A., Pinto, R. S., de Bittencourt Junior, P. I. H., &amp; Krause, M. (2024). Effects of resistance training on heat shock response (HSR), HSP70 expression, oxidative stress, inflammation, and metabolism in middle&#x2010;aged people. Journal of Physiology and Biochemistry, 80, 161&#x2013;173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimauro, I., Mercatelli, N., &amp; Caporossi, D. (2016). Exercise&#x2010;induced ROS in heat shock proteins response. Free Radical Biology and Medicine, 98, 46&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fennel, Z. J., Ducharme, J. B., Berkemeier, Q. N., Specht, J. W., McKenna, Z. J., Simpson, S. E., Nava, R. C., Escobar, K. A., Hafen, P. S., Deyhle, M. R., Amorim, F. T., &amp; Mermier, C. M. (2023). Effect of heat stress on heat shock protein expression and hypertrophy&#x2010;related signaling in the skeletal muscle of trained individuals. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 325(6), R735&#x2013;R749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godwin, J. S., Telles, G. D., Vechin, F. C., Conceicao, M. S., Ugrinowitsch, C., Roberts, M. D., &amp; Libardi, C. A. (2023). Time course of proteolysis biomarker responses to resistance, high&#x2010;intensity interval, and concurrent exercise bouts. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 37(12), 2326&#x2013;2332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hjorth, M., Norheim, F., Meen, A. J., Pourteymour, S., Lee, S., Holen, T., Jensen, J., Birkeland, K. I., Martinov, V. N., Langleite, T. M., Eckardt, K., Drevon, C. A., &amp; Kolset, S. O. (2015). The effect of acute and long&#x2010;term physical activity on extracellular matrix and serglycin in human skeletal muscle. Physiological Reports, 3(8), e12473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong, Z., Gong, W., Yang, J., Li, S., Liu, Z., Perrett, S., &amp; Zhang, H. (2023). Exploration of the cysteine reactivity of human inducible Hsp70 and cognate Hsc70. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 299(1), 102723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal, M. J., Chen, T. C., Thompson, P. D., &amp; Clarkson, P. M. (2008). Inflammatory gene changes associated with the repeated&#x2010;bout effect. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 294(5), R1628&#x2013;R1637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ihalainen, J. K., Schumann, M., Eklund, D., Hamalainen, M., Moilanen, E., Paulsen, G., Hakkinen, K., &amp; Mero, A. A. (2018). Combined aerobic and resistance training decreases inflammation markers in healthy men. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 28(1), 40&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavin, K. M., Graham, Z. A., McAdam, J. S., O'Bryan, S. M., Drummer, D., Bell, M. B., Kelley, C. J., Lixandrao, M. E., Peoples, B., Tuggle, S. C., Seay, R. S., Van Keuren&#x2010;Jensen, K., Huentelman, M. J., Pirrotte, P., Reiman, R., Alsop, E., Hutchins, E., Antone, J., Bonfitto, A., &#x2026;, Bamman, M. M. (2023). Dynamic transcriptomic responses to divergent acute exercise stimuli in young adults. Physiological Genomics, 55(4), 194&#x2013;212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavin, K. M., O'Bryan, S. M., Pathak, K. V., Garcia&#x2010;Mansfield, K., Graham, Z. A., McAdam, J. S., Drummer, D. J., Bell, M. B., Kelley, C. J., Lixandrao, M. E., Peoples, B., Seay, R. S., Torres, A. R., Reiman, R., Alsop, E., Hutchins, E., Bonfitto, A., Antone, J., Palade, J., &#x2026;, &amp; Bamman, M. M. (2025). Divergent multiomic acute exercise responses reveal the impact of sex as a biological variable. Physiological Genomics, 57(5), 321&#x2013;342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Law, C. W., Alhamdoosh, M., Su, S., Dong, X., Tian, L., Smyth, G. K., &amp; Ritchie, M. E. (2016). RNA&#x2010;seq analysis is easy as 1&#x2010;2&#x2010;3 with limma, Glimma and edgeR. F1000Res, 5, 1408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., &amp; Steinacker, J. M. (2001). Changes in skeletal muscle heat shock proteins: Pathological significance. Frontiers in Bioscience, 6, D12&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAdam, J. S., Craig, M. P., Graham, Z. A., Peoples, B., Tuggle, S. C., Seay, R. S., Lavin, K. M., Gargus, A. B., O'Bryan, S. M., Yang, S., Drummer, D. J., Kelley, C. J., Peri, K., Bell, M. B., Aban, I., Cutter, G. R., Mahyari, A., Wen, Y., Zhang, J., &#x2026;, Bamman, M. M. (2025). Multidimensional biocircuitry of exercise adaptation: Integrating in vivo and ex vivo phenomics with miRNA mapping. Physiological Genomics, 57(9), 526&#x2013;550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michel, J. M., Godwin, J. S., Plotkin, D. L., McIntosh, M. C., Mattingly, M. L., Agostinelli, P. J., Mueller, B. J., Anglin, D. A., Kontos, N. J., Berry, A. C., Vega, M. M., Pipkin, A. A., Stock, M. S., Graham, Z. A., Baweja, H. S., Mobley, C. B., Bamman, M. M., &amp; Roberts, M. D. (2025). Effects of leg immobilization and recovery resistance training on skeletal muscle&#x2010;molecular markers in previously resistance&#x2010;trained versus untrained adults. Journal of Applied Physiology, 138(2), 450&#x2013;467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michel, J. M., Godwin, J. S., Plotkin, D. L., Mesquita, P. H. C., McIntosh, M. C., Ruple, B. A., Libardi, C. A., Mobley, C. B., Kavazis, A. N., &amp; Roberts, M. D. (2023). Proteolytic markers associated with a gain and loss of leg muscle mass with resistance training followed by high&#x2010;intensity interval training. Experimental Physiology, 108(10), 1268&#x2013;1281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgner, N., Schmidt, C., Beilsten&#x2010;Edmands, V., Ebong, I. O., Patel, N. A., Clerico, E. M., Kirschke, E., Daturpalli, S., Jackson, S. E., Agard, D., &amp; Robinson, C. V. (2015). Hsp70 forms antiparallel dimers stabilized by post&#x2010;translational modifications to position clients for transfer to Hsp90. Cell Reports, 11(5), 759&#x2013;769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble, E. G., Milne, K. J., &amp; Melling, C. W. (2008). Heat shock proteins and exercise: A primer. Applied Physiology, Nutrition and Metabolism, 33(5), 1050&#x2013;1075.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojima, K., Ichimura, E., Suzuki, T., Oe, M., Muroya, S., &amp; Nishimura, T. (2018). HSP90 modulates the myosin replacement rate in myofibrils. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Cell Physiology, 315(1), C104&#x2013;C114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos, S. M., &amp; Carbone, J. W. (2014). Assessment of skeletal muscle proteolysis and the regulatory response to nutrition and exercise. Iubmb Life, 66(7), 478&#x2013;484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen, G., Vissing, K., Kalhovde, J. M., Ugelstad, I., Bayer, M. L., Kadi, F., Schjerling, P., Hallen, J., &amp; Raastad, T. (2007). Maximal eccentric exercise induces a rapid accumulation of small heat shock proteins on myofibrils and a delayed HSP70 response in humans. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 293(2), R844&#x2013;R853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake, J., Nosaka, K., &amp; Suzuki, K. (2005). Characterization of inflammatory responses to eccentric exercise in humans. Exercise Immunology Review, 11, 64&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plotkin, D. L., Mattingly, M. L., Anglin, D. A., Michel, J. M., Godwin, J. S., McIntosh, M. C., Kontos, N. J., Bergamasco, J. G. A., Scarpelli, M. C., Angleri, V., Taylor, L. W., Willoughby, D. S., Mobley, C. B., Kavazis, A. N., Ugrinowitsch, C., Libardi, C. A., &amp; Roberts, M. D. (2024). Skeletal muscle myosin heavy chain fragmentation as a potential marker of protein degradation in response to resistance training and disuse atrophy. Experimental Physiology, 109(10), 1739&#x2013;1754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts, M. D., McCarthy, J. J., Hornberger, T. A., Phillips, S. M., Mackey, A. L., Nader, G. A., Boppart, M. D., Kavazis, A. N., Reidy, P. T., Ogasawara, R., Libardi, C. A., Ugrinowitsch, C., Booth, F. W., &amp; Esser, K. A. (2023). Mechanisms of mechanical overload&#x2010;induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy: Current understanding and future directions. Physiological Reviews, 103(4), 2679&#x2013;2757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts, M. D., Young, K. C., Fox, C. D., Vann, C. G., Roberson, P. A., Osburn, S. C., Moore, J. H., Mumford, P. W., Romero, M. A., Beck, D. T., Haun, C. T., Badisa, V. L. D., Mwashote, B. M., Ibeanusi, V., &amp; Kavazis, A. N. (2020). An optimized procedure for isolation of rodent and human skeletal muscle sarcoplasmic and myofibrillar proteins. Journal of Biological Methods, 7(1), e127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli, M. C., Bergamasco, J. G. A., Godwin, J. S., Mesquita, P. H. C., Chaves, T. S., Silva, D. G., Bittencourt, D., Dias, N. F., Medalha Junior, R. A., Carello Filho, P. C., Angleri, V., Costa, L. A. R., Kavazis, A. N., Ugrinowitsch, C., Roberts, M. D., &amp; Libardi, C. A. (2024). Resistance training&#x2010;induced changes in muscle proteolysis and extracellular matrix remodeling biomarkers in the untrained and trained states. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 124(9), 2749&#x2013;2762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schober, P., Boer, C., &amp; Schwarte, L. A. (2018). Correlation coefficients: Appropriate use and interpretation. Anesthesia &amp; Analgesia, 126(5), 1763&#x2013;1768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson, H. S., Clarkson, P. M., &amp; Scordilis, S. P. (2002). The repeated bout effect and heat shock proteins: Intramuscular HSP27 and HSP70 expression following two bouts of eccentric exercise in humans. Acta Physiologica Scandinavica, 174(1), 47&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trcka, F., Durech, M., Vankova, P., Chmelik, J., Martinkova, V., Hausner, J., Kadek, A., Marcoux, J., Klumpler, T., Vojtesek, B., Muller, P., &amp; Man, P. (2019). Human stress&#x2010;inducible Hsp70 has a high propensity to form ATP&#x2010;dependent antiparallel dimers that are differentially regulated by cochaperone binding. Molecular &amp; Cellular Proteomics, 18(2), 320&#x2013;337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vann, C. G., Roberson, P. A., Osburn, S. C., Mumford, P. W., Romero, M. A., Fox, C. D., Moore, J. H., Haun, C. T., Beck, D. T., Moon, J. R., Kavazis, A. N., Young, K. C., Badisa, V. L. D., Mwashote, B. M., Ibeanusi, V., Singh, R. K., &amp; Roberts, M. D. (2020). Skeletal muscle myofibrillar protein abundance is higher in resistance&#x2010;trained men, and aging in the absence of training may have an opposite effect. Sports (Basel), 8(1), 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wette, S. G., Birch, N. P., Soop, M., Zugel, M., Murphy, R. M., Lamb, G. D., &amp; Smith, H. K. (2021). Expression of titin&#x2010;linked putative mechanosensing proteins in skeletal muscle after power resistance exercise in resistance&#x2010;trained men. Journal of Applied Physiology, 130(3), 545&#x2013;561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witard, O. C., Bannock, L., &amp; Tipton, K. D. (2022). Making sense of muscle protein synthesis: A focus on muscle growth during resistance training. International Journal of Sport Nutrition and Exercise Metabolism, 32(1), 49&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, W. G., Thomas, A. C. Q., Wilson, G. M., McGlory, C., Hibbert, J. E., Flynn, C. G., Sayed, R. K. A., Paez, H. G., Meinhold, M., Jorgenson, K. W., You, J. S., Steinert, N. D., Lin, K. H., MacInnis, M. J., Coon, J. J., Phillips, S. M., &amp; Hornberger, T. A. (2025). Identification of a resistance&#x2010;exercise&#x2010;specific signalling pathway that drives skeletal muscle growth. Nature Metabolism, 7(7), 1404&#x2013;1423.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>