<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41281624</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1565-3633</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2025</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Bioinorganic chemistry and applications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Bioinorg Chem Appl</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Multifunctional Oxovanadium(V) Schiff Base Complex: Integrated Pyridoxine Sensing and Anticancer and Antimicrobial Activities.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>8974330</StartPage><MedlinePgn>8974330</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8974330</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/bca/8974330</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The multifunctional properties of a new oxovanadium(V) complex [VO(L) (5-Cl-8-HQ)] containing a Schiff base derived from L-arginine and salicylaldehyde and 5-chloroquinolin-8-ol, were investigated in this study. The complex was characterized using elemental analysis, cyclic voltammetry, powder X-ray diffraction, as well as FTIR, UV-Vis, and <sup>1</sup>H NMR spectroscopies. The electrochemical function of the complex as a sensor for pyridoxine detection showed a quasireversible behavior with an electrochemical rate constant of <i>k</i> <sub><i>e</i></sub> &#x2009;=&#x2009;0.133&#x2009;s<sup>-1</sup> in the linear range of detection of 1.0&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>-8</sup> to 1.0&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>-4</sup>&#x2009;mol&#xb7;L<sup>-1</sup>, with a limit of detection of 4.24&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>-8</sup>&#x2009;mol&#xb7;L<sup>-1</sup>. The complex also exhibited good activity as a potential anticancer agent in regard to the MDA-MB-231 breast cancer cell line, with IC<sub>50</sub>&#x2009;=&#x2009;35.09&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.03&#x2009;&#x3bc;g/mL with a steep hill slope of 2.575 in the dose-response curve, suggesting a sensitive cellular response to the complex, indicating promising anticancer potential. UV-Vis spectroscopy remains the method of choice for stability studies conducted under physiological conditions. The results showed a progressive complex breakdown in the cell culture medium at 37&#xb0;C over 96&#x2009;h, implying that its biological activity could be a mixture of the degradation products of the complex. The complex also showed antimicrobial effects at concentrations of 10 and 20&#x2009;ppm against <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i>, <i>Enterococcus faecalis</i>, and <i>Aspergillus niger</i>, with the diameter of the inhibition zone (IZ) increasing with increasing complex concentration. The combination of these electrochemical sensing properties with the dual therapeutic potential as an anticancer and antimicrobial agent places this class of vanadium complexes in a versatile position for further development in both analytical and medicinal fields.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Tahmineh Kohanfekr and Hasan Ali Hosseini. Bioinorganic Chemistry and Applications published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kohanfekr</LastName><ForeName>Tahmineh</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4146-1685</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemistry Department, Payame Noor University, Tehran 19395-4697, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hosseini</LastName><ForeName>Hasan Ali</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemistry Department, Payame Noor University, Tehran 19395-4697, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Bioinorg Chem Appl</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101200445</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anticancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antimicrobial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electrochemical sensor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxovanadium complex</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41281624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12638153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/bca/8974330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pucci C., Martinelli C., Ciofani G. Innovative Approaches for Cancer Treatment: Current Perspectives and New Challenges. Ecancer Medical Science . 2020;13:p. 961. doi: 10.3332/ecancer.2019.961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3332/ecancer.2019.961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6753017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31537986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mccarthy M. W., Kontoyiannis D. P., Cornely O. A., Perfect J. R., Walsh T. J. Novel Agents and Drug Targets to Meet the Challenges of Resistant Fungi. The Journal of Infectious Diseases . 2017;216(suppl_3):s474&#x2013;s483. doi: 10.1093/infdis/jix130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jix130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28911042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudel M., Schwarte J. V., Fromm K. M. New Antimicrobial Strategies Based on Metal Complexes. Chemistry . 2020;2(4):849&#x2013;899. doi: 10.3390/chemistry2040056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/chemistry2040056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scalese G., P&#xe9;rez N., Pereyra J., et al. Broadening the Chemical Diversity of Oxidovanadium(V) Complexes for Targeting Neglected Tropical Diseases. Journal of Inorganic Biochemistry . 2025;269:p. 112891. doi: 10.1016/j.jinorgbio.2025.112891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinorgbio.2025.112891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40112427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohanfekr T., Hakimi M., Hosseini H. A., Dusek M., Kucerakova M. Synthesis, Crystal Structure and Spectral Characterization of a New Caesium-Sodium-Isopolyvanadate: Photodegradation of Methylene Blue Dye. Journal of Chemical Crystallography . 2024;54(2):132&#x2013;139. doi: 10.1007/s10870-024-01005-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10870-024-01005-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacopetta D., Ceramella J., Catalano A., et al. Schiff Bases: Interesting Scaffolds With Promising Antitumoral Properties. Applied Sciences . 2021;11(4):p. 1877. doi: 10.3390/app11041877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app11041877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehder D. Import and Implications of Vanadium in Live Aspects. Inorganics . 2023;11(6):p. 256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehder D. The Potentiality of Vanadium in Medicinal Applications. Inorganica Chimica Acta . 2020;504:p. 119445. doi: 10.1016/j.ica.2020.119445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ica.2020.119445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevi&#xf1;o S., D&#xed;az A., S&#xe1;nchez-Lara E., et al. Vanadium in Biological Action: Chemical, Pharmacological Aspects, and Metabolic Implications in Diabetes Mellitus. Biological Trace Element Research . 2018;188(1):68&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1007/s12011-018-1540-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12011-018-1540-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6373340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30350272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahirovi&#x107; A., Had&#x17e;ali&#x107; S., Vi&#x161;njevac A., et al. Vanadium(IV) Complexes of Salicylaldehyde-Based Furoic Acid Hydrazones: Synthesis, BSA Binding and In Vivo Antidiabetic Potential. Journal of Inorganic Biochemistry . 2023;244:p. 112232. doi: 10.1016/j.jinorgbio.2023.112232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinorgbio.2023.112232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37084582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correia I., Ad&#xe3;o P., Roy S., et al. Hydroxyquinoline Derived Vanadium(IV and V) and Copper(II) Complexes as Potential Anti-Tuberculosis and Anti-Tumor Agents. Journal of Inorganic Biochemistry . 2014;141:83&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1016/j.jinorgbio.2014.07.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinorgbio.2014.07.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25226436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Y., Qi H., Wang G., Li L., Zhou D. Anticancer Effect of Sodium Metavanadate on Murine Breast Cancer Both In Vitro and In Vivo. Biometals . 2021;34(3):557&#x2013;571. doi: 10.1007/s10534-021-00295-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10534-021-00295-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33689084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa Pessoa J., Garribba E., Santos M. F. A., Santos-silva T. Vanadium and Proteins: Uptake, Transport, Structure, Activity and Function. Coordination Chemistry Reviews . 2015;301-302:49&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1016/j.ccr.2015.03.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccr.2015.03.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oiye &#xc9;. N., Fernanda M., Ribeiro M., et al. Electrochemical Sensors Containing Schiff Bases and Their Transition Metal Complexes to Detect Analytes of Forensic, Pharmaceutical and Environmental Interest. Critical Reviews in Analytical Chemistry . 2019;49:488&#x2013;509. doi: 10.1080/10408347.2018.1561242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408347.2018.1561242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30767567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levina A., Lay P. A. Stabilities and Biological Activities of Vanadium Drugs: What is the Nature of the Active Species. Chemistry &#x2013; An Asian Journal . 2017;12(14):1692&#x2013;1699. doi: 10.1002/asia.201700463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/asia.201700463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28401668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turtoi M., Anghelache M., Patrascu A. A., et al. Synthesis, Characterization, and In Vitro Insulin-Mimetic Activity Evaluation of Valine Schiff Base Coordination Compounds of Oxidovanadium(V) Biomedicines . 2021;9(5):p. 562. doi: 10.3390/biomedicines9050562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines9050562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8156053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34067862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav P., Shah K. Quinolines, a Perpetual, Multipurpose Scaffold in Medicinal Chemistry. Bioorganic Chemistry . 2021;109:p. 104639. doi: 10.1016/j.bioorg.2021.104639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bioorg.2021.104639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33618829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherdtrakulkiat R., Boonpangrak S., Sinthupoom N., Prachayasittikul S., Ruchirawat S., Prachayasittikul V. Derivatives (Halogen, Nitro and Amino) of 8-Hydroxyquinoline With Highly Potent Antimicrobial and Antioxidant Activities. Biochemistry and Biophysics Reports . 2016;6:135&#x2013;141. doi: 10.1016/j.bbrep.2016.03.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrep.2016.03.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5689172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29214226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta R., Luxami V., Paul K. Insights of 8-Hydroxyquinolines: A Novel Target in Medicinal Chemistry. Bioorganic Chemistry . 2021;108:p. 104633. doi: 10.1016/j.bioorg.2021.104633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bioorg.2021.104633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33513476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal M., Nagaraju V., Karunakar G. V., Sarma B., Borah B. J., Bania K. K. Electronic, Conjugation, and Confinement Effects on Structure, Redox, and Catalytic Behavior of Oxido-Vanadium(IV) and (V) Chiral Schiff Base Complexes. Journal of Physical Chemistry C . 2015;119(52):28854&#x2013;28870. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpcc.5b07559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.5b07559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leuaa P., Priyadarshani D., Choudhury D., Maurya R., Neergat M. Resolving Charge-Transfer and Mass-Transfer Processes of VO 2+/VO2+ Redox Species Across the Electrode/Electrolyte Interface Using Electrochemical Impedance Spectroscopy for Vanadium Redox Flow Battery. RSC Advances . 2020;10(51):30887&#x2013;30895. doi: 10.1039/d0ra05224h.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d0ra05224h</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9056327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35516052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohanfekr T., Hakimi M., Hassani H., Hosseini H. A. Synthesis, Characterization, and Antimicrobial Studies on a New Schiff Base Complex of Vanadium (V) Chemical Methodologies . 2023;7:748&#x2013;760. doi: 10.48309/chemm.2023.414603.1718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48309/chemm.2023.414603.1718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meerloo J. V., Kaspers G. J. L., Cloos J. Cancer Cell Culture: Methods and Protocols . 2nd. Berlin: Springer; 2011. Cell Sensitivity Assays: The MTT Assay; pp. 237&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21516412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ISO. International Standard . ISO; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barry A. L., Nadler M. D. H., Reller P., Sanders C. C., Swenson J. M. M26-A Methods for Determining Bactericidal Activity of Antimicrobial Agents; Approved Guideline This Document Provides Procedures for Determining the Lethal Activity of Antimicrobial Agents. Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute . 1999;19:1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adam M. S. S., Elsawy H. Biological Potential of Oxo-Vanadium Salicylediene Amino-Acid Complexes as Cytotoxic, Antimicrobial, Antioxidant and DNA Interaction. Journal of Photochemistry and Photobiology B: Biology . 2018;184:34&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1016/j.jphotobiol.2018.05.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jphotobiol.2018.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29778887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gyepes R., Schwendt P., Tatiersky J., et al. Stereochemistry of Vanadium Peroxido Complexes: The Case of the Quinoline-2-Carboxylato Ligand. Inorganic Chemistry . 2020;59(23):17162&#x2013;17170. doi: 10.1021/acs.inorgchem.0c02430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.inorgchem.0c02430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33180504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurya M. R., Khurana S., Rehder D. Six-Coordinated Oxovanadium (V) Complexes of Reduced Schiff Bases Derived From Amino Acids: Synthesis, Reactivity and Redox Studies. Transition Metal Chemistry . 2003;28(5):511&#x2013;517. doi: 10.1023/A:1025016603173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1025016603173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guglielmero L., Meskinfam M., Khatib M. A., et al. Electrochimica Acta Electrochemical and Spectroscopic Study of Vanadyl Acetylacetonate &#x2013; Ionic Liquids Interactions. Electrochimica Acta . 2021;373:p. 137865. doi: 10.1016/j.electacta.2021.137865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2021.137865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fattuoni C., Vascellari S., Pivetta T. Synthesis, Protonation Constants and Biological Activity Determination of Amino Acid-Salicylaldehyde-Derived Schiff Bases. Amino Acids . 2020;52(3):397&#x2013;407. doi: 10.1007/s00726-019-02816-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-019-02816-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31932980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie L., Liu L., Wang W., et al. The Structures, Spectroscopic Properties, and Photodynamic Reactions of Three [RuCl(QN)NO]&#x2212; Complexes (HQN=8-Hydroxyquinoline and Its Derivatives) as Potential NO-Donating Drugs. Bioinorganic Chemistry and Applications . 2018;2018:7029376&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1155/2018/7029376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/7029376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6305033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30627138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostenkova K., Levina A., Walters D. A., Murakami H. A., Lay P. A., Crans D. C. Vanadium (V) Pyridine-Containing Schiff Base Catecholate Complexes Are Lipophilic, Redox-Active and Selectively Cytotoxic in Glioblastoma (T98G) Cells. Chemistry-A European Journal . 2023;29(68):p. e202302271. doi: 10.1002/chem.202302271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/chem.202302271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37581946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousef Ebrahimipour S., Mohamadi M., Sheikhshoaie I., Su&#xe1;rez S., Baggio R., Khaleghi M. A Novel Oxido-Vanadium(V) Schiff Base Complex: Synthesis, Spectral Characterization, Crystal Structure, Electrochemical Evaluation, and Biological Activity. Research on Chemical Intermediates . 2016;42(2):611&#x2013;623. doi: 10.1007/s11164-015-2045-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11164-015-2045-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son J., Wei J., Cobden D., et al. Hydrothermal Synthesis of Monoclinic VO2 Micro- and Nanocrystals in One Step and Their Use in Fabricating Inverse Opals. Chemistry of Materials . 2010;22(10):3043&#x2013;3050. doi: 10.1021/cm903727u.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/cm903727u</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z., Xiao X., Lu X., Zhan Y., Cheng H., Xu G. A Simple and Low-Cost Combustion Method to Prepare Monoclinic VO2 With Superior Thermochromic Properties. Scientific Reports . 2016;6(1):p. 39154. doi: 10.1038/srep39154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep39154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5156956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27976748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahani M. K., Yadava U., Pandey O. P., Sengupta S. K. Synthesis, Spectral Characterization and Antimicrobial Studies of Nano-Sized Oxovanadium(IV) Complexes With Schiff Bases Derived From 5-(Phenyl/Substituted Phenyl)-2-Hydrazino-1,3,4-Thiadiazole and Indoline-2,3-Dione. Spectrochimica Acta Part A: Molecular and Biomolecular Spectroscopy . 2014;125:189&#x2013;194. doi: 10.1016/j.saa.2014.01.041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.saa.2014.01.041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24548812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittemeijer E. J., Welzel U. The &#x201c;State of the Art&#x201d; of the Diffraction Analysis of Crystallite Size and Lattice Strain. Zeitschrift f&#xfc;r Kristallographie . 2008;223(9):552&#x2013;560. doi: 10.1524/zkri.2008.1213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1524/zkri.2008.1213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nechay B. R., Nanninga L. B., Nechay P. S. Vanadyl (IV) and Vanadate (V) Binding to Selected Endogenous Phosphate, Carboxyl, and Amino Ligands; Calculations of Cellular Vanadium Species Distribution. Archives of Biochemistry and Biophysics . 1986;251(1):128&#x2013;138. doi: 10.1016/0003-9861(86)90059-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0003-9861(86)90059-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3789729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raymundo-pereira P. A., Teixeira M. F. S., Fatibello-filho O., Dockal E. R., Bonif&#xe1;cio V. G., Marcolino-junior L. H. Electrochemical Sensor for Ranitidine Determination Based on Carbon Paste Electrode Modi Fi Ed With Oxovanadium (IV) Salen Complex. Materials Science and Engineering: C . 2013;33(7):4081&#x2013;4085. doi: 10.1016/j.msec.2013.05.051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msec.2013.05.051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23910317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan L., Xie Q., Yao S. Electrochemical and Spectroelectrochemical Studies on Pyridoxine Hydrochloride Using a Poly (Methylene Blue) Modified Electrode. Electroanalysis . 2004;16(19):1592&#x2013;1597. doi: 10.1002/elan.200302993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/elan.200302993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira M. F. S., Marino G., Dockal E. R., Cavalheiro &#xc9;. T. G. Voltammetric Determination of Pyridoxine (Vitamin B6) at a Carbon Paste Electrode Modified With Vanadyl (IV)-Salen Complex. Analytica Chimica Acta . 2004;508(1):79&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1016/j.aca.2003.11.046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aca.2003.11.046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waelder J., Maldonado S. Beyond the Laviron Method: A New Mathematical Treatment for Analyzing the Faradaic Current in Reversible, Quasi-Reversible, and Irreversible Cyclic Voltammetry of Adsorbed Redox Species. Analytical Chemistry . 2021;93(37):12672&#x2013;12681. doi: 10.1021/acs.analchem.1c02503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.analchem.1c02503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34498854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavagnini I., Antiochia R., Magno F. A Calibration&#x2010;Base Method for the Evaluation of the Detection Limit of an Electrochemical Biosensor. Electroanalysis . 2007;19(11):1227&#x2013;1230. doi: 10.1002/elan.200703847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/elan.200703847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levina A., Scalese G., Gambino D., Crans D. C., Lay P. A. Solution Chemistry and Anti-Proliferative Activity Against Glioblastoma Cells of a Vanadium (V) Complex With Two Bioactive Ligands. Frontiers in Chemical Biology . 2024;3:1394645&#x2013;14. doi: 10.3389/fchbi.2024.1394645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fchbi.2024.1394645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh M. Z., Ho W. Y., Yeap S. K., Ali N. M., Boo L., Alitheen N. B. Regulation of Cellular and Cancer Stem Cell-Related Putative Gene Expression of Parental and CD44+ CD24&#x2212; Sorted MDA-MB-231 Cells by Cisplatin. Pharmaceuticals . 2021;14(5):p. 391. doi: 10.3390/ph14050391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ph14050391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8143088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinda R., Garribba E., Sanna D., Crans D. C., Pessoa J. C. Hydrolysis, Ligand Exchange, and Redox Properties of Vanadium Compounds: Implications of Solution Transformation on Biological, Therapeutic, and Environmental Applications. Chemical Reviews . 2025;125(3):1468&#x2013;1603. doi: 10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39818783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pessoa J. C., Correia I. Misinterpretations in Evaluating Interactions of Vanadium Complexes With Proteins and Other Biological Targets. Inorganics . 2021;9(2):p. 17. doi: 10.3390/INORGANICS9020017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/INORGANICS9020017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowalski S., Wyrzykowski D., Inkielewicz-St&#x119;pniak I. Molecular and Cellular Mechanisms of Cytotoxic Activity of Vanadium Compounds Against Cancer Cells. Molecules . 2020;25(7):p. 1757. doi: 10.3390/molecules25071757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules25071757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7180481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32290299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohanfekr T., Gholamrezazadeh C., Hosseini H. A. Vanadium 8 &#x2013; Hydroxyquinoline Derivatives in Medicine: Current State and Future Outlook. Biometals . 2025;38(3):711&#x2013;736. doi: 10.1007/s10534-025-00683-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10534-025-00683-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40329148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma N., Thakur M., Chaudhry S. C., Chaudhry S. C. Monooxovanadium (V) 2- Phenylphenoxides: Synthesis, Characterization, and Antimicrobial Potential. Journal of Coordination Chemistry . 2010;63(6):1071&#x2013;1079. doi: 10.1080/00958971003710377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00958971003710377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damena T., Zeleke D., Desalegn T., Demissie T. B., Eswaramoorthy R. Synthesis, Characterization, and Biological Activities of Novel Vanadium (IV) and Cobalt (II) Complexes. ACS Omega . 2022;7(5):4389&#x2013;4404. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.1c06205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.1c06205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8829937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35155932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes A. T., Balagtey L. B., Doctolero J. S., Madrid F. N. Profiles of Enterococcus faecalis to Selected Antibiotics. Journal of Drug Delivery and Therapeutics Susceptibility . 2020;10:93&#x2013;96. doi: 10.22270/jddt.v10i4.4155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22270/jddt.v10i4.4155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prajapati S., Sharma M., Kumar A., et al. Antimicrobial Activity of Different Homoeopathic Drugs and Their Potencies Against &#x2018;Aspergillus niger&#x2019; In Vitro. Indian Journal of Research in Homoeopathy . 2019;13(3):150&#x2013;158. doi: 10.4103/ijrh.ijrh_46_18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijrh.ijrh_46_18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15a;cibior A., Kurus J. Vanadium and Oxidative Stress Markers &#x2013; In Vivo Model: A Review. Current Medicinal Chemistry . 2019;26(29):5456&#x2013;5500. doi: 10.2174/0929867326666190108112255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/0929867326666190108112255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30621554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15a;cibior A., Pietrzyk &#x141;., Plewa Z., et al. Vanadium: Risks and Possible Benefits in the Light of a Comprehensive Overview of Its Pharmacotoxicological Mechanisms and Multi-Applications With a Summary of Further Research Trends. Journal of Trace Elements in Medicine &amp; Biology . 2020;61:p. 126508. doi: 10.1016/j.jtemb.2020.126508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtemb.2020.126508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7152879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32305626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matada B. S., Pattanashettar R., Yernale G. A Comprehensive Review on the Biological Interest of Quinoline and Its Derivatives. Bioorganic &amp; Medicinal Chemistry . 2021;32:p. 115973. doi: 10.1016/j.bmc.2020.115973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bmc.2020.115973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33444846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>