<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41514411</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6831</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC oral health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Oral Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical and radiographic evaluation of autologous albumin-rich platelet-rich fibrin membrane versus synthetic collagen membrane for immediate dental implant placement in the maxillary esthetic zone: a preliminary randomized clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>292</StartPage><MedlinePgn>292</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">292</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12903-026-07683-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Long-term aesthetic stability following immediate implant placement depends on achieving predictable bone regeneration within the peri-implant &#x201c;jumping gap&#x201d; and existing labial bone defects. Despite using a beta-tricalcium phosphate/calcium sulfate putty bone graft (&#x3b2;-TCP&#x2009;+&#x2009;CS), regenerative membranes are essential adjuncts to ensure superior healing. Therefore, this preliminary study aimed to determine whether autologous Albumin-Platelet-Rich Fibrin (Alb-PRF) provides superior aesthetic and osseous outcomes compared with the standard synthetic collagen membrane.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS">This single-blind, preliminary randomized clinical trial involved 20 participants with a non-restorable maxillary aesthetic tooth and a labial bone defect who received immediate implants. Participants were allocated into two groups (n=10 each): Group I received a &#x3b2;-TCP + CS putty combined with a synthetic collagen membrane, while Group II received the same bone graft combined with an Alb-PRF membrane placed in the labial jumping gap. Primary outcome variables, including marginal bone loss (MBL) and labial bone thickness (LBT), were assessed via CBCT at baseline, 6 months, and 12 months. Secondary outcomes included the Pink Esthetic Score (PES) and clinical parameters (Plaque Index, Bleeding on Probing, and Peri-implant Probing Depth), which were measured at baseline, 4, 6, and 12 months post-surgery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Clinical parameters showed no significant inter-group differences. However, Group II demonstrated significantly higher PES scores at 4 months (p=0.027) and 12 months (p=0.018). While Group I exhibited significantly better preservation of LBT at 6 months (p=0.005) and 12 months (p=0.001), Group II showed significantly less MBL at 6 months (P &#x2264; 0.001) and 12 months (p=0.023).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Both membranes effectively treat peri-implant defects. While the collagen membrane better preserves labial bone thickness, Alb-PRF yields superior aesthetic scores and reduces marginal bone loss.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">This preliminary randomized clinical trial was registered on ClinicalTrials.gov and approved on 15/10/2024 with trial number (NCT06643468).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12903-026-07683-2.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alsabahi</LastName><ForeName>Hamza</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5690-9462</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oral Medicine and Periodontology, Faculty of Dentistry Ibb University, Ibb, Yemen. hamzadent4@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oral Medicine, Periodontology, Diagnosis, and Oral Radiology, Faculty of Dentistry, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Aldakahlia, Egypt. hamzadent4@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mowafey</LastName><ForeName>Bassant</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oral Medicine, Periodontology, Diagnosis, and Oral Radiology, Faculty of Dentistry, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Aldakahlia, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kandil</LastName><ForeName>Islam</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oral Medicine, Periodontology, Diagnosis, and Oral Radiology, Faculty of Dentistry, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Aldakahlia, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elgohary</LastName><ForeName>Nesma</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Fixed Prosthodontics, Faculty of Dentistry, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Aldakahlia, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Youssef</LastName><ForeName>Jilan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oral Medicine, Periodontology, Diagnosis, and Oral Radiology, Faculty of Dentistry, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Aldakahlia, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Oral Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088684</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6831</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Albumin-Platelet-Rich fibrin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alloplastic bone grafting material</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bone substitutes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calcium phosphates</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calcium sulfate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Collagen membrane</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dental implantation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted in compliance with the ethical standards of the responsible institutional committee and the Declaration of Helsinki (1964), as revised. The Research Ethics Committee of the Faculty of Dentistry, Mansoura University, Egypt, formally reviewed and approved the protocol (Approval No.: A02090230M). Informed consent was acquired from all participants involved in the study (provided as a supplementary file). Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41514411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12903329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-026-07683-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12903-026-07683-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jung RE, Ioannidis A, Hammerle CHF, Thoma DS. Alveolar ridge preservation in the esthetic zone. Periodontol 2000. 2018;77(1):165&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/prd.12209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29484712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naiem SN, Al-Nawas B, Tawfik OK, El-Nahass H. Jumping gap in immediate implant placement in the esthetic zone: A virtual implant planning using cone-beam computed tomography. J Prosthodont Res. 2024;68(2):347&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2186/jpr.JPR_D_23_00033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37574277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Ebiary SO, Atef M, Abdelaziz MS, Khashaba M. Guided immediate implant with and without using a mixture of autogenous and Xeno bone grafts in the dental esthetic zone. A randomized clinical trial. BMC Res Notes. 2023;16(1):331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13104-023-06612-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10644537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37957760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatahet F, Al-assaf M, Al Manadili AI, Alsabbagh MM, Tolibah YA. The effects of &#x3b2;-TCP and &#x3b2;-TCP/CS (EthOss<sup>&#xae;</sup>) bone substitutes on rabbit tibia bone healing: A histological comparative study. AMJ. 2023;63:10077&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas MV, Puleo DA. Calcium sulfate: properties and clinical applications. J Biomed Mater Res B Appl Biomater. 2009;88(2):597&#x2013;610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jbm.b.31269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19025981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Serrano J, Vallina C, Gonzalez-Serrano C, Sanchez-Monescillo A, Torres J, Hernandez G, Lopez-Pintor RM. Effect of platelet concentrates on marginal bone loss of immediate implant procedures: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis. Mater (Basel). 2021;14(16):4582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14164582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8401659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34443105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumari S, Sharma AK, Sunil MKS, Koppula SK, Sharma S. A randomized controlled study comparing Albumin-Enriched Platelet-Rich fibrin and conventional Platelet-Rich fibrin for the treatment of intrabony defects. J Pharm Bioallied Sci. 2025;17(Suppl 2):S1619&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jpbs.jpbs_190_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12244829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40655725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barros Mour&#xe3;o CA, Gheno E, Louren&#xe7;o E, Barbosa RL, Kurtzman G, Javid K, Mavropoulos E, Benedicenti S, Calasans-Maia M, de Mello Machado R et al. Characterization of a new membrane from concentrated growth factors associated with denaturized albumin (Alb-CGF) for clinical applications: A preliminary study. Int J Growth Factors Stem Cells Dent. 2018;1(2):64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miron RJ, Pikos MA, Estrin NE, Kobayashi-Fujioka M, Espinoza AR, Basma H, Zhang Y. Extended platelet-rich fibrin. Periodontol 2000. 2024;94(1):114&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/prd.12537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37986559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elian N, Cho SC, Froum S, Smith RB, Tarnow DP. A simplified socket classification and repair technique. Pract Proced Aesthet Dent. 2007;19(2):99&#x2013;104. quiz 106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17491484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daabiss M. American society of anaesthesiologists physical status classification. Indian J Anaesth. 2011;55(2):111&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0019-5049.79879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3106380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21712864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Zhang Z, Wang P, Zheng Y, Wang Z, Wang Z. The relationship between adequate keratinized mucosa and peri-implant disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Oral Health. 2025;25(1):345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-025-05680-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11883984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40050830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goutam M, Singh M, Patel D. A literature review on effects of smoking on the success of dental implants. J Dent Implant. 2013;3(1):46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0974-6781.111693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abed H. Dental considerations for head and neck cancer: A clinical review. Saudi Dent J. 2023;35(5):476&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sdentj.2023.05.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10373080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37520601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvi GE, Lang NP. Diagnostic parameters for monitoring peri-implant conditions. Int J Oral Maxillofac Implants. 2004;19 Suppl:116&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15635952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renvert S, Persson GR, Pirih FQ, Camargo PM. Peri-implant health, peri-implant mucositis, and peri-implantitis: case definitions and diagnostic considerations. J Clin Periodontol. 2018;45(Suppl 20):S278&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29926496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dukka H, Saleh MHA, Ravida A, Greenwell H, Wang HL. Is bleeding on probing a reliable clinical indicator of peri-implant diseases? J Periodontol. 2021;92(12):1669&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/JPER.20-0890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33829501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furhauser R, Florescu D, Benesch T, Haas R, Mailath G, Watzek G. Evaluation of soft tissue around single-tooth implant crowns: the Pink esthetic score. Clin Oral Implants Res. 2005;16(6):639&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0501.2005.01193.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16307569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi S, Ding F, Liu X, Wang L, Wang X, Zhang S, Zhao G, Song Y. Clinical and radiographic variables related to implants with simultaneous grafts among type 2 diabetic patients treated with different hypoglycemic medications: a retrospective study. BMC Oral Health. 2021;21(1):214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-021-01583-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8080327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33906655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuentes R, Flores T, Navarro P, Salamanca C, Beltran V, Borie E. Assessment of buccal bone thickness of aesthetic maxillary region: a cone-beam computed tomography study. J Periodontal Implant Sci. 2015;45(5):162&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5051/jpis.2015.45.5.162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4635437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26550524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gakonyo J, Mohamedali AJ, Mungure EK. Cone beam computed tomography assessment of the buccal bone thickness in anterior maxillary teeth: relevance to immediate implant placement. Int J Oral Maxillofac Implants. 2018;33(4):880&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11607/jomi.6274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30025005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh RU, Rudek I, Wang HL. Immediate implant placement: positives and negatives. Implant Dent. 2010;19(2):98&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ID.0b013e3181d47eaf</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20386212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jofre J, Valenzuela D, Quintana P, Asenjo-Lobos C. Protocol for immediate implant replacement of infected teeth. Implant Dent. 2012;21(4):287&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ID.0b013e31825cbcf8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22814552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kan JY, Rungcharassaeng K, Sclar A, Lozada JL. Effects of the facial osseous defect morphology on gingival dynamics after immediate tooth replacement and guided bone regeneration: 1-year results. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2007;65(7 Suppl 1):13&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joms.2007.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17586345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linares A, Dopico J, Magrin G, Blanco J. Critical review on bone grafting during immediate implant placement. Periodontol 2000. 2023;93(1):309&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/prd.12516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37658586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cinar IC, Zboun M, Saglanmak A, Mijiritsky E. Immediate implantation with autologous mineralized dentin graft versus deproteinized bovine bone as Space-Filling substitute in maxillary anterior zone: retrospective radiological and clinical study. J Clin Med. 2024;13(18):5521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm13185521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11432380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39337008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibly O, Patel N, Albandar JM, Kutkut A. Bone regeneration around implants in periodontally compromised patients: a randomized clinical trial of the effect of immediate implant with immediate loading. J Periodontol. 2010;81(12):1743&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1902/jop.2010.100162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20681808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairbairn P, Kilner S, O&#x2019;Hooley D, Fish A, Kurtzman GM. Sinus augmentation for implant placement utilizing a novel synthetic graft material with delayed immediate socket grafting: A 2-Year case study. J Clin Med. 2023;12(7):2485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12072485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10095567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37048568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leventis M, Fairbairn P, Horowitz RA, Kalyvas D. Synthetic bone grafts in contemporary oral surgery and Implantology. Newest developments and perspectives. Odontostomatol Prog. 2017;71:222&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Hooley D, Fairbairn P, Kilner S, Horowitz R, Kurtzman G. Bone regeneration using an alloplastic graft material that combines &#x3b2; tricalcium phosphate and calcium sulphate: A case series report with histology. Med Res Archives. 2024;12(8).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alruwaili AQA, Ahmed DWS, Yaseen DAA, Elgohary DN. Extended sticky bone versus ethoss bone graft in horizontal ridge augmentation with simultaneous implant placement in the maxillary esthetic zone. Afr J Biomed Res. 2025;28(4s):969&#x2013;974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lourenco ES, Rocha NRS, de Lima Barbosa R, Mello-Machado RC, de Souza Lima VH, Leite PEC, Pereira MR, Casado PL, Kawase T, Mourao CF, et al. Investigating the biological efficacy of Albumin-Enriched Platelet-Rich fibrin (Alb-PRF): A study on cytokine dynamics and osteoblast behavior. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25(21):11531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms252111531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11547010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39519084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujioka-Kobayashi M, Schaller B, Mourao C, Zhang Y, Sculean A, Miron RJ. Biological characterization of an injectable platelet-rich fibrin mixture consisting of autologous albumin gel and liquid platelet-rich fibrin (Alb-PRF). Platelets. 2021;32(1):74&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09537104.2020.1717455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31959025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosmidis K, Ehsan K, Pitzurra L, Loos B, Jansen I. An in vitro study into three different PRF preparations for osteogenesis potential. J Periodontal Res. 2023;58(3):483&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jre.13116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36942454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaskaran M, Avinash BS, Avinash B, Priyadarshini V, Prashanth A. Effect of platelet-rich fibrin membrane on gingival crevicular fluid alkaline phosphatase levels in patients undergoing periodontally accelerated osteogenic orthodontics. Med J Armed Forces India. 2023;79(1):54&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mjafi.2021.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9807745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36605348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vadiati Saberi B, Khalighi Sigaroudi A, Kamani M, Rafiei E. Comparison of the effect of albumin with platelet-rich fibrin (Alb-PRF) gel and hyaluronic acid gel injection on interdental papilla reconstruction: A randomized clinical trial. J Adv Periodontol Implant Dent. 2024;16(2):109&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34172/japid.2024.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11699259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39758262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Stefano DA, Arosio P, Cappare P, Barbon S, Gherlone EF. Stability of dental implants and thickness of cortical bone: clinical research and future Perspectives. A systematic review. Mater (Basel). 2021;14(23):7183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14237183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8658728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34885335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toy VE, Uslu MO. Evaluation of long-term dental implant success and marginal bone loss in postmenopausal women. Niger J Clin Pract. 2020;23(2):147&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/njcp.njcp_295_19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi X, Li X, Tian Y, Qu X, Zhai S, Liu Y, Jia W, Cui Y, Chu S. Physical, mechanical, and biological properties of collagen membranes for guided bone regeneration: a comparative in vitro study. BMC Oral Health. 2023;23(1):510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-023-03223-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10362553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37481548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia K, You J, Zhu Y, Li M, Chen S, Ren S, Chen S, Zhang J, Wang H, Zhou Y. Platelet-rich fibrin as an autologous biomaterial for bone regeneration: mechanisms, applications, optimization. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2024;12:1286035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2024.1286035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11058865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38689760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumida R, Maeda T, Kawahara I, Yusa J, Kato Y. Platelet-rich fibrin increases the osteoprotegerin/receptor activator of nuclear factor-kappaB ligand ratio in osteoblasts. Exp Ther Med. 2019;18(1):358&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6566034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31258673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro AB, Meschi N, Temmerman A, Pinto N, Lambrechts P, Teughels W, Quirynen M. Regenerative potential of leucocyte- and platelet-rich fibrin. Part B: sinus floor elevation, alveolar ridge preservation and implant therapy. A systematic review. J Clin Periodontol. 2017;44(2):225&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcpe.12658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5347939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27891638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>