<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41188436</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mechanism and prevention of bed separation water hazards in karst coal mining areas of Northern Guizhou Province, China.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>38655</StartPage><MedlinePgn>38655</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">38655</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-22593-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study used the Tenglong Coal Mine in northern Guizhou as a case study to prevent or control bed separation water disasters caused by complex hydrogeological conditions in karst mining areas. A systematic research approach integrating theoretical modeling, quantitative monitoring, and on-site prevention and control was used to analyze the dynamic evolution of overburden separation in karst areas and establish a prevention system. The rock mechanics theory was used to identify the location of bed separation and establish a mechanical model of the roof containing a conical funnel-shaped karst cave. The cusp catastrophe theory was applied to derive a safety distance criterion between the karst cave and the separation zone. The box-counting fractal dimension (D) was used to quantify the dynamic evolution of the separation. It was 1.1881 after the working face reached 240&#xa0;m, and the maximum separation was 2.64&#xa0;m. A similarity simulation was conducted, and fiber Bragg grating (FBG) sensors and digital image correlation (DIC) were employed to measure the separation space. A site-specific system was developed to analyze bed separation water disasters, perform spatiotemporal prediction, and prevent or control them. The following was observed. (1) The higher the karst water pressure, the higher the load, and the thinner the rock layer, the more prone the area was to water inrush disasters. (2) The fractal dimension accurately described bed separation. Bed separation became critical when D exhibited a sudden step-like increase above 1.15. (3) A strong positive correlation existed between the strain and the separation ratio F. The maximum subsidence of high-level separation derived from DIC was 10.5&#xa0;mm, and the highest bed separation position occurred beneath the thick Changxing Formation limestone. (4) The proposed surface and underground drainage approach improved the drainage efficiency. This research provides theoretical support and technical guidance to prevent or control bed separation water disasters in karst mining areas.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Zhu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of GeoSciences and Surveying Engineering, China University of Mining and Technology (Beijing), Beijing, 100083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mining Engineering, Guizhou University of Engineering Science, Bijie, 551700, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Jiulong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of GeoSciences and Surveying Engineering, China University of Mining and Technology (Beijing), Beijing, 100083, China. jlcheng@cumtb.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yangui</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mining Engineering, Guizhou University of Engineering Science, Bijie, 551700, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Huazhou</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Key Laboratory of Paleontology and Geological Environment Evolution, Wuhan Center, China Geological Survey, Wuhan, 430205, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Guosheng</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mining Engineering, Guizhou University of Engineering Science, Bijie, 551700, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yuben</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety and Environmental Engineering, Shandong University of Science and Technology, Qingdao, 266590, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024QJJ012, KY[2022]124</GrantID><Agency>Scientific and Technological Research Project of the Education Department of Guizhou Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023BKH56</GrantID><Agency>Bijie City Science and Technology Research Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MS[2025] (No. 241)</GrantID><Agency>the Guizhou Provincial Basic Research Program (Natural Science)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>42274194</GrantID><Agency>the National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bed separation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cusp catastrophe theory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital image correlation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fiber bragg grating</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fractal dimension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Karst geology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41188436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12586675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-22593-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-22593-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cui, F. et al. Dynamic formation mechanism of a karst landslide triggered by mining of multiple-layer &amp; shallow-seated coal seams. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>51</b>, 317&#x2013;333 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldscheider, N., Chen, Z. &amp; Auler, A. S. Global distribution of carbonate rocks and karst water resources. <i>Hydrogeol. J.</i><b>28</b>, 1661&#x2013;1677 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10040-020-02139-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S., Song, D. &amp; Gao, M. The tight balance state and mechanism of disaster-resilient resources in karst small towns: a Chinese karst landform case study. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 758 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-85107-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11700133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39755824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivanik, O., Shevchuk, V. &amp; Kravchenko, D. Geological and Geomorphological factors of natural hazards in Ukrainian Carpathians. <i>J. Ecol. Eng.</i><b>20</b>, 177&#x2013;186 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12911/22998993/102964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, G. &amp; Qin, Y. Coalbed methane enrichment characteristics and exploration potential in karst areas of Southwest China. <i>Energy Explor. Exploit.</i><b>35</b>, 523&#x2013;542 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S., Wang, J. &amp; Feng, K. Life cycle assessment of coal mining in ecologically sensitive karst regions: A case from Guizhou, China. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>230</b>, 1276&#x2013;1287 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, X. &amp; Zhang, W. Characteristics of an underground Stope channel supplied by atmospheric precipitation and its water disaster prevention in the karst mining areas of Guizhou. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>1</b>, 15892 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-43209-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10517996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37741890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parise, M. &amp; Gunn, J. Natural and anthropogenic hazards in karst areas: A review. <i>Environ. Geol.</i><b>51</b>, 627&#x2013;637 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez, F., Guerrero, J. &amp; Lucha, P. Quantitative sinkhole hazard assessment in karst areas. <i>Geomorphology</i><b>99</b>, 364&#x2013;373 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, M. et al. Multi-hole joint acquisition of a 3D-RVSP in a karst area: case study in the Wulunshan coal Field, China. <i>Appl. Geophys.</i><b>17</b>, 37&#x2013;53 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11770-020-0808-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng, C., Mo, X. &amp; Qiang, X. Influence of tunnel construction on karst groundwater environment in central Huaying mountain. <i>Hydrogeol. Eng. Geol.</i><b>52</b>, 214&#x2013;224 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batugin, A. S. Similarities between strong rock bursts with fault-slip mechanism and induced earthquakes. <i>IOP Conf. Series: Earth Environ. Sci.</i><b>861</b>, 052044 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, J. et al. Establishment and application of bed-separation water inrush coefficient method considering water resistance of fractured rock mass. <i>Geofluids</i> 2, 1&#x2013;19. (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X., Li, H. &amp; Zhang, Y. Mechanisms of water inrush caused by bed separation in deep coal mines: A case study from the Ordos basin. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>148</b>, 105012 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H., Chen, Q., Shu, Z., Li, L. &amp; Zhang, Y. On prevention and mechanism of bed separation water inrush for Thick coal seams: A case study in China. <i>Environ. Earth Sci.</i><b>77</b>, 759 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-018-7952-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, R., Wu, J., Zhai, X. &amp; Liu, W. Recognition and prevention of bed separation water: based on trapezoid platform model. <i>Geofluids</i><b>2021</b>(S2), 1010 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, L., Bai, H. &amp; Ma, D. Prediction and prevention of water inrush hazards from bed separation space. <i>Mine Water Environ.</i><b>40</b>, 657&#x2013;670 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10230-020-00748-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, B., Wei, J. &amp; Huang, P. Hydrogeological characteristics and risk assessment of bed separation water inrush in Thick coal seam mining. <i>J. Hydrol.</i><b>603</b>, 127015 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, T. et al. Study on the dynamic evolution of overburden bed separation based on a bed separation water disaster. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>14</b>, 6925 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app14166925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gui, H., Tong, S., Qiu, W. &amp; Lin, M. Research on preventive technologies for bed&#x2013;separation water hazard in China coal mines. <i>Appl. Water Sci.</i><b>8</b>, 1&#x2013;11 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13201-018-0667-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, W., Zhao, T. &amp; Yang, X. Prevention technology of bed separation water disaster in deep mining: A review. <i>J. Geotech. GeoEnviron. Eng.</i><b>144</b>, 04018047 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, H., Yang, Q. &amp; Wang, X. Energy evolution mechanism during the formation of mining-induced bed separation. <i>Energy Sci. Eng.</i><b>6</b>, 523&#x2013;535 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H., Li, X. &amp; Zhang, Q. Fractal evolution of mining-induced fractures in overlying strata: insights from physical modeling and field monitoring. <i>Rock Mech. Rock Eng.</i><b>52</b>, 3245&#x2013;3261 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, X. &amp; Lyu, G. Mechanism of bed separation water inrush during the mining of Extra-Thick coal seam under Super-Thick sandstone aquifer. <i>Sustainability</i><b>15</b>, 10599 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su151310599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, L. et al. Water inrush mechanism of roof bed-separation and surface-underground combination treatment technology in Yuanzigou coal mine. <i>Saf. Coal Mines</i>. <b>55</b>, 176&#x2013;185 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao, W., Li, W. P. &amp; Li, X. Q. Mechanism and prevention of hydrostatic water inrush from roof-separated aquifer in mining face. <i>J. Min. Saf. Eng.</i><b>31</b>, 96&#x2013;104 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao, W. et al. Formation mechanism, disaster-causing mechanism, and prevention technology of water disaster from coal mine roof separation. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>46</b>, 507&#x2013;522 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, K., Li, W. &amp; Wang, Q. Formation mechanism and prediction method of water inrush from separated layers within coal seam mining: A case study in the Shilawusu mining area. <i>Eng. Fail. Anal.</i><b>103</b>, 158&#x2013;172 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2019.04.057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, J. P., Zhou, Y., Pu, Z. H. &amp; Pang, S. Y. Estimation method of water accumulation in separated layers and prediction of water inrush from separation: A case study of water inrush in the 1304 working face of Zhaoxian coal Mine, Shaanxi Province. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>47</b>, 3083&#x2013;3090 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, H., Zhou, A. M., Li, S. L. &amp; Gu, S. B. Catastrophic analysis on the thickness of consolidation for the water retarding formation at the bottom of shaft above the loaded water body. <i>Min. Res. Dev.</i><b>1</b>, 22&#x2013;25 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai, Y. B. <i>Research on safety distance between concealed karst cave and tunnel and it&#x2019;s intelligent prediction model</i>. Ph.D. Thesis, BJU (Beijing Jiaotong University), (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, Z., Xu, G., Li, H., Su, D. &amp; Liu, Y. Bed separation formation mechanism and water inrush evaluation in coal seam mining under a karst cave landform. <i>Processes</i><b>11</b>, 3413 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr11123413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, T. X. <i>Analysis on the mechanism between karst roof and pile foundation and study on simulation test</i>. Ph.D. Thesis, CSU (Central South University), (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, B. &amp; Liu, Z. J. Construction of mechanical model of water inrush from water-rich confined karst cave in coal seam floor and study on criterion. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>50</b>, 232&#x2013;237 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X. &amp; Xiao, H. Safety thickness analysis of tunnel floor in karst region based on catastrophe theory. <i>J. Cent. South. Univ.</i><b>23</b>, 2364&#x2013;2372 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11771-016-3295-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, B., Wang, X., Liu, Z. &amp; Li, T. Study on multi-field catastrophe evolution laws of water inrush from concealed karst cave in roadway excavation: A case of Jiyuan coal mine. <i>Geomatics Nat. Hazards Risk</i>. <b>12</b>, 222&#x2013;243 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19475705.2020.1870170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An, P., Li, M., Ma, S., Zhang, J. &amp; Huang, Z. Analysis of the thickness of the outburst prevention layer in karst tunnels under the control of compressive faults. <i>Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol.</i><b>147</b>, 105710 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2024.105710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, G. et al. Stability prediction of surrounding rock in tunnel crossing fault zone based on cusp catastrophe theory. <i>KSCE J. Civ. Eng.</i><b>28</b>, 4146&#x2013;4157 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12205-024-2478-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, Y., Tang, Q. &amp; Peng, L. Stability analysis and instability time prediction of tunnel roofs in a karst region based on catastrophe theory. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>15</b>, 978 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app15020978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, G. et al. Characteristics of stratum movement induced by downward Longwall mining activities in middle-distance multi-seam. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>136</b>, 104517 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2020.104517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, G., Xie, H., Gao, M., Li, C. &amp; He, Z. Numerical simulation on the evolution of mining-induced fracture network in a coal seam and its overburden under the top coal caving method. <i>Adv. Civ. Eng.</i> 5, 1&#x2013;14 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. Y., Wu, W. D. &amp; Wu, B. W. Grouting of bed separation spaces to control sliding of the high-located main key stratum during Longwall mining. <i>Q. J. Eng. Geol.Hydrogeol.</i><b>53</b>, 569&#x2013;578 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1144/qjegh2019-064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gou, R., Jiang, C., Liu, Y., Wang, C. &amp; Li, Y. Study on fractal characteristics of evolution of mining-induced fissures in karst landform. <i>Energies</i><b>15</b>, 5372 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15155372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji, Y., Cao, H. &amp; Zhao, B. Mechanism and control of water inrush from separated roof layers in the jurassic coalfields. <i>Mine Water Environ.</i><b>40</b>, 357&#x2013;365 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10230-021-00755-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J. et al. Three-dimensional physical model experiment of mining-induced-deformation and failure characteristics of roof and floor in deep-under-ground coal seams. <i>Process Saf. Environ. Prot.</i><b>150</b>, 400&#x2013;415 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2021.04.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. et al. New type of similar material for simulating the processes of water inrush from roof bed separation. <i>ACS OMEGA</i>. <b>5</b>, 30405&#x2013;30415 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.0c03535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7711710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33283088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. Similar simulation test of overlying rock failure and crack evolution in fully mechanized caving face with compound roof. <i>Geotech. Geol. Eng.</i><b>40</b>, 73&#x2013;82 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10706-021-01892-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gui, H., Lin, M. &amp; Song, X. Identification and application of roof bed separation (water) in coal mines. <i>Mine Water Environ.</i><b>37</b>, 376&#x2013;384 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10230-018-0518-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Wang, N. &amp; Lei, X. The subsidence mechanisms of primary key stratum with different factors: a case study. <i>Geotech. Geol. Eng.</i><b>41</b>, 4351&#x2013;4366 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10706-023-02507-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuang, H. Q., Xin, Y. Q. &amp; Li, S. G. Characterization of fissure distribution of overburden rock under roof cutting and entry retaining based on key strata theory. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>52</b>, 102&#x2013;113 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Z. L. <i>Elastic Mechanics</i> (Higher Education Press, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, J., Li, W., Qiao, W. &amp; Qang, Q. Risk assessment of water inrushes from bed separations in Cretaceous strata corresponding to different excavation lengths during mining in the Ordos Basin. <i>Geomat. Nat. Hazards Risk</i><b>12</b>, 2300&#x2013;2327 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An, P., Li, M., Zhang, W. &amp; Liu, X. Influence mechanism and calculation of the minimum safe thickness of waterproof rock mass in karst tunnels. <i>J. Mt. Sci.</i><b>22</b>, 695&#x2013;709 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11629-024-9260-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Z. et al. Monitoring of coal mine roadway roof separation based on fiber Bragg grating displacement sensors. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>74</b>, 128&#x2013;132 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2015.01.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piao, C. et al. Model test study on overburden settlement law in coal seam backfill mining based on fiber Bragg grating technology. <i>Arab. J. Geosci.</i><b>12</b>, 1&#x2013;9 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-019-4564-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Y. &amp; Li, Z. Early warning of roof collapse in coal mines using distributed FBG sensing systems. <i>Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol.</i><b>124</b>, 104492 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chai, J. et al. Research on the application of fiber Bragg grating monitoring for deformation of coal pillar in sections. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>52</b>, 126&#x2013;137 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei, F. X., Shang, Y. Q., Kong, D. Z. &amp; Zhang, P. F. DIC-based similar simulation study on the evolution patterns of mining-induced fracture, displacement and strain in close distance coal seam. <i>J. Min. Sci. Technol.</i><b>9</b>, 519&#x2013;528 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, W. M., Sun, L. L. &amp; Wang, G. Experimental research on coal seam similar material proportion and its application. <i>Int. J. Min. Sci. Technol.</i><b>26</b>, 913&#x2013;918 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmst.2016.05.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, J., Zhao, J., Dong, Y. &amp; Dong, Q. Quantitative prediction of water abundance in rock mass by transient electro-magnetic method with LBA-BP neural network. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>45</b>, 330&#x2013;337 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. et al. Mine transient electromagnetic method in detecting the water abundance of rock strata with low resistance in roof. <i>Min. Saf. Environ. Prot.</i><b>50</b>, 76&#x2013;81 (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>