<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41783456</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>43</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhancing physical performance with ischemic preconditioning: a systematic review and meta-analysis of moderators and performance outcomes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>511</StartPage><EndPage>554</EndPage><MedlinePgn>511-554</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2026.154945</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study examined the effects of ischemic preconditioning (IPC) on physical performance, considering the influence of timing, warm-up (WU), participant characteristics, and IPC protocols structure. A total of 90 trials (1,439 participants) were retrieved from three databases and assessed using PICOS criteria. Multilevel meta-analyses with cluster-robust variance adjustments were conducted to calculate pooled effect sizes (Hedge's g). Risk of bias and certainty of evidence were assessed using the RoB 2 tool and GRADE framework. IPC produced a trivial but significant improvement in physical performance (g = 0.13, P &lt; 0.01), which persisted after excluding SHAM effects (g = 0.10; P &lt; 0.01). Significant improvements were observed for maximum repetitions, time to failure, and power output, but not for jump ability, strength, or oxygen uptake. Comparable benefits were found for anaerobic (g = 0.15) and aerobic (g = 0.10) exercise, with greater effects in males and less-trained participants. Performance was further enhanced when IPC was followed by WU (g = 0.16), with the optimal IPC-to-WU interval being ~42 minutes. Without WU, the effective IPC window narrowed to 6-7 minutes. In practice, IPC can enhance physical performance, independently of sham effects, moderated by sex, training level, and WU. For competition or testing, the most effective strategy appears to be 3 or 4 &#xd7; 5-min IPC protocol, followed by a 42-min interval, standardized warm-up, and endurance testing. For mechanistic studies, WU should be excluded, and testing conducted 6-7 minutes post-IPC. Future research should target women, middle-aged individuals, and elite athletes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Institute of Sport &#x2013; National Research Instutite.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yilin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sports Training, Tianjin University of Sport, No.16 Donghai Road, Tuanbo New Town West, Jinghai District, Tianjin, 301617, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Kai</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Healt Sciences, Centre for Human Performance, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kong</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sports Training, Tianjin University of Sport, No.16 Donghai Road, Tuanbo New Town West, Jinghai District, Tianjin, 301617, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Mingyue</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Mar MacKillop Institute for Health Research, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne,VIC. 3000, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chenghao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sports Training, Tianjin University of Sport, No.16 Donghai Road, Tuanbo New Town West, Jinghai District, Tianjin, 301617, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sports Training, Tianjin University of Sport, No.16 Donghai Road, Tuanbo New Town West, Jinghai District, Tianjin, 301617, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kilduff</LastName><ForeName>Liam</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>A-STEM, School of Engineering, Swansea University, Swansea, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Welsh Institute of Performance Science (WIPS), Swansea University Performance Science, Swansea, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mota</LastName><ForeName>Gustavo R</ForeName><Initials>GR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Science, Health and Human Performance Research Group, Department of Sport Sciences, Institute of Health Sciences, Federal University of Tri&#xe2;ngulo Mineiro, Uberaba/MG, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Girard</LastName><ForeName>Olivier</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Science (Exercise and Sport Sciences), The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood flow restriction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ergogenic aids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Placebo</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Time window</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training level</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Warm-up protocols</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>All authors declare no conflicts of interest related to the research, authorship, or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41783456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12954497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2026.154945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">56933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Girard O, Amann M, Aughey R, et al. Position statement--altitude training for improving team-sport players&#x2019; performance: current knowledge and unresolved issues. Br J Sports Med. 2013; 47 Suppl 1:i8&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3903313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24282213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caru M, Levesque A, Lalonde F, et al. An overview of ischemic preconditioning in exercise performance: A systematic review. J Sport Health Sci. 2019; 8:355&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6620415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31333890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davids CJ, Roberts LA, Bj&#xf8;rnsen T, et al. Where Does Blood Flow Restriction Fit in the Toolbox of Athletic Development? A Narrative Review of the Proposed Mechanisms and Potential Applications. Sports Med. 2023; 53:2077&#x2013;2093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10587223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37578669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Babault N. Post-activation Potentiation Versus Post-activation Performance Enhancement in Humans: Historical Perspective, Underlying Mechanisms, and Current Issues. Front Physiol. 2019; 10:1359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6838751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31736781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murry CE, Jennings RB, Reimer KA. Preconditioning with ischemia: a delay of lethal cell injury in ischemic myocardium. Circulation. 1986;74(5):1124&#x2013;1136. doi: 10.1161/01.cir.74.5.1124</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.cir.74.5.1124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3769170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murry CE, Richard VJ, Reimer KA, Jennings RB. Ischemic preconditioning slows energy metabolism and delays ultrastructural damage during a sustained ischemic episode. Circ Res. 1990;66(4):913&#x2013;931. doi: 10.1161/01.res.66.4.913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.res.66.4.913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2317895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reimer KA, Murry CE, Jennings RB. Cardiac adaptation to ischemia. Ischemic preconditioning increases myocardial tolerance to subsequent ischemic episodes. Circulation. 1990; 82:2266&#x2013;2268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2146994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reimer KA, Murry CE, Yamasawa I, Hill ML, Jennings RB. Four brief periods of myocardial ischemia cause no cumulative ATP loss or necrosis. Am J Physiol. 1986;251 (6 Pt 2): H1306&#x2013;H1315. doi: 10.1152/ajpheart.1986.251.6.H1306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.1986.251.6.H1306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3789183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marocolo M, Hohl R, Arriel RA, et al. Ischemic preconditioning and exercise performance: are the psychophysiological responses underestimated? Eur J Appl Physiol. 2023; 123:683&#x2013;693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36478078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira TN, Sabino-Carvalho JLC, Lopes TR, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning and Repeated Sprint Swimming: A Placebo and Nocebo Study. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016; 48:1967&#x2013;1975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27187105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marocolo M, da Mota GR, Pelegrini V, et al. Are the Beneficial Effects of Ischemic Preconditioning on Performance Partly a Placebo Effect? Int J Sports Med. 2015; 36:822&#x2013;825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26058479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho L, Barroso R. Ischemic Preconditioning Improves Strength Endurance Performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2019; 33:3332&#x2013;3337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30844989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva Novaes J, da Silva Telles LG, Monteiro ER, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning Improves Resistance Training Session Performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2021; 35:2993&#x2013;2998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32224716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pethick J, Casselton C, Winter SL, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning Blunts Loss of Knee Extensor Torque Complexity with Fatigue. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021; 53:306&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7803438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32735115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira HM, de Lima FF, Silva BM, et al. Sex differences in fatigability after ischemic preconditioning of nonexercising limbs. Biol Sex Differ. 2020; 11:59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7590792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33109241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey TG, Birk GK, Cable NT, et al. Remote ischemic preconditioning prevents reduction in brachial artery flow-mediated dilation after strenuous exercise. American Journal of Physiology-Heart and Circulatory Physiology 2012; 303:H533&#x2013;H538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22730390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey TG, Jones H, Gregson W, Atkinson G, Cable NT, Thijssen DH. Effect of ischemic preconditioning on lactate accumulation and running performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44(11):2084&#x2013;2089. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e318262cb17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318262cb17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22843115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung CP, Slysz JT, Burr JF. Ischemic Preconditioning: Improved Cycling Performance Despite Nocebo Expectation. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020; 15:354&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31188700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crisafulli A, Tangianu F, Tocco F, et al. Ischemic preconditioning of the muscle improves maximal exercise performance but not maximal oxygen uptake in humans. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2011;111(2):530&#x2013;536. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00266.2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00266.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21617078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz RS, de Aguiar RA, Turnes T, Pereira KL, Caputo F. Effects of ischemic preconditioning on maximal constant-load cycling performance. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2015;119(9):961&#x2013;967. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00498.2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00498.2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26359484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paull EJ, Van Guilder GP. Remote ischemic preconditioning increases accumulated oxygen deficit in middle-distance runners. J Appl Physiol. 2019; 126:1193&#x2013;1203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30653416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson N, White J, Neish M, Murray A. Effect of ischemic preconditioning on land-based sprinting in team-sport athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2013;8(6):671&#x2013;676. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.8.6.671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.8.6.671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23578975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jean-St-Michel E, Manlhiot C, Li J, et al. Remote preconditioning improves maximal performance in highly trained athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011; 43:1280&#x2013;1286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21131871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams N, Russell M, Cook CJ, et al. Effect of Ischemic Preconditioning on Maximal Swimming Performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2021; 35:221&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29389691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richard P, Billaut F. Time-Trial Performance in Elite Speed Skaters After Remote Ischemic Preconditioning. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018; 13:1308&#x2013;1316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29745735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindner TD, Scholten SD, Halverson JM, et al. The Acute Effects of Ischemic Preconditioning on Power and Sprint Performance. S D Med. 2021; 74:210&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9272512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34437779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niespodzinski B, Mieszkowski J, Kochanowicz M, et al. Effect of 10 consecutive days of remote ischemic preconditioning on local neuromuscular performance. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2021; 60:102584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34388409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza HLR, Arriel RA, Mota GR, et al. Does ischemic preconditioning really improve performance or it is just a placebo effect? PLoS One. 2021; 16:e0250572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8092792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33939730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenzuela PL, Mart&#xed;n-Candilejo R, S&#xe1;nchez-Mart&#xed;nez G, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning and Muscle Force Capabilities. J Strength Cond Res. 2021; 35:2187&#x2013;2192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30908369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slysz JT, Burr JF. Impact of 8 weeks of repeated ischemic preconditioning on running performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019; 119:1431&#x2013;1437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30953176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeger JPH, Timmers S, Ploegmakers DJM, et al. Is delayed ischemic preconditioning as effective on running performance during a 5 km time trial as acute IPC? J Sci Med Sport. 2017; 20:208&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27260003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradis-Desch&#xea;nes P, Lapointe J, Joanisse DR, et al. Similar Recovery of Maximal Cycling Performance after Ischemic Preconditioning, Neuromuscular Electrical Stimulation or Active Recovery in Endurance Athletes. J Sports Sci Med. 2020; 19:761&#x2013;771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mieszkowski J, Stankiewicz B, Kochanowicz A, et al. Effect of Ischemic Preconditioning on Marathon-Induced Changes in Serum Exerkine Levels and Inflammation. Front Physiol. 2020; 11:571220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7609818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33192567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cocking S, Wilson MG, Nichols D, et al. Is There an Optimal Ischemic-Preconditioning Dose to Improve Cycling Performance? Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018; 13:274&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28657799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrens M, Zschorlich V, Mittlmeier T, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning Did Not Affect Central and Peripheral Factors of Performance Fatigability After Submaximal Isometric Exercise. Front Physiol. 2020; 11:371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7199714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32411014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clevidence MW, Mowery RE, Kushnick MR. The effects of ischemic preconditioning on aerobic and anaerobic variables associated with submaximal cycling performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012; 112:3649&#x2013;3654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22350355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldsmith M, Siegler J, Green S. Targeted effect of ischemic preconditioning on the gas exchange threshold in healthy males and females. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024; 124:2697&#x2013;2706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11365842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38642096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur G, Binger M, Evans C, et al. No influence of ischemic preconditioning on running economy. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017; 117:225&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28012036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Wu W, Qiang L, Wang C, He Z, Wang Y. The effect of ischemic preconditioning on physical fitness and performance: a meta-analysis in healthy adults. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2025;125(3):805&#x2013;821. doi: 10.1007/s00421-024-05633-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-024-05633-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39422720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisb&#xf4;a FD, Turnes T, Cruz RSO, et al. The time dependence of the effect of ischemic preconditioning on successive sprint swimming performance. J Sci Med Sport. 2017; 20:507&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27717653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza HLR, Oliveira GT, Meireles A, et al. Does ischemic preconditioning enhance sports performance more than placebo or no intervention? A systematic review with meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. Published online November 12, 2024. doi: 10.1016/j.jshs.2024.101010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2024.101010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11880722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39536913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Kong H, Xu K, Yin M, Xie Y. Comment on &#x201e;Does ischemic preconditioning enhance sports performance more than placebo or no intervention? A systematic review with meta-analysis&#x201d;. J Sport Health Sci. Published online May 14, 2025. doi: 10.1016/j.jshs.2025.101056</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2025.101056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12272098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40379133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Noortgate W, L&#xf3;pez-L&#xf3;pez JA, Mar&#xed;n-Mart&#xed;nez F, et al. Three-level meta-analysis of dependent effect sizes. Behav Res Methods. 2013; 45:576&#x2013;594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23055166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges LV, Tipton E, Johnson MC. Robust variance estimation in meta-regression with dependent effect size estimates. Res Synth Methods. 2010; 1:39&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26056092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung MW-L. A Guide to Conducting a Meta-Analysis with Non-Independent Effect Sizes. Neuropsychol Rev. 2019; 29:387&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6892772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31446547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira AL, Gangat A, Bommarito JC, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning Acutely Improves Functional Sympatholysis during Handgrip Exercise in Healthy Males but not Females. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2023; 55:1250&#x2013;1257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36878187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021; 372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019; 366:l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al. Updated guidance for trusted systematic reviews: a new edition of the Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;10(10): ED000142. doi: 10.1002/14651858. ED000142</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31643080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastin PB. Energy system interaction and relative contribution during maximal exercise. Sports Med. 2001; 31:725&#x2013;741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11547894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incognito AV, Burr JF, Millar PJ. The Effects of Ischemic Preconditioning on Human Exercise Performance. Sports Med. 2016; 46:531&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26645697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, et al. Defining Training and Performance Caliber: A Participant Classification Framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022;17(2):317&#x2013;331. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34965513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffreys I. Warm up revisited&#x2013;the &#x2018;ramp&#x2019;method of optimising performance preparation. Prof Strength Cond. 2007;6(44):12&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slysz JT, Petrick HL, Marrow JP, et al. An examination of individual responses to ischemic preconditioning and the effect of repeated ischemic preconditioning on cycling performance. Eur J Sport Sci. 2020; 20:633&#x2013;640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31429381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomschi F, Niemann D, Bloch W, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning Enhances Performance and Erythrocyte Deformability of Responders. Int J Sports Med. 2018; 39:596&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29883988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges L, Olkin I. Statistical methods for meta-analysis. Academic press. 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. 2nd ed. New York: Routledge, 1988. Epub ahead of print 1 July 1988. doi: 10.4324/9780203771587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4324/9780203771587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Castilla B, Aloe AM, Declercq L, et al. Estimating outcome-specific effects in meta-analyses of multiple outcomes: A simulation study. Behav Res Methods. 2021; 53:702&#x2013;717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32808180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic I, Castilla AP, Ramos AG, et al. The Acute and Chronic Effects of Implementing Velocity Loss Thresholds During Resistance Training: A Systematic Review, Meta-Analysis, and Critical Evaluation of the Literature. Sports Med. 2023; 53:177&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9807551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36178597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vembye MH, Pustejovsky JE, Pigott TD. Power approximations for overall average effects in meta-analysis with dependent effect sizes. J Educ Behav Stat. 2023;48(1):70&#x2013;102. doi: 10.3102/10769986221127379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/10769986221127379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton E, Pustejovsky JE. Small-Sample Adjustments for Tests of Moderators and Model Fit Using Robust Variance Estimation in Meta-Regression. J Educ Behav Stat. 2015; 40:604&#x2013;634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W. Conducting metaanalyses in R with the metafor package. J Stat Softw. 2010;36(3):1&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pustejovsky JE, Tipton E. Meta-analysis with Robust Variance Estimation: Expanding the Range of Working Models. Prev Sci. 2022; 23:425&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33961175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson ZP, Pelland JC, Remmert JF, et al. Exploring the Dose-Response Relationship Between Estimated Resistance Training Proximity to Failure, Strength Gain, and Muscle Hypertrophy: A Series of Meta-Regressions. Sports Med. 2024; 54:2209&#x2013;2231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38970765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu K, Blazevich AJ, Boullosa D, et al. Optimizing Post-activation Performance Enhancement in Athletic Tasks: A Systematic Review with Meta-analysis for Prescription Variables and Research Methods. Sports Med. 2025;55(4):977&#x2013;1008. doi: 10.1007/s40279-024-02170-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02170-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39853660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nash JC, Varadhan R. Unifying Optimization Algorithms to Aid Software System Users: optimx for R. J Stat Softw. 2011; 43:1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham H. ggplot2. Wiley interdisciplinary reviews: computational statistics. 2011; 3:180&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters JL, Sutton AJ, Jones DR, et al. Contour-enhanced meta-analysis funnel plots help distinguish publication bias from other causes of asymmetry. J Clin Epidemiol. 2008; 61:991&#x2013;996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18538991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Davey Smith G, Schneider M, et al. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ. 1997; 315:629&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W, Cheung MW-L. Outlier and influence diagnostics for meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods. 2010; 1:112&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26061377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens J. Outliers and Influential Data Points in Regression-Analysis. Psychol Bull. 1984; 95:334&#x2013;344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguinis H, Gottfredson RK, Joo H. Best-Practice Recommendations for Defining, Identifying, and Handling Outliers. Organ Res Methods. 2013; 16:270&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hooren B, Jukic I, Cox M, et al. The Relationship Between Running Biomechanics and Running Economy: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Observational Studies. Sports Med. 2024; 54:1269&#x2013;1316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11127892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38446400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Higgins JP, Vist GE, et al. Completing &#x2018;Summary of findings&#x2019; tables and grading the certainty of the evidence. In: Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd, 2019, pp. 375&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt G, Oxman AD, Akl EA, et al. GRADE guidelines: 1. IntroductionGRADE evidence profiles and summary of findings tables. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64(4):383&#x2013;394. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.04.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.04.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21195583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Higgins JP, Vist GE, et al. Completing &#x2018;Summary of findings&#x2019; tables and grading the certainty of the evidence. 2019; 375&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santesso N, Carrasco-Labra A, Langendam M, et al. Improving GRADE evidence tables part 3: detailed guidance for explanatory footnotes supports creating and understanding GRADE certainty in the evidence judgments. J Clin Epidemiol. 2016; 74:28&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26796947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albuquerque MR, Fl&#xf4;r CAG, Ribeiro AIS, et al. Effects of Ischemic Preconditioning on Sport-Specific Performance in Highly Trained Taekwondo Athletes. Sports (Basel). 2024; 12:179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11280546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39058070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva Telles LG, Billaut F, Cunha G, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning Improves Handgrip Strength and Functional Capacity in Active Elderly Women. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022; 19:6628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9180149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35682213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allois R, Pagliaro P, Roatta S. Ischemic Conditioning to Reduce Fatigue in Isometric Skeletal Muscle Contraction. Biology (Basel). 2023; 12:460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10044801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36979152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa TC, Machado AC, Braz ID, et al. Remote ischemic preconditioning delays fatigue development during handgrip exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25(3):356&#x2013;364. doi: 10.1111/sms.12229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24731023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho L, Barroso R. Effects of ischemic preconditioning on the isometric test variables. Sci Sports 2019; 34:E225&#x2013;E228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceylan B, Franchini E. Ischemic preconditioning does not improve judo-specific performance but leads to better recovery in elite judo athletes. Sci Sports. 2022;37(4):322.e1&#x2013;322.e7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceylan B, Ta&#x15f;k&#x131;n HB, &#x160;imenko J. Effect of Ischemic Preconditioning on Acute Recovery in Elite Judo Athletes: A Randomized, Single-Blind, Crossover Trial. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 2023; 18:180&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36638812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng C-F, Kuo Y-H, Hsu W-C, et al. Local and Remote Ischemic Preconditioning Improves Sprint Interval Exercise Performance in Team Sport Athletes. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021; 18:10653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8535734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34682399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz RS de O, de Aguiar RA, Turnes T, et al. Effects of ischemic preconditioning on short-duration cycling performance. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2016; 41:825&#x2013;831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27404398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz R, Tramontin AF, Oliveira AS, et al. Ischemic preconditioning increases spinal excitability and voluntary activation during maximal plantar flexion contractions in men. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2024; 34:e14591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38429941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dantas PAM, Da Silva Novaes J, Paz CR, et al. Acute effect of Ischemic Preconditioning in different blood flow restriction compressions on the anaerobic performance of trained individuals. Retos. 2024; 721&#x2013;727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Santana VJ, de Oliveira Deangelo CE, Cury Salemi VM, et al. The Influence of Ischemic Preconditioning on Neuromuscular Performance. Rev Bras Med Esporte. 2021; 27:207&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao X, Wang A, Fan J, et al. The effect of ischemic preconditioning on repeated sprint cycling performance: a randomized crossover study. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2024;64(11):1147&#x2013;1156. doi: 10.23736/S0022-4707.24.16015-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0022-4707.24.16015-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39023202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson N, Mahony B, Tracey C, Fawkner S, Murray A. Effect of ischemic preconditioning on repeated sprint ability in team sport athletes. J Sports Sci. 2015;33(11):1182&#x2013;1188. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2014.988741</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2014.988741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25517761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin PJ, Hughes L, Gissane C, et al. Effects of local versus remote ischemic preconditioning on repeated sprint running performance. J Sports Med Phys Fit. 2019; 59:187&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29722251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guilherme da Silva Telles L, Cristiano Carelli L, Dutra Br&#xe1;z I, et al. Effects of Ischemic Preconditioning as a Warm-Up on Leg Press and Bench Press Performance. J Hum Kinet. 2020; 75:267&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7706675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33312313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang B-H, Wang T-Y, Lu K-H, et al. Effects of ischemic preconditioning on local hemodynamics and isokinetic muscular function. Isokinetics Exerc Sci. 2020; 28:73&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kataoka R, Song JS, Yamada Y, et al. The Impact of Different Ischemic Preconditioning Pressures on Pain Sensitivity and Resistance Exercise Performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2024; 38:864&#x2013;872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38170759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraus AS. Bilateral upper limb remote ischemic preconditioning improves peak anaerobic power, http://hdl.handle.net/2152/26114 (2014, accessed 26 September 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim AT, Lim J, Girard O, Aziz AR, Tan F, Ihsan M. Effect of ischemic preconditioning on badminton-specific endurance and subsequent changes in physical performance. Sci Sports. 2023;38(1):102.e1&#x2013;102.e7. doi: 10.1016/j.scispo.2021.10.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scispo.2021.10.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes TR, Sabino-Carvalho JL, Ferreira THN, et al. Effect of Ischemic Preconditioning on the Recovery of Cardiac Autonomic Control From Repeated Sprint Exercise. Front Physiol. 2018; 9:1465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6212507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30416451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marocolo M, Marocolo IC, da Mota GR, et al. Beneficial Effects of Ischemic Preconditioning in Resistance Exercise Fade Over Time. Int J Sports Med. 2016; 37:819&#x2013;824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27348720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marocolo M, Willardson JM, Marocolo IC, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning and Placebo Intervention Improves Resistance Exercise Performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2016; 30:1462&#x2013;1469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26466134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paix&#xe3;o RC, da Mota GR, Marocolo M. Acute effect of ischemic preconditioning is detrimental to anaerobic performance in cyclists. Int J Sports Med. 2014; 35:912&#x2013;915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24863728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradis-Desch&#xea;nes P, Joanisse DR, Billaut F. Ischemic preconditioning increases muscle perfusion, oxygen uptake, and force in strength-trained athletes. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2016; 41:938&#x2013;944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27574913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradis-Desch&#xea;nes P, Joanisse DR, Billaut F. Sex-Specific Impact of Ischemic Preconditioning on Tissue Oxygenation and Maximal Concentric Force. Front Physiol. 2016; 7:674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5215068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28105020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Bezodis NE, Glaister M, et al. The Effect of Ischemic Preconditioning on Repeated Sprint Cycling Performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015; 47:1652&#x2013;1658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25412297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues AL, Ide BN, Sasaki JE, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning Improves the Bench-Press Maximal Strength in Resistance-Trained Men. Int J Exerc Sci. 2023; 16:217&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10124736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37113512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salagas A, Tsoukos A, Terzis G, et al. Effectiveness of either short-duration ischemic pre-conditioning, single-set high-resistance exercise, or their combination in potentiating bench press exercise performance. Front Physiol. 2022; 13:1083299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9797974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36589445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slysz JT, Burr JF. Enhanced Metabolic Stress Augments Ischemic Preconditioning for Exercise Performance. Front Physiol. 2018; 9:1621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6249303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30498458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutter EN, Mattlage AE, Bland MD, et al. Remote Limb Ischemic Conditioning and Motor Learning: Evaluation of Factors Influencing Response in Older Adults. Transl Stroke Res. 2019; 10:362&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6367068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30088217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka D, Suga T, Tanaka T, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning Enhances Muscle Endurance during Sustained Isometric Exercise. Int J Sports Med. 2016; 37:614&#x2013;618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27176889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telles LG, Billaut F, de Souza Ribeiro A, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning with High and Low Pressure Enhances Maximum Strength and Modulates Heart Rate Variability. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022; 19:7655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9265721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35805313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson KMA, Whinton AK, Ferth S, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning: No Influence on Maximal Sprint Acceleration Performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018; 13:986&#x2013;990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29345532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vangsoe MT, Nielsen JK, Paton CD. A Comparison of Different Prerace Warm-Up Strategies on 1-km Cycling Time-Trial Performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020; 15:1109&#x2013;1116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32294619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christiansen D, Olsen CBL, Kehler F, et al. Active Relative to Passive Ischemic Preconditioning Enhances Intense Endurance Performance in Well-Trained Men. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022; 17:979&#x2013;990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35338107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cocking S, Landman T, Benson M, et al. The impact of remote ischemic preconditioning on cardiac biomarker and functional response to endurance exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27(10):1061&#x2013;1069. doi: 10.1111/sms.12724</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27430157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Groot PCE, Thijssen DHJ, Sanchez M, et al. Ischemic preconditioning improves maximal performance in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol 2010; 108:141&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2793394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19760432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster GP, Westerdahl DE, Foster LA, Hsu JV, Anholm JD. Ischemic preconditioning of the lower extremity attenuates the normal hypoxic increase in pulmonary artery systolic pressure. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2011;179(23):248&#x2013;253. doi: 10.1016/j.resp.2011.09.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resp.2011.09.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21924386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin PJ, Ferguson RA, Gissane C, et al. Ischemic preconditioning enhances critical power during a 3 minute all-out cycling test. J Sports Sci. 2018; 36:1038&#x2013;1043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28686083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halley SL, Peeling P, Brown H, et al. Repeat Application of Ischemic Preconditioning Improves Maximal 1,000-m Kayak Ergometer Performance in a Simulated Competition Format. J Strength Cond Res. Published online October 15, 2020. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003748</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33065705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halley SL, Marshall P, Siegler JC. Effect of ischemic preconditioning and changing inspired O<sub>2</sub> fractions on neuromuscular function during intense exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2019; 127:1688&#x2013;1697.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31600099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hittinger EA, Maher JL, Nash MS, et al. Ischemic preconditioning does not improve peak exercise capacity at sea level or simulated high altitude in trained male cyclists. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2015; 40:65&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25474566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessen S, Zeuthen M, Sommer Jeppesen J, et al. Active ischemic pre-conditioning does not additively improve short-term high-intensity cycling performance when combined with caffeine ingestion in trained young men. Eur J Sport Sci. 2024; 24:693&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11236065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38874987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kido K, Suga T, Tanaka D, et al. Ischemic preconditioning accelerates muscle deoxygenation dynamics and enhances exercise endurance during the work-to-work test. Physiol Rep. 2015; 3:e12395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4463825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25952936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kido K, Suga T, Tanaka D, et al. Remote ischemic preconditioning accelerates systemic O<sub>2</sub> dynamics and enhances endurance during work-to-work cycling exercise. Transl Sports Med. 2018; 1:204&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilding AE, Sequeira GM, Wood MR. Effects of ischemic preconditioning on economy, <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" overflow="scroll"><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mover accent="true"><mml:mtext>V</mml:mtext><mml:mo>&#x2d9;</mml:mo></mml:mover><mml:mtext>O</mml:mtext></mml:mrow><mml:mn>2</mml:mn></mml:msub></mml:mrow></mml:math> kinetics and cycling performance in endurance athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018; 118:2541&#x2013;2549.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30361766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjeld T, Rasmussen MR, Jattu T, et al. Ischemic preconditioning of one forearm enhances static and dynamic apnea. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014; 46:151&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23846166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDougall KB, McClean ZJ, MacIntosh BR, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning, But Not Priming Exercise, Improves Exercise Performance in Trained Rock Climbers. J Strength Cond Res. 2023; 37:2149&#x2013;2157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37607294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montoye AHK, Mitchinson CJ, Townsend OR, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning Does Not Improve Time Trial Performance in Recreational Runners. Int J Exerc Sci. 2020; 13:1402&#x2013;1417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7523890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33042381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morley WN, Murrant CL, Burr JF. Ergogenic effect of ischemic preconditioning is not directly conferred to isolated skeletal muscle via blood. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2023; 123:1851&#x2013;1861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37074464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mota GR, Rightmire ZB, Martin JS, et al. Ischemic preconditioning has no effect on maximal arm cycling exercise in women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2020; 120:369&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31813045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oz-G&#xf3;mez E, Moll&#xe0;-Casanova S, Sempere-Rubio N, et al. Potential Benefits of a Single Session of Remote Ischemic Preconditioning and Walking in Sedentary Older Adults: A Pilot Study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023; 20:3515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9966602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36834210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandorf Z, Erickson S, Scholten SD. Ischemic Preconditioning On Swimming Performance: An Exploration Into Practical Application. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2023; 55:377&#x2013;377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabino-Carvalho JL, Lopes TR, Obeid-Freitas T, et al. Effect of Ischemic Preconditioning on Endurance Performance Does Not Surpass Placebo. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017; 49:124&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27580156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka D, Suga T, Kido K, et al. Acute remote ischemic preconditioning has no effect on quadriceps muscle endurance. Transl Sports Med. 2020; 3:314&#x2013;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ter Beek F, Jokumsen PS, Sloth BN, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning Attenuates Rating of Perceived Exertion But Does Not Improve Maximal Oxygen Consumption or Maximal Power Output. J Strength Cond Res. 2022; 36:2479&#x2013;2485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32341247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tocco F, Marongiu E, Ghiani G, et al. Muscle ischemic preconditioning does not improve performance during self-paced exercise. Int J Sports Med. 2015; 36:9&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25264861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turnes T, de Aguiar RA, de Oliveira Cruz RS, et al. Impact of ischaemia&#x2013; reperfusion cycles during ischaemic preconditioning on 2000-m rowing ergometer performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018; 118:1599&#x2013;1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29796856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urbanski R, Aschenbrenner P, Zmijewski P, et al. Effect of Simultaneous Lower- and Upper-Body Ischemic Preconditioning on Lactate, Heart Rate, and Rowing Performance in Healthy Males and Females. Appl Sci-Basel. 2024; 14:3539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiggins CC, Constantini K, Paris HL, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning, O<sub>2</sub> Kinetics, and Performance in Normoxia and Hypoxia. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019; 51:900&#x2013;911.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30601792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong Z, Dong H, Wu Y, et al. Remote ischemic preconditioning enhances aerobic performance by accelerating regional oxygenation and improving cardiac function during acute hypobaric hypoxia exposure. Front Physiol. 2022; 13:950086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9500473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36160840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvador AF, De Aguiar RA, Lisb&#xf4;a FD, et al. Ischemic Preconditioning and Exercise Performance: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016; 11:4&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26218309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marocolo M, Simim MAM, Bernardino A, et al. Ischemic preconditioning and exercise performance: shedding light through smallest worthwhile change. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019; 119:2123&#x2013;2149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31451953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal S, Randhawa PK, Singh N, et al. Role of ATP-Sensitive Potassium Channels in Remote Ischemic Preconditioning Induced Tissue Protection. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol Ther. 2017; 22:467&#x2013;475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28793823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han HG, Wang ZW, Zhang NB, Zhu HY. Role of nitric oxide during early phase myocardial ischemic preconditioning in rats. Chin Med J (Engl). 2008;121(13):1210&#x2013;1214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18710640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcora SM, Staiano W, Manning V. Mental fatigue impairs physical performance in humans. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2009; 106:857&#x2013;864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19131473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okano AH, Fontes EB, Montenegro RA, et al. Brain stimulation modulates the autonomic nervous system, rating of perceived exertion and performance during maximal exercise. Br J Sports Med. 2015; 49:1213&#x2013;1218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23446641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meireles A, Souza HLR, Arriel RA, et al. Attenuation of Neuromuscular Fatigue by Ischemic Preconditioning with Moderate Cuff Pressure is Not Related to Muscle Oxygen Saturation in Men. Int J Exerc Sci. 2023; 16:1025&#x2013;1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10464762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37650034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C, Chou W, Wang W, Cai Z. Ischemic preconditioning combined with inter-set palm cooling enhances performance in strength-trained men during high-intensity resistance training: A randomized crossover trial. Biol Sport. 2026;43(1):139&#x2013;147. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2026.152344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2026.152344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12884898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41668937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva LM, Neiva HP, Marques MC, et al. Effects of Warm-Up, Post-Warm-Up, and Re-Warm-Up Strategies on Explosive Efforts in Team Sports: A Systematic Review. Sports Med. 2018; 48:2285&#x2013;2299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29968230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop D. Warm up II: performance changes following active warm up and how to structure the warm up. Sports Med. 2003; 33:483&#x2013;498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12762825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGowan CJ, Pyne DB, Thompson KG, et al. Warm-Up Strategies for Sport and Exercise: Mechanisms and Applications. Sports Med. 2015; 45:1523&#x2013;1546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26400696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop D. Warm up I: potential mechanisms and the effects of passive warm up on exercise performance. Sports Med. 2003; 33:439&#x2013;454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12744717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrary JM, Ackermann BJ, Halaki M. A systematic review of the effects of upper body warm-up on performance and injury. Br J Sports Med. 2015; 49:935&#x2013;942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25694615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fradkin AJ, Zazryn TR, Smoliga JM. Effects of warming-up on physical performance: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2010; 24:140&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19996770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehni AK, Shri R, Singh M. Remote ischaemic preconditioning and prevention of cerebral injury. Indian J Exp Biol. 2007; 45:247&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17373368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristiansen SB, Henning O, Kharbanda RK, et al. Remote preconditioning reduces ischemic injury in the explanted heart by a KATP channel-dependent mechanism. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2005; 288:H1252&#x2013;1256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15498829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laude K, Beauchamp P, Thuillez C, et al. Endothelial protective effects of preconditioning. Cardiovasc Res. 2002; 55:466&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12160943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeley AD, Jacobs KA. IPC recovery length of 45 minutes improves muscle oxygen saturation during active sprint recovery. Eur J Sport Sci. 2022; 22:1383&#x2013;1390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34110272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loukogeorgakis SP, Williams R, Panagiotidou AT, et al. Transient limb ischemia induces remote preconditioning and remote postconditioning in humans by a K(ATP)-channel dependent mechanism. Circulation. 2007; 116:1386&#x2013;1395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17724264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinken TM, Thijssen DHJ, Hopkins N, et al. Shear stress mediates endothelial adaptations to exercise training in humans. Hypertension. 2010; 55:312&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20048193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DD, Ridnour LA, Isenberg JS, et al. The chemical biology of nitric oxide: implications in cellular signaling. Free Radic Biol Med. 2008; 45:18&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2572721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18439435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louie JC, Fujii N, Meade RD, et al. The interactive contributions of Na(+)/K(+) &#x2013; ATPase and nitric oxide synthase to sweating and cutaneous vasodilatation during exercise in the heat. J Physiol. 2016; 594:3453&#x2013;3462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4908024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26852741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniel J. B, Montrezol FT, Maxwell JD, et al. Impact of handgrip exercise and ischemic preconditioning on local and remote protection against endothelial reperfusion injury in young men. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2023; 324:R329&#x2013;R335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36572551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos Cerqueira M, Kovacs D, Martins de Fran&#xe7;a I, et al. Effects of Individualized Ischemic Preconditioning on Protection Against Eccentric Exercise-Induced Muscle Damage: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Sports Health. 2021; 13:554&#x2013;564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8558991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33622116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza HLR, Hurst P, Oliveira GT, et al. Positive and Negative Verbal Instructions Associated With Sham Ischemic Preconditioning Moderate Improvements of Knee-Extension Resistance Exercise in Trained Men. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2025; 20:891&#x2013;898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40348391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bushell AJ, Klenerman L, Taylor S, et al. Ischaemic preconditioning of skeletal muscle. 1. Protection against the structural changes induced by ischaemia/reperfusion injury. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2002; 84:1184&#x2013;1188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12463668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gkari VN, Tsoukos A, Aspradakis N, et al. The Effects of Short-Duration Ischemic Preconditioning on Horizontal and Vertical Jump Performance in Male and Female Track and Field Jumpers. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2025; 10:265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12285931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40700201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarzynski MA, Ghosh S, Bouchard C. Genomic and transcriptomic predictors of response levels to endurance exercise training. J Physiol. 2017; 595:2931&#x2013;2939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27234805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan GE, Avery A, Thorson JLM, et al. Epigenome-wide association study of physical activity and physiological parameters in discordant monozygotic twins. Sci Rep. 2022; 12:20166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9691628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36424439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrod PJJ, Lund JN, Phillips BE. Time-efficient physical activity interventions to reduce blood pressure in older adults: a randomised controlled trial. Age Ageing 2021; 50:980&#x2013;984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8098795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33068100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zihan F, Yanqing F, Ying W. The effects of different ischemic conditioning on strength training recovery. Biol Sport. 2025;42(2):237&#x2013;248. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2025.144410</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2025.144410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11963143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40182711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>