<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41375096</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1420-3049</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>23</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecules (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Molecules</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Study on Sulfide Stress Corrosion Cracking Susceptibility of 20# Steel Weld Joints in H<sub>2</sub>S-Rich Environments.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4499</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/molecules30234499</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aims to clarify the influence of H<sub>2</sub>S concentration and temperature on the sulfide stress corrosion cracking (SSCC) susceptibility of 20# steel weld joints. 20# steel is a commonly selected pipe material for ground gas pipelines, and there is a risk of welds cracking after years of service. The selection of a corrosive environment is based on the working conditions of high-sulfur oil fields on site. Slow strain rate tensile (SSRT) tests were conducted under simulated high-sulfur gathering and transportation conditions across varying temperatures and H<sub>2</sub>S concentrations. The mechanical properties, SSCC susceptibility, fracture morphology, and elemental composition of fracture surfaces were systematically analyzed. As H<sub>2</sub>S concentration increased (5%, 7.5%, 10%) and temperature decreased (30-60 &#xb0;C), the elongation after fracture and the reduction in area of 20# steel decreased, while the yield strength and SSCC susceptibility increased. The H<sub>2</sub>S concentration range of 0-5% represented a critical sensitivity interval for the material, where elongation after fracture decreased by up to 74%. Within the 5-10% H<sub>2</sub>S range, elongation decreased by only 2.11%, indicating a slowing trend of fracture toughness deterioration, though SSCC susceptibility still increased by 12%. Increasing the temperature from 30 &#xb0;C to 60 &#xb0;C reduced SSCC susceptibility by approximately 30%, confirming higher susceptibility at lower temperatures. Temperature exerts a lesser influence on material performance than H<sub>2</sub>S concentration. Also, 20# steel remains within the SSCC brittle fracture sensitivity zone in sulfur-containing environments, necessitating strict quality control to avoid defects and stress concentrations. In high-sulfur environments (H<sub>2</sub>S &gt; 5%), further increases in H<sub>2</sub>S concentration have a diminished effect on cracking susceptibility.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xinze</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering, China University of Petroleum (Beijing) at Karamay, Karamay Campus, Karamay 834000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ran</LastName><ForeName>Yanqi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering, China University of Petroleum (Beijing) at Karamay, Karamay Campus, Karamay 834000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Zhiming</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-6583-663X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Natural Gas Technology, PetroChina Southwest Oil and Gas Field Company, Chengdu 610299, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mao</LastName><ForeName>Ting</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Natural Gas Technology, PetroChina Southwest Oil and Gas Field Company, Chengdu 610299, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024D105-01-01</GrantID><Agency>Postdoctoral Research Project of PetroChina Southwest Oil &amp; Gasfield Company (Project title: Critical Stress and Nondestructive Testing Technology for Sulfide Stress Cracking of Surface Pipe-lines in High-Sulfur Gas Fields&#xff09;</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52562047</GrantID><Agency>Supported by National Natural Science Foundation of China for Regional Fund</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023D01A19</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022TSYCTD0002</GrantID><Agency>Xinjiang Tianshan Innovation Team for Research and Application of High-Efficiency Oil and Gas Pipeline Transportation Technology</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>XQZX20240054</GrantID><Agency>Xinjiang Uygur Region "One Case, One Policy" Strategic Talent Introduction Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Molecules</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100964009</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1420-3049</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">20# steel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydrogen sulfide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stress corrosion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stress corrosion cracking susceptibility</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Authors Zhiming Yu and Ting Mao were employed by the company PetroChina Southwest Oil and Gas Field Company. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41375096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12693278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules30234499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">molecules30234499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cheng S., Yuan W. Corrosion mechanism and anticorrosion technology of oil and gas gathering and transportation pipeline. IOP Conf. Ser. Earth Environ. Sci. 2021;859:012115. doi: 10.1088/1755-1315/859/1/012115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1755-1315/859/1/012115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Y.K., Yang F.M., Yin Z.Q., Chen B.J. Statistical analysis and risk assessment of oil and gas pipeline accidents. Oil Gas Storage Transp. 2017;36:472&#x2013;476. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X., Qi J., Liu J., Li H., Du Q., Han Y., Fu A. Stress corrosion sensitivity of martensitic stainless steel in H2S environment. Corros. Prot. 2022;43:31&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu D., Liu Z., Du C., Huang H., Lin N. Research progress and prospects of stress corrosion cracking of pipeline steel in soil environments. J. Chin. Soc. Corros. Prot. 2021;41:737&#x2013;747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan J., Wen S.M., Yu Z.M., Shen P., Mo L., Xu L., Zeng D.Z., Xu J.Y. Key technological advances and future directions in corrosion control for high-sulfur gas field development. Nat. Gas Ind. 2024;44:136&#x2013;148. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S., Zhang Z., Qin G. Study on the seismic performance of corroded H-shaped steel columns. Eng. Struct. 2019;191:39&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2019.04.037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2019.04.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao K.X., Qin M., Yang N., He G.X., Zhao S., Zhang S. Corrosion main control factors and corrosion degree prediction charts in H2S and CO2 coexisting associated gas pipelines. Mater. Chem. Phys. 2022;292:126838. doi: 10.1016/j.matchemphys.2022.126838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchemphys.2022.126838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almusallam A.A. Effect of degree of corrosion on the properties of reinforcing steel bars. Constr. Build. Mater. 2001;15:361&#x2013;368. doi: 10.1016/S0950-0618(01)00009-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0950-0618(01)00009-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C., Zheng S., Chen C., Lu G. The effect of the partial pressure of H2S on the permeation of hydrogen in low carbon pipeline steel. Corros. Sci. 2013;67:184&#x2013;192. doi: 10.1016/j.corsci.2012.10.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.corsci.2012.10.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikeda A., Mukai S., Ueda M. Corrosion behavior of 9 to 25% Cr steels in wet CO2 environments. Corrosion. 1985;41:185&#x2013;192. doi: 10.5006/1.3581989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5006/1.3581989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orlikowski J., Kalinowski M., Lasota I., Maruszewski P., Szocinski M., Darowicki K. Wet H2S corrosion and degradation of pipeline in amine regeneration system. Mater. Corros. 2024;75:778&#x2013;785. doi: 10.1002/maco.202314252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/maco.202314252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia T.G., Ding Z.M., He Y.K., Shi Y.Z., Wen G.H. Corrosion and Fracture Mechanism of Drilling Tools in Wet H2S Environment and Preventive Measures. Corros. Prot. Petrochem. Ind. 2015;32:17&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui P. Corrosion resistance and mechanism analysis of carbon steel pipes for oil and gas gathering and transportation. Pet. Eng. Constr. 2021;47:30&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covered Electrodes for Manual Metal Are Welding of Non-Alloy and Fine Grain Steels. China Standards Press; Beijing, China: 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Code for Acceptance of Construction Quality of Field Equipment and Industrial Pipeline Welding Engineering. China Association for Engineering Construction Standardization; Beijing, China: 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L.J., Hu W.Q. Effect of welding parameters and post-welding heat treatment on the microstructure and properties of weld seam of 20# steel and 304 stainless steel. J. Phys. Conf. Ser. 2022;2383:012118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard for Welding Procedure Qualification of Oil and Gas Metal Pipeline. National Energy Administration; Beijing, China: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steel Pipe for Pipeline Transportation Systems. Standardization Administration of China; Beijing, China: 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welding Street Bending Test Method. Standardization Administration of China; Beijing, China: 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welding Procedure Evaluation of Petroleum and Natural Gas Metal Pipelines. National Energy Administration; Beijing, China: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corrosion of Metals and Alloys&#x2014;Stress Corrosion Testing&#x2014;Part 7: Slow Strain Rate Test. Standardization Administration of China; Beijing, China: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Z.M., He Z.Y., Gao Z.L. Calculation and regression analysis of stress corrosion susceptibility index for 316L stainless steel. J. Zhejiang Univ. Technol. 2007:198&#x2013;200+236. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Q.Y. Experimental study on stress corrosion of 20 carbon steel in liquid ammonia. Mater. Prot. 2025;58:159&#x2013;164. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu W., Hao W., Liu Z., Li X., Du C. Comparative study of the stress corrosion behavior of a multiuse bainite steel in the simulated tropical marine atmosphere and seawater environments. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;239:117903. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S.Z., Li C.F., Li H., Wen P. Effect of slow strain rate on stress corrosion behavior of 2205 duplex stainless steel in saturated H2S environment. Trans. Mater. Heat Treat. 2016;37:96&#x2013;102. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kass M.D., Keiser J.R., Yan L., Amy M., Yarom P. Assessing Compatibility of Natural Gas Pipeline Materials with Hydrogen, CO2, and Ammonia. J. Pipeline Syst. Eng. Pract. 2023;14:04023007. doi: 10.1061/JPSEA2.PSENG-1431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/JPSEA2.PSENG-1431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du J., Ming H., Wang J., Han E.H. Hydrogen embrittlement of 20# seamless steel in medium and low pressure gaseous hydrogen. Mater. Lett. 2023;334:133734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao Y., Liu X., Song Y., Zhang Z., Wang P., Xing X., Peng W., Xing S., Bian J., Cao X. Experimental study on slow tensile, fatigue, and impact on X42 steel and #20 carburizing steel. Int. J. Press. Vessel. Pip. 2024;208:105139. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpvp.2024.105139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpvp.2024.105139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Q., Chen C., Zhao X., Chi H., He Y., Li Y., Qi Y., Yu H. Ion-selectivity of iron sulfides and their effect on H2S corrosion. Corros. Sci. 2019;158:108085. doi: 10.1016/j.corsci.2019.07.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.corsci.2019.07.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Cai R., Chen J., Wu Z., He Q. Stress Corrosion Cracking Behavior of 2205 Duplex Stainless Steel in High Temperature and High Pressure H2S Containing Environment. Electroplat. Coat. 2024;43:76&#x2013;84. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D.L. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. China University of Petroleum; Beijing, China: 2017. Study on Stress Corrosion Behavior of 310S Austenitic Stainless Steel in High-Temperature and High-Pressure H2S/CO2 Environments. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilton J., Fals H., Trevisan R. Susceptibility to hydrogen-induced cracking in H2S corrosion environment of API 5L-X80 welding metal. Weld. Int. 2011;25:94&#x2013;100. doi: 10.1080/09507116.2010.527054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09507116.2010.527054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K., Zeng Y., Luo J.-L. Influence of H2S on the general corrosion and sulfide stress cracking of pipelines steels for supercritical CO2 transportation. Corros. Sci. 2021;190:109639. doi: 10.1016/j.corsci.2021.109639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.corsci.2021.109639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo S., Liu M., Shen Y., Lin X. Sulfide Stress Corrosion Cracking Behavior of G105 and S135 High-Strength Drill Pipe Steels in H2S Environment. J. Mater. Eng. Perform. 2019;28:1707&#x2013;1718. doi: 10.1007/s11665-019-03913-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11665-019-03913-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. China University of Petroleum; Beijing, China: 2022. Study on Stress Corrosion Cracking Behavior of Austenitic Stainless Steel in High Temperature and High Pressure H2S Environment.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H.S., Feng D.C., Fu A.Q., Wu M.W., Zhao G., Zhuo K. The influence of strip defects on the sensitivity of sulfide stress corrosion cracking in L360 pipeline steel circumferential welds. Pet. Pipes Instrum. 2024;10:87&#x2013;92. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu W., Deng Y., Zhang Z., Tan G., Guo X. Effect of tensile stress response for oxide films on the fatigue failure behavior of anodized AA6082 alloys. Mater. Sci. Eng. A. 2022;850:143552. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2022.143552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2022.143552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>