<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41827331</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2077-0383</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Use of Aflibercept to Treat Retinopathy of Prematurity in Children with Extremely Low Birth Weight.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1912</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/jcm15051912</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Background:</b> Aflibercept is one of the anti-VEGF drugs used, among others, for the treatment of retinopathy of prematurity, alongside the widely used bevacizuab and ranibizumab. It is a recombinant fusion protein composed of the human VEGFR-1 and VEGFR-2 domains combined with the Fc part of human IgG, called VEGF-TRAP. The paper describes a group of premature infants treated with aflibercept due to retinopathy of prematurity at the Regional Specialized Children's Hospital in Olsztyn, Poland, in the years 2017-2019. <b>Methods:</b> Eleven children (22 eyes) with extremely low birth weight and type 1 ROP and A-ROP qualified for treatment. The birth weight of the children was 460-940 g (average 677 g). Children were treated between 32 and 38 weeks of postconceptional age (on average in 33.3 week). We administered 1 mg (0.025 mL) of aflibercept intravitreal to each eye under local anesthesia. <b>Results:</b> In all cases, the retinopathy regressed. Between 2 and 7 weeks after treatment, the disease reactivated in five children (45%) in the form of ROP type 2, and these children underwent retinal laser photocoagulation. One child had a complication in the form of a cataract in one eye, while the remaining children had no complications after the injection and laser therapy. In all children, there was complete regression of ROP, and retinal vascularization was observed up to the end of zone III or up to the border of laser therapy. A child with cataract underwent lensectomy. All children are under the care of our center, and were examined ophthalmologically and strabologically; the results of these tests will be presented in a separate study. <b>Conclusions:</b> Aflibercept differs from other anti-VEGF drugs in its point of action and pharmacodynamics of action. In the literature, its effectiveness is estimated at over 80%, but there are also studies in which the reactivation of ROP after treatment reaches over 40%. In this study, the treated children were characterized by extremely low birth weight and, as a result, numerous complications related to prematurity occurred, such as bronchopulmonary dysplasia, sepsis, anemia, heart defects, and others. Many of them were in the intensive care unit. These factors may influence ROP reactivation and complications. The description compares studies in which aflibercept was administered at the same dose-1 mg. Currently, large studies (e.g., Firefleye and Butterfleye) describe the effects of a new aflibercept therapy at a dose of 0.4 mg. Studies on aflibercept obviously require further observations, so all reports, even from small groups, are important.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Szwajkowska</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Head and Neck Surgery for Children and Adolescents, University of Warmia and Mazury, 10-561 Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prof. Stanislaw Popowski Regional Specialized Children's Hospital, 10-561 Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaroszewska-&#x15a;wi&#x105;tek</LastName><ForeName>Beata</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prof. Stanislaw Popowski Regional Specialized Children's Hospital, 10-561 Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Pathology and Birth Defects in Newborns and Infants, University of Warmia and Mazury, 10-561 Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wo&#x15b;</LastName><ForeName>Ma&#x142;gorzata</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology Department with a Children's Unit, S. &#x17b;eromski Specialist Hospital, 31-912 Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101606588</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2077-0383</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ROP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aflibercept</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anti-VEGF</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">retinopathy of prematurity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41827331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12985830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm15051912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jcm15051912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhuang H., Lin L., Luo D., Zheng N.X. A Network Meta-Analysis of Success Rates following Low Dosage Anti-VEGF for Retinopathy of Prematurity. Curr. Eye Res. 2024;49:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1080/02713683.2023.2259628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02713683.2023.2259628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37708190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartnett M.E., Stahl A. Laser versus Anti-VEGF: A Paradigm Shift for Treatment-Warranted Retinopathy of Prematurity. Ophthalmol. Ther. 2023;12:2241&#x2013;2252. doi: 10.1007/s40123-023-00744-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40123-023-00744-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10442041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37337024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stahl A., Sukgen E.A., Wu W.C., Lepore D., Nakanishi H., Mazela J., Moshafegni D.M., Vitti R., Athanikar A., Chu K., et al. Effect of Intravitreal Aflibercept vs Laser Photocoagulation on Treat- ment Success of Retinopathy of Prematurity: The FIREFLEYE Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA. 2022;26:348&#x2013;359. doi: 10.1001/jama.2022.10564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2022.10564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9327573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35881122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salman A.G., Said A.M. Structural, visual and refractive outcomes of intravitreal aflibercept injection in high-risk prethreshold type 1 retinopathy of prematurity. Ophthalmic Res. 2015;53:15&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1159/000364809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000364809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25471087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukgen E.A., S&#xf6;ker G., Ko&#xe7;luk Y., Gulek B. Effect of Intravitreal Aflibercept on Central Retinal Arterial Blood Flow in Type 1 Retinopathy of Prematurity. Eur. J. Ophthalmol. 2017;8:751&#x2013;755. doi: 10.5301/ejo.5000938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5301/ejo.5000938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28218369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C.Y., Lien R., Wang N.K., Chao A.N., Chen K.J., Chen T.L., Hwang Y.S., Lai C.C., Wu W.C. Changes in systemic vascular andothelial growth factor levels after intravitreal injection of aflibercept in infants with retinopathy of prematurity. Graefes Arch. Clin. Exp. Ophthalmol. 2018;256:479&#x2013;487. doi: 10.1007/s00417-017-3878-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00417-017-3878-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29290015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vural A., Perente I., Onur I., Eris E., Seymen Z., Hergunsel G.O., Salihoglu O., Yigit F.U. Efficacy of intravitreal afliber- ceptmonotherapy iin retinopaty of prematurity evaluated by periodic fluorescence angiogryphy and optical coherence tomog- raphy. Int. Ophthalmol. 2019;39:2161&#x2013;2169. doi: 10.1007/s10792-018-1040-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10792-018-1040-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30478752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukgen E.A., Ko&#xe7;luk Y. Comparison of clinical outcomes of intravitral ranibizumab and aflibercept treatment for retinopaty of prematurity. Comparative study. Graefes Arch. Clin. Exp. Ophothalmol. 2019;257:49&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1007/s00417-018-4168-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00417-018-4168-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30397793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekinci D.Y., &#xc7;elik K. Comparison of the Efficacy Between Intravitreal Aflibercept and Laser Photocoagulation in the Treatment of Retinopathy of Prematurity. J. Pediatr. Ophthalmol. Strabismus. 2020;57:54&#x2013;60. doi: 10.3928/01913913-20191104-01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3928/01913913-20191104-01</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31972042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riazi-Esfahani H., Mahmoudi A., Sanatkar M., Farahani A.D., Bazvand F. Comparison of aflibercept and bevacizumab in the treatment of type 1 retinopathy of prematurity. Int. J. Retin. Vitr. 2021;13:60. doi: 10.1186/s40942-021-00334-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40942-021-00334-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8513371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34645516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becassio A., Mignini C., Caricato A., Iaccheri B., Di Cara G., Verotti A., Cagni C. New trends in intravitreal anti-VEGF therapy for ROP. Eur. J. Ophthalmol. 2022;32:1340&#x2013;1351. doi: 10.1177/11206721211073405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/11206721211073405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35040348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suren E., &#xd6;zkaya D., &#xc7;etinkaya E., Kalayci M., Yigit K., Kucuk M.F., Erol M.K. Comparison of bevacizumab, ranibizumab and aflibercept in retinopathy of prematurity treatment. Int. Ophthalmol. 2022;42:1905&#x2013;1913. doi: 10.1007/s10792-021-02188-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10792-021-02188-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35094229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang E., Josan A.S., Purohit R., Patel C.K., Xue K. A Network Meta- Analysis of Retreatment Rates following Bevacizumab, Ranibizumab, Aflibercept, and Laser for Retinopathy of Prematurity. Ophthalmology. 2022;129:1389&#x2013;1401. doi: 10.1016/j.ophtha.2022.06.042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ophtha.2022.06.042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35842190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eyela&#xae; (Aflibercept) for the Treatment of Retinopathy of Prematurity (ROP) January 09, 2023 Dermatologic and Ophtalmic Drugs Advisory Committee Regeneron Pharmaceuticals, Inc.  [(accessed on 9 January 2023)]; Available online:  https://www.fda.gov/media/164374/download.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmstr&#xf6;m G., Tornqvist K., Al-Hawasi A., Nilsson &#xc5;., Wallin A., Hellstr&#xf6;m A. Increased frequency of retinopathy of prem- aturiyu over the last decade and significant regional differences. Acta Ophthalmol. 2018;96:142&#x2013;148. doi: 10.1111/aos.13549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aos.13549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29068172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudu R.K., Pathak M., Nayak M.K., Kumar S. Risk Factors of Retinopathy of Prematurity in Very Low-Birth-Weight Neonates Under Optimized Oxygen Therapy. Perinatology. 2023;23:3&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae S.P., Kim E.K., Yun J., Yoon Y.M., Shin S.H., Park S.Y. Retinopathy of Prematurity Requiring Treatment Is Closely Related to Head Growth during Neonatal Intensive Care Unit Hospitalization in Very Low Birth Weight Infants. Neonatology. 2022;119:176&#x2013;183. doi: 10.1159/000519714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000519714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35139511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asim M., Sahu M.M., Asghar S., Abbas N., Shabeer A. Frequency of Retinopathy of Prematurity in Premature and Very Low Weight Infants. Pak. J. Ophthalmol. 2025;41:4. doi: 10.36351/pjo.v41i4.2116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36351/pjo.v41i4.2116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yucel O.E., Eraydin B., Niyaz L., Terzi O. Incidence and risk factors for retinopathy of prematurity in premature, extremaly low birth weight and extremaly low gestational age infants. BMC Ophthalmol. 2022;22:36. doi: 10.1186/s12886-022-02591-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12886-022-02591-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9469514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36096834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsiropoulus G.N., Seliniotaki A.K., Haidich A.B., Ziakas N., Matafsi A. Comparison of adverse events between intravitreal anti-VEGF and laser photocoagulation for treatment-requiring retinopathy of prematurity. A systemic review. Int. Ophthalmol. 2023;43:1027&#x2013;1062. doi: 10.1007/s10792-022-02480-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10792-022-02480-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10042936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36214992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clisal E., Sukgen E.A. Cardiovascular assessment after treatment for retinopathy of prematurity: A comparative study between anti-VEGF agent (aflibercept) and laser. Cardiovasc. J. Afr. 2020;31:123&#x2013;129. doi: 10.5830/cvja-2019-058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5830/cvja-2019-058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8762783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31995115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarbin M.A. Anti-VEGF Agents and the Risk of Arteriothrombotic Events. Asia Pac. J. Ophthalmol. 2018;7:63&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29405046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maloney M.H., Payne S.R., Herrin J., Sangaralingham L.R., Shah N.D., Barkmeier A.J. Risk of Systemic Adverse Events after Intravitreal Bevacizumab, Ranibizumab, and Aflibercept in Routine Clinical Practice. Ophthalmology. 2021;128:417&#x2013;424. doi: 10.1016/j.ophtha.2020.07.062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ophtha.2020.07.062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32781110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitchens J.W., Do D.V., Boyer D.S., Thompson D., Gibson A., Saroj N., Vitti R., Berliner A.J., Kaiser P.K. Comprehensive Review of Ocular and Systemic Safety Events with Intravitreal Aflibercept Injection in Randomized Controlled Trials. Ophthalmology. 2016;123:1511&#x2013;1520. doi: 10.1016/j.ophtha.2016.02.046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ophtha.2016.02.046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27084563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stahl A., Azuma N., Wu W.C., Lepore D., Sukgen E., Nakanishi H., Mazela J., Leal S., Pieper A., Schlief S., et al. Systemic exposure to aflibercept after intravitreal injection in premature neonates with retinopathy of prematurity: Results from the FIREFLEYE randomized phase 3 study. Eye. 2024;38:1444&#x2013;1453. doi: 10.1038/s41433-023-02919-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41433-023-02919-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11126565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38200320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stahl A., Nakanishi H., Lepore D., Wu W.C., Azuma N., Jacas C., Vitti R., Athanikar A., Chu K., Iveli P., et al. Intravitreal Aflibercept vs Laser Therapy for Retinopathy of Prematurity: Two-Year Efficacy and Safety Outcomes in the Nonrandomized Controlled Trial FIRE- FLEYE next. JAMA. Netw. Open. 2024;7:e248383. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.8383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.8383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11061767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38687481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Extension Study to Evaluate the Long-Term Outcomes of Pediatric Patients Who Received Treatment for Retinopathy of Prematurity in the VGFTe-ROP-1920 Study (Acronym: Butterfleye Next)  [(accessed on 5 February 2021)]; Available online:  https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT04515524?tab=study.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cayabyab R., Ramanathan R. Retinopathy of Prematurity: Therapeutic Strategies Based on Pathophysiology. Neonatology. 2016;109:369&#x2013;376. doi: 10.1159/000444901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000444901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27251645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>