<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41583329</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effectiveness and Acceptability of Visual Inspection With Acetic Acid as a Screening Test for Cervical Intraepithelial Neoplasia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e99960</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e99960</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e99960</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.99960</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Cervical carcinoma is a significant burden in developing countries, and it is preventable by early detection of its precursor lesions through screening.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study assessed the effectiveness and acceptability of visual inspection of the cervix with acetic acid as a screening test in a low-resource setting, comparing it with colposcopy-guided biopsy as a gold standard test. It also assessed the prevalence of preneoplastic conditions of the cervix and its association with known risk factors for cervical carcinoma.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODOLOGY" NlmCategory="METHODS">A comparative study was conducted among 978 women in the age group of 35-54 years from Velanai MOH area in Jaffna, Sri Lanka, during the period of April 2017 to March 2018. The interviewer administered a questionnaire, Visual Inspection of Cervix with Acetic acid (VIA), and colposcopy reporting forms were used for data collection. All participants were screened with VIA and then subjected to colposcopy immediately. Targeted biopsies were performed in 107 cases. Effectiveness of VIA was assessed by means of sensitivity, specificity, positive predictive value, and negative predictive value. Chi-squared test and Fisher's exact test were used to assess the association of risk factors with cervical intraepithelial neoplasia (CIN) and the acceptability of the screening test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The prevalence of preneoplastic conditions, including CIN 1, during the study period of April 2017 to March 2018, was 3.75% in the study population. Early sexual activity, usage of combined oral contraceptive pills, and multiparity were significantly associated with CIN 2 or more lesions (P&lt;0.05). 97.86% of women stated that they would recommend cervical screening with VIA to others. Only six women (0.64%) had heavy bleeding from the biopsy, and 71 women (7.6%) reported severe pain. In detecting CIN 2 or more, the sensitivity of VIA was 70.6%, the specificity was 74.7%, the positive predictive value was 4.9%, and the negative predictive value was 99.3%. When considering the performance of VIA and colposcopy, colposcopy performed well at detecting CIN 2 or more lesions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Even though the sensitivity, specificity, and negative predictive value of VIA were high, it has a low positive predictive value. VIA can be used as an alternative screening test in young women in low-resource settings like Sri Lanka. But it should be kept in mind that the higher false positive rate may result in unnecessary interventions and complications, and it is not suitable for older women with a non-visible transformation zone.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Theeparuban et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Theeparuban</LastName><ForeName>Mathanky</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Teaching Hospital Jaffna, Jaffna, LKA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kopalasuntharam</LastName><ForeName>Muhunthan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Obstetrics and Gynecology, Faculty of Medicine, University of Jaffna, Jaffna, LKA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">accuracy of via</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cervical screening</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">colposcopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">via</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">visual inspection of cervix</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Ethics Review Committee Faculty of Medicine, University of Jaffna issued approval J/ERC/16/78/NDR/0166. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: The Director of Teaching Hospital, Jaffna, provided transport facilities for mobile clinics to transport staff &amp; colposcope. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41583329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12826946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.99960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cancer today: International Agency for Research on Cancer.  [
Feb;
2025 
];https://gco.iarc.who.int/media/globocan/factsheets/cancers/23-cervix-uteri-fact-sheet.pdf 2022 2025:23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HPV information centre. Summary Report.  [
Feb;
2025 
]. 2023. https://hpvcentre.net/statistics/reports/LKA.pdf https://hpvcentre.net/statistics/reports/LKA.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancer Research UK; [ Feb; 2025 ]. 2023. Cancer Research UK.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Human papilloma virus is a necessary cause of invasive cervical cancer worldwide. Wallboomers JM, Jacobs MV, Manos MM, et al.  https://pathsocjournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9896(199909)189:1%3C12::AID-PATH431%3E3.0.CO;2-F. J Pathol. 1999;189:12&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10451482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Human papilloma virus and cervical cancer. Schiffman M, Castle PE, Jeronimo J, Rodrigues AC, Wacholder S. https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(07)61416-0/abstract. Lancet. 2007;370:890&#x2013;907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17826171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiologic classification of human papillomavirus types associated with cervical cancer. Mu&#xf1;oz N, Bosch FX, de Sanjos&#xe9; S, et al.  https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa021641. N Engl J Med. 2003;348:518&#x2013;527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12571259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Determinants of genital human papillomavirus detection in a US population. Peyton CL, Gravitt PE, Hunt WC, Hundley RS, Zhao M, Apple RJ, Wheeler CM.  https://doi.org/10.1086/320696. J Infect Dis. 2001;183:1554&#x2013;1564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11343204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Active and passive cigarette smoking and the risk of cervical neoplasia. Trimble CL, Genkinger JM, Burke AE, et al.  https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15625160/ Obstet Gynecol. 2005;105:174&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3064987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15625160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk of genital human papillomavirus infection in women with human immunodeficiency virus-induced immunosuppression. Ho GY, Burk RD, Fleming I, Klein RS.  https://doi.org/10.1002/ijc.2910560605. Int J Cancer. 1994;56:788&#x2013;792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8119767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>New technologies for cervical cancer screening. Brown AJ, Trimble CL. https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S1521693411001623?via%3Dihub. Best Pract Res Clin Obstet Gynaecol. 2012;26:233&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3632360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22119058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pooled analysis of the accuracy of five cervical cancer screening tests assessed in eleven studies in Africa and India. Arbyn M, Sankaranarayanan R, Muwonge R, et al.  https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/ijc.23489. Int J Cancer. 2008;123:153&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18404671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annual Report on Family Health 2016.  [
Feb;
2025 
];https://drive.google.com/file/d/1kNOB0IwEgIVKpP0-J3mC52dan6yY1qDL/view 2016 25:2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sankaranarayanan R, Wesley RS. France: IARC Technical Publications; 2003. A practical manual on visual screening for cervical neoplasia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellors JW, Sankaranarayanan R. Lyon France: IARC Technical Publications; [ Jan; 2017 ]. 2003. 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accuracy of visual screening for cervical neoplasia: results from an IARC multicentre study in India and Africa. Sankaranarayanan R, Basu P, Wesley RS, et al. Int J Cancer. 2004;110:907&#x2013;913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15170675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of cervical intraepithelial neoplasia (CIN) in patients attending Minia Maternity University Hospital. Sanad AS, Kamel HH, Hasan MM. https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00404-013-3109-0. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2014;289:1211&#x2013;1217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24305750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accuracy of visual inspection with acetic acid for cervical screening: a systematic review. Sritipsukho P, Thaweekul Y. https://www.thaiscience.info/Journals/Article/JMAT/10657804.pdf J Med Assoc Thai. 2010;93:254&#x2013;261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21294423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>