<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41585560</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2590-1575</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Food chemistry: X</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Food Chem X</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Multi-component chitosan-pectin films reinforced with <i>Padina pavonica</i> nanocellulose and <i>Thymus algeriensis</i> essential oil for red meat shelf-life enhancement.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103484</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103484</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">103484</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.fochx.2026.103484</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Perishable foods, including fresh meat, are particularly susceptible to microbial spoilage, lipid oxidation, and progressive quality degradation during storage. Conventional plastic packaging provides physical protection but lacks active functions to delay these processes, while also raising environmental concerns. Therefore, the objective of this study was to develop and evaluate chitosan-pectin biocomposite films incorporated with <i>Padina pavonica</i> nanocellulose (NC) and <i>Thymus algeriensis</i> essential oil (TEO) as sustainable active packaging components. Structural analyses (FTIR, XRD, SEM, profilometry) confirmed distinct modifications, with NC promoting chain alignment and crystallinity, while TEO introduced hydrophobic domains but showed partial phase separation. Their combination (NC&#xa0;+&#xa0;TEO) resulted in the most homogeneous morphology, as NC facilitated the dispersion of TEO within the polymer network. Mechanical and barrier properties revealed that NC enhanced tensile strength (43&#xa0;% increase) and reduced water vapor permeability by 29&#xa0;%, while TEO lowered strength but improved flexibility. The NC&#xa0;+&#xa0;TEO films exhibited balanced performance (TS&#xa0;=&#xa0;21.02&#xa0;MPa; EAB&#xa0;=&#xa0;33.44&#xa0;%) and the lowest WVP. Thermal analysis indicated reinforcement with NC, plasticization with TEO, and intermediate stability with NC&#xa0;+&#xa0;TEO. Antimicrobial assays showed &#x223c;2 log CFU/g reductions of <i>E. coli</i> and <i>S. aureus</i>. Meat packaging trials confirmed these benefits by slowing discoloration, limiting pH rise, reducing lipid oxidation, and delaying the deterioration of quality in refrigerated meat compared with the control films. Overall, NC&#xa0;+&#xa0;TEO films provided structural reinforcement, bioactivity, and sustainability advantages, highlighting their potential in active food packaging.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chenah</LastName><ForeName>May</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Soft Technologies Laboratory, Physical and Chemical Valorization of Biological Materials and Biodiversity, Faculty of Sciences, M'hamed Bougara University of Boumerd&#xe8;s, Algeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Food Quality and Safety Laboratory, Faculty of Biological and Agronomic Sciences, University of Tizi-Ouzou, 15000 Tizi-Ouzou, Algeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karabulut</LastName><ForeName>Gulsah</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, Sakarya University, Sakarya 54187, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zannou</LastName><ForeName>Oscar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Technology, Vocational School of Technical Sciences at Mersin Tarsus Organized Industrial Zone, Tarsus University, 33100 Mersin, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tosif</LastName><ForeName>Mansuri M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Technology, Vocational School of Technical Sciences at Mersin Tarsus Organized Industrial Zone, Tarsus University, 33100 Mersin, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goksen</LastName><ForeName>Gulden</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Technology, Vocational School of Technical Sciences at Mersin Tarsus Organized Industrial Zone, Tarsus University, 33100 Mersin, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Food Chem X</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101751436</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2590-1575</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biodegradable film</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chitosan-pectin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meat preservation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nanocellulose</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thyme essential oil</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Given her role as Guest Editor, Gulden Goksen had no involvement in the peer-review of this article and has no access to information regarding its peer-review.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41585560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12830248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fochx.2026.103484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2590-1575(26)00005-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Al Mamun A., Prasetya T.A.E., Dewi I.R., Ahmad M. Microplastics in human food chains: Food becoming a threat to health safety. Science of the Total Environment. 2023;858</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36461575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arokiyaraj S., Dinakarkumar Y., Shin H. A comprehensive overview on the preservation techniques and packaging of processed meat products: Emphasis on natural derivatives. Journal of King Saud University-Science. 2024;36(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azeredo H.M.C., Rosa M.F., Mattoso L.H.C. Nanocellulose in bio-based food packaging applications. Industrial Crops and Products. 2019;97:664&#x2013;671. doi: 10.1016/j.indcrop.2016.03.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.indcrop.2016.03.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benito-Gonzalez I., G&#xf6;ksen G., P&#xe9;rez-Bassart Z., L&#xf3;pez-Rubio A., S&#xe1;nchez R., Alonso J.M., Martinez-Sanz M. Pilot plant scale-up of the production of optimized starch-based biocomposites loaded with cellulosic nanocrystals from Posidonia oceanica waste biomass. Food Packaging and Shelf Life. 2021;30</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borzi F., Torrieri E., Wrona M., Ner&#xed;n C. Polyamide modified with green tea extract for fresh minced meat active packaging applications. Food Chemistry. 2019;300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31352285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brugnerotto J., Lizardi J., Goycoolea F.M., Arg&#xfc;elles-Monal W., Desbrieres J., Rinaudo M. An infrared investigation in relation with chitin and chitosan characterization. Polymer. 2001;42(8):3569&#x2013;3580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casalini S., Baschetti M.G., Cappelletti M., Guerreiro A.C., Gago C.M., Nici S., Antunes M.D. Antimicrobial activity of different nanocellulose films embedded with thyme, cinnamon, and oregano essential oils for active packaging application on raspberries. Frontiers in Sustainable Food Systems. 2023;7:1190979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casalini S., Giacinti Baschetti M. The use of essential oils in chitosan or cellulose-based materials for the production of active food packaging solutions: A review. Journal of the Science of Food and Agriculture. 2023;103(3):1021&#x2013;1041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10084250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35396735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S., Wu M., Wang C., Yan S., Lu P., Wang S. Developed chitosan/oregano essential oil biocomposite packaging film enhanced by cellulose nanofibril. Polymers. 2020;12(8):1780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7465515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chettri S., Sharma N., Mohite A.M. Formulation of extracted soyabean starch based edible coatings by different methods and their impact on shelf life of sapota fruit. Journal of the Saudi Society of Agricultural Sciences. 2024;23(3):205&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dailin D.J., Rithwan F., Hisham A.M., Rasid Z.I.A., Azelee N.I.W., Sapawe N.&#x2026;Enshasy H.E. A review on current status of plastic waste biodegradation using microbial approach. Bioscience Research. 2022;19:1599&#x2013;1606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng L., Kang X., Liu Y., Luo X. Pectin-based films for food packaging: Barrier properties and improvement strategies. Food Hydrocolloids. 2022;128 doi: 10.1016/j.foodhyd.2022.107596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodhyd.2022.107596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Y., Zhang H., Mei J., Xie J. Stunning methods before slaughter induce oxidation changes of large yellow croaker during cold storage: The role of mitochondria and underlying mechanisms. Journal of the Science of Food and Agriculture. 2023;103(15):7747&#x2013;7756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37439124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elshamy S., Khadizatul K., Uemura K., Nakajima M., Neves M.A. Chitosan-based film incorporated with essential oil nanoemulsion foreseeing enhanced antimicrobial effect. Journal of Food Science and Technology. 2021;58(9):3314&#x2013;3327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8292478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34366449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esazadeh K., Ezzati Nazhad Dolatabadi J., Andishmand H., Mohammadzadeh-Aghdash H., Mahmoudpour M., Naemi Kermanshahi M., Roosta Y. Cytotoxic and genotoxic effects of tert-butylhydroquinone, butylated hydroxyanisole and propyl gallate as synthetic food antioxidants. Food Science &amp; Nutrition. 2024;12(10):7004&#x2013;7016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11521724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39479655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng P., Luo Y., Ke C., Qiu H., Wang W., Zhu Y., Wu S. Chitosan-based functional materials for skin wound repair: Mechanisms and applications. Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology. 2021;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7931995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33681176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiamingo A., de Moura Delezuk J.A., Trombotto S., David L., Campana-Filho S.P. Extensively deacetylated high molecular weight chitosan from the multistep ultrasound-assisted deacetylation of beta-chitin. Ultrasonics Sonochemistry. 2016;32:79&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27150748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firmanda A., Fahma F., Warsiki E., Syamsu K., Arnata I.W., Sartika D.&#x2026;Suyanto A. Antimicrobial mechanism of nanocellulose composite packaging incorporated with essential oils. Food Control. 2023;147</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghaffari A., Navaee K., Oskoui M., Bayati K., Rafiee-Tehrani M. Preparation and characterization of free mixed-film of pectin/chitosan/Eudragit&#xae; RS intended for sigmoidal drug delivery. European Journal of Pharmaceutics and Biopharmaceutics. 2007;67(1):175&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17346954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granata G., Stracquadanio S., Leonardi M., Napoli E., Consoli G.M.L., Cafiso V.&#x2026;Geraci C. Essential oils encapsulated in polymer-based nanocapsules as potential candidates for application in food preservation. Food Chemistry. 2018;269:286&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30100436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gumus R., Gelen S.U. Effects of dietary thyme and rosemary essential oils on performance parameters with lipid oxidation, water activity, pH, colour and microbial quality of breast and drumstick meats in broiler chickens. Archives Animal Breeding. 2023;66(1):17&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9850245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36687212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamidpour R., Hamidpour S., Hamidpour M., Sohraby M., Hamidpour M. Turmeric (Curcuma longa): From a variety of traditional medicinal applications to its novel roles as active antioxidant, anti-inflammatory, anti-cancer, and anti-diabetes. International Journal of Pharmacology, Phytochemistry and Ethnomedicine. 2015;1(1):37&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J., Goksen G., Cong X., Khan M.R., Ahmad N., Zhang W. Development and characterization of zein co-encapsulated wampee essential oil and propolis extract films for food preservation. Food Control. 2025;168</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J., Hu Z., Hu L., Li G., Yao Q., Hu Y. Pectin-based active packaging: A critical review on preparation, physical properties and novel application in food preservation. Trends in Food Science &amp; Technology. 2021;118:167&#x2013;178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim N.I., Shahar F.S., Sultan M.T.H., Shah A.U.M., Safri S.N.A., Mat Yazik M.H. Overview of bioplastic introduction and its applications in product packaging. Coatings. 2021;11(11):1423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail K.A., El Askary A., Farea M.O., Awwad N.S., Ibrahium H.A., Moustapha M.E., Menazea A.A. Perspectives on composite films of chitosan-based natural products (ginger, curcumin, and cinnamon) as biomaterials for wound dressing. Arabian Journal of Chemistry. 2022;15(4)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jemaa M.B., Falleh H., Serairi R., Neves M.A., Snoussi M., Isoda H.&#x2026;Ksouri R. Nanoencapsulated Thymus capitatus essential oil as natural preservative. Innovative Food Science &amp; Emerging Technologies. 2018;45:92&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonoobi M., Oladi R., Davoudpour Y., Oksman K., Dufresne A., Hamzeh Y., Davoodi R. Different preparation methods and properties of nanostructured cellulose from various natural resources and residues: A review. Cellulose. 2015;22(2):935&#x2013;969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karim M.M., Lasker T., Sahin M.A.Z., Hossain M.S., Saputra H.A. Low-cost production of chitosan biopolymer from seafood waste: Extraction and physiochemical characterization. Journal of Research Updates in Polymer Science. 2024;13:17&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi Sani I., Alizadeh Khaledabad M., Pirsa S., Moghaddas Kia E. Physico-chemical, organoleptic, antioxidative and release characteristics of flavoured yoghurt enriched with microencapsulated Melissa officinalis essential oil. International Journal of Dairy Technology. 2020;73(3):542&#x2013;551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khezrian A., Shahbazi Y. Application of nanocompostie chitosan and carboxymethyl cellulose films containing natural preservative compounds in minced camel&#x2019;s meat. International Journal of Biological Macromolecules. 2018;106:1146&#x2013;1158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28847602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laorenza Y., Harnkarnsujarit N. Carvacrol, citral and &#x3b1;-terpineol essential oil incorporated biodegradable films for functional active packaging of Pacific white shrimp. Food Chemistry. 2021;363</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34118755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazi&#x107; V., Vivod V., Per&#x161;in Z., Stoiljkovi&#x107; M., Ratnayake I.S., Ahrenkiel P.S.&#x2026;Kokol V. Dextran-coated silver nanoparticles for improved barrier and controlled antimicrobial properties of nanocellulose films used in food packaging. Food Packaging and Shelf Life. 2020;26</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y., Zhao Y., Xie J., Sameen D.E., Ahmed S., Dai J.&#x2026;Liu Y. Optimization, characterization and evaluation of papaya polysaccharide-corn starch film for fresh cut apples. International Journal of Biological Macromolecules. 2021;166:1057&#x2013;1071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33157135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meydanju N., Pirsa S., Farzi J. Biodegradable film based on lemon peel powder containing xanthan gum and TiO2&#x2013;ag nanoparticles: Investigation of physicochemical and antibacterial properties. Polymer Testing. 2022;106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nechyporchuk O., Belgacem M.N., Bras J. Production of cellulose nanofibrils: A review of recent advances. Industrial Crops and Products. 2016;93:2&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojeda-Piedra S.A., Zambrano-Zaragoza M.L., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Reza R.M., Garc&#xed;a-Betanzos C.I., Real-Sandoval S.A., Quintanar-Guerrero D. Nano-encapsulated essential oils as a preservation strategy for meat and meat products storage. Molecules. 2022;27(23):8187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9738418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36500284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira Filho J.G.D., Silva G.D.C., Oldoni F.C.A., Miranda M., Florencio C., Oliveira R.M.D.D.&#x2026;Ferreira M.D. Edible coating based on carnauba wax nanoemulsion and Cymbopogon martinii essential oil on papaya postharvest preservation. Coatings. 2022;12(11):1700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelissari F.M., Grossmann M.V., Yamashita F., Pineda E.A.G. Antimicrobial, mechanical, and barrier properties of cassava starch&#x2013;chitosan films incorporated with oregano essential oil. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 2009;57(16):7499&#x2013;7504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19627142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podgorbunskikh E., Kuskov T., Rychkov D., Lomovskii O., Bychkov A. Mechanical amorphization of chitosan with different molecular weights. Polymers. 2022;14(20):4438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9606905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36298017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjbaryan S., Pourfathi B., Almasi H. Reinforcing and release controlling effect of cellulose nanofiber in sodium caseinate films activated by nanoemulsified cinnamon essential oil. Food Packaging and Shelf Life. 2019;21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romulo A., Anjani V.S., Wardana A.A. Enhancing antimicrobial activity of thyme essential oil through cellulose Nano crystals-stabilized Pickering emulsions. Foods. 2024;13(22):3706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11593629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39594121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy S., Priyadarshi R., &#x141;opusiewicz &#x141;., Biswas D., Chandel V., Rhim J.W. Recent progress in pectin extraction, characterization, and pectin-based films for active food packaging applications: A review. International Journal of Biological Macromolecules. 2023;239</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37003387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sani I.K., Geshlaghi S.P., Pirsa S., Asdagh A. Composite film based on potato starch/apple peel pectin/ZrO2 nanoparticles/microencapsulated Zataria multiflora essential oil; investigation of physicochemical properties and use in quail meat packaging. Food Hydrocolloids. 2021;117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva S.J., Samba N., Mendes J., Pires J.R., Rodrigues C., Curto J.&#x2026;Silva L. Sustainable food packaging with chitosan biofilm reinforced with nanocellulose and essential oils. Macromol. 2023;3(4):704&#x2013;722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souadia A. Chemical composition and antioxidant activity of Thymus ciliatus (Desf.) Benth. essential oils of Algeria. Natural Product Communications. 2022;17(2) 1934578X221080337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza A.G., Ferreira R.R., Paula L.C., Mitra S.K., Rosa D.S. Starch-based films enriched with nanocellulose-stabilized Pickering emulsions containing different essential oils for possible applications in food packaging. Food Packaging and Shelf Life. 2021;27</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J., Pan X., Wang T., Liu L., Li Z., Wang X. Preparation, characterization and application of chitosan/thyme essential oil composite film. Scientific Reports. 2025;15(1):7934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11885837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40050689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabatabaei A., Ahari H., Yousefi S., Jannat B., Anvar S.A. Application of pectin/cellulose nanocrystal films loaded with summer savory essential oil as a novel packaging for chicken breast fillets. Journal of Food Measurement and Characterization. 2024;18(6):5073&#x2013;5087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu W., Wu Y., Lin Y., Shao P. Facile fabrication of multifunctional citrus pectin aerogel fortified with cellulose nanofiber as controlled packaging of edible fungi. Food Chemistry. 2022;374</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34896953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Zhang Y., Zhu Z., Jiao X., Shang Y., Wen Y. Encapsulation of thymol in biodegradable nanofiber via coaxial eletrospinning and applications in fruit preservation. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 2019;67(6):1736&#x2013;1741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30676718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y., Wu W., Wang L., Goksen G., Shao P. Multifunctional pectin films based on mussel-inspired modified 2D Ag nanosheets for long-lasting antibacterial and enhanced barrier properties. Food Hydrocolloids. 2023;137</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu H., Cheng J.H., Han Z., Han Z. Cold plasma enhanced natural edible materials for future food packaging: Structure and property of polysaccharides and proteins-based films. Critical Reviews in Food Science and Nutrition. 2023;63(20):4450&#x2013;4466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34766864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>