<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41298643</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Characteristic variation of Mach number in subsonic co-flowing jets by varying lip thickness.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>42038</StartPage><MedlinePgn>42038</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">42038</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-26077-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Jet noise reduction is achieved by jet mixing enhancement which is attributed to potential core length reduction of the primary jet. Varying lip thickness can be considered as a passive control method to reduce the potential core, to enhance mixing. This article focuses on certain novel attributes of subsonic co-flowing jet Mach number decay for the wake dominated flow by varying the lip thickness, which is defined as the gap between the core nozzle and surrounding duct along with varying bypass ratio. Three different lip thicknesses namely of 2&#xa0;mm, 10&#xa0;mm, and 15&#xa0;mm at jet exit Mach number of 0.6 was experimentally studied for the bypass ratios ranging from 0.7 to 6.4. To study the flow characteristics, Pitot static measurements was conducted experimentally in both axial and radial directions of the jet. To visualize the jet flow development for the tested cases, numerical simulations with experimental validation, were also carried out. For exit Mach number of 0.6, the single free jet has a potential core length up to X/D<sub>p</sub> = 3.8, whereas for 10&#xa0;mm lip co-flowing jet with bypass ratio 0.7, 1.4 and 6.4 the potential core length extends up to X/D<sub>p</sub> = 2.8, 2.7 and 2.1 and their corresponding percentage reduction is 26, 29, 45% respectively. Similarly for 15&#xa0;mm lip for co-flowing jet with bypass ratio 1, 1.7 and 6, the potential core length extends up to X/D<sub>p</sub> = 2.7, 2.2 and 1.6 and their corresponding reduction percentage is 29, 42, 58% respectively. Concluding that for the thick lip co-flowing jet, the presence of recirculation zone at the near field of the nozzle wall, the centreline Mach number increases initially due to the wake dominant sub-atmospheric pressure, exists in the flow regime and also when the bypass ratio increases, the potential core length decreases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>K Sathish</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Aeronautical Engineering, Nehru Institute of Engineering and Technology, T.M Palayam, Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shankar</LastName><ForeName>R Naren</ForeName><Initials>RN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Aeronautical Engineering, Vel Tech Rangarajan Dr. Sagunthala R&amp;D Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai, 600062, India. narensankar@veltech.edu.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ganesan</LastName><ForeName>V G</ForeName><Initials>VG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kumarguru Centre for Industrial Research and Innovation, Kumaraguru College of Technology, Coimbatore, 641049, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bastola</LastName><ForeName>Rohan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Aeronautical Engineering, Vel Tech Rangarajan Dr. Sagunthala R&amp;D Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai, 600062, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajendran</LastName><ForeName>Parvathy</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, United Arab Emirates University, Al Ain, UAE. aeparvathy@uaeu.ac.ae.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>It Ee</ForeName><Initials>IE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Smart Systems and Automation, COE for Robotics and Sensing Technologies, Faculty of Artificial Intelligence and Engineering (FAIE), Multimedia University, Persiaran Multimedia, Cyberjaya, 63100, Selangor, Malaysia. ielee@mmu.edu.my.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>VTU / RDF / FY 2025-26 / 042</GrantID><Agency>Vel Tech Rangarajan Dr. Sagunthala R&amp;D Institute of Science and Technology, Research and Development Fund</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>TAR/2023/000022 and TAR/2021/000093</GrantID><Agency>Department of Science and Technology, Science and Engineering Research Board</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bypass ratio</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lip thickness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pitot static tube</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recirculation zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Subsonic co-flowing jet</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41298643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12658213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-26077-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-26077-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rathakrishnan, E. <i>Applied Gas Dynamics</i> 2nd edn (Wiley, 2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko, N. W. M. &amp; Kwan, A. S. H. The initial region of subsonic coaxial jets. <i>J. Fluid Mech.</i><b>73</b>, 305&#x2013;332 (1976).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0022112076001389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shankar, R. N. et al. Numerical investigation of critical lip thickness of subsonic co-flowing jet. <i>Aircr. Eng. Aerosp. Technol.</i><b>93</b>, 1193&#x2013;1203 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/AEAT-10-2020-0225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shankar, R. N. et al. Characteristics of a co-flowing jet with varying lip thickness and constant velocity ratio. <i>Aircr. Eng. Aerosp. Technol.</i><b>92</b>, 633&#x2013;644 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/AEAT-05-2019-0104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forstall, W. &amp; Shapiro, A. H. <i>Momentum and Mass Transfer in Coaxial Gas Jets</i> (MIT Guided Missiles Program, 1949).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgiadis, N. J. &amp; Papamoschou, D. Computational investigations of high-speed dual-stream jets. In <i>9th AIAA/CEAS Aeronautics Conf. and Exhibit.</i> 1&#x2013;11 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papamoschou, D. Mixing enhancement using axial flow. <i>AIAA</i> 1&#x2013;19 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaman, K. B. M. Q. &amp; Dahl, M. D. Noise and spreading of subsonic coannular jets: comparison with single equivalent jet. <i>AIAA J</i><b>45</b>, (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovaraju, P. &amp; Rathakrishnan, E. Experimental studies on co-flowing subsonic and Sonic jets. <i>Flow. Turbul. Combust.</i><b>87</b>, 115&#x2013;132 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10494-011-9332-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasarao, T., Lovaraju, P. &amp; Rathakrishnan, E. Effect of co-flow on near field shock structure. <i>J. Fluids Eng.</i><b>134</b>, 071203 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4006911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto, R. &amp; Kimoto, K. Tsuchimoto, N. A study on double concentric jets. <i>Bull. JSME</i>. <b>16</b>, 529&#x2013;540 (1973).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1299/jsme1958.16.529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huda, A. A., Widodo, A. S. &amp; Siswanto, E. Pengaruh lip thickness turncated nozzle sudut luar terhadap karakteristik api difusi concentric jet flow. <i>Rekayasa Mesin</i><b>10</b>, (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahm, W. J. A., Frieler, C. E. &amp; Tryggvason, G. Vortex structure and dynamics in the near field of a coaxial jet. <i>J. Fluid Mech.</i><b>241</b>, 371&#x2013;402 (1992).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0022112092002088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durao, D. &amp; Whitelaw, J. H. Turbulent mixing in the developing region of coaxial jets. <i>Trans. ASME</i>. <b>95</b>, 467&#x2013;473 (1973).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;rl&#xfc;, R. et al. On the passive control of the near-field of coaxial jets by means of vortex shedding. In <i>Proc. 2nd Int. Conf. on Jets, Wakes and Separated Flows</i> (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehab, H., Villermaux, E. &amp; Hopfinger, E. J. Geometrical effects on the near-field flow structure of coaxial jets. <i>AIAA J.</i><b>36</b>, 867&#x2013;869 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2514/2.449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talamelli, A. &amp; Gavarini, I. Linear instability characteristics of incompressible coaxial jets. <i>Flow. Turbul. Combust.</i><b>76</b>, 221&#x2013;240 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10494-006-9015-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villermaux, E. &amp; Rehab, H. Mixing in coaxial jets. <i>J. Fluid Mech.</i><b>425</b>, 161&#x2013;185 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S002211200000210X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villermaux, E. &amp; Rehab, H. (ed J. Hopfinger, E.) Breakup r&#xe9;gimes and self-sustained pulsations in coaxial jets. <i>Meccanica</i><b>29</b>393&#x2013;401 (1994).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00987574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warda, H. A. et al. An experimental investigation of the near-field region of a free turbulent coaxial jet using LDA. <i>Flow. Meas. Instrum.</i><b>10</b>, 15&#x2013;26 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0955-5986(98)00041-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasarao, T., Lovaraju, P. &amp; Rathakrishnan, E. Characteristics of co-flow jets from orifices. <i>Int. J. Turbo Jet-</i>. <b>Engines31</b>, 141&#x2013;148 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasarao, T., Murthy, I. D., Lovaraju, P. &amp; Rathakrishnan, E. Effect of inner nozzle lip thickness on co-flow jet characteristics. <i>Int. J. Turbo Jet-</i>. <b>Engines34</b>, 287&#x2013;293 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shankar, R. N., Thanigaiarasu, S. &amp; Rathakrishnan, E. Co-flowing jet control using lip thickness variation. <i>Int. J. Turbo Jet Engines</i><b>35</b>, (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shankar, R. N. <i>Effect of lip thickness and bypass co-flowing jets</i>. PhD Thesis, Anna University (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thanigaiarasu, S., Shankar, R. N. &amp; Rathakrishnan, E. Influence of bypass ratio on subsonic and correctly expanded Sonic co-flowing jets with finite lip thickness. <i>Proc. Inst. Mech. Eng. G J. Aerosp. Eng.</i><b>233</b>, 2536&#x2013;2548 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0954410018782511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shankar, R. N. &amp; Bennett, S. K. Characteristics of a co-flowing jet with varying lip thickness and constant bypass ratio. <i>Aircr. Eng. Aerosp. Technol.</i><b>91</b>, 1205&#x2013;1213 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/AEAT-01-2019-0007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datta, A. &amp; Sinhamahapatra, K. P. Investigation of the influence of co-flow velocity ratio on a compressible plane jet exhausting into parallel streams. <i>Aerosp. Sci. Technol.</i><b>45</b>, 186&#x2013;195 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datta, A. &amp; Sinhamahapatra, K. P. Investigation of the influence of convective Mach number on compressible plane jet exhausting into parallel streams. <i>J. Inst. Eng. India Ser.</i><b>C99</b>, 401&#x2013;412 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perumal, A. K., Singh, H. &amp; Rathakrishnan, E. Passive control of coaxial jet with supersonic primary jet and Sonic secondary jet. <i>Phys. Fluids</i><b>32</b> (7), (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathish Kumar, K., Shankar, R. N. &amp; Anusindhiya, K. Senthil Kumar, B. R. Numerical analysis of supersonic co-flow jet with varying lip thickness. <i>Aircr. Eng. Aerosp. Technol.</i><b>94</b>, 198&#x2013;209 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radha Krishnan, N. S., Kumar, S. K., Kengaiah, V., Chidambaram, S. &amp; Rathakrishnan, E. Effect of bypass ratio on Sonic underexpanded co-flow jets with finite lip thickness. <i>Int J. Turbo Jet Engines</i> (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shankar, R. N., Thanigaiarasu, S. &amp; Rathakrishnan, E. Numerical characterization of lip thickness on subsonic and correctly expanded Sonic co-flowing jets. <i>Trans. Jpn Soc. Aeronaut. Space Sci.</i><b>59</b>, 134&#x2013;141 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2322/tjsass.59.134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spalart, P. R. &amp; Allmaras, S. R. One-equation turbulence model for aerodynamic flows. <i>AIAA</i><b>23</b> (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chien, K. Y. Predictions of channel and boundary-layer flows with a low-Reynolds-number two-equation model of turbulence. <i>AIAA J.</i><b>20</b>, 33&#x2013;38 (1982).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2514/3.51043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menter, F. R. Two-equation eddy-viscosity turbulence models for engineering applications. <i>AIAA J.</i><b>32</b>, 1598&#x2013;1605 (1994).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2514/3.12149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilcox, D. C. <i>Turbulence Modeling for CFD</i> (DCW Industries, 1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Launder, B. E., Reece, G. J. &amp; Rodi, W. Progress in the development of a Reynolds-stress turbulence closure. <i>J. Fluid Mech.</i><b>68</b>, 537&#x2013;566 (1975).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0022112075001814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgiadis, N. J., Yoder, D. A. &amp; Engblom, W. A. Evaluation of modified two-equation turbulence models for jet flow predictions. <i>AIAA J.</i><b>44</b>, 3107&#x2013;3114 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2514/1.22650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, O. Verification and validation of the Spalart-Allmaras turbulence model for strand grids. <i>PhDT</i>10.26076/ff0d-3e7b (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26076/ff0d-3e7b</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng, K. H. &amp; Spalding, D. B. Turbulence model for boundary layers near walls. <i>Phys. Fluids</i>. <b>15</b> (1), 20&#x2013;30. 10.1063/1.1693739 (1972).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.1693739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>