<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41276531</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Seismogenic strength and anatomy of mahendragarh-dehradun fault: implication to seismic risk.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>42192</StartPage><MedlinePgn>42192</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">42192</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-26160-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We examined stress transfer associated with four moderate earthquakes (M<sub>L</sub>&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;4.0) along the Mahendragarh-Dehradun Fault (MDF) to assess its seismogenic strength and potential for triggering future events in the Delhi-NCR region. The selected earthquakes occurred on 2006-05-07 (M<sub>L</sub> 4.2), 2012-03-05 (M<sub>L</sub> 5.1), 2017-06-01 (M<sub>L</sub> 4.6), and 2020-05-29 (M<sub>L</sub> 4.2). Coulomb Failure Stress (CFS) analysis revealed notable stress redistribution and fault interactions near the MDF and adjacent structures such as the Delhi-Haridwar Ridge (DHR). The 2017 earthquake showed significant stress transfer perpendicular to the MDF, with stress release along the fault itself and enhanced stress in surrounding areas likely influenced by prior events. The faulting mechanisms found normal (2006, 2020), reverse (2012), and strike-slip with reverse (2017) aligned with distinct stress zones, indicating varied rupture dynamics. While the 2006, 2012, and 2020 events occurred in stress concentration zones, the 2017 event was located in a stress reduction zone, highlighting complex fault interactions and stress evolution, suggesting the varying structural heterogeneities associated with MDF at varying depths. These findings emphasize the role of fault geometry, cumulative stress transfer, and rupture style in regional hazard potential. Based on these insights, a seismotectonic model for the MDF is proposed that supports its intricate anatomy, which found very much useful for seismic hazard assessment and earthquake preparedness in the Delhi-NCR.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gera</LastName><ForeName>Sasi Kiran</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Seismology, Ministry of Earth Sciences, Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ammani</LastName><ForeName>Ambikapathy</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Seismology, Ministry of Earth Sciences, Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sandeep</LastName><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geophysics, Banaras Hindu University, Varanasi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Priya</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Seismology, Ministry of Earth Sciences, Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mishra</LastName><ForeName>O P</ForeName><Initials>OP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Seismology, Ministry of Earth Sciences, Delhi, India. opmishra2010.saarc@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coulomb stress change</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mahendragarh-Dehradun fault (MDF)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Optimally normal fault</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Optimally strike slip fault</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Optimally thrust fault</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Seismic hazard assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Seismogenic strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stress transfer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41276531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12657863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-26160-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-26160-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dubey, C. S. et al. Present activity and seismogenic potential of Himalayan sub-parallel thrust faults in Delhi: Inferences from remote sensing, GPR, gravity data and seismicity. <i>Near Surf Geophys.</i><b>10</b>, 369&#x2013;380 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3997/1873-0604.2012006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamble, V. P. &amp; Chaudhary, H. M. Recent seismic activity in Delhi and neighborhood. <i>Mausam</i><b>30</b>, 305&#x2013;312 (1979).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.54302/mausam.v30i2.3046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parvez, I. A., Vaccari, F. &amp; Panza, G. F. Influence of source distance on site-effects in Delhi city. <i>Curr. Sci.</i><b>91</b>, 825&#x2013;835 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal, B. K. et al. Source study of two small earthquakes of Delhi, India, and estimation of ground motion from future moderate, local events. <i>J. Seismolog.</i><b>13</b>, 89&#x2013;105 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10950-008-9118-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharya, S. N. &amp; Dattatrayam, R. S. Some characteristics of recent earthquake sequences in Peninsular India. <i>Gondwana Geol Magazine</i><b>5</b>, 67&#x2013;85 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayalakshmi, S. &amp; Raghukanth, S. T. G. Regional ground motion simulation around Delhi due to future large earthquake. <i>Nat. Hazards</i><b>82</b>(3), 1479&#x2013;1513 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11069-016-2254-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittal, H., Sharma, B., Sandeep, &amp; Ambikapathy, A. Characteristics of earthquake ground motions governing the damage potential for Delhi and the surrounding region of India. <i>Quat Sci Adv</i>10.1016/j.qsa.2023.100098 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.qsa.2023.100098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, C. H. &amp; Stein, R. S. Stress evolution following the 1999 Chi-Chi, Taiwan, earthquake: consequences for afterslip, relaxation, aftershocks and departures from Omori decay. <i>Geophys J Int</i><b>177</b>, 179&#x2013;192 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-246X.2008.04069.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein, R. S., Barka, A. A. &amp; Dieterich, J. H. Progressive failure on the North Anatolian fault since 1939 by earthquake stress triggering. <i>Geophys. J. Int.</i><b>128</b>(3), 594&#x2013;604. 10.1111/j.1365-246X.1997.tb05321.x (1997).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-246X.1997.tb05321.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, C., Dong, P. &amp; Shi, Y. Stress change from the 2015 Mw 7.8 Gorkha earthquake and increased hazard in the southern Tibetan Plateau. <i>Phys Earth Planet Inter</i><b>267</b>, 1&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.pepi.2017.04.002 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pepi.2017.04.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, C. H., Wang, Y., Almeida, R. &amp; Yadav, R. B. S. Enhanced stress and changes to regional seismicity due to the 2015 Mw 7.8 Gorkha, Nepal, earthquake on the neighbouring segments of the Main Himalayan Thrust. <i>J Asian Earth Sci</i>10.1016/j.jseaes.2016.03.004 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jseaes.2016.03.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal, P. Estimation of static stress changes after the 2001 Bhuj Earthquake: Implications towards the Northward spatial migration of the seismic activity in Kachchh, Gujarat. <i>J Geol Soc India</i><b>74</b>, 487&#x2013;497 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12594-009-0151-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambikapathy, A. et al. The 2007 Bengkulu earthquake, its rupture model and implications for seismic hazard. <i>J. Earth Syst. Sci.</i><b>119</b>, 553&#x2013;560 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12040-010-0037-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, A. P. et al. Rainfall-induced seismicity beneath the Dharwar Craton of the Indian Shield. <i>Environ Earth Sci</i><b>82</b>, 410 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-023-11092-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, M. L., Wason, H. &amp; Dimri, R. Seismic zonation of the Delhi region for bedrock ground motion. <i>Pure Appl. Geophys.</i><b>160</b>, 2381&#x2013;2398. 10.1007/s00024-003-2400-6 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00024-003-2400-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delhi Microzonation Report, 2016. A report on seismic hazard microzonation of NCT Delhi. National center for seismology, ministry of earth sciences, Govt of India.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukhopadhyay, S. et al. Seismic Microzonation of Delhi for ground-shaking site effects. <i>Curr. Sci.</i><b>82</b>, 877&#x2013;881 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parvez, I.A., Vaccari, F., Panza, G.F Site-specific microzonation study in Delhi metropolitan City by 2-D modelling of SH and P-SV Waves. In: Panza, G.F., Paskaleva, I., Nunziata, C. (eds) Seismic ground motion in large urban areas. Pageoph topical volumes. Birkh&#xe4;user Basel. 10.1007/978-3-0348-7355-0_13. (2004)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel, N. K. et al. Seismicity around the Mahendragarh-Dehradun basement fault in the western Ganga plain, India: A neotectonic perspective. <i>Int. J. Earth Sci.</i><b>109</b>, 689&#x2013;706. 10.1007/s00531-020-01826-8 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00531-020-01826-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey, A. P., Suresh, G., Singh, A., Sutar, A. K. &amp; Bansal, B. K. A widely felt Tremor (ML 3.5) of 12 April 2020 in and around NCT Delhi in the backdrop of prevailing COVID-19 pandemic lockdown: Analysis and observations. <i>Geomat. Nat. Haz. Risk</i><b>11</b>, 1638&#x2013;1652 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19475705.2020.1810785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, S. K. et al. Delhi earthquake of 25 November 2007 (Mw 4.1): Implications for seismic hazard. <i>Curr. Sci.</i><b>99</b>, 1&#x2013;9 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma, R. K. et al. Seismicity of Delhi and its surrounding region. <i>J. Himal. Geol.</i><b>6</b>, 75&#x2013;82 (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oldham, T. A catalogue of indian earthquakes from the earliest to the end of AD 1869. <i>Memoirs Geol Surv India</i><b>19</b>, 53 (1883).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chouhan, R. K. S. Seismotectonics of Delhi region. <i>Proc. Indian Natl. Sci. Acad.</i><b>41</b>, 429&#x2013;447 (1975).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava, V. K., Roy, A.K. Seismotectonics and seismic risk study in and around Delhi region. In: Proceedings, IV Congress International Association of Engineering Geology, New Delhi, III: 77&#x2013;86. 1982</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava LS., Somayajulu JG. The seismicity of area around Delhi. In: Proc. III symposium on Earthquake Engineering., Univ. of Roorkee. 417&#x2013;22. 1966</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, S. K. et al. The Delhi 1960 earthquake: epicentre, depth and magnitude. <i>Curr. Sci.</i><b>105</b>(8), 1155&#x2013;1164 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyengar, R. N. &amp; Ghosh, S. Microzonation of earthquake hazard in greater Delhi area. <i>Curr. Sci.</i><b>87</b>(9), 1193&#x2013;1202 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyengar, R. N., Ghosh, S., Seismic hazard mapping of Delhi city. In: Proceedings of 13th world conference on earthquake engineering. Vancouver, B.C., Canada. Paper No. 180. 2004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyengar, R. N. Seismic status of Delhi megacity. <i>Curr. Sci.</i><b>78</b>(5), 568&#x2013;574 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasgupta, S. &amp; Mukhopadhyay, B. 1803 earthquake in Garhwal Himalaya: Archival materials with commentary. <i>Indian J History Sci</i><b>49</b>(1), 21&#x2013;33 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakash, R. &amp; Shrivastava, J. P. A review of the seismicity and seismotectonics of Delhi and adjoining areas. <i>J Geol Soc India</i><b>79</b>(6), 603&#x2013;617 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12594-012-0099-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava, V. K., Jalote, P.M. Seismicity and tectonic set up of the area around Delhi. In: Proceedings sixth world conference on earthquake engineering, New Delhi 1 791&#x2013;798. 1977</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, S., Mohanty, W. K., Prakash, R. &amp; Shukla, A. K. Crustal heterogeneity and seismotectonics of the national capital region, Delhi. <i>India. Pure Appl. Geophys.</i><b>170</b>, 607&#x2013;616. 10.1007/s00024-012-0572-7 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00024-012-0572-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal, B. K., Mohan, K., Verma, M. &amp; Anup, K. S. A holistic seismotectonic model of Delhi region. <i>Sci Report</i><b>11</b>, 13818. 10.1038/s41598-021-93291-9 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-93291-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8257579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34226587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik, S. P. et al. Archeoseismic study of damage in medieval monuments around new Delhi, India: An Approach to understanding paleoseismicity in an intraplate region. <i>GeoHazards</i><b>5</b>(1), 142&#x2013;165. 10.3390/geohazards5010007 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/geohazards5010007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawat, G. et al. Geoelectric characterisation of the junction of seismically active Delhi Hardwar Ridge and Delhi Sargodha Ridge. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>13</b>(1), 18488. 10.1038/s41598-023-42722-w (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-42722-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10613208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37898633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhali, M., Gadhavi, M. S., Mohan, K., Narayana, P. P. &amp; Malik, J. N. Active faults studies in Delhi and national capital region (NCR): Inferences from satellite data and field investigations. <i>Front Earth Sci</i><b>11</b>, 1092927 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feart.2023.1092927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra, O. P. Seismic microzonation study of south Asian cities and its implications to urban risk resiliency under climate change scenario. <i>Int. J. Geosci.</i><b>11</b>, 197&#x2013;237. 10.4236/ijg.2020.114012 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ijg.2020.114012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra, O. P. et al. <i>Seismic microzonation of Indian cities and strategy for safer design of structures. Social and economic impact of earth sciences</i> (Springer, Singapore, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gera, S. K., Singh, A. P., Ammani, A., Sandeep, &amp; Mishra, O. P. Structural Heterogeneity and Seismogenesis of the national capital region NCR-Delhi India. <i>J Asian Earth Sci</i><b>286</b>, 106576. 10.1016/j.jseaes.2025.106576 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jseaes.2025.106576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavankumar, G. et al. Magnetotelluric evidence for the presence of a deep electrical conductor in the vicinity of the Delhi Seismic Zone. <i>India. J Earth Syst Sci</i><b>130</b>, 79. 10.1007/s12040-021-01565-7 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12040-021-01565-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, R., Yadav, R. B. S., Mittal, H., Saini, A., &amp; Mishra, O. P. Estimation of earthquake recurrence parameters for the Himalayan seismic belt: a comprehensive analysis. Natural Hazards, 1&#x2013;39. (2025)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein, R. S. The role of stress transfer in earthquake occurrence. <i>Nature</i><b>402</b>, 605&#x2013;609 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/45144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toda, S., Stein, R. S., Reasenberg, P. A., Dieterich, J. H., &amp; Yoshida, A Coulomb 3.3 graphic-rich deformation and stress-change software for earthquake, tectonic, and volcano research and teaching-user guide. US Geological Survey Open-File Report, 2010&#x2013;1316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King, G., Stein, R. &amp; Lin, J. Static stress changes and the triggering of earthquakes. <i>Bull Seismol Soc Am.</i><b>84</b>(3), 935&#x2013;953 (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shukla, A. K., Prakash, R., Singh, R. K., Mishra, P. S. &amp; Bhatnagar, A. K. Seismotectonic implications of Delhi region through fault plane solutions of some recent earthquakes. <i>Curr Sci</i><b>93</b>(12), 1848&#x2013;1853 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18520/cs/v120/i12/1848-1853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra, O. P., Kumar, V. &amp; Gera, S. K. A new insight into seismic attenuation characteristics of Northwest Himalaya and its surrounding region: Implications to structural heterogeneities and earthquake hazards. <i>Phys. Earth Planet. Inter.</i><b>306</b>, 106500 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pepi.2020.106500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittal, H.&#xa0;Estimation of ground motion in Delhi&#xa0;(Doctoral dissertation, Roorkee, India). (2011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, S. K., Mohanty, W. K., Bansal, B. K. &amp; Roonwal, G. S. Ground motion in Delhi from future large/Great earthquakes in the central seismic gap of the Himalayan arc. <i>Bull. Seismol. Soc. Am.</i><b>92</b>(2), 555&#x2013;569. 10.1785/0120010139 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1785/0120010139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardebeck, J. L., Nazareth, J. J. &amp; Hauksson, E. The static stress change triggering model: Constraints from two southern California aftershock sequences. <i>J Geophys Res.</i><b>103</b>, 427&#x2013;437 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/98JB00573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons, T. Significance of stress transfer in time-dependent earthquake probability calculations. <i>J Geophys Res</i><b>110</b>, B05S02. 10.1029/2004JB003190 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2004JB003190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manga, M. et al. Changes in permeability caused by transient stresses: Field observations, experiments, and mechanisms. <i>Rev. Geophys.</i><b>50</b>, RG2004. 10.1029/2011RG000382 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2011RG000382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goebel, T. H. W. et al. Wastewater disposal and earthquake swarm activity at the southern end of the Central Valley, California. <i>Geophys. Res. Lett.</i><b>43</b>, 1092&#x2013;1099. 10.1002/2015GL066948 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/2015GL066948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal, B. K. &amp; Verma, M. The M 4.9 Delhi earthquake of 5 March 2012. <i>Curr Sci</i><b>102</b>(12), 1704&#x2013;1708 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Indian Meteorological Department. Report on micro earthquake survey of the Jind region (Haryana), pp. 1&#x2013;8 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, D., Sarkar, I., Sriram, V. &amp; Teotia, S. S. Evaluating the seismic hazard to the national capital (Delhi) region, India, from moderate earthquakes using simulated accelerograms. <i>Nat. Hazards</i><b>61</b>(2), 481&#x2013;500 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11069-011-9933-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajput, S., Gahalaut, V. K. &amp; Sahu, V. K. Coulomb stress changes and aftershocks of recent Indian earthquakes. <i>Curr. Sci.</i><b>88</b>(4), 576&#x2013;588 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rastogi, B. K. Seismotectonics inferred from Earthquakes and Earthquakes Sequences in Indian during the 1980s. <i>Curr. Sci.</i><b>62</b>, 101&#x2013;108 (1992).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>