<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41361229</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Structural characteristics of the slurry-filled receptive zone in longwall goaf filled with gangue slurry.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>952</StartPage><MedlinePgn>952</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">952</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-30546-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To address the dual challenges of environmentally sustainable coal gangue disposal and the effective utilization of underground mined-out spaces, this study investigates the structural characteristics of goafs that govern the efficiency of gangue slurry filling. An integrated methodology combining theoretical analysis, physical simulation experiments, and field-scale industrial testing was employed to systematically examine the spatial architecture and void distribution within the goaf. The research elucidates the spatial evolution mechanism of overlying strata, which follows a sequential "arch-beam-shell" pattern, leading to the identification of the stable residual "shell" structure as the Slurry-Filled Receptive (SF-R) zone. The key stratum governing slurry migration is defined as the Slurry Movement Control (SM-C) stratum, for which a discriminant criterion is established based on mechanical stiffness, strength, and stratal control principles. The influence of the SM-C stratum on the formation of three distinct structural zones-namely, free accumulation, load-affected, and compacted zones-along both strike and dip directions is clarified. Furthermore, the void distribution within the goaf is quantitatively characterized, revealing that the bulking factor of caved rock decreases with increasing depth and height into the goaf, following a negative logarithmic function. The SF-R zone constitutes a quantifiable and exploitable space for slurry injection, with its structural configuration and porosity primarily regulated by the SM-C stratum. These findings were validated through an industrial application at Huangling No. 2 Coal Mine, where targeted filling was implemented in the overlapping region of the free accumulation and load-affected zones. This study establishes a robust theoretical framework and provides a practical methodology for the design and optimization of high-efficiency gangue slurry filling systems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Mengye</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Coal Energy Research Institute Co., Ltd, Xi'an, 710000, Shaanxi, PR China. ruoatm8@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Coal Energy Research Institute Co., Ltd, Xi'an, 710000, Shaanxi, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chengyong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Coal Energy Research Institute Co., Ltd, Xi'an, 710000, Shaanxi, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Wenzhe</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Coal Energy Research Institute Co., Ltd, Xi'an, 710000, Shaanxi, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Zhicheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Coal Energy Research Institute Co., Ltd, Xi'an, 710000, Shaanxi, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>ZMYHT*CK-W-GSZYHLY-03-23-040</GrantID><Agency>The Key Project of China National Coal Group Corporation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gangue slurry filling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Goaf structure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical simulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Slurry movement control (SM-C) stratum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Slurry-Filled receptive (SF-R) field</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Void distribution</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41361229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12783790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-30546-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-30546-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhu, L. et al. Research progress and prospect of coal gangue slurry backfilling technology in Goaf. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>51</b> (2), 143&#x2013;154 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, H. et al. New ideas of coal revolution and layout of coal science and technology development. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>43</b> (5), 1178&#x2013;1197 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, L. et al. Basic theories and applied exploration of functional backfill in mines. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>43</b> (7), 1811&#x2013;1820 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, K., Zhao, X., He, X. &amp; Wei, Z. Basic theory and key technology of multi-source coal-based solid waste for green backfilling. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>47</b> (12), 4201&#x2013;4216 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, W., Yang, B., Pan, H. &amp; Song, T. Research and engineering practice on space characteristics of gangue slurry filling. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>13</b>, 22006 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-46222-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10716274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38086846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, D., Fan, Y., Dong, X., Ma, X. &amp; Liu, P. Mechanical properties and hydration mechanism of coal flotation tailing cemented filling materials. <i>Minerals</i><b>13</b> (3), 389 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min13030389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv, W. et al. Research on the distribution characteristics of the bulking coefficient in the strike direction of the Longwall Goaf filled with slurry. <i>Sustainability</i><b>15</b> (3), 2508 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su15032508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J., Li, X. &amp; He, T. Application status and prospect of backfill mining in Chinese coal mines. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>45</b> (1), 141&#x2013;150 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, J. Research and progress of coal mine green mining in 20 years. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>48</b> (9), 1&#x2013;15 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, W., Zhu, L. &amp; Song, T. Research on key parameters of pipeline transportation of waste rock treatment in underground residual space. <i>Front. Earth Sci.</i><b>10</b>, 1098674 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feart.2022.1098674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, Z. et al. Simulation test study on filling flow law of gangue slurry in Goaf. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>13</b>, 19117 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-45596-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10625934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37926708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. Low-carbon utilization of coal gangue under the carbon neutralization strategy: a short review. <i>J. Mater. Cycles Waste Manag</i>. <b>25</b>, 1978&#x2013;1987 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10163-023-01712-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, S. et al. Technology and engineering test of filling Goaf with coal gangue slurry. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>13</b>, 20536 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-47621-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10667347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37996503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, L. et al. Experimental study on flow and diffusion law of gangue filling slurry in caving zone. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>46</b> (S2), 629&#x2013;638 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, J., Ding, Z., Gao, C., Gong, X. &amp; Zhang, C. Space effect of loading-unloading stress path evolution of roof strata and surrounding rock control in deep mining. <i>Rock. Mech. Rock. Eng.</i><b>08</b>10.1007/s00603-025-04794-0 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, L. et al. Experimental research on transport-resistance characteristics of gangue slurry and its flow trend in Goaf. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>47</b> (S1), 39&#x2013;48 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L. et al. Study on the slurry diffusion law of fluidized filling gangue in the caving Goaf of Thick coal seam fully mechanized caving mining. <i>Energies</i><b>15</b> (21), 8164 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15218164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, J., Liu, X. &amp; Ren, T. Overburden stability of an inclined backfill Stope in the context of the nonlinear elastic mechanical properties of the backfill body. <i>Environ. Earth Sci.</i><b>78</b>, 719 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-019-8728-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Y. et al. Preparation of the geopolymer grouting material by coal-based solid wastes for the aquiclude key strata and its application. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>408</b>, 133539 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. et al. Diffusion law of coal gangue slurry and the application of fluidized filling technology of gangue in caving area. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>13</b>, 13226 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-38165-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10425454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37580337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, W. et al. Fluidization slurry backfilling technology of coal mine solid waste. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>49</b> (3), 83&#x2013;91 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, Z. et al. Carbonation curing of modified magnesium-coal based solid waste backfill material for CO2 sequestration. <i>Process. Saf. Environ. Prot.</i><b>180</b>, 778&#x2013;788 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2023.10.049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, X. et al. Feasibility and challenges of multi-source coal-based solid waste (CSW) for underground backfilling-A case study. <i>Process. Saf. Environ. Prot.</i><b>181</b>, 8&#x2013;25 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2023.11.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. &amp; Wang, J. Comprehensive utilization and environmental risks of coal gangue: A review. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>239</b>, 117946 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.117946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, M., Miao, X. &amp; Xu, J. Theoretical study of key stratum in ground control. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>35</b> (3), 355&#x2013;359 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, L. et al. Dynamic loading induced by the instability of voussoir beam structure during mining below the slope. <i>Int. J. Rock. Mech. Min.</i><b>132</b>, 104343 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2020.104343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, M. et al. Properties of a backfill material prepared by cementing coal gangue and fly Ash through microbial-induced calcite precipitation. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>384</b>, 131329 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua, X. et al. Strength evolution law and acoustic-emission characteristics of multi-source coal-based filling body of solid wastes. <i>Chin. J. Rock. Mech. Eng.</i><b>41</b> (8), 1536&#x2013;1551 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, L. et al. Research progress and prospect of coal gangue slurry backfilling technology in Goaf. <i>Chin. Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>48</b> (4), 81&#x2013;86 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, W. et al. Integration of protective mining and underground backfilling for coal and gas outburst control: A case study. <i>Process. Saf. Environ. Prot.</i><b>157</b>, 273&#x2013;283 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2021.11.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding, Z., Zhang, C., Jia, J. &amp; Gao, C. A data-driven method for intelligent lithology identification in coal mines based on drilling parameters. <i>Eng. Geolo.</i><b>359</b>, 108448&#xa0;(2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enggeo.2025.108448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>