<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41238952</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1896-1851</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>70</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta parasitologica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Parasitol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence of Free-Living Amoebae in Various Water Sources in Iran: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>220</StartPage><MedlinePgn>220</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11686-025-01154-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Free-living amoebae (FLA) are widespread protozoa found in various water sources and can cause serious human infections. Identifying their occurrence and diversity in environmental waters is crucial for public health risk assessment and prevention. This study aimed to systematically review the prevalence and species/genotype distribution of FLA in different Iranian water sources.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic search was conducted in major international (PubMed, Scopus, Web of Science, Google Scholar) and Persian (SID, MagIran) databases from inception up to June 6, 2025. Eligible studies reporting the detection of FLA from Iranian water sources were included. In total, 58 studies met the inclusion criteria, encompassing 4,387 water samples from 24 provinces. Water sources were categorized into five groups: drinking/domestic water (six studies, 454 samples), natural recreational water (14 studies, 606 samples), artificial recreational water (16 studies, 1,666 samples), surface/stagnant water (eight studies, 703 samples), and mixed water (14 studies, 958 samples). Statistical analyses were performed using Comprehensive Meta-Analysis (CMA) software, applying a random-effects model with 95% confidence intervals (CIs). Heterogeneity was assessed using the I<sup>2</sup> statistic. Sensitivity analysis was performed by sequentially removing individual studies, and meta-regression was applied to explore potential sources of heterogeneity. Subgroup analyses were conducted based on publication year, water type, geographical region, climate zone, and sample size.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The pooled prevalence of FLA in Iranian water sources was 40.2% (95% CI: 33.7-47.1%). Among water categories, the highest contamination was observed in surface/stagnant waters (59.9%), followed by mixed waters (42.5%), natural recreational waters (42.1%), drinking/domestic waters (38.0%), and artificial recreational waters (29.0%). By climate zone, water sources in warm/humid and temperate/humid areas showed the highest prevalence (49.2% and 44.7%, respectively). Provincially, the highest contamination rates were recorded in Sistan and Baluchestan (88.2%), Hamedan (87.5%), Kermanshah (76.7%), Khuzestan (71.7%), and North Khorasan (68.0%). Ten FLA genera were reported from Iranian water resources: Acanthamoeba, Naegleria, Vahlkampfia, Vermamoeba, Vannella, Platyamoeba, Saccamoeba, Balamuthia, Protacanthamoeba, and Stenamoeba. Reported species/genotypes included Acanthamoeba T2-T6, T11, T13, and T15; Naegleria fultoni, N. pagei, N. clarki, N. carteri, N. australiensis, N. gruberi, N. dobsoni, N. americana, N. polaris, N. lovaniensis, and N. philippinensis; Vahlkampfia avara; Vermamoeba vermiformis; Vannella persistens; Saccamoeba limax; Stenamoeba polymorpha; Balamuthia mandrillaris; and Protacanthamoeba bohemica. Sensitivity analysis confirmed the robustness of the pooled estimates, while meta-regression identified sample size as a significant contributor to result variability and a potential source of heterogeneity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">FLA are widely prevalent in various water sources of Iran, especially in surface waters and warm/humid climates. The presence of multiple pathogenic genera and genotypes highlights significant health risks. Continuous monitoring and targeted control strategies are essential to reduce exposure and guide future research on environmental and epidemiological factors influencing FLA distribution.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Shamsi</LastName><ForeName>Laya</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathobiology, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Urmia University, Urmia, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Mamizadeh</LastName><ForeName>Mina</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zoonotic Diseases Research Center, Ilam University of Medical Sciences, Ilam, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, School of Medicine, Ilam University of Medical Sciences, Ilam, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammadi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Reza</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bacteriology, Faculty of Medical Sciences, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pouryousef</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Leishmaniasis Research Center, Sabzevar University of Medical Sciences, Sabzevar, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kheiry</LastName><ForeName>Maryam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Non-Communicable Diseases Research Center, Ilam University of Medical Sciences, Ilam, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Badri</LastName><ForeName>Milad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Microbiology Research Center, Qazvin University of Medical Sciences, Qazvin, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asghari</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4005-2687</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Basic Medical Sciences, Khoy University of Medical Sciences, Khoy, Iran. asghari3@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shadfar</LastName><ForeName>Fariba</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zoonotic Diseases Research Center, Ilam University of Medical Sciences, Ilam, Iran. faribashadfar03@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, School of Medicine, Ilam University of Medical Sciences, Ilam, Iran. faribashadfar03@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Parasitol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9301947</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1230-2821</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D060766">Drinking Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007492" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Iran</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000656" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amoeba</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060766" MajorTopicYN="N">Drinking Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000469" MajorTopicYN="N">parasitology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Free-living amoebae (FLA)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Genotype distribution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Iran</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Species diversity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Water contamination</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Water sources</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41238952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11686-025-01154-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11686-025-01154-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Schuster FL, Visvesvara GS (2004) Free-living amoebae as opportunistic and non-opportunistic pathogens of humans and animals. Int J Parasitol 34:1001&#x2013;1027. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijpara.2004.06.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpara.2004.06.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15313128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loret J-F, Greub G (2010) Free-living amoebae: biological by-passes in water treatment. Int J Hyg Environ Health 213:167&#x2013;175. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheh.2010.03.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijheh.2010.03.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20418158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arberas-Jim&#xe9;nez I, Rodr&#xed;guez-Exp&#xf3;sito RL, Sifaoui I, Chao-Pellicer J, Sancho L, Urruticoechea A, Pi&#xf1;ero JE, Lorenzo-Morales J (2024) Influence of salt and temperature in the growth of pathogenic free-living amoebae. Front Microbiol 15:1356452. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2024.1356452</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2024.1356452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38426057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10902715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar-Ardiles C, Asserella-Rebollo L, Andrade DC (2022) Free-living amoebas in extreme environments: the true survival in our planet. Biomed Res Int 2022:2359883. https://doi.org/10.1155/2022/2359883</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/2359883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36303587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9596261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz JH (2011) Behavioral and recreational risk factors for free-living amebic infections. J Travel Med 18:130&#x2013;137. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1708-8305.2011.00493.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1708-8305.2011.00493.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21366798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cha&#xfa;que BJM, Dos Santos DL, Anvari D, Rott MB (2022) Prevalence of free-living amoebae in swimming pools and recreational waters, a systematic review and meta-analysis. Parasitol Res 121:3033&#x2013;3050. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00436-022-07631-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00436-022-07631-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36040629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9424809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saburi E, Rajaii T, Behdari A, Kohansal MH, Vazini H (2017) Free-living amoebae in the water resources of Iran: a systematic review. J Parasit Dis 41:919&#x2013;928. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12639-017-0950-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12639-017-0950-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29114120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5660050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javanmard E, Niyyati M, Lorenzo-Morales J, Lasjerdi Z, Behniafar H, Mirjalali H (2017) Molecular identification of waterborne free living amoebae (Acanthamoeba, Naegleria and Vermamoeba) isolated from municipal drinking water and environmental sources, Semnan province, north half of Iran. Exp Parasitol 183:240&#x2013;244. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.exppara.2017.09.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exppara.2017.09.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28916458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoudi MR, Rahmati B, Seyedpour SH, Karanis P (2015) Occurrence and molecular characterization of free-living amoeba species (Acanthamoeba, Hartmannella, and Saccamoeba limax) in various surface water resources of Iran. Parasitol Res 114:4669&#x2013;4674. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00436-015-4712-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00436-015-4712-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26346454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niyyati M, Lasjerdi Z, Nazar M, Haghighi A, Nazemalhosseini Mojarad E (2012) Screening of recreational areas of rivers for potentially pathogenic free-living amoebae in the suburbs of Tehran, Iran. J Water Health 10:140&#x2013;146. https://doi.org/10.2166/wh.2011.068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wh.2011.068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22361709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badirzadeh A, Niyyati M, Babaei Z, Amini H, Badirzadeh H, Rezaeian M (2011) Isolation of free-living amoebae from Sarein Hot Springs in Ardebil province, Iran. Iran J Parasitol 6:1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22347281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3279877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niyyati M, Lasgerdi Z, Lorenzo-Morales J (2015) Detection and molecular characterization of potentially pathogenic free-living amoebae from water sources in Kish Island, Southern Iran. Microbiol insights 8:MBI-S24099. https://doi.org/10.4137/MBI.S24099</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, Shamseer L, Tetzlaff JM, Akl EA, Brennan SE (2021) The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. bmj 372: 22&#x2013;28. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n71</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute JB (2017) Checklist for prevalence studies. Joanna Briggs Inst Adelaide, Aust</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asghari A, Ebrahimi M, Shamsi L, Sadrebazzaz A, Shams M (2023) Global molecular prevalence of Giardia duodenalis in pigs (Sus domesticus): a systematic review and meta-analysis. Heliyon 9:e13243. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e13243</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e13243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36846671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9946859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shams M, Khazaei S, Ghasemi E, Nazari N, Javanmardi E, Majidiani H, Bahadory S, Anvari D, Fatollahzadeh M, Nemati T (2022) Prevalence of urinary schistosomiasis in women: a systematic review and meta-analysis of recently published literature (2016&#x2013;2020). Trop Med Health 50:12. https://doi.org/10.1186/s41182-022-00402-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41182-022-00402-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35093180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8800356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behravan M, Malekaneh M, Mesbahzadeh B, Sharifzadeh G, Namaei MH, Behniafar H, Lasjerdi Z (2015) Microscopic isolation and characterization of free living amoebae (FLA) from surface water sources in Birjand, the capital city of the South Khorasan. J Transl Med Res 22:161&#x2013;168</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodangeh S, Kialashaki E, Daryani A, Sharif M, Sarvi S, Moghaddam YD, Hosseini SA (2018) Isolation and molecular identification of Acanthamoeba spp. from hot springs in Mazandaran province, northern Iran. J Water Health 16:807&#x2013;813. https://doi.org/10.2166/wh.2018.098</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wh.2018.098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30285961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eftekhar M, Nazem AME, Haghighi A, Sharifi KH, Nouchi Z, Athari A (2009) Detection of Acanthamoeba from fresh water using polymerase chain reaction. Res Med 33:39&#x2013;42</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eftekhari-Kenzerki R, Solhjoo K, Babaei Z, Rezanezhad H, Abolghazi A, Taghipour A (2021) High occurrence of Acanthamoeba spp. in the water samples of public swimming pools from Kerman Province, Iran. J Water Health 19:864&#x2013;871. https://doi.org/10.2166/wh.2021.162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wh.2021.162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34665778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esboei BR, Fakhar M, Saberi R, Barati M, Moslemi M, Hassannia H, Dadimoghadam Y, Jalallou N (2020) Genotyping and phylogenic study of Acanthamoeba isolates from human keratitis and swimming pool water samples in Iran. Parasite Epidemiol Control 11:e00164. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.parepi.2020.e00164</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parepi.2020.e00164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32671234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7341446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fani M, Fuerst PA, Mosayebi M, Javadi A, Harandi MF, Saraei M, Badri M, Hajialilo E (2022) Molecular identification and phylogenetic analysis of free-living amoeba in the water resources of Arak, Iran. J Water Health 20:1051&#x2013;1063. https://doi.org/10.2166/wh.2022.030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wh.2022.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35902987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathollahzadeh P, Zare I, Hosseini MA, Javadi A, Heydarian P, Hajialilo E (2024) Isolation and Identification of Acanthamoeba and Naegleria from Drinking Water of Qazvin. Iran J Isfahan Med Sch 41:1075&#x2013;1081. https://doi.org/10.48305/jims.v41.i746.1075</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48305/jims.v41.i746.1075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sh G, Solhjoo K, MJ N, Rohi R, Zia-Jahromi S (2012) Isolation and identification of free living amoeba (Naegleria and Acanthamoeba) in Shiraz water resources by morphological criteria. J Jahrom Univ Med Sci 10:33. https://doi.org/10.29252/jmj.10.3.33</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghaderifar S, Najafpoor AA, Zarrinfar H, Esmaily H, Hajialilo E (2018) Isolation and identification of Acanthamoeba from pond water of parks in a tropical and subtropical region in the Middle East, and its relation with physicochemical parameters. BMC Microbiol 18:139. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12866-018-1301-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12866-018-1301-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30340522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6195741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghadesi A, Hasanpour H, Naserifar R, Abdi J, Mahmoudi MR, Turki H, Raiesi O, Getso MI, Mirzaei A (2024) Surface water contamination with Acanthamoeba spp. in Ilam city, Iran. J Water Sanit Hyg Dev 14:302&#x2013;312. https://doi.org/10.2166/washdev.2024.153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/washdev.2024.153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad MHF, Khoshnood S, Mahmoudi MR, Habibpour H, Ali SA, Mirzaei H, Haddad RF, Ahmadiangali K (2019) Molecular identification of free-living amoebae (Naegleria spp., Acanthamoeba spp. and Vermamoeba spp.) isolated from un-improved hot springs, Guilan Province, Northern Iran. Iran J Parasitol 14:584</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooshyar H, Hosseinbigi B, Saraei M, Alizadeh S, Eftakhar M, Rasti S, Khosro-Shahi N (2013) Genotyping of Acanthamoeba isolated from surface and stagnant waters of Qazvin, Central Iran. Iran Red Crescent Med J 15:536. https://doi.org/10.5812/ircmj.4121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/ircmj.4121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24349758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3840847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golestani MH, Rasti S, Hooshyar H, Delavari M, Mousavi SGA, Iranshahi L, Aghajani A (2018) Molecular identification and genotyping of Acanthamoeba isolated from environmental sources in Kashan, central Iran. Jundishapur J Microbiol 11:1&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.5812/jjm.55582</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/jjm.55582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseinbigi B, SahnehSaraie MS, Alizadeh SA, Rasti S, Eftakhar M, Khosro-Shahi N, Hooshyar H (2012) Isolation and molecular identification of Acanthamoeba in surface stagnant waters of Qazvin. J Inflamm Dis 16:26&#x2013;32</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javanmard E, Kazemirad E, Rahimi HM, Mohebali M, Rezaeian M, Alimohammadi M, Mirjalali H (2025) Prevalence of free-living amoebae in five rivers associated with high human activity in Tehran province, Iran. J Water Health 23:493&#x2013;506. https://doi.org/10.2166/wh.2025.350</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wh.2025.350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40298268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi A, Kheirandish F, Mamaghani AJ, Taghipour N, Mousavi SF, Aghajani A, Zebardast N, Faraji M, Fallahi S (2023) Identification and genotyping of Acanthamoeba spp. in the water resources of western Iran. Parasite Epidemiology and Control 22:e00308</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parepi.2023.e00308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37638113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10450349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khedri M, Fallah M, Saidijam M, Matini M, Bazzazi N, Maghsood AH (2023) Genotyping of environmental isolates of Acanthamoeba in Hamadan, west of Iran. Iran J Parasitol 18:1. https://doi.org/10.18502/ijpa.v18i1.12374</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18502/ijpa.v18i1.12374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37197069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10183446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khezri A, Fallah E, Mostafazadeh M, Spotin A, Shahbazi A, Mahami-Oskouei M, Hazratian T (2016) Molecular and morphometric characterization of Acanthamoeba spp. from different water sources of Northwest Iran as a neglected focus, co-bordered with the country of Iraq. Jundishapur J Microbiol 9:e38481</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/jjm.38481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28138374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5240160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latifi AR, Niyyati M, Lorenzo-Morales J, Haghighi A, Tabaei SJS, Lasjerdi Z, Azargashb E (2017) Occurrence of Naegleria species in therapeutic geothermal water sources, Northern Iran. Acta Parasitol 62:104&#x2013;109. https://doi.org/10.1515/ap-2017-0012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/ap-2017-0012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28030337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latifi A, Niyyati M, Valayi N, Lasjerdi Z (2014) Frequency survey of free-living amoebae isolated from improved hot springs of Mazandaran Province, 2014. Res Med 38:214&#x2013;220</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latifi AR, Niyyati M, Lorenzo-Morales J, Haghighi A, Tabaei SJS, Lasjerdi Z (2016) Presence of Balamuthia mandrillaris in hot springs from Mazandaran province, northern Iran. Epidemiol Infect 144:2456&#x2013;2461</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S095026881600073X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27086943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latifi A, Salami M, Kazemirad E, Soleimani M (2020) Isolation and identification of free-living amoeba from the hot springs and beaches of the Caspian Sea. Parasite Epidemiol Control 10:e00151. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.parepi.2020.e00151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parepi.2020.e00151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32923701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7474157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mafi M, Niyyati M, Haghighi A, Lasjerdi Z (2016) Contamination of swimming pools and park ponds with free living amoebae in Tehran. Med J Tabriz Univ Med Sci 38:60&#x2013;67</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maghsoodloorad S, Maghsoodloorad E, Tavakoli Kareshk A, Motazedian MH, Yusuf MA, Solgi R (2019) Thermotolerant Acanthamoeba spp. isolated from recreational water in Gorgan City, north of Iran. J Parasit Dis 43:240&#x2013;245. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12639-018-01081-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12639-018-01081-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31263329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6570728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoudi MR, Taghipour N, Eftekhar M, Haghighi A, Karanis P (2012) Isolation of Acanthamoeba species in surface waters of Gilan province-north of Iran. Parasitol Res 110:473&#x2013;477. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00436-011-2530-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00436-011-2530-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21748347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi A, Dalimi A, Ghaffarifar F, Pirestani M, Akbari M (2025) Detection of Acanthamoeba harboring Campylobacter jejuni endosymbionts in hospital environments of Markazi Province, Iran. J Parasitol Res 2025:6626888. https://doi.org/10.1155/japr/6626888</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/japr/6626888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39991014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11845261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoudi MR, Kazemi B, Haghighi A, Karanis P (2015) Detection of Acanthamoeba and Toxoplasma in river water samples by molecular methods in Iran. Iran J Parasitol 10:250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26246823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4522301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammady A, Dalimi A, Ghafarifar F, Akbari M, Pirestani M (2023) Genotyping of Acanthamoeba isolated from hospital environments and thermal water of recreational baths in Markazi province, Iran. Iran J Parasitol 18:38</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37197073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10183454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosayebi M, Ejtehadifar M, Ghorbanzadeh B, Rastad B, Eslamirad Z (2014) The isolation and detection of Acanthamoeba keratitis in rural water sources of Arak, Iran. Med Lab J 7:1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazar M, Haghighi A, Niyyati M, Eftekhar M, Tahvildar-Biderouni F, Taghipour N, Abadi A, Mojarad EN, Athari A (2011) Genotyping of Acanthamoeba isolated from water in recreational areas of Tehran, Iran. J Water Health 9:603&#x2013;608. https://doi.org/10.2166/wh.2011.152</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wh.2011.152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21976207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazar M, Haghighi A, Taghipour N, Ortega-Rivas A, Tahvildar-Biderouni F, Mojarad EN, Eftekhar M (2012) Molecular identification of Hartmannella vermiformis and Vannella persistens from man-made recreational water environments, Tehran, Iran. Parasitol Res 111:835&#x2013;839. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00436-012-2906-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00436-012-2906-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22476603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niyyati M, Nazar M, Lasjerdi Z, Haghighi A, Nazemalhosseini E (2015) Reporting of T4 genotype of Acanthamoeba isolates in recreational water sources of Gilan Province, Northern Iran. Nov Biomed 3:20&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.22037/nbm.v3i1.7177</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22037/nbm.v3i1.7177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niyyati M, Lasjerdi Z, Zarein-Dolab S, Nazar M, Behniafar H, Mahmoudi MR, Nazemalhosseini Mojarad E (2015) Morphological and molecular survey of Naegleria spp. in water bodies used for recreational purposes in Rasht city, Northern Iran. Iran J Parasitol 10:523&#x2013;529</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26811717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4724827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niyyati M, Saberi R, Latifi A, Lasjerdi Z (2016) Distribution of Acanthamoeba genotypes isolated from recreational and therapeutic geothermal water sources in Southwestern Iran. Environ Health Insights 10:EHI-S38349. https://doi.org/10.4137/EHI.S38349</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4137/EHI.S38349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niyyati M, Mahyar M, Haghighi A, Vala MH (2015) Occurrence of potentially pathogenic bacterial-endosymbionts in Acanthamoeba spp. Iran J Parasitol 10:181</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26246815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4522293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paknejad N, Hajialilo E, Saraei M, Javadi A (2020) Isolation and identification of Acanthamoeba genotypes and Naegleria spp. from the water samples of public swimming pools in Qazvin, Iran. J Water Health 18:244&#x2013;251. https://doi.org/10.2166/wh.2019.074</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wh.2019.074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32300097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourabbasi Ardekan A, Niyyati M, Saberi R, Zanjirani Farahani L, Fatemi M (2023) Isolation and genotyping of Acanthamoeba species and Vahlkampfiidae in the harsh environmental conditions in the centre of Iran. J Water Health 21:1572&#x2013;1579. https://doi.org/10.2166/wh.2023.203</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wh.2023.203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37902210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahdar M, Niyyati M, Salehi M, Feghhi M, Makvandi M, Pourmehdi M, Farnia S (2012) Isolation and genotyping of Acanthamoeba strains from environmental sources in Ahvaz City, Khuzestan Province. Southern Iran Iran J Parasitol 7:22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23323088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasti S, Asadi MA, Iranshahi L, Hooshyar H, Gilasi HR, Zahiri A (2011) Evaluation of parasitic and fungal contamination and physicochemical parameters of indoor public swimming pools in Kashan during 2008&#x2013;9. Feyz Med Sci J 15:74&#x2013;80</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaian M, Bagheri F, Farnia S, Babai Z (2002) Isolation of pathogenic amoebae (Naegleria and Acanthamoeba) from water sources and margin soils of rivers and lakes in Kazerun. J Public Health 1:41&#x2013;48</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagheri HR, Shafiei R, Shafiei F, Sajjadi S (2010) Isolation of Acanthamoeba spp. from drinking waters in several hospitals of Iran. Iran J Parasitol 5:19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22347240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3279834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaeian M, Niati M, Farnia SH, Motevali HA (2008) Isolation of Acanthamoeba spp. from different environmental sources. Iran J Parasitol 3:44&#x2013;47</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitra S (2014) Acanthamoeba Strains Genotypes Prevalence in Water Sources in Bojnurd City: Short Communication 9:260&#x2013;266</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehi M, Niazkar H, Nasirzadeh A (2019) Isolation and genotyping of Acanthamoeba strains from water sources of Kermanshah. Iran Ann Parasitol 65:397&#x2013;402. https://doi.org/10.17420/ap6504.226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17420/ap6504.226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32191987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehi M, Spotin A, Hajizadeh F, Soleimani F, Shokri A (2022) Molecular characterization of Acanthamoeba spp. from different sources in Gonabad, Razavi Khorasan, Iran. Gene Rep 27:101573. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.genrep.2022.101573</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genrep.2022.101573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarmadian H, Hazbavi Y, Didehdar M, Ghannadzadeh MJ, Hajihossein R, Khosravi M, Ghasemikhah R (2020) Fungal and parasitic contamination of indoor public swimming pools in Arak, Iran. J Egypt Public Health Assoc 95:8. https://doi.org/10.1186/s42506-020-0036-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42506-020-0036-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32813116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7366294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shokri A, Sarvi S, Daryani A, Sharif M (2016) Isolation and genotyping of Acanthamoeba spp. as neglected parasites in north of Iran. Korean J Parasitol 54(4):447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3347/kjp.2016.54.4.447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27658596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5040085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solgi R, Niyyati M, Haghighi A, Mojarad EN (2012) Occurrence of thermotolerant Hartmannella vermiformis and Naegleria spp. in hot springs of Ardebil Province, Northwest Iran. Iran J Parasitol 7:47</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solgi R, Niyyati M, Haghighi A, Taghipour N, Tabaei SJS, Eftekhar M, Nazemalhosseini Mojarad E (2012) Thermotolerant Acanthamoeba spp. isolated from therapeutic hot springs in northwestern Iran. J Water Health 10:650&#x2013;656. https://doi.org/10.2166/wh.2012.032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wh.2012.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23165720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aghajani A, Dabirzadeh M, Maroufi Y, Hooshyar H (2016) Identification of Acanthamoeba genotypes in pools and stagnant water in ponds in Sistan region in Southeast Iran. Turkiye Parazitol Derg 40:132&#x2013;136. https://doi.org/10.5152/tpd.2016.4428</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5152/tpd.2016.4428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27905281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armand B, Motazedian MH, Asgari Q (2016) Isolation and identification of pathogenic free-living amoeba from surface and tap water of Shiraz City using morphological and molecular methods. Parasitol Res 115:63&#x2013;68. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00436-015-4721-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00436-015-4721-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26412057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attariani H, Turki H, Shoja S, Salahi-Moghaddam A, Ghanbarnejad A, Shamseddin J (2020) Investigating the frequency of free-living amoeba in water resources with emphasis on Acanthamoeba in Bandar Abbas city, Hormozgan province, Iran in 2019&#x2013;2020. BMC Res Notes 13:420. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13104-020-05267-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13104-020-05267-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32891184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7487464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behniafar H, Niyyati M, Lasjerdi Z (2015) Molecular characterization of pathogenic Acanthamoeba isolated from drinking and recreational water in East Azerbaijan, Northwest Iran. Environ Health Insights 9:EHI-S27811. https://doi.org/10.4137/EHI.S27811</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4137/EHI.S27811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabr NS, Mohamed RM, Belal USS, Abdel-Hafeez EH, Abdel-Fatah MM, Ahmed RF (2020) Isolation and identification of pathogenic Acanthamoeba species from different water sources in Minia Governorate, Egypt. Minia J Med Res 31:298&#x2013;303</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/mjmr.2022.220296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnamoorthi S, Sharma C, Mewara A, Khurana S (2022) Environmental water surveillance for free-living amoeba in North India. Indian J Med Microbiol 40:389&#x2013;393. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijmmb.2022.05.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmmb.2022.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35660264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salahuldeen A, Abd El-Aziz A, A Gad M, F Abou-El Nour M, Z Al-Herrawy A (2020) Potentially pathogenic free-living amoebae in fresh and sea waters from Alexandria, Egypt. Egypt J Aquat Biol Fish 24:307&#x2013;318</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hounkong K, Sornying P, Saechan V, Sawangjaroen N (2022) Isolation and identification of Acanthamoeba spp. from water and soil in southern Thailand. Southeast Asian J Trop Med Public Health 53:9&#x2013;20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matos de Oliveira YL, Lima ETS, Rott MB, Fernandes RPM, Jain S, de Arag&#xe3;o Batista MV, Santana Dolabella S (2023) Occurrence, molecular diversity and pathogenicity of Acanthamoeba spp. isolated from aquatic environments of Northeastern Brazil. Int J Environ Health Res 33:1686&#x2013;1696. https://doi.org/10.1080/09603123.2022.2117280</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09603123.2022.2117280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36041225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otero-Ruiz A, Gonzalez-Zu&#xf1;iga LD, Rodriguez-Anaya LZ, Lares-Jim&#xe9;nez LF, Gonzalez-Galaviz JR, Lares-Villa F (2022) Distribution and current state of molecular genetic characterization in pathogenic free-living amoebae. Pathogens 11:1199. https://doi.org/10.3390/pathogens11101199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pathogens11101199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36297255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9612019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva TCB, Cha&#xfa;que BJM, Benitez GB, Rott MB (2024) Global prevalence of potentially pathogenic free-living amoebae in sewage and sewage-related environments: systematic review with meta-analysis. Parasitol Res 123:148. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00436-024-08164-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00436-024-08164-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38433138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alanazi A, Younas S, Ejaz H, Alruwaili M, Alruwaili Y, Mazhari BBZ, Atif M, Junaid K (2025) Advancing the understanding of Naegleria fowleri: global epidemiology, phylogenetic analysis, and strategies to combat a deadly pathogen. J Infect Public Health 18:102690. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiph.2025.102690</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiph.2025.102690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39913985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diehl MLN, Paes J, Rott MB (2021) Genotype distribution of Acanthamoeba in keratitis: a systematic review. Parasitol Res 120:3051&#x2013;3063. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00436-021-07261-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00436-021-07261-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34351492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8339388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mungroo MR, Khan NA, Siddiqui R (2020) Balamuthia mandrillaris: pathogenesis, diagnosis, and treatment. Expert Opin Orphan Drugs 8:111&#x2013;119. https://doi.org/10.1080/21678707.2020.1758061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21678707.2020.1758061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aykur M, Selver OB, Dagci H, Palamar M (2024) Vermamoeba vermiformis as the etiological agent in a patient with suspected non-Acanthamoeba keratitis. Parasitol Res 123:323. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00436-024-08347-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00436-024-08347-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39254717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson OR (2018) A half-century of research on free-living amoebae (1965&#x2013;2017): review of biogeographic, ecological and physiological studies. Acta Protozool 57:1&#x2013;28. https://doi.org/10.4467/16890027AP.18.001.8395</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4467/16890027AP.18.001.8395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>