<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41609441</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1827-1928</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of sports medicine and physical fitness</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sports Med Phys Fitness</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Profiling Fireball Extreme Challenge&#x2122; athletes: an exploratory multidimensional study in an emerging co-ed sport.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.23736/S0022-4707.25.17557-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Fireball Extreme Challenge<sup>TM</sup> is a coeducational high-intensity intermittent-explosive sport that lacks normative performance data; this study aimed to create multidimensional athlete profiles and establish reference benchmarks to support talent identification and training prescription.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty-one national-level athletes (13 males and 8 females; mean age 26.2&#xb1;5.8 years) completed countermovement jump, one-repetition maximum strength assessment, bilateral handgrip testing, and the 30-15 intermittent fitness test under standardized indoor (21 &#xb0;C, 50% relative humidity) and outdoor (37 &#xb0;C, 68% relative humidity) field conditions representative of the athletes' typical training environment in coastal southern Mexico, recorded for ecological validity rather than thermal control. We calculated descriptive statistics and percentile distributions (25<sup>th</sup>, 50<sup>th</sup>, 75<sup>th</sup>), performed sex-stratified analyses adjusted for age, and conducted exploratory principal component and cluster analyses to examine interdomain associations and emergent performance groupings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Across all participants, the observed performance spectrum spanned a broad range of neuromuscular and metabolic capacities, with individual variability captured through percentile reference values (25<sup>th</sup>, 50<sup>th</sup>, 75<sup>th</sup>). The highest jump heights (up to 48 cm) and peak power outputs (&#x2248;2100 W) coexisted with moderate endurance and balanced heart rate responses, defining the multidimensional nature of Fireball Extreme Challenge&#x2122; performance. Sex-stratified distributions are presented descriptively but were not the primary analytical outcome. Principal component analysis identified two dominant performance domains-neuromuscular power and metabolic strain-explaining 59% of total variance. Hierarchical clustering revealed three mixed profiles that integrated both male and female athletes, illustrating overlapping phenotypes rather than categorical differences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study provides the first multidimensional performance profile of Fireball Extreme Challenge&#x2122; athletes, establishing normative reference percentiles and identifying key physical domains-neuromuscular power and metabolic capacity-that characterize success in this coeducational, high-intensity team sport. The derived phenotypic clusters highlight overlapping attributes between male and female athletes, reflecting the integrated dynamics of mixed-team performance. These findings offer a foundational framework for evidence-based training design, athlete monitoring, and future validation in larger international cohorts.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>R&#xed;os-Gallardo</LastName><ForeName>Pablo T</ForeName><Initials>PT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports Organization, Autonomous University of Nuevo Le&#xf3;n, San Nicol&#xe1;s de los Garza, Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gotoo-V&#xe1;zquez</LastName><ForeName>Pedro J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internacional FXC Organization Inc., North Port, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xf3;pez-Walle</LastName><ForeName>Jeannette</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports Organization, Autonomous University of Nuevo Le&#xf3;n, San Nicol&#xe1;s de los Garza, Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mendoza-Farias</LastName><ForeName>Francisco J</ForeName><Initials>FJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports Organization, Autonomous University of Nuevo Le&#xf3;n, San Nicol&#xe1;s de los Garza, Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Figueroa-Jimenez</LastName><ForeName>Martha O</ForeName><Initials>MO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Sciences and Physical Education, University of Lille, Ronchin, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Montalvo</LastName><ForeName>Samuel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiovascular Medicine, Wu Tsai Human Performance Alliance, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, CA, USA - smontal@stanford.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>J Sports Med Phys Fitness</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0376337</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-4707</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41609441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0022-4707.25.17557-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0022-4707.25.17557-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>