<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41859630</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Conjunctival Intraepithelial Neoplasia With IgG and Complement Deposition: Spurious Association or Biologically Explainable?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103709</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103709</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103709</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103709</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Conjunctival intraepithelial squamous neoplasia (CIN) is a premalignant ocular surface lesion typically diagnosed by clinical features and confirmed with routine histopathologic examination, rather than immunofluorescence studies. Direct immunofluorescence (DIF) of conjunctival tissue is most commonly used to support the&#xa0;diagnosis&#xa0;of autoimmune blistering diseases, particularly mucous membrane pemphigoid, by identifying immunoreactant deposition along the basement membrane zone (BMZ). However, such findings are not expected in CIN and may complicate interpretation. We report a case of CIN&#xa0;with unexpected positive DIF&#xa0;findings of IgG and C3 in the BMZ. A 63-year-old man with a clinically apparent conjunctival lesion underwent biopsy, which confirmed CIN on routine histopathology. A portion of the specimen was inadvertently submitted for DIF, revealing linear deposition of IgG and C3 along the conjunctival BMZ. The patient had no clinical history or examination findings suggestive of mucous membrane pemphigoid, other autoimmune blistering disease, or systemic inflammatory disorder that could account for these immunoreactant deposits. This association suggests nonspecific deposition of immunoglobulins and complement in the setting of conjunctival neoplasia, a phenomenon rarely reported in the literature. This case highlights the potential for false-positive DIF results in conjunctival lesions and emphasizes the importance of submitting a concomitant biopsy for routine light microscopy when ordering DIF in patients with suspected mucous membrane pemphigoid to ensure accurate diagnosis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Zhang et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Daniel D</ForeName><Initials>DD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, University of Central Florida College of Medicine, Orlando, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raja</LastName><ForeName>Deepak</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Remagin Ophthalmology and Oculofacial Plastic Surgery Center, Orlando, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheung</LastName><ForeName>Wang L</ForeName><Initials>WL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pathology, Orlando Health, Orlando, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Margo</LastName><ForeName>Curtis E</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Pathology, and Cell Biology, University of South Florida Morsani College of Medicine, Tampa, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complement c3</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">corneal intraepithelial neoplasia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">direct immunofluorescence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">igg</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ocular cicatricial pemphigoid</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41859630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12998399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ocular surface squamous neoplasia. Kiire CA, Srinivasan S, Karp CL. Int Ophthalmol Clin. 2010;50:35&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20611016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krachmer JH, Mannis MJ, Holland EJ. Maryland Heights: Mosby Elsevier; 2011. Cornea: Fundamentals, Diagnosis and Management.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conjunctival squamous-cell carcinoma associated with HIV infection in Kampala, Uganda. Ateenyi-Agaba C. Lancet. 1995;345:695&#x2013;696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7885126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumors of the conjunctiva and cornea. Shields CL, Shields JA. Surv Ophthalmol. 2004;49:3&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14711437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ocular surface squamous neoplasia - review of etio-pathogenesis and an update on clinico-pathological diagnosis. Mittal R, Rath S, Vemuganti GK. Saudi J Ophthalmol. 2013;27:177&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3770226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24227983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of early and late presentation of patients with ocular mucous membrane pemphigoid to two major tertiary referral hospitals in the United Kingdom. Williams GP, Radford C, Nightingale P, Dart JK, Rauz S. Eye (Lond) 2011;25:1207&#x2013;1218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3173873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21799523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ocular mucous membrane pemphigoid: current state of pathophysiology, diagnostics and treatment. Georgoudis P, Sabatino F, Szentmary N, et al. Ophthalmol Ther. 2019;8:5&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6393250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30694513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Update on conjunctival pathology. Mudhar HS. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2017;65:797&#x2013;807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5621260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28905821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Direct immunofluorescence findings and factors affecting conjunctival biopsy positivity in ocular mucous membrane pemphigoid. Jain N, Jakati S, Shanbhag SS, Basu S. Cornea. 2024;43:159&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10752260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37699562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The first international consensus on mucous membrane pemphigoid: definition, diagnostic criteria, pathogenic factors, medical treatment, and prognostic indicators. Chan LS, Ahmed AR, Anhalt GJ, et al. Arch Dermatol. 2002;138:370&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11902988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paraneoplastic conjunctival cicatrization: two different pathogenic types. Ahuero AE, Jakobiec FA, Bhat P, Ciralsky JB, Papaliodis GN. Ophthalmology. 2010;117:659&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20045572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conjunctival squamous cell neoplasia associated with ocular cicatricial pemphigoid. Choi CJ, Jakobiec FA, Zakka FR, Foster CS, Chodosh J, Freitag SK. Ophthalmic Plast Reconstr Surg. 2017;33:0&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5680111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28509683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IgA and complement immunofluorescent pattern in sebaceous gland carcinoma of the eyelid. Grossniklaus HE, Swerlick RA, Solomon AR. Am J Ophthalmol. 1990;109:353&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2178437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Analysis of the autoimmune response against BP180 in patients with Alzheimer's disease. Wang YN, Hammers CM, Mao X, Jin HZ, Yuan J, Li L. Ann Transl Med. 2021;9:107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7867912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment of diagnostic strategy for mucous membrane pemphigoid. Rashid H, Meijer JM, Diercks GF, Sieben NE, Bolling MC, Pas HH, Horvath B. JAMA Dermatol. 2021;157:780&#x2013;787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8082433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33909024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>