<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41467686</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2690-7097</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ATS scholar</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ATS Sch</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Leaning into Necessary Discomforts: Striving for Clinical Excellence While Maintaining Wellness.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>420</StartPage><EndPage>431</EndPage><MedlinePgn>420-431</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.34197/ats-scholar.2025-0033PS</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Medical education is redefining clinical excellence in the face of high learner (medical student and house staff) burnout rates, exposing a dichotomy between clinical rigor and well-being. Endurance-based traditions that once equated long hours with competence persist, yet contemporary evidence shows that effective learning environments, grounded in psychological safety and timely bidirectional feedback, improve both performance and well-being. Through the lens of early career clinician educators, we trace the origins of hardship-driven training, review data linking burnout to impaired clinical performance, and describe how competency-based medical education, anchored in entrustable professional activities and qualitative milestones, shifts success metrics from hours logged to skills demonstrated. We explore generational shifts that intensify the need for transparent discussions of expectations between learners and educators. We advocate for a culture in which mistakes are viewed as learning opportunities rather than failures. Finally, we argue that educational reforms must undergo rigorous, longitudinal evaluation before widespread implementation to ensure that they enhance competence, reduce burnout, and maximize patient safety. Clarifying which stressors cultivate mastery and which merely exhaust will allow us to produce physicians who learn more effectively, care for patients more safely, and remain in the profession longer. By cocreating psychologically safe, data-driven training models that retain "necessary discomforts" while eliminating "unnecessary harms," medical education can reconcile its dual obligations to clinical excellence and learner well-being.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patel</LastName><ForeName>Hitesh H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Erica</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of California, San Diego, La Jolla, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>ATS Sch</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101774447</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2690-7097</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002055" MajorTopicYN="Y">Burnout, Professional</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002983" MajorTopicYN="Y">Clinical Competence</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004501" MajorTopicYN="Y">Education, Medical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003162" MajorTopicYN="Y">Competency-Based Education</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013337" MajorTopicYN="Y">Students, Medical</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">burnout</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical excellence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wellness</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41467686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12712816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34197/ats-scholar.2025-0033PS</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rosenbaum L. Being well while doing well&#x2014;distinguishing necessary from unnecessary discomfort in training. N Engl J Med . 2024;390:568&#x2013;572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38231543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee E, Gonzalez LA, Zingman M. Being well while doing well. N Engl J Med . 2024;390:1635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38692305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shurin SB. Being well while doing well. N Engl J Med . 2024;390:1635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38692306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckman JA, Fang JC. Resident burnout. Ann Intern Med . 2002;137:698&#x2013;700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12379077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazer LM, Bereknyei Merrell S, Hasty BN, Stave C, Lau JN. Assessment of programs aimed to decrease or prevent mistreatment of medical trainees. JAMA Netw Open . 2018;1:e180870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6324298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30646041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng MY, Neves SL, Rainwater J, Wang JZ, Davari P, Maverakis E. et al. Exploration of mistreatment and burnout among resident physicians: a cross-specialty observational study. Med Sci Educ . 2020;30:315&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8368104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34457673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell JD. A history of medical residency. Rev Am Hist . 2016;44:126&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27116889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson C, Low G, Shiau G. Resident physician burnout: insights from a Canadian multispecialty survey. Postgrad Med J . 2020;96:331&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32123129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanafelt TD, Bradley KA, Wipf JE, Back AL. Burnout and self-reported patient care in an internal medicine residency program. Ann Intern Med . 2002;136:358&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11874308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purdy RR, Lemkau JP, Rafferty JP, Rudisill JR. Resident physicians in family practice: who&#x2019;s burned out and who knows? Fam Med . 1987;19:203&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3596113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues H, Cobucci R, Oliveira A, Cabral JV, Medeiros L, Gurgel K. et al. Burnout syndrome among medical residents: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One . 2018;13:e0206840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6231624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30418984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu DW, Dresden SM, Mark Courtney D, Salzman DH, Coates WC. An investigation of the relationship between emergency medicine trainee burnout and clinical performance in a high&#x2010;fidelity simulation environment. AEM Educ Train . 2017;1:55&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6001818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30051010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong KP, Kaliya-Perumal AK, Oh J. Orthopaedic resident burnout: a literature review on vulnerability, risk factors, consequences and management strategies. Malays Orthop J . 2019;13:15&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6702976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31467646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West CP, Dyrbye LN, Shanafelt TD. Physician burnout: contributors, consequences and solutions. J Intern Med . 2018;283:516&#x2013;529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29505159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore E, Soh M, Stuber M, Warde C. Well-being for trainees caring for homeless veterans. Clin Teach . 2019;16:367&#x2013;372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31297939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willard-Grace R, Hessler D, Rogers E, Dube K, Bodenheimer T, Grumbach K. Team structure and culture are associated with lower burnout in primary care. J Am Board Fam Med . 2014;27:229&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24610185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IsHak W, Nikravesh R, Lederer S, Perry R, Ogunyemi D, Bernstein C. Burnout in medical students: a systematic review. Clin Teach . 2013;10:242&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23834570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahart ER, Gilmer L, Tenpenny K, Krase K. Improving resident well-being: a narrative review of wellness curricula. Postgrad Med J . 2023;99:679&#x2013;686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37389582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karangizi AHK, Chanouzas D, Mahdi A, Foggensteiner L. How can we make renal medicine careers more appealing to UK trainees? Clin Kidney J . 2019;12:756&#x2013;759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6768304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31583100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martyn TLB, Savage E, MacLean SBM. An assessment of burnout in New Zealand orthopaedic resident medical officers. N Z Med J . 2022;135:11&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36455176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munroe CA, Lee P, Copland A, Wu KK, Kaltenbach T, Soetikno RM. et al. A tandem colonoscopy study of adenoma miss rates during endoscopic training: a venture into uncharted territory. Gastrointest Endosc . 2012;75:561&#x2013;567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22341103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doll KM, Milad MP, Gossett DR. Surgeon volume and outcomes in benign hysterectomy. J Minim Invasive Gynecol . 2013;20:554&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23622760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes N, Mohamed R, Raman M. Learning curve for endoscopy training: is it all about numbers? Best Pract Res Clin Gastroenterol . 2016;30:349&#x2013;356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27345644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christmas C, Kravet SJ, Durso SC, Wright SM. Clinical excellence in academia: perspectives from masterful academic clinicians. Mayo Clin Proc . 2008;83:989&#x2013;994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18775198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank JR, Snell LS, Cate OT, Holmboe ES, Carraccio C, Swing SR. et al. Competency-based medical education: theory to practice. Med Teach . 2010;32:638&#x2013;645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20662574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmboe ES, Sherbino J, Long DM, Swing SR, Frank JR. The role of assessment in competency-based medical education. Med Teach . 2010;32:676&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20662580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsh DA, Ogur B, Thibault GE, Cox M. &#x201c;Continuity&#x201d; as an organizing principle for clinical education reform. N Engl J Med . 2007;356:858&#x2013;866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17314348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannheim K. The problem of generations. Psychoanal Rev . 1970;57:378&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satoh K, Mitani Y, Ishikane M, Kamada S. A cross-sectional survey on generation Z physicians: professional value, educational expectations, and work environment preferences. Cureus . 2023;17:e83317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12126209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40452672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harari TT, Sela Y, Bareket-Bojmel L. Gen Z during the COVID-19 crisis: a comparative analysis of the differences between gen Z and gen X in resilience, values and attitudes. Curr Psychol . 2022 doi: 10.1007/s12144-022-03501-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12144-022-03501-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9362676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35967492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobrino-De Toro I, Labrador-Fern&#xe1;ndez J, De Nicol&#xe1;s VL. Generational diversity in the workplace: psychological empowerment and flexibility in Spanish companies. Front Psychol . 2019;10:1953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6736616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31551856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seemiller C, Grace M. Generation Z: educating and engaging the next generation of students. About Campus . 2017;22:21&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grelle K, Shrestha N, Ximenes M, Perrotte J, Cordaro M, Deason RG. et al. The generation gap revisited: generational differences in mental health, maladaptive coping behaviors, and pandemic-related concerns during the initial COVID-19 pandemic. J Adult Dev . 2023 doi: 10.1007/s10804-023-09442-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10804-023-09442-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9934502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36811122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shorey S, Chan V, Rajendran P, Ang E. Learning styles, preferences and needs of generation Z healthcare students: scoping review. Nurse Educ Pract . 2021;57:103247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34768214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ripp JA, Privitera MR, West CP, Leiter R, Logio L, Shapiro J. et al. Well-being in graduate medical education: a call for action. Acad Med . 2017;92:914&#x2013;917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28471780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edmondson AC. The fearless organization: creating psychological safety in the workplace for learning, innovation, and growth. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst C, Kahan D, Ruetalo M, Edwards S. A year in transition: a qualitative study examining the trajectory of first year residents&#x2019; well-being. BMC Med Educ . 2013;13:96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3712006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23842470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheepers RA, van den Goor M, Arah OA, Heineman MJ, Lombarts K. Physicians&#x2019; perceptions of psychological safety and peer performance feedback. J Contin Educ Health Prof . 2018;38:250&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30346339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolpaw J, Saddawi-Konefka D, Dwivedi P, Toy S. Faculty underestimate resident desire for constructive feedback and overestimate retaliation. J Educ Periop Med . 2019;21:E634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7039676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32123699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner AK, Scott DJ. Repaying in kind: examination of the reciprocity effect in faculty and resident evaluations. J Surg Educ . 2016;73:e91&#x2013;e94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27211878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saberzadeh-Ardestani B, Sima AR, Khosravi B, Young M, Mortaz Hejri S. The impact of prior performance information on subsequent assessment: is there evidence of retaliation in an anonymous multisource assessment system? Adv Health Sci Educ Theory Pract . 2024;29:531&#x2013;550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37488326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Housawi A, Al Amoudi A, Alsaywid B, Lytras M, H. bin &#x39c;oreba Y, Abuznadah W. et al. A progressive model for quality benchmarks of trainees&#x2019; satisfaction in medical education: towards strategic enhancement of residency training programs at Saudi Commission for Health Specialties (SCFHS) Sustainability . 2020;12:10186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramani S, K&#xf6;nings KD, Ginsburg S, van der Vleuten CPM. Twelve tips to promote a feedback culture with a growth mind-set: swinging the feedback pendulum from recipes to relationships. Med Teach . 2019;41:625&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29411668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandhane N, Ansari S, Shaikh T, Deolekar S. Positive feedback: a tool for quality education in field of medicine. Int J Res Med Sci . 2015:1868&#x2013;1873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kornegay JG, Kraut A, Manthey D, Omron R, Caretta-Weyer H, Kuhn G. et al. Feedback in medical education: a critical appraisal. AEM Educ Train . 2017;1:98&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6001508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30051017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory S, Demartini C. Satisfaction of doctors with their training: evidence from UK. BMC Health Serv Res . 2017;17:851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5747190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29284467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenton JJ, Jerant AF, Bertakis KD, Franks P. The cost of satisfaction: a national study of patient satisfaction, health care utilization, expenditures, and mortality. Arch Intern Med . 2012;172:405&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22331982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stroebe W. Why good teaching evaluations may reward bad teaching: on grade inflation and other unintended consequences of student evaluations. Perspect Psychol Sci . 2016;11:800&#x2013;816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27899725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller A, Archer J. Impact of workplace based assessment on doctors&#x2019; education and performance: a systematic review. BMJ . 2010;341:c5064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2945627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20870696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McQueen SA, Petrisor B, Bhandari M, Fahim C, McKinnon V, Sonnadara RR. Examining the barriers to meaningful assessment and feedback in medical training. Am J Surg . 2016;211:464&#x2013;475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26679827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flannery MT. Next accreditation system outcomes and special review as part of graduate medical oversight of internal medicine programs in the United States. Eur J Intern Med . 2015;26:e36&#x2013;e37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26242809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zehra T, Tariq M, Motiwala A, Ali SK, Boulet J. Challenges of providing timely feedback to residents: faculty perspectives. J Pak Med Assoc . 2015;65:1069&#x2013;1074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26440835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein J, Delany C, Fischer MD, Smallwood D, Trumble S. A growth mindset approach to preparing trainees for medical error. BMJ Qual Saf . 2017;26:771&#x2013;774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28400404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins SR, Rae VI, Smith SE, Tallentire VR. Trainee growth vs. fixed mindset in clinical learning environments: enhancing, hindering and goldilocks factors. BMC Med Educ . 2024;24:1199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11515685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39443909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tedeschi RG, Calhoun LG. Posttraumatic growth: conceptual foundations and empirical evidence. Psychol Inquiry . 2004;15:1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healy S, Tyrrell M. Stress in emergency departments: experiences of nurses and doctors. Emerg Nurse . 2011;19:31&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21877616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwack J, Schweitzer J. If every fifth physician is affected by burnout, what about the other four? Resilience strategies of experienced physicians. Acad Med . 2013;88:382&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23348093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West CP, Huschka MM, Novotny PJ, Sloan JA, Kolars JC, Habermann TM. et al. Association of perceived medical errors with resident distress and empathy: a prospective longitudinal study. JAMA . 2006;296:1071&#x2013;1078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16954486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCray LW, Cronholm PF, Bogner HR, Gallo JJ, Neill RA. Resident physician burnout: is there hope? Fam Med . 2008;40:626&#x2013;632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2903755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18830837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang A, Karunungan KL, Story JD, Shlobin NA, Woo J, Ha EL. et al. Reimagining a pass/fail clinical core clerkship: a US residency program director survey and meta-analysis. BMC Med Educ . 2023;23:788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10598945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37875929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warm E, Hirsh DA, Kinnear B, Besche HC. The shadow economy of effort: unintended consequences of pass/fail grading on medical students&#x2019; clinical education and patient care skills. Acad Med . 2025;100:419&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39773910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khorfan R, Yuce T, Love R, Yang A, Chung JW, Hoyt DB. et al. Cumulative effect of flexible duty hour policies on resident outcomes: long-term follow-up results from the FIRST trial. J Am Coll Surg . 2019;229:S237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32149826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolster L, Rourke L. The effect of restricting residents&#x2019; duty hours on patient safety, resident well-being, and resident education: an updated systematic review. J Grad Med Educ . 2015;7:349&#x2013;363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4597944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26457139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>