<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41626439</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rare Earth Element Distribution and Paleoenvironmental Implications of Harmanl&#x131; (G&#xf6;lba&#x15f;&#x131;, Ad&#x131;yaman) Coals, SE Anatolia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4699</StartPage><EndPage>4711</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4699-4711</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.5c11429</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study investigates in detail the lanthanide and yttrium (REY) geochemistry, mineralogical characterization, and paleoenvironmental conditions of the Harmanl&#x131; coal deposits (G&#xf6;lba&#x15f;&#x131;, Ad&#x131;yaman) located in the southwestern region of the East Anatolian Fault Zone (EAFZ). Analyses of coal samples using XRD, SEM-EDS, ICP-AES, and ICP-MS provide data on the mineralogical composition, distribution of major and trace elements, and REY enrichment mechanisms. The Harmanl&#x131; coal consists primarily of quartz, feldspar, and clay minerals (kaolinite, illite, and smectite), including small quantities of dolomite, gypsum, pyrite, and mica, and trace amounts of barite, Ti-oxide, Fe-oxide, phosphate minerals, and zircon. The range of REY concentrations is 20.6-78.2 ppm. Light REY (LREY) is more enriched than medium REY (MREY) and heavy REY (HREY). The strong correlation between REY and major oxides indicates that REY is concentrated in clay and Fe-Ti minerals. SEM-EDS analyses have confirmed that REY is associated with these minerals. Furthermore, several phosphate minerals have been discovered to display REY enrichments. Paleosalinity assessments suggest a depositional environment affected by freshwater, whereas redox indicators often point to reducing conditions. It is also understood that oxidizing conditions were effective in some areas during the coal deposition process. Paleoclimatic indicators show that the climate was generally humid and tropical, but arid phases also occurred in some areas. The geochemistry of detrital minerals and Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/TiO<sub>2</sub> ratios indicate predominantly felsic sources for the detrital material, with a smaller amount of mafic/ophiolitic material present. Evaluation of the tectonic influences suggests that the sedimentary system developed under the control of the EAFZ.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xdc;nal-Kartal</LastName><ForeName>Neslihan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3684-9984</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>G&#xf6;lhisar School of Applied Sciences, Burdur Mehmet Akif Ersoy University, Burdur 15400, Turkiye.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">175651</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Altunsoy</LastName><ForeName>Mehmet</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geological Engineering, Akdeniz University, Antalya 07058, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karag&#xf6;z</LastName><ForeName>Mehmet</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Turkish Petroleum Corporation, Batman Regional Directorate, Batman 72100, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41626439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12854614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c11429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Seredin V. V., Dai S. F.. Coal Deposits as Potential Alternative Sources for Lanthanides and Yttrium. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2012;94:67&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2011.11.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2011.11.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karadirek S.. Future Prospects of Rare Earth Elements in Coal and Coal Ash: Based on Mapping of Global Research (1973&#x2013;2023) J. Eng. Sci. Design. 2024;12(2):430&#x2013;442. doi: 10.21923/jesd.1494169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21923/jesd.1494169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reedy R. C., Scanlon B. R., Bagdonas D. A., Hower J. C., James D., Kyle J. R., Uhlman K.. Coal Ash Resources and Potential for Rare Earth Element Production in the United States. Int. J. Coal Sci. Technol. 2024;11(1):74. doi: 10.1007/s40789-024-00710-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40789-024-00710-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balaram V.. Potential Future Alternative Resources for Rare Earth Elements: Opportunities and Challenges. Minerals. 2023;13(3):425. doi: 10.3390/min13030425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min13030425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B., Cheng C., Li Y. X., Cheng W., Zang J. K., Lai X. P., Wang X. R.. Modes of Occurrence and Pre-Concentration of Rare Earth Elements in No. 17 Coal in Liupanshui Coalfield, China. J. Rare Earths. 2022;40(8):1323&#x2013;1332. doi: 10.1016/j.jre.2021.09.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jre.2021.09.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erik N.. A Non-Traditional Resource for Critical Minerals; Rare Earths (REY+Sc) Contents of Some Turkish Low Rank Coals. KSU J Eng Sci. 2022;25(2):155&#x2013;172. doi: 10.17780/ksujes.954292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17780/ksujes.954292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hower J. C., Granite E. J., Mayfield D. B., Lewis A. S., Finkelman R. B.. Notes on Contributions to the Science of Rare Earth Element Enrichment in Coal and Coal Combustion Byproducts. Minerals. 2016;6(2):32. doi: 10.3390/min6020032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min6020032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolker A., Scott C., Hower J. C., Vazquez J. A., Lopano C. L., Dai S. F.. Distribution of Rare Earth Elements in Coal Combustion Fly Ash, Determined by SHRIMP-RG Ion Microprobe. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2017;184:1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2017.10.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2017.10.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin R. H., Soong Y., Granite E. J.. Evaluation of Trace Elements in US Coals Using the USGS COALQUAL Database Version 3.0. Part I: Rare Earth Elements and Yttrium (REY) Int. J. Coal Geol. 2018;192:1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2018.04.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2018.04.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, S. F. ; Finkelman, R. B. ; Hower, J. C. ; French, D. ; Graham, I. T. ; Zhao, L. . Inorganic Geochemistry of Coal; Elsevier, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;eng&#xf6;r A. M. C., Y&#x131;lmaz Y.. Tethyan Evolution of Turkey, a Plate Tectonic Approach. Tectonophysics. 1981;75(3&#x2013;4):181&#x2013;241. doi: 10.1016/0040-1951(81)90275-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0040-1951(81)90275-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;eng&#xf6;r, A. M. C. ; G&#xf6;r&#xfc;r, N. ; &#x15e;aro&#x11f;lu, F. . Strike-Slip Faulting and Related Basin Formation in Zones of Tectonic Escape: Turkey as a Case Study. In Strike-Slip Deformation, Basin Formation, and Sedimentation; Biddle, K. T. , Christie-Blick, N. , Eds.; GeoscienceWorld, 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozkurt E.. Neotectonics of Turkey - a Synthesis. Geodin. Acta. 2001;14(1&#x2013;3):3&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1016/S0985-3111(01)01066-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0985-3111(01)01066-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaymakci N., Ince&#xf6;z M., Ertepinar P.. 3D-Architecture and Neogene Evolution of the Malatya Basin: Inferences for the Kinematics of the Malatya and Ovacik Fault Zones. Turk. J. Earth Sci. 2006;15(2):123&#x2013;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewey J. F., Hempton M. R., Kidd W. S. F., Saroglu F., &#x15e;eng&#xf6;r A. M. C.. Shortening of Continental Lithosphere: The Neotectonics of Eastern Anatolia&#xe5f8;a Young Collision Zone. Geol. Soc. Spec. Publ. (London) 1986;19(1):1&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1144/GSL.SP.1986.019.01.01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1144/GSL.SP.1986.019.01.01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taymaz T., Eyidogan H., Jackson J.. Source Parameters of Large Earthquakes in the East Anatolian Fault Zone (Turkey) Geophys J. Int. 1991;106(3):537&#x2013;550. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-246X.1991.tb06328.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-246X.1991.tb06328.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westaway R.. Present-day Kinematics of the Middle East and Eastern Mediterranean. J. Geophys. Res.:Solid Earth. 1994;99(B6):12071&#x2013;12090. doi: 10.1029/94JB00335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/94JB00335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barka A. A., Reilinger R.. Active Tectonics of the Eastern Mediterranean Region: Deduced from GPS, Neotectonic and Seismicity Data. Ann. Geophys. 1997;40(3):4. doi: 10.4401/ag-3892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4401/ag-3892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hempton M. R., Dewey J. F., Saroglu F.. The East Anatolian Transform Fault: Along Strike Variations in Geometry and Behavior. EOS Trans. 1981;62:393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barka A. A., Kadinsky-Cade K.. Strike-slip Fault Geometry in Turkey and Its Influence on Earthquake Activity. Tectonics. 1988;7(3):663&#x2013;684. doi: 10.1029/TC007i003p00663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/TC007i003p00663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#xf6;nl&#xfc; &#xd6;., Altunel E., Karabacak V., Aky&#xfc;z H. S.. Evolution of the Golbasi Basin and Its Implications for the Long-Term Offset on the East Anatolian Fault Zone, Turkey. J. Geodyn. 2013;65:272&#x2013;281. doi: 10.1016/j.jog.2012.04.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jog.2012.04.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perincek D., Cemen I.. The Structural Relationship between the East Anatolian and Dead-Sea Fault Zones in Southeastern Turkey. Tectonophysics. 1990;172(3&#x2013;4):331&#x2013;340. doi: 10.1016/0040-1951(90)90039-B.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0040-1951(90)90039-B</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x130;mamo&#x11f;lu M. S. &#xb8;., G&#xf6;kten E.. Neotectonic characteristics of the G&#xf6;lba&#x15f;&#x131; segment of the East Anatolian fault zone and G&#xf6;lba&#x15f;&#x131;-Saray fault wedge basin. Bull. Geol. Congress Turkey. 1996;(11):176&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westaway R. O. B., Arger J. A. N.. The G&#xf6;lbasi Basin, Southeastern Turkey: A Complex Discontinuity in a Major Strike-Slip Fault Zone. J. Geol Soc. London. 1996;153(5):729&#x2013;744. doi: 10.1144/gsjgs.153.5.0729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1144/gsjgs.153.5.0729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuncali, E. ; &#xc7;ift&#xe7;i, B. ; Yavuz, N. ; Toprak, S. ; K&#xf6;ker, A. ; Gencer, Z. ; Ay&#xe7;&#x131;k, H. ; Pahin, N. . Chemical and technological properties of Turkish tertiary coals; General Directorate of Mineral Research and Exploration; General Directorate of Mineral Research and Exploration: Ankara, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavak O., Toprak S.. Organic geochemical and petrographic properties of G&#xf6;lba&#x15f;&#x131;-Harmanl&#x131; (Ad&#x131;yaman) coals. J. Geol. Eng. 2011;35(1):43&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suata-Alpaslan, F. ; Din&#xe7;arslan, I. . The Middle Pleistocene Fauna from Southeastern Anatolia (G&#xf6;lba&#x15f;&#x131;-Ad&#x131;yaman, Turkey). In Proc. 11th Int. Multidisciplinary Scientific Geo Conf. (SGEM2001): Albena, 2011, pp 277&#x2013;282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karayigit A. I., Oskay R. G., Tuncer A., Mastalerz M., G&#xfc;m&#xfc;s B. A., Seng&#xfc;ler I., Yaradilmis H., Tunoglu C.. A Multidisciplinary Study of the Golbasi-Harmanh Coal Seam, SE Turkey. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2016;167:31&#x2013;47. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2016.09.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2016.09.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karag&#xf6;z, M. Major and trace element enrichments and their environmental impacts in the G&#xf6;lba&#x15f;&#x131; (Ad&#x131;yaman) coals. Master Thesis, Institute of Science, Antalya, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westaway R.. Kinematic Consistency between the Dead Sea Fault Zone and the Neogene and Quaternary Left-Lateral Faulting in SE Turkey. Tectonophysics. 2004;391(1&#x2013;4):203&#x2013;237. doi: 10.1016/j.tecto.2004.07.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tecto.2004.07.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM D3174&#x2013;12 . Standard Test Method for Ash in the Analysis Sample of Coal and Coke from Coal; ASTM International: West Conshohocken, PA, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer C. A., Tuncali E., Dennen K. O., Coburn T. C., Finkelman R. B.. Characterization of Turkish Coals: A Nationwide Perspective. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2004;60(2&#x2013;4):85&#x2013;115. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2004.05.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2004.05.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai S. F., Ren D. Y., Chou C. L., Finkelman R. B., Seredin V. V., Zhou Y. P.. Geochemistry of Trace Elements in Chinese Coals: A Review of Abundances, Genetic Types, Impacts on Human Health, and Industrial Utilization. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2012;94:3&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2011.02.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2011.02.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finkelman, R. B. Trace and Minor Elements in Coal. In Organic geochemistry: principles and applications; Springer, 1993; pp 593&#x2013;607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ketris M. P., Yudovich Y. E.. Estimations of Clarkes for Carbonaceous Biolithes: World Averages for Trace Element Contents in Black Shales and Coals. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2009;78(2):135&#x2013;148. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2009.01.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2009.01.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bau M., Dulski P.. Distribution of Yttrium and Rare-Earth Elements in the Penge and Kuruman Iron-Formations, Transvaal Supergroup, South Africa. Precambrian Res. 1996;79(1&#x2013;2):37&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1016/0301-9268(95)00087-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0301-9268(95)00087-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai S. F., Graham I. T., Ward C. R.. A Review of Anomalous Rare Earth Elements and Yttrium in Coal. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2016;159:82&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2016.04.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2016.04.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, S. R. ; McLennan, S. M. . The Continental Crust: Its Composition and Evolution; Blackwell: Oxford, 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X. Y., Dai S. F., Graham I. T., He X., Shan K. H., Liu X.. Determination of Eu Concentrations in Coal, Fly Ash and Sedimentary Rocks Using a Cation Exchange Resin and Inductively Coupled Plasma Mass Spectrometry (ICP-MS) Int. J. Coal Geol. 2018;191:152&#x2013;156. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2018.03.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2018.03.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burger K., Zhou Y. P., Ren Y. L.. Petrography and Geochemistry of Tonsteins from the 4th Member of the Upper Triassic Xujiahe Formation in Southern Sichuan Province, China. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2002;49(1):1&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1016/S0166-5162(01)00053-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0166-5162(01)00053-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young G. M., Nesbitt H. W.. Processes Controlling the Distribution of Ti and Al in Weathering Profiles, Siliciclastic Sediments and Sedimentary Rocks. J. Sediment. Res. 1998;68(3):448&#x2013;455. doi: 10.2110/jsr.68.448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2110/jsr.68.448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai S. F., Ji D. P., Ward C. R., French D., Hower J. C., Yan X. Y., Wei Q.. Mississippian Anthracites in Guangxi Province, Southern China: Petrological, Mineralogical, and Rare Earth Element Evidence for High-Temperature Solutions. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2018;197:84&#x2013;114. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2018.08.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2018.08.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiro B. F., Liu J. J., Dai S. F., Zeng R. S., Large D., French D.. Marine Derived 87Sr/86Sr in Coal, a New Key to Geochronology and Palaeoenvironment: Elucidation of the India-Eurasia and China-Indochina Collisions in Yunnan, China. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2019;215:103304. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2019.103304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2019.103304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai S. F., Bechtel A., Eble C. F., Flores R. M., French D., Graham I. T., Hood M. M., Hower J. C., Korasidis V. A., Moore T. A., P&#xfc;ttmann W., Wei Q., Zhao L., O&#x2019;Keefe J. M. K.. Recognition of Peat Depositional Environments in Coal: A Review. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2020;219:103383. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2019.103383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2019.103383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson A. H. F., Parlak O., Yildirim N., Dumitrica P., Tasli K.. Late Triassic Rifting and Jurassic-Cretaceous Passive Margin Development of the Southern Neotethys: Evidence from the Ad&#x131;yaman Area, SE Turkey. Int. J. Earth Sci. 2016;105(1):167&#x2013;201. doi: 10.1007/s00531-015-1176-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00531-015-1176-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seredin V. V., Finkelman R. B.. Metalliferous Coals: A Review of the Main Genetic and Geochemical Types. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2008;76(4):253&#x2013;289. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2008.07.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2008.07.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai S. F., Wang P. P., Ward C. R., Tang Y. G., Song X. L., Jiang J. H., Hower J. C., Li T., Seredin V. V., Wagner N. J., Jiang Y. F., Wang X. B., Liu J. J.. Elemental and Mineralogical Anomalies in the Coal-Hosted Ge Ore Deposit of Lincang, Yunnan, Southwestern China: Key Role of N2-CO2-Mixed Hydrothermal Solutions. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2015;152:19&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2014.11.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2014.11.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai S. F., Li T. J., Jiang Y. F., Ward C. R., Hower J. C., Sun J. H., Liu J. J., Song H. J., Wei J. P., Li Q. Q., Xie P. P., Huang Q.. Mineralogical and Geochemical Compositions of the Pennsylvanian Coal in the Hailiushu Mine, Daqingshan Coalfield, Inner Mongolia, China: Implications of Sediment-Source Region and Acid Hydrothermal Solutions. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2015;137:92&#x2013;110. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2014.11.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2014.11.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Shao L. Y., Yan Z. M., Wang X. T.. The Coal-Forming Environment during Mass Extinction in the Latest Permian: Evidence from Geochemistry of Rare Earth Elements. Front Earth Sci. (Lausanne) 2023;10:1057831. doi: 10.3389/feart.2022.1057831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feart.2022.1057831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatia M. R.. Rare Earth Elements Geochemistry of Australian Paleozoic Graywackes and Mudstones: Provenance and Tectonic Control. Sediment Geol. 1985;45(1&#x2013;2):97&#x2013;113. doi: 10.1016/0037-0738(85)90025-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0037-0738(85)90025-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones B., Manning D. A. C.. Comparison of Geochemical Indices Used for the Interpretation of Palaeoredox Conditions in Ancient Mudstones. Chem. Geol. 1994;111(1&#x2013;4):111&#x2013;129. doi: 10.1016/0009-2541(94)90085-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0009-2541(94)90085-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatch J. R., Leventhal J. S.. Relationship between Inferred Redox Potential of the Depositional Environment and Geochemistry of the Upper Pennsylvanian (Missourian) Stark Shale Member of the Dennis Limestone, Wabaunsee County, Kansas, USA. Chem. Geol. 1992;99(1&#x2013;3):65&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1016/0009-2541(92)90031-Y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0009-2541(92)90031-Y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das A., Kumar R., Patel S. S., Saha C., Das A., Mandal H., Patel R. S.. Geochemical Variations of Major, Trace, Rare Earth Elements in Some Gondwana and Eocene Coals of India with a Comparison of Their Germanium, Lithium, and Mercury Content. Geochemistry. 2023;83(2):125960. doi: 10.1016/j.chemer.2023.125960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemer.2023.125960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallberg R. O.. A Geochemical Method for Investigation of Palaeoredox Conditions in Sediments. Ambio Spec. Rep. 1976;4(4):139&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtis C. D., Coleman M. L., Love L. G.. Pore Water Evolution during Sediment Burial from Isotopic and Mineral Chemistry of Calcite, Dolomite and Siderite Concretions. Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta. 1986;50(10):2321&#x2013;2334. doi: 10.1016/0016-7037(86)90085-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0016-7037(86)90085-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasconcelos C., Mckenzie J. A., Bernasconi S., Grujic D., Tiens A. J.. Microbial Mediation as a Possible Mechanism for Natural Dolomite Formation at Low Temperatures. Nature. 1995;377(6546):220&#x2013;222. doi: 10.1038/377220a0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/377220a0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J. J., Spiro B. F., Dai S. F., French D., Graham I. T., Wang X. B., Zhao L., Zhao J. T., Zeng R. S.. Strontium Isotopes in High- and Low-Ge Coals from the Shengli Coalfield, Inner Mongolia, Northern China: New Indicators for Ge Source. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2021;233:103642. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2020.103642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2020.103642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yandoka B. M. S., Abdullah W. H., Abubakar M. B., Hakimi M. H., Adegoke A. K.. Geochemical Characterisation of Early Cretaceous Lacustrine Sediments of Bima Formation, Yola Sub-Basin, Northern Benue Trough, NE Nigeria: Organic Matter Input, Preservation, Paleoenvironment and Palaeoclimatic Conditions. Mar Pet Geol. 2015;61:82&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2014.12.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2014.12.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nesbitt H. W., Young G. M.. Early Proterozoic Climates and Plate Motions Inferred from Major Element Chemistry of Lutites. Nature. 1982;299(5885):715&#x2013;717. doi: 10.1038/299715a0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/299715a0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., An Z. S., Head J.. Variation of Rb Sr Ratios in the Loess-Paleosol Sequences of Central China during the Last 130,000 Years and Their Implications for Monsoon Paleoclimatology. Quat. Res. 1999;51(3):215&#x2013;219. doi: 10.1006/qres.1999.2038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/qres.1999.2038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai S. F., Seredin V. V., Ward C. R., Hower J. C., Xing Y. W., Zhang W. G., Song W. J., Wang P. P.. Enrichment of U-Se-Mo-Re-V in Coals Preserved within Marine Carbonate Successions: Geochemical and Mineralogical Data from the Late Permian Guiding Coalfield, Guizhou, China. Miner Depos. 2015;50(2):159&#x2013;186. doi: 10.1007/s00126-014-0528-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00126-014-0528-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai S. F., Zhang W. G., Ward C. R., Seredin V. V., Hower J. C., Li X., Song W. J., Wang X. B., Kang H., Zheng L. C., Wang P. P., Zhou D.. Mineralogical and Geochemical Anomalies of Late Permian Coals from the Fusui Coalfield, Guangxi Province, Southern China: Influences of Terrigenous Materials and Hydrothermal Fluids. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2013;105:60&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2012.12.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2012.12.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi K., Fujisawa H., Holland H. D., Ohmoto H.. Geochemistry of Similar to 1.9 Ga Sedimentary Rocks from Northeastern Labrador, Canada. Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta. 1997;61(19):4115&#x2013;4137. doi: 10.1016/S0016-7037(97)00214-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0016-7037(97)00214-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11540490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Condie K. C.. Chemical Composition and Evolution of the Upper Continental Crust: Contrasting Results from Surface Samples and Shales. Chem. Geol. 1993;104(1&#x2013;4):1&#x2013;37. doi: 10.1016/0009-2541(93)90140-E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0009-2541(93)90140-E</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLennan, S. M. ; Hemming, S. ; McDaniel, D. K. ; Hanson, G. N. . Geochemical Approaches to Sedimentation, Provenance, and Tectonics. In Processes controlling the composition of clastic sediments; Johnsonn, M. J. , Basu, A. , Eds.; Geological Society of America, 1993; pp 21&#x2013;40. 10.1130/SPE284-p21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1130/SPE284-p21</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>