<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41608479</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2046-2069</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>RSC advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>RSC Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A spatially defined Sr/Zn gradient coating with dual osteogenic and anti-corrosion functions on Ti6Al4V <i>via</i> softened spark MAO.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5666</StartPage><EndPage>5679</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5666-5679</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/d5ra08533k</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In order to overcome the problems of highly interconnected pores and insufficient long-term corrosion resistance in micro-arc oxidation (MAO) coatings this study integrated softened spark MAO (S-MAO) with a Sr<sup>2+</sup>/Zn<sup>2+</sup> complexation regulation strategy to fabricate composite MAO coatings on Ti6Al4V implant surfaces. The S-MAO treatment transformed coating architecture from a bilayer into a three-layer gradient structure (barrier layer/softened-spark layer/porous layer). This significantly diminished the interconnectedness of interior pores. Electrochemical tests showed that the way S-MAO coatings corrode changed from diffusion control to the interfacial charge transfer process being the most important. This indicates that the coatings' electrochemically protective qualities are more stable. The Z<sub>1</sub>S<sub>3</sub>MAO coating, with a Sr/Zn ratio of 3&#x2009;:&#x2009;1, demonstrated elevated interfacial charge transfer resistance (443.6 &#x3a9; cm<sup>2</sup>) and enhanced impedance responsiveness. The examination of the elemental distribution showed that Sr was spread out evenly throughout the coating thickness. However, Zn had a localized enrichment zone at the interface between the softened-spark layer and the porous outer layer. The spatial distribution is determined by the varying stability of ion complexation. The Z<sub>1</sub>S<sub>3</sub>MAO coating exhibited superior performance regarding wettability and cytocompatibility associated with osteogenesis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>This journal is &#xa9; The Royal Society of Chemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hao</LastName><ForeName>Yiting</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanical and Energy Engineering, Shaoyang University Shaoyang 422000 China 18873994427@163.com 919513838@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ning</LastName><ForeName>Liwei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-1918-9328</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanical and Energy Engineering, Shaoyang University Shaoyang 422000 China 18873994427@163.com 919513838@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanical and Energy Engineering, Shaoyang University Shaoyang 422000 China 18873994427@163.com 919513838@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoming</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanical and Energy Engineering, Shaoyang University Shaoyang 422000 China 18873994427@163.com 919513838@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Zixiong</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanical and Energy Engineering, Shaoyang University Shaoyang 422000 China 18873994427@163.com 919513838@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>RSC Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101581657</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2046-2069</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors declared no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41608479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12835843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d5ra08533k</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">d5ra08533k</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chou Y. Weng S. Cheng F. et al. , Denture use mitigates the cognitive impact of tooth loss in older adults. J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 2025;80(1):glae248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39626020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X. Kang L. Bi J. Epidemiology of oral health in older adults aged 65 or over: prevalence, risk factors and prevention. Aging:Clin. Exp. Res. 2025;37(1):193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12185596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40549221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padilha D. M. P. Hilgert J. B. Hugo F. N. et al. , Number of teeth and mortality risk in the Baltimore Longitudinal Study of Aging. J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 2008;63(7):739&#x2013;744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4984838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18693229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroll P. Hou L. Radaideh H. Sharifi N. et al. , Oral health-related outcomes in edentulous patients treated with mandibular implant-retained dentures versus complete dentures: systematic review with meta-analyses. J. Oral Implantol. 2018;44(4):313&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29457932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X. Zhai J.-J. Liao J. et al. , Masticatory efficiency and oral health-related quality of life with implant-retained mandibular overdentures. Saudi Med. J. 2014;35(10):1195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4362122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25316463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsiao V. K. Shih M.-H. Wu H.-C. et al. , Comparative study of surface modification techniques for enhancing biocompatibility of Ti-6Al-4V alloy in dental implants. Appl. Sci. 2024;14(23):10904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albrektsson T. Tengvall P. Amengual L. et al. , Osteoimmune regulation underlies oral implant osseointegration and its perturbation. Front. Immunol. 2023;13:1056914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9902598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36761175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghodrati H. Goodarzi A. Golrokhian M. et al. , A narrative review of recent developments in osseointegration and anti-corrosion of titanium dental implants with nano surface. Bone Rep. 2025:101846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12123356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40454244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y. Wan K. Lu J. et al. , Research Progress on Surface Modification of Titanium Implants. Coatings. 2025;15(2):229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang H. Xu J. Guo B. et al. , Review on the Fabrication of Surface Functional Structures for Enhancing Bioactivity of Titanium and Titanium Alloy Implants. Chin. J. Mech. Eng. 2024;37(1):87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z.-Y. Huang T.-Y. Zhai D.-J. et al. , Study on Zn-doped antibacterial bioactive coatings on Ti6Al4V titanium alloy surfaces by micro-arc oxidation. Surf. Coat. Technol. 2023;467:129724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen Z. Shi X. Li X. et al. , Mesoporous TiO2 coatings regulate ZnO nanoparticle loading and Zn2+ release on titanium dental implants for sustained osteogenic and antibacterial activity. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2023;15(12):15235&#x2013;15249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36926829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G. Cao H. Zhang W. et al. , Enhanced osseointegration of hierarchical micro/nanotopographic titanium fabricated by microarc oxidation and electrochemical treatment. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2016;8(6):3840&#x2013;3852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26789077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gnedenkov S. S. Filonina V. et al. , Hydroxyapatite-containing PEO-coating design for biodegradable Mg-0.8 Ca alloy: Formation and corrosion behaviour. J. Magnesium Alloys. 2023;11(12):4468&#x2013;4484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W. Yang K. Yang J. et al. , Effect of laser surface melting pretreatment on wear and corrosion properties of micro-arc oxidation coatings on magnesium alloys. Ceram. Int. 2025;51(3):3037&#x2013;3052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Z. Wang T. Yu X. et al. , Functionalization treatment of micro-arc oxidation coatings on magnesium alloys: A review. J. Alloys Compd. 2021;879:160453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong Q. Liu Y. Luo Y. et al. , Enhancing corrosion resistance, durability, and hydrophobic properties of MAO-coated magnesium alloy through synergistic sealing at ambient conditions. Ceram. Int. 2025:24000&#x2013;24013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D.-y. Lin H.-m. Wang X.-m. et al. , Nucleation and growth process of a softened-spark layer during microarc oxidation on a selective laser melted Ti alloy. RSC Adv. 2024;14(36):25975&#x2013;25985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11331398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39161444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S. Huang J. Liu B. et al. , Distinct effects of spark softening on micro-arc oxidized coating growth, wear resistance and corrosion resistance: A comparative study between Ti-Nb-Zr medium entropy alloy and Ti-6Al-4V as substrates. Surf. Interfaces. 2025;64:106416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D. Zhou Z. Li M. et al. , Zn/Mg/Cu co-doped Ti-6Al-4V alloy simultaneously modulates immune responses and stimulates osteogenesis. Colloids Surf., B. 2025:115281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41297220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X.-m. Zhang F.-q. Effects of soft sparking on micro/nano structure and bioactive components of microarc oxidation coatings on selective laser melted Ti6Al4V alloy. Surf. Coat. Technol. 2023;462:129478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W. Wei L. Harnessing strontium in regenerative dentistry: progress and perspectives. Front. Bioeng. Biotechnol. 2025;13:1724610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12678298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41356110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng T.-X. Yang N.-Y. Deng J.-P. et al. , Multifunctional Sr/Zn-doped TiO2 micro/nanoporous coating enhances osseointegration by modulating signaling crosstalk of bone-related cells. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;511:161734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y. Chen C. Liang T. Wang Y. In vitro long-term antibacterial performance and mechanism of Zn-doped micro-arc oxidation coatings. Colloids Surf., B. 2024;233:113634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37956591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J. Fang K. Xu K. et al. , Effect of zinc or copper doping on corrosion resistance and anti-oxidative stress of strontium-based micro-arc oxidation coatings on titanium. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2023;626:157229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L. Ma F. Liu P. et al. , Preparation and antibacterial properties of ZnSr-doped micro-arc oxidation coatings on titanium. Surf. Coat. Technol. 2023;462:129469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliramezani R. Raeissi K. Santamaria M. et al. , Effects of pulse current mode on plasma electrolytic oxidation of 7075 Al in KMnO4 containing solution. J. Electrochem. Soc. 2017;164(12):C690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mojsilovi&#x107; K. Serdechnova M. Blawert C. et al. , Tailoring plasma electrolytic oxidation through metallic cation addition: Insights from bipolar and unipolar electrical regimes. Appl. Surf. Sci. Adv. 2025;29:100845.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X.-m. Zhang F.-q. Influence of anions in phosphate and tetraborate electrolytes on growth kinetics of microarc oxidation coatings on Ti6Al4V alloy. Trans. Nonferrous Met. Soc. China. 2022;32(7):2243&#x2013;2252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W. Yang Y. Liu C. et al. , Study of Coating Growth Direction of 6061 Aluminum Alloy in Soft Spark Discharge of Plasma Electrolytic Oxidation. Materials. 2024;17(12):2947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11205352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38930316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai D. Qiu T. Shen J. et al. , Mechanism of tetraborate and silicate ions on the growth kinetics of microarc oxidation coating on a Ti6Al4V alloy. RSC Adv. 2023;13(8):5382&#x2013;5392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9923455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36793295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikonopisov S. Theory of electrical breakdown during formation of barrier anodic films. Electrochim. Acta. 1977;22(10):1077&#x2013;1082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alteri G. B. Bonomo M. Decker F. et al. , Contact Glow Discharge Electrolysis: Effect of Electrolyte Conductivity on Discharge Voltage. Catalysts. 2020;10(10):1104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling K. Mo Q. Lv X. et al. , Growth characteristics and corrosion resistance of micro-arc oxidation coating on Al&#x2013;Mg composite plate. Vacuum. 2022;195:110640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Q. Qiu T. Ni P. et al. , Soft sparking discharge mechanism of micro-arc oxidation occurring on Titanium alloys in different electrolytes. Coatings. 2022;12(8):1191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai D. Tang Q. Ni P. et al. , Growth pattern of soft-spark micro-arc oxide coating on titanium alloy in silicon anion electrolyte. Surf. Coat. Technol. 2023;473:130030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X. Shi Q. Huang Y. et al. , Microstructure and properties of TC4 titanium alloy micro-arc oxide composite coating based on laser surface texturing. Sci. Rep. 2025;15(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11926383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40113794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderegg G., Critical Survey of Stability Constants of EDTA Complexes: Critical Evaluation of Equilibrium Constants in Solution: Stability Constants of Metal Complexes, Elsevier, 2013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa K. Takahashi Y. Sato H. Effect of the formation of EDTA complexes on the diffusion of metal ions in water. Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta. 2007;71(18):4416&#x2013;4424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begum Z. A. Rahman I. M. Hasegawa H. Complexation behavior of SrII and geochemically-related elements (MgII, CaII, BaII, and YIII) with biodegradable aminopolycarboxylate chelators (GLDA and HIDS) J. Mol. Liq. 2017;242:1123&#x2013;1130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinnat B. Rahman Ismail M. Tate Yousuke E. Y. et al. , Formation and stability of binary complexes of divalent ecotoxic ions (Ni, Cu, Zn, Cd, Pb) with biodegradable aminopolycarboxylate chelants (dl-2-(2-carboxymethyl) nitrilotriacetic acid. J. Solution Chem. 2012;41(10):1713&#x2013;1728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge Y. Cheng J. Xue L. et al. , Pore defect and corrosion behavior of HVAF-sprayed Co21Fe14Ni8Cr16Mo16C15B10 high entropy metallic glass coatings. Corros. Sci. 2025;242:112564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S. Peng X. Yang Y. et al. , Insight into microstructure evolution and corrosion mechanisms of K2ZrF6/Al2O3-doped hot-dip aluminum/micro-arc oxidation coatings. Coatings. 2023;13(9):1543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J. Lou Y. Zhang C. et al. , Improved corrosion resistance and antibacterial properties of composite arch-wires by N-doped TiO 2 coating. RSC Adv. 2017;7(69):43938&#x2013;43949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh J. K. Mandal S. Adnin R. J. et al. , Role of coating processes on the corrosion kinetics and mechanism of zinc in artificial seawater. Materials. 2021;14(23):7464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8659072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34885619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>