<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41227847</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>21</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Study on Alkali-Activated Slag Mortar Based on Co-Modified Recycled Fine Aggregate with Nano-SiO<sub>2</sub> and Sodium Silicate Integrating Waste Liquid Recycling.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4889</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma18214889</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The widespread use of recycled fine aggregate (RFA) is hindered by its porous and weak adhered mortar. In this study, a nano-SiO<sub>2</sub>-sodium silicate mixed solution (NMS) was used to soak and strengthen the adhered mortar. Alkali-activated slag was adopted as the cementitious material, and the resulting treated waste liquid (RNMS) was recycled as a sodium silicate source for the alkali activator. The effects of modified RFA (MRFA) incorporation and RNMS use on the performance, economic, and environmental benefits of alkali-activated slag recycled fine aggregate mortar (AASRM) were evaluated. Compared with the control group, mortars using only MRFA showed significantly improved performance, with a 28-day compressive strength increase of 57.6% (reaching 38.3 MPa) and enhanced workability. The capillary water absorption and 90-day drying shrinkage rates decreased by 49.5% and 40.2%, respectively. Microstructural analysis revealed that NMS treatment promoted the formation of additional C-(N)-A-S-H gel, thereby densifying the surface of the RFA and strengthening the interfacial transition zone (ITZ). More importantly, using RNMS as the alkali activator source maintained the excellent performance of the AASRM mortar, with the compressive strength reaching 95.6% of that prepared with a fresh alkali activator, while effectively reducing material costs and embodied carbon. This study not only successfully applies MRFA in alkali-activated mortar systems but also provides an effective approach for the in situ recycling of treated waste liquid.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Qiushi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-1195-8201</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Anhui University of Science and Technology, Huainan 232001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Changbai</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Anhui University of Science and Technology, Huainan 232001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Safe Mining of Deep Coal and Environmental Protection, Anhui University of Science and Technology, Huainan 232001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Jimin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Anhui University of Science and Technology, Huainan 232001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Safe Mining of Deep Coal and Environmental Protection, Anhui University of Science and Technology, Huainan 232001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Qinghua</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Anhui University of Science and Technology, Huainan 232001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2019110106</GrantID><Agency>Shanxi Province Key Science and Technology Special Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">alkali-activated slag mortar</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">co-modification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recycled fine aggregate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sustainability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">waste liquid recycling</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41227847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12608491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18214889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma18214889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lee S., Chang H., Lee J. Construction and demolition waste management and its impacts on the environment and human health: Moving forward sustainability enhancement. Sustain. Cities Soc. 2024;102:105855. doi: 10.1016/j.scs.2024.105855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2024.105855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fecko T., Kormo&#x161;ov&#xe1; L., Ramos A.P., Halvonik J. Punching shear behaviour of full-scale slab-column connections cast from concrete with coarse recycled aggregate. Eng. Struct. 2025;345:121460. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2025.121460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2025.121460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youssef O.F. Sustainable concrete with recycled brick and ceramic aggregates: A statistical validation and performance evaluation. Next Mater. 2025;9:101319. doi: 10.1016/j.nxmate.2025.101319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nxmate.2025.101319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T., Chen M., Wang Y., Zhang M. Roles of carbonated recycled fines and aggregates in hydration, microstructure and mechanical properties of concrete: A critical review. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2023;138:104994. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2023.104994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2023.104994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu R., Zhou Y., Xing F. Strategies to Improve the Life Cycle Net CO2 Benefit of Recycled Aggregate Concrete. Engineering. 2025 doi: 10.1016/j.eng.2024.11.040. in press .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eng.2024.11.040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X., Hu H., Luo Y., Yao W., Wei Y., She A. A carbon footprint assessment for usage of recycled aggregate and supplementary cementitious materials for sustainable concrete: A life-cycle perspective in China. J. Clean. Prod. 2025;490:144772. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.144772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.144772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recycled fine aggregate for concrete and mortar. General Administration of Quality Supervision, Inspection and Quarantine of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China. Standardization Administration of China; Beijing, China: 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recycled coarse aggregate for concrete. General Administration of Quality Supervision, Inspection and Quarantine of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China. Standardization Administration of China; Beijing, China: 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Feng C., Wang Y., Du M., Luo W., Zhao X., Zhang W., Zhu J. Study on the method of reinforcing recycled fine aggregate by wrapping slag and cement powder. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;483:141771. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.141771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.141771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vahidi A., Mostaani A., Gebremariam A.T., Di Maio F., Rem P. Feasibility of utilizing recycled coarse aggregates in commercial concrete production. J. Clean. Prod. 2024;474:143578. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.143578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.143578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panghal H., Kumar A. Enhancing concrete performance: Surface modification of recycled coarse aggregates for sustainable construction. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;411:134432. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Q., Zhuang Y., Nasr A., Liu H., Duan Z. Assessing the effect of particle characteristics on the rheological properties of mortar with recycled fine aggregate. J. Build. Eng. 2025;107:112673. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2025.112673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2025.112673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J., Wang Y., Zhang L., Zeng L., Wang X., Dang J. Influence of geometric shape, pore structure and surface modification of recycled fine aggregate on the rheology behaviour and strength development of mortar. J. Build. Eng. 2024;91:109604. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revilla-Cuesta V., Skaf M., Faleschini F., Manso J.M., Ortega-L&#xf3;pez V. Self-compacting concrete manufactured with recycled concrete aggregate: An overview. J. Clean. Prod. 2020;262:121362. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.121362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.121362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Tian C., Li M., Zhan Q., Wang X., Dong W. Study on the Performance Enhancement of Recycled Fine Aggregate Through Carbonation with Calcium Source Supplied by Industrial Waste Residue. Materials. 2025;18:1589. doi: 10.3390/ma18071589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18071589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11990114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40271782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Y., Liu J., Shi C. Autogenous shrinkage and drying shrinkage of recycled aggregate concrete: A review. J. Clean. Prod. 2021;295:126435. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.126435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.126435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Li M., Wang C., Li Y., Fan Y., Liu X., Ding Y., Shen W. Multi-parameter analysis of nano-SiO2 modified recycled aggregate concrete: Fatigue damage and microscopic mechanisms. Structures. 2025;79:109414. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2025.109414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2025.109414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaeicherati F., Memarzadeh A., Esmailpour A., Fallahnejad H., Ghorbanzadeh A., Nematzadeh M. Durability evaluation and environmental implications of blended cement with colloidal nano-silica for use in recycled fine aggregate concrete: Experimental and theoretical study. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;402:132926. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaei F., Memarzadeh A., Davoodi M.-R., Dashab M.-A., Nematzadeh M. Mechanical features and durability of concrete incorporating recycled coarse aggregate and nano-silica: Experimental study, prediction, and optimization. J. Build. Eng. 2023;73:106715. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M., Cheng C., Chiang K., Wang X., Zhu Y., Zhao Z., Luo H. Influence of Nano-Silicon Dioxide in the Enhancement of Surface Structure of Public Filler and Properties of Recycled Mortar. Buildings. 2024;14:2093. doi: 10.3390/buildings14072093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings14072093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Z., Chen G., Tu Y., Xiao X., Cheng S., Xu X. Study on mechanical properties and microstructure of recycled fine aggregate concrete modified by Nano-SiO2. J. Mater. Cycles Waste Manag. 2023;25:2135&#x2013;2145. doi: 10.1007/s10163-023-01683-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10163-023-01683-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y., Zhuang J., Lin W., Xu W., Hu R. Creep and Shrinkage Properties of Nano-SiO2-Modified Recycled Aggregate Concrete. Materials. 2024;17:1904. doi: 10.3390/ma17081904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17081904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11052056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38673261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahbazpanahi S., Tajara M.K., Faraj R.H., Mosavi A. Studying the C&#x2013;H Crystals and Mechanical Properties of Sustainable Concrete Containing Recycled Coarse Aggregate with Used Nano-Silica. Crystals. 2021;11:122. doi: 10.3390/cryst11020122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cryst11020122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Taengua E., Sonebi M., Hossain K.M.A., Lachemi M., Khatib J. Effects of the addition of nanosilica on the rheology, hydration and development of the compressive strength of cement mortars. Compos. Part B Eng. 2015;81:120&#x2013;129. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2015.07.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2015.07.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y., Fan L., Xing F., Lin W., Hu R., Guo M., Zhu Z. Effect of nano-SiO2 modification on the seismic performance of recycled aggregate concrete shear walls. Eng. Struct. 2024;307:117945. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2024.117945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2024.117945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y., Xu W., Lin W., Zhuang J., Xing F., Hu R. Cyclic Behavior and Stress&#x2013;Strain Model of Nano-SiO2-Modified Recycled Aggregate Concrete. Materials. 2024;17:1180. doi: 10.3390/ma17051180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17051180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10934829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38473651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan P., Xu J., Wang J., Zuo J., He Z. A review of recycled aggregate concrete modified by nanosilica and graphene oxide: Materials, performances and mechanism. J. Clean. Prod. 2022;375:134116. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.134116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.134116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim K.M., Heo Y.S., Kang S.P., Lee J. Effect of sodium silicate- and ethyl silicate-based nano-silica on pore structure of cement composites. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2014;49:84&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2013.12.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2013.12.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L., Xuan D., Sojobi A.O., Liu S., Chu S.H., Poon C.S. Development of nano-silica treatment methods to enhance recycled aggregate concrete. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2021;118:103963. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.103963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.103963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W.Z., Jiao C.J., Zhang X.C., Yang Y., Chen X.F. Study on the microstructure of recycled aggregate concrete strengthened by the nano-SiO2 soaking method. Structures. 2023;58:105388. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2023.105388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2023.105388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng W., Zhao Y., Zheng H., Poon C.S. Improvement in corrosion resistance of recycled aggregate concrete by nano silica suspension modification on recycled aggregates. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2020;106:103476. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.103476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.103476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar R.R. Evaluation of mechanical and carbonation properties of self-compacting treated recycled coarse aggregates with two-stage mixing approaches. Clean. Waste Syst. 2022;3:100060. doi: 10.1016/j.clwas.2022.100060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clwas.2022.100060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Liu L., Zuo J., Zhao P., Xie X., Li S., Lyu K., Wu C., Shah S.P. Evaluation of Various Modification Methods for Enhancing the Performance of Recycled Concrete Aggregate. J. Renew. Mater. 2022;10:2685&#x2013;2698. doi: 10.32604/jrm.2022.019527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32604/jrm.2022.019527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Xie X., Liu R., Lyu K., Zuo J., Li S., Liu L., Shah S.P. Research on the durability of nano-SiO2 and sodium silicate co-modified recycled coarse aggregate (RCA) concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;378:131185. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raza M.H., Khan M., Zhong R.Y. Investigating the impact of alkaline activator on the sustainability potential of geopolymer and alternative hybrid materials. Mater. Today Sustain. 2024;26:100742. doi: 10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tejas S., Pasla D. Approach to design sustainable alkali-activated slag recycled aggregate concrete: Mechanical and micro-structural characterization. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2024;21:e03886. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2024.e03886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2024.e03886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi C., Jim&#xe9;nez A.F., Palomo A. New cements for the 21st century: The pursuit of an alternative to Portland cement. Cem. Concr. Res. 2011;41:750&#x2013;763. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2011.03.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2011.03.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Provis J.L. Alkali-activated materials. Cem. Concr. Res. 2018;114:40&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2017.02.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2017.02.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moranville-Regourd M., Kamali-Bernard S. 10-Cements Made From Blastfurnace Slag. In: Hewlett P.C., Liska M., editors. Lea&#x2019;s Chemistry of Cement and Concrete. 5th ed. Butterworth-Heinemann; Oxford, UK: 2019. pp. 469&#x2013;507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangat P., Lambert P. 18-Sustainability of alkali-activated cementitious materials and geopolymers. In: Khatib J.M., editor. Sustainability of Construction Materials. 2nd ed. Woodhead Publishing; London, UK: 2016. pp. 459&#x2013;476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Li Z., Ye G. Mitigating the efflorescence of alkali-activated slag mortars by aluminosilicate-based lightweight fine aggregate. Cem. Concr. Res. 2025;195:107917. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2025.107917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2025.107917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marvila M.T., de Azevedo A.R.G., de Matos P.R., Monteiro S.N., Vieira C.M.F. Rheological and the Fresh State Properties of Alkali-Activated Mortars by Blast Furnace Slag. Materials. 2021;14:2069. doi: 10.3390/ma14082069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14082069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8073173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33924013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldas P.H.C.H., de Azevedo A.R.G., Marvila M.T. Silica fume activated by NaOH and KOH in cement mortars: Rheological and mechanical study. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;400:132623. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye H., Radli&#x144;ska A. Shrinkage mitigation strategies in alkali-activated slag. Cem. Concr. Res. 2017;101:131&#x2013;143. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2017.08.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2017.08.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W., Li B., Wang J., Thom N. Effects of alkali dosage and silicate modulus on autogenous shrinkage of alkali-activated slag cement paste. Cem. Concr. Res. 2021;141:106322. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins F., Sanjayan J.G. Effect of pore size distribution on drying shrinking of alkali-activated slag concrete. Cem. Concr. Res. 2000;30:1401&#x2013;1406. doi: 10.1016/S0008-8846(00)00327-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(00)00327-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai C.J. Investigate the mechanical behavior of alkali-activated slag mortar using sustainable waste sodium silicate-bonded sand as an alkali activator and carbon free aggregate. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;429:136448. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fo&#x159;t J., Mildner M., Keppert M., Abed M., &#x10c;ern&#xfd; R. Potential of industrial waste as alternative alkaline activator for development of eco-efficient mortars. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2023;18:e01716. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Specification for Mix Proportion Design of Masonry Mortar. Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Develop-ment of China; Beijing, China: 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Z., Shi C., Wan S., Zhang Z. Effects of alkali dosage and silicate modulus on alkali-silica reaction in alkali-activated slag mortars. Cem. Concr. Res. 2018;111:104&#x2013;115. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2018.06.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2018.06.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xi X., Zheng Y., Zhuo J., Zhang P., Golewski G.L., Du C. Influence of water glass modulus and alkali content on the properties of alkali-activated thermally activated recycled cement. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;452:138867. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burciaga-D&#xed;az O., Dur&#xf3;n-Sifuentes M., D&#xed;az-Guill&#xe9;n J.A., Escalante-Garc&#xed;a J.I. Effect of waste glass incorporation on the properties of geopolymers formulated with low purity metakaolin. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2020;107:103492. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.103492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.103492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M., Hu R., Zhang Y., Wang C., Ma Z. Effect of ground concrete waste as green binder on the micro-macro properties of eco-friendly metakaolin-based geopolymer mortar. J. Build. Eng. 2023;68:106191. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Test Method for Fluidity of Cement Mortar. General Administration of Quality Supervision, Inspection and Quarantine of PR China; Beijing, China: 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Measurement of Rate of Absorption of Water by Hydraulic Cement Concretes. ASTM International; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard for Test Method of Performance on Building Mortar. Ministry of Construction of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B., Zhang W., Fang X., Kong X., Liu F., Li G. Coupling effects of sewage sludge and recycled fine aggregate on the properties of geopolymer recycled mortars. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2024;20:e03067. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2024.e03067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2024.e03067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar G.S. Influence of fluidity on mechanical and permeation performances of recycled aggregate mortar. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;213:404&#x2013;412. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.04.093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.04.093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu D., Qu F., Su Y., Cui K. Nano-engineered the interfacial transition zone between recycled fine aggregates and paste with graphene oxide for sustainable cement composites. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2024;154:105762. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luan C., Liu J., Zhao S., Li Y., Yang Y. Enhancing the properties of UHPC with recycled concrete powder and iron ore tailings sand, and evaluating the environmental impact. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;452:138769. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firdous R., Stephan D. Effect of silica modulus on the geopolymerization activity of natural pozzolans. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;219:31&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.05.161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.05.161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao G., Xu H., Bao J., Wang Y., Cui Y., Song Q., Sun J. Durability-related properties of alkali-activated recycled aggregate concrete: Effect of alkali equivalent, recycled coarse aggregate replacement rate and slag content. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;486:142018. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.142018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.142018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi J., Fu S., Huang J., Chen Y. Synergistic modification of recycled aggregate using carbonation and hydrophobic Nano-Silica: Effect on interfacial performance of recycled aggregate concrete. J. Build. Eng. 2025;107:112740. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2025.112740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2025.112740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W., Wang B. Study on the influence of nano-silica substitution of reactive Si on the properties and hydration process of alkali-activated cementitious materials paste. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;443:137759. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyu K., Sun B., Liu X., Xie X., Liu R. Evaluation of the ITZ modification efficiency via aggregate surface coating with nano SiO2 (NS) and its influence on properties. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2022;17:e01488. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T., Gong L., Jin C., Qin J., Dang D., Cui X. Study on the pore characteristics and ITZ properties of recycled aggregate concrete by desert sand subjecting to salt freeze-thaw environments. J. Build. Eng. 2025;108:112918. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2025.112918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2025.112918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyu K., Garboczi E.J., She W., Miao C. The effect of rough vs. smooth aggregate surfaces on the characteristics of the interfacial transition zone. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2019;99:49&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.03.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie J., Li J., Zhang B., Chen W., Zhong H., Yang J., Yu T., Feng Y. Effects of pretreated recycled fine aggregates on the mechanical properties and microstructure of alkali-activated mortar. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2024;20:e02819. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Th&#xe9;R&#xe9;n&#xe9; F., Keita E., Na&#xeb;l-Redolfi J., Boustingorry P., Bonafous L., Roussel N. Water absorption of recycled aggregates: Measurements, influence of temperature and practical consequences. Cem. Concr. Res. 2020;137:106196. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adessina A., Fraj A.B., Barth&#xe9;l&#xe9;my J.-F., Chateau C., Garnier D. Experimental and micromechanical investigation on the mechanical and durability properties of recycled aggregates concrete. Cem. Concr. Res. 2019;126:105900. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes H.C., da Silva Bezerra A.C., de Souza Rodrigues C., Poggiali F.S.J., Kim B. Carbonation for enhancement of fine recycled aggregate applied to mortar. Clean. Waste Syst. 2025;12:100413. doi: 10.1016/j.clwas.2025.100413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clwas.2025.100413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J., Guo Y., Tam V.W.Y., Tan J., Shen A., Zhang C., Zhang J. Feasibility of recycled aggregates modified with a compound method involving sodium silicate and silane as permeable concrete aggregates. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;361:129747. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo L., Yao W., Liang G.W., Luo Y. Workability, autogenous shrinkage and microstructure of alkali-activated slag/fly ash slurries: Effect of precursor composition and sodium silicate modulus. J. Build. Eng. 2023;73:106712. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian Y., Yang D., Yan Y., Ren G., Liu M. Synergistic effects of alkali content and silicate modulus optimization for enhanced properties in alkali-activated ultra-high performance concrete at ambient and high temperature. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2025;22:e04606. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2025.e04606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2025.e04606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu R., Kong F., Yang R., Wang H., Hong T. Influences of silicate modulus and alkali content on macroscopic properties and microstructure of alkali-activated blast furnace slag-copper slag. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;442:137622. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang N., Yang Q., Li D., Yu Y., Jiang X., Xu J. Autogenous and drying shrinkage properties of precast recycled aggregate concrete. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2025;22:e04355. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2025.e04355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2025.e04355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Wang W., Huang J., Wang Z., Ma S., Liu Y. Relationship between internal humidity and drying shrinkage of recycled aggregate thermal insulation concrete considering recycled aggregate content. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;355:129224. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu H., Wang Y., Zhang P., Lin Q., Chen Z., Qiu R., Zheng X. Nano-SiO2 coating and silane modified bamboo cellulose nanofibers for alkali-activated slag mortar with recycled aggregate: Performance enhancement and mechanism. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;458:139703. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H., Xu Y. Fracture properties and acoustic emission characteristics of manufactured sand recycled fine aggregate concrete. Theor. Appl. Fract. Mech. 2024;133:104633. doi: 10.1016/j.tafmec.2024.104633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tafmec.2024.104633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei C., Chen P., Tan W., Zhou T., Li J. Effect of wet copper tailings on the performance of high-performance concrete. J. Build. Eng. 2023;74:106931. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y., Wang J., Qian X., Wang L., Chen P., Qiao P. A renewable admixture to enhance the performance of cement mortars through a pre-hydration method. J. Clean. Prod. 2022;332:130095. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.130095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.130095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q.-H., Zhao S.-Y., Huang B.-T., Xu L.-Y., Xu S.-L. Simultaneous enhancement of ductility and sustainability of high-strength Strain-Hardening Cementitious Composites (SHCC) using recycled fine aggregates. J. Clean. Prod. 2024;470:143357. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.143357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.143357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie J.K., Chen P.Y., Li J., Xu Y., Fang Y., Wang A.G., Wang J.L. Directly upcycling copper mining wastewater into a source of mixing water for the preparation of alkali-activated slag materials. Process Saf. Environ. Prot. 2022;168:362&#x2013;371. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2022.10.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2022.10.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J.Y., Tan J.X., Liu B.J., Chen J.Z., Dai J.D., He Z.H. Experimental study on full-volume slag alkali-activated mortars: Air-cooled blast furnace slag versus machine-made sand as fine aggregates. J. Hazard. Mater. 2021;403:123983. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2020.123983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2020.123983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33265022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie X., Liu X., Liu R., Lyu K., Zhu Y., Zuo J., Zhang P., Wu C., Shah S.P. Optimization formulation of low carbon MSWIFA cement-based composites modified by nano SiO2. J. Build. Eng. 2023;80:108043. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.108043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.108043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>