<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41801641</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2199-1170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine - open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Core Strength Training on Maximal Trunk Muscle Strength and Cycling Economy in Female Mountain Bikers.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">26</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40798-026-00996-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">In cross-country mountain biking (MTB), performance is primarily determined by aerobic capacity. However, shortened race durations from 150 to 80&#xa0;min increased the relevance of anaerobic capacity, muscle strength, and power. Adequate levels of trunk muscle strength (TMS) enable force transfer between lower and upper extremities during starts, inclines, and finishes. Cycling economy (CE) may benefit from TMS training. This study examined the effects of TMS training on TMS, TMS endurance, and CE in MTB athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty-four trained or highly-trained female (Tier 2-3) MTB athletes aged 14-22 years were pair-matched by age and randomly assigned to a TMS group or an active control. Control exercised lower limb but not trunk muscles. Over eight weeks during the off-season, both groups completed three weekly 30-min sessions. Pre-, post training, assessments included maximal isometric TMS, lateral trunk endurance, and CE. Hormonal measures were included to account for menstrual cycle-related variability. CE was assessed during an MTB race course treadmill simulation via physiological (O&#x2082;/CO&#x2082;&#xb7;min&#x207b;&#xb9;&#xb7;kg&#x207b;&#xb9;) and CE-related mechanical parameters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">TMS training improved maximal trunk flexor (p&lt;0.001, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.1), extensor strength (p&lt;0.001, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.7), and lateral TMS endurance (p=0.03, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.74), compared with controls. Lateral bike displacement was reduced in the TMS group (p=0.001, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.8). Physiological CE parameters showed no between-group differences. Hormonal measures did not moderate effects (p&gt;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Eight weeks of global TMS training improved maximal isometric trunk flexor, extensor strength and lateral bike displacement in female MTB athletes. These findings suggest that off-season TMS training may improve MTB performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blechschmied</LastName><ForeName>Roland</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, Exercise and Human Movement Science, University of Freiburg, Sandfangweg 4, 79102, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strahler</LastName><ForeName>Jana</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, Sport Psychology, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Granacher</LastName><ForeName>Urs</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7095-813X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, Exercise and Human Movement Science, University of Freiburg, Sandfangweg 4, 79102, Freiburg, Germany. urs.granacher@sport.uni-freiburg.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101662568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-9761</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiorespiratory fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Youth sports</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics Approval and Consent to Participate: The study was approved by the ethics committee of University Clinic Freiburg, Freiburg im Breisgau, Germany (approval number: 24-1179-S2). The study was conducted in accordance with the ethical standards of the 1964 Declaration of Helsinki and its later amendments or comparable ethical standards. Written informed consent was obtained from the athletes and their legal representatives. Consent for Publication: Written informed consent for the recording and publication of photographs was obtained from the athletes and their legal representatives. Competing Interests: The authors Roland Blechschmied, Urs Granacher and Jana Strahler declare that they have no conflicts of interest to disclose related to this research.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41801641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12972400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-026-00996-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40798-026-00996-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Krohm L, Kr&#xfc;ger T, Markov A, Helm N, Granacher U. Systematische Analyse des konditionellen Anforderungs-Profils im olympischen Cross-Country Mountainbike. Leistungssport. 2022;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Marcora SM, Rampinini E, Mognoni P, Sassi A. Correlations between physiological variables and performance in high level cross country off road cyclists. BJSM. 2005;39:747&#x2013;51. 10.1136/bjsm.2004.017236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2004.017236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1725050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16183772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bompa T. Periodization Training for Sports-3rd Edition. Human Kinetics; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theobald U. Leistungsanforderungen und Trainingsmittel in der Radsportdisziplin mountainbike cross-country. 20th ed. Leistungssport: Philippka-Sport; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikmoen O, Ellefsen S, Tr&#xf8;en &#xd8;, Hollan I, Hanestadhaugen M, Raastad T, R&#xf8;nnestad BR. Strength training improves cycling performance, fractional utilization of VO2max and cycling economy in female cyclists. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2016;26:384&#x2013;96. 10.1111/sms.12468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25892654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roecker K, Prettin S, Sorichter S. Gas exchange measurements with high temporal resolution: the breath-by-breath approach. Int J Sports Med. 2005;26(Suppl 1):S11&#x2013;8. 10.1055/s-2004-830506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2004-830506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15702451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faria EW, Parker DL, Faria IE. The science of cycling: physiology and training - part 1. Sports Med. 2005;35:285&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200535040-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mornieux G, Stapelfeldt B, Gollhofer A, Belli A. Effects of pedal type and pull-up action during cycling. Int J Sports Med. 2008;29:817&#x2013;22. 10.1055/s-2008-1038374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2008-1038374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18418807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stapelfeldt B. Kraft-und Ausdauerleistungen im Mountainbikesport. PhD dissertation. Albert-Ludwigs-Universit&#xe4;t Freiburg; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeterbakken AH, Stien N, Andersen V, Scott S, Cumming KT, Behm DG, et al. The Effects of Trunk Muscle Training on Physical Fitness and Sport-Specific Performance in Young and Adult Athletes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2022;52:1599&#x2013;622. 10.1007/s40279-021-01637-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01637-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9213339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35061213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granacher U, Gollhofer A, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Kressig RW, Muehlbauer T. The importance of trunk muscle strength for balance, functional performance, and fall prevention in seniors: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2013;43:627&#x2013;41. 10.1007/s40279-013-0041-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-013-0041-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23568373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmark A. Stability of the lumbar spine. A study in mechanical engineering. Acta Orthop Scand Suppl. 1989;230:1&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/17453678909154177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2658468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;sch D, Meyer G, Wiegel C, Kurrat H, Braun J, Granacher U. Bedeutung, Diagnostik und Training der lokalen Rumpfkraftausdauer im Handball. Leistungssport. 2016;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hibbs AE, Thompson KG, French D, Wrigley A, Spears I. Optimizing performance by improving core stability and core strength. Sports Med. 2008;38:995&#x2013;1008. 10.2165/00007256-200838120-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200838120-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19026017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller AI, Heath EM, Bressel E, Smith GA. The metabolic cost of balance in cycling. J Sci Cycl. 2013;2:20&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDaniel J, Subudhi A, Martin JC. Torso stabilization reduces the metabolic cost of producing cycling power. Can J Appl Physiol. 2005;30:433&#x2013;41. 10.1139/h05-132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h05-132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16258182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDaniel J, Durstine JL, Hand GA, Martin JC. Determinants of metabolic cost during submaximal cycling. J Appl Physiol. 2002;93:823&#x2013;8. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00982.2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00982.2001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12183473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granacher U, Schellbach J, Klein K, Prieske O, Baeyens J-P, Muehlbauer T. Effects of core strength training using stable versus unstable surfaces on physical fitness in adolescents: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2014;6:40. 10.1186/2052-1847-6-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2052-1847-6-40</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4290805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25584193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asplund C, Ross M. Core stability and bicycling. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2010;9:155&#x2013;60. 10.1249/JSR.0b013e3181de0f91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0b013e3181de0f91</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20463499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinke F, Warnke T, G&#xe4;bler M, Granacher U. Effects of isokinetic training on trunk muscle fitness and body composition in world-class canoe sprinters. Front Physiol. 2019;10:21. 10.3389/fphys.2019.00021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.00021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6360172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30745878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granacher U, Lacroix A, Muehlbauer T, Roettger K, Gollhofer A. Effects of core instability strength training on trunk muscle strength, spinal mobility, dynamic balance and functional mobility in older adults. Gerontology. 2013;59:105&#x2013;13. 10.1159/000343152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000343152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23108436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson N, Robinson DG, Verhagen E, Fagher K, Edouard P, Rojas-Valverde D, et al. Under-representation of women is alive and well in sport and exercise medicine: What it looks like and what we can do about it. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2023;9:e001606. 10.1136/bmjsem-2023-001606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2023-001606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10186450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37200777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Reilly N, Brunette M, Bradish C. Lifelong female engagement in sport: A framework for advancing girls&#x2019; and women&#x2019;s participation. JASM. 2018;10:15&#x2013;30. 10.18666/jasm-2017-v10-i2-8742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18666/jasm-2017-v10-i2-8742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strahler J, Skoluda N, Kappert MB, Nater UM. Simultaneous measurement of salivary cortisol and alpha-amylase: Application and recommendations. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2017;83:657&#x2013;77. 10.1016/j.neubiorev.2017.08.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2017.08.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28864234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blagrove RC, Bruinvels G, Pedlar CR. Variations in strength-related measures during the menstrual cycle in eumenorrheic women: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2020;23:1220&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.jsams.2020.04.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2020.04.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32456980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T. The menstrual cycle and human performance: An overview. Biol Rhythm Res. 2000;31(20000231:11):29&#x2013;40. 10.1076/0929-1016. -0;FT029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1076/0929-1016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebrun CM. Effect of the different phases of the menstrual cycle and oral contraceptives on athletic performance. Sports Med. 1993;16:400&#x2013;30. 10.2165/00007256-199316060-00005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199316060-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8303141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, Martin DT, Mujika I, Goosey-Tolfrey VL, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: A participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022;17:317&#x2013;31. 10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34965513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas S, Reading J, Shepard RJ. Revision of the physical activity readiness questionnaire (PAR-Q). Can J Sport Sci. 1992;17(4):338&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1330274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tschopp M. Manual Leistungsdiagnostik Kraft. Qualit&#xe4;tsentwicklung Sportmed. Swiss Olympic. 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrigan J, Stute N, Eckerle J, Mackowski N, Walters J, O&#x2019;Connor M, et al. Reliability and validity of contemporary bioelectrical impedance analysis devices for body composition assessment. JEN. 2022;5(4). 10.53520/jen2022.103133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Perea A, Chirosa R&#xed;os LJ, Martinez-Garcia D, Ulloa-D&#xed;az D, Guede Rojas F, Jerez-Mayorga D, Chirosa Rios IJ. Reliability of isometric and isokinetic trunk flexor strength using a functional electromechanical dynamometer. PeerJ. 2019;7:e7883. 10.7717/peerj.7883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.7883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6827544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31695965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tschopp M, Bourban P, H&#xfc;bner K, Marti B. Reliability of a standardized, dynamic trunk muscle strength test: experiences with healthy male elite athletes. Swiss J Sports Med Sports Traumatol. 2001;49,:67&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoppe MW, Sperlich B, Baumgart C, Janssen M, Freiwald J. Reliabilit&#xe4;t ausgew&#xe4;hlter Parameter der Fahrradergospirometrie anhand des PowerCube-Ergo-Atemgasanalysators. [Reliability of Selected Parameters of Cycling Ergospirometry from the PowerCube-Ergo Respiratory Gas Analyser]. Sportverletz Sportschaden. 2015;29:173&#x2013;9. 10.1055/s-0034-1399096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0034-1399096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25710394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkert K, Kirsten J, Kamnig R, Steinacker JM, Treff G. Differences in V&#x2d9;O2max measurements between breath-by-breath and mixing-chamber mode in the COSMED K5. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021;16:1335&#x2013;40. 10.1123/ijspp.2020-0634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2020-0634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33771939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garmin. Rally XC. Power meter pedals for off-road cyclists. 2025. https://www.garmin.com</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao W, Stalder T, Kirschbaum C. Quantitative analysis of estradiol and six other steroid hormones in human saliva using a high throughput liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry assay. Talanta. 2015;143:353&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.talanta.2015.05.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2015.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26078170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman LA. Kolmogorov-Smirnov tests for psychological research. Psychol Bull. 1954;51:160&#x2013;8. 10.1037/h0060275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/h0060275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13155707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastwirth JL, Gel YR, Miao W. The impact of Levene&#x2019;s test of equality of variances on statistical theory and practice. Statist Sci. 2009;24:343&#x2013;60. 10.1214/09-STS301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1214/09-STS301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis PD. The essential guide to effect sizes: Sattistical power, meta-analysis and the interpretation of research results. 11th ed. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacroix A, Kressig RW, Muehlbauer T, Gschwind YJ, Pfenninger B, Bruegger O, Granacher U. Effects of a supervised versus an unsupervised combined balance and strength training program on balance and muscle power in healthy older adults: A randomized controlled trial. Gerontology. 2016;62:275&#x2013;88. 10.1159/000442087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000442087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26645282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonhart R, Wirtz M, Bengel J. Measuring effect sizes using manifest versus latent variables: consequences and implications for research. Int J Rehabil Res. 2008;31:207&#x2013;16. 10.1097/MRR.0b013e3282fb7872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MRR.0b013e3282fb7872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18708843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. Routledge; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiseman K. An investigation into the effectiveness of core muscle strengthening on cycling performance in asymptomatic cyclists. PhD dissertation. Durban University of Technology. 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieske O, Muehlbauer T, Granacher U. The role of trunk muscle strength for physical fitness and athletic performance in trained individuals: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2016;46:401&#x2013;19. 10.1007/s40279-015-0426-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0426-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26589515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beattie K, Carson BP, Lyons M, Kenny IC. The effect of maximal- and explosive-strength training on performance indicators in cyclists. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12:470&#x2013;80. 10.1123/ijspp.2016-0015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2016-0015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27618339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikmoen O, R&#xf8;nnestad BR. A Comparison of the effect of strength training on cycling performance between men and women. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2021. 10.3390/jfmk6010029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk6010029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33803041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gei&#xdf;ler D, Lison A, Schulze C. The relationship between ergometric treadmill or bicycle performance and isokinetic trunk strength - A retrospective analysis. Int J Sports Med. 2023;44:258&#x2013;67. 10.1055/a-1953-6809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1953-6809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36564026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J-H, Kim J-E, Yoo J-I, Kim Y-P, Kim E-H, Seo T-B. Comparison of maximum muscle strength and isokinetic knee and core muscle functions according to pedaling power difference of racing cyclist candidates. J Exerc Rehabil. 2019;15:401&#x2013;6. 10.12965/jer.1938180.090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.1938180.090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6614766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31316932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitko S, L&#xf3;pez-Laval I, Cirer-Sastre R. Influence of conventional resistance training compared to core exercises on road cycling power output. Cureus. 2024;16:e59371. 10.7759/cureus.59371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.59371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11137631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38817493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson RD, Kram R. The influence of bicycle lean on maximal power output during sprint cycling. J Biomech. 2021;125:110595. 10.1016/j.jbiomech.2021.110595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2021.110595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34246911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott-Sale KJ, Altini M, Doyle-Baker P, Ferrer E, Flood TR, Harris R, et al. Why we must stop assuming and estimating menstrual cycle phases in laboratory and field-based sport related research. Sports Med. 2025;55:1339&#x2013;51. 10.1007/s40279-025-02189-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-025-02189-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12152053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40085421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>