<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41814360</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2661-801X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC chemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Chem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of fertilizer on biochemical composition, and antioxidant properties of white&#x2011;fleshed sweet potato (Ipomoea batatas L.) flour.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">71</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13065-026-01771-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study evaluated the impact of different fertilizer treatments on the proximate composition and antioxidant properties of flour from two white-fleshed sweet potato varieties (PCS and LCCS). The tubers were cultivated in the Sayo district of the Kellem Wollega Zone, Ethiopia. A two-factor experimental design with three blocks was employed, incorporating six treatments: eluate (T1), digestate (T2), compost (T3), a digestate-compost mixture (T4), a negative control (T-), and a positive control with NPK fertilizer (T+), each replicated three times. Analysis of variance (ANOVA) revealed significant differences (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) in the biochemical and antioxidant properties of the flours due to both treatment and variety. The PCS variety exhibited the highest ranges for water content (70.09&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.02% to 72.95&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.98%) and lipid content (0.45&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.12&#xa0;g/100&#xa0;g to 1.08&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.02&#xa0;g/100&#xa0;g). In contrast, the LCCS variety showed superior values for carotenoid, (536.56&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;58.04-1888.78&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;35.52) &#xb5;g/100&#xa0;g, total sugar (5.77&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.74-46.98&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.39) g/100&#xa0;g, and protein content, (1.20&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.23-6.68&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.83) g/100&#xa0;g. The digestate-compost mixture (T4) consistently produced flour with the highest nutritional quality across most parameters. These findings provide valuable insights for optimizing fertilizer strategies to enhance the nutritional and functional value of white-fleshed sweet potato flour.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tegegn</LastName><ForeName>Dereje Fedasa</ForeName><Initials>DF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, College of Natural and Computational Science, Dambi Dollo University, P.O.Box. 260, Dambi Dollo, Oromia, Ethiopia. derejefedasakiya@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Belachew</LastName><ForeName>Habtamu Zewude</ForeName><Initials>HZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, College of Natural and Computational Science, Dambi Dollo University, P.O.Box. 260, Dambi Dollo, Oromia, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, College of Natural and Computational Science, Jimma University, P.O.Box. 378, Jimma, Oromia, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Efa</LastName><ForeName>Dame Alemayehu</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Institute of Technology, Wallaga University, P.O.Box. 395, Nekemte, Oromia, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mamo</LastName><ForeName>Samson Ayele</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Environmental Health Science and Technology, Faculty of Public Health, Jimma University, Jimma, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Chem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101741142</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2661-801X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antioxidant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fertilizer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Three-block two factorial experiment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">White&#x2011;fleshed sweet potato</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Informed consent to participate in this study was obtained from farmland owners prior to the collection of data for the " Effect of Fertilizer on Biochemical Composition, and Antioxidant Properties of White&#x2011;Fleshed Sweet Potato (Ipomoea batatas L.) Flour&#x201d; study. The farmland owners were fully briefed on the study&#x2019;s objectives, procedures, potential risks, and benefits. They were given the opportunity to ask questions and received satisfactory answers. Consent was documented in written form, and participation was voluntary, with the option to withdraw from the study at any time without any repercussions. This study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41814360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13045033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13065-026-01771-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13065-026-01771-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cartabiano-Leite CE, Porcu OM, de Casas AF. Sweet potato (<i>Ipomoea batatas</i> L. Lam) nutritional potential and social relevance: a review. history. 2020;11:23&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanbol KK, Namo O. The contribution of root and tuber crops to food security: A review. J Agric Sci Technol B. 2019;9(1017265):2161&#x2013;6264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunz R, Reddy K, Mthembu T, Lake S, Mabhaudhi T, Chimonyo V, Naiken V. Crop and nutritional water productivity of sweet potato and taro.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferdaus MJ, Chukwu-Munsen E, Foguel A, da Silva RC. Taro Roots: An Underexploited Root Crop. Nutrients. 2023;15(15):3337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15153337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10421445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37571276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barba&#x15b; P, Noaema AH, Sawicka B. Potato (<i>Solanum Tuberosum</i> L.) as a rich source of nutrients and bioactive compounds: a review. J Cell Tissue Res. 2023;23(2):7337&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh B, Raigond P, Dutt S, Lal MK, Jaiswal A, Changan SS, Koundal B. Nutrition in potato and its food products. Vegetables for nutrition and entrepreneurship. Singapore: Springer Nature Singapore; 2023. pp. 179&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawicka B, Skiba D, Pszcz&#xf3;&#x142;kowski P, Krochmal-Marczak B. Tuber quality. In: Jerusalem artichoke food science and technology: helianthus tuberosus. Singapore: Springer Nature Singapore; 2022. pp. 45&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ernazarova R. Studying The Quantity Of Vitamins Contained In Tubers And Root Crops. J Res Innov. 2024;2(3):30&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lal MK, Kumar A, Kumar A, Jena R, Raigond P, Kumar D, Singh B. Minerals in potato. Potato Nutr Food Secur. 2020; p. 87&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mberekpe P, Igbo C. An analysis of micro-nutrients composition of cocoyam (<i>Colocasiae esculenta</i>) and sweet potato (<i>Ipomoea batatas</i> L) leaves in melon soup. Niger J Home Econ. 2024;12(10):152&#x2013;61 Issn: 2782&#x2013;8131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaganathan PPD, Immanuel S, Sivakumar S. (2020). Analysis of global and national scenario of tuber crops production-trends and prospects.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zierer W, R&#xfc;scher D, Sonnewald U, Sonnewald S. Tuber and tuberous root development. Annu Rev Plant Biol. 2021;72:551&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-arplant-080720-084456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33788583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perovi&#x107; J, &#x160;aponjac VT, Koji&#x107; J, Krulj J, Moreno DA, Garc&#xed;a-Viguera C, Ili&#x107; N. Chicory (<i>Cichorium intybus</i> L.) as a food ingredient&#x2013;nutritional composition, bioactivity, safety, and health claims: a review. Food Chem. 2021;336: 127676.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2020.127676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32768902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moodley P, Trois C. Roots, tubers, and bulb crops wastes: residue utilization for industrial biotechnology. In: Roots, tubers, and bulb crop wastes: management by biorefinery approaches. Singapore: Springer Nature Singapore; 2024. p. 1&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agubosi OCP, Dumkenechukwu IF, Alagbe JO. Evaluation of the nutritive value of air-dried and sun-dried sweet potato (<i>Ipomoea batatas</i>) peels. Tex J Agric Biol Sci. 2021;1:14&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamidon NH, Abang Zaidel DN, Mohd Jusoh YM. Optimization of pectin extraction from sweet potato peels using citric acid and its emulsifying properties. Recent Patents Food Nutr Agric. 2020;11(3):202&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/2212798411666200207102051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bebber DP, Richards VR. A meta-analysis of the effect of organic and mineral fertilizers on soil microbial diversity. Appl Soil Ecol. 2022;175:104450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsoil.2022.104450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George J, Reddy GV, Wadl PA, Rutter W, Culbreath J, Lau PW, et al. Sustainable sweetpotato production in the United States: current status, challenges, and opportunities. Agron J. 2024. 10.1002/agj2.21539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/agj2.21539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michael PS. Soil fertility status and sweet potato cultivation in composted mounds under humid lowland tropical climatic conditions. SAINS TANAH-J Soil Sci Agroclimatol. 2020;17(2):144&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tchuenteu TL, Derogoh NAN, Megueni C. Study of intercropping system castor bean and vegetables are seeds yield and yield related traits in two agroecological zones of Cameroon Odessa. Psychol Assess Resour. 2018;4(1):193&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye L, Zhao X, Bao E, Li J, Zou Z, Cao K. Bio-organic fertilizer with reduced rates of chemical fertilization improves soil fertility and enhances tomato yield and quality. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-56954-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6957517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31932626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawit M, Habte A. Yield and profitability of sweet potato (<i>Ipomoea batatas</i> (L.) Lam) as a function of increasing levels of phosphorus and varieties in southern Ethiopia. Appl Environ Soil Sci. 2023. 10.1155/2023/2716227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/2716227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobena TL, Asemie MM, Firisa TB. Evaluation of released sweet potato [<i>Ipomoea batatas</i> (L.) Lam] varieties for yield and yield-related attributes in Semen-Bench district of Bench-Sheko-Zone, South-Western Ethiopia. Heliyon. 2022. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2022.e10950.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2022.e10950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9582706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36276733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ejigu F, Yonas W, Amare A, Gadisa A. Adaptation of recently released improved orange flesh sweet potato (<i>Ipomoea batatas</i> L.) varieties in Southwestern Ethiopia. Int J Agricultural Res Innov Technol (IJARIT). 2022;12(2):111&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3329/ijarit.v12i2.64095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pahalvi HN, Rafiya L, Rashid S, Nisar B, Kamili AN. Chemical fertilizers and their impact on soil health. Microbiota Biofertilizers. 2021;2:1&#x2013;20. Ecofriendly tools for reclamation of degraded soil environs.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav KK, Dash S, Mandal BN, Parsad R. Row-column designs for two level factorial experiments. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L, Tang Q, Wu J, Yu W, Zhang M, Jiang D, et al. Design and test of seedbed preparation machine before transplanting of rapeseed combined transplanter. Agriculture. 2022;12(9):1427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture12091427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambers H, Oliveira RS, Lambers H, Oliveira RS. Plant water relations. Plant Physiol Ecol. 2019; p. 187&#x2013;263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbdAllah AM, Burkey KO, Mashaheet AM. Reduction of plant water consumption through anti-transpirants foliar application in tomato plants (<i>Solanum lycopersicum</i> L). Sci Hort. 2018;235:373&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2018.03.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurmu G. Soil organic matter and its role in soil health and crop productivity improvement. For Ecol Manag. 2019;7(7):475&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q, Wang L, Fu Y, Lin D, Hou M, Li X, Wang Z. Transformation of soil organic matter subjected to environmental disturbance and preservation of organic matter bound to soil minerals: a review. J Soils Sediments. 2023;23(3):1485&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11368-022-03381-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupke S, Buchholz U, Fastner J, F&#xf6;rster C, Frank C, Lewin A, Selinka HC. Impact of climate change on waterborne infections and intoxications. J Health Monit. 2023;8(Suppl 3):62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10278370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37342430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiong YW, Sharma P, Xu S, Bu J, An S, Foo JBL, et al. Enhancing sustainable crop cultivation: the impact of renewable soil amendments and digestate fertilizer on crop growth and nutrient composition. Environ Pollut. 2024;342:123132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envpol.2023.123132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38081377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan M, Tian H, Song S, Tan HT, Lee JT, Zhang J, et al. Effects of digestate-encapsulated biochar on plant growth, soil microbiome and nitrogen leaching. J Environ Manage. 2023;334:117481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2023.117481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36801683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulkareem OA, Akhere EP. Effect of some preliminary processing techniques on nutrients, anti-nutrients, mineral and vitamin composition of four varieties of Nigerian sweet potato [<i>Ipomoea batatas</i> L.(Lam)]. J Culin Sci Technol. 2023;21(3):466&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15428052.2021.1955796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farida S, Saati EA, Damat D, Wahyudi A. Assessment of purple sweet potato flour Antin 2 and Antin 3 varieties nutritional quality using various drying temperature. Carpathian J Food Sci Technol. 2023;15(2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezeoha SL, Ide PE, Ifeanyieze CE. Modelling temperature and slice thickness effect on b-carotene, carbohydrate and moisture contents of orange-fleshed sweet potato flour. Agricultural Eng International: CIGR J. 2024;26(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azeem M, Rehman MAU. Effect of soaking solution and high hydrostatic pressure on in vitro digestibility of &#x3b2;-carotene in gluten free sweet potato noodles. Innov Food Sci Emerg Technol. 2024. 10.1016/j.ifset.2024.103677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ifset.2024.103677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okpalanma EF, Ukpong ES, Ezegbe CC, Nwagbo CC, Chude COC. Evaluation of the physico-chemical properties of cassava, cocoyam, sweet potato starches and glucose syrups produced from the hydrolysis of the starches with sorghum malt enzyme extract. Food Sci Appl Biotechnol. 2024;7(1):24&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30721/fsab2024.v7.i1.314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujianto M, Zalizar L, Damat D, Relawati R, Robbany MD, Sebayang NS, et al. The the effects of additioning purple sweet potato flour (<i>Ipomoea batatas</i> L.) on the characteristics of white dragon fruit pudding (<i>Selenicereus undatus</i>). Demeter J Farming Agric. 2024;2(1):74&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.58905/demeter.v2i1.227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuliana N, Nurdjanah S, Sugiharto R, Amethy D. (2023). Effect of spontaneous lactic acid fermentation on physico-chemical properties of sweet potato flour.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meenakumari R, Ravichandran C, Vimalarani M. Nutritional, sensory, and antioxidant characteristics of composite multigrain flour biscuits blended with sweet potato flour. Int Food Res J. 2023. 10.47836/ifrj.30.1.14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47836/ifrj.30.1.14</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng H, Xu C, Wu M, Feng Y. Effects of potato and sweet potato flour addition on properties of wheat flour and dough, and bread quality. Food Sci Nutr. 2022;10(3):689&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/fsn3.2693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8907709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35282011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korese JK, Chikpah SK, Hensel O, Pawelzik E, Sturm B. Effect of orange-fleshed sweet potato flour particle size and degree of wheat flour substitution on physical, nutritional, textural and sensory properties of cookies. Eur Food Res Technol. 2021;247(4):889&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00217-020-03672-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Souza DM, Coelho SRM, Christ D, Kottwitz LBM, Lewandoski CF, Kowaleski J, Gurgacz F. Optimization of the drying process for production of biofortified sweet potato flour. J Food Process Preserv. 2021;45(1):e15039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jfpp.15039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>