<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">BMC Anesthesiol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">BMC Anesthesiol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">11</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">bmcanes</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>BMC Anesthesiology</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">1471-2253</issn><publisher><publisher-name>BMC</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC13037277</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC13037277.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">13037277</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">13037277</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41731363</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12871-026-03719-w</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">3719</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Application of anterior sciatic nerve block with liposomal bupivacaine in lower leg fracture surgery: a randomized clinical trial</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" equal-contrib="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names initials="Y">Yue</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" equal-contrib="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names initials="L">Libin</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Shen</surname><given-names initials="X">Xinyi</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chai</surname><given-names initials="B">Bin</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhan</surname><given-names initials="L">Li</given-names></name><address><email>lz20250310@163.com</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/03xb04968</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.186775.a</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0000 9490 772X</institution-id><institution>Department of Anesthesiology, </institution><institution>Lu’an Hospital of Anhui Medical University, </institution></institution-wrap>Lu’an, 237000 People’s Republic of China </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/00mcjh785</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.12955.3a</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0001 2264 7233</institution-id><institution>Department of Anesthesiology, </institution><institution>Zhongshan Hospital Affiliated to Xiamen University, </institution></institution-wrap>Xiamen, China </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/01mv9t934</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.419897.a</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0369 313X</institution-id><institution>Key Laboratory of Anesthesiology and Resuscitation (Huazhong University of Science and Technology), Ministry of Education, </institution></institution-wrap>Wuhan, China </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>23</day><month>2</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2026</year></pub-date><volume>26</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">503728</issue-id><elocation-id>202</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>23</day><month>6</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>19</day><month>2</month><year>2026</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>23</day><month>02</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>01</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-04-01 10:25:15.320"><day>01</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>© The Author(s) 2026</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2026</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License, which permits any non-commercial use, sharing, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if you modified the licensed material. You do not have permission under this licence to share adapted material derived from this article or parts of it. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article’s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article’s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="12871_2026_Article_3719.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1"><sec><title>Background</title><p id="Par1">Postoperative acute pain management remains a critical challenge in orthopedic surgery. This study compared the analgesic efficacy of liposomal bupivacaine versus conventional ropivacaine when administered via an ultrasound-guided anterior sciatic nerve block in patients undergoing lower leg fracture surgery.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p id="Par2">In a randomized, double-blinded trial, eighty adult patients scheduled for elective open reduction and internal fixation (ORIF) of lower leg fractures. Patients were randomized into Group LB (20 mL liposomal bupivacaine, 266 mg) or Group R (20 mL 0.5% ropivacaine). The primary outcome was postoperative pain scores (Visual Analog Scale, VAS) at 6 h (T1), 24 h (T2), 48 h (T3), and 72 h (T4). Secondary outcomes included perioperative opioid use, motor block onset time, Postoperative hospital stay, functional recovery (Barthel Index), and complications.</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p id="Par3">Group LB exhibited significantly lower VAS scores at T2 (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001), T3 (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.007), and T4 (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.042), though with higher scores at T1 (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001). Postoperative hospital stay was shorter in Group LB (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.021), and functional recovery at discharge (Barthel Index) was superior (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.020). No significant differences in perioperative opioid use or complication rates were observed.</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusions</title><p id="Par4">Compared to ropivacaine, liposomal bupivacaine administered via anterior sciatic nerve block provided prolonged postoperative analgesia and was associated with improved functional recovery and shorter hospital stay in patients undergoing lower leg fracture surgery.</p></sec><sec><title>Trial registration</title><p id="Par5">The study protocol was registered at the Chinese Clinical Trial Registry (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.chictr.org.cn">http://www.chictr.org.cn</ext-link>, ChiCTR2400084397, 15/05/2024).</p></sec><sec><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12871-026-03719-w.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>Liposomal bupivacaine</kwd><kwd>Nerve Block</kwd><kwd>Orthopedic Procedures</kwd><kwd>Postoperative analgesia</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution>Research Grant of Key Laboratory of Anesthesiology and Resuscitation (Huazhong University of Science and Technology), Ministry of Education</institution></funding-source><award-id>No.4</award-id><principal-award-recipient><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhan</surname><given-names>Li</given-names></name></principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution>the Science and Technology Bureau of Lu'an City</institution></funding-source><award-id>2024lakj008</award-id><principal-award-recipient><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhan</surname><given-names>Li</given-names></name></principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>© BioMed Central Ltd., part of Springer Nature 2026</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Background</title><p id="Par6">Lower leg fractures, particularly distal tibiofibular fractures (OTA/AO 43 type), frequently necessitate surgical intervention via open reduction and internal fixation (ORIF) to achieve anatomical alignment and stability [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>]. Despite surgical success, postoperative acute pain management remains a critical challenge, prompting widespread adoption of multimodal analgesia protocols combining patient-controlled intravenous analgesia (PCIA) with peripheral nerve blocks [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>]. The sciatic nerve’s anatomical trajectory [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>] supports its blockade as a routine intervention for knee and lower limb surgeries [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>]. While the traditional posterior approach under ultrasound guidance remains effective, it necessitates lateral positioning, which can aggravate discomfort in fracture patients during preparation. To resolve these challenges, we devised an optimized anterior technique employing a distinct sonographic landmark. Originally introduced by Beck in 1963 as a landmark-based technique [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>], the anterior approach has evolved with the advent of ultrasound guidance. A comparative trial by Ota et al. demonstrated that the ultrasound-guided anterior approach—using the lesser trochanter as a key bony landmark for nerve localization—was as efficacious as the posterior subgluteal approach for knee surgery [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>]. Our technique employs a distinct sonographic landmark: the interface between the semitendinosus muscle and the sciatic nerve in the proximal thigh. Under real-time ultrasound guidance, we target this specific muscle-nerve relationship rather than relying on deeper osseous structures for initial orientation. This direct visualization enhances accuracy across varied patient anatomies. Moreover, despite ropivacaine’s established safety [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>], its limited duration (2–8 h) inadequately addresses prolonged postoperative pain in fracture cases. Liposomal bupivacaine circumvents this temporal gap via controlled-release mechanisms, where phospholipid bilayers encapsulate the drug to sustain therapeutic levels for up to 72 h [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>]. Although liposomal bupivacaine has been extensively investigated in clinical practice [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>], no studies have investigated its application in anterior sciatic nerve block for patients undergoing lower leg fracture surgery. This prospective randomized controlled trial aims to: Systematically assess whether the application of liposomal bupivacaine, administered via a standardized ultrasound-guided anterior approach to sciatic nerve block, can prolong analgesia and improve perioperative pain management compared to ropivacaine. We hypothesized that liposomal bupivacaine would provide superior prolonged analgesia compared to ropivacaine, as evidenced by a significantly lower longitudinal pain profile over the 72-hour postoperative period, which will be analyzed as the primary endpoint using Generalized Estimating Equations (GEE).</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Methods</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Ethical approval and study design </title><p id="Par7">This trial was approved by the Ethics Committee of Lu’an Hospital (No. 2024LL003) and registered at the Chinese Clinical Trial Registry (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.chictr.org.cn">http://www.chictr.org.cn</ext-link>, ChiCTR2400084397, date of registration: May 15, 2024). Written informed consent was obtained from all participants.</p><p id="Par8">A total of 88 patients undergoing open reduction and internal fixation (ORIF) for lower leg fractures at Lu’an People’s Hospital were enrolled and randomized into two groups between June 1, 2024, and December 31, 2024: Group LB (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 44): Received ultrasound-guided anterior approach sciatic nerve block (SNB) with liposomal bupivacaine 20 mL (266 mg), Group R (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 44): Received identical SNB technique with 0.5% ropivacaine 20 ml. Inclusion Criteria: (1) ASA physical status I-III ; (2) Age 18–65 years ; (3) BMI 18–30 kg/m² ; (4) Scheduled for elective lower leg fracture surgery ; (5) Voluntarily signed informed consent. Exclusion criteria comprised: (1) Allergy to amide local anesthetics; (2) BMI &gt; 30 kg/m²; (3) Severe cardiac/hepatic dysfunction (NYHA class &gt; III, Child-Pugh B/C); (4) Chronic renal insufficiency or uncontrolled comorbidities; (5) History of substance abuse or chronic opioid use; (6) Uncontrolled hypertension (BP &gt; 180/110 mmHg) or diabetes (HbA1c &gt; 8%); (7) Pregnancy/lactation; (8) Neurological/psychiatric disorders impairing communication.</p><p id="Par9">Patients were randomly assigned using a computer-generated permuted block randomization sequence (block size = 4) created with SPSS software (Version 27, IBM). Patients were randomized into two groups: Group LB and Group R. To ensure allocation concealment and blinding, the group assignment for each patient was placed in sequentially numbered, opaque, sealed envelopes. An independent anesthesiologist uninvolved in the study opened the envelope and prepared the identical-appearing 20 mL formulation used for the block. The anesthesiologist performing the nerve blocks did not participate in study drug preparation or postoperative follow-up. The syringes were concealed by an opaque label during drug administration. The patient was placed in a supine position and could not view the syringe. The operating surgeon and the post‑anesthesia care unit (PACU) nursing staff were not involved in the pre‑operative block procedure. Therefore, the performing anesthesiologist, operating surgeon, PACU nursing team, patients, and outcome assessors were all blinded to group allocation.</p><p id="Par10">Prior to the nerve block, patients received light sedation with an intravenous loading dose of dexmedetomidine (0.8 µg/kg) administered over 10 min, followed by a continuous infusion of 0.5 µg/kg/h, and a single bolus of sufentanil (5 µg) to alleviate anxiety and procedural discomfort. The level of sedation was titrated to achieve and maintain a Richmond Agitation-Sedation Scale (RASS) score of 0 (alert and calm) to -1 (drowsy, maintains eye contact). the ultrasound-guided anterior SNB was performed in supine position with hip abduction. Anterior sciatic nerve block was used in all patients preoperatively, group LB received 20 mL liposomal bupivacaine (266 mg); Group R received 20 mL 0.5% ropivacaine. No posterior approach blocks were performed in either group.</p><p id="Par11">Patients were positioned supine with the affected hip slightly abducted. A low-frequency curvilinear ultrasound probe was placed on the proximal thigh of the affected limb, 10 cm distal to the inguinal crease (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>A). The probe orientation was adjusted to visualize the following anatomical structures in the transverse plane: femur, deep femoral artery and vein, quadriceps femoris muscle, biceps femoris muscle, adductor longus muscle, adductor brevis muscle, adductor magnus muscle, and semitendinosus muscles (Figs. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>B and <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>A). Under real-time ultrasound guidance, the sciatic nerve was identified at the level of the proximal thigh, lying lateral to the semitendinosus muscle. The characteristic spatial relationship, where the oval semitendinosus muscle is positioned immediately medial to the hyperechoic sciatic nerve bundle, served as the primary landmark for needle advancement, its depth from the skin surface was typically approximately 8 cm in our study cohort, a 10-cm short-bevel nerve block needle was advanced from lateral to medial via a short-axis in-plane approach, with meticulous attention to vascular avoidance. For Group LB, 20 mL of liposomal bupivacaine (266 mg) was injected perineurally, whereas Group R received 20 mL of 0.5% ropivacaine (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>B). Sensory block was assessed after target sedation (RASS 0 to -1) was achieved and with the patient responsive to verbal commands. Sensory blockade was assessed via pinprick testing (22-gauge blunt needle) at 1-min intervals post-block until surgical incision. Testing ceased when analgesia (0/10 VAS) was confirmed in all four dermatomes: plantar surface (tibial nerve), dorsal foot (superficial peroneal nerve), posterolateral leg (sural nerve), and posterior thigh (posterior femoral cutaneous nerve). Patients failing to achieve complete blockade within 30 min would be excluded (none encountered).</p><p id="Par12">
<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><p><bold>A</bold> Ultrasound probe placement and puncture point. The probe is placed on the proximal thigh of the affected limb, 10 cm distal to the inguinal crease, the arrow indicates puncture point. <bold>B</bold> Anatomy of anterior sciatic nerve. ALM, adductor longus muscle; ABM, adductor brevis muscle; AMM, adductor magnus muscle; STM, semitendinosus muscle; ScN, sciatic nerve; QFM, quadriceps femoris muscle; BFM, biceps femoris muscle; DFV, deep femoral vein; DFA, deep femoral artery</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e350" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12871_2026_3719_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par13">
<fig id="Fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><p>The ultrasound images of the sciatic nerve obtained through anterior approach blockade before (<bold>A</bold>) injection and after (<bold>B</bold>) injection are displayed. ALM, adductor longus muscle; ABM, adductor brevis muscle; AMM, adductor magnus muscle; STM, semitendinosus muscle; QFM, quadriceps femoris muscle; arrows, sciatic nerve; LA, local anesthetic</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e367" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12871_2026_3719_Fig2_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par14">Following confirmation of an adequate sensory block, patients were transferred to the operating room, where standard monitoring was applied, including electrocardiography (ECG), non-invasive blood pressure (NIBP), pulse oximetry (SpO₂), and bispectral index (BIS) monitoring. general anesthesia was induced. general anesthesia was induced with intravenous midazolam (0.02–0.05 mg·kg⁻¹), sufentanil (0.5–0.7 µg·kg⁻¹), etomidate (0.3–0.5 mg·kg⁻¹), and cisatracurium (0.2–0.25 mg·kg⁻¹). Following tracheal intubation, anesthesia was maintained with a continuous infusion of propofol (280–400 mg·h⁻¹), remifentanil (0.2–0.8 mg·h⁻¹), and cisatracurium (3–6 mg·h⁻¹), and by maintaining BIS values between 40 and 60. Supplemental sufentanil boluses (5–10 µg IV) were administered based on predefined hemodynamic triggers (Systolic blood pressure fluctuations exceeding 20% from baseline) or at the anesthesiologist’s discretion for clinical signs of nociception (e.g., tachycardia &gt; 100 bpm). All perioperative medications and interventions, apart from the study drug (liposomal bupivacaine or ropivacaine), were standardized and administered identically to both groups according to the study protocol. Following surgical completion, patients were transferred to the PACU under continuous cardiorespiratory monitoring, where tracheal extubation was performed after meeting strict neurological recovery criteria. In the PACU, patients were connected to a standardized PCIA pump. The PCIA solution contained sufentanil 150 µg and flurbiprofen axetil 100 mg, diluted with 0.9% saline to a total volume of 150 mL. The pump was programmed with a basal infusion of 3 mL/h, a bolus dose of 2 mL, and a lockout interval of 20 min. Supplemental rescue analgesia with intravenous sufentanil 5 µg boluses was available in the PACU for breakthrough pain (VAS ≥ 4) before the PCIA became fully effective. Sufentanil was administered intravenously in 5-µg boluses every 30 min until VAS &lt; 4. Total sufentanil consumption during the initial 2-hour PACU phase was recorded. Following transfer from the PACU, the PCIA pump remained the primary mode of analgesia on the ward for a standardized duration of 48 h. The PCIA protocol was consistent with that used in the PACU (basal infusion of 3 mL/h, bolus dose of 2 mL, lockout interval of 20 min). For the management of breakthrough pain on the ward, defined as a patient-reported VAS score ≥ 4 despite the basal infusion, the first-line intervention was for the patient to self-administer a PCIA bolus dose. All patients received standardized pre-operative education on the use of the PCIA device. Pain scores and the cumulative number of PCIA bolus demands were recorded by the blinded outcome assessors during their scheduled follow-up visits at 72 h postoperatively.</p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Measurement of outcomes</title><p id="Par15">Outcome measures were analyzed for participants who received the allocated intervention and completed the surgical procedure. Outcome measures were systematically evaluated by a blinded independent researcher using standardized protocols. The primary outcome measure was the longitudinal profile of postoperative pain scores assessed using the VAS ( 0–10 cm) at predetermined intervals: 6 h (T1), 24 h (T2), 48 h (T3), and 72 h (T4) following surgery, with pain severity categorized as mild (0–3), moderate (4–7), or severe (8–10) based on functional impact criteria [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. Secondary outcomes included perioperative opioid use, assessed as intraoperative sufentanil consumption (µg), PACU rescue(the number of patients requiring rescue sufentanil boluses during their PACU stay), PCIA demands(the number of demand attempts during PCIA). Postoperative motor function of the sciatic nerve was assessed by testing active ankle dorsiflexion and plantarflexion, recorded as ‘present’ or ‘absent’. Postoperative Hospital Stay, sensory block onset time, functional recovery measured by the Barthel Index [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>], which assesses 10 domains of basic ADL (e.g., feeding, bathing, grooming, dressing, bowel/bladder control, toileting, chair/bed transfers, ambulation, stair climbing) with a total score ranging from 0 (completely dependent) to 100 (completely independent); and incidence of postoperative complications including nausea/vomiting, shivering, and respiratory depression. All outcome data were collected by an independent researcher blinded to group allocation.</p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Samples size calculation</title><p id="Par16">Based on the preliminary pilot study, with a two-sided significance level (α) of 0.05, a statistical power of 80%, and accounting for a potential 10% dropout rate, the calculated sample size was 46 patients per group. To account for enrollment logistics, we ultimately aimed to recruit 48 patients per group, resulting in a total planned sample size of <italic toggle="yes">N</italic> = 96. This target aligns precisely with our final enrollment population.</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Statistical analysis</title><p id="Par17">The analysis was performed in the intention-to-treat (ITT) population, with missing data handled using multiple imputation. Baseline characteristics including demographic variables, ASA classification, and preoperative functional status were analyzed descriptively using means ± SD for normally distributed continuous variables (verified by Shapiro-Wilk test), frequencies/percentages for categorical data. and non-normally distributed continuous variables are presented as medians with interquartile ranges (IQR). The primary outcome was the longitudinal profile of postoperative pain scores assessed by the VAS at 6, 24, 48, and 72 h. For the primary analysis of this outcome, a GEE model with an independent working correlation structure was employed to analyze the effects of time, group, and their interaction. Between-group comparisons utilized independent samples t-test, GEE for non-normal data, and χ²/Fisher’s exact tests for categorical outcomes. All analyses were two-sided, with p-values &lt; 0.05 deemed statistically significant. Statistical analysis was done using the SPSS version 27 (IBM Software).</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Results</title><p id="Par18">After screening 96 eligible candidates, 88 patients met the inclusion criteria and were randomized. All randomized patients (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 88) were included in the final analysis according to the intention-to-treat principle. Among them, 80 patients received the allocated intervention and completed the study (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>). Baseline demographic characteristics, including age, sex distribution, ASA physical status, and body mass index, demonstrated comparable profiles between groups (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &gt; 0.05; Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>). A statistically significant difference was observed in operative duration (Group LB: 94.98 ± 35.55 min vs. Group R: 110.61 ± 21.68 min; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.015), Subgroup analysis of fracture patterns using the OTA/AO classification system revealed comparable distribution between groups (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.815), indicating fracture complexity did not account for the operative time discrepancy.</p><p id="Par19">
<fig id="Fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><p>Consolidated Standards of Reporting Trials (CONSORT) flow diagram showing patient progress through the study ­phases</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e425" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12871_2026_3719_Fig3_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par20">
<table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Baseline characteristics of study population</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Characteristic</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Group LB(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 44)</th><th align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Group R(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 44)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">t/x<sup>2</sup></th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cohen’s d/φ</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Age</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">47.20 ± 9.39</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">48.32 ± 8.36</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">-0.587</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.558</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.125</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sex, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> (%)</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.409</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.522</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.068</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Male</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">23(52.27)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">20(45.45)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Female</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">21(47.73)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">24(54.55)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Body mass index</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">23.62 ± 2.57</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">24.07 ± 2.92</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">-0.771</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.443</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.164</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">ASA status, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> (%)</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.725</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.189</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.140</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">I</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">20(45.45)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14(31.82)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">II</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">24(54.55)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30(68.18)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">III</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">0(0)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0(0)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Duration of surgery(min)</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">94.98 ± 35.55</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">110.61 ± 21.68</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">-2.491</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.015</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.531</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Fracture Type</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.409</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.815</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.068</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">43-A(simple)</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">23(52.27%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">20(45.45%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">43-B(wedge)</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">14(31.82%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16(36.36%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">43-C(complex)</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">7(15.91%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8(18.18%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>ASA status: The classification standard of the American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA); continuous variables expressed as mean ± standard deviation (such as age, BMI, duration of surgery); categorical variables expressed as number of cases (percentage) (such as gender, ASA classification). Fracture classification according to OTA/AO system: 43-A = extra-articular simple fracture; 43-B = partial articular fracture (wedge); 43-C = complete articular fracture (complex)</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par21">The longitudinal profile of postoperative pain, analyzed using GEE, revealed a significant Time × Group interaction effect (Wald χ² =35.657, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001), indicating that the pattern of pain relief over time differed between the two treatment groups. Group LB reported higher median pain scores at T1 compared to Group R [4.5 (4–5) vs. 4 (3–5); <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001]. Subsequently, Group LB demonstrated statistically significant and clinically relevant superior analgesia at T2[2 (2–3) vs. 3.5 (3–4); <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001], T3 [1 (1–2) vs. 2 (2-2.75); <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.007], and T4 [0 (0–1) vs. 1 (0–1); <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.042]. Significant main effects for both Time (Wald χ² = 1165.594, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001) and Group (Wald χ² = 4.526, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.033) were also observed. (Table <xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref>)</p><p id="Par22">
<table-wrap id="Tab2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Postoperative pain scores between groups</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Group LB</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Group <italic toggle="yes">R</italic></th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Wald χ<sup>2</sup></th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>
</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">T1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.5(4,5)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4(3,5)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10.690</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.001</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">T2</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2(2,3)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.5(3,4)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">19.831</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.001</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">T3</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1(1,2)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2(2,2.75)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.154</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.007</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">T4</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0(0,1)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1(0,1)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.152</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.042</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Wald X<sup>2</sup></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">808.431</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">463.529</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>
</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.001</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.001</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Group effect</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Wald χ<sup>2</sup> = 4.526, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.033</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Time effect</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Wald χ<sup>2</sup> = 1165.594, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Group*Time interaction effect</td><td align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Wald χ<sup>2</sup> = 35.657, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>Data presented as median [interquartile range] for descriptive purposes; T1, T2, T3, T4: 6, 24, 48, and 72 h postoperatively</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par23">No significant intergroup differences were observed in total perioperative opioid utilization, including intraoperative sufentanil consumption, postoperative rescue doses in PACU, and the number of PCIA demand attempts. Notably, Group LB demonstrated a clinically meaningful reduction in Postoperative Hospital Stay (7.84 ± 3.82 vs. 9.77 ± 3.88 days; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.021). Functional recovery, as quantified by the Barthel Index, revealed comparable baseline functional status at admission (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.139). However, Group LB achieved superior functional recovery at discharge (42.73 ± 5.85 vs. 39.43 ± 7.09; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.02). All patients achieved a complete sensory block. There was no significant difference in sensory block onset time between group LB and group R (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.301). No surgery was delayed due to inadequate block onset (Table <xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref>).</p><p id="Par24">
<table-wrap id="Tab3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>Results of comparing secondary outcomes measures between groups</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Outcome Measures</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Group LB(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 44)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Group R(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 44)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">t/x<sup>2</sup></th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cohen’s d/φ</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">perioperative opioid use</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">194.64 ± 8.09</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">197.82 ± 12.82</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">-1.392</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.168</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.297</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">During operation (µg)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">44.41 ± 7.95</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">47.22 ± 13.19</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">-1.208</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.230</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.257</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">PACU rescue (n, %)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1(2.27)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3(6.82)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.262</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.711</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.172</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">PCIA demands (n, %)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3(6.28)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8(18.18)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.597</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.107</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.109</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">the Barthel Index</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">At admission</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">37.39 ± 5.86</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">35.34 ± 6.94</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.494</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.139</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.319</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">At discharge</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">42.73 ± 5.85</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">39.43 ± 7.09</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.378</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.020</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.507</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">hospitalization duration (days)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.84 ± 3.82</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9.77 ± 3.88</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">-2.353</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.021</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.502</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sensory block onset time(mins)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">22.66 ± 6.41</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21.23 ± 6.49</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.041</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.301</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.222</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>Data expressed as number (%) or mean ± SD </p><p><italic toggle="yes">VAS</italic> Visual Analog Scale, <italic toggle="yes">PACU</italic> post anesthesia care unit, <italic toggle="yes">PCIA</italic> patient-controlled intravenous analgesia</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par25">To control for potential confounding factors, we performed a multiple linear regression analysis that included operative duration, fracture type (with type C as the reference), and treatment group in the model. The results demonstrated that after adjusting for these variables, the group LB remained a significant independent predictor of both the 24-hour VAS score (β = -0.467, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001) and the Barthel Index (β = 0.361, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.008). Neither operative duration nor fracture type were significantly associated with the outcomes(<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &gt; 0.05), indicating that the treatment effect is an independent factor influencing postoperative pain and recovery.</p><p id="Par26">No loss of active ankle dorsiflexion or plantarflexion was observed in any patient in either group during the 72-hour postoperative follow-up. Complication analysis showed transient sensory abnormalities in 17 participants (Group LB: 22.73% vs. Group R: 15.91%), all resolving within 24 h. PONV rates were 11.36% (Group LB) and 6.82% (Group R). Serious adverse events included one delayed union requiring revision (Group LB) and one persistent thermohypesthesia with 50% symptom resolution by day 7 (Group R). No motor blockade or group differences in overall complication rates were observed. (Table <xref rid="Tab4" ref-type="table">4</xref>).</p><p id="Par27">
<table-wrap id="Tab4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4</label><caption><p>Postoperative Complications</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Group LB(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 44)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Group R(<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 44)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">φ</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">PONV, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic>(%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5(11.36)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3(6.82)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.711</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.079</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Leg numbness, <italic toggle="yes">n</italic>(%)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10(22.73)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7(15.91)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.418</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.086</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p><italic toggle="yes">PONV</italic> postoperative nausea and vomiting</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par28">For patients with lower leg fractures, postoperative acute pain management remains a critical challenge. Although the ultrasound-guided anterior approach to sciatic nerve block offers practical advantages [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>] and liposomal bupivacaine is increasingly used clinically, [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>] high-quality evidence regarding the efficacy and safety of liposomal bupivacaine administered via this route remains limited. Therefore, this randomized controlled trial aimed to evaluate LB in ultrasound-guided anterior approach sciatic nerve block for postoperative pain management following lower-leg fracture surgery.</p><p id="Par29">This randomized controlled trial demonstrated that, in patients undergoing lower leg fracture surgery, an ultrasound-guided anterior sciatic nerve block with liposomal bupivacaine provided prolonged postoperative analgesia, associated with improved functional recovery at discharge and shorter hospital stay compared with ropivacaine. This is the first RCT to investigate the combination of the ultrasound-guided anterior sciatic nerve block with liposomal bupivacaine specifically for lower leg fracture surgery, addressing an evidence gap regarding the efficacy and safety of this long-acting formulation administered via this particular anatomical approach.</p><p id="Par30">The longitudinal profile of postoperative VAS scores exhibited a distinct biphasic pattern. Although Group LB demonstrated higher pain scores at 6 h postoperatively, it achieved significantly lower scores at 24, 48, and 72 h. This pattern aligns with the known pharmacokinetics of liposomal bupivacaine, which is characterized by a delayed peak effect due to its sustained-release mechanism while maintaining extended plasma concentrations. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>] These observations are consistent with those reported by Hamilton et al., [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>] who noted comparable or even inferior early analgesia with liposomal bupivacaine compared with conventional agents, likely attributable to its biphasic release properties. Therefore, the early analgesic gap highlights a clinically relevant consideration: to fully exploit the prolonged analgesic benefits of liposomal bupivacaine, a proactive supplemental strategy during the initial postoperative hours is warranted. This may include bridging with oral analgesics (acetaminophen or NSAIDs). For more comprehensive coverage, particularly in surgeries involving the lower limb, combining the sciatic nerve block with a femoral nerve block could be considered.</p><p id="Par31">The observed reduction in postoperative hospital duration and the superior Barthel Index at discharge in Group LB are clinically meaningful secondary outcomes that likely stem from the improved quality of sustained analgesia. Better pain control during the postoperative period may facilitate earlier mobilization and participation in rehabilitation, thereby accelerating functional recovery. These findings align with previous studies by Cherian et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>] and Chughtai et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>], which highlighted LB’s efficacy in reducing opioid consumption and enhancing recovery in joint arthroplasty, suggesting its broad applicability in diverse surgical settings. Notably, these benefits were achieved without an increase in total perioperative opioid consumption or in the incidence of opioid-related adverse events, suggesting that liposomal bupivacaine can enhance recovery without exacerbating opioid-related risks.</p><p id="Par32">The anterior approach utilized in this study simplified patient positioning and landmark identification, avoiding the need for lateral decubitus positioning required in traditional posterior approaches—a practical advantage in fracture patients. No motor blockade or serious nerve-related complications were observed, aligning with previous safety reports of sciatic nerve blocks in lower extremity surgery. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>] The transient sensory abnormalities reported were self-limiting and comparable between groups, reinforcing the procedural safety when performed under ultrasound guidance.</p><p id="Par33">It is noteworthy that, despite comparable fracture complexity, a statistically significant difference in operative duration was observed between groups. However, multiple linear regression analysis indicated that the superior analgesia and functional recovery in the group LB were primarily attributable to the intervention itself.</p><p id="Par34">The present findings have several limitations that warrant consideration. First, this was a single-center study, which may affect the generalizability of findings. Second, the sciatic nerve block was not combined with a femoral nerve block; given the dual innervation of the lower leg, a combined approach might have provided more comprehensive analgesia, particularly in the early postoperative period. Notably, a meta-analysis [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>] demonstrates that combined nerve blocks significantly reduce postoperative resting pain scores, suggesting that a combined femoral-sciatic nerve block approach may achieve more comprehensive analgesia for patients with lower leg fractures. Third, this study did not include a formal cost-effectiveness analysis. While the observed reduction in hospital stay with liposomal bupivacaine suggests potential economic benefits, future studies incorporating detailed cost data are needed to fully evaluate its economic value. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>] Fourth, the follow-up period was limited to 72 h, precluding assessment of potential late complications or chronic neuropathic outcomes. Fifth, the exclusion of patients with a BMI &gt; 30 kg/m² limits the generalizability of our findings, particularly as obesity represents a growing proportion of the surgical population. Further studies are needed to evaluate the feasibility of this anterior approach in obese patients. Additionally, the continuous administration of a potent opioid (sufentanil) via PCIA in the postoperative period may have attenuated the observable difference in pain scores attributable solely to the nerve block, thereby potentially obscuring the independent analgesic effect of the intervention.</p><p id="Par35">The clinical utility of liposomal bupivacaine also remains a point of discussion. While its prolonged efficacy in major joint arthroplasty is established [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>] our findings confirm that it provides superior prolonged analgesia compared to ropivacaine. However, several limitations of the present study must be acknowledged. Future high-quality randomized controlled trials focusing on lower leg fracture populations should consider conducting multicenter studies with enlarged sample sizes. These trials should incorporate broader patient populations, including those with higher BMI, and extend the observation period to assess long-term complications and safety. Regarding clinical application, further investigation is warranted to evaluate the efficacy and cost-effectiveness profile of combined nerve block regimens that incorporate liposomal bupivacaine.</p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Conclusions</title><p id="Par36">Compared to ropivacaine, liposomal bupivacaine administered via the ultrasound-guided anterior sciatic nerve block approach provided superior postoperative analgesia with a prolonged duration, which was associated with improved functional recovery and reduced hospital stay in patients undergoing lower leg fracture surgery. </p></sec><sec id="Sec11" sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="12871_2026_3719_MOESM1_ESM.docx" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Supplementary Material 1.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="12871_2026_3719_MOESM2_ESM.doc" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Supplementary Material 2.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher’s note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn><fn><p>Yue Li and Libin Zhao contributed equally to this work.</p></fn></fn-group><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>We sincerely thank the anesthesiology team for their expertise and support.</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Authors’ contributions</title><p>Li Zhan designed experiments; Yue Li, Libin Zhao, Xinyi Shen, and Bin Chai performed experiments; Yue Li, Libin Zhao analyzed the data. Yue Li, Libin Zhao and Li Zhan wrote the manuscript. All authors reviewed the manuscript. Li Zhan acts as guarantor.</p></notes><notes notes-type="funding-information"><title>Funding</title><p>This work was supported by Research Grant of Key Laboratory of Anesthesiology and Resuscitation (Huazhong University of Science and Technology), Ministry of Education No.4; the Science and Technology Bureau of Lu’an City(2024lakj008).</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>All data generated or analysed during this study are included in this published article.</p></notes><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar3"><title>Ethics approval and consent to participate</title><p id="Par37">This trial was approved by the Ethics Committee of Lu’an Hospital (No. 2024LL003). Written informed consent was obtained from all participants. All procedures were performed in accordance with the ethical standards laid down in the 1964 Declaration of Helsinki and its later amendments.</p></notes><notes id="FPar4"><title>Consent for publication</title><p id="Par38">Not applicable.</p></notes><notes id="FPar5" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par39">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes></notes><glossary><title>Abbreviations</title><def-list><def-item><term>ORIF</term><def><p id="Par40">Open reduction and internal fixation</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>PCIA</term><def><p id="Par41">Patient-controlled intravenous analgesia</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>SNB</term><def><p id="Par42">Sciatic nerve block</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>BMI</term><def><p id="Par43">Body mass index</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>ECG</term><def><p id="Par44">Electrocardiogram</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>SpO2</term><def><p id="Par45">Oxygen saturation</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>BIS</term><def><p id="Par46">Bispectral index</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>PACU</term><def><p id="Par47">Post-anesthesia care unit</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>VAS</term><def><p id="Par48">Visual Analog Scale</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>PCA</term><def><p id="Par49">Patient-controlled analgesia</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>ASA status</term><def><p id="Par50">The classification standard of the American society of anesthesiologists</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>ADL</term><def><p id="Par51">Activities of daily living</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>PONV</term><def><p id="Par52">Postoperative nausea and vomiting</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>RCT</term><def><p id="Par53">Randomized controlled trial</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>LB</term><def><p id="Par54">Liposomal bupivacaine</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>SD</term><def><p id="Par55">Standard deviations</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>IQR</term><def><p id="Par56">Interquartile range</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>MD</term><def><p id="Par57">Mean difference</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>GEE</term><def><p id="Par58">Generalized Estimating Equations</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>NIBP</term><def><p id="Par59">Non-invasive blood pressure</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>RASS</term><def><p id="Par60">Richmond Agitation-Sedation Scale</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>ITT</term><def><p id="Par61">Intention-to-treat</p></def></def-item></def-list></glossary><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR1" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Carter</surname><given-names>TH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Duckworth</surname><given-names>AD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Oliver</surname><given-names>WM</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Open Reduction and Internal Fixation of Distal Tibial Pilon Fractures</article-title><source>JBJS Essent Surg Tech</source><year>2019</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>e29</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2106/JBJS.ST.18.00093</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32021729</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6948997</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR1" publication-type="journal">Carter TH, Duckworth AD, Oliver WM, et al. Open Reduction and Internal Fixation of Distal Tibial Pilon Fractures. JBJS Essent Surg Tech. 2019;9:e29.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32021729</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2106/JBJS.ST.18.00093</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6948997</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR2" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Frodl</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Erdle</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schmal</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Osteosynthesis or non-operative treatment of the fibula for distal lower-leg fractures with tibial nailing: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>EFORT Open Rev</source><year>2021</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>816</fpage><lpage>22</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1302/2058-5241.6.210003</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34667653</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8489479</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR2" publication-type="journal">Frodl A, Erdle B, Schmal H. Osteosynthesis or non-operative treatment of the fibula for distal lower-leg fractures with tibial nailing: a systematic review and meta-analysis. EFORT Open Rev. 2021;6:816–22.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34667653</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1302/2058-5241.6.210003</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8489479</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR3" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Charlebois</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cain</surname><given-names>EL</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Effect of fibular plate fixation on rotational stability of simulated distal tibial fractures treated with intramedullary nailing</article-title><source>J Bone Joint Surg Am</source><year>2003</year><volume>85</volume><fpage>604</fpage><lpage>8</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2106/00004623-200304000-00003</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12672833</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR3" publication-type="journal">Kumar A, Charlebois SJ, Cain EL, et al. Effect of fibular plate fixation on rotational stability of simulated distal tibial fractures treated with intramedullary nailing. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2003;85:604–8.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12672833</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2106/00004623-200304000-00003</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR4" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>JQ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>ZX</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>WJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Comparison of plate and intramedullary nail fixation of extra-articular tibial fractures: A retrospective study exploring hidden blood loss</article-title><source>Injury</source><year>2019</year><volume>50</volume><fpage>546</fpage><lpage>50</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.injury.2018.12.016</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30580930</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR4" publication-type="journal">Wang JQ, Chen ZX, Guo WJ, et al. Comparison of plate and intramedullary nail fixation of extra-articular tibial fractures: A retrospective study exploring hidden blood loss. Injury. 2019;50:546–50.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30580930</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.injury.2018.12.016</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR5" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Elhence</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jalan</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Talreja</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>To fix or not to fix? The role of fibular fixation in distal shaft fractures of the leg</article-title><source>Injury</source><year>2014</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>1802</fpage><lpage>3</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.injury.2014.02.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24671008</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR5" publication-type="journal">Elhence A, Jalan D, Talreja H. To fix or not to fix? The role of fibular fixation in distal shaft fractures of the leg. Injury. 2014;45:1802–3.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24671008</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.injury.2014.02.004</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR6" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Qiu</surname><given-names>GX</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pei</surname><given-names>FX</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>PF</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Clinical practice guidelines for common pain management in orthopedics (2018 Edition) [in Chinese]</article-title><source>Chin J Orthop Joint Surg</source><year>2019</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>161</fpage><lpage>7</lpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR6" publication-type="journal">Qiu GX, Pei FX, Tang PF, et al. Clinical practice guidelines for common pain management in orthopedics (2018 Edition) [in Chinese]. Chin J Orthop Joint Surg. 2019;12:161–7.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR7" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Moayeri</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>van Geffen</surname><given-names>GJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bruhn</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Correlation among ultrasound, cross-sectional anatomy, and histology of the sciatic nerve: a review</article-title><source>Reg Anesth Pain Med</source><year>2010</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>442</fpage><lpage>9</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/AAP.0b013e3181ef4cab</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20814285</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR7" publication-type="journal">Moayeri N, van Geffen GJ, Bruhn J, et al. Correlation among ultrasound, cross-sectional anatomy, and histology of the sciatic nerve: a review. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2010;35:442–9.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20814285</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/AAP.0b013e3181ef4cab</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR8" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Abdallah</surname><given-names>FW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chan</surname><given-names>VW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gandhi</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The analgesic effects of proximal, distal, or no sciatic nerve block on posterior knee pain after total knee arthroplasty: a double-blind placebo-controlled randomized trial</article-title><source>Anesthesiology</source><year>2014</year><volume>121</volume><fpage>1302</fpage><lpage>10</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/ALN.0000000000000406</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25099748</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR8" publication-type="journal">Abdallah FW, Chan VW, Gandhi R, et al. The analgesic effects of proximal, distal, or no sciatic nerve block on posterior knee pain after total knee arthroplasty: a double-blind placebo-controlled randomized trial. Anesthesiology. 2014;121:1302–10.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25099748</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/ALN.0000000000000406</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR9" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><collab>BECK GP</collab></person-group><article-title>Anterior approach to sciatic nerve block</article-title><source>Anesthesiology</source><year>1963</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>222</fpage><lpage>4</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/00000542-196303000-00011</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13970060</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR9" publication-type="journal">BECK GP. Anterior approach to sciatic nerve block. Anesthesiology. 1963;24:222–4.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13970060</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/00000542-196303000-00011</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR10" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ota</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sakura</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hara</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Ultrasound-guided anterior approach to sciatic nerve block: a comparison with the posterior approach</article-title><source>Anesth Analg</source><year>2009</year><volume>108</volume><fpage>660</fpage><lpage>5</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1213/ane.0b013e31818fc252</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19151305</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR10" publication-type="journal">Ota J, Sakura S, Hara K, et al. Ultrasound-guided anterior approach to sciatic nerve block: a comparison with the posterior approach. Anesth Analg. 2009;108:660–5.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19151305</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1213/ane.0b013e31818fc252</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR11" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>McClellan</surname><given-names>KJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Faulds</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Ropivacaine: an update of its use in regional anaesthesia</article-title><source>Drugs</source><year>2000</year><volume>60</volume><fpage>1065</fpage><lpage>93</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2165/00003495-200060050-00007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11129123</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR11" publication-type="journal">McClellan KJ, Faulds D. Ropivacaine: an update of its use in regional anaesthesia. Drugs. 2000;60:1065–93.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11129123</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2165/00003495-200060050-00007</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR12" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ilfeld</surname><given-names>BM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Eisenach</surname><given-names>JC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gabriel</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Clinical Effectiveness of Liposomal Bupivacaine Administered by Infiltration or Peripheral Nerve Block to Treat Postoperative Pain</article-title><source>Anesthesiology</source><year>2021</year><volume>134</volume><fpage>283</fpage><lpage>344</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/ALN.0000000000003630</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33372949</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR12" publication-type="journal">Ilfeld BM, Eisenach JC, Gabriel RA. Clinical Effectiveness of Liposomal Bupivacaine Administered by Infiltration or Peripheral Nerve Block to Treat Postoperative Pain. Anesthesiology. 2021;134:283–344.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33372949</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/ALN.0000000000003630</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR13" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Domb</surname><given-names>BG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gupta</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hammarstedt</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The effect of liposomal bupivacaine injection during total hip arthroplasty: a controlled cohort study</article-title><source>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</source><year>2014</year><volume>15</volume><fpage>310</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/1471-2474-15-310</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25248686</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4190483</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR13" publication-type="journal">Domb BG, Gupta A, Hammarstedt JE, et al. The effect of liposomal bupivacaine injection during total hip arthroplasty: a controlled cohort study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2014;15:310.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25248686</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/1471-2474-15-310</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4190483</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR14" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Emerson</surname><given-names>RH</given-names><suffix>Jr</suffix></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Barrington</surname><given-names>JW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Olugbode</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Femoral Nerve Block Versus Long-Acting Wound Infiltration in Total Knee Arthroplasty</article-title><source>Orthopedics</source><year>2016</year><volume>39</volume><fpage>e449</fpage><lpage>55</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3928/01477447-20160315-03</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27018607</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR14" publication-type="journal">Emerson RH Jr, Barrington JW, Olugbode O, et al. Femoral Nerve Block Versus Long-Acting Wound Infiltration in Total Knee Arthroplasty. Orthopedics. 2016;39:e449–55.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27018607</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3928/01477447-20160315-03</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR15" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Heim</surname><given-names>EA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Grier</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Butler</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Use of Liposomal Bupivacaine Instead of an Epidural Can Improve Outcomes Following Total Knee Arthroplasty</article-title><source>J Surg Orthop Adv</source><year>2015</year><volume>24</volume><fpage>230</fpage><lpage>4</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26731386</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR15" publication-type="journal">Heim EA, Grier AJ, Butler RJ, et al. Use of Liposomal Bupivacaine Instead of an Epidural Can Improve Outcomes Following Total Knee Arthroplasty. J Surg Orthop Adv. 2015;24:230–4.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26731386</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR16" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Purcell</surname><given-names>RL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Brooks</surname><given-names>DI</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Steelman</surname><given-names>TJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Fascia Iliaca Blockade With the Addition of Liposomal Bupivacaine Versus Plain Bupivacaine for Perioperative Pain Management During Hip Arthroscopy: A Double-Blinded Prospective Randomized Control Trial</article-title><source>Arthroscopy</source><year>2019</year><volume>35</volume><fpage>2608</fpage><lpage>16</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2019.03.056</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31402223</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR16" publication-type="journal">Purcell RL, Brooks DI, Steelman TJ, et al. Fascia Iliaca Blockade With the Addition of Liposomal Bupivacaine Versus Plain Bupivacaine for Perioperative Pain Management During Hip Arthroscopy: A Double-Blinded Prospective Randomized Control Trial. Arthroscopy. 2019;35:2608–16.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31402223</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.arthro.2019.03.056</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR17" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Golf</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Daniels</surname><given-names>SE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Onel</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A phase 3, randomized, placebo-controlled trial of DepoFoam<sup>®</sup> bupivacaine (extended-release bupivacaine local analgesic) in bunionectomy</article-title><source>Adv Ther</source><year>2011</year><volume>28</volume><fpage>776</fpage><lpage>88</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12325-011-0052-y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21842428</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR17" publication-type="journal">Golf M, Daniels SE, Onel E. A phase 3, randomized, placebo-controlled trial of DepoFoam<sup>®</sup> bupivacaine (extended-release bupivacaine local analgesic) in bunionectomy. Adv Ther. 2011;28:776–88.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21842428</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s12325-011-0052-y</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR18" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Robbins</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Green</surname><given-names>CL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Parekh</surname><given-names>SG</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Liposomal bupivacaine in forefoot surgery</article-title><source>Foot Ankle Int</source><year>2015</year><volume>36</volume><fpage>503</fpage><lpage>7</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/1071100714568664</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25614060</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR18" publication-type="journal">Robbins J, Green CL, Parekh SG. Liposomal bupivacaine in forefoot surgery. Foot Ankle Int. 2015;36:503–7.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25614060</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/1071100714568664</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR19" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chitty</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ridley</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Liposomal compared to 0.25% bupivacaine in patients undergoing hemorrhoidectomy: A pre- and post-implementation quality improvement evaluation</article-title><source>J Clin Anesth</source><year>2022</year><volume>80</volume><fpage>110868</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jclinane.2022.110868</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35500430</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR19" publication-type="journal">Chitty L, Ridley B, Johnson B, et al. Liposomal compared to 0.25% bupivacaine in patients undergoing hemorrhoidectomy: A pre- and post-implementation quality improvement evaluation. J Clin Anesth. 2022;80:110868.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35500430</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jclinane.2022.110868</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR20" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hjermstad</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fayers</surname><given-names>PM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Haugen</surname><given-names>DF</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Studies comparing Numerical Rating Scales, Verbal Rating Scales, and Visual Analogue Scales for assessment of pain intensity in adults: a systematic literature review</article-title><source>J Pain Symptom Manage</source><year>2011</year><volume>41</volume><fpage>1073</fpage><lpage>93</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2010.08.016</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21621130</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR20" publication-type="journal">Hjermstad MJ, Fayers PM, Haugen DF, et al. Studies comparing Numerical Rating Scales, Verbal Rating Scales, and Visual Analogue Scales for assessment of pain intensity in adults: a systematic literature review. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2011;41:1073–93.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21621130</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2010.08.016</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR21" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Collin</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wade</surname><given-names>DT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Davies</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The Barthel ADL Index: a reliability study</article-title><source>Int Disabil Stud</source><year>1988</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>61</fpage><lpage>3</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3109/09638288809164103</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3403500</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR21" publication-type="journal">Collin C, Wade DT, Davies S, et al. The Barthel ADL Index: a reliability study. Int Disabil Stud. 1988;10:61–3.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3403500</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3109/09638288809164103</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR22" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chevrollier</surname><given-names>GS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Klinger</surname><given-names>AL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Green</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Liposomal Bupivacaine Transversus Abdominis Plane Blocks in Laparoscopic Colorectal Resections: A Single-Institution Randomized Controlled Trial</article-title><source>Dis Colon Rectum</source><year>2023</year><volume>66</volume><fpage>322</fpage><lpage>30</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/DCR.0000000000002346</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35849756</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR22" publication-type="journal">Chevrollier GS, Klinger AL, Green HJ, et al. Liposomal Bupivacaine Transversus Abdominis Plane Blocks in Laparoscopic Colorectal Resections: A Single-Institution Randomized Controlled Trial. Dis Colon Rectum. 2023;66:322–30.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35849756</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/DCR.0000000000002346</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR23" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cherian</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Barrington</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Elmallah</surname><given-names>RK</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Liposomal Bupivacaine Suspension, Can Reduce Length of Stay and Improve Discharge Status of Patients Undergoing Total Hip Arthroplasty</article-title><source>Surg Technol Int</source><year>2015</year><volume>27</volume><fpage>235</fpage><lpage>9</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26680403</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR23" publication-type="journal">Cherian JJ, Barrington J, Elmallah RK, et al. Liposomal Bupivacaine Suspension, Can Reduce Length of Stay and Improve Discharge Status of Patients Undergoing Total Hip Arthroplasty. Surg Technol Int. 2015;27:235–9.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26680403</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR24" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Onel</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Singla</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Pharmacokinetic profile of liposome bupivacaine injection following a single administration at the surgical site</article-title><source>Clin Drug Investig</source><year>2013</year><volume>33</volume><fpage>109</fpage><lpage>15</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s40261-012-0043-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23229686</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR24" publication-type="journal">Hu D, Onel E, Singla N, et al. Pharmacokinetic profile of liposome bupivacaine injection following a single administration at the surgical site. Clin Drug Investig. 2013;33:109–15.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23229686</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s40261-012-0043-z</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR25" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hamilton</surname><given-names>TW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Knight</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Stokes</surname><given-names>JR</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Efficacy of Liposomal Bupivacaine and Bupivacaine Hydrochloride vs Bupivacaine Hydrochloride Alone as a Periarticular Anesthetic for Patients Undergoing Knee Replacement: A Randomized Clinical Trial</article-title><source>JAMA Surg</source><year>2022</year><volume>157</volume><fpage>481</fpage><lpage>9</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jamasurg.2022.0713</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35385072</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8988023</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR25" publication-type="journal">Hamilton TW, Knight R, Stokes JR, et al. Efficacy of Liposomal Bupivacaine and Bupivacaine Hydrochloride vs Bupivacaine Hydrochloride Alone as a Periarticular Anesthetic for Patients Undergoing Knee Replacement: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Surg. 2022;157:481–9.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35385072</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1001/jamasurg.2022.0713</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8988023</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR26" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chughtai</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cherian</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mistry</surname><given-names>JB</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Liposomal Bupivacaine Suspension Can Reduce Lengths of Stay and Improve Discharge Status of Patients Undergoing Total Knee Arthroplasty</article-title><source>J Knee Surg</source><year>2016</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>224</fpage><lpage>7</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1055/s-0036-1571431</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26838971</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR26" publication-type="journal">Chughtai M, Cherian JJ, Mistry JB, et al. Liposomal Bupivacaine Suspension Can Reduce Lengths of Stay and Improve Discharge Status of Patients Undergoing Total Knee Arthroplasty. J Knee Surg. 2016;29:224–7.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26838971</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1055/s-0036-1571431</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR27" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mulligan</surname><given-names>RP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Morash</surname><given-names>JG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>DeOrio</surname><given-names>JK</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Liposomal Bupivacaine Versus Continuous Popliteal Sciatic Nerve Block in Total Ankle Arthroplasty</article-title><source>Foot Ankle Int</source><year>2017</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>1222</fpage><lpage>8</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/1071100717722366</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28786304</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR27" publication-type="journal">Mulligan RP, Morash JG, DeOrio JK, et al. Liposomal Bupivacaine Versus Continuous Popliteal Sciatic Nerve Block in Total Ankle Arthroplasty. Foot Ankle Int. 2017;38:1222–8.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28786304</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/1071100717722366</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR28" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Grape</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kirkham</surname><given-names>KR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baeriswyl</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The analgesic efficacy of sciatic nerve block in addition to femoral nerve block in patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>Anaesthesia</source><year>2016</year><volume>71</volume><fpage>1198</fpage><lpage>209</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/anae.13568</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27469381</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR28" publication-type="journal">Grape S, Kirkham KR, Baeriswyl M, et al. The analgesic efficacy of sciatic nerve block in addition to femoral nerve block in patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Anaesthesia. 2016;71:1198–209.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27469381</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/anae.13568</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR29" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kirkness</surname><given-names>CS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Asche</surname><given-names>CV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Cost-benefit evaluation of liposomal bupivacaine in the management of patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty</article-title><source>Am J Health Syst Pharm</source><year>2016</year><volume>73</volume><fpage>e247</fpage><lpage>54</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2146/ajhp150332</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27099332</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR29" publication-type="journal">Kirkness CS, Asche CV, Ren J, et al. Cost-benefit evaluation of liposomal bupivacaine in the management of patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty. Am J Health Syst Pharm. 2016;73:e247–54.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27099332</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2146/ajhp150332</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>