<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">BMC Musculoskelet Disord</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">BMC Musculoskelet Disord</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">46</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">bmcmudis</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>BMC Musculoskeletal Disorders</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">1471-2474</issn><publisher><publisher-name>BMC</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC13020331</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC13020331.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">13020331</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">13020331</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41703548</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12891-026-09638-8</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">9638</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Recovery outcomes for military personnel undergoing surgery for lumbar spinal stenosis induced by physical overload: a retrospective study</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Melenko</surname><given-names initials="V">Vasyl</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kravchuk</surname><given-names initials="L">Lyudmila</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Nozdrenko</surname><given-names initials="D">Dmytro</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Maznychenko</surname><given-names initials="A">Andriy</given-names></name><address><email>maznychenko@biph.kiev.ua</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Abramovych</surname><given-names initials="T">Tetiana</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sokolowska</surname><given-names initials="I">Inna</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Fishchenko</surname><given-names initials="I">Iakіv</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/042dnf796</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.419973.1</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 9534 1405</institution-id><institution>Department of Spinal Surgery, State Institution “Institute of Traumatology and Orthopedics”, </institution><institution>National Academy of Medical Science of Ukraine, </institution></institution-wrap>Bulvarno-Kudriavska Str. 27, Kyiv, 01054 Ukraine </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/02aaqv166</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.34555.32</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0385 8248</institution-id><institution>Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv, ESC “Institute of Biology and Medicine”, </institution></institution-wrap>Volodymyrska Str. 64, Kyiv, 01601 Ukraine </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/01r6bzv07</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.417551.3</institution-id><institution>Department of Movement Physiology, </institution><institution>Bogomoletz Institute of Physiology, </institution></institution-wrap>Bogomoletz Str. 4, Kyiv, 01024 Ukraine </aff><aff id="Aff4"><label>4</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/03rq9c547</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.445131.6</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0001 1359 8636</institution-id><institution>Gdansk University of Physical Education and Sport, </institution></institution-wrap>Kazimierza Górskiego Str. 1, Gdańsk, 80-336 Poland </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>17</day><month>2</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2026</year></pub-date><volume>27</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">503907</issue-id><elocation-id>245</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>16</day><month>1</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>13</day><month>2</month><year>2026</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>17</day><month>02</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>27</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-03-27 10:25:15.507"><day>27</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>© The Author(s) 2026</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2026</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License, which permits any non-commercial use, sharing, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if you modified the licensed material. You do not have permission under this licence to share adapted material derived from this article or parts of it. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article’s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article’s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="12891_2026_Article_9638.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1" abstract-type="structured"><sec><title>Background</title><p id="Par1">Servicemen are at high risk for musculoskeletal injuries, particularly lumbar spinal stenosis (LSS), due to the physical demands of combat and training. LSS often leads to significant disability, impacting soldiers’ quality of life and operational readiness. Surgical intervention is frequently needed, but the optimal technique for military patients remains debated. This study aimed to evaluate the outcomes of different surgical approaches for treating LSS, unilateral laminectomy for bilateral decompression (ULBD), open decompression, and decompression laminectomy with transpedicular stabilization, in wounded Ukrainian military personnel, focusing on pain relief, functional recovery, and rehabilitation timelines.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p id="Par2">Sixty-four male servicemen (43 ± 4 years) with LSS were divided into three groups according to the surgery type: the servicemen with LSS were divided into three groups according to the surgery type: Group 1 (ULBD), Group 2 (open decompression), and Group 3 (decompression with transpedicular stabilization). Preoperative and postoperative assessments included pain intensity (Visual Analog Scale), quality of life and disability (Oswestry Disability Index), and functional recovery using the International Classification of Functioning, Disability, and Health. Follow-up evaluations were conducted at one week, one month, and six months postsurgery.</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p id="Par3">Postoperative outcomes revealed significant pain reduction across all groups. However, Group 3 patients exhibited slower recovery, with persistent moderate impairments in quality of life and mobility six months postsurgery. In contrast, Groups 1 and 2 demonstrated faster rehabilitation, with minimal impairments by six months. The time to return to duty was notably longer in Group 3 (80.8 ± 20.8 days) than in Group 1 (27.4 ± 15.3 days) and Group 2 (38.4 ± 16.6 days).</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusions</title><p id="Par4">ULBD and open decompression techniques offer faster recovery and better functional outcomes for military personnel with LSS compared to decompression with transpedicular stabilization. These findings suggest that less invasive procedures may be more suitable for military patients requiring a swift return to duty.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>Lumbar spinal stenosis</kwd><kwd>Decompression</kwd><kwd>Spine surgery</kwd><kwd>Servicemen</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>© BioMed Central Ltd., part of Springer Nature 2026</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Background</title><p id="Par13">The professional demands of military personnel are characterized by extreme physical exertion and prolonged performance of high-impact tasks. These challenges significantly increase the risk of musculoskeletal injuries [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. A review of the work of the US Navy Physical Assessment Board over a one-year period revealed that musculoskeletal disorders were the most common medical issues among servicemen, accounting for 43% of cases, with low back pain being the most prevalent at 29%. Specific risk factors for military personnel include constant physical strain from wearing bullet-proof vests and carrying ammunition, psychological trauma, exposure to extreme shock and vibration, heavy combat loads, and injuries sustained during airborne, air assault, and ground operations in urban environments [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. In addition to injuries, low back pain is a leading cause of combat unit exhaustion and disability among servicemen, often resulting in a low rate of return to active duty. Notably, the incidence of low back pain is the lowest among younger soldiers, and it increases with age [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. One severe outcome of such musculoskeletal strain is degenerative lumbar spinal stenosis (LSS), a condition closely associated with hypertrophy and osteophyte formation in intervertebral joints [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>]. Overload and micro-trauma leading to hypertrophy of the spinal joints significantly contribute to narrowing of the spinal canal [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. Furthermore, degeneration of the intervertebral joints results in spinal instability, spondylolisthesis, and impaired mobility [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>]. Evidence from U.S. and international armed forces shows that surgical treatment of lumbar spinal stenosis and related degenerative conditions can substantially influence recovery timelines and return‑to‑duty rates, with minimally invasive decompression techniques generally associated with faster rehabilitation and earlier resumption of military tasks [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. These findings underscore the importance of selecting surgical approaches that balance clinical effectiveness with the need for rapid functional recovery in active‑duty personnel.</p><p id="Par14">Conservative treatment for lumbar spinal stenosis is effective only in the early stages of the disease [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>]. In contrast, surgical intervention becomes necessary in later stages or for patients who do not respond to conservative measures. Traditional laminectomy, as well as less invasive procedures such as unilateral laminectomy for bilateral decompression (ULBD) and decompression laminectomy with transpedicular stabilization, are among the most common surgical strategies for treating LSS [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>]. The severity of the disease and surgical risks, such as infection, hemorrhage, nerve injury, or dura mater injury, largely determine the choice of treatment strategy. However, the efficacy and safety of various surgical approaches for treating LSS remain subjects of ongoing debate [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>].</p><p id="Par15">The purpose of this study was to evaluate the impact of surgical treatment for lumbar spinal stenosis induced by excessive physical loads on the recovery process of middle-aged military personnel from the Armed Forces of Ukraine, using clinical pain assessment, functional disability questionnaires, and radiological evaluation of spinal canal decompression. The study evaluated recovery after different surgical methods (open decompression, ULBD, and decompression laminectomy with transpedicular stabilization techniques, including transforaminal lumbar interbody fusion (TLIF) and posterior lumbar interbody fusion (PLIF)) at short postoperative period of time: one week, one month, and six months postsurgery.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Methods</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Study design and participants</title><p id="Par16">This single-center retrospective study involved 64 servicemen who underwent surgical intervention for lumbar spinal canal stenosis at the Spine Surgery Department of the Spinal (Neurosurgical) Centre, SI “Institute of Traumatology and Orthopedics” in Kyiv NAMS of Ukraine,” between 2023 and 2024. The study was conducted in accordance with the Local Ethics Committee of the Institute and performed in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to their inclusion in the research. The study was conducted in accordance with STROBE guidelines.</p><p id="Par17">The cohort consisted of men with a mean age of 43 ± 4 years and an average BMI of 22.9 ± 1.6. Inclusion criteria: patients were eligible for the study if they were active‑duty servicemen of the Armed Forces of Ukraine with MRI‑confirmed lumbar spinal canal stenosis, accompanied by neurological symptoms consistent with the condition, including radiculopathy and/or neurogenic intermittent claudication. Only individuals who had undergone an adequate course of conservative treatment without clinical improvement were considered for surgical intervention and inclusion in the study. Exclusion criteria: Patients were excluded if they had neurological disorders unrelated to lumbar spinal stenosis that could confound postoperative functional assessment. These conditions included peripheral polyneuropathy and traumatic nerve injuries of the lower extremities (e.g., gunshot‑related nerve damage), confirmed by electroneuromyography (ENMG). Individuals with such conditions were excluded to ensure that postoperative outcomes reflected the effects of spinal decompression rather than unrelated neurological deficits. All patients treated during the study period were male servicemen; no female patients meeting the inclusion criteria presented for surgical treatment. Out of 98 individuals who underwent surgical treatment for lumbar spinal stenosis, 64 met the established inclusion criteria. Postoperative treatment strategies included the prevention of postoperative swelling and scar formation, as well as wearing an orthosis for 21 days and performing therapeutic exercises.</p><p id="Par18">As this was a retrospective study, no randomization was performed. The choice of surgical procedure (ULBD, open decompression, or decompression with transpedicular stabilization) was made individually for each patient based on preoperative MRI findings and the severity of degenerative changes, including facet joint hypertrophy, spondyloarthrosis, and segmental instability. Additional factors considered in the decision-making process included sagittal alignment and the anticipated postoperative mechanical load associated with active military service. In selected cases, decompression with transpedicular stabilization was extended to adjacent levels to reduce the risk of postoperative instability or adjacent segment degeneration, particularly in patients exposed to sustained high physical demands. Thus, surgical allocation reflected clinical indications rather than random assignment.</p><p id="Par19">In cases where adequate decompression required facet resection exceeding 50%, the risk of iatrogenic instability was considered clinically significant. While such risk may be acceptable in low‑demand civilian populations, it is substantially amplified in active‑duty servicemen who routinely carry loads ≥ 35 kg and are exposed to repetitive high‑impact activities.</p><p id="Par20">Fusion was therefore indicated only when these structural or biomechanical factors were present, including: (1) radiographic segmental instability on flexion–extension views; (2) advanced facet joint degeneration or spondyloarthrosis; (3) severe foraminal stenosis requiring extensive facet removal; (4) adjacent‑segment degeneration increasing the likelihood of postoperative mechanical failure; and (5) sagittal imbalance not correctable with decompression alone. In such cases, transpedicular stabilization was selected to ensure durable postoperative stability under military occupational demands.</p><p id="Par21">The participants were divided into three groups based on the type of surgery they underwent:<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p id="Par22">Group 1 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 21): Patients in this group underwent endoscopic decompression (ULBD) at various levels: L3–L4 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 7), L4–L5 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 12), and L5–S1 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 2).</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par23">Group 2 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 19): Patients in this group underwent open decompression at the levels of L3–L4 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 6), L4–L5 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 5), and L5–S1 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 8).</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par24">Group 3 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 24): Patients in this group underwent decompression laminectomy with transpedicular stabilization at the levels of L4–L5 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 4), L5–S1 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 4), L3–L4–L5 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 3), and L4–L5–S1 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 3). This group also included 6 patients with interbody cage placement: PLIF L4–L5 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 3), L5–S1 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 2), TLIF L4–L5 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 3), L5–S1 (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 2).</p></list-item></list></p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Measurements and assessments</title><p id="Par25">The cross-sectional area of the spinal canal was measured using T2 MR images at the level of the middle of the disc in the affected segment via the Radiant Dicom software for Windows. Examples of pre- and postoperative MRI scans for the different groups are shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>. Decompression results were assessed using pre- and postoperative MRI (1 day after surgery).</p><p id="Par26">
<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><p>Examples of pre- and postoperative MRI scans of the spinal canal for various surgical cases. Cross-sectional images were obtained using the Radiant Dicom Viewer program. <bold>A</bold>, <bold>B</bold> Views before and after UBLD, respectively. <bold>C</bold>, <bold>D</bold> Views before and after open decompression, respectively. <bold>E</bold>, <bold>F</bold> Views before and after decompression laminectomy with transpedicular stabilization, respectively. In the fusion case, multilevel stabilization was performed due to radiographic evidence of adjacent‑segment degeneration and biomechanical considerations, including sagittal balance and the anticipated high postoperative physical load associated with active military service. Extending the fusion construct was indicated to ensure adequate long‑term stability. Lines (in yellow) indicate the areas of surgical intervention</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e456" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12891_2026_9638_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par27">The severity of the pain syndrome was assessed using a visual analog pain scale (VAS, cm), and patient satisfaction and quality of life were assessed using the Oswestry low back pain disability questionnaire (ODI). The Oswestry Questionnaire (version 2.0) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>] allowed us to determine the level of impairment of patients’ quality of life in terms of points and the JoSw disability index: 0% to 20% as minimal; 20% to 40% as moderate; 40% to 60% as significant; 60% to 80% as leading to disability; 80% to 100% as bedridden or as simulated symptoms. VAS pain intensity was evaluated at four time points: preoperatively, and at 7 days, 1 month, and 6 months after surgery. Functional status was assessed using the ODI before surgery and at 1 and 6 months postoperatively.</p><p id="Par28">Additionally, a survey using the International Classification of Functioning, Disability, and Health (ICF) was conducted among the operated soldiers to assess the early rehabilitation process and their ability to perform daily and professional activities. The survey focused on the following criteria:<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p id="Par29">Patient verticalization postsurgery (domain d410, changing body position);</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par30">Walking ability and distance postsurgery (domain d450, walking and moving);</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par31">Ability and duration of sitting postsurgery (domain d4153, sitting position);</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par32">Activity limitations (restricted movements and actions) (domain d430-d449, moving, handling objects, d9201, sports activities).</p></list-item></list></p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Statistical analysis</title><p id="Par33">The data were analyzed using two-way ANOVA with repeated measures, and the results are graphically presented. The mean values ± SD were compared across different time points: before surgery, 1 day after surgery, 1 month after surgery, and 6 months after surgery for the VAS score; before surgery, 1 month after surgery, and 6 months after surgery for the ODI score; and for the ICF criterion during the postoperative period. The analysis considered two factors: participant groups and time. A Bonferroni <italic toggle="yes">post hoc</italic> analysis was also conducted to determine differences among the groups, with significance set at <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05. The Shapiro‒Wilk test was used to assess the normality of the data distribution, with a <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> value &gt; 0.05 indicating no evidence of nonnormality. The data analysis was performed using the software “Statistica 8.0” (StatSoft, Inc.).</p><p id="Par34">The study size of 64 participants was determined based on a moderate effect size expectation (0.4) to achieve a desired statistical power of 0.80 in a two-way ANOVA with repeated measures. This size was sufficient to detect meaningful differences in outcomes (pain reduction, functional recovery, and return-to-duty time) across the three surgical groups.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec7"><title>Preoperative assessment</title><p id="Par35">The severity of back pain and lower limb(s) pain reported by the servicemen during the preoperative period ranged from 4 to 8 cm for back pain, with averages of 5.3 ± 1.3 cm (95% CI [4.71, 5.89]), 5.8 ± 1.4 cm (95% CI [5.13, 6.47]), and 5.5 ± 1.1 (95% CI [5.04, 5.96]) cm in the first, second, and third groups, respectively (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>). For lower limb pain, the scores ranged from 3 to 7 points, with corresponding averages of 4.7 ± 1.1 (95% CI [4.20, 5.20]) cm, 5.1 ± 1.2 (95% CI [4.52, 5.68]) cm, and 5.2 ± 1.3 (95% CI [4.65, 5.75]) cm across the three groups (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>). The substantial overlap of confidence intervals indicates comparable baseline pain intensity and no clinically meaningful preoperative differences between groups. Moreover, no relevant differences in quality of life or self-care ability were detected between groups according to the ODI during the preoperative period, with mean values of 52.7 ± 19.8 (95% CI [43.7, 61.7]), 57.9 ± 15.4 (95% CI [50.5, 65.3]) and 51.2 ± 16.6, (95% CI [44.2, 58.2]), for groups 1–3, respectively) (Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>).</p><p id="Par36">
<fig id="Fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><p>Dynamics of back pain syndrome in servicemen according to the visual analog scale (cm) before and 7 days, 1 month and 6 months after surgery. Gr. 1, 2, and 3 – patients in groups 1, 2 and 3, respectively. The asterisks (<bold>*</bold>) that are placed on the columns indicate a significant difference between pre- and postsurgical values among the different groups (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05). The asterisks on the arrows indicate a significant difference between the values of group 3 and the other postsurgery groups (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05). The <bold>#</bold> symbol represents the difference between groups at different postsurgery periods, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05. The symbol (<bold>+)</bold> denotes the difference between the postsurgery periods of group 2 (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05)</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e539" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12891_2026_9638_Fig2_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par37">
<fig id="Fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><p>Dynamics of lower extremity pain syndrome in servicemen according to the visual analog scale (cm) before and 7 days, 1 month and 6 months after surgery. The designations in this figure correspond to those in Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e552" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12891_2026_9638_Fig3_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par38">
<fig id="Fig4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 4</label><caption><p>Assessment of quality of life and self-care ability using the Oswestry Disability Index before surgery and 1 and 6 months after surgery. The designations in this figure correspond to those in Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e565" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12891_2026_9638_Fig4_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Postoperative VAS pain assessment</title><p id="Par39">Pain decreased in all groups after surgery. Early back pain scores dropped significantly to 1.4 ± 0.6 (95% CI [1.13, 1.67]) cm (group 1, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.00.1 vs. pre) and 2.1 ± 0.7 cm (95% CI [1.91, 2.29]) (group 2, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.00.1 vs. pre), while group 3 showed a more modest reduction to 4.1 ± 0.7 cm (95% CI [3.77, 4.43]) (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.07 vs. pre). After 1 month, late postoperative back pain averaged 1.1 ± 0.3 cm (95% CI [0.97, 1.23]) (group 1), 0.9 ± 0.4 cm (95% CI [0.71, 1.09]) (group 2), and 2.1 ± 0.9 cm (95% CI [1.81, 2.39]) (group 3, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001 vs. pre, Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>). By 6 months, pain levels converged, with scores of 0.5 ± 0.3 (95% CI [0.37, 0.63]) cm, 0.6 ± 0.4 (95% CI [0.41, 0.79]) cm, and 1.2 ± 0.9 (95% CI [0.82, 1.58]) cm for groups 1–3, respectively. Two-way repeated measures ANOVA for back pain revealed a significant main effect of <italic toggle="yes">Time</italic> (F(3,183) = 114.2, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, η<sub>p</sub>² = 0.65), a non-significant main effect of <italic toggle="yes">Group</italic> (F(2,61) = 1.06, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.35, η<sub>p</sub>² = 0.04), and a significant <italic toggle="yes">Group × Time</italic> interaction (F(6,183) = 8.6, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, η<sub>p</sub>² = 0.22), indicating similar baseline pain but different recovery trajectories across groups.</p><p id="Par40">Leg pain followed similar trends (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>). Early reductions to 2.3 ± 1.0 (95% CI [1.85, 2.75]) cm (group 1, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05), 1.1 ± 0.9 (95% CI [0.67, 1.53]) cm (group 2, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001 vs. pre), and 3.2 ± 1.1 (95% CI [2.74, 3.66]) cm (group 3, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.09 vs. pre) were noted, with further improvements after 1 month. Late postoperative leg pain scores were 0.9 ± 0.7 (95% CI [0.59, 1.29]) cm (group 1), 1.1 ± 0.3 (95% CI [0.96, 1.24]) cm (group 2), and 2.2 ± 1.3 (95% CI [1.66, 2.74]) cm (group 3, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001 vs. pre). At 6 months, scores were 1.1 ± 0.4 (95% CI [0.92, 1.28]) cm, 1.2 ± 0.3 (95% CI [1.06, 1.34]) cm, and 1.4 ± 0.9 (95% CI [1.02, 1.78]) cm, respectively (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001 compared to preoperative data). For leg pain, two-way RM ANOVA similarly showed a significant main effect of <italic toggle="yes">Time</italic> (F(3,183) = 91.4, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, η<sub>p</sub>² = 0.60), non-significant main effect of <italic toggle="yes">Group</italic> (F(2,61) = 1.30, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.28, η<sub>p</sub>² = 0.05), and significant <italic toggle="yes">Group × Time</italic> interaction (F(6,183) = 7.6, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, η<sub>p</sub>² = 0.20).</p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Postoperative ODI</title><p id="Par41">The assessment of quality of life and self-care ability using the ODI showed significant improvement in patients in the first and second groups 1 month after surgery compared to their preoperative condition (Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>).</p><p id="Par42">Before surgery, the ODI was similar across the first and second groups, with values of 52.7 ± 19.8% (95% CI [43.85, 61.55]) and 57.9 ± 15.4% (95% CI [50.49, 65.31]), respectively (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.41). However, at just one month postsurgery, these scores significantly improved, dropping to 21.4 ± 8.5% (95% CI [17.50, 25.30]) in the first group and 19.1 ± 5.3% (95% CI [16.53, 21.67]) in the second group, reflecting a satisfactory quality of life and positive outcomes (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001) compared to the preoperative data. In contrast, the third group (those treated with decompression and stabilization) showed no significant changes one month after surgery, with scores decreasing from 51.2 ± 16.6% (95% CI [44.24, 58.16]) to 40.2 ± 9.4% (95% CI [36.26, 44.14]) (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.12), indicating that most patients in this group still experienced significant impairments in self-care and daily activities.</p><p id="Par43">Six months after surgery, the ODI score was 10.7 ± 5.4% (95% CI [8.24, 13.16]) in the first group and 15.0 ± 4.1% (95% CI [13.02, 16.98]) in the second group (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001), indicating minimal impairment that did not interfere with daily activities or military duties. However, in the third group, moderate impairments persisted, with an ODI of 20.3 ± 8.1% (95% CI [16.90, 23.70]) (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.06), suggesting that those in the transpedicular stabilization group required further rehabilitation and monitoring.</p><p id="Par44">Two-way RM ANOVA for ODI showed a significant main effect of <italic toggle="yes">Time</italic> (F(2,122) = 142.3, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, η<sub>p</sub>² = 0.70), non-significant main effect of <italic toggle="yes">Group</italic> (F(2,61) = 0.49, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.62, η<sub>p</sub>² = 0.03), and a significant <italic toggle="yes">Group × Time</italic> interaction (F(4,122) = 10.2, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, η<sub>p</sub>² = 0.25), confirming differential recovery patterns.</p></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>ICF evaluation</title><p id="Par45">The survey results in the early postoperative period revealed the following differences: patient verticalization in the first group occurred on average 6.2 ± 2.9 h after surgery; in the second group, it occurred after 10.7 ± 4.4 h; and in the third group, with transpedicular stabilization, verticalization without complications according to the patient’s capabilities occurred on average 20.4 ± 5.7 h postsurgery (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001).</p><p id="Par46">The ability to sit during the first week postsurgery was limited in the second group (0–15 min) and in the third group (0–15 min). In the first group, the sitting time was extended to 20–65 min, which is associated with minimal tissue trauma during surgical access (Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>).</p><p id="Par47">
<table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Function limitations and activity (according to the ICF) after endoscopic, open and stabilization surgical interventions in servicemen with lumbar spinal stenosis</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">ICF domain</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Characteristics</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1group</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2 group</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3 group</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">d410</italic>
</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Verticalization technique</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">over the stomach / over the side</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">over the stomach / over the side</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">over the stomach / over the side</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">d410</italic>
</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Verticalization after surgery</p><p>(number of hours after surgery)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.2 ± 2.9</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10.7 ± 4.4</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">20.4 ± 5.7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="3" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">d4153</italic>
</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Ability to sit after surgery during the day,</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes,</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Not recommended</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No,</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">duration min.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">20–65</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0–15</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0–15</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">After 1 month min.</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No restrictions</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No restrictions</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Up to 2 h</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="4" colspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">d450</italic>
</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Walking distance after surgery</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">After 1 week (m)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">738.7 ± 186.2</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">500 ± 145.5</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">283 ± 123.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">After 1 month (m)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1950 ± 302.6</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1840 ± 321.5</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">902.5 ± 100.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">After 6 months (m)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5590 ± 702.3</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4900.7 ± 598.9</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2040.7 ± 409.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">е 110</italic>
</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Wearing a corset</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">If required</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">d9201</italic>
</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Prohibited movements: bending, jumping, carrying heavy loads</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Within 1–2 months</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Within 1–2 months</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Within 2–3 months</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">d859</italic>
</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Time when you can return to exercises (day)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">The day after surgery</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">After 2–3 days</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">After 3–7 days</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">d859</italic>
</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Return to professional duties, days</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">27.4 ± 15.3</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">38.4 ± 16.6</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">80.8 ± 20.8</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>Quantitative data are presented as mean ± Standard Deviation</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par48">The following was used to determine the postoperative walking distance:</p><p id="Par49">One month after surgery, the average walking distance among patients in the first group was 738.7 ± 186.2 m (95% CI [655.5, 821.9]); in the second group, it was 500 ± 145.5 m (95% CI [430.0, 570.0]); and in the third group, the distance that patients could walk in the early postoperative period was almost half that, 283 ± 123.4 m (95% CI [231.1, 334.9]) (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001), compared to the results of the first and second groups.</p><p id="Par50">Six months postsurgery, limitations in the ability to walk long distances persisted in the third group (2040.7 ± 409.5 m, 95% CI [1868.8, 2212.6])). The results for the first group (5590 ± 702.3 m, 95% CI [5270.7, 5909.3]) and the second group (4900.7 ± 598.9 m, 95% CI [4612.7, 5188.7]) did not significantly differ (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.21) and were almost three times greater than the results for the transpedicular stabilization group (Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>).</p></sec><sec id="Sec14"><title>Return to duty</title><p id="Par51">A survey of military personnel regarding their return to professional duties during long-term follow-up showed that servicemen returned to work after an average of 27.4 ± 15.3 days in the first group and 38.4 ± 16.6 days in the second group, whereas return to work was substantially delayed in the third group with transpedicular stabilization (80.8 ± 20.8 days) (Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>). Patients in the endoscopic and open decompression groups returned to full military duty without restrictions, with earlier return observed in the endoscopic group. In contrast, patients who underwent decompression with transpedicular stabilization required longer rehabilitation, and several returned to duty with activity restrictions at the 6-month follow-up.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec15"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par52">The results of this study describe the varying outcomes of different surgical interventions for LSS in wounded servicemen, emphasizing the need for a tailored approach to surgical treatment depending on the severity of the condition and the specific needs of the patient.</p><p id="Par53">The most pronounced early postoperative pain relief was observed in patients who underwent ULBD and open decompression, which aligns with the findings of previous research indicating that minimally invasive techniques generally offer faster pain relief and recovery [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>]. The relatively greater pain levels in the group that underwent decompression laminectomy with transpedicular stabilization suggest that this more invasive approach, while necessary for patients with more severe or complex cases, results in a more prolonged and painful recovery period [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>].</p><p id="Par54">The assessment of functional outcomes using the ODI provides a clear indication of the impact of surgical intervention on the quality of life and self-care abilities of patients. The first and second groups, which underwent ULBD and open decompression, respectively, showed substantial improvements in ODI scores within one month postsurgery, reflecting a return to near-normal function and minimal impairment in daily activities. It is likely that this improvement suggests that less invasive procedures generally allow for quicker functional recovery and better quality-of-life outcomes [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>].</p><p id="Par55">In contrast, the third group, which underwent decompression laminectomy with stabilization, exhibited only modest improvements in ODI scores one month postsurgery, with moderate impairments persisting at the six-month follow-up. These findings suggest that while transpedicular stabilization is effective at stabilizing the spine and preventing further degeneration, it may require a longer rehabilitation period to achieve functional outcomes comparable to those of less invasive procedures [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>].</p><p id="Par56">The ability of servicemen to return to active duty was a critical outcome measure in this study. The rapid return to work observed in the first group (average of 27.4 days) compared to the second (38.4 days) and third groups (80.8 days) highlights the benefits of minimally invasive surgery in reducing downtime and allowing quicker reintegration into professional roles. This is particularly important in military settings where operational readiness and the ability to quickly return to duty are paramount. The extended recovery period required for those undergoing transpedicular stabilization underscores the need for careful patient selection and counseling regarding the expected recovery timeline and potential delays in returning to active duty [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>].</p><p id="Par57">For patients with mild to moderate stenosis, less invasive techniques such as ULBD may be preferred due to their association with quicker recovery and less postoperative pain [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>]. Conversely, for patients with severe or complex stenosis, where spinal instability is a concern, more invasive techniques, such as decompression laminectomy with stabilization, may be necessary, although these patients are likely to require a longer recovery period. Given the specific occupational demands, there is concern that less invasive decompression techniques could present stability challenges over time. Studies indicate that while techniques like ULBD reduce immediate recovery time, they may not address the mechanical stresses of high-intensity activities, potentially leading to instability or degeneration [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>]. Future research focusing on biomechanical evaluations post-surgery could help validate these approaches for military use.</p><p id="Par58">The findings of the study have important implications for surgical decision-making in military settings. Given the significant differences in pain, functional recovery, and time to return to duty among the three groups, the choice of surgical technique should be guided by the severity of LSS, the overall health of the patient, and the specific functional requirements of military service. Additionally, the literature on rehabilitation suggests that early, structured physical therapy focusing on core stability and mobility can significantly accelerate return-to-duty timelines [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>]. Integrating these findings may serve as a practical extension of our study’s findings.</p><sec id="Sec16"><title>Study limitations</title><p id="Par59">Although this study provides insights into the outcomes of different surgical interventions for LSS in military personnel, it has several limitations. The sample size was relatively small, and the study was conducted at a single center, which may limit the generalizability of the findings. Additionally, the study did not account for long-term outcomes beyond six months, which are critical for understanding the durability of surgical benefits and the potential for recurrent symptoms or complications. Future research should include larger, multicenter studies with longer follow-up periods to validate these findings and provide more comprehensive guidance for clinical practice.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec17"><title>Conclusions</title><p id="Par60">In conclusion, this study underscores the importance of individualized surgical planning for wounded servicemen with lumbar spinal canal stenosis. While minimally invasive procedures such as ULBD offer significant advantages in terms of pain relief and quicker return to duty, more invasive techniques such as decompression laminectomy with stabilization remain essential for patients with severe or complex conditions, despite their longer recovery times. These findings contribute to the ongoing discussion about optimizing surgical strategies for LSS, particularly in the context of military medicine, where the balance between effective treatment and rapid return to operational readiness is crucial.</p></sec></body><back><glossary><title>Abbreviations</title><def-list><def-item><term>BMI</term><def><p id="Par5">Body mass index</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>ICF</term><def><p id="Par6">International Classification of Functioning, Disability, and Health</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>LSS</term><def><p id="Par7">Lumbar spinal stenosis</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>ODI</term><def><p id="Par8">Oswestry Disability Index</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>PLIF</term><def><p id="Par9">Posterior lumbar interbody fusion</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>TLIF</term><def><p id="Par10">Transforaminal lumbar interbody fusion</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>ULBD</term><def><p id="Par11">Unilateral laminectomy for bilateral decompression</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>VAS</term><def><p id="Par12">Visual Analogue Scale</p></def></def-item></def-list></glossary><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher’s note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>Not applicable.</p><sec id="FPar1"><title>Clinical trial number</title><p id="Par61">Not applicable.</p></sec></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Authors’ contributions</title><p>VM, LK and IF participated in the design and investigation of this study. VM and LK participated in data acquisition and collection. DN, AM, TA and IS analyzed the data. DN and AM drafted the manuscript. AM was a major contributor in writing the manuscript. IS was involved in funding acquisition. All authors read and approved the final manuscript.</p></notes><notes notes-type="funding-information"><title>Funding</title><p>This publication was prepared without any external source of funding.</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>The datasets used and/or analysed during the current study are available from the corresponding author on reasonable request.</p></notes><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar2"><title>Ethics approval and consent to participate</title><p id="Par62">The study was conducted in accordance with the Local Ethics Committee of the Spine Surgery Department of the Spinal (Neurosurgical) Centre, SI “Institute of Traumatology and Orthopedics” in Kyiv NAMS of Ukraine,” and performed in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to their inclusion in the research.</p></notes><notes id="FPar3"><title>Consent for publication</title><p id="Par63">Not applicable.</p></notes><notes id="FPar4" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par64">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR1" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lovalekar</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hauret</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Roy</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Taylor</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Blacker</surname><given-names>SD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Newman</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Musculoskeletal injuries in military personnel-Descriptive epidemiology, risk factor identification, and prevention</article-title><source>J Sci Med Sport</source><year>2021</year><volume>24</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>963</fpage><lpage>9</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2021.03.016</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33824080</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR1" publication-type="journal">Lovalekar M, Hauret K, Roy T, Taylor K, Blacker SD, Newman P, et al. Musculoskeletal injuries in military personnel-Descriptive epidemiology, risk factor identification, and prevention. J Sci Med Sport. 2021;24(10):963–9.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33824080</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jsams.2021.03.016</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR2" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>To</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rezai</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Murnaghan</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cancelliere</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Risk factors for low back pain in active military personnel: a systematic review</article-title><source>Chiropr Man Th</source><year>2021</year><volume>29</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>52</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12998-021-00409-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8719410</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34969400</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR2" publication-type="journal">To D, Rezai M, Murnaghan K, Cancelliere C. Risk factors for low back pain in active military personnel: a systematic review. Chiropr Man Th. 2021;29(1):52.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12998-021-00409-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8719410</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34969400</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR3" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cohen</surname><given-names>SP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gallagher</surname><given-names>RM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Griffith</surname><given-names>SR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carragee</surname><given-names>EJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Spine-area pain in military personnel: a review of epidemiology, etiology, diagnosis, and treatment</article-title><source>Spine J</source><year>2012</year><volume>12</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>833</fpage><lpage>42</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.spinee.2011.10.010</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22100208</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR3" publication-type="journal">Cohen SP, Gallagher RM, Davis SA, Griffith SR, Carragee EJ. Spine-area pain in military personnel: a review of epidemiology, etiology, diagnosis, and treatment. Spine J. 2012;12(9):833–42.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22100208</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.spinee.2011.10.010</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR4" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Clark</surname><given-names>LL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Diagnoses of low back pain, active component, U.S. Armed Forces, 2010–2014</article-title><source>MSMR</source><year>2015</year><volume>22</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>8</fpage><lpage>11</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26726722</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR4" publication-type="journal">Clark LL, Hu Z. Diagnoses of low back pain, active component, U.S. Armed Forces, 2010–2014. MSMR. 2015;22(12):8–11.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26726722</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR5" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Marcia</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zini</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bellini</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Image-guided percutaneous treatment of lumbar stenosis and disc degeneration: neuroimaging</article-title><source>Clin N Am</source><year>2019</year><volume>29</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>563</fpage><lpage>80</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.nic.2019.07.010</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31677731</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR5" publication-type="journal">Marcia S, Zini C, Bellini M. Image-guided percutaneous treatment of lumbar stenosis and disc degeneration: neuroimaging. Clin N Am. 2019;29(4):563–80.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.nic.2019.07.010</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31677731</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR6" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Murata</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Akeda</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Takegami</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Morphology of intervertebral disc ruptures evaluated by vacuum phenomenon using multi-detector computed tomography: association with lumbar disc degeneration and Canal stenosis</article-title><source>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</source><year>2018</year><volume>19</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>164</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12891-018-2086-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29793459</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5968599</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR6" publication-type="journal">Murata K, Akeda K, Takegami N. Morphology of intervertebral disc ruptures evaluated by vacuum phenomenon using multi-detector computed tomography: association with lumbar disc degeneration and Canal stenosis. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2018;19(1):164.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29793459</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12891-018-2086-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5968599</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR7" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sobański</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Staszkiewicz</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Filipowicz</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Holiński</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jędrocha</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Migdał</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Evaluation of the concentration of selected elements in the serum of patients with degenerative stenosis of the lumbosacral spine</article-title><source>Biol Trace Elem Res</source><year>2024</year><volume>202</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>4945</fpage><lpage>60</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12011-024-04083-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38321303</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR7" publication-type="journal">Sobański D, Staszkiewicz R, Filipowicz M, Holiński M, Jędrocha M, Migdał M, et al. Evaluation of the concentration of selected elements in the serum of patients with degenerative stenosis of the lumbosacral spine. Biol Trace Elem Res. 2024;202(11):4945–60.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38321303</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s12011-024-04083-x</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR8" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Iorio</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jakoi</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Singla</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Biomechanics of degenerative spinal disorders</article-title><source>Asian Spine J</source><year>2016</year><volume>10</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>377</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4184/asj.2016.10.2.377</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27114783</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4843079</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR8" publication-type="journal">Iorio JA, Jakoi AM, Singla A. Biomechanics of degenerative spinal disorders. Asian Spine J. 2016;10(2):377.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27114783</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.4184/asj.2016.10.2.377</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4843079</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR9" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rudnicka</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Napierała</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Podfigurna</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Męczekalski</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Smolarczyk</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Grymowicz</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The world health organization (WHO) approach to healthy ageing</article-title><source>Maturitas</source><year>2020</year><volume>139</volume><fpage>6</fpage><lpage>11</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2020.05.018</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32747042</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7250103</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR9" publication-type="journal">Rudnicka E, Napierała P, Podfigurna A, Męczekalski B, Smolarczyk R, Grymowicz M. The world health organization (WHO) approach to healthy ageing. Maturitas. 2020;139:6–11.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32747042</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.maturitas.2020.05.018</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7250103</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR10" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Aoki</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Saito</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nakajima</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sonobe</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Akatsu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Unilateral laminectomy for bilateral decompression improves low back pain while standing equally on both sides in patients with lumbar Canal stenosis: analysis using a detailed visual analogue scale</article-title><source>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</source><year>2019</year><volume>20</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>100</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12891-019-2475-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30832643</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6399850</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR10" publication-type="journal">Takahashi H, Aoki Y, Saito J, Nakajima A, Sonobe M, Akatsu Y, et al. Unilateral laminectomy for bilateral decompression improves low back pain while standing equally on both sides in patients with lumbar Canal stenosis: analysis using a detailed visual analogue scale. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2019;20(1):100.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30832643</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12891-019-2475-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6399850</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR11" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>de Kunder</surname><given-names>SL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>van Kuijk</surname><given-names>SMJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rijkers</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Caelers</surname><given-names>IJMH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>van Hemert</surname><given-names>WLW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>de Bie</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Transforaminal lumbar interbody fusion (TLIF) versus posterior lumbar interbody fusion (PLIF) in lumbar spondylolisthesis: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>Spine J</source><year>2017</year><volume>17</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>1712</fpage><lpage>21</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.spinee.2017.06.018</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28647584</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR11" publication-type="journal">de Kunder SL, van Kuijk SMJ, Rijkers K, Caelers IJMH, van Hemert WLW, de Bie RA, et al. Transforaminal lumbar interbody fusion (TLIF) versus posterior lumbar interbody fusion (PLIF) in lumbar spondylolisthesis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Spine J. 2017;17(11):1712–21.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28647584</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.spinee.2017.06.018</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR12" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ulrich</surname><given-names>NH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Burgstaller</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gravestock</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pichierri</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wertli</surname><given-names>MM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Steurer</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Outcome of unilateral versus standard open midline approach for bilateral decompression in lumbar spinal stenosis: is over the top really better? A Swiss prospective multicenter cohort study</article-title><source>J Neurosurg Spine</source><year>2019</year><volume>26</volume><issue>312</issue><fpage>236</fpage><lpage>45</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3171/2019.2.SPINE181309</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31026821</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR12" publication-type="journal">Ulrich NH, Burgstaller JM, Gravestock I, Pichierri G, Wertli MM, Steurer J, et al. Outcome of unilateral versus standard open midline approach for bilateral decompression in lumbar spinal stenosis: is over the top really better? A Swiss prospective multicenter cohort study. J Neurosurg Spine. 2019;26(312):236–45.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3171/2019.2.SPINE181309</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31026821</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR13" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Heider</surname><given-names>FC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mayer</surname><given-names>HM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Unilateral approach for over the top bilateral lumbar decompression</article-title><source>Oper Orthop Traumatol</source><year>2019</year><volume>31</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>513</fpage><lpage>35</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00064-019-00632-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31728562</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR13" publication-type="journal">Heider FC, Mayer HM. Unilateral approach for over the top bilateral lumbar decompression. Oper Orthop Traumatol. 2019;31(6):513–35.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31728562</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00064-019-00632-z</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR14" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yoshikane</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kikuchi</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Okazaki</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Lumbar endoscopic unilateral laminotomy for bilateral decompression for lumbar spinal stenosis provides comparable clinical outcomes in patients with and without degenerative spondylolisthesis</article-title><source>World Neurosurg</source><year>2021</year><volume>150</volume><fpage>e361</fpage><lpage>71</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.wneu.2021.03.018</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33722714</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR14" publication-type="journal">Yoshikane K, Kikuchi K, Okazaki K. Lumbar endoscopic unilateral laminotomy for bilateral decompression for lumbar spinal stenosis provides comparable clinical outcomes in patients with and without degenerative spondylolisthesis. World Neurosurg. 2021;150:e361–71.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33722714</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.wneu.2021.03.018</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR15" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effectiveness and safety of unilateral pedicle screw fixation in transforaminal lumbar interbody fusion (TLIF): a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>Arch Orthop Trauma Surg</source><year>2017</year><volume>137</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>441</fpage><lpage>50</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00402-017-2641-y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28168642</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR15" publication-type="journal">Ren C, Qin R, Sun P, Wang P. Effectiveness and safety of unilateral pedicle screw fixation in transforaminal lumbar interbody fusion (TLIF): a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2017;137(4):441–50.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28168642</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00402-017-2641-y</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR16" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Weinstein</surname><given-names>JN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tosteson</surname><given-names>TD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lurie</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tosteson</surname><given-names>AN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Blood</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hanscom</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Surgical versus nonsurgical therapy for lumbar spinal stenosis</article-title><source>N Engl J Med</source><year>2008</year><volume>358</volume><fpage>794</fpage><lpage>810</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0707136</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18287602</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2576513</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR16" publication-type="journal">Weinstein JN, Tosteson TD, Lurie JD, Tosteson AN, Blood E, Hanscom B, et al. Surgical versus nonsurgical therapy for lumbar spinal stenosis. N Engl J Med. 2008;358:794–810.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18287602</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1056/NEJMoa0707136</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2576513</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR17" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>GX</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>He</surname><given-names>LR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nan</surname><given-names>JN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>WB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Que</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Comparing outcomes of Banana-Shaped and straight cages in transforaminal lumbar interbody fusion for lumbar degenerative diseases: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis</article-title><source>Neurospine</source><year>2024</year><volume>21</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>261</fpage><lpage>72</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.14245/ns.2347078.539</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38317558</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10992667</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR17" publication-type="journal">Lin GX, He LR, Nan JN, Xu WB, Xiao K, Que Z, et al. Comparing outcomes of Banana-Shaped and straight cages in transforaminal lumbar interbody fusion for lumbar degenerative diseases: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis. Neurospine. 2024;21(1):261–72.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38317558</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.14245/ns.2347078.539</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10992667</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR18" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Microendoscopic lumbar posterior decompression surgery for lumbar spinal stenosis</article-title><source>Literature Rev Med (Kaunas)</source><year>2022</year><volume>58</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>384</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/medicina58030384</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8954505</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35334560</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR18" publication-type="journal">Suzuki A, Nakamura H. Microendoscopic lumbar posterior decompression surgery for lumbar spinal stenosis. Literature Rev Med (Kaunas). 2022;58(3):384.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/medicina58030384</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8954505</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35334560</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR19" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Roland</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fairbank</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The Roland–Morris disability questionnaire and the Oswestry disability questionnaire</article-title><source>Spine</source><year>2000</year><volume>25</volume><issue>24</issue><fpage>3115</fpage><lpage>24</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/00007632-200012150-00006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11124727</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR19" publication-type="journal">Roland M, Fairbank J. The Roland–Morris disability questionnaire and the Oswestry disability questionnaire. Spine. 2000;25(24):3115–24.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11124727</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/00007632-200012150-00006</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR20" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Shu</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Research progress of different minimally invasive spinal decompression in lumbar spinal stenosis</article-title><source>Zhongguo Xiu Fu Chong Jian Wai Ke Za Zhi</source><year>2023</year><volume>37</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>895</fpage><lpage>900</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37460188</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.7507/1002-1892.202303110</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10352501</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR20" publication-type="journal">Shu T, Wu D, Shen M. Research progress of different minimally invasive spinal decompression in lumbar spinal stenosis. Zhongguo Xiu Fu Chong Jian Wai Ke Za Zhi. 2023;37(7):895–900.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37460188</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.7507/1002-1892.202303110</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10352501</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR21" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Murata</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Minamide</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Takami</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Iwasaki</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Okada</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nonaka</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Microendoscopic decompression for lumbar spinal stenosis caused by facet-joint cysts: a novel technique with a cyst-dyeing protocol and cohort comparison study</article-title><source>J Neurosurg Spine</source><year>2021</year><volume>34</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>573</fpage><lpage>9</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3171/2020.8.SPINE201209</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33450739</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR21" publication-type="journal">Murata S, Minamide A, Takami M, Iwasaki H, Okada S, Nonaka K, et al. Microendoscopic decompression for lumbar spinal stenosis caused by facet-joint cysts: a novel technique with a cyst-dyeing protocol and cohort comparison study. J Neurosurg Spine. 2021;34(4):573–9.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33450739</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3171/2020.8.SPINE201209</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR22" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Korge</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mehren</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ruetten</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Minimally invasive decompression techniques for spinal cord stenosis</article-title><source>Orthopade</source><year>2019</year><volume>48</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>824</fpage><lpage>30</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00132-019-03732-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31053867</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR22" publication-type="journal">Korge A, Mehren C, Ruetten S. Minimally invasive decompression techniques for spinal cord stenosis. Orthopade. 2019;48(10):824–30.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31053867</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00132-019-03732-7</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR23" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hussain</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kirnaz</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wibawa</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wipplinger</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Härtl</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Minimally invasive approaches for surgical treatment of lumbar spondylolisthesis</article-title><source>Neurosurg Clin N Am</source><year>2019</year><volume>30</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>305</fpage><lpage>12</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.nec.2019.02.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31078231</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR23" publication-type="journal">Hussain I, Kirnaz S, Wibawa G, Wipplinger C, Härtl R. Minimally invasive approaches for surgical treatment of lumbar spondylolisthesis. Neurosurg Clin N Am. 2019;30(3):305–12.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31078231</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.nec.2019.02.004</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR24" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ko</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Oh</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Comparison of bilateral decompression via unilateral laminotomy and conventional laminectomy for single-level degenerative lumbar spinal stenosis regarding low back pain, functional outcome, and quality of life – A randomized Controlled, prospective trial</article-title><source>J Orthop Surg Res</source><year>2019</year><volume>14</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>252</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s13018-019-1298-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31395104</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6686452</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR24" publication-type="journal">Ko S, Oh T. Comparison of bilateral decompression via unilateral laminotomy and conventional laminectomy for single-level degenerative lumbar spinal stenosis regarding low back pain, functional outcome, and quality of life – A randomized Controlled, prospective trial. J Orthop Surg Res. 2019;14(1):252.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31395104</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s13018-019-1298-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6686452</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR25" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kalina</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Minimally invasive transforaminal lumbar interbody fusion (MIS TLIF) in treatment of degenerative diseases of lumbosacral spine compared to modified open TLIF: a prospective randomised controlled study</article-title><source>Neurol Neurochir Pol</source><year>2024</year><volume>58</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>503</fpage><lpage>11</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5603/pjnns.97784</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39101649</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR25" publication-type="journal">Kalina R. Minimally invasive transforaminal lumbar interbody fusion (MIS TLIF) in treatment of degenerative diseases of lumbosacral spine compared to modified open TLIF: a prospective randomised controlled study. Neurol Neurochir Pol. 2024;58(5):503–11.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39101649</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.5603/pjnns.97784</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR26" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>TF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shan</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wan</surname><given-names>ZY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Viswanath</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Decompression using minimally invasive surgery for lumbar spinal stenosis associated with degenerative spondylolisthesis: A review</article-title><source>Pain Ther</source><year>2021</year><volume>10</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>941</fpage><lpage>59</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s40122-021-00293-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34322837</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8586290</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR26" publication-type="journal">Zhang J, Liu TF, Shan H, Wan ZY, Wang Z, Viswanath O, et al. Decompression using minimally invasive surgery for lumbar spinal stenosis associated with degenerative spondylolisthesis: A review. Pain Ther. 2021;10(2):941–59.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34322837</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s40122-021-00293-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8586290</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR27" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Manni</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ferri</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vanti</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ferrari</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cuoghi</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gaeta</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Rehabilitation after lumbar spine surgery in adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis</article-title><source>Arch Physiother</source><year>2023</year><volume>13</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>21</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s40945-023-00175-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37845718</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10578022</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR27" publication-type="journal">Manni T, Ferri N, Vanti C, Ferrari S, Cuoghi I, Gaeta C, et al. Rehabilitation after lumbar spine surgery in adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Arch Physiother. 2023;13(1):21.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37845718</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s40945-023-00175-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10578022</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>