<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41932352</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2215-0374</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The lancet. Psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Joint statement by the World Psychiatric Association, the American Psychiatric Association, the European Psychiatric Association, and the Global Expert Task Force on ECT on the portrayal of electroconvulsive therapy in the WHO Guidance on Mental Health Policy and Strategic Action Plans.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2215-0366(26)00059-3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S2215-0366(26)00059-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The World Psychiatric Association, the American Psychiatric Association, the European Psychiatric Association, and the Global Expert Task Force on ECT welcome the WHO's emphasis on rights-based, person-centered, and recovery-oriented mental health policies. However, they express concern that the WHO Guidance contains scientifically inaccurate and misleading statements particularly regarding electroconvulsive therapy (ECT). These portray ECT as inherently dangerous and advocate for its restriction or prohibition, thereby reinforcing stigma and potentially limiting access to evidence-based care for severely ill patients. Substantial scientific evidence shows that ECT is an effective, safe, and well-tolerated treatment, supported by decades of research and international clinical guidelines. Although acknowledging global variations in regulation and access, the associations stress that denying ECT in life-threatening situations, including in children and adolescents or in patients who lack decision-making capacity, would be unethical. The authors call on WHO to integrate robust scientific evidence and lived experience into future guidance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved, including those for text and data mining, AI training, and similar technologies.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zilles-Wegner</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, University Medical Center G&#xf6;ttingen, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wasserman</LastName><ForeName>Danuta</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden; WHO Collaborating Centre, Research, Methods Development, Training in Suicide Prevention, Stockholm, Sweden; World Psychiatric Association, Geneva University Psychiatric Hospital, Geneva, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schulze</LastName><ForeName>Thomas G</ForeName><Initials>TG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Psychiatric Phenomics and Genomics, University Hospital, LMU Munich, Munich, Germany; Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Norton College of Medicine, SUNY Upstate Medical University, Syracuse, NY, USA; Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA; World Psychiatric Association, Th&#xf4;nex, Geneva, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pogarell</LastName><ForeName>Oliver</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, LMU Hospital, LMU Munich, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miskimen</LastName><ForeName>Theresa</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rapaport</LastName><ForeName>Mark H</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Huntsman Mental Health Institute, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Summergrad</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Tufts University School of Medicine, Boston, MA, USA; Department of Psychiatry, Tufts Medical Center, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fiorillo</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Campania Luigi Vanvitelli, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arango</LastName><ForeName>Celso</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Hospital Universitario La Paz, Universidad Aut&#xf3;noma de Madrid, Madrid, Spain; King's College London, London, UK; University of California San Francisco, San Francisco, CA, USA; University of Maryland, College Park, MD, USA; Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n Biom&#xe9;dica en Red de Salud Mental, CIBERSAM, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Global Expert Task Force on ECT</CollectiveName></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sartorius</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, Central Institute of Mental Health, Medical Faculty Mannheim, University of Heidelberg, Mannheim, Germany; German Center for Mental Health, Mannheim, Germany. Electronic address: alexander.sartorius@zi-mannheim.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101638123</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2215-0366</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests OP is the Section Chair for the World Psychiatric Association Section Psychiatric Electrophysiology and Neurostimulation. PS reports consulting fees from MindMed (now known as Definium Therapeutics); is on the executive committee and is the Secretary of Finances of the World Psychiatric Association; is a past President of the American Psychiatric Association; reports stock in Sensorium Therapeutics and stock options in Definium Therapeutics; and is on the board of directors for and has stock in Health and Productivity Sciences (outside the scope of this paper and receiving no current revenue). CA reports grants or contracts from Bristol-Myers Squibb, Comunidad de Madrid, Fundaci&#xf3;n Alicia Koplowitz, Fundaci&#xf3;n Familia Alonso, Fundaci&#xf3;n Mutua Madrile&#xf1;a, Instituto de Salud Carlos IIII, and Ministerio Educaci&#xf3;n; consulting fees from Acadia, Ambrosetti, Angelini, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Boehringer, Gedeon Richter, Janssen Cilag, Lundbeck, Otsuka, Roche, Rovi, The Stanley Foundation, Sumitomo Dainippon Pharma, Sunovion, and Teva; and payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing, or educational events from Janssen-Cilag, Lundbeck, Otsuka, Rovi, and Takeda; and support for attending meetings and travel from Acadia, Ambrosetti, Angelini, Janssen Cilag, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Otsuka, Roche, Rovi, The Stanley Foundation, Sunovion, and Teva. AS is Head of the Neurostimulation Section of the German Association for Psychiatry and Deputy Head of the Electroconvulsive Therapy Working Group of the Arbeitsgemeinschaft f&#xfc;r Neuropsychopharmakologie und Pharmakopsychiatrie. DZ-W reports lecture fees fromVitos Gie&#xdf;en-Marburg, Sophien-und Hufeland-Klinikum Weimar, Klinikum Itzehoe, and FomF and is Deputy Head of the Neurostimulation Section of the German Association for Psychiatry and Chairman of the Electroconvulsive Therapy Working Group of the Arbeitsgemeinschaft f&#xfc;r Neuropsychopharmakologie und Pharmakopsychiatrie. All other authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41932352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(26)00059-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2215-0366(26)00059-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>