<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41884233</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2220-6124</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of nephrology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Nephrol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of focused nursing training on infection control measures on nurses' practice for patients undergoing percutaneous nephrolithotomy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>116965</StartPage><MedlinePgn>116965</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">116965</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5527/wjn.v15.i1.116965</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Nursing care for patients undergoing percutaneous nephrolithotomy (PNL) is a crucial step in reducing complications and promoting recovery. Infection control procedures are vital tools for preventing most complications. Proper nursing education and training for managing these patients can provide sufficient protection against urinary tract infections and related issues, such as secondary hemorrhage and hospital readmission.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate nurses' performance after receiving nursing instructions regarding the infection control measures for patients with PNL.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A quasi-experimental research design (pretest-posttest) was employed. The study was conducted at Assiut University Urology Hospital, Assiut University, Egypt. The participant nurses worked in units providing healthcare for patients who underwent PNL and received focused nursing instructions on infection control measures. The tools used included a structured questionnaire assessing their knowledge of PNL healthcare and a nurses' practice observation checklist. The researchers completed these tools before and after the nurses received focused education on infection control measures. The focused education was provided through an illustrated booklet. The local ethics committee approved this study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">This study comprised 30 nurses, including 19 females (63.3%). Of these, 46.7% were in the 20-25 age group, 90% had a high educational level, and 50% had less than 5 years of work experience. Significant differences were observed between pre- and post-test scores in overall performance (<i>P</i> = 0.001), total preoperative scores (<i>P</i> = 0.001), immediate postoperative scores (<i>P</i> = 0.006), infection control measures (<i>P</i> = 0.001), and respiratory hygiene practices (<i>P</i> = 0.001). In the pretest, 16.7% of the nurses demonstrated adequate practice levels of infection control measures for patients undergoing PNL, compared to 100% in the posttest (<i>P</i> = 0.001). No significant relationships were found between nurses' practice levels and their demographic variables (<i>P</i> &gt; 0.050).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The nurses' performance improved significantly after receiving focused nursing instructions on infection control measures for patients with PNL. Nurses should participate in ongoing training programs on infection control procedures.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gadelkareem</LastName><ForeName>Rabea A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Assiut Urology and Nephrology Hospital, Faculty of Medicine, Assiut University, Assiut 71515, Assiut, Egypt. rabeagad@aun.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdelfatah</LastName><ForeName>Kamilia F</ForeName><Initials>KF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical-Surgical Nursing, Faculty of Nursing, Assiut University, Assiut 71515, Assiut, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abozead</LastName><ForeName>Shalabia E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical-Surgical Nursing, Faculty of Nursing, Assiut University, Assiut 71515, Assiut, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sayed</LastName><ForeName>Samia Y</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical-Surgical Nursing, Faculty of Nursing, Assiut University, Assiut 71515, Assiut, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fawzy</LastName><ForeName>Waheed</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Faculty of Medicine, New Valley University, Kharga 72511, New Valley, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Nephrol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610229</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2220-6124</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infection control measures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing instructions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Percutaneous nephrolithotomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surgical nursing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All authors have no conflict of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41884233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13010492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5527/wjn.v15.i1.116965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hatwar G, Dhale A, Dharamshi JD, Pendkar R. Comparative Analysis of Standard Percutaneous Nephrolithotomy (PCNL) and Mini-Percutaneous Nephrolithotomy (Mini-PCNL) for Renal Stones Larger Than 2 cm at a Rural Hospital: A Study Protocol. Cureus. 2024;16:e61963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11230606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38978895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaed EAA, Bendary LA, Ali MM, Eldereey MSE. Percutaneous Nephrolithotomy Role in Management of Renal Stones: Review Article. Egypt J Hosp Med. 2022;89:5439&#x2013;5443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coman RA, Tzelves L, Julieb&#xf8;-Jones P, Talyshinskii A, Nedbal C, Ventimiglia E, Davis N, Somani BK. Pre- and post-operative safety considerations for patients undergoing percutaneous nephrolithotomy. Expert Opin Drug Saf. 2025;24:1367&#x2013;1381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40254899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim Abdeen Mhana E, Ahmed Abd El-Aziz N, Mohamed Hassan M. Nurses&#x2019; performance regarding Infection Control Precautions in Primary Health Care Centers. Egypt J Health Care. 2022;13:420&#x2013;431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talizin TB, Danilovic A, Torricelli FCM, Marchini GS, Batagello C, Vicentini FC, Nahas WC, Mazzucchi E. Postoperative antibiotic prophylaxis for percutaneous nephrolithotomy and risk of infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int Braz J Urol. 2024;50:152&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10953597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38386786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdallah E, Nabih M, Bazeed M, Othman W. Effect of Nursing Protocol on Knowledge and Health Outcomes of Patient undergoing Percutaneous Nephrolithotomy. Mansoura Nurs J. 2024;11:131&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosny S, Almasry M, Almasry M. Effect of A Designing Nursing Infection Control Protocol on Operating Room Nurses Performance, A Comparative Study. Assiut Sci Nurs J. 2021;9:100&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eldesouky IME, AL Awamleh RA, Ahmed HAE, Abdelal MMI, Abdelaal AAH. Impact of Coaching Intervention Program on Nurses' Performance Regarding Caring for Patients Undergoing Percutaneous Nephrostomy Tube. Egypt J Health Care. 2024;15:888&#x2013;896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albarmawi M, Al Hadid L, Alnjadat R, Aljabery A. A multi-institute, follow-up, observational study measuring nursing students' adherence to infection prevention and control protocols in Saudi Arabia. Front Med (Lausanne) 2023;10:1282723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10808488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38274447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulay MV, Naik SD, Wyawahare AS, Mahajan SM, Kulkarni SS. Awareness and monitoring of infection control practices among healthcare workers in three primary health centers in India. GMS Hyg Infect Control. 2024;19:Doc59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11638719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39677009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amavasi B, Zimmerman PA. Infection prevention and control continuous education and training in pre-registration nursing programmes. Nurse Educ Today. 2024;133:106051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38035497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Xiao Y, Yue X, Wang Q. Safety and efficacy of enhanced recovery after surgery among patients undergoing percutaneous nephrolithotomy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Surg. 2024;110:3768&#x2013;3777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11175736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38349202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo BFY, Goh YS, Zhou W. Understanding the gender gap in advanced practice nursing: A qualitative study. J Nurs Manag. 2022;30:4480&#x2013;4490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10099508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36325680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masibo RM, Kibusi SM, Masika GM. Gender dynamics in nursing profession: impact on professional practice and development in Tanzania. BMC Health Serv Res. 2024;24:1179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11451068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39363160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed Helmy N, Anwar Aly A, Reafaat Abdelkader Atia R, Mahrous Abdel Hameed Mohammed B, Gamal Mohamed Ellatif Abouelezz Z. Effect of Educational Guidelines on Nurses' Performance regarding Percutaneous Nephrostomy Tube. Egypt J Health Care. 2023;14:578&#x2013;593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed S, Ghanem H, Hassan A, Khalil S. Assessment of Nurses&#x2019; Knowledge and Practice for Patients Undergoing a Bronchoscopy [Suggested Nursing Care Guidelines] Assiut Sci Nurs J. 2020;8:83&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a D, Baz&#xe1;n MJA, P&#xe9;rez-Rivas FJ. Correlation between Health and eHealth Literacy and a Healthy Lifestyle: A Cross-Sectional Study of Spanish Primary Healthcare Patients. Healthcare (Basel) 2023;11:2980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10671402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37998472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed D, Abdallah A, Mehany M, Mahgoub A. Effect of implementing nursing guidelines on reduction of acute Complications for patient with Percutaneous nephrostomy admitted to emergency unit. Assiut Sci Nurs J. 2022;10:218&#x2013;230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussien AH, Khalil SS, Mohammed GT. Effect of Nursing Educational Protocol on Nurses&#x2019; Knowledge and Practice Regarding Septicemia among Burned Patients. ARC J Nurs Healthcare. 2019;5:19&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed GT, Hassan AM, Abo Elmagd NS, Gamal NM, Saleh ZMM, Khalil S. COVID-19: Knowledge, perception and infection control practice of health care workers (A suggested ward-based educational package) Assiut Sci Nurs J. 2020;8:175&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohd Assiri FF, Dahl Alanazi MM, Mohmmad Alanazi NT, Saqer Alruwaili NW, Nihal Alruwaili SQ, Anoud Asiri FM, Mashael Alanazy HS, Eman Alruwaili FS, Alanazi HS, Intisar Ali AA, Musnad O Alanazi A. The Role of Nurses in Preventing Hospital-Acquired Infections. Int J Comp Exp Sci Eng. 2024;10:2513&#x2013;2526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhumaid S, Al Mutair A, Al Alawi Z, Alsuliman M, Ahmed GY, Rabaan AA, Al-Tawfiq JA, Al-Omari A. Knowledge of infection prevention and control among healthcare workers and factors influencing compliance: a systematic review. Antimicrob Resist Infect Control. 2021;10:86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8173512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34082822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asif M, Jameel A, Hussain A, Hwang J, Sahito N. Linking Transformational Leadership with Nurse-Assessed Adverse Patient Outcomes and the Quality of Care: Assessing the Role of Job Satisfaction and Structural Empowerment. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16:2381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6651060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31277478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alanazi NH, Alshamlani Y, Baker OG. The association between nurse managers' transformational leadership and quality of patient care: A systematic review. Int Nurs Rev. 2023;70:175&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36583960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah N, Castro-S&#xe1;nchez E, Charani E, Drumright LN, Holmes AH. Towards changing healthcare workers' behaviour: a qualitative study exploring non-compliance through appraisals of infection prevention and control practices. J Hosp Infect. 2015;90:126&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25820128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ariosto DA, Harper EM, Wilson ML, Hull SC, Nahm ES, Sylvia ML. Population health: a nursing action plan. JAMIA Open. 2018;1:7&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6951917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31984313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed N, Ahmed G, Khalil S. Effect of Nursing Protocol on Nurses' Performance and Venous Thromboembolism Risks among the Patients with Cancer Undergoing Surgery. Assiut Sci Nurs J. 2020;8:22&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasab N, Basal A, EL-Tatawy H, Mohamed A. Effect of Implementing Nursing Guidelines on Clinical Outcomes for Patients Undergoing Extracorporeal Shock Waves Lithotripsy for Urolithiasis. Tanta Sci Nurs J. 2023;28:86&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serdar CC, Cihan M, Y&#xfc;cel D, Serdar MA. Sample size, power and effect size revisited: simplified and practical approaches in pre-clinical, clinical and laboratory studies. Biochem Med (Zagreb) 2021;31:010502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7745163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33380887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faber J, Fonseca LM. How sample size influences research outcomes. Dental Press J Orthod. 2014;19:27&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4296634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25279518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez Cacho LM, Ayesa Arriola R. Health Education Intervention for Patients Undergoing Placement of Percutaneous Nephrostomy Tube: A Randomized Controlled Trial. J Wound Ostomy Continence Nurs. 2021;48:307&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34117190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd El-Fatah Ibrahim R, Talaat Elshamaa E, Hamed Mahmoud M, Abd El-Salam Sheta H. Effect of Educational Guidelines Prior Nephrolithotripsy on Patients' Performance and Satisfaction. J Nurs Sci Benha Univ. 2022;3:728&#x2013;744.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>