<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41822249</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Divergent Mechanisms of Antidepressant Efficacy: A Unified Computational Comparison of Synaptogenesis, Stabilization, and Tonic Inhibition in a Model of Depression.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e105040</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e105040</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e105040</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.105040</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Major depressive disorder (MDD) is increasingly viewed as a disorder of impaired neural plasticity, yet the mechanisms underlying diverse antidepressant classes - glutamatergic (e.g., ketamine), monoaminergic (e.g., selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs)), and GABAergic (e.g., neurosteroids) - remain incompletely integrated. The objective of this study was to extend a pruning-plasticity model of depression and directly compare, from an identical severely pruned baseline state, the efficacy, stress resilience, durability, and relapse vulnerability of three mechanistically distinct interventions: ketamine-like targeted synaptogenesis, SSRI-like gradual refinement of existing connectivity, and neurosteroid-like tonic inhibition. Computational models offer a controlled means to compare these pathways, but prior work has typically examined single mechanisms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We extended a pruning-plasticity model of depression by applying 95% magnitude-based synaptic elimination to overparameterized feed-forward networks trained on a four-class Gaussian classification task. From identical pruned states, three interventions were tested: ketamine-like gradient-guided regrowth (50% reinstatement) with consolidation; SSRI-like prolonged low-learning-rate training with gradual internal noise reduction; and neurosteroid-like global tonic inhibition (30% damping plus tanh activations) with brief consolidation. Outcomes included baseline accuracy, resilience to graded internal activation noise (up to &#x3c3; = 2.5) plus input perturbation, and relapse vulnerability after an additional 40% pruning.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">All treatments restored near-ceiling performance on unchallenged inputs. Ketamine-like synaptogenesis uniquely reduced sparsity (to ~47%) and conferred superior stress resilience (extreme noise accuracy 84.5%) with near-zero relapse drop (-0.2%). SSRI-like refinement improved combined stress accuracy to 83.5% but showed limited extreme noise tolerance (44.0%) and substantial relapse vulnerability (10.8% drop). Neurosteroid-like inhibition achieved rapid combined stress recovery (97.5%) while active, but was state-dependent (decline upon removal) with poor extreme noise buffering (42.5%) and moderate relapse drop (4.1%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These simulations demonstrate that antidepressants operate through mechanistically distinct routes-structural rebuilding (ketamine), gradual optimization of existing connectivity (SSRIs), or reversible dynamic stabilization (neurosteroids)-yielding trade-offs in onset speed, durability, and stress resilience. The findings support a multifaceted plasticity framework for depression and provide computational rationale for mechanism-based treatment selection and combination strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Cheung et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheung</LastName><ForeName>Ngo</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychiatry, Cheung Ngo Medical Limited, Hong Kong, HKG.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">computational psychiatry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ketamine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurosteroid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (ssris)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve human participants or tissue. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41822249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12978026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.105040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. World Health Organization; 2022. World Mental Health Report: Transforming Mental Health For All.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute and longer-term outcomes in depressed outpatients requiring one or several treatment steps: a STAR*D report. Rush AJ, Trivedi MH, Wisniewski SR, et al. Am J Psychiatry. 2006;163:1905&#x2013;1917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17074942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of outcomes with citalopram for depression using measurement-based care in STAR*D: implications for clinical practice. Trivedi MH, Rush AJ, Wisniewski SR, et al. Am J Psychiatry. 2006;163:28&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16390886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antidepressant efficacy of ketamine in treatment-resistant major depression: a two-site randomized controlled trial. Murrough JW, Iosifescu DV, Chang LC, et al. Am J Psychiatry. 2013;170:1134&#x2013;1142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3992936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23982301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ketamine and other N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor antagonists in the treatment of depression: a perspective review. Iadarola ND, Niciu MJ, Richards EM, et al. Ther Adv Chronic Dis. 2015;6:97&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4416968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25954495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Development of neuroactive steroids for the treatment of postpartum depression. Gunduz-Bruce H, Takahashi K, Huang MY. J Neuroendocrinol. 2022;34:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9285576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34462985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preclinical and clinical pharmacology of brexanolone (allopregnanolone) for postpartum depression: a landmark journey from concept to clinic in neurosteroid replacement therapy. Reddy DS, Mbilinyi RH, Estes E. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 2023;240:1841&#x2013;1863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10471722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37566239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Synaptic dysfunction in depression: potential therapeutic targets. Duman RS, Aghajanian GK. Science. 2012;338:68&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4424898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23042884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyond the serotonin deficit hypothesis: communicating a neuroplasticity framework of major depressive disorder. Page CE, Epperson CN, Novick AM, Duffy KA, Thompson SM. Mol Psychiatry. 2024;29:3802&#x2013;3813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11692567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38816586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Computational psychiatry as a bridge from neuroscience to clinical applications. Huys QJ, Maia TV, Frank MJ. Nat Neurosci. 2016;19:404&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5443409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26906507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Computational Psychiatry: towards a mathematically informed understanding of mental illness. Adams RA, Huys QJ, Roiser JP. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87:53&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4717449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26157034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simulating synaptic pruning and ketamine-like recovery in depression: insights from consolidation duration and iterative regimens on resilience and relapse. Cheung N. Zenodo. 2026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuroplasticity in cognitive and psychological mechanisms of depression: an integrative model. Price RB, Duman R. Mol Psychiatry. 2020;25:530&#x2013;543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7047599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31801966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ketamine: a paradigm shift for depression research and treatment. Krystal JH, Abdallah CG, Sanacora G, Charney DS, Duman RS. Neuron. 2019;101:774&#x2013;778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6560624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30844397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanism of action of serotonin selective reuptake inhibitors: Serotonin receptors and pathways mediate therapeutic effects and side effects. Stahl SM. J Affect Disord. 1998;51:215&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10333979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The complex clinical response to selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors in depression: a network perspective. Boschloo L, Hieronymus F, Lisinski A, Cuijpers P, Eriksson E. Transl Psychiatry. 2023;13:19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9867733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36681669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>