<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41678671</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1535-1386</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>108</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of bone and joint surgery. American volume</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Bone Joint Surg Am</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhancing Patient Comprehension in Orthopaedic Surgery: The EXPLAIN Framework for Surgeon-Patient Communication.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>482</StartPage><EndPage>490</EndPage><MedlinePgn>482-490</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2106/JBJS.25.01047</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>&#x27a2; Patient comprehension in orthopaedic surgery is frequently limited, with substantial gaps between perceived and actual understanding of conditions, procedures, and recovery timelines.&#x27a2; Expectation management is a central communication challenge, as patients often anticipate surgery or outcomes in ways that are unrealistic, directly affecting satisfaction and informed consent.&#x27a2; The EXPLAIN framework provides a structured, orthopaedic-specific approach to improve communication through 7 components: Educate, eXample, Purpose, Language/Learn, Analogy/Articulate, Illustrate, and Navigate.&#x27a2; Evidence supports the use of strategies such as plain language, teach-back, anatomical models, 3-dimensional aids, and structured navigation programs to improve comprehension, reduce anxiety, and lower readmissions.&#x27a2; Implementing EXPLAIN can enhance shared decision-making, reduce communication-related malpractice risk, and improve both patient satisfaction and outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by The Journal of Bone and Joint Surgery, Incorporated.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hershfeld</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4536-1278</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northwell, New Hyde Park, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Northwell Health - Huntington Hospital, Huntington, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Donald and Barbara Zucker School of Medicine at Hofstra/Northwell, Hempstead, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lucido</LastName><ForeName>Christine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-7282-6928</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northwell, New Hyde Park, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Northwell Health - Huntington Hospital, Huntington, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Donald and Barbara Zucker School of Medicine at Hofstra/Northwell, Hempstead, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cohn</LastName><ForeName>Randy M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9876-1497</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northwell, New Hyde Park, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Northwell Health - Huntington Hospital, Huntington, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Donald and Barbara Zucker School of Medicine at Hofstra/Northwell, Hempstead, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mont</LastName><ForeName>Michael A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Rubin Institute, Sinai Hospital of Baltimore, Baltimore, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bitterman</LastName><ForeName>Adam D</ForeName><Initials>AD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4905-5796</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northwell, New Hyde Park, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Northwell Health - Huntington Hospital, Huntington, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Donald and Barbara Zucker School of Medicine at Hofstra/Northwell, Hempstead, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Bone Joint Surg Am</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0014030</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0021-9355</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D032882" MajorTopicYN="Y">Comprehension</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010817" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physician-Patient Relations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019637" MajorTopicYN="Y">Orthopedic Procedures</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003142" MajorTopicYN="Y">Communication</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010353" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Education as Topic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017060" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Satisfaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007258" MajorTopicYN="N">Informed Consent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000080536" MajorTopicYN="N">Decision Making, Shared</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Disclosure: The Disclosure of Potential Conflicts of Interest forms are provided with the online version of the article ( http://links.lww.com/JBJS/J105 ).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41678671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.25.01047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004623-990000000-01718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kadakia RJ, Tsahakis JM, Issar NM, Archer KR, Jahangir AA, Sethi MK, Obremskey WT, Mir HR. Health literacy in an orthopedic trauma patient population: a cross-sectional survey of patient comprehension. J Orthop Trauma. 2013 Aug;27(8):467-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosic F, Kimmel L, Edwards E. Patient comprehension of common orthopedic terminology. Health Lit Res Pract. 2019 Aug 8;3(3):e187-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quigley DD, Elliott MN, Farley DO, Burkhart Q, Skootsky SA, Hays RD. Specialties differ in which aspects of doctor communication predict overall physician ratings. J Gen Intern Med. 2014 Mar;29(3):447-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hershfeld B, Klein B, White PB, Mont MA, Bitterman AD. Informed consent in orthopaedic surgery: a primer. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2024 Mar 6;106(5):472-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum ZC, Lyles CR. What&#x2019;s important: health literacy in orthopaedics. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2024 Nov 6;106(21):2042-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braddock CH 3rd, Edwards KA, Hasenberg NM, Laidley TL, Levinson W. Informed decision making in outpatient practice: time to get back to basics. JAMA. 1999 Dec 22-29;282(24):2313-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Reilly OC, Shamrock AG, Rosenbaum M, Clark CR, Patterson BM. Physician-patient communication in the orthopedic clinic: surgeon-identified challenges. Iowa Orthop J. 2022 Jun;42(1):275-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldchmit SM, de Queiroz MC, Dos Anjos Rabelo ND, Junior WR, Polesello GC. Patient education in orthopedics: the role of information design and user experience. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2021 Feb;14(1):9-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lans A, Bales JR, Fourman MS, Borkhetaria PP, Verlaan JJ, Schwab JH. Health literacy in orthopedic surgery: a systematic review. HSS J. 2023 Feb;19(1):120-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan LY, Yam GJM. Three-dimensional printed anatomical models as an educational tool for orthopaedic surgical trainees - a single institution experience. J Clin Orthop Trauma. 2024 Dec 24;62:102885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seely KD, Higgs JA, Butts L, Roe JM, Merrill CB, Zapata I, Nigh A. The &#x201c;teach-back&#x201d; method improves surgical informed consent and shared decision-making: a proof of concept study. Patient Saf Surg. 2022 Oct 28;16(1):33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright MA, Murthi AM, Aleem A, Zmistowski B. Patient disparities and provider diversity in orthopaedic surgery: a complex relationship. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2023 Feb 1;31(3):132-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badarudeen S, Sabharwal S. Assessing readability of patient education materials: current role in orthopaedics. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2010 Oct;468(10):2572-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira DC, Vieira I, Pedro MI, Caldas P, Varela M. Patient satisfaction with healthcare services and the techniques used for its assessment: a systematic literature review and a bibliometric analysis. Healthcare (Basel). 2023 Feb 21;11(5):639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waryasz GR, Gil JA, Kosinski LR, Chiou D, Schiller JR. Patient comprehension of hip arthroscopy: an investigation of health literacy. J Hip Preserv Surg. 2020 Jun 15;7(2):340-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbaum AJ, Dunkman A, Goldberg D, Uhl RL, Mulligan M. A cross-sectional study of musculoskeletal health literacy in patients with carpal tunnel syndrome. Hand (N Y). 2016 Sep;11(3):330-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbaum AJ, Marinescu AG, Levine D, Ellis SJ. Republication of &#x201c;Cross-sectional assessment of orthopedic foot and ankle patient knowledge&#x201d;. Foot Ankle Orthop. 2023 Jul 23;8(3):24730114231188095.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milone MT, Karim A, Klifto CS, Capo JT. Analysis of expected costs of carpal tunnel syndrome treatment strategies. Hand (N Y). 2019 May;14(3):317-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker CA. Promoting personal health literacy through readability, understandability, and actionability of online patient education materials. J Am Heart Assoc. 2024 Apr 16;13(8):e033916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagley CH, Hunter AR, Bacarese-Hamilton IA. Patients&#x2019; misunderstanding of common orthopaedic terminology: the need for clarity. Ann R Coll Surg Engl. 2011 Jul;93(5):401-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirsch M, Brown S, Smith BW, Chang KWC, Koduri S, Yang LJS. The presence and persistence of unrealistic expectations in patients undergoing nerve surgery. Neurosurgery. 2020 Jun 1;86(6):778-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunzli S, O&#x2019;Brien P, Klem N, Incoll I, Singh J, Davaris M, Choong P, Dowsey M. Misconceived expectations: patient reflections on the total knee replacement journey. Musculoskeletal Care. 2020 Dec;18(4):415-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattad PB, Pacifico L. Empowering patients: promoting patient education and health literacy. Cureus. 2022 Jul 27;14(7):e27336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutilli CC. Excellence in patient education: evidence-based education that &#x201c;sticks&#x201d; and improves patient outcomes. Nurs Clin North Am. 2020 Jun;55(2):267-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zambouri A. Preoperative evaluation and preparation for anesthesia and surgery. Hippokratia. 2007 Jan;11(1):13-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takemura Y, Sakurai Y, Yokoya S, Otaki J, Matsuoka T, Ban N, Hirata I, Miki T, Tsuda T. Open-ended questions: are they really beneficial for gathering medical information from patients? Tohoku J Exp Med. 2005 Jun;206(2):151-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satteson ES, Roe AK, Eppler SL, Yao J, Shapiro LM, Kamal RN. Development and testing of a question prompt list for common hand conditions: an exploratory sequential mixed-methods study. J Hand Surg Am. 2020 Nov;45(11):1087.e1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bl&#xf6;ndal K, Sveinsd&#xf3;ttir H, Ingadottir B. Patients&#x2019; expectations and experiences of provided surgery-related patient education: a descriptive longitudinal study. Nurs Open. 2022 Sep;9(5):2495-505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez AU, Dos Anjos GQ, de Oliveira DGC, Lima JA, de Lira MS, Costa J&#xfa;nior MA, de Almeida MBV, Heilmann RM, Rolim Filho EL. Impact of 3D-printed anatomical models on doctor-patient communication in orthopedic consultations: a randomized clinical trial. Cureus. 2024 Oct 4;16(10):e70822.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar P, Vatsya P, Rajnish RK, Hooda A, Dhillon MS. Application of 3D printing in hip and knee arthroplasty: a narrative review. Indian J Orthop. 2020 Oct 6;55(Suppl 1):14-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards PK, Mears SC, Lowry Barnes C. Preoperative education for hip and knee replacement: never stop learning. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2017 Sep;10(3):356-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mian SY, Jayasangaran S, Qureshi A, Hughes MA. Exploring the impact of using patient-specific 3D prints during consent for skull base neurosurgery. J Neurol Surg B Skull Base. 2022 Sep 13;84(5):463-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao CX, Yam M. Role of patient specific 3D printed models in patient confidence, understanding and satisfaction of care in Singapore. J Orthop. 2024 Feb 10;52:28-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang YD, Zhou MC, Liu SC, Wu JF, Wang R, Chen CM. Effectiveness of personalized 3D printed models for patient education in degenerative lumbar disease. Patient Educ Couns. 2019 Oct;102(10):1875-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas CN, Mavrommatis S, Schroder LK, Cole PA. An overview of 3D printing and the orthopaedic application of patient-specific models in malunion surgery. Injury. 2022 Mar;53(3):977-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendon&#xe7;a CJA, Guimar&#xe3;es RMDR, Pontim CE, Gasoto SC, Setti JAP, Soni JF, Schneider B Jr. An overview of 3D anatomical model printing in orthopedic trauma surgery. J Multidiscip Healthc. 2023 Apr 4;16:875-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacMahon A, Cody EA, Caolo K, Henry JK, Drakos MC, Demetracopoulos CA, Savenkov A, Ellis SJ. Comparison of patients&#x2019; and surgeons&#x2019; expectations in foot and ankle surgery. Foot Ankle Int. 2020 Oct;41(10):1173-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, Yu J, Chiu YL, Hsu YT. Can online health information sources really improve patient satisfaction? Front Public Health. 2022 Aug 5;10:940800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradis BE, Klein BJ, Bartlett LE, Cohn RM, Bitterman AD. Goals of care discussions in orthopaedic surgery: geriatric hip fractures. J Arthroplasty. 2024 May;39(5):1144-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarze ML, Kruser JM, Clapp JT. F. JAMA Surg. 2023 Oct 1;158(10):994-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotlieb R, Praska C, Hendrickson MA, Marmet J, Charpentier V, Hause E, Allen KA, Lunos S, Pitt MB. Accuracy in patient understanding of common medical phrases. JAMA Netw Open. 2022 Nov 1;5(11):e2242972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vranceanu AM, Elbon M, Adams M, Ring D. The emotive impact of medical language. Hand (N Y). 2012 Sep;7(3):293-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson KM, Leister S, De Rego R. The 5Ts for teach back: an operational definition for teach-back training. Health Lit Res Pract. 2020 Apr 9;4(2):e94-103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dayaa JA, Howard M, Li W, Doctor D. Ask-tell-ask with bidirectional feedback improves feedback culture. Acad Psychiatry. 2024 Oct;48(5):420-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez JE, Vasan N, Huff S, Melovitz-Vasan C. Learning styles/preferences among medical students: kinesthetic learner&#x2019;s multimodal approach to learning anatomy. Med Sci Educ. 2020 Aug 27;30(4):1633-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roark CL, Lescht E, Hampton Wray A, Chandrasekaran B. Auditory and visual category learning in children and adults. Dev Psychol. 2023 May;59(5):963-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JS, P&#xe9;rez-Stable EJ, Gregorich SE, Crawford MH, Green A, Livaudais-Toman J, Karliner LS. Increased access to professional interpreters in the hospital improves informed consent for patients with limited English proficiency. J Gen Intern Med. 2017 Aug;32(8):863-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. The CDC Clear Communication Index. 2013. Accessed 2025 Dec 12. https://www.cdc.gov/ccindex/index.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yen PH, Leasure AR. Use and effectiveness of the teach-back method in patient education and health outcomes. Fed Pract. 2019 Jun;36(6):284-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bidlespacher K, Mulkey DC. The effect of teach-back on readmission rates in rehabilitation patients. Rehabil Nurs. 2024 Mar-Apr 01;49(2):65-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green UR, Dearmon V, Taggart H. Improving transition of care for veterans after total joint replacement. Orthop Nurs. 2015 Mar-Apr;34(2):79-86, quiz 87-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahajan M, Hogewoning JA, Zewald JJA, Kerkmeer M, Feitsma M, van Rijssel DA. The impact of teach-back on patient recall and understanding of discharge information in the emergency department: the Emergency Teach-Back (EM-TeBa) study. Int J Emerg Med. 2020 Sep 24;13(1):49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talevski J, Wong Shee A, Rasmussen B, Kemp G, Beauchamp A. Teach-back: a systematic review of implementation and impacts. PLoS One. 2020 Apr 14;15(4):e0231350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson MI, Hudson M, Ryan CG. Perspectives on the insidious nature of pain metaphor: we literally need to change our metaphors. Front Pain Res (Lausanne). 2023 Sep 15;4:1224139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatehi A, Table B, Peck S, Mackert M, Ring D. Medical metaphors: increasing clarity but at what cost? Arch Bone Jt Surg. 2022 Aug;10(8):721-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad GV. How the creative use of analogies can shape medical practice. J Eval Clin Pract. 2015 Jun;21(3):455-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pena GP, Andrade-Filho JdeS. Analogies in medicine: valuable for learning, reasoning, remembering and naming. Adv Health Sci Educ Theory Pract. 2010 Oct;15(4):609-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hildenbrand GM. The influence of physician use of analogies on patient understanding and perceptions of physician. West Lafayette: Purdue University Graduate School; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ten Have H, Gordijn B. Metaphors in medicine. Med Health Care Philos. 2022 Dec;25(4):577-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reviewer P, Reviewer S. The patient experience in medical imaging: a qualitative systematic review (protocol). JBI Libr Syst Rev. 2010;8(8)(Suppl):1-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutruel SP, Hentel KD, Hecht EM, Kadom N. Patient-centered radiology communications: engaging patients as partners. J Am Coll Radiol. 2024 Jan;21(1):7-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recht MP, Westerhoff M, Doshi AM, Young M, Ostrow D, Swahn DM, Krueger S, Thesen S. Video radiology reports: a valuable tool to improve patient-centered radiology. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2022 Sep;219(3):509-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Oirschot G, Pomphrey A, Dunne C, Murphy K, Blood K, Doherty C. An evaluation of the design of multimedia patient education materials in musculoskeletal health care: systematic review. JMIR Rehabil Assist Technol. 2024 Oct 15;11:e48154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galmarini E, Marciano L, Schulz PJ. The effectiveness of visual-based interventions on health literacy in health care: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Health Serv Res. 2024 Jun 11;24(1):718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrorie AD, Donnelly C, McGlade KJ. Infographics: healthcare communication for the digital age. Ulster Med J. 2016 May;85(2):71-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill B, Perri-Moore S, Kuang J, Bray BE, Ngo L, Doig A, Zeng-Treitler Q. Automated pictographic illustration of discharge instructions with Glyph: impact on patient recall and satisfaction. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2016 Nov;23(6):1136-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alowais SA, Alghamdi SS, Alsuhebany N, Alqahtani T, Alshaya AI, Almohareb SN, Aldairem A, Alrashed M, Bin Saleh K, Badreldin HA, Al Yami MS, Al Harbi S, Albekairy AM. Revolutionizing healthcare: the role of artificial intelligence in clinical practice. BMC Med Educ. 2023 Sep 22;23(1):689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabharwal S, Badarudeen S, Unes Kunju S. Readability of online patient education materials from the AAOS web site. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2008 May;466(5):1245-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hand C, Bohn C, Tannir S, Ulrich M, Saniei S, Girod-Hoffman M, Lu Y, Forsythe B. American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons OrthoInfo provides more readable information regarding rotator cuff injury than ChatGPT. J ISAKOS. 2025 Jun;12:100841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips JLH, Rondon AJ, Vannello C, Fillingham YA, Austin MS, Courtney PM. A Nurse Navigator Program is effective in reducing episode-of-care costs following primary hip and knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty. 2019 Aug;34(8):1557-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Predmore Z, Hero J, Dellva S, Burns R, Peltz A, Ryan J. Exploring patient care navigation in the Medicare program. 2024. Accessed 2025 Dec 12. https://aspe.hhs.gov/reports/exploring-patient-care-navigation-medicare-program</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neshan M, Padmanaban V, Tsilimigras DI, Obeng-Gyasi S, Fareed N, Pawlik TM. Screening tools to address social determinants of health in the United States: a systematic review. J Clin Transl Sci. 2024 Apr 5;8(1):e60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budde H, Williams GA, Scarpetti G, Kroezen M, Maier CB. What are patient navigators and how can they improve integration of care? Copenhagen: European Observatory on Health Systems and Policies; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen LWH, Rahbek O, Lauritsen REK, Kold S, Dinesen B. Patient perspectives on communication pathways after orthopedic surgery and discharge and evaluation of team-based digital communication: qualitative exploratory study. JMIR Hum Factors. 2024 Mar 29;11:e49696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobbs RJ, Amin T, Stulberg SD, Kerina JM, Hernandez V, Bolander R. Remote monitoring using wearable technology after knee arthroplasty using a joint-specific wearable device: a prospective cohort study of 435 patients with 6-week follow-up. J Orthop Exp Innov. 2023 May 16;4(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacobelli F, Yang A, Tom L, Leung IS, Crissman J, Salgado R, Simon M. Predicting social determinants of health in patient navigation: case study. JMIR Form Res. 2023 Mar 28;7:e42683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng LJ, Goldsmith LJ, Sawhney M, Jussaume L. Hip and knee replacement patients&#x2019; experiences with an orthopaedic patient navigator: a qualitative study. Orthop Nurs. 2021 Sep-Oct 01;40(5):292-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright JG. Revised grades of recommendation for summaries or reviews of orthopaedic surgical studies. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2006 May;88(5):1161-2.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>