<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41792147</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effectiveness of pelvic floor rehabilitation after radical prostatectomy and continence recovery in relation to surgical technique.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-36972-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The potential influence of surgical technique and pelvic floor rehabilitation on continence recovery continues to be debated. This prospective cohort study included 182 men undergoing robot-assisted or laparoscopic radical prostatectomy. All patients were referred for physiotherapist-guided pelvic floor muscle training. Urinary incontinence was assessed using a standardized 1-h pad test and a three-stage UI grading system at 1, 3, and 6&#xa0;months after catheter removal. Ordinal and logistic regression models were used to identify predictors of continence, including surgical technique, age, pathological features, and rehabilitation-related variables. Exploratory time-to-event analyses (Cox proportional hazards models) were also performed to assess the dynamics of continence recovery, with catheter removal as time zero and achievement of full continence (pad test&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;2&#xa0;g) as the event. Patients undergoing RARP demonstrated higher odds of early full continence shortly after surgery (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;5.26; 95% CI 2.34-11.80; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) and functional continence (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.00; 95% CI 1.96-8.14; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). After adjustment for baseline incontinence severity, surgical technique was no longer an independent predictor of continence recovery. However, in multivariable analyses, baseline incontinence severity and timing of rehabilitation were the strongest independent predictors of continence recovery. Robotic prostatectomy is associated with a more favorable continence status at the start of rehabilitation, whereas continence recovery during physiotherapy is primarily determined by baseline incontinence severity and timely initiation of pelvic floor therapy rather than surgical approach. These results highlight the need to integrate precise surgical techniques with standardized, early, and individualized physiotherapy to optimize continence recovery and improving quality of life after radical prostatectomy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Terek-Derszniak</LastName><ForeName>Ma&#x142;gorzata</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Holycross Cancer Centre, Kielce, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>G&#x105;sior-Perczak</LastName><ForeName>Danuta</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Collegium Medicum Jan Kochanowski University of Kielce, Kielce, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Endocrinology Clinic, Holycross Cancer Centre, Kielce, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biskup</LastName><ForeName>Ma&#x142;gorzata</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Holycross Cancer Centre, Kielce, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Collegium Medicum Jan Kochanowski University of Kielce, Kielce, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Skowronek</LastName><ForeName>Tomasz</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Holycross Cancer Centre, Kielce, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nowak</LastName><ForeName>Mariusz</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Holycross Cancer Centre, Kielce, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Falana</LastName><ForeName>Justyna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oncology Clinic, Holycross Cancer Centre, Kielce, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaskulski</LastName><ForeName>Jaros&#x142;aw</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Collegium Medicum Jan Kochanowski University of Kielce, Kielce, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Holycross Cancer Centre, Kielce, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Obarzanowski</LastName><ForeName>Mateusz</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Collegium Medicum Jan Kochanowski University of Kielce, Kielce, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Holycross Cancer Centre, Kielce, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gozdz</LastName><ForeName>Stanislaw</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Collegium Medicum Jan Kochanowski University of Kielce, Kielce, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oncology Clinic, Holycross Cancer Centre, Kielce, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Macek</LastName><ForeName>Pawel</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Collegium Medicum Jan Kochanowski University of Kielce, Kielce, Poland. pawel.macek@onkol.kielce.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Scientific Research, Epidemiology and R&amp;D Centre, Holycross Cancer Centre, Kielce, Poland. pawel.macek@onkol.kielce.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Laparoscopic surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic floor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognostic factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prostatectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Robot-assisted surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Urinary incontinence</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article. Ethical approval: This study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki and approved by the Bioethics Committee of Collegium Medicum, Jan Kochanowski University in Kielce, Poland (protocol number 34/2018; approval date: 28 May 2018). Consent to participate: Informed consent was obtained from all the subjects involved in this study. Consent for publication: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41792147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-36972-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-36972-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ma, J. et al. Robotic-Assisted versus Laparoscopic Radical Prostatectomy for Prostate Cancer: The First Separate Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Randomised Controlled Trials and Non-Randomised Studies. Int J Surg 109, 1350&#x2013;1359. https://doi.org/10.1097/JS9.0000000000000193 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castellan, P., Ferretti, S., Litterio, G., Marchioni, M. &amp; Schips, L. Management of Urinary Incontinence Following Radical Prostatectomy: Challenges and Solutions. Ther Clin Risk Manag 19, 43&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.2147/TCRM.S283305 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasai, T. et al. Duration and Influencing Factors of Postoperative Urinary Incontinence after Robot-Assisted Radical Prostatectomy in a Japanese Community Hospital: A Single-Center Retrospective Cohort Study. Int J Environ Res Public Health 20, 4085. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph20054085 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radoja, I. &amp; Degme&#x10d;i&#x107;, D. Urinary Incontinence: Diagnostic Evaluation and First-Line Treatment. Southeastern European Medical Journal&#x202f;: SEEMEDJ 4, 63&#x2013;73. https://doi.org/10.26332/seemedj.v4i1.133 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pak, S., Kim, M. &amp; Ahn, H. Changes in Health-Related Quality of Life after Radical Prostatectomy for Prostate Cancer: A Longitudinal Cohort Study in Korea. Investig Clin Urol 59, 313&#x2013;320. https://doi.org/10.4111/icu.2018.59.5.313 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gacci, M. et al. Urinary and Sexual Outcomes in Long-Term (5+ Years) Prostate Cancer Disease Free Survivors after Radical Prostatectomy. Health Qual Life Outcomes 7, 94. https://doi.org/10.1186/1477-7525-7-94 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teo, J. L., Zheng, Z. &amp; Bird, S. R. Identifying the Factors Affecting &#x2018;Patient Engagement&#x2019; in Exercise Rehabilitation. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil 14, 18. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13102-022-00407-3 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Str&#x105;czy&#x144;ska, A. et al. The Impact Of Pelvic Floor Muscle Training On Urinary Incontinence In Men After Radical Prostatectomy (RP) &#x2013; A Systematic Review. CIA 14, 1997&#x2013;2005. https://doi.org/10.2147/CIA.S228222 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soto Gonz&#xe1;lez, M. et al. Early 3-Month Treatment with Comprehensive Physical Therapy Program Restores Continence in Urinary Incontinence Patients after Radical Prostatectomy: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Neurourol Urodyn 39, 1529&#x2013;1537. https://doi.org/10.1002/nau.24389 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lira, G. H. S. et al. Effects of Perioperative Pelvic Floor Muscle Training on Early Recovery of Urinary Continence and Erectile Function in Men Undergoing Radical Prostatectomy: A Randomized Clinical Trial. Int Braz J Urol 45, 1196&#x2013;1203. https://doi.org/10.1590/S1677-5538.IBJU.2019.0238 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farraj, H.; Alriyalat, S. Urinary Incontinence Following Robotic-Assisted Radical Prostatectomy: A Literature Review. Cureus 16, e53058, https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.53058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filocamo, M. T. et al. Effectiveness of Early Pelvic Floor Rehabilitation Treatment for Post-Prostatectomy Incontinence. Eur Urol 48, 734&#x2013;738. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eururo.2005.06.004 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gershman, B. et al. Patient-Reported Functional Outcomes Following Open, Laparoscopic, and Robotic Assisted Radical Prostatectomy Performed by High-Volume Surgeons at High-Volume Hospitals. Eur. Urol. Focus 2, 172&#x2013;179. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.euf.2015.06.011 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, J., Li, C., Liu, H.-Y. &amp; Zhu, Z.-Y. Relationship between Abnormal Pelvic Floor Electromyography and Obstetric Factors in Postpartum Women: A Cross-Sectional Study. BMC Women&#x2019;s Health 24, 239. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12905-024-03045-8 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tienza, A.; Robles ,Jose E.; Hevia ,Mateo; Algarra ,Ruben; Diez-Caballero ,Fernando; and Pascual, J.I. Prevalence Analysis of Urinary Incontinence after Radical Prostatectomy and Influential Preoperative Factors in a Single Institution. The Aging Male 2018, 21, 24&#x2013;30, https://doi.org/10.1080/13685538.2017.1369944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinkhasov, R. M. et al. Prediction of Incontinence after Robot-Assisted Radical Prostatectomy: Development and Validation of a 24-Month Incontinence Nomogram. Cancers (Basel) 14, 1644. https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers14071644 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Th&#xfc;roff, J. W. et al. EAU Guidelines on Urinary Incontinence. Eur. Urol. 59, 387&#x2013;400. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eururo.2010.11.021 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galfano, A. et al. Beyond the Learning Curve of the Retzius-Sparing Approach for Robot-Assisted Laparoscopic Radical Prostatectomy: Oncologic and Functional Results of the First 200 Patients with &#x2265; 1 Year of Follow-Up. Eur Urol 64, 974&#x2013;980. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eururo.2013.06.046 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asimakopoulos, A. D. et al. Retzius-Sparing versus Standard Robot-Assisted Radical Prostatectomy: A Prospective Randomized Comparison on Immediate Continence Rates. Surg Endosc 33, 2187&#x2013;2196. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00464-018-6499-z (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x130;nkaya, A. et al. Comparison of Surgical, Oncological, and Functional Outcomes of Robot-Assisted and Laparoscopic Radical Prostatectomy in Patients with Prostate Cancer. Turk J Urol 45, 410&#x2013;417. https://doi.org/10.5152/tud.2019.48457 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kural, A. R., Obek, C. &amp; Doganca, T. Can We Accomplish Better Oncological Results with Robot-Assisted Radical Prostatectomy?. J Endourol 31, S54&#x2013;S58. https://doi.org/10.1089/end.2016.0585 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Mauro, E. et al. Technical Modifications Employed in RARP to Improve Early Continence Recovery: A Literature Review. Life 15, 415. https://doi.org/10.3390/life15030415 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terek-Derszniak, M. et al. Pelvic Floor Rehabilitation After Prostatectomy: Baseline Severity as a Predictor of Improvement&#x2014;A Prospective Cohort Study. J. Clin. Med. 14, 4180. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm14124180 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, J. I., Lam, V. &amp; Patel, M. I. Preoperative Pelvic Floor Muscle Exercise and Postprostatectomy Incontinence: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Eur Urol 69, 460&#x2013;467. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eururo.2015.11.004 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goonewardene, S. S., Gillatt, D. &amp; Persad, R. A Systematic Review of PFE Pre-Prostatectomy. J Robot Surg 12, 397&#x2013;400. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11701-018-0803-8 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d&#x2019;Agate, D. et al. Patient Experience and Satisfaction after Same-Day Discharge Radical Prostatectomy Using a Personalized. Digital Perioperative Programme. World J Urol 42, 378. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00345-024-05099-7 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, K.; Bu, F.; Jian, T.; Liu, Z.; Hu, R.; Chen, S.; Lu, J. Urinary Incontinence Rehabilitation of after Radical Prostatectomy: A Systematic Review and Network Meta-Analysis. Front. Oncol. 2024, 13, https://doi.org/10.3389/fonc.2023.1307434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouchi, M. et al. Physiotherapy for Continence and Muscle Function in Prostatectomy: A Randomised Controlled Trial. BJU Int. 134, 398&#x2013;406. https://doi.org/10.1111/bju.16369 (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>