<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41754047</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2227-9032</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Healthcare (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Healthcare (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sex-Based Differences in Psychosocial Recovery Following Posterior Spinal Fusion for Adolescent Idiopathic Scoliosis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">534</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/healthcare14040534</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Background:</b> Although posterior spinal fusion (PSF) for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis (AIS) reliably improves radiographic alignment, radiological correction alone does not necessarily reflect postoperative recovery, particularly in terms of psychosocial well-being. Patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs) have become central to outcome assessment in AIS; however, the relative contributions of disease-specific and generic instruments, sex-based differences, and functional recovery, including return to sports, remain unclear. <b>Methods:</b> This prospective single-center cohort study encompassed adolescents aged 13-18 years who underwent PSF for AIS between December 2020 and November 2023. All included patients had a minimum postoperative follow-up of 24 months at the time of analysis. Health-related quality of life (HRQoL) was evaluated preoperatively and at least 2 years postoperatively using the Scoliosis Research Society-22 revised questionnaire (SRS-22r) and the Pediatric Quality of Life Inventory (PedsQL) Teen Report (ages 13-18 years). Outcomes were compared between male and female patients. Return to the preoperative level of sports was evaluated as a functional outcome. <b>Results:</b> Overall, 108 adolescents with AIS (32 males, 76 females) were included. Male patients were slightly older at the time of surgery, whereas baseline radiographic characteristics, treatment patterns, and follow-up duration were comparable between sexes. At preoperative assessment, male patients reported higher SRS-22r self-image and mental health scores compared with female patients (both <i>p</i> &lt; 0.001). These differences were no longer present at the last follow-up (all <i>p</i> &gt; 0.05). Emotional functioning improved significantly in both sexes (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.001), whereas changes in pain and physical function were limited. The total PedsQL score increased significantly in female patients but not in males (<i>p</i> = 0.521). Patients across all Lenke curve types demonstrated postoperative improvements. Those with Lenke type 1 exhibited higher mean changes in SRS-22r and PedsQL total scores; however, differences in change scores between Lenke types demonstrated no statistical significance. At final follow-up, 93.5% of patients had not returned to their preoperative level of physical activity. <b>Conclusions:</b> PSF for AIS was associated with domain-specific improvements in HRQoL, predominantly reflecting psychosocial domains rather than changes in pain or physical function. Preoperative sex-based differences resolve postoperatively, and patients with Lenke curve types demonstrate improvements, with a tendency toward greater gains in Lenke type 1. Despite these improvements, return to preoperative sport levels remains restricted, indicating a gap between patient-reported recovery and functional reintegration.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karaali</LastName><ForeName>Evren</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics and Traumatology, Adana City Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Adana 01230, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc7;ilo&#x11f;lu</LastName><ForeName>Osman</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics and Traumatology, Adana City Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Adana 01230, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keklik&#xe7;io&#x11f;lu</LastName><ForeName>Burak</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4246-8862</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics and Traumatology, Adana City Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Adana 01230, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc7;i&#xe7;ek</LastName><ForeName>O&#x11f;uzhan</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2268-4709</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics and Traumatology, Adana City Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Adana 01230, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G&#xfc;rb&#xfc;z</LastName><ForeName>H&#xfc;seyin Mehmet</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics and Traumatology, Adana City Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Adana 01230, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ar&#x131;c&#x131; G&#xfc;rb&#xfc;z</LastName><ForeName>Asiye</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Adana City Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Adana 01230, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yakar</LastName><ForeName>Mustafa Turan</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-8076-2276</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics and Traumatology, Adana City Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Adana 01230, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Healthcare (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101666525</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2227-9032</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adolescent idiopathic scoliosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health-related quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sex characteristics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spinal fusion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41754047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12940519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare14040534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">healthcare14040534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Barone G., Giudici F., Manzini F., Pironti P., Vigan&#xf2; M., Minoia L., Archetti M., Zagra A., Scaramuzzo L. Adolescent Idiopathic Scoliosis Surgery: Postoperative Functional Outcomes at 32 Years Mean Follow-Up. Children. 2024;11:52. doi: 10.3390/children11010052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/children11010052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10814093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38255365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruyama T., Takeshita K. Surgical treatment of scoliosis: A review of techniques currently applied. Spine. 2008;33:E302&#x2013;E309. doi: 10.1186/1748-7161-3-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-7161-3-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2346456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18423027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asher M., Lai S.M., Burton D., Manna B. The Scoliosis Research Society&#x2013;22 questionnaire: Responsiveness to change after surgery. Spine. 2003;28:70&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1097/00007632-200301010-00016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00007632-200301010-00016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12544959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carreon L.Y., Sanders J.O., Diab M., Sucato D.J., Sturm P.F., Glassman S.D. Determination of the minimum clinically important difference in SRS-22r outcomes after surgery for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Spine. 2018;43:E965&#x2013;E970.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varni J.W., Seid M., Kurtin P.S. The PedsQL&#x2122; 4.0 generic core scales: Reliability and validity. Med. Care. 2001;39:800&#x2013;812. doi: 10.1097/00005650-200108000-00006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005650-200108000-00006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11468499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tor&#xe9;n S., Diarbakerli E. Health-related quality of life in adolescents with idiopathic scoliosis: A cross-sectional study including healthy controls. Eur. Spine J. 2022;31:3512&#x2013;3518. doi: 10.1007/s00586-022-07428-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00586-022-07428-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36260134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan K.C.A., Lee K.M., Wong M.S. Relationship between SRS-22r and PedsQL in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Qual. Life Res. 2025;34:101&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ersberg A., Gerdhem P. Pre- and postoperative health-related quality of life in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Spine. 2013;38:1874&#x2013;1881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamrani S., Parent S., Labelle H. Content validity of the SRS-22r questionnaire in adolescents with idiopathic scoliosis. Spine J. 2021;21:1012&#x2013;1020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaleeq T., Sanders J.O., Browne R.H. Return to sports following posterior spinal fusion for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Eur. Spine J. 2024;33:412&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11888032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40061196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alanay A., Cil A., Berk H. Reliability and validity of the adapted Turkish version of the Scoliosis Research Society-22 (SRS-22) questionnaire. Spine. 2005;30:2464&#x2013;2468. doi: 10.1097/01.brs.0000184366.71761.84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.brs.0000184366.71761.84</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16261127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carreon L.Y., Glassman S.D., Sanders J.O. Subtotal versus total SRS-22 scoring in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Spine. 2018;43:E545&#x2013;E550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memik N.C., A&#x11f;ao&#x11f;lu B., Co&#x15f;kun A. The validity and reliability of the Turkish Pediatric Quality of Life Inventory (PedsQL) 4.0 Generic Core Scales. Turk. J. Pediatr. 2008;50:256&#x2013;262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tetreault T., Garg S., Erickson M. Return to play after posterior spinal fusion for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Spine. 2023;48:389&#x2013;396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruffilli A., Traina F., Faldini C. Sports participation after adolescent idiopathic scoliosis fusion surgery. Spine J. 2022;22:1615&#x2013;1622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamrani S., Parent S., Labelle H. Concept elicitation of health-related quality of life in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Spine Deform. 2023;11:845&#x2013;853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barone G., Bassani R., Borghi R. Long-term health-related quality of life outcomes after surgery for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Eur. Spine J. 2023;32:1981&#x2013;1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastrom T.P., Bartley C.E., Yaszay B. Impact of complications on SRS outcomes in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Spine. 2019;44:E515&#x2013;E521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghandhari H., Ameri E., Nikouei F. Long-term outcomes of posterior spinal fusion for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Spine Deform. 2018;6:451&#x2013;458. doi: 10.1186/s13013-018-0157-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13013-018-0157-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6090875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30123840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arima H., Takahashi S., Suzuki A. Patient satisfaction following surgery for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Spine. 2021;46:E289&#x2013;E295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari L., Rossi M., Bianchi A., Lungu C.N., Dragomirescu M.C., Charkaoui A. Clinical value of the SRS-30 questionnaire in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis outcomes. Medicina. 2022;58:674. doi: 10.3390/medicina58050674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/medicina58050674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9147138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35630090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tetreault T.A. Return to sport after spine surgery. Clin. Sports Med. 2023;42:95&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V., Sharma S., Mehta N. Return to sport after adolescent idiopathic scoliosis surgery: Current perspectives. Spine. 2023;48:845&#x2013;852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pishnamaz M., Schmid S.L., Eysel P. Long-term outcomes after fusion for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. EFORT Open Rev. 2024;9:97&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>