<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41676248</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1943-8141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of translational research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Transl Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Modified constraint-induced movement therapy improves functional recovery after ischemic stroke and its impacts on exosome-derived microRNAs.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>248</StartPage><EndPage>264</EndPage><MedlinePgn>248-264</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.62347/YBJF9113</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate whether modified constraint-induced movement therapy (mCIMT) improves brain function after stroke by increasing the concentrations of exosomes and microRNA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Blood samples from 16 stroke patients (mCIMT group N=8, control group N=8) were analyzed for cytokines and exosomal microRNAs. Data from electronic medical records and clinical outcomes were also correlated. For the animal model, SD rats underwent middle cerebral artery occlusion (MCAO). The mCIMT group received 2 hours of daily intensive limb training for 14 days, starting 7 days post-MCAO, while the control group was untreated. Exosomes were extracted from brain tissue on day 21, followed by nanoparticle tracking and microRNA sequencing. Exosomes from both groups, as well as a vehicle, were injected into the lateral ventricles of MCAO rats, and they were named the Exo-mCIMT group, Exo-control group and vehicle group. Behavioral tests and histopathological staining were performed on day 21 among the three groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">mCIMT significantly increased exosome content in the plasma of stroke patients, with exosome size correlated with the Fugl-Meyer Motor Function Assessment (FMA-UE, R<sup>2</sup>=0.428). In rats, the mCIMT group had a higher concentration of exosomes in brain tissue (3.73e+10 particles/ml) compared to the control group (0.95e+10 particles/ml, P=0.0030). MicroRNA sequencing revealed distinct expression profiles between the groups. Furthermore, the exo-mCIMT group exhibited significantly higher levels of MAP2 and VEGF expression, along with notable improvements in neurobehavioral outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These findings suggest that mCIMT promotes neural recovery through increased exosome and microRNA activity in the brain, which plays an important role in neuronal activity after brain injury.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>AJTR Copyright &#xa9; 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Beiyao</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ge</LastName><ForeName>Ruidong</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xing</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Zhongshan Hospital, Fudan University Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Peile</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Fujian Medical University Union Hospital Fuzhou, Fujian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Shan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, China-Japan Friendship Hospital Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Transl Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101493030</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1943-8141</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebral ischaemic injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exosomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mCIMT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stroke</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41676248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12886140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62347/YBJF9113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>de Azevedo JA, Barbosa FDS, Seixas VM, da Silva Scipioni KRD, Sampaio PYS, da Cruz DMC, Piscitelli D, Chui KK, de Freitas Zanona A. Effects of constraint-induced movement therapy on activity and participation after a stroke: systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Hum Neurosci. 2022;16:987061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9760712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36545351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tedla JS, Gular K, Reddy RS, de Sa Ferreira A, Rodrigues EC, Kakaraparthi VN, Gyer G, Sangadala DR, Qasheesh M, Kovela RK, Nambi G. Effectiveness of constraint-induced movement therapy (CIMT) on balance and functional mobility in the stroke population: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Healthcare (Basel) 2022;10:459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8949312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35326973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palomo-Carrion R, Romay-Barrero H, Romero-Galisteo RP, Pinero-Pinto E, Lopez-Munoz P, Martinez-Galan I. Modified constraint-induced movement therapy at home-is it possible? Families and children&#x2019;s experience. Children (Basel) 2020;7:248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7700425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33266393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sicari M, Longhi M, D&#x2019;Angelo G, Boetto V, Lavorato A, Cocchini L, Beatrici M, Battiston B, Garbossa D, Massazza G, Titolo P. Modified constraint induced movement therapy in children with obstetric brachial plexus palsy: a systematic review. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2022;58:43&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9980490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34747579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleet A, Page SJ, MacKay-Lyons M, Boe SG. Modified constraint-induced movement therapy for upper extremity recovery post stroke: what is the evidence? Top Stroke Rehabil. 2014;21:319&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25150664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi YX, Tian JH, Yang KH, Zhao Y. Modified constraint-induced movement therapy versus traditional rehabilitation in patients with upper-extremity dysfunction after stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2011;92:972&#x2013;982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21621674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu P, Li C, Zhang B, Zhang Z, Gao B, Liu Y, Wang Y, Hua Y, Hu J, Qiu X, Bai Y. Constraint induced movement therapy promotes contralesional-oriented structural and bihemispheric functional neuroplasticity after stroke. Brain Res Bull. 2019;150:201&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31181321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J, Li C, Hua Y, Zhang B, Gao BY, Liu PL, Sun LM, Lu RR, Wang YY, Bai YL. Constrained-induced movement therapy promotes motor function recovery by enhancing the remodeling of ipsilesional corticospinal tract in rats after stroke. Brain Res. 2019;1708:27&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30471245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr AL. Contralesional plasticity following constraint-induced movement therapy benefits outcome: contributions of the intact hemisphere to functional recovery. Rev Neurosci. 2021;33:269&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34761646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Li L, Zhang Q, Liang Z, Huang L, He C, Wei Q. Combination of electroacupuncture and constraint-induced movement therapy enhances functional recovery after ischemic stroke in rats. J Mol Neurosci. 2021;71:2116&#x2013;2125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34101150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullahi A, Truijen S, Saeys W. Neurobiology of recovery of motor function after stroke: the central nervous system biomarker effects of constraint-induced movement therapy. Neural Plast. 2020;2020:9484298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7312560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32617098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao BY, Xu DS, Liu PL, Li C, Du L, Hua Y, Hu J, Hou JY, Bai YL. Modified constraint-induced movement therapy alters synaptic plasticity of rat contralateral hippocampus following middle cerebral artery occlusion. Neural Regen Res. 2020;15:1045&#x2013;1057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7034265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31823884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu XH, Bi HY, Cao J, Ren S, Yue SW. Early constraint-induced movement therapy affects behavior and neuronal plasticity in ischemia-injured rat brains. Neural Regen Res. 2019;14:775&#x2013;782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6375040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30688263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcantara CC, Garcia-Salazar LF, Silva-Couto MA, Santos GL, Reisman DS, Russo TL. Post-stroke BDNF concentration changes following physical exercise: a systematic review. Front Neurol. 2018;9:637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6121011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30210424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiner CT, Pierce KD, Thompson-Butel AG, Trinh T, Schofield PR, McNulty PA. BDNF genotype interacts with motor function to influence rehabilitation responsiveness poststroke. Front Neurol. 2016;7:69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4868962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27242654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishida A, Misumi S, Ueda Y, Shimizu Y, Cha-Gyun J, Tamakoshi K, Ishida K, Hida H. Early constraint-induced movement therapy promotes functional recovery and neuronal plasticity in a subcortical hemorrhage model rat. Behav Brain Res. 2015;284:158&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25700666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livingston-Thomas JM, McGuire EP, Doucette TA, Tasker RA. Voluntary forced use of the impaired limb following stroke facilitates functional recovery in the rat. Behav Brain Res. 2014;261:210&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24388978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livingston-Thomas JM, Hume AW, Doucette TA, Tasker RA. A novel approach to induction and rehabilitation of deficits in forelimb function in a rat model of ischemic stroke. Acta Pharmacol Sin. 2013;34:104&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4086495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23103624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colvett I, Saternos H, Coughlan C, Vielle A, Ledreux A. Extracellular vesicles from the CNS play pivotal roles in neuroprotection and neurodegeneration: lessons from in vitro experiments. Extracell Vesicles Circ Nucl Acids. 2023;4:72&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10586524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37859665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez SH, Andrews AM, Paul D, Pachter JS. Extracellular vesicles: mediators and biomarkers of pathology along CNS barriers. Fluids Barriers CNS. 2018;15:19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6026502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29960602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirshman BR, Kras RT, Akers JC, Carter BS, Chen CC. Extracellular vesicles in molecular diagnostics: an overview with a focus on CNS diseases. Adv Clin Chem. 2016;76:37&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27645815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang X, Ren Y, Zeng W, Feng X, He M, Lv Y, Li Y, He Y. MicroRNA-based interventions in aberrant cell cycle diseases: Therapeutic strategies for cancers, central nervous system disorders and comorbidities. Biomed Pharmacother. 2024;177:116979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38906026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Mao L, Wang H. The neuroprotection effects of exosome in central nervous system injuries: a new target for therapeutic intervention. Mol Neurobiol. 2022;59:7152&#x2013;7169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36103108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, Hou K, Ji T, Wang X, Liu Y, Zheng Y, Xu J, Hou Y, Chi G. The role of exosomal microRNAs in central nervous system diseases. Mol Cell Biochem. 2021;476:2111&#x2013;2124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33528706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin H, Li Y, Chopp M. Exosomes/miRNAs as mediating cell-based therapy of stroke. Front Cell Neurosci. 2014;8:377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4226157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25426026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otero-Ortega L, Gomez de Frutos MC, Laso-Garcia F, Rodriguez-Frutos B, Medina-Gutierrez E, Lopez JA, Vazquez J, Diez-Tejedor E, Gutierrez-Fernandez M. Exosomes promote restoration after an experimental animal model of intracerebral hemorrhage. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2018;38:767&#x2013;779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5987932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28524762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascual M, Ibanez F, Guerri C. Exosomes as mediators of neuron-glia communication in neuroinflammation. Neural Regen Res. 2020;15:796&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6990780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31719239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao B, Chai Y, Lv S, Ye M, Wu M, Xie L, Fan Y, Zhu X, Gao Z. Endothelial cell-derived exosomes protect SH-SY5Y nerve cells against ischemia/reperfusion injury. Int J Mol Med. 2017;40:1201&#x2013;1209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5593464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28849073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin H, Li Y, Cui Y, Yang JJ, Zhang ZG, Chopp M. Systemic administration of exosomes released from mesenchymal stromal cells promote functional recovery and neurovascular plasticity after stroke in rats. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2013;33:1711&#x2013;1715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3824189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23963371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin H, Li Y, Liu Z, Wang X, Shang X, Cui Y, Zhang ZG, Chopp M. MiR-133b promotes neural plasticity and functional recovery after treatment of stroke with multipotent mesenchymal stromal cells in rats via transfer of exosome-enriched extracellular particles. Stem Cells. 2013;31:2737&#x2013;2746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3788061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23630198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin H, Li Y, Buller B, Katakowski M, Zhang Y, Wang X, Shang X, Zhang ZG, Chopp M. Exosome-mediated transfer of miR-133b from multipotent mesenchymal stromal cells to neural cells contributes to neurite outgrowth. Stem Cells. 2012;30:1556&#x2013;1564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3495063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22605481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurwitz SN, Olcese JM, Meckes DG Jr. Extraction of extracellular vesicles from whole tissue. J Vis Exp. 2019;7 10.3791/59143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7098067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30799860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vella LJ, Scicluna BJ, Cheng L, Bawden EG, Masters CL, Ang CS, Willamson N, McLean C, Barnham KJ, Hill AF. A rigorous method to enrich for exosomes from brain tissue. J Extracell Vesicles. 2017;6:1348885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5533148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28804598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J, Li C, Hua Y, Liu P, Gao B, Wang Y, Bai Y. Constraint-induced movement therapy improves functional recovery after ischemic stroke and its impacts on synaptic plasticity in sensorimotor cortex and hippocampus. Brain Res Bull. 2020;160:8&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32298779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu YH, Zhao Y, Huang FZ, Chen YH, Wang HX, Bonney E, Liu BQ. Combination of early constraint-induced movement therapy and fasudil enhances motor recovery after ischemic stroke in rats. Int J Neurosci. 2016;126:168&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25526355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao S, Zhao M, Xiao T, Jolkkonen J, Zhao C. Constraint-induced movement therapy overcomes the intrinsic axonal growth-inhibitory signals in stroke rats. Stroke. 2013;44:1698&#x2013;1705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23632976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai Z, Guo Y. Combination of constraint-induced movement therapy with fasudil amplifies neurogenesis after focal cerebral ischemia/reperfusion in rats. Int J Neurosci. 2022;132:1254&#x2013;1260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33527868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Zhang B, Zhu Y, Li Y, Liu P, Gao B, Tian S, Du L, Bai Y. Post-stroke constraint-induced movement therapy increases functional recovery, angiogenesis, and neurogenesis with enhanced expression of HIF-1&#x3b1; and VEGF. Curr Neurovasc Res. 2017;14:368&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29189156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao C, Wang J, Zhao S, Nie Y. Constraint-induced movement therapy enhanced neurogenesis and behavioral recovery after stroke in adult rats. Tohoku J Exp Med. 2009;218:301&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19638734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian S, Xu TL, Sun T. Tuning the cell fate of neurons and glia by microRNAs. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2013;23:928&#x2013;934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3830639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23978589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fineberg SK, Kosik KS, Davidson BL. MicroRNAs potentiate neural development. Neuron. 2009;64:303&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19914179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y, Zhao X, Hsieh J, Wichterle H, Impey S, Banerjee S, Neveu P, Kosik KS. MicroRNA regulation of neural stem cells and neurogenesis. J Neurosci. 2010;30:14931&#x2013;14936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3071711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21068294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Cao H, Xie Y, Zhang Y, Du M, Xu X, Ye R, Liu X. Exosome-shuttled miR-92b-3p from ischemic preconditioned astrocytes protects neurons against oxygen and glucose deprivation. Brain Res. 2019;1717:66&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30986407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Liu H, Chen S, Zhang W, Chen Y, Yang Y. Moderate exercise has beneficial effects on mouse ischemic stroke by enhancing the functions of circulating endothelial progenitor cell-derived exosomes. Exp Neurol. 2020;330:113325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11055452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32325158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Z, Qin X, Hu Y, Zhang X, Li G, Wu J, Li J, Sha J, Chen J, Xia J, Wang L, Gao F. Longterm exercise-derived exosomal miR-342-5p: a novel exerkine for cardioprotection. Circ Res. 2019;124:1386&#x2013;1400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30879399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Yin T, Zhang M, Li Z, Xu B, Lv H, Wang P, Wang J, Hao J, Zhang L. Function of miR-21-5p derived from ADSCs-exos on the neuroinflammation after cerebral ischemia. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2024;33:107779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38768666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y, Zhao X, Liu R, Yang D, Ge G. Effect of oxygen-glucose deprivation of microglia-derived exosomes on hippocampal neurons: a study on miR-124 and inflammatory cytokines. J Mol Histol. 2024;55:349&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38598045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagase T, Kin K, Yasuhara T. Targeting neurogenesis in seeking novel treatments for ischemic stroke. Biomedicines. 2023;11:2773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10604112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37893146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Zou X, Zhang R, Xie Y, Feng Z, Li F, Han J, Sun H, Ouyang Q, Hua S, Lv B, Hua T, Liu Z, Cai Y, Zou Y, Tang Y, Jiang X. Human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cell-derived exosomal miR-146a-5p reduces microglial-mediated neuroinflammation via suppression of the IRAK1/TRAF6 signaling pathway after ischemic stroke. Aging (Albany NY) 2021;13:3060&#x2013;3079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7880318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33479185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otsu Y, Hatakeyama M, Kanayama T, Akiyama N, Ninomiya I, Omae K, Kato T, Onodera O, Fukushima M, Shimohata T, Kanazawa M. Oxygen-glucose deprived peripheral blood mononuclear cells protect against ischemic stroke. Neurotherapeutics. 2023;20:1369&#x2013;1387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10480381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37335500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JJ, Wang B, Kodali MC, Chen C, Kim E, Patters BJ, Lan L, Kumar S, Wang X, Yue J, Liao FF. In vivo evidence for the contribution of peripheral circulating inflammatory exosomes to neuroinflammation. J Neuroinflammation. 2018;15:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5759808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29310666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkat P, Cui C, Chopp M, Zacharek A, Wang F, Landschoot-Ward J, Shen Y, Chen J. MiR-126 mediates brain endothelial cell exosome treatment-induced neurorestorative effects after stroke in Type 2 diabetes mellitus mice. Stroke. 2019;50:2865&#x2013;2874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6756941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31394992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Fu CH, Zhu X, Liu J, Gong X, Pan Q, Ma X. Exosomes and exosomal microRNAs in age-associated stroke. Curr Vasc Pharmacol. 2021;19:587&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33563154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>