<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41715070</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2474</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC musculoskeletal disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Minimally invasive reconstruction of a large chronic complete flexor hallucis longus tendon rupture: a case report and literature review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">253</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12891-026-09612-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Isolated rupture of the flexor hallucis longus (FHL) tendon is a scarce condition, with limited reported cases documented since 1980. Most reported cases have been managed surgically, using approaches such as direct repair, tendon transfers, or grafting, with variable outcomes. Meanwhile large chronic flexor hallucis longus (FHL) tendon defects exceeding 10&#xa0;cm are rare and lack a standardized surgical treatment approach, particularly in physically active individuals. We present a distinctive case of a delayed, complete traumatic FHL tendon rupture in an active-demand individual, successfully treated using a combination of ultrasound-guided tendon localization and arthroscopy-assisted tendon allografting to address a tendon gap exceeding 10&#xa0;cm. Given the rarity of this technique and the favorable postoperative recovery, we aim to contribute this case to the existing literature and review previously reported cases of isolated FHL tendon rupture.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE PRESENTATION">A 48-year-old male recreational basketball player without past medical history presented two months after a traumatic complete FHL rupture, confirmed on MRI, with a tendon defect greater than 10&#xa0;cm, pronounced push-off weakness, loss of hallux interphalangeal (IP) joint flexion, and significant psychological distress after a landing injury. Although acceptable functional outcomes have been reported following flexor hallucis longus (FHL) transfer in Achilles tendon reconstruction, these findings reflect a different clinical context. In this case of isolated FHL rupture, preservation of native hallux flexion was prioritized based on the patient&#x2019;s activity demands. With limited guidance in the existing literature for managing such a large chronic defect, we proceeded with a minimally invasive approach combining ultrasound-guided identification of the tendon stump and arthroscopic debridement of the fibro-osseous tunnel of the FHL. The large gap was reconstructed using a flexor digitorum longus (FDL) tendon allograft. Postoperatively, the patient demonstrated marked improvement in push-off stability, recovery of hallux flexion strength, and renewed confidence during athletic activities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The current literature provides limited descriptions of the surgical management of flexor hallucis longus (FHL) ruptures with tendon defects greater than 10&#xa0;cm, and these cases therefore remain challenging. In this case, reconstruction using an ultrasound-guided and arthroscopy-assisted approach with a flexor digitorum longus (FDL) graft was feasible and associated with a favorable clinical outcome. Although this technique has been infrequently reported, our findings suggest that it may be considered as one of several possible options when alternative methods are limited or unsuitable, particularly in active individuals for whom restoration of hallux function is important.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12891-026-09612-4.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Taipei Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, No. 289, Jianguo Rd., Xindian Dist, New Taipei, 231016, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Ume&#xe5; University, Ume&#xe5;, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Kai-Chiang</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Dental Technology, College of Oral Medicine, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, 110301, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Chen-Chie</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1694-7579</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Taipei Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, No. 289, Jianguo Rd., Xindian Dist, New Taipei, 231016, Taiwan. xavier-wang@yahoo.com.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences and Engineering, School of Biomedical Technology, Tzu Chi University, Hualien, Taiwan. xavier-wang@yahoo.com.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, School of Medicine, Tzu Chi University, Hualien, 970473, Taiwan. xavier-wang@yahoo.com.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968565</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2474</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Arthroscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Flexor hallucis longus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tendon allografting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tendon rupture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasound-guided localization</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval for this single-patient case report was granted by the Institutional Review Board of Taipei Tzu Chi General Hospital, Taiwan. The patient was managed according to standard clinical practice, and informed consent was obtained as detailed below. Written informed consent was obtained from the patient for publication of this case report and all accompanying clinical images. No identifying personal information or facial features are shown. Consent for publication: Written informed consent was obtained from the patient for publication of this case report and any accompanying images. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41715070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13023162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-026-09612-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12891-026-09612-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chun DI, Lee HS, Won SH, Moon SI, Jung KJ, Seo JH, et al. Closed atraumatic complete rupture of the flexor hallucis longus tendon during forward lunge exercise: a case report. Med (Baltim). 2019;98(50):e18409. 10.1097/MD.0000000000018409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000018409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6922354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31852162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr DL, Butler S, Thompson K, Higgs A. Complete rupture of the flexor hallucis longus tendon in an isolated closed injury: a systematic literature and qualitative analysis. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 2019;9(1):105&#x2013;11. 10.32098/mltj.01.2019.09.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32098/mltj.01.2019.09</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romash MM. Closed rupture of the flexor hallucis longus tendon in a long-distance runner: report of a case and review of the literature. Foot Ankle Int. 1994;15(8):433-6. 10.1177/107110079401500806. PMID: 7981815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7981815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasopoulos N, Paraskevas G, Lazaridis N, Natsis K. Reconstruction of neglected flexor hallucis longus tendon rupture: A case report. J Foot Ankle Surg. 2018 Nov-Dec;57(6):1256&#x2013;8. 10.1053/j.jfas.2018.03.041. Epub 2018 Jun 21. PMID: 29937339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29937339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krackow KA. Acute, traumatic rupture of a flexor hallucis longus tendon: a case report. Clin Orthop Rel Res. 1980;150:261&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00003086-198007000-00044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6107195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holt KW, Cross MJ. Isolated rupture of the flexor hallucis longus tendon. A case report. Am J Sports Med. 1990;18(6):645&#x2013;6. 10.1177/036354659001800616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/036354659001800616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2285095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson FM, Snow SW, Hershon SJ. Spontaneous atraumatic rupture of the flexor hallucis longus tendon under the sustentaculum tali: case report, review of the literature, and treatment options. Foot Ankle. 1993;14(7):414-7. 10.1177/107110079301400709. PMID: 8406263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8406263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza LJ, Rutledge E. Closed Rupture of the Flexor Hallucis Longus Tendon with Evaluation of the Mechanism of Injury: A Case Report. JBJS Case Connect. 2014;4(2): e45. doi: 10.2106/JBJS.CC. M.00167. PMID: 29252349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29252349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards SR, Kingsford AC. Surgical repair of a ruptured flexor hallucis longus tendon via tenoplasty and autogenous peroneus longus tendon graft. Foot Ankle Surgery: Techniques Rep Cases. 2021;1(1):100009. 10.1016/j.fastrc.2021.100009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fastrc.2021.100009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inokuchi S, Usami N. Closed complete rupture of the flexor hallucis longus tendon at the groove of the talus. Foot Ankle Int. 1997;18(1):47&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/107110079701800110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9013115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hikichi T, Matsubara H, Tsubouchi H, Igarashi K, Fujieda T, Tokita T, Tsuchiya H. Case Report Tendon Rerouting and Transfer for Atraumatic Rupture of the Flexor Hallucis Longus: A Case Report. JBJS Case Connect. 2025;15(1). 10.2106/JBJS.CC.24.00559. PMID: 39946511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39946511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayel FA, Pitakveerakul A, Alshalawi S, Wiewiorski M, Valderrabano V. Neglected Iatrogenic Flexor Hallucis Longus Tendon Rupture After Haglund&#x2019;s Endoscopic Surgery: A Case Report. J Foot Ankle Surg. 2020 Jan-Feb;59(1):169&#x2013;72. 10.1053/j.jfas.2019.07.009. Epub 2019 Nov 19. PMID: 31753576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31753576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei SY, Kneeland JB, Okereke E. Complete atraumatic rupture of the flexor hallucis longus tendon: a case report and review of the literature. Foot Ankle Int. 1998;19(7):472-4. 10.1177/107110079801900709. PMID: 9694126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9694126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Jonbergen JPW, Faber FWM, Treurniet FEE. Non-traumatic isolated rupture of the flexor hallucis longus tendon related to an Os trigonum: a case report. Foot Ankle Surg. 2001;7:109&#x2013;11. 10.1046/j.1460-9584.2001.00238.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1460-9584.2001.00238.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe I, Williamson ERC, Godwin K, Schon LC, Rose DJ. Allograft reconstruction of a ruptured flexor hallucis longus tendon in a professional dancer: A case Report. Foot ankle spec. 2025 Apr 15:19386400251330103. doi: 10.1177/19386400251330103. Epub ahead of print. PMID: 40231779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40231779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandalia V, Williamson DM. Conservative management of rupture of the flexor hallucis longus tendon: a case report and literature review. Foot Ankle Surg. 2002;8(4):247&#x2013;50. 10.1046/j.1460-9584.2002.00335.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1460-9584.2002.00335.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JY, Wang C, Kim HD, et al. Tendon split lengthening technique for flexor hallucis longus tendon rupture. J Orthop Surg Res. 2017;12:165. 10.1186/s13018-017-0668-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-017-0668-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5674746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29110725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grispigni C, De Ponti A, Danasini P, et al. Closed subcutaneous rupture of the flexor hallucis longus tendon. Case report and review of the literature. J Orthopaed Traumatol. 2000;1:107&#x2013;10. 10.1007/PL00012198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/PL00012198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heikkila JT, Mattila K, Alanen J, Orava S. Chronic rupture of flexor hallucis longus tendon in a world class runner. Foot Ankle Surg. 2004;10(2):71&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1268-7731(03)00103-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenschink J, Leveille R, Leveille D. Flexor hallucis longus rupture repaired with split flexor digitorum longus tendon transfer: A case report. Foot Ankle Surgery: Techniques Rep Cases. 2021;1(2):100034. 10.1016/j.fastrc.2021.100034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fastrc.2021.100034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato K, Sugawa I, Moriwaki M. A case of subcutaneous rupture of exor hallucislongus. Rinsho Seikei Geka. 1983;18:1317&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noda D, Yoshimura I, Kanazawa K, Hagio T, Naito M. Subcutaneous rupture of the flexor hallucis longus tendon: a case report. J Foot Ankle Surg. 2012;51(2):234&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.jfas.2011.10.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22153296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue S, Yuasa K, Sasaki Y. Traumatic rupture of the exor hallucis longus tendon:a case report. Rinsho Seikei Geka. 1995;30:1331&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coghlan BA, Clarke NM. Traumatic rupture of the flexor hallucis longus tendon in a marathon runner. Am J Sports Med. 1993 Jul-Aug;21(4):617-8. 10.1177/036354659302100422. PMID: 8103644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8103644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinokida T, Mizuno Y, Kobayashi T. Subcutaneous rupture of the exor hallucis longus tendon: case report. Rinsho Seikei Geka. 2005;40:209&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosokawa T, Ikoma K, Kido M, Hara Y, Maki M, Ohashi S, Kubo T. Subcutaneous rupture of the flexor hallucis longus tendon at the musculotendinous junction in a soccer player. J Orthop Sci. 2021;26(2):311&#x2013;4. 10.1016/j.jos.2018. 08 011. Epub 2018 Sep 14. PMID: 30 224 230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jos.2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30224230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2022;Kateva M, Vasileva D, Petrov G. M. flexor hallucis longus tendon reconstruction with M. plantaris graft &#x2013; a case description and rehab program. J IMAB. 2023;29(2):4857&#x2013;62. 10.5272/jimab.2023292.4857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5272/jimab.2023292.4857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr J, Germain M, Winters M, et al. Disinfection of human musculoskeletal allografts in tissue banking: a systematic review. Cell Tissue Bank. 2016;17(4):573&#x2013;84. 10.1007/s10561-016-9584-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10561-016-9584-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5116033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27665294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen RB, Thyssen EP. Rupture of the Flexor Hallucis Longus Tendon: case report. Foot &amp; Ankle. 1990;10(5):288&#x2013;9. 10.1177/107110079001000509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2341101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>