<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41908098</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2768-2765</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the Pediatric Orthopaedic Society of North America</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Pediatr Soc North Am</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fracture Patterns, Skeletal Age, and Outcomes in Adolescent Supracondylar Humerus Fractures Treated With Open Reduction Internal Fixation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100345</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100345</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100345</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jposna.2026.100345</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Supracondylar humerus fractures (SCHF) in adolescents transitioning to skeletal maturity are less common, and literature on the management of complex cases with open reduction internal fixation (ORIF) is limited. The objective of this study was to retrospectively evaluate SCHFs treated with ORIF at a single tertiary pediatric center.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Patients of ages 7-18 who received ORIF between 2015 and 2024 for SCHF with intercondylar extension (T-type; OTA/AO 13-E/4.2) or extraarticular SCHF (eSCHF; OTA/AO 13-M/3.1, 13/E/1.1) were included. Patients treated with percutaneous pinning alone or with prior elbow fractures were excluded. Demographic characteristics, skeletal age, injury mechanism, fracture morphology, and fixation strategy were compared. Outcomes included fracture union, range of motion (ROM), and complications. Stiffness was defined using Morrey's criteria. Final ROM was graded as defined by Jarvis et al.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Twenty-eight patients (12.7 years, 45% Female) were included and represented 3% of SCHFs in this age range. The T-type group (n = 14) was older and more skeletally mature (modified Sauvegrain score 6.8 vs 4.5; <i>P</i> = .003) than the eSCHF group. Plate and screw constructs were preferred in T-type fractures (9/14, 64%), while 79% (11/14) of eSCHF received cannulated screws (<i>P</i> = .008). All fractures achieved union (mean 11 wks). The T-type group was immobilized for a shorter period (2.3 vs 3.2 weeks; <i>P</i> = .043) and had more stiffness at 3 months (50 vs 9%; <i>P</i> = .042), but the difference in arc of motion at final follow-up did not reach statistical significance (133 vs eSCHF 142 deg; <i>P</i> = .07). The ROM in T-type fractures did not differ by construct type. Most patients (n = 18, 64%) were skeletally advanced compared to their chronological age (range 6-30 months). Complication rate was high (64%) primarily from hardware pain (9; 32%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">T-type SCHF were seen in skeletally mature patients and were associated with slower ROM recovery. Fixation strategy was correlated with fracture type. There were no significant differences in clinical outcomes between the two fixation methods. Future prospective studies are warranted to optimize the treatment of adolescent SCHF injuries.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="KEY CONCEPTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">(1)Patients with SCHF with intraarticular extension were older and more skeletally mature.(2)Plate and screws were preferred over cannulated screws for intraarticular extension.(3)All fractures achieved union and final arc of motion did not differ by fracture type.(4)Elbows with T-type fractures were immobilized 1 week less but stiffer at 3-months.(5)Complication rate was high at 64%, and half were due to hardware pain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">III, Retrospective Cohort Study.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murata</LastName><ForeName>Asahi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wolf</LastName><ForeName>Josiah</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Talerico</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and Sports Medicine, College of Medicine, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Slyepkan</LastName><ForeName>Ivan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tulchin-Francis</LastName><ForeName>Kirsten</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tabaie</LastName><ForeName>Sean</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Pediatr Soc North Am</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101776896</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2768-2765</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Open reduction internal fixation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Skeletal age</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Supracondylar humerus fracture</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41908098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13019066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jposna.2026.100345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2768-2765(26)00024-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bekmez S., Camp MW., Ling R., El-Amiri N., Howard AW. Supracondylar humerus fractures in older children: success of closed reduction and percutaneous pinning. J Pediatr Orthop. 2021;41:242&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33655902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell P., Scannell BP., Loeffler BJ., Brighton BK., Gaston RG., Casey V., et al. Adolescent distal humerus fractures: ORIF versus CRPP. J Pediatr Orthop. 2017;37:511&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26683504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minkowitz B., Busch M.T. Supracondylar humerus fractures. Current trends and controversies. Orthop Clin N Am. 1994;25:581&#x2013;594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8090472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holt J.B., Glass N.A., Shah A.S. Understanding the epidemiology of pediatric supracondylar humeral fractures in the United States: identifying opportunities for intervention. J Pediatr Orthop. 2018;38:e245&#x2013;e251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29462120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anari JB., Neuwirth AL., Carducci NM., Donegan DJ., Baldwin KD. Pediatric T-Condylar humerus fractures: a systematic review. J Pediatr Orthop. 2017;37:36&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26165551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck NA., Ganley TJ., McKay S., Tomlinson L., Ahn J., Flynn JM., et al. T-condylar fractures of the distal humerus in children: does early motion affect final range of motion? J Child Orthop. 2014;8:161&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3965770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24643671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher ND., Schiller J.R., Garg S., Weller A., Larson AN., Kwon M., et al. Increased severity of type III supracondylar humerus fractures in the preteen population. J Pediatr Orthop. 2012;32:567&#x2013;572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22892617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarvis J.G., D'Astous J.L. The pediatric T-supracondylar fracture. J Pediatr Orthop. 1984;4:697&#x2013;699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6511896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolac UC., Oral M., Sili MV., Ibik S., Aydinoglu HS., Bakircioglu S., et al. Identifying risk factors for open reduction in pediatric supracondylar humerus fractures. J Pediatr Orthop. 2024;44:573&#x2013;578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39099078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popkin C.A., Rosenwasser K.A., Ellis H.B., Jr. Pediatric and adolescent T-type distal humerus fractures. J Am Acad Orthop Surg Glob Res Rev. 2017;1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6132339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30211365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young J., Hendrick C., Miller PE., Vuillermin CB., Yen YM., Bauer AS. Outcomes of adolescent T-condylar fractures: kids do not always make you look good. J Pediatr Orthop. 2023;43:e726&#x2013;e733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37573548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons  Treatment of pediatric supracondylar humerus fractures evidence-based clinical practice guideline. https://www.aaos.org/globalassets/quality-and-practice-resources/pshf/pshf_cpg_10.31.16.pdf</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22553105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahlberg PS., Mosd&#xf8;l A., Ding Y., Bleka &#xd8;., Rolseth V., Straumann GH., et al. A systematic review of the agreement between chronological age and skeletal age based on the Greulich and Pyle atlas. Eur Radiol. 2019;29:2936&#x2013;2948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30377790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahk MS., Srikumaran U., Ain MC., Erkula G., Leet AI., Sargent MC., et al. Patterns of pediatric supracondylar humerus fractures. J Pediatr Orthop. 2008;28:493&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18580360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauvegrain J., Nahum H., Bronstein H. Study of bone maturation of the elbow. Ann Radiol. 1962;5:542&#x2013;550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13986863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dim&#xe9;glio A., Charles YP., Daures JP., de Rosa V., Kabor&#xe9; B. Accuracy of the sauvegrain method in determining skeletal age during puberty. J Bone Joint Surg. 2005;87:1689&#x2013;1696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16085606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrey B.F., Askew L.J., Chao E.Y. A biomechanical study of normal functional elbow motion. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1981;63:872&#x2013;877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7240327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook JB., Riccio AI., Anderson T., Chen W., Shaha SH., Wimberly RL. Outcomes after surgical treatment of adolescent intra-articular distal humerus fractures. J Pediatr Orthop. 2016;36:773&#x2013;779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26090965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doornberg JN., van Duijn PJ., Linzel D., Ring DC., Zurakowski D., Marti RK., et al. Surgical treatment of intra-articular fractures of the distal part of the humerus. Functional outcome after twelve to thirty years. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2007;89:1524&#x2013;1532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17606792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S., John R., Dhillon M.S., Kishore K. Surgical approaches for open reduction and internal fixation of intra-articular distal humerus fractures in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Injury. 2018;49:1381&#x2013;1391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29934098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducic S., Stojanovic B., Lazovic M., Bukva B., Radlovic V., Bumbasirevic V., et al. T-condylar humerus fracture in children: treatment options and outcomes. Int Orthop. 2021;45:1065&#x2013;1070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32980938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Movassaghi K., Locker P., Kunze KN., Khoo KM., Hoekzema N. Predictors of adverse events in the surgical treatment of adult distal humerus fractures. Orthopedics. 2023;46:352&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37018621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yetter T.R., Weatherby P.J., Somerson J.S. Complications of articular distal humeral fracture fixation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2021;30:1957&#x2013;1967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33711499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcu DM., Balts J., McCarthy JJ., Kozin SH., Noonan KJ. Iatrogenic radial nerve injury with cannulated fixation of medial epicondyle fractures in the pediatric humerus: a report of 2 cases. J Pediatr Orthop. 2011;31:e13&#x2013;e16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21307699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyfuss D., Eidelman M. Treatment of complex intercondylar humeral fractures in adolescents by open reduction and internal fixation through the transolecranon approach. J Pediatr Orthop B. 2014;23:364&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24667148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han SB., Kim H., Jeong J., Kim YS., Ji JH., Lee SU., et al. Low transcondylar fractures of the distal humerus: a multicenter cohort study. J Orthop Trauma. 2023;37:e57&#x2013;e62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36084238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>