<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41640901</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Paradoxical Immune Reconstitution Inflammatory Syndrome Presenting as Extrapulmonary Tuberculosis in a Patient With HIV.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e100745</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e100745</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e100745</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.100745</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Immune reconstitution inflammatory syndrome (IRIS) is an uncoordinated hyperinflammatory response to&#xa0;latent or de novo active infection in immunocompromised individuals&#xa0;following immune recovery. More specifically, paradoxical IRIS refers to the deterioration of a pre-existing infection, whereas unmasking IRIS can be thought of as the unveiling of a previously undiagnosed infection as immune function reconstitutes. HIV-positive patients with advanced&#xa0;disease&#xa0;who are also coinfected with tuberculosis have a uniquely&#xa0;high risk&#xa0;for&#xa0;this complication&#xa0;once started on&#xa0;highly active antiretroviral therapy (HAART). We present a case of a 58-year-old HIV and tuberculosis (TB)-positive woman from Northern Tanzania who presented to a rural care and treatment clinic (CTC) after a 17-month lapse from HAART. She had previously undergone curative treatment for tuberculosis three years prior, which was also the time of her initial HIV diagnosis and initiation of HAART. She arrived in the clinic cachectic, unwell, and with complaint of malaise and diarrhea. Blood analysis confirmed advanced HIV disease (AHD), and consequently, she was immediately restarted on HAART. Almost three weeks later, she returned to the clinic febrile, severely fatigued, and with grossly evident cervical lymphadenitis. Given her coinfection (HIV and TB positive) history, depleted CD4+ count, new onset of clinical findings, and temporal relationship of symptom appearance from HAART reinitiation, a diagnosis of paradoxical TB-IRIS presenting as TB lymphadenitis was made.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Shang et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shang</LastName><ForeName>Wendy</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Education, California Health Sciences University College of Osteopathic Medicine, Clovis, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bruno</LastName><ForeName>Tony F</ForeName><Initials>TF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Education, California Health Sciences University College of Osteopathic Medicine, Clovis, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Infectious Disease, HIV Program, Doctors With Africa Collegio Universitario Aspiranti Medici Missionari (CUAMM), Padova, ITA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hiv aids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hiv aids antiretroviral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hiv sub-saharan africa</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immune reconstitution inflammatory syndrome (iris)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tb-iris</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41640901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12867074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.100745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2019. Global tuberculosis report: executive summary.  [
May;
2025 
]. 2019. https://cdn.who.int/media/docs/default-source/documents/tuberculosis/global-tb-report-2019-executive-summary7248223a-1e25-42a6-ada7-a9503c31bb77.pdf https://cdn.who.int/media/docs/default-source/documents/tuberculosis/global-tb-report-2019-executive-summary7248223a-1e25-42a6-ada7-a9503c31bb77.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2022. Global tuberculosis report.  [
May;
2025 
]. 2022. http://who.int/teams/global-programme-on-tuberculosis-and-lung-health/tb-reports/global-tuberculosis-report-2022 http://who.int/teams/global-programme-on-tuberculosis-and-lung-health/tb-reports/global-tuberculosis-report-2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of tuberculosis, HIV, and TB-HIV co-infection among pulmonary tuberculosis suspects in a predominantly pastoralist area, northeast Ethiopia. Belay M, Bjune G, Abebe F. Glob Health Action. 2015;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4685972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26689454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnostic accuracy of the INSHI consensus case definition for the diagnosis of paradoxical tuberculosis-IRIS. Stek C, Buyze J, Menten J, et al. J Acquir Immune Defic Syndr. 2021;86:587&#x2013;592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7938911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33394813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Immune reconstitution inflammatory syndrome in HIV-infected patients. Walker NF, Scriven J, Meintjes G, Wilkinson RJ. HIV AIDS (Auckl) 2015;7:49&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4334287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25709503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa S, Shrestha U. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing; 2023. Immune reconstitution inflammatory syndrome.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33620872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuberculosis-associated immune reconstitution inflammatory syndrome: case definitions for use in resource-limited settings. Meintjes G, Lawn SD, Scano F, et al. Lancet Infect Dis. 2008;8:516&#x2013;523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2804035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18652998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Immune reconstitution inflammatory syndrome in patients starting antiretroviral therapy for HIV infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. M&#xfc;ller M, Wandel S, Colebunders R, Attia S, Furrer H, Egger M. Lancet Infect Dis. 2010;10:251&#x2013;261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4183458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20334848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradoxical TB-IRIS in HIV-infected adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Namale PE, Abdullahi LH, Fine S, Kamkuemah M, Wilkinson RJ, Meintjes G. Future Microbiol. 2015;10:1077&#x2013;1099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26059627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuberculosis-associated immune reconstitution inflammatory syndrome - an extempore game of misfiring with defense arsenals. Vignesh R, Balakrishnan P, Tan HY, Yong YK, Velu V, Larsson M, Shankar EM. Pathogens. 2023;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9964757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36839482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altered IL-6 signalling and risk of tuberculosis: a multi-ancestry Mendelian randomisation study. Hamilton F, Schurz H, Yates TA, et al. Lancet Microbe. 2025;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39579785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuberculosis IRIS: pathogenesis, presentation, and management across the spectrum of disease. Quinn CM, Poplin V, Kasibante J, Yuquimpo K, Gakuru J, Cresswell FV, Bahr NC. Life (Basel) 2020;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7693460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33138069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>