<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41917835</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2318</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC geriatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Geriatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A rehabilitation intervention to improve recovery after delirium in older people: mixed methods process evaluation of the RecoverED multi-site feasibility study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12877-026-07314-z</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raghuraman</LastName><ForeName>Shruti</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Community Sciences, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK. s.raghuraman@exeter.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahmoud</LastName><ForeName>Aseel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Community Sciences, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bingham</LastName><ForeName>Alison</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Community Sciences, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laverick</LastName><ForeName>Abigail</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Community Sciences, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chandler</LastName><ForeName>Kirstie</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Community Sciences, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Connell</LastName><ForeName>Abby</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exeter Clinical Trials Unit, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Um</LastName><ForeName>Jinpil</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Community Sciences, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ukoumunne</LastName><ForeName>Obioha C</ForeName><Initials>OC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR Applied Research Collaboration South West Peninsula, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goodwin</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Economics Group, University of Exeter Medical School, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hawton</LastName><ForeName>Annie</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Economics Group, University of Exeter Medical School, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Collier</LastName><ForeName>Lesley</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health and Well&#x2011;Being, University of Winchester, Winchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Richardson</LastName><ForeName>Sarah Joanna</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AGE Research Group, Newcastle upon Tyne Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Cumbria Northumberland Tyne and Wear NHS Foundation Trust, Newcastle University, Newcastle Upon Tyne, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medical Sciences, NIHR Newcastle Biomedical Research Centre, Newcastle Upon Tyne, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maclullich</LastName><ForeName>Alasdair</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Scottish Hip Fracture Audit (SHFA), NHS National Services Scotland, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ageing and Health Group, Usher Institute, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Litherland</LastName><ForeName>Rachael</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Innovations in Dementia, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goodwin</LastName><ForeName>Victoria A</ForeName><Initials>VA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Community Sciences, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR Applied Research Collaboration South West Peninsula, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clare</LastName><ForeName>Linda</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Community Sciences, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR Applied Research Collaboration South West Peninsula, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Allan</LastName><ForeName>Louise</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Community Sciences, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR Applied Research Collaboration South West Peninsula, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morgan-Trimmer</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Primary Care, Population Sciences and Medical Education, University of Southampton, Southampton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health and Life Sciences, University of Exeter, Exeter, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>NIHR202338</GrantID><Agency>National Institute of Health and Care Research Programme Grants for Applied Research Programme</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Geriatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968548</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2318</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acceptability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Delirium</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthcare delivery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Implementation fidelity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This feasibility study has been approved by the London &#x2013; South East Research Ethics Committee (IRAS ID: 302675) and Scotland A Research Ethics Committee (IRAS ID 319555). All participants provided appropriate informed consent prior to their participation in the study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41917835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-026-07314-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12877-026-07314-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Allan LM, O&#x2019;Connell A, Harwood RH, Bingham A, Laverick A, Chandler K, Raghuraman S, Ukoumunne O, Jackson TA, Richardson SJ, Anderson R, Litherland R, Collier L, Goodwin VA, Morgan-Trimmer S, Hawton A, Goodwin E, Clare L. The challenges of rehabilitation and delirium trials in the current NHS landscape: Learning from the RecoverED feasibility trial. In Age and Ageing. 2025 (Vol. 54, Issue 7). Oxford Academic. https://doi.org/10.1093/ageing/afaf196</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allan L, O&#x2019;Connell A, Raghuraman S, Bingham A, Laverick A, Chandler K, Connors J, Jones B, Um J, Morgan-Trimmer S, Harwood R, Goodwin VA, Ukoumunne OC, Hawton A, Anderson R, Jackson T, MacLullich AMJ, Richardson S, Davis D, Clare L. A rehabilitation intervention to improve recovery after an episode of delirium in adults over 65 years (RecoverED): study protocol for a multi-centre, single-arm feasibility study. Pilot Feasibility Stud. 2023;9(1):1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40814-023-01387-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrew MK, Freter SH, Rockwood K. Incomplete functional recovery after delirium in elderly people: A prospective cohort study. BMC Geriatrics, 2005 ;5. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2318-5-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellelli G, Brathwaite JS, Mazzola P. Delirium: A Marker of Vulnerability in Older People. Front Aging Neurosci. 2021;13(April):1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2021.626127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel H, Gradinger R, Kochs E, F&#xf6;rstl H. High risk of cognitive and functional decline after postoperative delirium: A three-year prospective study. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord. 2008;26(1):26&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1159/000140804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll C, Birken SA, Nilsen P. Fidelity. Handbook on Implementation Science. Edward Elgar Publishing; 2020. pp. 291&#x2013;316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll C, Patterson M, Wood S, Booth A, Rick J, Balain S. A conceptual framework for implementation fidelity. Implement Sci. 2007;2(1):1&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1186/1748-5908-2-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole MG, Bailey R, Bonnycastle M, McCusker J, Fung S, Ciampi A, Belzile E, Bai C. Partial and no recovery from delirium in older hospitalized adults: Frequency and baseline risk factors. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2015;63(11):2340&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1111/jgs.13791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole MG, Ciampi A, Belzile E, Zhong L. Persistent delirium in older hospital patients: A systematic review of frequency and prognosis. Age Ageing. 2009;38(1):19&#x2013;26. https://doi.org/10.1093/ageing/afn253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig P, Dieppe P, Macintyre S, Mitchie S, Nazareth I, Petticrew M. Developing and evaluating complex interventions: The new Medical Research Council guidance. In BMJ. 2008. (Vol. 337, Issue 7676, pp. 979&#x2013;983). BMJ. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.a1655</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fick DM, Steis MR, Waller JL, Inouye SK. Delirium superimposed on dementia is associated with prolonged length of stay and poor outcomes in hospitalized older adults. J Hosp Med. 2013;8(9):500&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.1002/JHM.2077.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frost J, Wingham J, Britten N, Greaves C, Abraham C, Warren FC, Jolly K, Doherty PJ, Miles J, Singh SJ, Paul K, Taylor R, Dalal H. Home-based rehabilitation for heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: Mixed methods process evaluation of the REACH-HF multicentre randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open. 2019a;9(8):e026039. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2018-026039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginsburg LR, Hoben M, Easterbrook A, Anderson RA, Estabrooks CA, Norton PG. Fidelity is not easy! Challenges and guidelines for assessing fidelity in complex interventions. Trials. 2021;22(1):1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13063-021-05322-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Robert G, Macfarlane F, Bate P, Kyriakidou O. Diffusion of innovations in service organizations: Systematic review and recommendations. Milbank Q. 2004;82(4):581&#x2013;629. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.0887-378X.2004.00325.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths RD, Jones C. Delirium, cognitive dysfunction and posttraumatic stress disorder. Curr Opin Anaesthesiol. 2007;20(2):124&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1097/ACO.0B013E3280803D4B.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grover S, Sahoo S, Chakrabarti S, Avasthi A. Post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD)related symptoms following an experience of delirium. J Psychosom Res. 2019;123. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychores.2019.05.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasson H. Systematic evaluation of implementation fidelity of complex interventions in health and social care. Implement Sci. 2010;5(1). https://doi.org/10.1186/1748-5908-5-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasson H, Blomberg S, Dun&#xe9;r A. Fidelity and moderating factors in complex interventions: A case study of a continuum of care program for frail elderly people in health and social care. Implement Sci. 2012;7(1):1&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.1186/1748-5908-7-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawe P, Shiell A, Riley T. Complex interventions: How out of control can a randomised controlled trial be? BMJ. 2004;328(7455):1561. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.328.7455.1561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk JW, Haines ER. Ethnography. In: Nilsen P, Birken SA, editors. Handbook on Implementation Science. Edward Elgar Publishing Ltd; 2020. pp. 480&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.4337/9781788975995.00032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahue SC, Douglas VC, Kuo T, Conell CA, Liu VX, Josephson SA, Angel C, Brooks KB. Association between inpatient Delirium and hospital readmission in patients&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;65 years of age: A retrospective cohort study. J Hosp Med. 2019;14(4):201&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.12788/jhm.3130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lykes MB, Mallona A. The SAGE Handbook of Action Research. In: Peter Reason, Bradbury H, editors. The SAGE Handbook of Action Research. 2nd ed. SAGE Publications Ltd; 2008. https://doi.org/10.4135/9781848607934.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCusker J, Cole M, Dendukuri N, Han L, Belzile &#xc9;. The course of delirium in older medical inpatients: A prospective study. J Gen Intern Med. 2003;18(9):696&#x2013;704. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1525-1497.2003.20602.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore GF, Audrey S, Barker M, Bond L, Bonell C, Hardeman W, Moore L, O&#x2019;Cathain A, Tinati T, Wight D, Baird J. Process evaluation of complex interventions: Medical Research Council guidance. BMJ (Online). 2015;350:h1258. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.h1258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morandi A, Davis D, Fick DM, Turco R, Boustani M, Lucchi E, Guerini F, Morghen S, Torpilliesi T, Gentile S, MacLullich AM, Trabucchi M, Bellelli G. Delirium superimposed on dementia strongly predicts worse outcomes in older rehabilitation inpatients. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2014;15(5):349&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jamda.2013.12.084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan-Trimmer S, Channon S, Gregory JW, Townson J, Lowes L. Family preferences for home or hospital care at diagnosis for children with diabetes in the DECIDE study. Diabet Med. 2016;33(1):119&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1111/DME.12891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muntinga ME, Van Leeuwen KM, Schellevis FG, Nijpels G, Jansen APD. From concept to content: Assessing the implementation fidelity of a chronic care model for frail, older people who live at home. BMC Health Serv Res. 2015;15(1). https://doi.org/10.1186/s12913-014-0662-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson S, Rustad JK, Catalano G, Stern TA, Kozel FA. Depressive Symptoms Before, During, and After Delirium: A Literature Review. Psychosomatics. 2016;57(2):131&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psym.2015.11.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE. Delirium: prevention, diagnosis and management Clinical guideline Your responsibility. (2010). March 2019. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/cg103</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oakley A, Strange V, Bonell C, Allen E, Stephenson J. (2006). Process evaluation in randomised controlled trials of complex interventions. In British Medical Journal (Vol. 332, Issue 7538, pp. 413&#x2013;416). British Medical Journal Publishing Group. https://doi.org/10.1080/1750984X.2021.2001838</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawson R, Tilley N. Realistic evaluation. SAGE; London1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pope C, Ziebland S, Mays N. Analysis. Qualitative Research in Health Care. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd; 2019. pp. 111&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119410867.ch9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proctor E, Silmere H, Raghavan R, Hovmand P, Aarons G, Bunger A, Griffey R, Hensley M. Outcomes for implementation research: Conceptual distinctions, measurement challenges, and research agenda. Adm Policy Mental Health Mental Health Serv Res. 2011;38(2):65&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10488-010-0319-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resnick B, Bellg AJ, Borrelli B, DeFrancesco C, Breger R, Hecht J, Sharp DL, Levesque C, Orwig D, Ernst D, Ogedegbe G, Czajkowski S. Examples of implementation and evaluation of treatment fidelity in the BCC Studies: Where we are and where we need to go. Ann Behav Med. 2005;29(SUPPL):46&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.1207/s15324796abm2902s_8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salluh JIF, Wang H, Schneider EB, Nagaraja N, Yenokyan G, Damluji A, Serafim RB, Stevens RD. Outcome of delirium in critically ill patients: Systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ (Online). 2015;350:1&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.h2538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqi N, House AO, Holmes JD. Occurrence and outcome of delirium in medical in-patients: A systematic literature review. In Age and Ageing. 2006, (Vol. 35, Issue 4, pp. 350&#x2013;364). Oxford Academic. https://doi.org/10.1093/ageing/afl005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skivington K, Matthews L, Simpson SA, Craig P, Baird J, Blazeby JM, Boyd KA, Craig N, French DP, McIntosh E, Petticrew M, Rycroft-Malone J, White M, Moore L. A new framework for developing and evaluating complex interventions: Update of Medical Research Council guidance. BMJ. 2021;374. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n2061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson J, Tiplady S, McNall A, Murray J, Cook G. Workforce Competency Framework: Enhanced Care for Older People with Complex Needs (EnCOP). Enhancedcare.Org, January. 2017 https://www.enhancedcare.org/s/WCFfinal.docx</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wade D, Hardy R, Howell D, Mythen M. Identifying clinical and acute psychological risk factors for PTSD after critical care: A systematic review. In Minerva Anestesiologica, 2013 (Vol. 79, Issue 8, pp. 944&#x2013;963). https://europepmc.org/article/med/23558761</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton H, Spector A, Tombor I, Michie S. Measures of fidelity of delivery of, and engagement with, complex, face-to-face health behaviour change interventions: A systematic review of measure quality. Br J Health Psychol. 2017;22(4):872&#x2013;903. https://doi.org/10.1111/bjhp.12260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton H, Tombor I, Burgess J, Groarke H, Swinson T, Wenborn J, Spector A, Orrell M, Mountain G, Michie S. Measuring fidelity of delivery of the Community Occupational Therapy in Dementia-UK intervention. BMC Geriatr. 2019;19(1):1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12877-019-1385-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witlox J, Eurelings LSM, De Jonghe JFM, Kalisvaart KJ, Eikelenboom P, Van Gool WA. Delirium in Elderly Patients and the Risk of Postdischarge Mortality, Institutionalization, and Dementia: A Meta-analysis. JAMA. 2010;304(4):443&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1001/JAMA.2010.1013.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>