<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41660880</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2426-8887</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>SICOT-J</Title><ISOAbbreviation>SICOT J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Functional positioning in robotic lateral unicompartmental knee arthroplasty: a step-by-step technique.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>8</StartPage><MedlinePgn>8</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1051/sicotj/2025055</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Lateral unicompartmental knee arthroplasty (UKA) represents 1-2% of knee replacement procedures, yet offers distinct advantages including reduced surgical burden, bone stock preservation, and faster functional recovery. However, lateral UKA presents unique technical difficulties due to the surgical complexity of the lateral compartment. Recent advances in image-based robotic systems have demonstrated improved accuracy in implant positioning and promoted more individualized surgical strategies. This article presents a step-by-step surgical technique for lateral UKA using Functional Positioning (FP) principles in combination with an image-based robotic system. The technique ensures precise preoperative planning based on CT imaging, real-time intraoperative kinematic evaluation, and accurate component placement tailored to individual patient anatomy. The key steps of this surgical technique include comprehensive preoperative planning with 3D anatomical modeling, intraoperative kinematic evaluation following osteophyte removal, achieving centered femorotibial contact points throughout the full range of motion with precise lateral laxity gap boundaries, and cartilage mapping to ensure optimal component positioning and avoid overstuffing. FP addresses the characteristic posterior cartilage wear pattern of valgus knees while preserving pre-arthritic coronal alignment and avoiding varus overcorrection. This systematic approach demonstrates reproducible surgical steps that may translate into improved long-term outcomes and implant survivorship for lateral UKA procedures.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Authors, published by EDP Sciences, 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andriollo</LastName><ForeName>Luca</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-1586-2542</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedics Surgery and Sports Medicine Department, FIFA Medical Center of Excellence, Croix-Rousse Hospital, Hospices Civils de Lyon, Lyon North University Hospital, 69004 Lyon, France - Ortopedia e Traumatologia, Fondazione Poliambulanza Istituto Ospedaliero, 25124 Brescia, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mazzella</LastName><ForeName>Giovan Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>GG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedics Surgery and Sports Medicine Department, FIFA Medical Center of Excellence, Croix-Rousse Hospital, Hospices Civils de Lyon, Lyon North University Hospital, 69004 Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leggieri</LastName><ForeName>Filippo</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedics Surgery and Sports Medicine Department, FIFA Medical Center of Excellence, Croix-Rousse Hospital, Hospices Civils de Lyon, Lyon North University Hospital, 69004 Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Servien</LastName><ForeName>Elvire</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedics Surgery and Sports Medicine Department, FIFA Medical Center of Excellence, Croix-Rousse Hospital, Hospices Civils de Lyon, Lyon North University Hospital, 69004 Lyon, France - LIBM-EA 7424, Interuniversity Laboratory of Biology of Mobility, Claude Bernard Lyon 1 University, 69100 Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Batailler</LastName><ForeName>C&#xe9;cile</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedics Surgery and Sports Medicine Department, FIFA Medical Center of Excellence, Croix-Rousse Hospital, Hospices Civils de Lyon, Lyon North University Hospital, 69004 Lyon, France - Univ Lyon, Claude Bernard Lyon 1 University, IFSTTAR, LBMC UMR_T9406, 69622 Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lustig</LastName><ForeName>S&#xe9;bastien Henri Michel</ForeName><Initials>SHM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedics Surgery and Sports Medicine Department, FIFA Medical Center of Excellence, Croix-Rousse Hospital, Hospices Civils de Lyon, Lyon North University Hospital, 69004 Lyon, France - Univ Lyon, Claude Bernard Lyon 1 University, IFSTTAR, LBMC UMR_T9406, 69622 Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>France</Country><MedlineTA>SICOT J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101675099</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2426-8887</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional positioning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Personalized knee arthroplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Robotic knee</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">UKA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Unicompartmental knee arthroplasty</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>In relation to the contents of this article, SL is a consultant for Stryker and declares royalties from Stryker. CB is a consultant for Stryker. The other authors have nothing to declare in relation to this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41660880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12884707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/sicotj/2025055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">sicotj250135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Achakri H, Ben-Shlomo Y, Blom A, et al. (2022) The National Joint Registry 20th Annual Report 2023. London: National Joint Registry.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38422195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangaletti R, Meschini C, Capece G, et al. (2024) A morphometric medial compartment-specific unicompartmental knee system: 5&#xa0;years follow up results from a pilot center. Knee 47, 179&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38401342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunyoz KI, Troelsen A, Gromov K, et al. (2025) Indications for lateral unicompartmental knee arthroplasty &#x2013; A systematic review. The Knee 52, 58&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39541657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buzin SD, Geller JA, Yoon RS, Macaulay W (2021) Lateral unicompartmental knee arthroplasty: A review. World J Orthop 12, 197&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8082511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33959483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangaletti R, Andriollo L, Montagna A, et al. (2024) Lateral UKA can be a safe solution in a young patients&#x2019; population: a 10-year follow-up report. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg 144, 4029&#x2013;4035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38231208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaggiotti S, Foissey C, Pineda T, et al. (2024) Enhancing robotic precision in medial UKA: Image-based robot-assisted system had higher accuracy in implant positioning than imageless robot-assisted system across 292 knees. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 32, 2097&#x2013;2106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38690988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andriollo L, Montagna A, Mazzella GG, et al. (2024) Navigated versus conventional medial unicompartmental knee arthroplasty: Minimum 18&#xa0;years clinical outcomes and survivorship of the original Cartier design. Knee 49, 183&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39043013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andriollo L, Mazzella GG, Koutserimpas C, et al. (2025) Functional positioning in robotic medial unicompartmental knee arthroplasty: a step-by-step technique. SICOT J 11, 34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12158242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40498988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foissey C, Batailler C, Fontalis A, et al. (2024) Long-term outcomes in unicompartmental knee arthroplasty: Survivorship of medial versus lateral unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. J ISAKOS 9, 100329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39413926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berend KR, Kolczun MC, George JW, Lombardi AV (2012) Lateral unicompartmental knee arthroplasty through a lateral parapatellar approach has high early survivorship. Clin Orthop Relat Res 470, 77&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3237974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21822570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunyoz KI, Lindberg-Larsen M, Gromov K, Troelsen A (2025) Optimising outcomes in lateral unicompartmental knee arthroplasty: Analysing 25 years of registry data. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. Advance online publication. 10.1002/ksa.12785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.12785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12684322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40652369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foissey C, Batailler C, Vahabi A, et al. (2023) Combination of a high residual varus and joint-line lowering strongly increases the risk of early implant failure in medial unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty 38, 2275&#x2013;2281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37271228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaudiani MA, Nwachukwu BU, Baviskar JV, et al. (2017) Optimization of sagittal and coronal planes with robotic-assisted unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. Knee 24, 837&#x2013;843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28579132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron G, Ruid&#xed;az S, Torres R (2024) Perfect indications and how to avoid complications in lateral unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. J ISAKOS 9, 100342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39413923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>