<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41920292</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physiological Outcomes of Physical Activity Interventions in Persistent Postconcussive Symptoms: A Scoping Review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-026-02421-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Persistent postconcussive symptoms (PPCS) are associated with prolonged functional impairment and physiological dysregulation following mild traumatic brain injury, yet objective markers of recovery and treatment response remain limited.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The objective of this review was to synthesize the impact of aerobic exercise on physiological alterations in PPCS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This paper is a scoping review reported in accordance with PRISMA-ScR. A protocol was published in advance, with the last search&#xa0;conducted on 31 May 2025. This review scanned the following databases: PubMed, MEDLINE, EMBASE, Cochrane Library, Web of Science, and Scopus. Eligible studies were original human studies with clinically diagnosed persistent postconcussive symptoms or mild traumatic brain injury that implemented a physical activity or aerobic exercise intervention and reported at least one physiological outcome (e.g., blood pressure, cerebrovascular indices, or heart rate variability). The exclusion criteria were as follows: moderate/severe traumatic brain injury, self-reported concussion without clinical diagnosis, non-English studies, animal studies, and review papers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of 1451 papers found, five were eligible. Individualized sub-symptom-threshold aerobic exercise consistently improved exercise tolerance and heart rate thresholds; several studies showed normalization of exertional blood pressure responses and improved CO<sub>2</sub> sensitivity/cerebral blood flow control. Resting heart rate variability and resting blood pressure findings were mixed. Evidence gaps include small sample sizes and limited equity-relevant reporting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Aerobic exercise yields physiological benefits in PPCS and is actionable for management and progression. Future studies should standardize physiological endpoints, include underrepresented populations, and test predictive markers to allow for precise rehabilitation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dehghani</LastName><ForeName>Bayan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prairie Vascular Research Inc, Regina, SK, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ellingson</LastName><ForeName>Chase J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prairie Vascular Research Inc, Regina, SK, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neary</LastName><ForeName>J Patrick</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kinesiology and Health Studies, University of Regina, Regina, SK, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Jyotpal</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prairie Vascular Research Inc, Regina, SK, Canada. jsingh.pvri@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: &#xa0;The authors have no relevant financial or non-financial interests to disclose. &#xa0; Ethics approval: Ethics approval was not applicable. This study synthesizes previously published data only and did not involve human participants or animals. Data availability statement: All data extracted for this review are contained within the article and its supplementary materials [35]. Author contributions: Bayan Dehghani&#xa0;and Jyotpal Singh&#xa0;conceived and proposed the review.&#xa0;Bayan Dehghani&#xa0;and Jyotpal Singh executed the database searches, managed screening and data charting, and drafted the initial manuscript.&#xa0;All authors&#xa0;verified extractions and resolved discrepancies. All authors jointly developed the research questions, study design, and methods; and contributed to subsequent and final revisions of the manuscript.&#xa0;Jyotpal Singh&#xa0;is the corresponding author. All authors approved the final version.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41920292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-026-02421-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-026-02421-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lubbers VF, van den Hoven DJ, van der Naalt J, Jellema K, van den Brand C, Backus B. Emergency department risk factors for post-concussion syndrome after mild traumatic brain injury: a systematic review. J Neurotrauma. 2024;41:1253&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.1089/neu.2023.0302 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/neu.2023.0302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38390830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barlow KM. Postconcussion syndrome: a review. J Child Neurol. 2016;31:57&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073814543305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25330797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patricios JS, Schneider KJ, Dvorak J, Ahmed OH, Blauwet C, Cantu RC, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport: the 6th International Conference on Concussion in Sport-Amsterdam, October 2022. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57:695&#x2013;711. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2023-106898 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-106898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37316210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellingson CA, Singh J, Ellingson CJ, Shafiq MA, Sirant LW, Dorsch KD, et al. Sport-related concussion alters cerebral hemodynamic activity during controlled respiration. J Neurophysiol. 2024;131:556&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00477.2023 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jn.00477.2023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38324895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellingson CJ, Shafiq MA, Ellingson CA, Neary JP, Dehghani P, Singh J. Assessment of cardiovascular functioning following sport-related concussion: a physiological perspective. Auton Neurosci. 2024;252:103160. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autneu.2024.103160 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2024.103160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38428323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellingson CJ, Singh J, Ellingson CA, Sirant LW, Kratzig GP, Dorsch KD, et al. Alterations in baroreflex sensitivity and blood pressure variability following sport-related concussion. Life. 2022. https://doi.org/10.3390/life12091400 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/life12091400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36143435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9500648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leddy JJ, Burma JS, Toomey CM, Hayden A, Davis GA, Babl FE, et al. Rest and exercise early after sport-related concussion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57:762&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2022-106676 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2022-106676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37316185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirant LW, Singh J, Martin S, Gaul CA, Stuart-Hill L, Candow DG, et al. Long-term effects of multiple concussions on prefrontal cortex oxygenation during neurovascular coupling activation in retired male contact sport athletes. Curr Res Physiol. 2022;5:421&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.crphys.2022.11.002 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.crphys.2022.11.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36466150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9713254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirant LW, Singh J, Martin S, Gaul CA, Stuart-Hill L, Candow DG, et al. Long-term effects of multiple concussions on prefrontal cortex oxygenation during repeated squat-stands in retired contact sport athletes. Brain Inj. 2022;36:931&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1080/02699052.2022.2109737 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02699052.2022.2109737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35968581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop SA, Dech RT, Guzik P, Neary JP. Heart rate variability and implication for sport concussion. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2018;38:733&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpf.12487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29144026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dech RT, Bishop SA, Neary JP. Why exercise may be beneficial in concussion rehabilitation: a cellular perspective. J Sci Med Sport. 2019;22:1090&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2019.06.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31349959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giza CC, Hovda DA. The new neurometabolic cascade of concussion. Neurosurgery. 2014;75:S24&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1227/NEU.0000000000000505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25232881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4479139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haider MN, Bezherano I, Wertheimer A, Siddiqui AH, Horn EC, Willer BS, et al. Exercise for sport-related concussion and persistent postconcussive symptoms. Sports Health. 2021;13:154&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738120946015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33147117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Len TK, Neary JP, Asmundson GJ, Goodman DG, Bjornson B, Bhambhani YN. Cerebrovascular reactivity impairment after sport-induced concussion. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:2241&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0b013e3182249539 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3182249539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21606867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacFarlane MP, Glenn TC. Neurochemical cascade of concussion. Brain Inj. 2015;29:139&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/02699052.2014.965208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25587743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh J, Bhagaloo L, Piskorski J, Neary JP. Effects of phytocannabinoids on heart rate variability and blood pressure variability in female post-concussion syndrome patients: case series. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 2022;100:192&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1139/cjpp-2021-0395 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/cjpp-2021-0395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34597522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh J, Neary JP. Neuroprotection following concussion: the potential role for cannabidiol. Can J Neurol Sci. 2020;47:289&#x2013;300. https://doi.org/10.1017/cjn.2020.23 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/cjn.2020.23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32029015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehghani B, Singh J, Ellingson CJ, Neary JP. Physiological outcomes of physical activity interventions in persistent postconcussive symptoms: a scoping review protocol. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2025;11:e002529. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjsem-2025-002529 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2025-002529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40092167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11907037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercier LJ, McIntosh SJ, Boucher C, Joyce JM, Batycky J, Galarneau JM, et al. Evaluating a 12-week aerobic exercise intervention in adults with persisting post-concussive symptoms. Front Neurol. 2024;15:1482266. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2024.1482266 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2024.1482266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39777319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11703733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moser N, Popovic MR, Kalsi-Ryan S. Complexity of post-concussion syndrome assessment and management: a case for customizing rehabilitation. Biomed Eng Online. 2025;24:48. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12938-025-01380-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12938-025-01380-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40281618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12032806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen JVK, McKay A, Ponsford J, Davies K, Makdissi M, Drummond SPA, et al. Interdisciplinary rehabilitation for persisting post-concussion symptoms after mTBI: N = 15 single case experimental design. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2023;66:101777. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rehab.2023.101777 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rehab.2023.101777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37890339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clausen M, Pendergast DR, Willer B, Leddy J. Cerebral blood flow during treadmill exercise is a marker of physiological postconcussion syndrome in female athletes. J Head Trauma Rehabil. 2016;31:215&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1097/htr.0000000000000145 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/htr.0000000000000145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26098254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leddy JJ, Kozlowski K, Donnelly JP, Pendergast DR, Epstein LH, Willer B. A preliminary study of subsymptom threshold exercise training for refractory post-concussion syndrome. Clin J Sport Med. 2010;20:21&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1097/JSM.0b013e3181c6c22c .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0b013e3181c6c22c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20051730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen A, Pope R, Rando N. Clinical application of the buffalo concussion treadmill test and the buffalo concussion bike test: a systematic review. J Concuss. 2022;6:20597002221127551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20597002221127551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vedung F, Fahlstrom M, Wall A, Antoni G, Lubberink M, Johansson J, et al. Chronic cerebral blood flow alterations in traumatic brain injury and sports-related concussions. Brain Inj. 2022;36:948&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1080/02699052.2022.2109746 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02699052.2022.2109746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35950271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Q, Levine BD. Exercise and non-pharmacological treatment of POTS. Auton Neurosci. 2018;215:20&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autneu.2018.07.001 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2018.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30001836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6289756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leddy JJ, Haider MN, Ellis M, Willer BS. Exercise is medicine for concussion. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2018;17:262&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.1249/jsr.0000000000000505 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/jsr.0000000000000505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30095546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6089233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cano Sokoloff N, Misra M, Ackerman KE. Exercise, training, and the hypothalamic&#x2013;pituitary&#x2013;gonadal axis in men and women. Front Horm Res. 2016;47:27&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.1159/000445154 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000445154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27348623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7043068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassilhas RC, Tufik S, de Mello MT. Physical exercise, neuroplasticity, spatial learning and memory. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2016;73:975&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00018-015-2102-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00018-015-2102-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26646070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainslie PN, Cotter JD, George KP, Lucas S, Murrell C, Shave R, et al. Elevation in cerebral blood flow velocity with aerobic fitness throughout healthy human ageing. J Physiol. 2008;586:4005&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2008.158279 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2008.158279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18635643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2538930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smirl JD, Hoffman K, Tzeng YC, Hansen A, Ainslie PN. Methodological comparison of active- and passive-driven oscillations in blood pressure; implications for the assessment of cerebral pressure-flow relationships. J Appl Physiol. 2015;119(5):487&#x2013;501. https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00264.2015 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00264.2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26183476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4556839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rytter HM, Graff HJ, Henriksen HK, Aaen N, Hartvigsen J, Hoegh M, et al. Nonpharmacological treatment of persistent postconcussion symptoms in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis and guideline recommendation. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e2132221. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.32221 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.32221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34751759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8579233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moser N, Gargoum S, Popovic MR, Kalsi-Ryan S. Effectiveness of non-pharmacological therapy on physical symptoms in patients with persistent concussion symptoms: a systematic review. J Neurotrauma. 2024;41:1473&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1089/neu.2023.0474 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/neu.2023.0474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38149605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrisman SP, Rivara FP, Schiff MA, Zhou C, Comstock RD. Risk factors for concussive symptoms 1 week or longer in high school athletes. Brain Inj. 2013;27:1&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.3109/02699052.2012.722251 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/02699052.2012.722251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23252433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.n71 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8005924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>