<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41822254</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease and Overtraining Syndrome: A Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e105016</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e105016</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e105016</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.105016</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) is a condition that inevitably leads to airflow limitation. COPD is among the leading causes of increased mortality and morbidity worldwide. A non-invasive and non-pharmacological approach is rehabilitation training, where the patient follows an active program to stimulate the limb and respiratory muscles. Training involves a constant increase in workloads throughout the rehabilitation process. A fundamental concept absent from the literature is that of including training sessions with reduced loads and periods of "unloading" intensity within the rehabilitation program. Without adequate recovery and rest between sessions, the patient may lack the resources necessary to tackle a subsequent demanding rehabilitation session. This situation could lead to the onset of overtraining syndrome (OTS), where the patient experiences an unexplained decline in performance. The article reviews the muscular adaptation of COPD patients and the planned rehabilitation and emphasizes the concept that clinicians should structure the rehabilitation training program not in a linear fashion (constantly increasing loads), but in a wave-like fashion (scheduling some sessions with decreased loads). This organization could benefit the patient's performance, reducing the risk of OTS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Bordoni et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bordoni</LastName><ForeName>Bruno</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Fondazione Don Carlo Gnocchi, Milan, ITA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mattia</LastName><ForeName>Enricomaria</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Centro di Radiologia Medica e Terapia Fisica Morrone, Servizio Sanitario Nazionale, Caserta, ITA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morabito</LastName><ForeName>Bruno</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Universit&#xe0; Cattolica del Sacro Cuore, Agostino Gemelli University Hospital, Rome, ITA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">american thoracic society</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">copd</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diaphragm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">european respiratory society</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fev1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inspiratory muscle training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">maximal inspiratory pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">overtraining syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41822254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12976572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.105016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of treatable traits among patients with very severe COPD across STAR and GOLD classification: a multicenter cohort study. Meng W, Ma Y, Wu J, et al. Pulmonology. 2026;32:2613525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41532221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mortality and exacerbation risk according to GOLD and STAR severity stages of COPD: a 5-year multicenter prospective cohort study. Ogata H, Tsubouchi K, Takano T, et al. Sci Rep. 2025;15:19097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12125300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40447720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical impact of disease stability on exacerbation and mortality in COPD: a retrospective cohort study. Kim SH, Lee JK, Min KH, Kim DK, Lee HW. Ann Med. 2026;58:2611466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12778000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41492099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The glymphatic system and diaphragmatic dysfunction in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and chronic heart failure: the importance of inspiratory rehabilitation training. Bordoni B, Morabito B, Myftari V, D'Amato A, Severino P. J Cardiovasc Dev Dis. 2025;12:390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12564880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41149261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The importance of the diaphragm in neuromotor function in the patient with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Bordoni B, Escher A, Compalati E, Mapelli L, Toccafondi A. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2023;18:837&#x2013;848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10184771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37197600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costen's syndrome and COPD. Bordoni B. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2019;14:457&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6388777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30863046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chest pain in patients with COPD: the fascia's subtle silence. Bordoni B, Marelli F, Morabito B, Castagna R. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2018;13:1157&#x2013;1165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5903840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29695899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low back pain and gastroesophageal reflux in patients with COPD: the disease in the breath. Bordoni B, Marelli F, Morabito B, Sacconi B, Caiazzo P, Castagna R. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2018;13:325&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5777378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29403270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Depression, anxiety and chronic pain in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: the influence of breath. Bordoni B, Marelli F, Morabito B, Sacconi B. Monaldi Arch Chest Dis. 2017;87:811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28635197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heart failure, myocardial infarction, lung cancer and death in COPD patients: a UK primary care study. Rodr&#xed;guez LA, Wallander MA, Mart&#xed;n-Merino E, Johansson S. Respir Med. 2010;104:1691&#x2013;1699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20483577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osteoporosis and the risk of temporomandibular disorder in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Lee KC, Wu YT, Chien WC, Chung CH, Shen CH, Chen LC, Shieh YS. J Bone Miner Metab. 2021;39:201&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32725266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exploring the risk association between psoriasis and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, and asthma using the NHIS database. Liu M, Ji S, Ye P, Gong M, Liu Q. PLoS One. 2026;21:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12904444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41686756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stroke risk of COPD patients and death risk of COPD patients following a stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ding C, Wang R, Gong X, Yuan Y. Medicine (Baltimore) 2023;102:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10681394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38013361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of anion inhalation in a mouse model of cigarette smoke-induced chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Li Y, Lu J, Chen Y, et al. COPD. 2026;23:2603725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41649473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of smoking in the mechanisms of development of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and atherosclerosis. Kotlyarov S. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24:8725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10217854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37240069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skeletal muscle function in relation to COPD severity and its predictive significance for disease progression. He Z, Cao B, Liu K, Wei Q. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2025;20:389&#x2013;397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11853920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40008111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skeletal muscle dysfunction in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. What we know and can do for our patients. Jaitovich A, Barreiro E. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2018;198:175&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6058991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29554438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An official American Thoracic Society/European Respiratory Society statement: key concepts and advances in pulmonary rehabilitation. Spruit MA, Singh SJ, Garvey C, et al. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2013;188:0&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24127811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulmonary rehabilitation for adults with chronic respiratory disease: an official American Thoracic Society clinical practice guideline. Rochester CL, Alison JA, Carlin B, et al. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2023;208:0&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10449064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37581410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>British Thoracic Society clinical statement on pulmonary rehabilitation. Man W, Chaplin E, Daynes E, et al. Thorax. 2023;78:0&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37770084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Summary for clinicians: clinical practice guideline on pulmonary rehabilitation for adults with chronic respiratory disease. Jenkins AR, Cox NS, Tappan RS, et al. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2024;21:533&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38241016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise prescription training in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: benefits and mechanisms. Liu S, Yang A, Yu Y, Xu B, Yu G, Wang H. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2025;20:1071&#x2013;1082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12009044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40255692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Characteristics of rehabilitation programs for chronic respiratory diseases in Asia: a scoping review. Chadha N, Blackstock FC, Smith S, Camp PG, Tang C. Respir Med. 2025;236:107885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39603392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Supervised maintenance programmes following pulmonary rehabilitation compared to usual care for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Malaguti C, Dal Corso S, Janjua S, Holland AE. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;8:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8407510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34404111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enhanced diaphragm excursion and exercise tolerance in COPD patients through inspiratory muscle training after standardised pulmonary rehabilitation: randomised controlled trial. Shiraishi M, Higashimoto Y, Sugiya R, et al. ERJ Open Res. 2024;10:35&#x2013;2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11587166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39588075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inspiratory muscle training, with or without concomitant pulmonary rehabilitation, for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) Ammous O, Feki W, Lotfi T, Khamis AM, Gosselink R, Rebai A, Kammoun S. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2023;1:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9817429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36606682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of power-breath versus transcutaneous electrical diaphragmatic stimulation on the severity of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a randomized controlled trial. Abdelsalam EM, Serry ZM, Soliman YM, Elmasry DM, El Moatassem AM. Physiother Res Int. 2025;30:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40478627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of inspiratory muscle training in people with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Han B, Chen Z, Ruan B, Chen Y, Lv Y, Li C, Yu L. Life (Basel) 2024;14:1470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11595718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39598268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of pulmonary rehabilitation combined with inspiratory muscle training on lung function and exercise capacity in older patients with COPD: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Xie J, Zhu Y, Wang Y, et al. Front Med (Lausanne) 2025;12:1621375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12285735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40703265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1334&#x2013;1359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of non-functional overreaching and overtraining syndrome on psychological and cognitive functioning in elite athletes: a systematic review. Valdesalici A, Sella E, Domenicucci R, Ghisi M, Borella E. Psychol Sport Exerc. 2026;84:103079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41580212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comprehensive analysis of overtraining syndrome in athletes and recreational exercisers. Buchwald RL, Buchwald J, Lehtonen E, Peltonen JE, Uusitalo AL. Int J Sports Med. 2025;46:898&#x2013;907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40628368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overtraining and recovery: a conceptual model. Kentt&#xe4; G, Hassm&#xe9;n P. Sports Med. 1998;26:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9739537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Current concepts in periodization of strength and conditioning for the sports physical therapist. Lorenz D, Morrison S. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26618056/ Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2015;10:734&#x2013;747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4637911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26618056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reverse linear neuro periodization model for rehabilitation after arthroscopic rotator cuff repair: a narrative review. Kakavas G, Brilakis E, Papatzikou M, Malliaropoulos N, Mazeas J, Forelli F. Clin Pract. 2025;15:105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12192029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40558223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of the overtraining syndrome: joint consensus statement of the European College of Sport Science and the American College of Sports Medicine. Meeusen R, Duclos M, Foster C, et al. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45:186&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23247672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overtraining syndrome: a practical guide. Kreher JB, Schwartz JB. Sports Health. 2012;4:128&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3435910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23016079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyond physical exhaustion: understanding overtraining syndrome through the lens of molecular mechanisms and clinical manifestation. Fiala O, Hanzlova M, Borska L, Fiala Z, Holmannova D. Sports Med Health Sci. 2025;7:237&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12010411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40264836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overtraining syndrome as a complex systems phenomenon. Armstrong LE, Bergeron MF, Lee EC, Mershon JE, Armstrong EM. Front Netw Physiol. 2021;1:794392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10013019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36925581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overtraining syndrome as a risk factor for bone stress injuries among paralympic athletes. Madzar T, Masina T, Zaja R, et al. Medicina (Kaunas) 2023;60:52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10819479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38256312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trainability of young athletes and overtraining. Matos N, Winsley RJ. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24149422/ J Sports Sci Med. 2007;6:353&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3787286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peripheral signals of energy homeostasis as possible markers of training stress in athletes: a review. J&#xfc;rim&#xe4;e J, M&#xe4;estu J, J&#xfc;rim&#xe4;e T, Mangus B, von Duvillard SP. Metabolism. 2011;60:335&#x2013;350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20304442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novel causes and consequences of overtraining syndrome: the EROS-DISRUPTORS study. Cadegiani FA, Kater CE. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2019;11:21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6751688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31548891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Use of heart-rate variability to examine readiness to perform in response to overload and taper in swimmers. Bulte KR, Bruce L, Hammond K, Corrigan SL, Main LC. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2025;20:918&#x2013;924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40360152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heart rate variability, blood pressure variability, and baroreflex sensitivity in overtrained athletes. Baumert M, Brechtel L, Lock J, Hermsdorf M, Wolff R, Baier V, Voss A. Clin J Sport Med. 2006;16:412&#x2013;417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17016118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heart rate variability during night sleep and after awakening in overtrained athletes. Hynynen E, Uusitalo A, Konttinen N, Rusko H. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38:313&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16531900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orthostatic testing for heart rate and heart rate variability monitoring in exercise science and practice. Gronwald T, Schaffarczyk M, Hoos O. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024;124:3495&#x2013;3510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39259398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A novel approach to training monotony and acute-chronic workload index: a comparative study in soccer. Afonso J, Nakamura FY, Can&#xe1;rio-Lemos R, et al. Front Sports Act Living. 2021;3:661200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8200417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34136806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Variations of training load, monotony, and strain and dose-response relationships with maximal aerobic speed, maximal oxygen uptake, and isokinetic strength in professional soccer players. Clemente FM, Clark C, Castillo D, Sarmento H, Nikolaidis PT, Rosemann T, Knechtle B. PLoS One. 2019;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6892557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31800617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A novel role for the ADHD risk gene latrophilin-3 in learning and memory in Lphn3 knockout rats. Regan SL, Pitzer EM, Hufgard JR, Sugimoto C, Williams MT, Vorhees CV. Neurobiol Dis. 2021;158:105456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34352385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of overtraining on cognitive function in endurance athletes: a systematic review. Symons IK, Bruce L, Main LC. Sports Med Open. 2023;9:69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10409951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37552398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>How much is too much? (Part 2) International Olympic Committee consensus statement on load in sport and risk of illness. Schwellnus M, Soligard T, Alonso JM, et al. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:1043&#x2013;1052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27535990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise-induced oxidative stress: cellular mechanisms and impact on muscle force production. Powers SK, Jackson MJ. Physiol Rev. 2008;88:1243&#x2013;1276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2909187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18923182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The emerging role of glutamine as an indicator of exercise stress and overtraining. Rowbottom DG, Keast D, Morton AR. Sports Med. 1996;21:80&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8775515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Can we predict top-level sports performance in power vs endurance events? A genetic approach. Buxens A, Ruiz JR, Arteta D, et al. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011;21:570&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20459474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hungry runners - low energy availability in male endurance athletes and its impact on performance and testosterone: mini-review. Cupka M, Sedliak M. Eur J Transl Myol. 2023;33:11104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10388605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37052052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COPD and the burden of multimorbidity: navigating the complexity. Kallieri M, Hillas G, Bartziokas K, Loukides S, Toumpanakis D. Expert Rev Respir Med. 2026;20:251&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41054835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genome-wide differential airway gene expression analysis identifies genes associated with COPD comorbidities. Faiz A, Ter Haar EA, Hartman JE, et al. Lung. 2025;203:58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12033178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40287517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscle metabolic status in patients with severe COPD with and without long-term prednisolone. Pouw EM, Koerts-de Lang E, Gosker HR, Freling G, van der Vusse GJ, Wouters EF, Schols AM. Eur Respir J. 2000;16:247&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10968499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skeletal muscle dysfunction in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and chronic heart failure: underlying mechanisms and therapy perspectives. Gosker HR, Wouters EF, van der Vusse GJ, Schols AM. Am J Clin Nutr. 2000;71:1033&#x2013;1047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10799364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exogenous glutamine in respiratory diseases: myth or reality? Oliveira GP, de Abreu MG, Pelosi P, Rocco PR. Nutrients. 2016;8:76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4772040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26861387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autonomic nervous system dysfunction in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: mechanistic insights and therapeutic implications. Chen D, Zhou Z, Zhou Z, Zhao L, Chen Y. Ann Med. 2025;57:2596426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12687893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41355150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The gut-lung axis in COPD: immunomodulatory roles of gut microbiota and novel therapeutic strategies. Ni FX, Wang HX, Hu J, et al. Front Immunol. 2026;17:1733726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12886472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41676136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>