<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41850425</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2090-1224</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of advanced research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Adv Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Rsv@HMnO<sub>2</sub>-HA nanozyme for AKI therapy via targeting inflammatory storm and activating SIRT1/PGC-1&#x3b1; to restore mitochondrial homeostasis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2090-1232(26)00250-X</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jare.2026.03.029</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Acute kidney injury (AKI) is a devastating global health burden. Its pathogenesis, particularly in ischemia/reperfusion (I/R) injury, centers on a vicious cycle between a reactive oxygen species (ROS)-driven inflammatory storm and severe mitochondrial dysfunction in renal tubular cells. While activation of the SIRT1/PGC-1&#x3b1; pathway is a promising therapeutic target for mitochondrial recovery, its potent agonist resveratrol (Rsv) suffers from poor bioavailability, and monotherapy fails to address the concomitant inflammatory pathology.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to develop a kidney-targeted theranostic nanoplatform that synergistically breaks this pathological cycle. We hypothesized that a nanoplatform co-delivering Rsv and a ROS-scavenging component could concurrently suppress inflammation via direct ROS elimination and restore mitochondrial homeostasis via SIRT1/PGC-1&#x3b1; activation, with integrated magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) capability for monitoring.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We engineered a theranostic nanoplatform designated Rsv@HMnO<sub>2</sub>-HA (HMRH NPs). The platform was constructed by loading Rsv into hollow mesoporous manganese dioxide (HMnO<sub>2</sub>) nanozymes, followed by surface coating with hyaluronic acid (HA) for active targeting to CD44 receptors over expressed on injured renal tubules. The system's physicochemical properties were thoroughly characterized. Its therapeutic efficacy and theranostic performance were systematically evaluated in a well-established murine model of renal I/R-induced AKI, using a combination of biochemical assays, histological analysis, molecular biology techniques, and in vivo MRI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">HMRH NPs successfully accumulated in injured kidneys and disassembled in situ. The HMnO<sub>2</sub> shell effectively scavenged excess ROS, attenuating the inflammatory response. The co-released Rsv activated the SIRT1/PGC-1&#x3b1; pathway, restored mitochondrial biogenesis, and improved cellular energy homeostasis. The released Mn<sup>2+</sup> ions enabled clear T<sub>1</sub>-weighted MRI contrast, allowing real-time visualization of renal targeting and therapeutic progression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results conclusively demonstrate that the HMRH NPs successfully implements a synergistic two-pronged therapeutic strategy. By co-delivering a ROS-scavenger and a mitochondrial-regenerative agent directly to the site of injury, the platform effectively disrupts the critical pathological crosstalk between inflammation and mitochondrial damage in AKI. This work presents a holistic, targeted, and image-guided nanomedicine strategy, offering a promising approach for the effective treatment and monitoring of AKI.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Jiaxin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Children's Hospital of Chongqing Medical University, National Clinical Research Center for Child Health and Disorders, Ministry of Education Key Laboratory of Child Development and Disorders, China International Science and Technology Cooperation Base of Child Development and Critical Disorders, Chongqing Key Laboratory of Child Neurodevelopment and Cognitive Disorders, Chongqing 400014, PR China; Clinical Pathology Laboratory of Pathology Diagnostic Center, and Molecular Medicine Diagnostic &amp; Testing Center, Chongqing Medical University, 1 Yixueyuan Road, Yuzhong Distinct, Chongqing 400016, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Lingcheng</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Pathology Laboratory of Pathology Diagnostic Center, and Molecular Medicine Diagnostic &amp; Testing Center, Chongqing Medical University, 1 Yixueyuan Road, Yuzhong Distinct, Chongqing 400016, PR China; Department of Urology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Chongqing Medical University, Chongqing 400016, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Huiru</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Children's Hospital of Chongqing Medical University, National Clinical Research Center for Child Health and Disorders, Ministry of Education Key Laboratory of Child Development and Disorders, China International Science and Technology Cooperation Base of Child Development and Critical Disorders, Chongqing Key Laboratory of Child Neurodevelopment and Cognitive Disorders, Chongqing 400014, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Haoru</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Children's Hospital of Chongqing Medical University, National Clinical Research Center for Child Health and Disorders, Ministry of Education Key Laboratory of Child Development and Disorders, China International Science and Technology Cooperation Base of Child Development and Critical Disorders, Chongqing Key Laboratory of Child Neurodevelopment and Cognitive Disorders, Chongqing 400014, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoya</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Children's Hospital of Chongqing Medical University, National Clinical Research Center for Child Health and Disorders, Ministry of Education Key Laboratory of Child Development and Disorders, China International Science and Technology Cooperation Base of Child Development and Critical Disorders, Chongqing Key Laboratory of Child Neurodevelopment and Cognitive Disorders, Chongqing 400014, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Bing</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, College of Basic Medicine, Chongqing Medical University, 1 Yixueyuan Road, Yuzhong Distinct, Chongqing, 400016, PR China; Clinical Pathology Laboratory of Pathology Diagnostic Center, and Molecular Medicine Diagnostic &amp; Testing Center, Chongqing Medical University, 1 Yixueyuan Road, Yuzhong Distinct, Chongqing 400016, PR China. Electronic address: doctorliang51@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cai</LastName><ForeName>Jinhua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Children's Hospital of Chongqing Medical University, National Clinical Research Center for Child Health and Disorders, Ministry of Education Key Laboratory of Child Development and Disorders, China International Science and Technology Cooperation Base of Child Development and Critical Disorders, Chongqing Key Laboratory of Child Neurodevelopment and Cognitive Disorders, Chongqing 400014, PR China. Electronic address: cai_jinhua@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Egypt</Country><MedlineTA>J Adv Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101546952</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2090-1224</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute kidney injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hollow mesoporous manganese dioxide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammatory storm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mitochondrial homeostasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nanoplatform</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Theranostics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41850425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jare.2026.03.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2090-1232(26)00250-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>