<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41856352</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-6500</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of shoulder and elbow surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Shoulder Elbow Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biomechanical Changes After Reverse Total Shoulder Arthroplasty: A Systematic Review of Advanced Measurement Technologies.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1058-2746(26)00144-8</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jse.2026.03.002</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Reverse total shoulder arthroplasty (rTSA) consistently improves pain and function; however, the biomechanical mechanisms underpinning postoperative function and joint-level adaptations remain incompletely defined. Advanced measurement tools, including motion capture, electromyography (EMG), inertial measurement units (IMU), and accelerometry, enable objective assessment of joint motion, muscle activation, and real-world arm use. This systematic review synthesizes evidence from studies using advanced biomechanical methods to evaluate postoperative kinematics, upper-limb activity, and muscle activation after rTSA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Seven databases (1985-2025) were searched for observational studies reporting quantitative biomechanical outcomes after rTSA, compared with preoperative baselines, contralateral shoulders, or healthy controls. Outcomes were categorized as kinematics, real-world upper-limb activity, or neuromuscular activation. Methodological quality was assessed using Joanna Briggs Institute criteria, and levels of evidence were classified according to Journal of Shoulder and Elbow Surgery guidelines.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-four studies (10 cohort and 14 case-control; all Level III) met inclusion criteria. Twenty-one had moderate risk-of-bias and three high risk. Implant designs, surgical indications, and follow-up durations were heterogeneous. High-rigor optical and electromagnetic motion capture studies showed consistent gains in forward elevation, while glenohumeral contribution, axial rotation, and scapulohumeral rhythm remained reduced relative to contralateral or healthy shoulders. Elevation occurred predominantly through increased scapulothoracic upward rotation, retraction, and posterior tilt. Laboratory-based IMU studies showed similar patterns of greater scapular contribution despite non-standardized coordinate systems. Wearable sensors reported increased postoperative arm use and improved interlimb symmetry, although time spent above shoulder height remained limited. EMG studies demonstrated increased deltoid and upper-trapezius activation with limited posterior cuff recruitment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">rTSA restores forward elevation primarily via compensatory scapulothoracic motion and deltoid-driven neuromuscular strategies rather than normalization of glenohumeral mechanics. Standardized, longitudinal studies integrating high-fidelity kinematics, EMG, and real-world activity monitoring, with explicit reporting of implant construct parameters, are needed to clarify how surgical technique and implant design influence postoperative biomechanics and functional recovery.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026. Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thomson</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Unit for Advanced Shoulder Research (QUASR), Brisbane, Queensland, Australia; Australian Research Council Industrial Transformation Training Centre for Joint Biomechanics, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Australia; School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Australia. Electronic address: anna.thomson@hdr.qut.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Felix</LastName><ForeName>Terence</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lichtwark</LastName><ForeName>Glen</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Whitehouse</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Unit for Advanced Shoulder Research (QUASR), Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Ashish</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Unit for Advanced Shoulder Research (QUASR), Brisbane, Queensland, Australia; Australian Research Council Industrial Transformation Training Centre for Joint Biomechanics, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kerr</LastName><ForeName>Graham</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Unit for Advanced Shoulder Research (QUASR), Brisbane, Queensland, Australia; Australian Research Council Industrial Transformation Training Centre for Joint Biomechanics, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Australia; School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Shoulder Elbow Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9206499</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1058-2746</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reverse total shoulder arthroplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomechanics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electromyography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inertial measurement units</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kinematics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motion capture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scapulohumeral rhythm</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41856352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jse.2026.03.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1058-2746(26)00144-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>