<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41776410</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2180</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Deciphering of a bioactive molecule with a three-domain inhibitory activity from a halophilic bacterium Arhodomonas sp. AD133.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12866-026-04899-8</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Shao</LastName><ForeName>Shilong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Sciences, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, 241000, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Huihui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chinese Materia Medica, Yunnan University of Chinese Medicine, Kunming, Yunnan, 650500, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Yue</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Sciences, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, 241000, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Xinran</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Sciences, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, 241000, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gong</LastName><ForeName>Ming</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Sciences, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, 241000, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Shengda</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Sciences, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, 241000, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Canhong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Sciences, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, 241000, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boyu</LastName><ForeName>Tang</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Sciences, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, 241000, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jucheng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chinese Materia Medica, Yunnan University of Chinese Medicine, Kunming, Yunnan, 650500, China. zhangjc@ynucm.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gong</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Key Laboratory of Intelligent Tracking and Forecasting for Infectious Diseases, National Institute for Communicable Disease Control and Prevention, Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Beijing, 102206, China. gongjie@icdc.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Pathogenic Fungi, National Institute for Communicable Disease Control and Prevention Joint, Peking University First Hospital, Beijing, 102206, China. gongjie@icdc.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Collaborative Innovation Center of Recovery and Reconstruction of Degraded Ecosystem in Wanjiang Basin Co-Founded by Anhui Province and Ministry of Education, School of Ecology and Environment, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, 241002, China. gongjie@icdc.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Shaoxing</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Sciences, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, 241000, Anhui, China. chensx@ahnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Microbial Technology, Shandong University, Qingdao, 266237, Shandong, China. chensx@ahnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yunnan Key Laboratory for Fungal Diversity and Green Development, Kunming Institute of Botany, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Kunming, Yunnan, 650201, China. chensx@ahnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>202401AZ070001-009</GrantID><Agency>Yunnan Fundamental Research Projects</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022YFC2504800</GrantID><Agency>National Key Research and Development Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>102393240020020000003</GrantID><Agency>Enhancement of Communicable Disease Surveillance and Control Technical Capabilities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2208085MC39</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Anhui Province, China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SKLMR-20220702</GrantID><Agency>Opening Project of the State Key Laboratory of Microbial Resources</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100966981</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2180</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Arhodomonas</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-domain inhibition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Halophiles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypersaline environments</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pyoluteorin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biological pesticides</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Conflict of interest: The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41776410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12866-026-04899-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12866-026-04899-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hibbing ME, Fuqua C, Parsek MR, Peterson SB. Bacterial competition: surviving and thriving in the microbial jungle. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2010;8:15&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linares JF, Gustafsson I, Baquero F, Martinez JL. Antibiotics as intermicrobial signaling agents instead of weapons. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2006;103:19484&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waksman SA, Woodruff HB. The soil as a source of microorganisms antagonistic to disease-producing bacteria. J Bacteriol. 1940;40:581&#x2013;600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murindangabo YT, Kopeck&#xfd; M, Pern&#xe1; K, Nguyen TG, Konvalina P, Kavkov&#xe1; M. Prominent use of lactic acid bacteria in soil-plant systems. Appl Soil Ecol. 2023;189:104955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parafati L, Vitale A, Restuccia C, Cirvilleri G. Biocontrol ability and action mechanism of food-isolated yeast strains against Botrytis cinerea causing post-harvest bunch rot of table grape. Food Microbiol. 2015;47:85&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belkaid Y, Segre JA. Dialogue between skin microbiota and immunity. Science. 2014;346:954&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakatsuji T, Chen TH, Butcher AM, Trzoss LL, Nam SJ, Shirakawa KT, Zhou W, Oh J, Otto M, Fenical W, Gallo RL. A commensal strain of Staphylococcus epidermidis protects against skin neoplasia. Sci Adv. 2018;4:eaao4502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson TP, Gilmore BF. Exploring halophilic environments as a source of new antibiotics. Crit Rev Microbiol. 2024;50:341&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur N, Singh SP, Zhang C. Microorganisms under extreme environments and their applications. Curr Res Microb Sci. 2022;3:100141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long RA, Eveillard D, Franco SL, Reeves E, Pinckney JL. Antagonistic interactions between heterotrophic bacteria as a potential regulator of community structure of hypersaline microbial mats. FEMS Microbiol Ecol. 2013;83:74&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oren A. Diversity of halophilic microorganisms: environments, phylogeny, physiology, and applications. J Ind Microbiol Biotechnol. 2002;28:56&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Singh B, van Belkum MJ, Diep DB, Chikindas ML, Ermakov AM, Tiwari SK. Halocins, natural antimicrobials of Archaea: Exotic or special or both? Biotechnol Adv. 2021;53:107834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Sun S, Wang R, Feng H, Xiang H. Halolysin R4 of Haloferax mediterranei confers its host antagonistic and defensive activities. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2021;87:e02889&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corral P, Amoozegar MA, Ventosa A. Halophiles and their biomolecules: recent advances and future applications in biomedicine. Mar Drugs. 2019;18:33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell R, Carmeli S, Sar N. Vibrindole A, a metabolite of the marine bacterium, Vibrio parahaemolyticus, isolated from the toxic mucus of the boxfish Ostracion cubicus. J Nat Prod. 1994;57:1587&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangamuri UK, Vijayalakshmi M, Poda S, Manavathi B, Chitturi B, Yenamandra V. 2016. Isolation and biological evaluation of N-(4-aminocyclooctyl)-3, 5-dinitrobenzamide, a new semisynthetic derivative from the Mangrove-associated actinomycete Pseudonocardia endophytica VUK-10. 3 Biotech 6:158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadj Rabia-Boukhalfa Y, Eveno Y, Karama S, Selama O, Lauga B, Duran R, Hac&#xe8;ne H, Eparvier V. Isolation, purification and chemical characterization of a new angucyclinone compound produced by a new halotolerant Nocardiopsis sp. HR-4 strain. World J Microbiol Biotechnol. 2017;33:126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lach J, Krupi&#x144;ska M, Miko&#x142;ajczyk A, Strapagiel D, St&#x105;czek P, Matera-Witkiewicz A. Novel antimicrobial peptides from saline environments active against E. faecalis and S. aureus: identification, characterisation and potential Usage. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24:11787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atanasova NS, Pietil&#xe4; MK, Oksanen HM. Diverse antimicrobial interactions of halophilic archaea and bacteria extend over geographical distances and cross the domain barrier. MicrobiologyOpen. 2013;2:811&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghanmi F, Carr&#xe9;-Mlouka A, Vandervennet M, Boujelben I, Frikha D, Ayadi H, Peduzzi J, Rebuffat S, Maalej S. Antagonistic interactions and production of halocin antimicrobial peptides among extremely halophilic prokaryotes isolated from the solar saltern of Sfax. Tunisia Extremophiles. 2016;20:363&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui HL, Mou YZ, Yang X, Zhou YG, Liu HC, Zhou PJ. 2012. Halorubellus salinus gen. nov., sp. nov. and Halorubellus litoreus sp. nov., novel halophilic archaea isolated from a marine solar saltern. Syst Appl Microbiol 35:30&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertani G. Studies on lysogenesis. I. The mode of phage liberation by lysogenic Escherichia coli. J Bacteriol. 1951;62:293&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westphal KR, Heidelbach S, Zeuner EJ, Riisgaard-Jensen M, Nielsen ME, Vestergaard SZ, Bekker NS, Skovmark J, Olesen CK, Thomsen KH, Niebling SK, S&#xf8;rensen JL, Sondergaard TE. The effects of different potato dextrose agar media on secondary metabolite production in Fusarium. Int J Food Microbiol. 2021;347:109171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu D, Ke J, Luo Y, Hong T, Sun S, Han J, Chen S. Microbial community structure and shift pattern of industry brine after a long-term static storage in closed tank. Front Microbiol. 2022;13:975271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue Q, Zhao D, Zhang S, Zhou H, Zuo Z, Zhou J, Li M, Xiang H. Highly integrated adaptive mechanisms in Spiribacter halalkaliphilus, a bacterium abundant in Chinese soda-saline lakes. Environ Microbiol. 2021;23:6463&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kharroub K, Quesada T, Ferrer R, Fuentes S, Aguilera M, Boulahrouf A, Ramos-Cormenzana A, Monteoliva-S&#xe1;nchez M. Halorubrum ezzemoulense sp. nov., a halophilic archaeon isolated from Ezzemoul sabkha, Algeria. Int J Syst Evol Microbiol. 2006;56:1583&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirsam H, Suriani, Aqil M, Azrai M, Efendi R, Muliadi A, Sembiring H, Azis AI. Molecular characterization of indigenous microbes and its potential as a biological control agent of Fusarium stem rot disease (Fusarium verticillioides) on maize. Heliyon. 2022;8:e11960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S, Stecher G, Li M, Knyaz C, Tamura K. MEGA X: molecular evolutionary genetics analysis across computing platforms. Mol Biol Evol. 2018;35:1547&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dussault HP. An improved technique for staining red halophilic bacteria. J Bacteriol. 1955;70:484&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonev B, Hooper J, Parisot J. Principles of assessing bacterial susceptibility to antibiotics using the agar diffusion method. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2008;61:1295&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphries R, Bobenchik AM, Hindler JA, Schuetz AN. Overview of changes to the clinical and laboratory standards institute performance standards for antimicrobial susceptibility testing, M100, 31st Edition. J Clin Microbiol. 2021;59:e0021321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu SJ, Kim BS. Biocontrol of fusarium crown and root rot and promotion of growth of tomato by Paenibacillus strains isolated from soil. Mycobiology. 2014;42:158&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagaye BT, Guo J. Optimization of alkali treatment conditions of ramie fabrics using box&#x2013;behnken method. Biopolymers. 2024;115:e23621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Gao K, Wang C, Liu S. A novel antibacterial component and the mechanisms of an Amaranthus tricolor leaf ethyl acetate extract against Acidovorax avenae subsp. citrulli. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;23:312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anumolu PD, Gurrala S, Gellaboina A, Mangipudi DG, Menkana S, Chakka R. Spectrophotometric quantification of anti-inflammatory drugs by application of chromogenic reagents. Turk J Pharm Sci. 2019;16:410&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JC, Yang XQ, Zhou H, Yan YB, Ding ZT. The new analogues of &#x3b2;-trans-bergamotene from endophytic fungus Nigrospora sp. E121 with yam culture medium. Nat Prod Res. 2024;14:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Zhou Y, Chen Y, Gu J. fastp: an ultra-fast all-in-one FASTQ preprocessor. Bioinformatics. 2018;34:i884&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bankevich A, Nurk S, Antipov D, Gurevich AA, Dvorkin M, Kulikov AS, Lesin VM, Nikolenko SI, Pham S, Prjibelski AD, Pyshkin AV, Sirotkin AV, Vyahhi N, Tesler G, Alekseyev MA, Pevzner PA. SPAdes: a new genome assembly algorithm and its applications to single-cell sequencing. J Comput Biol. 2012;19:455&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yepes-Garc&#xed;a J, Falquet L. Metagenome quality metrics and taxonomical annotation visualization through the integration of MAGFlow and BIgMAG. F1000Res. 2024;13:640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habibi N, Mustafa AS, Nasser K, Al-Obaid I, Alfouzan W, Uddin S, Khan MW. Genomic characterization and identification of multiple drug resistance genes in clinical isolates of Acinetobacter baumannii through whole genome sequencing. Mol Biol Rep. 2025;52:233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gross H, Loper JE. Genomics of secondary metabolite production by Pseudomonas spp. Nat Prod Rep. 2009;26:1408&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez A, Vaneechoutte M. Comparison of the efficiency of different cell lysis methods and different commercial methods for RNA extraction from Candida albicans stored in RNAlater. BMC Microbiol. 2019;19:94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D, Paggi JM, Park C, Bennett C, Salzberg SL. Graph-based genome alignment and genotyping with HISAT2 and HISAT-genotype. Nat Biotechnol. 2019;37:907&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao Y, Smyth GK, Shi W. featureCounts: an efficient general purpose program for assigning sequence reads to genomic features. Bioinformatics. 2014;30:923&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanehisa M, Furumichi M, Sato Y, Matsuura Y, Ishiguro-Watanabe M. KEGG: biological systems database as a model of the real world. Nucleic Acids Res. 2025;53:D672&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowak-Thompson B, Chaney N, Wing JS, Gould SJ, Loper JE. Characterization of the pyoluteorin biosynthetic gene cluster of Pseudomonas fluorescens Pf-5. J Bacteriol. 1999;181:2166&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Q, Lopes LD, Shaffer BT, Kidarsa TA, Vining O, Philmus B, Song C, Stockwell VO, Raaijmakers JM, McPhail KL, Andreote FD, Chang JH, Loper JE. 2018. Secondary metabolism and interspecific competition affect accumulation of spontaneous mutants in the GacS-GacA regulatory system in Pseudomonas protegens. mBio 9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei X, Huang X, Tang L, Wu D, Xu Y. Global control of GacA in secondary metabolism, primary metabolism, secretion systems, and motility in the rhizobacterium Pseudomonas aeruginosa M18. J Bacteriol. 2013;195:3387&#x2013;400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza JT, Raaijmakers JM. Polymorphisms within the prnD and pltC genes from pyrrolnitrin and pyoluteorin-producing Pseudomonas and Burkholderia spp. FEMS Microbiol Ecol. 2003;43:21&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Yan B, Yang T, Jiang J, Wei H, Zhu X. Purification and crystallographic analysis of a FAD-dependent halogenase from Streptomyces sp. JCM9888. Acta Crystallogr F Struct Biol Commun. 2015;71:972&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreolli M, Zapparoli G, Angelini E, Lucchetta G, Lampis S, Vallini G. Pseudomonas protegens MP12: A plant growth-promoting endophytic bacterium with broad-spectrum antifungal activity against grapevine phytopathogens. Microbiol Res. 2019;219:123&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zameer M, Shahid I, Saleem RS, Baig DN, Zareen M, Malik KA, Mehnaz S. Assessment of anticancer and antimicrobial potential of bioactive metabolites and optimization of culture conditions of Pseudomonas aurantiaca PB-St2 for high yields. J Microbiol Biotechnol. 2025;35:e2311041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y, Ke J, Hong T, Zhang A, Wu X, Jiang X, Shao S, Gong M, Zhao S, Shen L, Chen S. Microbial diversity and ecological roles of halophilic microorganisms in Dingbian (Shaanxi, China) saline-alkali soils and salt lakes. BMC Microbiol. 2025;25:287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi X, Gao G, Tian J, Wang XC, Jin X, Jin P. Symbiosis of sulfate-reducing bacteria and methanogenic archaea in sewer systems. Environ Int. 2020;143:105923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Igarashi K, Liu L, Mayumi D, Ujiie T, Fu L, Yang M, Lu Y, Cheng L, Kato S, Nobu MK. Methanol transfer supports metabolic syntrophy between bacteria and archaea. Nature. 2025;639:190&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Y, Yannarell AC, Mackie RI. Changes in N-transforming archaea and bacteria in soil during the establishment of bioenergy crops. PLoS ONE. 2011;6:e24750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson SB, Bertolli SK, Mougous JD. The central role of interbacterial antagonism in bacterial life. Curr Biol. 2020;30:R1203&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghrairi T, Braiek OB, Hani K. Detection and characterization of a bacteriocin, putadicin T01, produced by Pseudomonas putida isolated from hot spring water. Apmis. 2015;123:260&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Z, Zhang X, Shi L, Jin J, Yang B, Xing F. Functional characterization and mechanism of two zearalenone-degrading enzymes from Bacillus velezensis B.26. J Agric Food Chem. 2025;73:14629&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fee CJ, Van Alstine JM. Purification of pegylated proteins. Methods Biochem Anal. 2011;54:339&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duong-Ly KC, Gabelli SB. Salting out of proteins using ammonium sulfate precipitation. Methods Enzymol. 2014;541:85&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang N, Song F. Bioprospecting of novel and bioactive compounds from marine actinomycetes isolated from south china sea sediments. Curr Microbiol. 2018;75:142&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddharth S, Rai VR. Isolation and characterization of bioactive compounds with antibacterial, antioxidant and enzyme inhibitory activities from marine-derived rare actinobacteria, Nocardiopsis sp. SCA21. Microb Pathog. 2019;137:103775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaremko MJ, Lee DJ, Opella SJ, Burkart MD. Structure and substrate sequestration in the pyoluteorin type II peptidyl carrier protein PltL. J Am Chem Soc. 2015;137:11546&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X, Yan A, Zhang X, Xu Y. Identification and characterization of a putative ABC transporter PltHIJKN required for pyoluteorin production in Pseudomonas sp. M18. Gene. 2006;376:68&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan A, Wang X, Zhang X, Xu Y. LysR family factor PltR positively regulates Pyoluteorin production in a pathway-specific manner in Pseudomonas sp. M18. Sci China C Life Sci. 2007;50:518&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boniolo FS, Rodrigues RC, Delatorre EO, da Silveira MM, Flores VM, Berbert-Molina MA. Glycine betaine enhances growth of nitrogen-fixing bacteria Gluconacetobacter diazotrophicus PAL5 under saline stress conditions. Curr Microbiol. 2009;59:593&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang N, Ding R, Liu J. Synthesizing glycine betaine via choline oxidation pathway as an osmoprotectant strategy in Haloferacales. Gene. 2022;847:146886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunde-Cimerman N, Plemenita&#x161; A, Oren A. Strategies of adaptation of microorganisms of the three domains of life to high salt concentrations. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2018;42:353&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Zhang C, Wu Q, Wang M, Zhou Y, Wang D, Zhou L. Deciphering nitrogen removal performance concerning heterotrophic microorganism&#x2019;s succession by using three typical acid-rich fermentation liquids of food waste as carbon sources in high ammonium and high salt wastewater treatment. Environ Res. 2025;268:120763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin Y, Zhang Z, Yang K, Gu P, Liu S, Jia Y, Zhang Z, Wang T, Yin J, Miao H. Deeper insight into the effect of salinity on the relationship of enzymatic activity, microbial community and key metabolic pathway during the anaerobic digestion of high strength organic wastewater. Bioresour Technol. 2022;363:127978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding T, Yang LJ, Zhang WD, Shen YH. Pyoluteorin induces cell cycle arrest and apoptosis in human triple-negative breast cancer cells MDA-MB-231. J Pharm Pharmacol. 2020;72:969&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>