<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41764495</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1477-3155</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of nanobiotechnology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Nanobiotechnology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>3D printed HAMA/GelMA/lignosulfonate hydrogel integrating oxygen-releasing and antioxidative modules for liver regeneration.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12951-026-04197-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A multifunctional polysaccharide-based hydrogel was developed for liver regeneration by integrating sodium alginate (SA), sodium lignosulfonate (SL), and 3D bioprinting technology. The hydrogel incorporated FH1@SA microspheres and CaO<sub>2</sub>@ZIF-8@SL nanoparticles to reconstruct the hepatic microenvironment through coordinated oxygen generation, antioxidant activity, and anti-inflammatory modulation. The FH1@SA microspheres enabled sustained release of FH1, facilitating hepatocyte adaptation to hypoxia and promoting functional recovery. Meanwhile, the CaO<sub>2</sub>@ZIF-8@SL nanoparticles achieved controlled oxygen release and pH-responsive degradation, while the lignosulfonate component scavenged reactive oxygen species and mitigated inflammatory stress. The 3D-printed hydrogel exhibited favorable mechanical strength, injectability, and cytocompatibility, effectively supporting hepatocyte proliferation and tissue regeneration. By simultaneously relieving hypoxia and oxidative stress, this polysaccharide hydrogel provides a synergistic strategy for enhancing hepatic repair, offering a promising platform for bioartificial liver construction and treatment of liver injury.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Sang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Sciences, General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, Ningxia, China. NXLS87@nyfy.com.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Basic Medical Science, Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, Ningxia, China. NXLS87@nyfy.com.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ningxia Key Laboratory of Prevention and Control of Common Infectious Diseases, Yinchuan, Ningxia, China. NXLS87@nyfy.com.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>, No. 804 Shengli South Street, Xingqing District, Yinchuan, 75004, Ningxia, China. NXLS87@nyfy.com.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Longbao</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Biomaterials of Guangdong Higher Education Institutes, Key Laboratory of Regenerative Medicine of Ministry of Education, Guangdong Provincial Engineering and Technological Research Centre for Drug Carrier Development, Department of Biomedical Engineering, Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Bingren</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Sciences, General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, Ningxia, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Fang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ningxia Regional Key Laboratory of Integrated Traditional Chinese and Western Medicine for Prevention and Treatment of Regional High Incidence Disease, Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, Ningxia, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Wenjun</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ningxia Medical 3D Printing Engineering Technology Research Center, General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Shuai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of life sciences and health, Hubei University of Technology, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaojun</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, Ningxia, China. yxjicu@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>, No. 804 Shengli South Street, Xingqing District, Yinchuan, 75004, Ningxia, China. yxjicu@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024SF045</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Support Project of Yinchuan City</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Nanobiotechnology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101152208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1477-3155</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrogel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Liver regeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen release</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sodium alginate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sodium lignosulfonate</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval: This study was reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of the General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University. The approved project, titled &#x201c;Application of Human Mesenchymal Stem Cell 3D Bioprinted Organoids with Slow-Release FH1 in Liver Injury Repair,&#x201d; was granted ethical clearance. The approval number for this project is KYLL-2023-0157, and the date of approval is November 7, 2023. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41764495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12951-026-04197-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12951-026-04197-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhou R, et al. Prevention of hepatic ischemia-reperfusion injury by reactive oxygen species-responsive nanozymes. J Control Release. 2025;385:114057. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jconrel.2025.114057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, et al. Nanotuner targeting mitochondrial redox and iron homeostasis imbalance for the treatment of acute liver injury. Theranostics. 2025;15:9131&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.7150/thno.119357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni HM, Lopez-Pascual A. Eosinophils: a novel therapeutic target to promote liver regeneration in acute liver injury? Gut. 2024;73:1409&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.1136/gutjnl-2024-332692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, et al. A defend&#x2013;attack and capture flag strategy for cascade management of hepatic ischemia reperfusion injury. Chem Eng J. 2024;487. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Yao H, Xia J, Wan X, Wu J. Chitosan-based Immunomodulatory bioadhesive hydrogel promotes liver hemostasis and repair. Carbohydr Polym. 2025;353:123268. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbpol.2025.123268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosrowshahi ND, Amini H, Khoshfetrat AB, Rahbarghazi R. Oxidized pectin/collagen self-healing hydrogel accelerated the regeneration of acute hepatic injury in a mouse model. Int J Biol Macromol. 2025;304:140931. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.140931.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Shen K, Chu D, Cheng Y. Tempo-Functionalized Janus hydrogel crosslinked by tandem dynamic covalent bonds for internal organ injury repair and deep Second-Degree burn wound healing. Adv Funct Mater. 2025;35:2505194. https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202505194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang D, et al. Target-Engineered liposomes decorated with nanozymes alleviate liver fibrosis by remodeling the liver microenvironment. ACS Appl Mater Interfaces. 2024;16:64536&#x2013;53. https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin X, et al. Hydrogels and hydrogel-based drug delivery systems for promoting refractory wound healing: applications and prospects. Int J Biol Macromol. 2025;285:138098. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.138098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Li Y, Ma Z, He D, Li H. Modulating degradation of sodium alginate/bioglass hydrogel for improving tissue infiltration and promoting wound healing. Bioact Mater. 2021;6:3692&#x2013;704. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bioactmat.2021.03.038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao J, Wu B, Yuan P, Liu Y, Hu C. Research progress of sodium Alginate-Based hydrogels in biomedical engineering. Gels. 2025;11. https://doi.org/10.3390/gels11090758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang S, et al. Construction of physically crosslinked chitosan/sodium alginate/calcium ion double-network hydrogel and its application to heavy metal ions removal. Chem Eng J. 2020;393. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2020.124728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, et al. Calcium ion cross-linked sodium alginate hydrogels containing deferoxamine and copper nanoparticles for diabetic wound healing. Int J Biol Macromol. 2022;202:657&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2022.01.080.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Horani RA, Aliter KF. Triple action of lignosulfonic acid sodium: Anti-protease, Antioxidant, and Anti-inflammatory effects of a polymeric heparin mimetic. Med Chem. 2024;20:414&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.2174/0115734064275120231222111145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balaji S, et al. Injectable antioxidant and Oxygen-Releasing lignin composites to promote wound healing. ACS Appl Mater Interfaces. 2023;15:18639&#x2013;52. https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.2c22982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhang Z, Qin Z, Sillanp&#xe4;&#xe4; M. Prevention of dextran sulfate sodium-induced acute enteritis by zinc nanoparticles green-formulated by sodium lignosulfonate. Inorg Chem Commun. 2024;168. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo S, Ai Y, Xiao S, Wang B, Wang Y. Functional hit 1 (FH1)-based rapid and efficient generation of functional hepatocytes from human mesenchymal stem cells: a novel strategy for hepatic differentiation. Ann Transl Med. 2021;9:1087. https://doi.org/10.21037/atm-21-2829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan J, et al. Identification of small molecules for human hepatocyte expansion and iPS differentiation. Nat Chem Biol. 2013;9:514&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1038/nchembio.1270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng A, et al. Microsphere strategy to generate conformal bone organoid units with osteoimmunomodulation and sustainable oxygen supply for bone regeneration. Adv Sci (Weinh). 2025;12:e01437. https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202501437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anavi S, Madar Z, Tirosh O. Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease, to struggle with the strangle: oxygen availability in fatty livers. Redox Biol. 2017;13:386&#x2013;92. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.redox.2017.06.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahmani Z, Shakeri A, Razavi SR, Salehi H, Bonsale R, Lignosulfonate-Coated. ZIF-8 as an effective nanofiller to prepare High-Performance Thin-Film nanocomposite forward osmosis membrane for heavy metal ions removal. ACS ES&amp;T Water. 2024;4:1460&#x2013;71. https://doi.org/10.1021/acsestwater.3c00608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimo R, et al. Bletilla striata polysaccharide microneedles with Astragaloside &#x2163; loaded ZIF-8 nanoparticles for wound healing and anti-scar treatment. J Nanobiotechnol. 2025;23:644. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12951-025-03736-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shit A, et al. Stimuli-responsive pressure-strain sensor-based conductive hydrogel for alleviated non-alcoholic fatty liver disease by scavenging reactive oxygen species in adipose tissue. Acta Biomater. 2023;171:406&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actbio.2023.09.030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, et al. Fabricating oxygen self-supplying 3D printed bioactive hydrogel scaffold for augmented vascularized bone regeneration. Bioact Mater. 2024;40:227&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bioactmat.2024.06.016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Z, et al. Bioengineered multifunctional hydrogel integrating oxygen sustention, oxidative stress alleviation and pro-angiogenic cues for regenerative MI therapy. Chem Eng J. 2025;520. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.165859.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J, et al. Fabricating active egg Albumin/Sodium Alginate/Sodium lignosulfonate nanoparticles film with significantly improved multifunctional characteristics for food packing. Int J Biol Macromol. 2024;273:133110. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.133110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong B, et al. Fiber reinforced GelMA hydrogel to induce the regeneration of corneal stroma. Nat Commun. 2020;11:1435. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-14887-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ai Y, et al. Photo-crosslinked bioactive BG/BMSCs@GelMA hydrogels for bone-defect repairs. Mater Today Bio. 2023;23:100882. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtbio.2023.100882.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, et al. HAMA-SBMA hydrogel with anti-inflammatory properties delivers cartilage organoids, boosting cartilage regeneration. J Nanobiotechnol. 2025;23:401. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12951-025-03475-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu XJ, et al. A novel spherical GelMA-HAMA hydrogel encapsulating APET&#xd7;2 polypeptide and CFIm25-targeting SgRNA for immune microenvironment modulation and nucleus pulposus regeneration in intervertebral discs. J Nanobiotechnol. 2024;22:556. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12951-024-02783-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Zhao C, Xu J, Sun D. Enhanced Ca2&#x2009;+&#x2009;binding with sulfonic acid type polymers at increased temperatures. Colloids Surf A. 2013;417:256&#x2013;63. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2012.09.030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, et al. The injectable cationic double-crosslinked hydrogel facilitates bone regeneration and repair through sustained antibacterial activity. Mater Today Bio. 2025;35:102461. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtbio.2025.102461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo S, Ai Y, Xiao S, Wang B, Wang Y. Functional hit 1 (FH1)-based rapid and efficient generation of functional hepatocytes from human mesenchymal stem cells: a novel strategy for hepatic differentiation. Ann Transl Med. 2021;9:1087. https://doi.org/10.21037/atm-21-2829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo S, Wu F, Jin Y, Liu D. The potential hepatocyte differentiation targets and MSC proliferation by FH1. J Cell Mol Med. 2025;29:e70601. https://doi.org/10.1111/jcmm.70601.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>