<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41710078</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2753-4294</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMJ public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMJ Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Our stories matter: a mixed methods survey of lived and living experience perspectives of media and public communication of suicide in Australia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e004225</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e004225</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e004225</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1136/bmjph-2025-004225</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Suicide is a major global public health issue, yet the voices of people who have a lived and living experience of suicide are often left out of public discussion about suicide. Media plays a critical role in shaping perception and community discourse, with much of the current work to develop media guidelines focused on reducing suicide risk. Despite the known benefits of sharing lived and living experience stories of hope, recovery and coping with suicidality (the Papageno effect), guidelines on safe and effective storytelling remain limited. This study aimed to (1) understand how people with lived and living experience of suicide engage with and perceive media representations of suicide; (2) identify essential considerations for safe storytelling; and (3) understand best practices for media and communication professionals supporting lived or living experience storytellers. To meet these aims, people with lived and living experience were included across all aspects of the project, including as authors on this paper.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A mixed method survey (with both quantitative and qualitative components) of people with a lived and living experience of suicide was distributed in Australia using a purposive, non-probability convenience sampling method. Participants answered questions about developing guidelines for safely sharing personal stories of suicide by drawing on their experiences of engaging in content relating to suicide on news media and other public communication platforms (part 1 of survey). In addition, participants who had direct experience sharing their story publicly were asked additional questions (part 2 of survey).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 309 participants engaged with part 1 of the survey, with 125 continuing to complete part 2. Findings indicated significant gaps in mainstream media representation, with 75% identifying that their lived experience is not represented in the media, with only bereaved participants reporting representation. Further, 79% believe media does not recognise diversity in experiences of suicide. Results from part 2 participants indicated key considerations for storytelling included: before sharing, having clarity on purpose (81.3%), differentiating meaningful from tokenistic opportunities (80.5%) and self-care planning (77.1%); during sharing, careful language use (81.2%) and consent when involving others' experiences (81.2%); and after sharing, preparation for distress contacts (82.4%) and boundary maintenance (74.8%). Notably, 40.9% of participants experienced burnout from public storytelling, with boundary-setting, adequate rest and organisational support identified as essential protective factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The results suggest opportunities for media to increase and diversify public narratives of suicide to include stories of hope and survival, in addition to existing narratives of bereavement. They also suggest essential supports for storytellers must include improved protocols for preventing burnout. These findings informed the development of Australia's first comprehensive guidelines for sharing personal experiences of suicide safely, and guidance for media and public communication professionals supporting advocates and lived and living experience spokespeople (Our stories matter, 2024). This addresses a critical gap in suicide prevention practice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Author(s) (or their employer(s)) 2026. Re-use permitted under CC BY-NC. Published by BMJ Group.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pryse Jones</LastName><ForeName>Emma</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Everymind, Newcastle, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paton</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4649-4862</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Everymind, Newcastle, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Human and Social Futures, The University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barrow</LastName><ForeName>Megan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Everymind Lived Experience Advisory Group, Everymind, Newcastle, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eddy</LastName><ForeName>Jon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Everymind Lived Experience Advisory Group, Everymind, Newcastle, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peprah</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Everymind, Newcastle, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cuenca</LastName><ForeName>Jose</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Everymind, Newcastle, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Skehan</LastName><ForeName>Jaelea</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Everymind, Newcastle, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Health, Medicine and Wellbeing, The University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMJ Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918697578906676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2753-4294</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mental Health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Public Health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The Mindframe programme is funded by the Australian Government Department of Health, Disability and Ageing through the National Suicide Prevention Leadership and Support Program. At the time of research, authors EPJ, EP, JC, JP and JS were employed by Everymind, which administers the Mindframe programme, and authors MB and JE were members of the Everymind Lived Experience Advisory Group and remunerated by Everymind for their time working on the project. JE was employed by lived experience organisation Roses in the Ocean and held a paid position on Standby Support After Suicide&#x2019;s Lived Experience Advisory Group. JS held unpaid roles on the Movember Global Men&#x2019;s Health Advisory Committee and the Australian Institute of Health and Welfare&#x2019;s Expert Advisory Group for the National Suicide and Self-harm Monitoring System. EP held unpaid roles on LGBTIQ+ Health Australia&#x2019;s MindOut Sector Expert Advisory Group and the Australian Institute of Health and Welfare&#x2019;s National Suicide &amp; Self-harm Monitoring System User Experience Group.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41710078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12911772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjph-2025-004225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">bmjph-2025-004225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . Suicide Worldwide In 2019: Global Health Estimates. 1st. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2021. p. 1. edn.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Association of Suicide Prevention  Lived experience of suicide. https://www.iasp.info/wp-content/uploads/Lived-Experience-Outreach-Brief-WSPD.pdf n.d. Available.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirkis J, Dandona R, Silverman M, et al. Preventing suicide: a public health approach to a global problem. Lancet Public Health. 2024;9:e787&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1016/S2468-2667(24)00149-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-2667(24)00149-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39265611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niederkrotenthaler T, Braun M, Pirkis J, et al. Association between suicide reporting in the media and suicide: systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ. 2020;368:m575. doi: 10.1136/bmj.m575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7190013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32188637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips DP. The influence of suggestion on suicide: substantive and theoretical implications of the Werther effect. Am Sociol Rev. 1974;39:340&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11630757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley LL, Niederkrotenthaler T, Zaheer R, et al. Is the narrative the message? The relationship between suicide-related narratives in media reports and subsequent suicides. Aust N Z J Psychiatry. 2023;57:758&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1177/00048674221117072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00048674221117072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10126449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35999688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niederkrotenthaler T. A suicide-protective Papageno effect of media portrayals of coping with suicidality. Inj Prev. 2016;22:A8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niederkrotenthaler T, Voracek M, Herberth A, et al. Role of media reports in completed and prevented suicide: Werther v. Papageno effects. Br J Psychiatry . 2010;197:234&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1192/bjp.bp.109.074633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.109.074633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20807970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niederkrotenthaler T, Till B, Kirchner S, et al. Effects of media stories of hope and recovery on suicidal ideation and help-seeking attitudes and intentions: systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Public Health. 2022;7:e156&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1016/S2468-2667(21)00274-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-2667(21)00274-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35122759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arendt F, Till B, Gutsch A, et al. Social media influencers and the Papageno effect: Experimental evidence for the suicide-preventive impact of social media posts on hope, healing, and recovery. Social Science &amp; Medicine . 2025;370:117852. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2025.117852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2025.117852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40010233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everymind . Newcastle, Australia: 2020. Reporting suicide and mental ill-health: a mindframe resource for media professionals.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samaritans  Media guidelines for reporting suicide. 2020. https://www.samaritans.org/about-samaritans/media-guidelines/media-guidelines-reporting-suicide/ Available.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation  . Geneva: World Health Organisation; 2023. Preventing suicide: a resource for media professionals.https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240076846 Available.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skehan J, Paton E, Tynan R. The uptake of evidence-informed guidelines for reporting suicide into media codes of practice and policies in Australia. Health Promot J Austr . 2020;31:482&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1002/hpja.316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hpja.316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31846517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maple M, Wayland S, Kendall S, et al. A Report for the National Suicide Prevention Advisor and Suicide Prevention Taskforce. University of New England; 2020. They can only talk themselves out of it if they&#x2019;re talking.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canberra: Australian Government Department of Health and Aged Care; 2020. National Suicide Prevention Taskforce. Compassion first: designing our national approach from the lived experience of suicidal behaviour.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan S, Newton J. How Do You Feel?: Preparing novice reporters for the death knock. Journalism Practice. 2010;4:439&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson A. Devising an ethical &#x2018;death knock&#x2019; model: the role of preparations, precursors, and professional identity in mitigating moral injury for journalists. Communication Research and Practice. 2024;0:1&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skehan J, Maple M, Fisher J, et al. Suicide bereavement and the media: A qualitative study. Advances in Mental Health . 2013;11:223&#x2013;37. doi: 10.5172/jamh.2013.11.3.223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5172/jamh.2013.11.3.223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapple A, Ziebland S, Simkin S, et al. How people bereaved by suicide perceive newspaper reporting: qualitative study. Br J Psychiatry. 2013;203:228&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1192/bjp.bp.112.114116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.112.114116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23391729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory P, Stevenson F, King M, et al. The experiences of people bereaved by suicide regarding the press reporting of the death: qualitative study. BMC Public Health. 2020;20:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1186/s12889-020-8211-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-020-8211-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7031901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32075618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skehan J, Tynan R, Thienel R, et al. What factors influence Australian media professionals&#x2019; level of agreement with guidelines for reporting suicide? Media International Australia . 2025 doi: 10.1177/1329878X241309369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1329878X241309369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirchner S, Niederkrotenthaler T. Experiences of suicide survivors of sharing their stories about suicidality and overcoming a crisis in media and public talks: a qualitative study. BMC Public Health. 2024;24:142. doi: 10.1186/s12889-024-17661-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-024-17661-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10777649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38200460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson J, Hill NTM, Thorn P, et al. The #chatsafe project. Developing guidelines to help young people communicate safely about suicide on social media: A Delphi study. PLoS One. 2018;13:e0206584. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0206584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0206584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6237326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30439958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V, Boulton E, et al. The online survey as a qualitative research tool. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2021;24:641&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter A, Brewer JD. In: The Oxford Handbook of Multimethod and Mixed Methods Research Inquiry. Hesse-Biber SN, Johnson RB, editors. Oxford University Press; 2015. Designing multimethod research. Available.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/oxfordhb/9780199933624.013.13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley K, Clark B, Brown V, et al. Good practice in the conduct and reporting of survey research. Int J Qual Health Care. 2003;15:261&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1093/intqhc/mzg031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intqhc/mzg031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12803354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual Res Psychol. 2006;3:77&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1191/1478088706qp063oa.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krysinska K, Ozols I, Ross A, et al. Active involvement of people with lived experience of suicide in suicide research: a Delphi consensus study. BMC Psychiatry. 2023;23:496. doi: 10.1186/s12888-023-04973-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-023-04973-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10334649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37434145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell S, Greenwood M, Prior S, et al. Purposive sampling: complex or simple. Research Case Examples J Res Nurs. 2020;25:652&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1177/1744987120927206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1744987120927206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7932468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34394687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>