<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41668042</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2393</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC pregnancy and childbirth</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of information and progressive relaxation exercises before the planned cesarean section on primigravida women's surgical fear, anxiety, pain and postpartum comfort: a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">288</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12884-026-08753-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Elective cesarean section rates continue to rise worldwide, and women frequently experience preoperative fear and anxiety, which negatively affect perioperative outcomes, pain perception, and postpartum recovery. Non-pharmacological interventions such as relaxation exercises are increasingly encouraged to support maternal well-being and improve surgical outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM">The purpose of this study is to determine the effect of Jacobson&#x2019;s progressive relaxation exercise on primigravida women&#x2019;s surgical fear, anxiety, postpartum comfort, and pain levels.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD">This two-group parallel randomized controlled study was conducted with a total of 68 primigravida women, 34 in the experimental and control groups. Women in the experimental group were given information and two sessions of progressive relaxation exercise before cesarean surgery. The control group received routine institutional care. The State Anxiety Scale, Surgical Fear Scale, Visual Analog Scale (VAS), and Postpartum Comfort Scale were used in data collection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Women in the experimental group showed a significant reduction in preoperative state anxiety scores after the intervention (from 44.32&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.78 to 31.02&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.33), whereas anxiety scores increased in the control group (from 43.97&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.40 to 48.38&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;3.10), with a significant between-group difference (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001; Cohen&#x2019;s d&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.62). Similarly, total surgical fear scores decreased significantly in the experimental group (54.82&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;3.64) compared with the control group (76.76&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;3.65) after the intervention (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001; Cohen&#x2019;s d&#x2009;=&#x2009;6.02). Postoperative pain scores measured by the VAS were lower in the experimental group than in the control group (6.08&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.62 vs. 6.55&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.61; <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002). In addition, postpartum comfort scores were significantly higher in the experimental group compared with the control group (4.07&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.36 vs. 3.12&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.19; <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">It was determined that information and progressive relaxation exercise applications applied before cesarean surgery reduced preoperative fear and anxiety, reduced postoperative pain and increased postpartum comfort.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">ClinicalTrials.gov NCT06708585. Registered retrospectively on 24 November 2024.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yes&#x131;ldag</LastName><ForeName>B&#x131;rnur</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4239-1295</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Faculty of Health Sciences, Nigde Omer Halisdemir University Zubeyde Hanim, N&#x130;&#x11e;DE, Turkey. nurumbirnur@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology Nursing, Z&#xfc;beyde Hanim Faculty of Health Sciences, Ni&#x11f;de &#xd6;mer Halisdemir University, Ni&#x11f;de, 51240, Turkey. nurumbirnur@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Golbas&#x131;</LastName><ForeName>Zehra</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0410-7433</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lokman Hekim University Faculty of Health Sciences, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Temur</LastName><ForeName>Isa</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5342-8113</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nigde Omer Halisdemir University Training and Research Hospital, Nigde, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967799</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2393</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Comfort</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fear</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primigravida</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Relaxation therapy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Before the study was started, ethical approval was obtained from the Ethics Committee of Nigde Omer Halisdemir University on 15 July 2024 (Approval No: 2024/15-03), and permission was obtained from the hospital where the study was conducted. The study was carried out in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Prior to data collection, all participants were informed about the study, and written and verbal informed consent was obtained from women who voluntarily agreed to participate. The study is registered with Clinical Trials Number NCT06708585 Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41668042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12998347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-026-08753-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12884-026-08753-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abarghoee SN, Mardani A, Baha R, Aghdam NF, Khajeh M, Eskandari F, et al. Effects of Benson relaxation technique and music therapy on the anxiety of primiparous women prior to Cesarean section: a randomized controlled trial. Anesthesiol Res Pract. 2022;2022:9986587. 10.1155/2022/9986587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/9986587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9803568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36589598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dibabu AM, Ketema TG, Beyene MM, Belachew DZ, Abocherugn HG, Mohammed AS. Preoperative anxiety and associated factors among women admitted for elective obstetric and gynecologic surgery in public hospitals, Southern ethiopia: a cross-sectional study. BMC Psychiatry. 2023;23:728. 10.1186/s12888-023-05005-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-023-05005-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10561508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37807071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferede YA, Bizuneh YB, Mulu M, Admass BA. Prevalence and associated factors of preoperative anxiety among obstetric patients who underwent Cesarean section: a cross-sectional study. Ann Med Surg (Lond). 2022;74:103272. 10.1016/j.amsu.2022.103272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amsu.2022.103272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8844776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35198163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Caesarean section rates continue to rise, amid growing inequalities in access. Geneva: World Health Organization. 2021. https://www.who.int/news/item/16-06-2021-caesarean-section-rates-continue-to-rise-amid-growing-inequalities-in-access. Accessed 10 Feb 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samadi S. The effect of preoperative education on preoperative anxiety in patients waiting for surgery: a literature review. J Health Rep Technol. 2024;10(1):e144503. 10.5812/jhrt-144503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/jhrt-144503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaala NK, Hepp P, Heil M, Wolfe OT, Hagenbeck C, Fleisch M, et al. Perioperative anxiety and length of hospital stay after caesarean section: a cohort study. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2020;248:252&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejogrb.2020.03.045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32283431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noben L, Goossens SMTA, Truijens SEM, van Berckel MMG, Perquin CW, Slooter GD, et al. A virtual reality video to improve information provision and reduce anxiety before Cesarean delivery: randomized controlled trial. JMIR Ment Health. 2019;6(12):e15872. 10.2196/15872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/15872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6939281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31850850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agbayani CG, Fortier MA, Kain ZN. Non-pharmacological methods of reducing perioperative anxiety in children. BJA Educ. 2020;20(12):424&#x2013;30. 10.1016/j.bjae.2020.08.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bjae.2020.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7807851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33456927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R, Huang X, Wang Y, Akbari M. Non-pharmacologic approaches in preoperative anxiety: a comprehensive review. Front Public Health. 2022;10:854673. 10.3389/fpubh.2022.854673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2022.854673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9035831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35480569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamady S, Abd Elmoniem S, Araby O, Elrefaeys S, Nageeb S. Effect of Benson relaxation technique on reducing pain and stress among post-cesarean section mothers. J Posit Sch Psychol. 2022;6(8):6820&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vagnoli L, Bettini A, Amore E, De Masi S, Messeri A. Relaxation-guided imagery reduces perioperative anxiety and pain in children: a randomized study. Eur J Pediatr. 2019;178:913&#x2013;21. 10.1007/s00431-019-03376-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00431-019-03376-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30944985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim H, Elgzar W, Hablas R. The effect of jacobson&#x2019;s progressive relaxation technique on postoperative pain, activity tolerance, and sleep quality in patients undergoing gynecological surgery. Iran J Nurs Midwifery Res. 2021;26:295&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijnmr.IJNMR_180_20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8344632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34422608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob S, Sharma S. Efficacy of progressive muscular relaxation on coping strategies and management of stress, anxiety and depression. Int J Indian Psychol. 2018;6:106&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Chen Y, Wu D, Lin R, Wang Z, Pan L. Effects of progressive muscle relaxation on anxiety and sleep quality in patients with COVID-19. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2020;39:101&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctcp.2020.101132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bushra M, Ajaz AK. Jacobson muscle relaxation technique (JPMR). JOJ Nurse Health Care. 2018;8(1):55726. 10.19080/JOJNHC.2018.08.555726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19080/JOJNHC.2018.08.555726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;ner N, Le Compte A. State-Trait anxiety inventory handbook. 1st ed. Istanbul: Bo&#x11f;azi&#xe7;i University; 1983. pp. 1&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba&#x11f;digen M, &#xd6;zl&#xfc; ZK. Validation of the Turkish version of the surgical fear questionnaire. J Perianesth Nurs. 2016;33(5):708&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jopan.2017.05.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30236578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;rkan A, Aldemir K, G&#xfc;l A. Comparison of four different pain scales in the evaluation of postoperative acute pain intensity. Cukurova Med J. 2020;45(4):1562&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17826/cumj.741465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karakaplan S, Y&#x131;ld&#x131;z H. Postpartum comfort scale development study. Maltepe Univ J Nurs Sci Art. 2010;3(1):55&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prastini MS, Herawati L, Frety EE, Aditiawarman A. The effect of progressive muscle relaxation and slow deep breathing combinations on sleep quality of pregnant women. Hal Olahraga Nusant J Ilmu Keolahragaan. 2022;5(1):158&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31851/hon.v5i1.6919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajeswari R, Sanjeeva Reddy S. Efficacy of progressive muscle relaxation on pregnancy outcome among anxious Indian primi mothers. Iran J Nurs Midwifery Res. 2020;25(1):23&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijnmr.IJNMR_207_18</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6952921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31956594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harichandana S, Philip TA. Effectiveness of Benson relaxation therapy on prenatal anxiety among mothers in a tertiary care hospital, Kochi. Int J Reprod Contracept Obstet Gynecol. 2023;12(10):3149&#x2013;53. 10.18203/2320-1770.ijrcog20232963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18203/2320-1770.ijrcog20232963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaghloul M, Hassan S, Saraya O, Abd Elmasieh H, Ali H. Effect of Benson relaxation technique on pain intensity, anxiety level and sleep quality among post-cesarean women. Egypt J Health Care. 2022;13(3):1002&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/ejhc.2022.256112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ElShora SNAE, Elsayed HEM, El-Feshawy NI, Hassen HAEAE. The effect of benson&#x2019;s relaxation therapy on pre-cesarean section fear and anxiety among nulliparous women. Assiut Sci Nurs J. 2024;12(41):75&#x2013;83. 10.21608/asnj.2024.259888.1746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/asnj.2024.259888.1746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim SS, Nasr Allah TMAA, Mohamed MRA, Badr RMM. Effectiveness of applying jacobson&#x2019;s progressive relaxation technique on post-cesarean section pain and sleep quality. Port Said Sci J Nurs. 2023;10(2):29&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rady SE, El-Deeb HAE. Effect of progressive muscle relaxation technique on postoperative pain and quality of recovery among patients with abdominal surgeries. Egypt J Health Care. 2020;11(4):566&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/ejhc.2020.152563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brezeanu D, Brezeanu A, Chiril&#x103; SI, Tica V. The role of lactic acid in episiotomy wound healing: A systematic review. Healthc (Basel). 2025;13(8):956. 10.3390/healthcare13080956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare13080956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12026564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40281905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brezeanu D, Brezeanu AM, Chirila SI, Tica V. A preliminary study of intravaginal lactic acid gel (Canesbalance<sup>&#xae;</sup>) for Post-Episiotomy healing: A randomized clinical trial. Healthc (Basel). 2025;13(13):1581. 10.3390/healthcare13131581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare13131581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12249008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40648604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brezeanu AM, Brezeanu D, Tica VI. Intraoperative Platelet-Rich plasma (PRP) for Post-Cesarean Scar healing: A Single-Center randomized controlled pilot study. Healthc (Basel). 2025;15(22):2928. 10.3390/healthcare13222928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare13222928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12652183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41302316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>