<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41793277</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2042-3306</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Equine veterinary journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Equine Vet J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Transcriptomic signatures reveal systemic adaptations and immune modulation in response to training and competitive racing in horses.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/evj.70154</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The molecular mechanisms underlying adaptation to physical exertion and racing stress in horses remain incompletely understood. Peripheral blood transcriptomics offers a minimally invasive method to monitor systemic responses to exercise and identify biomarkers of adaptation or overload.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate transcriptomic changes in peripheral blood of racehorses during different phases of training and competition and to identify molecular markers of physiological adaptation and race-induced stress.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Prospective transcriptomic profiling of trained racehorses across three exercise conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Forty racehorses (29 Arabian, 11 Thoroughbred) were sampled before (p0) and after (p1) exercise at three stages: initial training (T1), mid-season training (T2) and racing (R). RNA-seq was performed, followed by differential expression analysis (DESeq2) and pathway enrichment (g:Profiler, DAVID). Identified differentially expressed genes were integrated into STRING protein-protein interaction condition-exclusive subnetworks (Merge tool in Cytoscape) to compare the transcriptomes between conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Distinct molecular programmes were identified at each stage. At T1, immediate-early response genes such as FOS, FOSB and HSPA6 were strongly up-regulated, reflecting acute stress and immune activation. At T2, immune-related transcripts (KLRD1, CCL4, PRF1) remained enriched, but genes linked to remodelling and adaptation, including DNAJA1, HSPH1 and CXCR4, became prominent, suggesting a shift toward recovery and regulatory processes. Post-race, chemokines such as CCL5 and stress markers (HSP90 family, JUN) were highly induced, accompanied by widespread transcriptomic divergence and down-regulation of certain immune regulators (IL18, ARHGAP44), indicating both heightened innate activation and transient immune suppression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN LIMITATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Transcriptomic profiling was limited to peripheral blood, which may not reflect tissue-specific responses. Only three sampling points were included, potentially overlooking transient transcriptomic changes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Transcriptomic dynamics in blood reflect the transition from early immune activation (T1), through adaptation (T2), to stress-related activation post-race (R). This approach offers promising molecular biomarkers for monitoring training adaptation and detecting physiological overload in equine athletes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Equine Veterinary Journal published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of EVJ Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>D&#x105;browska</LastName><ForeName>Izabela</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3253-2277</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Large Animal Diseases and Clinic, Institute of Veterinary Medicine, Warsaw University of Life Sciences, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grz&#x119;dzicka-Agko</LastName><ForeName>Jowita</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7281-5992</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Large Animal Diseases and Clinic, Institute of Veterinary Medicine, Warsaw University of Life Sciences, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kie&#x142;bik</LastName><ForeName>Paula</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6069-6201</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Large Animal Diseases and Clinic, Institute of Veterinary Medicine, Warsaw University of Life Sciences, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trela</LastName><ForeName>Micha&#x142;</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6456-6722</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Large Animal Diseases and Clinic, Institute of Veterinary Medicine, Warsaw University of Life Sciences, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Witkowska-Pi&#x142;aszewicz</LastName><ForeName>Olga</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3541-5914</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Large Animal Diseases and Clinic, Institute of Veterinary Medicine, Warsaw University of Life Sciences, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2021/41/B/NZ7/03548</GrantID><Agency>Narodowe Centrum Nauki</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Science Development Fund of the Warsaw University of Life Sciences-SGGW</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Equine Vet J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0173320</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0425-1644</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="ger"><AbstractText Label="HINTERGRUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Die molekularen Mechanismen, die der Anpassung an k&#xf6;rperliche Anstrengung und Rennstress bei Pferden zugrunde liegen, sind noch nicht vollst&#xe4;ndig gekl&#xe4;rt. Die Transkriptomik des peripheren Blutes bietet eine minimalinvasive Methode zur &#xdc;berwachung systemischer Reaktionen auf k&#xf6;rperliche Belastung und zur Identifizierung von Biomarkern f&#xfc;r Anpassung oder &#xdc;berlastung.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ZIELE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Bewertung der transkriptomischen Ver&#xe4;nderungen im peripheren Blut von Rennpferden w&#xe4;hrend verschiedener Trainings&#x2010; und Wettkampfphasen und Identifizierung molekularer Marker f&#xfc;r physiologische Anpassung und rennbedingten Stress.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDIENDESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Prospektive Transkriptom&#x2010;Profilierung von trainierten Rennpferden unter drei Trainingsbedingungen.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODEN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Vierzig Rennpferde (29 Araber, 11 Vollbl&#xfc;ter) wurden vor (p0) und nach (p1) dem Training in drei Phasen untersucht: zu Beginn des Trainings (T1), in der Mitte der Saison (T2) und w&#xe4;hrend des Rennens (R). Es wurde eine RNA&#x2010;Sequenzierung durchgef&#xfc;hrt, gefolgt von einer Differentialexpressionsanalyse (DESeq2) und einer Signalweg&#x2010;Anreicherung (g:Profiler, DAVID). Identifizierte DEGs wurden in STRING PPIs bedingungsspezifische Subnetzwerke integriert (Merge&#x2010;Tool in Cytoscape), um die Transkriptome zwischen den Bedingungen zu vergleichen.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ERGEBNISSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In jeder Phase wurden unterschiedliche molekulare Programme identifiziert. Bei T1 waren sofortige Fr&#xfc;hreaktionsgene wie FOS, FOSB und HSPA6 stark hochreguliert, was auf akuten Stress und eine Immunaktivierung hindeutet. Bei T2 blieben immunbezogene Transkripte (KLRD1, CCL4, PRF1) angereichert, aber Gene, die mit Umbau und Anpassung in Verbindung stehen, darunter DNAJA1, HSPH1 und CXCR4, traten in den Vordergrund, was auf eine Verlagerung hin zu Erholungs&#x2010; und Regulationsprozessen hindeutet. Nach dem Rennen waren Chemokine wie CCL5 und Stressmarker (HSP90&#x2010;Familie, JUN) stark induziert, begleitet von einer weitreichenden transkriptomischen Divergenz und einer Herunterregulierung bestimmter Immunregulatoren (IL18, ARHGAP44), was sowohl auf eine verst&#xe4;rkte angeborene Aktivierung als auch auf eine vor&#xfc;bergehende Immunsuppression hindeutet.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="HAUPTLIMITATIONEN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Die Transkriptom&#x2010;Profilierung beschr&#xe4;nkte sich auf peripheres Blut, was m&#xf6;glicherweise nicht die gewebespezifischen Reaktionen widerspiegelt. Es wurden nur drei Probenentnahmepunkte ber&#xfc;cksichtigt, wodurch m&#xf6;glicherweise vor&#xfc;bergehende transkriptomische Ver&#xe4;nderungen &#xfc;bersehen wurden.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SCHLUSSFOLGERUNGEN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Die Transkriptomdynamik im Blut spiegelt den &#xdc;bergang von der fr&#xfc;hen Immunaktivierung (T1) &#xfc;ber die Anpassung (T2) bis hin zur stressbedingten Aktivierung nach dem Rennen (R) wider. Dieser Ansatz bietet vielversprechende molekulare Biomarker f&#xfc;r die &#xdc;berwachung der Trainingsanpassung und die Erkennung physiologischer &#xdc;berlastung bei Sportpferden.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Equine Veterinary Journal published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of EVJ Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gene expression profiling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">horse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immune response</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">overtraining biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">race&#x2010;induced stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">training adaptation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transcriptomics</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41793277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/evj.70154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Chanda M, Petchdee S. Cardiac morphology changes in horses as a response to various types of sports. J Appl Anim Res. 2022;50(1):453&#x2013;459. https://doi.org/10.1080/09712119.2022.2097245</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plisak U, Szczepaniak J, &#x17b;migrodzka M, Giercuszkiewicz&#x2010;Hecold B, Witkowska&#x2010;Pi&#x142;aszewicz O. Changes in novel anti&#x2010;inflammatory cytokine concentration in the blood of endurance and race horses at different levels of training. Comput Struct Biotechnol J. 2023;21:418&#x2013;424. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.csbj.2022.12.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>te Pas MFW, Wijnberg ID, Hoekman AJW, de Graaf&#x2010;Roelfsema E, Keizer HA, van Breda E, et al. Skeletal muscle transcriptome profiles related to different training intensities and detraining in standardbred horses: a search for overtraining biomarkers. Vet J. 2013;197(3):717&#x2013;723. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tvjl.2013.03.052</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermeulen R, De Mee&#xfb;s C, Plancke L, Boshuizen B, De Bruijn M, Delesalle C. Fysiologische effecten van verschillende soorten arbeid op de spierontwikkeling van het paard. Vlaams Diergeneeskd Tijdschr. 2017;86(4):224&#x2013;230. https://doi.org/10.21825/vdt.v86i4.16183</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson J, De Donato M, Appelbaum B, Garcia CT, Peters S. Differential expression of innate and adaptive immune genes during acute physical exercise in American quarter horses. Animals. 2023;13(2):308. https://doi.org/10.3390/ani13020308</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piccione G, Fazio F, Giannetto C, Assenza A, Caola G. Oxidative stress in Thoroughbreds during official 1800&#x2010;metre races. Vet Arch. 2007;77(3):219&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esser MM, McKenzie EC, Payton ME. Serum immunoglobulin concentrations in horses racing a multiday endurance event. Comp Exerc Physiol. 2014;10(3):173&#x2013;179. https://doi.org/10.3920/CEP140009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klobu&#x10d;ar K, Vrbanac Z, Goti&#x107; J, Bojani&#x107; K, Bure&#x161; T, Bottegaro NB. Changes in biochemical parameters in horses during 40 km and 80 km endurance races. Acta Vet Brno. 2019;69(1):73&#x2013;87. https://doi.org/10.2478/acve-2019-0005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyypp&#xe4; S. Endocrinal responses in exercising horses. Livest Prod Sci. 2005;92:113&#x2013;121. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.livprodsci.2004.11.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purvis D, Gonsalves S, Deuster PA. Physiological and psychological fatigue in extreme conditions: overtraining and elite athletes. PM&amp;R. 2010;2(5):442&#x2013;450. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmrj.2010.03.025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pillon NJ, Gabriel BM, Dollet L, Smith JAB, Sard&#xf3;n Puig L, Botella J, et al. Transcriptomic profiling of skeletal muscle adaptations to exercise and inactivity. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):470. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-019-13869-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefaniuk&#x2010;Szmukier M, Szmato&#x142;a T, Ropka&#x2010;Molik K. Molecular signatures of exercise adaptation in Arabian racing horses: transcriptomic insights from blood and muscle. Genes. 2025;16(4):431. https://doi.org/10.3390/genes16040431</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill EW, Gu J, Eivers SS, Fonseca RG, McGivney BA, Govindarajan P, et al. A sequence polymorphism in MSTN predicts sprinting ability and racing stamina in Thoroughbred horses. PLoS One. 2010;5(1):8645. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0008645</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGivney BA, McGettigan PA, Browne JA, Evans ACO, Fonseca RG, Loftus BJ, et al. Characterization of the equine skeletal muscle transcriptome identifies novel functional responses to exercise training. BMC Genomics. 2010;11(1):398. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2164-11-398</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebisuda Y, Mukai K, Takahashi Y, Yoshida T, Kawano A, Matsuhashi T, et al. Acute exercise in a hot environment increases heat shock protein 70 and peroxisome proliferator&#x2010;activated receptor &#x3b3; coactivator 1&#x3b1; mRNA in Thoroughbred horse skeletal muscle. Front Vet Sci. 2023;10:1230212. https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2023.1230212</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ropka&#x2010;Molik K, Stefaniuk&#x2010;Szmukier M, &#x17b;ukowski K, Pi&#xf3;rkowska K, Gurgul A, Bugno&#x2010;Poniewierska M. Transcriptome profiling of Arabian horse blood during training regimens. BMC Genet. 2017;18(1):31. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12863-017-0499-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonometti S, Menarim BC, Reinholt BM, Ealy AD, Johnson SE. Growth factor modulation of equine trophoblast mitosis and prostaglandin gene Expression1. J Anim Sci. 2019;97(2):865&#x2013;873. https://doi.org/10.1093/jas/sky473</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martano M, Power K, Restucci B, Pagano I, Altamura G, Borzacchiello G, et al. Expression of vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) in equine sarcoid. BMC Vet Res. 2018;14(1):266. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12917-018-1576-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ak&#xe7;ay S, Gurkok&#x2010;Tan T, Ekici S. Identification of key genes in immune&#x2010;response post&#x2010;endurance run in horses. J Equine Vet Sci. 2025;149:105418. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jevs.2025.105418</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capomaccio S, Vitulo N, Verini&#x2010;Supplizi A, Barcaccia G, Albiero A, D'Angelo M, et al. RNA sequencing of the exercise transcriptome in equine athletes. PLoS One. 2013;8(12):83504. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0083504</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi K, Mukai K, Takahashi Y, Ebisuda Y, Hatta H, Kitaoka Y. Comparison of long&#x2010; and short&#x2010;rest periods during high&#x2010;intensity interval exercise on transcriptomic responses in equine skeletal muscle. Physiol Genomics. 2025;57(1):28&#x2013;39. https://doi.org/10.1152/physiolgenomics.00066.2024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page AE, Adam E, Arthur R, Barker V, Franklin F, Friedman R, et al. Expression of select mRNA in Thoroughbreds with catastrophic racing injuries. Equine Vet J. 2022;54(1):63&#x2013;73. https://doi.org/10.1111/evj.13423</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tozaki T, Kikuchi M, Kakoi H, Hirota KI, Mukai K, Aida H, et al. Profiling of exercise&#x2010;induced transcripts in the peripheral blood cells of Thoroughbred horses. J Equine Sci. 2016;27(4):157&#x2013;164. https://doi.org/10.1294/jes.27.157</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khummuang S, Lee HG, Joo SS, Park JW, Choi JY, Oh JH, et al. Comparison for immunophysiological responses of Jeju and Thoroughbred horses after exercise. Asian Australas J Anim Sci. 2019;33(3):424&#x2013;435. https://doi.org/10.5713/ajas.19.0260</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose R. Haematological changes associated with endurance exercise. Vet Rec. 1982;110(8):175&#x2013;177. https://doi.org/10.1136/vr.110.8.175</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Law CW, Chen Y, Shi W, Smyth GK. Voom: precision weights unlock linear model analysis tools for RNA&#x2010;seq read counts. Genome Biol. 2014;15(2):R29. https://doi.org/10.1186/gb-2014-15-2-r29</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shannon P, Markiel A, Ozier O, Baliga NS, Wang JT, Ramage D, et al. Cytoscape: a software environment for integrated models of biomolecular interaction networks. Genome Res. 2003;13(11):2498&#x2013;2504. https://doi.org/10.1101/gr.1239303</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith JE, Erickson HH, Debowes RM, Clark M. Changes in circulating equine erythrocytes induced by brief, high&#x2010;speed exercise. Equine Vet J. 1989;21(6):444&#x2013;446. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.2042-3306.1989.tb02193.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boucher JH, Ferguson EW, Wilhelmsen CL, Statham N, McMeekin RR. Erythrocyte alterations endurance exercise in horses. J Appl Physiol. 1981;51(1):131&#x2013;134. https://doi.org/10.1152/jappl.1981.51.1.131</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baskurt OK, Farley RA, Meiselman HJ. Erythrocyte aggregation tendency and cellular properties in horse, human, and rat: a comparative study. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 1997;273(6):H2604&#x2013;H2612. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpheart.1997.273.6.H2604</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanzawa K, Watanabe S. Changes in osmotic fragility of erythrocytes during exercise in athletic horses. J Equine Sci. 2000;11(3):51&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.1294/jes.11.51</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappelli K, Felicetti M, Capomaccio S, Pieramati C, Silvestrelli M, Verini&#x2010;Supplizi A. Exercise&#x2010;induced up&#x2010;regulation of MMP&#x2010;1 and IL&#x2010;8 genes in endurance horses. BMC Physiol. 2009;9(1):12. https://doi.org/10.1186/1472-6793-9-12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HG, Choi JY, Park JW, Park TS, Song KD, Shin D, et al. Effects of exercise on myokine gene expression in horse skeletal muscles. Asian&#x2010;Australas J Anim Sci. 2019;32(3):350&#x2013;356. https://doi.org/10.5713/ajas.18.0375</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murcia RY, Vargas A, Lavoie JP. The interleukin&#x2010;17 induced activation and increased survival of equine neutrophils is insensitive to glucocorticoids. PLoS One. 2016;11(5):e0154755. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0154755</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGivney BA, Eivers SS, MacHugh DE, MacLeod JN, O'Gorman GM, Park SDE, et al. Transcriptional adaptations following exercise in Thoroughbred horse skeletal muscle highlights molecular mechanisms that lead to muscle hypertrophy. BMC Genomics. 2009;10(1):638. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2164-10-638</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pernow J, &#xd6;hl&#xe9;n A, H&#xf6;kfelt T, Nilsson O, Lundberg JM. Neuropeptide Y: presence in perivascular noradrenergic neurons and vasoconstrictor effects on skeletal muscle blood vessels in experimental animals and man. Regul Pept. 1987;19(5&#x2010;6):313&#x2013;324. https://doi.org/10.1016/0167-0115(87)90173-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puntschart A, Wey E, Jostarndt K, Vogt M, Wittwer M, Widmer HR, et al. Expression of fos and jun genes in human skeletal muscle after exercise. Am J Physiol. 1998;274(1):C129&#x2013;C137. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpcell.1998.274.1.C129</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel RS, Tomlinson JE, Divers TJ, Van De Walle GR, Rosenberg BR. Single&#x2010;cell resolution landscape of equine peripheral blood mononuclear cells reveals diverse cell types including T&#x2010;bet+ B cells. BMC Biol. 2021;19(1):13. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12915-020-00947-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riihim&#xe4;ki M, Fegraeus K, Nordlund J, Waern I, Wernersson S, Akula S, et al. Single&#x2010;cell transcriptomics delineates the immune cell landscape in equine lower airways and reveals upregulation of FKBP5 in horses with asthma. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):16261. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-43368-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witkowska&#x2010;Pi&#x142;aszewicz O, Pingwara R, Winnicka A. The effect of physical training on peripheral blood mononuclear cell ex vivo proliferation, differentiation, activity, and reactive oxygen species production in racehorses. Antioxidants. 2020;9(11):1155. https://doi.org/10.3390/antiox9111155</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park KD, Park J, Ko J, Kim BC, Kim HS, Ahn K, et al. Whole transcriptome analyses of six Thoroughbred horses before and after exercise using RNA&#x2010;seq. BMC Genomics. 2012;13(1):473. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2164-13-473</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pakula PD, Halama A, Al&#x2010;Dous EK, Johnson SJ, Filho SA, Suhre K, et al. Characterization of exercise&#x2010;induced hemolysis in endurance horses. Front Vet Sci. 2023;10:1115776. https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2023.1115776</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plasenzotti R, Stoiber B, Posch M, Windberger U. Red blood cell deformability and aggregation behaviour in different animal species. Clin Hemorheol Microcirc. 2004;31(2):105&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ropka&#x2010;Molik K, Stefaniuk&#x2010;Szmukier M, &#x17b;ukowski K, Pi&#xf3;rkowska K, Bugno&#x2010;Poniewierska M. Exercise&#x2010;induced modification of the skeletal muscle transcriptome in Arabian horses. Physiol Genomics. 2017;49(6):318&#x2013;326. https://doi.org/10.1152/physiolgenomics.00130.2016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitaoka Y, Mukai K, Tonai S, Ohmura H, Takahashi T. Effect of post&#x2010;exercise muscle cooling on PGC&#x2010;1&#x3b1; and VEGF mRNA expression in Thoroughbreds. Comp Exerc Physiol. 2022;18(1):21&#x2013;26. https://doi.org/10.3920/CEP210006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiscock N, Fischer CP, Pilegaard H, Pedersen BK. Vascular endothelial growth factor mRNA expression and arteriovenous balance in response to prolonged, submaximal exercise in humans. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2003;285(4):H1759&#x2013;H1763. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpheart.00150.2003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song KD, Cho HW, Lee HK, Cho BW. Molecular characterization and expression analysis of equine vascular endothelial growth factor alpha (VEGF&#x3b1;) gene in horse (Equus caballus). Asian Australas J Anim Sci. 2014;27(5):743&#x2013;748. https://doi.org/10.5713/ajas.2013.13821</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovac M, Berestov IV, Aimaletdinov AM, Rutland CS, Rizvanov AA, Zakirova EY. Gene therapy using plasmid DNA encoding bone morphogenetic protein 2 and vascular endothelial growth factor 164 genes for the treatment of equine proximal suspensory desmitis: case reports. OM&amp;P. 2024;11(2):74&#x2013;89. https://doi.org/10.24412/2500-2295-2024-2-74-89</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaVigne EK, Jones AK, Londo&#xf1;o AS, Schauer AS, Patterson DF, Nadeau JA, et al. Muscle growth in young horses: effects of age, cytokines, and growth factors1. J Anim Sci. 2015;93(12):5672&#x2013;5680. https://doi.org/10.2527/jas.2015-9634</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JW, Bae JH, Go GY, Lee JR, Jeong Y, Kim JY, et al. Epsti1 regulates the inflammatory stage of early muscle regeneration through STAT1&#x2010;VCP interaction. Int J Biol Sci. 2024;20(9):3530&#x2013;3543. https://doi.org/10.7150/ijbs.94675</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trenerry MK, Della Gatta PA, Larsen AE, Garnham AP, Cameron&#x2010;Smith D. Impact of resistance exercise training on interleukin&#x2010;6 and JAK/STAT in young men. Muscle Nerve. 2011;43(3):385&#x2013;392. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.21875</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajiir H, Ramm GA, Macdonald GA, McGuckin MA, Prins JB, Hasnain SZ. Harnessing IL&#x2010;22 for metabolic health: promise and pitfalls. Trends Mol Med. 2025;31(6):574&#x2013;584. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molmed.2024.10.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Yu F, Ding Y, Zhang H, Li X, Wang X, et al. Hepatic IL22RA1 deficiency promotes hepatic steatosis by modulating oxysterol in the liver. Hepatology. 2025;81(5):1564&#x2013;1582. https://doi.org/10.1097/HEP.0000000000000998</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kauffman AS. Emerging functions of gonadotropin&#x2010;releasing hormone II in mammalian physiology and behaviour. J Neuroendocrinol. 2004;16(9):794&#x2013;806. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2826.2004.01229.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burcelin R, Thorens B, Glauser M, Gaillard RC, Pralong FP. Gonadotropin&#x2010;releasing hormone secretion from hypothalamic neurons: stimulation by insulin and potentiation by leptin. Endocrinology. 2003;144(10):4484&#x2013;4491. https://doi.org/10.1210/en.2003-0457</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson TJ, Hahn TP, MacDougall&#x2010;Shackleton SA, Ball GF. Gonadotropin&#x2010;releasing hormone plasticity: a comparative perspective. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2012;33(3):287&#x2013;300. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yfrne.2012.09.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapronova &#x410;&#x410;, Ryabushkina YA, Kisaretov&#x430; PE, Bondar NP. Mechanisms of adaptation of the hypothalamic&#x2010;pituitary&#x2010;adrenal axis in male mice under chronic social defeat stress. Zh Vyssh Nerv Deiat Im I P Pavlova. 2024;74(2):197&#x2013;209. https://doi.org/10.31857/S0044467724020058</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuizon E, Pearce EG, Bailey SG, Chen&#x2010;Scarabelli C, Yuan Z, Abounit K, et al. Mechanisms of action and clinical implications of cardiac urocortin: a journey from the heart to the systemic circulation, with a stopover in the mitochondria. Int J Cardiol. 2009;137(3):189&#x2013;194. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijcard.2009.03.112</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavalakatt S, Khadir A, Madhu D, Hammad M, Devarajan S, Abubaker J, et al. Urocortin 3 levels are impaired in overweight humans with and without type 2 diabetes and modulated by exercise. Front Endocrinol. 2019;10:762. https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2019.00762</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi M, Kubota S. Exercise&#x2010;related novel gene is involved in myoblast differentiation. Biomed Res. 2005;26(2):79&#x2013;85. https://doi.org/10.2220/biomedres.26.79</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zang D, Wang C, Ji X, Wang Y. Tamarix hispida zinc finger protein ThZFP1 participates in salt and osmotic stress tolerance by increasing proline content and SOD and POD activities. Plant Sci. 2015;235:111&#x2013;121. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plantsci.2015.02.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Den Bergen JA, Robevska G, Eggers S, Riedl S, Grover SR, Bergman PB, et al. Analysis of variants in GATA4 and FOG2 / ZFPM2 demonstrates benign contribution to 46,XY disorders of sex development. Mol Genet Genomic Med. 2020;8(3):e1095. https://doi.org/10.1002/mgg3.1095</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabenstein RL, Addy NA, Caldarone BJ, Asaka Y, Gruenbaum LM, Peters LL, et al. Impaired synaptic plasticity and learning in mice lacking &#x3b2;&#x2010;adducin, an actin&#x2010;regulating protein. J Neurosci. 2005;25(8):2138&#x2013;2145. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3530-04.2005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiang KMY, Leung GKK. A review on adducin from functional to pathological mechanisms: future direction in cancer. Biomed Res Int. 2018;2018:1&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1155/2018/3465929</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozzi D, Corradini I, Matteoli M. The control of neuronal calcium homeostasis by SNAP&#x2010;25 and its impact on neurotransmitter release. Neuroscience. 2019;420:72&#x2013;78. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2018.11.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endo Y, Zhang Y, Olumi S, Karvar M, Argawal S, Neppl RL, et al. Exercise&#x2010;induced gene expression changes in skeletal muscle of old mice. Genomics. 2021;113(5):2965&#x2013;2976. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ygeno.2021.06.035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rademacher N, Schmerl B, Lardong JA, Wahl MC, Shoichet SA. MPP2 is a postsynaptic MAGUK scaffold protein that links SynCAM1 cell adhesion molecules to core components of the postsynaptic density. Sci Rep. 2016;6(1):35283. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep35283</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmerl B, Gimber N, Kuropka B, Stumpf A, Rentsch J, Kunde S&#x2010;A, et al. The synaptic scaffold protein MPP2 interacts with GABAA receptors at the periphery of the postsynaptic density of glutamatergic synapses. PLoS Biol. 2022;20(3):e3001503. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.3001503</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hestand MS, Kalbfleisch TS, Coleman SJ, Zeng Z, Liu J, Orlando L, et al. Annotation of the protein coding regions of the equine genome. PLoS One. 2015;10(6):e0124375. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0124375</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong C, Wang H, Yuan X, He Y, Cong J, Yang R, et al. The crucial role of HFM1 in regulating FUS ubiquitination and localization for oocyte meiosis prophase I progression in mice. Biol Res. 2024;57(1):36. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40659-024-00518-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DH, Lee HG, Sp N, Kang DY, Jang KJ, Lee HK, et al. Validation of exercise&#x2010;response genes in skeletal muscle cells of Thoroughbred racing horses. Anim Biosci. 2021;34(1):134&#x2013;142. https://doi.org/10.5713/ajas.18.0749</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Barcellos LAM, Gon&#xe7;alves WA, de Esteves Oliveira MP, Guimar&#xe3;es JB, Queiroz&#x2010;Junior CM, de Resende CB, et al. Effect of physical training on exercise&#x2010;induced inflammation and performance in mice. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2021;9:1&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcell.2021.625680</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn H, Kim J, Lee H, Lee E, Lee GS. Characterization of equine inflammasomes and their regulation. Vet Res Commun. 2020;44(2):51&#x2013;59. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11259-020-09772-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang H, Lee GKC, Bienzle D, Arroyo LG, Sears W, Lillie BN, et al. Equine alveolar macrophages and monocyte&#x2010;derived macrophages respond differently to an inflammatory stimulus. PLoS One. 2023;18(3):e0282738. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0282738</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mach N, Ramayo&#x2010;Caldas Y, Clark A, Moroldo M, Robert C, Barrey E, et al. Understanding the response to endurance exercise using a systems biology approach: combining blood metabolomics, transcriptomics and miRNomics in horses. BMC Genomics. 2017;18(1):187. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12864-017-3571-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hjorth M, Egan CL, Telles GD, Pal M, Gallego&#x2010;Ortega D, Fuller OK, et al. Decorin, an exercise&#x2010;induced secretory protein, is associated with improved prognosis in breast cancer patients but does not mediate anti&#x2010;tumorigenic tissue crosstalk in mice. J Sport Health Sci. 2025;14:100991. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jshs.2024.100991</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Ren W, Ma S, Meng J, Yao X, Zeng Y, et al. Comparative analysis of blood whole transcriptome profiles in Yili horses pre&#x2010; and post&#x2010;5000&#x2010;meter racing. Front Genet. 2025;16:1651628. https://doi.org/10.3389/fgene.2025.1651628</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wubuli A, Su Y, Yao X, Meng J, Wang J, Zeng Y, et al. Transcriptome analysis of muscle tissue from three anatomical locations in male and female Kazakh horses. Biology. 2025;14(9):1216. https://doi.org/10.3390/biology14091216</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunn HM. Differences in the histochemical properties of skeletal muscles of different breeds of horses and dogs. J Anat. 1978;127(Pt 3):615&#x2013;634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marlin DJ, Harris RC, Gash SP, Snow DH. Carnosine content of the middle gluteal muscle in Thoroughbred horses with relation to age, sex and training. Comp Biochem Physiol A Physiol. 1989;93(3):629&#x2013;632. https://doi.org/10.1016/0300-9629(89)90023-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryan K, McGivney BA, Farries G, McGettigan PA, McGivney CL, Gough KF, et al. Equine skeletal muscle adaptations to exercise and training: evidence of differential regulation of autophagosomal and mitochondrial components. BMC Genomics. 2017;18(1):595. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12864-017-4007-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farries G, Bryan K, McGivney CL, McGettigan P, Gough KF, Browne JA, et al. Expression quantitative trait loci in equine skeletal muscle reveals heritable variation in metabolism and the training responsive transcriptome. Front Genet. 2019;10:10. https://doi.org/10.3389/fgene.2019.01215</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haller N, Behringer M, Reichel T, Wahl P, Simon P, Kr&#xfc;ger K, et al. Blood&#x2010;based biomarkers for managing workload in athletes: considerations and recommendations for evidence&#x2010;based use of established biomarkers. Sports Med. 2023;53(7):1315&#x2013;1333. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-023-01836-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cywinska A, Szarska E, Kowalska A, Ostaszewski P, Schollenberger A. Gender differences in exercise &#x2013; induced intravascular haemolysis during race training in Thoroughbred horses. Res Vet Sci. 2011;90(1):133&#x2013;137. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rvsc.2010.05.004</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>