<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41927730</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Post-exercise auricular vagus nerve stimulation modulates autonomic and recovery responses in physically inactive young adults: a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-47143-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Efficient post-exercise recovery largely depends on rapid parasympathetic reactivation of the autonomic nervous system. Auricular transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation (taVNS) has emerged as a non-invasive neuromodulatory approach with the potential to facilitate autonomic recovery following physical exertion. This study aimed to investigate the acute effects of auricular transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation applied immediately after exercise on autonomic nervous system activity and recovery-related physiological, metabolic, and perceptual parameters in healthy young adults. This cross-sectional study with an acute intervention bout included sixty physically inactive healthy young adults (18-35 years) who were randomly allocated to an exercise&#x2009;+&#x2009;taVNS group (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;30) or an exercise-only control group (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;30). All participants completed a standardized 30-minute treadmill walking protocol. Immediately after exercise, the intervention group received 20&#xa0;min of bilateral taVNS, while the control group underwent a matched recovery period. Autonomic function was assessed using heart rate variability indices, including the root mean square of successive differences (RMSSD), a time-domain indicator of parasympathetic activity, and the low-frequency/high-frequency (LF/HF) ratio, which reflects sympathovagal balance, together with cardiovascular, metabolic, and perceptual recovery markers. Both groups demonstrated recovery-related improvements following exercise. However, the taVNS group showed greater reductions in systolic and diastolic blood pressure compared with the control group (p = .003 and p = .004). The parasympathetic nervous system index increased significantly more in the taVNS group (p = .009). Blood lactate concentration decreased more markedly in the taVNS group (-&#x2009;4.90&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;3.02 mmol&#xb7;L&#x207b;&#xb9;) than in the control group (-&#x2009;1.38&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.97 mmol&#xb7;L&#x207b;&#xb9;; p &lt; .001). Participants receiving taVNS also demonstrated a greater reduction in perceived fatigue scores (p &lt; .001). In contrast, heart rate variability parameters such as heart rate, RMSSD, and LF/HF ratio showed comparable recovery patterns between groups (p &gt; .05). Auricular transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation applied immediately after exercise appears to enhance parasympathetic reactivation and improve cardiovascular, metabolic, and perceptual recovery beyond spontaneous post-exercise recovery. These findings suggest that taVNS may represent a feasible non-invasive strategy to support acute post-exercise recovery in healthy young adults when applied under appropriate stimulation parameters (ClinicalTrials.gov: NCT07371676).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ert&#xfc;rk</LastName><ForeName>&#xc7;a&#x11f;&#x131;l</ForeName><Initials>&#xc7;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Department of Occupational Therapy, Istanbul Gelisim University, Avc&#x131;lar, 34310, Istanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye. certurk@gelisim.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mutu&#x15f;</LastName><ForeName>R&#x131;fat</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Department of Odiology, Istanbul Gelisim University, Avc&#x131;lar, 34310, Istanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT07371676</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Grant No.: TGA-2024-168.</GrantID><Agency>This study was supported by Istanbul Gelisim University Office of Scientific Research Projects</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Grant No.: TGA-2024-168.</GrantID><Agency>This study was supported by Istanbul Gelisim University Office of Scientific Research Projects</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Auricular transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomic nervous system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heart rate variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parasympathetic reactivation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-exercise recovery</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethics approval and consent to participate: All procedures were conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Ethical approval for the study was obtained from the Istanbul Gelisim University Ethics Committee (Meeting No: 2024/05, Decision No: 2024-05-88, approval date: 19 April 2024), which confirmed that the study protocol complied with relevant ethical standards. Written informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to enrollment. The study was prospectively registered as a clinical trial at ClinicalTrials.gov (Registration No: NCT07371676, registration date: 28 January 2026).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41927730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-47143-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-47143-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yuan, H. &amp; Silberstein, S. D. Vagus nerve and vagus nerve stimulation, a comprehensive review: Part I. Headache 56(1), 71&#x2013;78. https://doi.org/10.1111/head.12647 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xe2;mara, R. &amp; Griessenauer, C. J. Anatomy of the vagus nerve. In Nerves and nerve injuries (eds Tubbs, R. S. et al.) 385&#x2013;397 (Academic, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capilupi, M. J., Kerath, S. M. &amp; Becker, L. B. Vagus nerve stimulation and the cardiovascular system. Cold Spring Harb Perspect. Med. 10 (2), a034173. https://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a034173 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, H. &amp; Silberstein, S. D. Vagus nerve and vagus nerve stimulation, a comprehensive review: Part II. Headache 56 (2), 259&#x2013;266 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peuker, E. T. &amp; Filler, T. J. The nerve supply of the human auricle. Clin. Anat. 15 (1), 35&#x2013;37. https://doi.org/10.1002/ca.1089 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butt, M. F., Albusoda, A., Farmer, A. D. &amp; Aziz, Q. The anatomical basis for transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation. J. Anat. 236 (4), 588&#x2013;611. https://doi.org/10.1111/joa.13122 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilz, M. J. Transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation &#x2013; a brief introduction and overview. Auton. Neurosci. 243, 103038. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autneu.2022.103038 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chae, J. H. et al. A review of functional neuroimaging studies of vagus nerve stimulation (VNS). J. Psychiatr Res. 37 (6), 443&#x2013;455. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-3956(03)00074-8 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poppa, T. et al. Auricular transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation modulates the heart-evoked potential. Brain Stimul. 15 (1), 260&#x2013;269. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brs.2021.12.004 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yap, J. Y. Y. et al. Critical review of transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation: challenges for translation to clinical practice. Front. Neurosci. 14, 284. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2020.00284 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hat&#x131;k, S. H., Arslan, M., Demirbilek, &#xd6;. &amp; &#xd6;zden, A. V. The effect of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation on cycling ergometry and recovery in healthy young individuals. Brain Behav. 13 (12), e3332. https://doi.org/10.1002/brb3.3332 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;&#xe7;l&#xfc;er, E. &#xd6;., Ural, &#x130;. H., &#xd6;zden, A. V., Alptekin, H. K. &amp; Hat&#x131;k, S. H. Effects of auricular vagus nerve stimulation on cardiorespiratory functions after aerobic exercise. Int. J. Disabil. Sports Health Sci. 7 (3), 494&#x2013;501 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, A. Y. et al. Safety of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation (taVNS): a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci. Rep. 12 (1), 22055. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-25864-1 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackland, G. L. et al. Non-invasive vagus nerve stimulation and exercise capacity in healthy volunteers: a randomized trial. Eur. Heart J. 46 (17), 1634&#x2013;1644. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf037 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, S. H. et al. The effects of vagus nerve stimulation on stress, competitive anxiety, and depression in elite shooters: randomized controlled trial. Appl. Sci. 15 (16), 9105 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ert&#xfc;rk, &#xc7;. &amp; &#xd6;zden, A. V. Comparison of the acute effects of auricular vagus nerve stimulation and deep breathing exercise on the autonomic nervous system activity and biomechanical properties of the muscle in healthy people. J. Clin. Med. 14 (4), 1046. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm14041046 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michael, S., Graham, K. S. &amp; Davis, G. M. Cardiac autonomic responses during exercise and post-exercise recovery using heart rate variability and systolic time intervals: a review. Front. Physiol. 8, 301. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2017.00301 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W., Shao, M., Du, W. &amp; Xu, Y. Impact of exhaustive exercise on autonomic nervous system activity: insights from HRV analysis. Front. Physiol. 15, 1462082. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2024.1462082 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weberruss, H., Maucher, J., Oberhoffer, R. &amp; M&#xfc;ller, J. Recovery of the cardiac autonomic nervous and vascular system after maximal cardiopulmonary exercise testing in recreational athletes. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 118 (1), 205&#x2013;211. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-017-3762-2 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laborde, S., Wanders, J., Mosley, E. &amp; Javelle, F. Influence of physical post-exercise recovery techniques on vagally-mediated heart rate variability: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin. Physiol. Funct. Imaging. 44 (1), 14&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.1111/cpf.12855 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferstl, M. et al. Non-invasive vagus nerve stimulation boosts mood recovery after effort exertion. Psychol. Med. 52 (14), 3029&#x2013;3039. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291720005073 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulders, D. M., de Vos, C. C., Vosman, I. &amp; van Putten, M. J. The effect of vagus nerve stimulation on cardiorespiratory parameters during rest and exercise. Seizure 33, 24&#x2013;28. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seizure.2015.10.004 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gen&#xe7;, H., Tahmaz, T. &amp; Demircio&#x11f;lu, G. The impact of non-invasive vagus nerve stimulation on recovery following aerobic exercise in individuals with post-COVID syndrome: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Eurasian J. Pulmonol. 26 (3), 189&#x2013;196 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniela, M. et al. Effects of exercise training on the autonomic nervous system with a focus on anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effects. Antioxid. (Basel). 11 (2), 350. https://doi.org/10.3390/antiox11020350 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zden, A. V., Alptekin, H. K., Pehlivano&#x11f;lu, B. E. &amp; &#xdc;nal, M. A new method for sportive performance and recovery: auricular vagus nerve stimulation. BAU Health Innov. 2 (1), 34&#x2013;41 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez Blanco, C. &amp; Tyler, W. J. The vagus nerve: a cornerstone for mental health and performance optimization in recreation and elite sports. Front. Psychol. 16, 1639866. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1639866 (2025).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>