<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41798098</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2325-9671</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Orthopaedic journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Orthop J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Early Functional Recovery Is Improved in Patients Treated With Bioinductive Collagen Implant Augmentation Compared With Standard Arthroscopic Repair of High-grade Partial-Thickness Rotator Cuff Tears: A Prospective Randomized Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23259671261418675</StartPage><MedlinePgn>23259671261418675</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23259671261418675</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/23259671261418675</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Arthroscopic surgical takedown and repair of symptomatic partial-thickness rotator cuff tears are commonly undertaken. An alternative approach is the use of a bioinductive collagen implant to augment the rotator cuff tear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To investigate early function and rotator cuff tendon integrity in patients undergoing arthroscopic bioinductive collagen implant augmentation (REG group) versus rotator cuff takedown and repair (RCR group) for high-grade partial-thickness rotator cuff tears.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Randomized controlled clinical trial; Level of evidence, 2.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Patients 35 to 75 years of age with symptoms &gt;3 months and unresponsive to nonoperative treatment, with high-grade partial-thickness rotator cuff tears confirmed on 3-T magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), were randomly allocated to RCR or REG groups. Exclusion criteria included previous ipsilateral shoulder surgery, multitendon tears/pathology, and concomitant surgery including labral repair, long head of biceps tenodesis, or chondroplasty/microfracture. Patients were assessed preoperatively and at 6 weeks as well as 3, 6, and 12 months postoperatively. The primary study outcome was the Western Ontario Rotator Cuff Index (WORC) at 3 months after surgery. Secondary outcomes included the American Shoulder and Elbow Surgeons (ASES) and Constant scores, and the time taken to return to work and activities of daily living (ADLs). MRI-based rotator cuff repair integrity was assessed using the Sugaya grading system.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study recruited 41 patients (REG n = 21; RCR n = 20). No group differences (<i>P</i> &gt; .05) were observed in mean age (REG 57.1 years; RCR 57.8 years), preoperative duration of symptoms, and previous nonoperative treatments. The REG group reported superior outcomes for the WORC at 6 weeks (<i>P</i> = .001) and 3 months (<i>P</i> = .026) as well as the ASES at 6 weeks (<i>P</i> &lt; .001) and WORC Work, Sport, and Emotions domains at 6 weeks and 3 months (<i>P</i> &lt; .05). There were no group-based differences (<i>P</i> &gt; .05) in patient-reported outcomes at 6 or 12 months after surgery. The REG group was faster (<i>P</i> &lt; .05) to permanently remove the sling, drive a motor vehicle, and return to office duties and moderate-intensity chores. No MRI-based differences were observed, with 19 (90%) and 17 (85%) REG and RCR patients, respectively, graded Sugaya 1 to 2 at 12 months.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">For symptomatic high-grade partial-thickness rotator cuff tears, bioinductive collagen implant augmentation versus standard rotator cuff repair demonstrated improved early function with equivalent MRI-based healing rates.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Australian New Zealand Clinical Trials Register (ACTRN12620000926932p).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Allan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, St John of God Subiaco Hospital, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Breidahl</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Perth Radiological Clinic, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ek</LastName><ForeName>Eugene T</ForeName><Initials>ET</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Melbourne Orthopaedic Group, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Monash Medical Center, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Falconer</LastName><ForeName>Travis</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Perth Orthopaedic &amp; Sports Medicine Centre, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>D'Alessandro</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedic Research Foundation of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fiona Stanley and Fremantle Hospitals Group, South Metropolitan Health Service, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Surgery, University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ebert</LastName><ForeName>Jay R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5843-6243</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Sciences (Exercise and Sport Science), University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HFRC Rehabilitation Clinic, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Orthop J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101620522</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2325-9671</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bioinductive collagen implant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">magnetic resonance imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rotator cuff partial-thickness tear</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>One or more of the authors has declared the following potential conflict of interest or source of funding: This research study received funding from Smith and Nephew (IIS749).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41798098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12961150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671261418675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_23259671261418675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bauer S, Wang A, Butler R, et al. Reliability of a 3 T MRI protocol for objective grading of supraspinatus tendonosis and partial thickness tears. J Orthop Surg Res. 2014;9:128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4278262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25519001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bokor DJ, Sonnabend D, Deady L, et al. Evidence of healing of partial-thickness rotator cuff tears following arthroscopic augmentation with a collagen implant: a 2-year MRI follow-up. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 2016;6(1):16-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4915456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27331028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bushnell BD, Bishai SK, Krupp RJ, et al. Treatment of partial-thickness rotator cuff tears with a resorbable bioinductive bovine collagen implant: 1-year results from a prospective multicenter registry. Orthop J Sports Med. 2021;9(8):23259671211027850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8366148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34409115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camacho Chacon JA, Roda Rojo V, Martin Martinez A, et al. An isolated bioinductive repair vs sutured repair for full-thickness rotator cuff tears: 2-year results of a double blinded, randomized controlled trial. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2024;33(9):1894-1904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38734130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castricini R, La Camera F, De Gori M, et al. Functional outcomes and repair integrity after arthroscopic repair of partial articular supraspinatus tendon avulsion. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2019;139(3):369-375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30269221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constant CR, Gerber C, Emery RJ, Sojbjerg JO, Gohlke F, Boileau P. A review of the Constant score: modifications and guidelines for its use. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2008;17(2):355-361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18218327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constant CR, Murley AH. A clinical method of functional assessment of the shoulder. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1987(214):160-164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3791738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cucchi D, Menon A, Maggi S, et al. Treatment of partial rotator cuff lesions is associated with a higher frequency of post-operative shoulder stiffness: a prospective investigation on the role of surgery-related risk factors for this complication. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2022;142(11):3379-3387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9522663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34905067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagnier JJ, Robbins C, Bedi A, Carpenter JE, Miller BS. Establishing minimally important differences for the American Shoulder and Elbow Surgeons score and the Western Ontario Rotator Cuff Index in patients with full-thickness rotator cuff tears. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2018;27(5):e160-e166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29307675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houck DA, Kraeutler MJ, Schuette HB, McCarty EC, Bravman JT. Early versus delayed motion after rotator cuff repair: a systematic review of overlapping meta-analyses. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45(12):2911-2915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28288280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan RW, Bentick K, Saithna A. Transtendinous repair of partial articular sided supraspinatus tears is associated with higher rates of stiffness and significantly inferior early functional scores than tear completion and repair: a systematic review. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2018;104(6):829-837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30036723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamath G, Galatz LM, Keener JD, Teefey S, Middleton W, Yamaguchi K. Tendon integrity and functional outcome after arthroscopic repair of high-grade partial-thickness supraspinatus tears. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2009;91(5):1055-1062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19411453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keener JD, Galatz LM, Teefey SA, et al. A prospective evaluation of survivorship of asymptomatic degenerative rotator cuff tears. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2015;97(2):89-98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4296477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25609434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkley A, Alvarez C, Griffin S. The development and evaluation of a disease-specific quality-of-life questionnaire for disorders of the rotator cuff: the Western Ontario Rotator Cuff Index. Clin J Sport Med. 2003;13(2):84-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12629425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo IK, Denkers MR, More KD, Nelson AA, Thornton GM, Boorman RS. Partial-thickness rotator cuff tears: clinical and imaging outcomes and prognostic factors of successful nonoperative treatment. Open Access J Sports Med. 2018;9:191-197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6149897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30271226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIntyre LF, Bishai SK, Brown PB, III, Bushnell BD, Trenhaile SW. Patient-reported outcomes after use of a bioabsorbable collagen implant to treat partial and full-thickness rotator cuff tears. Arthroscopy. 2019;35(8):2262-2271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31350082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters KS, McCallum S, Briggs L, Murrell GA. A comparison of outcomes after arthroscopic repair of partial versus small or medium-sized full-thickness rotator cuff tears. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2012;94(12):1078-1085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22717826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly P, Amis AA, Wallace AL, Emery RJ. Supraspinatus tears: propagation and strain alteration. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2003;12(2):134-138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12700564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz Iban MA, Garcia Navlet M, Moros Marco S, et al. Augmentation of a posterosuperior cuff repair with a bovine bioinductive collagen implant shows a lower retear rate but similar outcomes compared with no augmentation: 2-year results of a randomized controlled trial. Arthroscopy. 2025;41(10):3869-3879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40209829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sano H, Wakabayashi I, Itoi E. Stress distribution in the supraspinatus tendon with partial-thickness tears: an analysis using two-dimensional finite element model. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2006;15(1):100-105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16414477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlegel TF, Abrams JS, Angelo RL, Getelman MH, Ho CP, Bushnell BD. Isolated bioinductive repair of partial-thickness rotator cuff tears using a resorbable bovine collagen implant: two-year radiologic and clinical outcomes from a prospective multicenter study. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2021;30(8):1938-1948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sher JS, Uribe JW, Posada A, Murphy BJ, Zlatkin MB. Abnormal findings on magnetic resonance images of asymptomatic shoulders. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1995;77(1):10-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7822341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin SJ. A comparison of 2 repair techniques for partial-thickness articular-sided rotator cuff tears. Arthroscopy. 2012;28(1):25-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22000411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugaya H, Maeda K, Matsuki K, Moriishi J. Repair integrity and functional outcome after arthroscopic double-row rotator cuff repair. A prospective outcome study. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2007;89(5):953-960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17473131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tirefort J, Schwitzguebel AJ, Collin P, Nowak A, Plomb-Holmes C, Ladermann A. Postoperative mobilization after superior rotator cuff repair: sling versus no sling: a randomized prospective study. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2019;101(6):494-503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30893230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren JR, Domingo-Johnson ER, Sorensen AA, Cheng AL, Latz KH, Cil A. Bioinductive patch as an augmentation for rotator cuff repair, a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2024;33(11):2515-2529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38942225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterman BR, Newgren J, Gowd AK, et al. Randomized trial of arthroscopic rotator cuff with or without acromioplasty: no difference in patient-reported outcomes at long-term follow-up. Arthroscopy. 2021;37(10):3072-3078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33940126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodmass JM, Al Khatib L, McRae S, et al. Arthroscopic rotator cuff repair with and without acromioplasty in the treatment of full-thickness rotator cuff tears: long-term outcomes of a multicenter, randomized controlled trial. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2022;104(23):2101-2107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36476738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S, Pang L, Zhang C, et al. Lower reoperation rate and superior patient-reported outcome following arthroscopic rotator cuff repair with concomitant acromioplasty: an updated systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Arthroscopy. 2025;41(5):1618-1634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38876445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeazell S, Lutz A, Bohon H, et al. Increased stiffness and reoperation rate in partial rotator cuff repairs treated with a bovine patch: a propensity-matched trial. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2022;31(6S):S131-S135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35288296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L, Natarajan M, Miller BS, Gagnier JJ. Establishing minimal important differences for the VR-12 and SANE scores in patients following treatment of rotator cuff tears. Orthop J Sports Med. 2018;6(7):2325967118782159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6077909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30090834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>