<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41885398</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2691-3321</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JBI evidence implementation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JBI Evid Implement</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>De-implementation of movement precautions after total hip replacement in a German university hospital: a best practice implementation project.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/XEB.0000000000000573</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Total hip replacement (THR) constitutes one of the most frequently performed surgical interventions in Germany. Despite robust evidence demonstrating that routine post-operative movement restrictions neither reduce dislocation risk nor enhance functional recovery, such precautions remain commonplace.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This project aimed to assess and improve clinical practice among health care professionals in a German university hospital-including physicians, physiotherapists, and occupational therapists-regarding patient education on post-operative movement precautions after THR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This implementation project followed the 7-phase JBI Evidence Implementation Framework, which uses an audit and feedback approach to promote change. A baseline audit was conducted to assess adherence to the best practice recommendation that no routine hip movement precautions should be applied to patients after THR surgery. This was followed by two implementation workshops that included evidence-based presentations and group discussions, culminating in a re-audit to assess compliance improvements.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The baseline audit revealed a compliance rate of 16.67% with the best practice recommendation. Following the intervention, compliance improved to 100%.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This project significantly enhanced adherence to best practice recommendations. Future efforts should focus on ensuring the sustainability of these short-term changes through policy integration and ongoing education, and validating the results for generalizability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SPANISH ABSTRACT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">http://links.lww.com/IJEBH/A533.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 JBI. Unauthorized reproduction of this article is prohibited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosen</LastName><ForeName>Diane</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, University Hospital Brandenburg, Brandenburg Medical School, Brandenburg/Havel, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>JBI Center of Evidence Based Practice Germany, Brandenburg Medical School, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lettner</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, University Hospital Brandenburg, Brandenburg Medical School, Brandenburg/Havel, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>JBI Center of Evidence Based Practice Germany, Brandenburg Medical School, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaster</LastName><ForeName>Christina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, University Hospital Brandenburg, Brandenburg Medical School, Brandenburg/Havel, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>JBI Center of Evidence Based Practice Germany, Brandenburg Medical School, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klugarov&#xe1;</LastName><ForeName>Jitka</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>JBI Czech Republic, Prague, Czech Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>JBI Center of Evidence-Based Education and Arts Therapies, Palack&#xfd; University, Olomouc, Czech Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biostatistics and Analyses, Faculty of Medicine, Masaryk University, Brno, Czech Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vrbov&#xe1;</LastName><ForeName>Tereza</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>JBI Center of Evidence-Based Education and Arts Therapies, Palack&#xfd; University, Olomouc, Czech Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ba&#x142;a</LastName><ForeName>Ma&#x142;gorzata M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chair of Epidemiology and Preventive Medicine, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krak&#xf3;w, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Becker</LastName><ForeName>Roland</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, University Hospital Brandenburg, Brandenburg Medical School, Brandenburg/Havel, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prill</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, University Hospital Brandenburg, Brandenburg Medical School, Brandenburg/Havel, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>JBI Center of Evidence Based Practice Germany, Brandenburg Medical School, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JBI Evid Implement</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101772772</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2691-3321</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">evidence-based health care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hip arthroplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">implementation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">movement restrictions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality improvement</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41885398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/XEB.0000000000000573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">02205615-990000000-00239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kunutsor SK, Barrett MC, Beswick AD, Judge A, Blom AW, Wylde V, et al. Risk factors for dislocation after primary total hip replacement: a systematic review and meta-analysis of 125 studies involving approximately five million hip replacements. Lancet Rheumatol 2019;1(2):e111&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnsley L, Barnsley L, Page R. Are hip precautions necessary post total hip arthroplasty? A systematic review. Geriatr Orthop Surg Rehabil 2015;6(3):230&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Der Weegen W, Kornuijt A, Das D. Do lifestyle restrictions and precautions prevent dislocation after total hip arthroplasty? A systematic review and meta-analysis of the literature. Clin Rehabil 2016;30(4):329&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reimert J, Lockwood KJ, Hau R, Taylor NF. Are hip movement precautions effective in preventing prosthesis dislocation post hip arthroplasty using a posterior surgical approach? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Disabil Rehabil 2022;44(12):2560&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith TO, Jepson P, Beswick A, Sands G, Drummond A, Davis ET, et al. Assistive devices, hip precautions, environmental modifications and training to prevent dislocation and improve function after hip arthroplasty. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2016;7(7):CD010815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crompton J, Osagie-Clouard L, Patel A. Do hip precautions after posterior-approach total hip arthroplasty affect dislocation rates? A systematic review of 7 studies with 6,900 patients. Acta Orthop 2020;91(6):687&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsaleem MK, Alkhars AM, Alalwan HA, Almutairi A, Alonayzan A, AlYeesh IA. Kinesiophobia post total hip arthroplasty: a retrospective study. Cureus 2021;13(6):e15991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown OS, Hu L, Demetriou C, Smith TO, Hing CB. The effects of kinesiophobia on outcome following total knee replacement: a systematic review. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg 2020;140(12):2057&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerra ML, Singh PJ, Taylor NF. Early mobilization of patients who have had a hip or knee joint replacement reduces length of stay in hospital: a systematic review. Clin Rehabil 2015;29(9):844&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konnyu KJ, Pinto D, Cao W, Aaron RK, Panagiotou OA, Bhuma MR, et al. Rehabilitation for total hip arthroplasty: a systematic review. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 2023;102(1): 11&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Martino A, Brunello M, Pederiva D, Schilardi F, Rossomando V, Cataldi P, et al. Fast track protocols and early rehabilitation after surgery in total hip arthroplasty: a narrative review. Clin Pract 2023;13(3):569&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scurlock-Evans L, Upton P, Upton D. Evidence-based practice in physiotherapy: a systematic review of barriers, enablers and interventions. Physiother 2014;100(3):208&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prill R, Mouton C, Klugorov&#xe1; J, Kr&#xf3;likowska A, Karlsson J, Becker R. Implementation of evidence-based medicine in everyday clinical practice. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 2023;31(8):3034&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porritt K, McArthur A, Lockwood C, Munn Z. JBI's approach to evidence implementation: a 7-phase process model to support and guide getting evidence into practice. JBI Evid Implement 2023;21(1):3&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogrinc G, Mooney SE, Estrada C, Foster T, Goldmann D, Hall LW, et al. The SQUIRE (Standards for QUality Improvement Reporting Excellence) guidelines for quality improvement reporting: explanation and elaboration. Qual Saf Health Care 2008;17(Suppl_1):i13&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinnock H, Barwick M, Carpenter CR, Eldridge S, Grandes G, Griffiths CJ, et al. Standards for Reporting Implementation Studies (StaRI) statement. BMJ 2017;356:i6795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan Z, Lockwood C, Munn Z, Aromataris E. The updated Joanna Briggs Institute Model of Evidence-Based Healthcare. Int J Evid-Based Healthc 2019;17(1):58&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lizarondo L. JBI Best Practice Evidence Summary. Total hip replacement: movement precautions. JBI Best Practice. 2021; JBI-ES-1064-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowie J, Nicoll A, Dimova ED, Campbell P, Duncan EA. The barriers and facilitators influencing the sustainability of hospital-based interventions: a systematic review. BMC Health Serv Res 2020;20(1):588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lennox L, Maher L, Reed J. Navigating the sustainability landscape: a systematic review of sustainability approaches in health care. Implement Sci 2018;13(1):27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zurynski Y, Ludlow K, Testa L, Augustsson H, Herkes-Deane J, Hutchinson K, et al. Built to last? Barriers and facilitators of health care program sustainability: a systematic integrative review. Implement Sci 2023;18(1):62.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>