<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41846269</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1464-5165</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Disability and rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Disabil Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Perspectives of Japanese physical therapists on the use of virtual reality in stroke rehabilitation: a mixed-methods study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>16</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-16</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/09638288.2026.2638656</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Virtual reality (VR) provides engaging and motivating environments that may enhance motor recovery and patient engagement in stroke rehabilitation. However, clinical adoption remains limited in Japan. This study explored Japanese physical therapists' perspectives on VR use and identified factors influencing adoption.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A sequential explanatory mixed-methods design was used. In Phase 1, 141 physical therapists completed a survey adapted from the ADOPT-VR framework. Correlation and multiple regression analyses identified predictors of behavioral intention. In Phase 2, semi-structured interviews with 12 therapists provided in-depth insights, analyzed using thematic analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Compatibility (<i>r</i> = .456), perceived usefulness (<i>r</i> = .419), attitude (<i>r</i> = .415), time availability (<i>r</i> = .409), and technical support (<i>r</i> = .405) were moderately correlated with behavioral intention. Regression results indicated that compatibility, technical support, and social norms were significant predictors. Qualitative findings highlighted barriers such as limited training, equipment complexity, and unclear patient selection, while facilitators included peer modeling, hands-on learning, and leadership support.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Although attitudes toward VR are positive, adoption is constrained by contextual and organizational barriers. Clinically compatible implementation strategies, targeted training, and institutional support are needed to enhance VR integration in stroke rehabilitation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Minjoon</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1511-5604</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, School of Health and Environmental Science, College of Health Science, Korea University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Reiwa Rehabilitation Hospital, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Graduate School of Human Health Sciences, Tokyo Metropolitan University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thawisuk</LastName><ForeName>Chirathip</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7650-617X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Therapy, Faculty of Associated Medical Sciences, Chiang Mai University, Chiang Mai, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uetake</LastName><ForeName>Shunichi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Touto Rehabilitation College, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaneko</LastName><ForeName>Fuminari</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7125-0689</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Graduate School of Human Health Sciences, Tokyo Metropolitan University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Hyeong-Dong</ForeName><Initials>HD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Science and School of Health and Environmental Science, College of Health Science, Korea University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Disabil Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9207179</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0963-8288</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Virtual reality (VR) adoption in stroke rehabilitation is shaped by interacting individual, organizational, and contextual factors rather than therapist attitudes alone.Successful integration of VR in stroke rehabilitation requires organizational leadership, managerial support, and clear implementation frameworks to move beyond individual therapist enthusiasm.Hands-on, peer-led training programs and institutionally supported learning environments can enhance therapists&#x2019; competence, confidence, and sustained use of VR in clinical practice.Compatibility with existing clinical routines and infrastructure is a stronger determinant of VR adoption than perceived usefulness alone, emphasizing the need for context-sensitive implementation strategies.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">implementation science</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical therapists</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stroke rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">technology adoption</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">virtual reality</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41846269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638288.2026.2638656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>