<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41649654</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1750-0680</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Carbon balance and management</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Carbon Balance Manag</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Remote sensing analysis of forest fire impacts on ecosystem productivity, greenhouse gas emissions, and fire risk in Pakistan.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">54</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13021-026-00410-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study investigates the spatial variability of forest fire intensity, burn indices, ecosystem productivity, and Greenhouse Gas (GHG) emissions in Pakistan from 2001 to 2023. Using satellite-derived burn indices such as SAVI, LST, NMDI, LSWI, NBR, and MSAVI2, the study examines the relationship between forest fires and net primary productivity (NPP) across diverse ecological regions. The analysis reveals that northern Pakistan, particularly Khyber Pakhtunkhwa and Gilgit-Baltistan, experiences high fire intensity, resulting in significant reductions in NPP and increased emissions of COx, NOx, and CH&#x2084;. Central and southern Pakistan, including the arid regions of Balochistan and Sindh, exhibit lower fire intensity but remain vulnerable due to climate-driven dry conditions. The study also applies the &#x394;NPP/&#x394;Burn approach to evaluate how changes in burn indices correspond to shifts in NPP, revealing that small increases in fire intensity can lead to substantial ecosystem productivity loss. Additionally, a comparative analysis of Random Forest (RF) and XGBoost machine learning models for fire prediction found RF to be the more accurate model, achieving 88.0% accuracy and a 93.8% AUC score. These findings underscore the importance of developing region-specific fire management strategies to mitigate the ecological and environmental impacts of wildfires. The study highlights the critical need for improved fire prediction, early warning systems, and long-term monitoring of post-fire ecosystem recovery. By drawing comparisons with global research, this study contributes to understanding the broader implications of forest fires on carbon dynamics and ecosystem productivity, providing valuable insights for future fire management policies in Pakistan.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahzad</LastName><ForeName>Fahad</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Precision Forestry Key Laboratory of Beijing, Beijing Forestry University, Beijing, 100083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehmood</LastName><ForeName>Kaleem</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Silviculture and Conservation of Ministry of Education, Beijing Forestry University, Beijing, 100083, P. R. China. kaleemmehmood55@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Forest Science, University of Swat, Main Campus Charbagh 19120, Swat, Pakistan. kaleemmehmood55@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anees</LastName><ForeName>Shoaib Ahmad</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Forestry, The University of Agriculture, Dera Ismail Khan, 29050, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adnan</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Resources and Environmental Information System, Institute of Geographic Sciences and Natural Resources Research, CAS, Beijing, 100101, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haidar</LastName><ForeName>Ijlal</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Forest Science, University of Swat, Main Campus Charbagh 19120, Swat, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jabbarov</LastName><ForeName>Umarbek</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of "Accounting and business administration", Mamun University, Khiva, Uzbekistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yaxshimuratov</LastName><ForeName>Murodjon</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Urganch State University, Urgench, Uzbekistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Manuela</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Center for Research on Mathematics and its Applications, University of &#xc9;vora, &#xc9;vora, Portugal. mmo@uevora.pt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>343 UIDB/04674/2020 (CIMA)</GrantID><Agency>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o para a Ci&#xea;ncia e a Tecnologia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>H2020-MSCA-RISE-2020/101007950</GrantID><Agency>DecisionES - Decision Support for the Supply of Ecosystem Services under Global Change</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Carbon Balance Manag</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101271519</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1750-0680</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Burn indices</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ecosystem resilience</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Forest fire</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Greenhouse gas emissions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Remote sensing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval: This research did not involve human or animal subjects; therefore, formal ethical approval was not required. The study strictly adheres to general ethical principles, and the authors are committed to upholding the highest standards of ethical research conduct. Any potential conflicts of interest that could have influenced the ethical conduct of this research have been declared. Consent to participate: Informed consent was obtained from all participants involved in this study. Participants were provided with detailed information about the research objectives, procedures, potential risks, and benefits before agreeing to participate. They were assured that their participation was voluntary, and they had the right to withdraw from the study at any time without facing any consequences. All participants were informed about the confidentiality measures in place to protect their identity and personal information. Data collected during the study will be used solely for research purposes and will be securely stored. This study was conducted in accordance with ethical standards and guidelines, and participants were encouraged to ask questions and seek clarification at any stage of the research process. If you have any further questions or concerns regarding the consent process, please contact fahadshahzadbjfu@gmail.com. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41649654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12973728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13021-026-00410-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13021-026-00410-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abatzoglou JT, Williams AP. Impact of anthropogenic climate change on wildfire across Western US forests. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2016;113(42):11770&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1607171113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5081637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27791053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aizari AR, Al-Masnay YA, Aydda A, Zhang J, Ullah K, Islam ARMT, Habib T, Kaku DU, Nizeyimana JC, Al-Shaibah B. Assessment analysis of flood susceptibility in tropical desert area: a case study of Yemen. Remote Sens. 2022;14(16):4050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs14164050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aizari AR, Alzahrani H, Althuwaynee OF, Al-Masnay YA, Ullah K, Park H-J, et al. Uncertainty reduction in flood susceptibility mapping using Random Forest and extreme Gradient Boosting algorithms in two Tropical Desert cities, Shibam and Marib, Yemen. Remote Sens. 2024;16(2):336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs16020336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Masnay YA, Al-Areeq NM, Ullah K, Al-Aizari AR, Rahman M, Wang C, et al. Estimate earth fissure hazard based on machine learning in the Qa&#x2019;Jahran Basin, Yemen. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):21936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-26526-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9763334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36536056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali J, Haoran W, Mehmood K, Hussain W, Iftikhar F, Shahzad F, et al. Remote sensing and integration of machine learning algorithms for above-ground biomass estimation in <i>Larix principis-rupprechtii</i> Mayr plantations: a case study using Sentinel-2 and Landsat-9 data in northern China. Frontiers in Environmental Science. 2025;13:1577298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenvs.2025.1577298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amiro BD, Todd JB, Wotton BM, Logan KA, Flannigan MD, Stocks BJ, et al. Direct carbon emissions from Canadian forest fires, 1959&#x2013;1999. Can J For Res. 2001;31(3):512&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/x00-197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anees SA, Mehmood K, Luo M, Abuelgasim A, Pan S, Shahzad F, Muhammad S, Khan WR. Advancing forest fire burn severity and vegetation recovery assessments using remote sensing and machine learning approaches. Ecol Inf. 2025;92. 10.1016/j.ecoinf.2025.103446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anees SA, Mehmood K, Khan WR, Shahzad F, Zhran M, Ayub R, et al. Spatiotemporal dynamics of vegetation cover: integrative machine learning analysis of multispectral imagery and environmental predictors. Earth Sci Inform. 2025;18(1):1&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12145-024-01673-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Tameemi N, Xuexia Z, Shahzad F, Mehmood K, Linying X, Zhou J. From Trends to Drivers: Vegetation Degradation and Land-Use Change in Babil and Al-Qadisiyah, Iraq (2000&#x2013;2023). Remote Sens. 2025. 10.3390/rs17193343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs17193343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Tameemi N, Xuexia Z, Shahzad F, Mehmood K, Zhou J. Enhancing desertification risk mapping with entropy-based weighting and machine learning: Insights from Iraq. J Environ Manage. 2025. 10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.127976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.127976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41270480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balch JK, Bradley BA, Abatzoglou JT, Nagy C, Fusco R, Mahood AL. Human-started wildfires expand the fire niche across the United States. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2017. 10.1073/pnas.1617394114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1617394114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5358354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28242690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belgiu M, Dr&#x103;gu&#x163; L. Random forest in remote sensing: a review of applications and future directions. ISPRS J Photogramm Remote Sens. 2016;114:24&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2016.01.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowman DMJS, Kolden CA, Abatzoglou JT, Johnston FH, van der Werf GR, Flannigan M. Vegetation fires in the Anthropocene. Nature Reviews Earth &amp; Environment. 2020;1(10):500&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43017-020-0085-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chai Y, Miao C, AghaKouchak A, Pokhrel Y, Fu Y, Li X, Ji J, Zhang Q, Pe&#xf1;uelas J. (2025). Flash droughts exacerbate global vegetation loss and delay recovery. Nat Commun.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12804894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41354731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T, Guestrin C. Xgboost: A scalable tree boosting system. Proceedings of the 22nd Acm Sigkdd International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining. 2016;785&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Wang Y, Zhou D, Luo X. Regression-based predictive modeling of summer urban microclimate: quantifying contributions from urban design and urban heat emissions. Urban Clim. 2025;62:102550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.uclim.2025.102550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Zheng W, Li W, Huang Y. Large group activity security risk assessment and risk early warning based on random forest algorithm. Pattern Recognit Lett. 2021;144:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.patrec.2021.01.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuvieco E, Giglio L, Justice C. Global characterization of fire activity: toward defining fire regimes from Earth observation data. Glob Change Biol. 2008;14(7):1488&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2486.2008.01585.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuvieco E, Ventura G, Mart&#xed;n MP, G&#xf3;mez I. Assessment of multitemporal compositing techniques of MODIS and AVHRR images for burned land mapping. Remote Sens Environ. 2005. 10.1016/j.rse.2004.11.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2004.11.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;olak E, Sunar F. The importance of ground-truth and crowdsourcing data for the statistical and spatial analyses of the NASA FIRMS active fires in the Mediterranean Turkish forests. Remote Sens Applications: Soc Environ. 2020. 10.1016/j.rsase.2020.100327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui T, Wang Y, Sun R, Qiao C, Fan W, Jiang G, Hao L, Zhang L. Estimating vegetation primary production in the Heihe River Basin of China with multi-source and multi-scale data. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(4). 10.1371/journal.pone.0153971}</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4835106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27088356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cvetkovi&#x107; VM, Renner R, Aleksova B, Luki&#x107; T. Geospatial and temporal patterns of natural and man-made (technological) disasters (1900&#x2013;2024): insights from different socio-economic and demographic perspectives. Appl Sci. 2024;14(18):8129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app14188129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doorn M, Towprayoon S, Vieira S, Irving W, Palmer C, Pipatti R. 2006 IPCC guidelines for national greenhouse gas inventories: volume 5&#x2014;waste. In The National Greenhouse Gas Inventories Programme, The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change.&#xa0;2006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duff TJ, Tolhurst KG. Operational wildfire suppression modelling: a review evaluating development, state of the art and future directions. Int J Wildland Fire. 2015;24(6):735&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/WF15018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duro DC, Franklin SE, Dub&#xe9; MG. Multi-scale object-based image analysis and feature selection of multi-sensor Earth observation imagery using random forests. Int J Remote Sens. 2012;33(14):4502&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431161.2011.649864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dye AW, Reilly MJ, McEvoy A, Lemons R, Riley KL, Kim JB, et al. Simulated future shifts in wildfire regimes in moist forests of Pacific Northwest, USA. J Geophys Res Biogeosci. 2024. 10.1029/2023JG007722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2023JG007722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falge E, Baldocchi D, Tenhunen J, Aubinet M, Bakwin P, Berbigier P, et al. Seasonality of ecosystem respiration and gross primary production as derived from FLUXNET measurements. Agric For Meteorol. 2002;113(1&#x2013;4):53&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0168-1923(02)00102-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan J, Lu X, Cai G, Lou Z, Wen J. Multi-feature driver variable fusion downscaling TROPOMI solar-induced chlorophyll fluorescence approach. Agronomy. 2025;15(1):133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy15010133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francos M, Colino-Prieto F, S&#xe1;nchez-Garc&#xed;a C. How mediterranean ecosystem deals with wildfire impact on soil ecosystem services and functions: a review. Land. 2024;13(4):407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/land13040407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Llamas P, Su&#xe1;rez-Seoane S, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Guisuraga JM, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Garc&#xed;a V, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Manso A, Quintano C, et al. Evaluation and comparison of Landsat 8, Sentinel-2 and Deimos-1 remote sensing indices for assessing burn severity in Mediterranean fire-prone ecosystems. Int J Appl Earth Obs Geoinf. 2019. 10.1016/j.jag.2019.04.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jag.2019.04.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitas I, Mitri G, Veraverbeke S, Polychronaki A. Advances in remote sensing of post-fire vegetation recovery monitoring&#x2014;a review. Remote Sens Biomass-Principles Appl. 2012;1:334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grieve SWD, Chen S-A, Singer MB, Michaelides K. GDBM: a database of global drainage basin morphology. PLoS One. 2025;20(4):e0320771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0320771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11975112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40193489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo F, Zhang L, Jin S, Tigabu M, Su Z, Wang W. Modeling anthropogenic fire occurrence in the boreal forest of China using logistic regression and random forests. Forests. 2016;7(11):250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f7110250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guria R, Mishra M, Mohanta S, Paul S. Forest fire probability zonation using dNBR and machine learning models: a case study at the Similipal Biosphere Reserve (SBR), Odisha, India. Environ Sci Pollut Res. 2025. 10.1007/s11356-025-35976-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-025-35976-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39885073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen MC, Potapov PV, Moore R, Hancher M, Turubanova SA, Tyukavina A, Thau D, Stehman SV, Goetz SJ, Loveland TR. High-resolution global maps of 21st-century forest cover change. Science. 2013;342(6160):850&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1244693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24233722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X, Waller LA, Lyapustin A, Wang Y, Liu Y. Improving satellite-driven PM2. 5 models with moderate resolution imaging spectroradiometer fire counts in the southeastern US. J Geophys Res Atmos. 2014;119(19):11&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/2014JD021920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5619254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28967648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Sun C, Nguyen MT, Wu Q, He C, Yang H, et al. Spatio-temporal dynamics of terrestrial net ecosystem productivity in the ASEAN from 2001 to 2020 based on remote sensing and improved CASA model. Ecol Indic. 2023. 10.1016/j.ecolind.2023.110920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2023.110920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain K, Badshah T, Mehmood K, Shahzad F, Anees SA, Khan WR, et al. Comparative analysis of sensors and classification algorithms for land cover classification in Islamabad, Pakistan. Earth Sci Inform. 2025;18(2):1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12145-025-01720-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain K, Mehmood K, Yujun S, Badshah T, Anees SA, Shahzad F, Nooruddin, Ali J, Bilal M. Analysing LULC transformations using remote sensing data: insights from a multilayer perceptron neural network approach. Ann GIS. 2024;1&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC). IPCC - Task Force on National Greenhouse Gas Inventories. Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC); 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irifi H, Tribak A, Benaddi A. The post-fire forest landscape dynamics in Mediterranean environment: the case of the Mesguina forest. Western High Atlas Mountains (Morocco). Territoires, Environnement et D&#xe9;veloppement (TED). 2025;4(1):83&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain P, Coogan SCP, Subramanian SG, Crowley M, Taylor S, Flannigan MD. A review of machine learning applications in wildfire science and management. Environ Rev. 2020;28(4):478&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/er-2020-0019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia J, Zheng X, Wang Y, Chen Y, Karjalainen M, Dong S, et al. The effect of artificial intelligence evolving on hyperspectral imagery with different signal-to-noise ratio, spectral and spatial resolutions. Remote Sens Environ. 2024;311:114291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2024.114291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing X, Zhang D, Li X, Zhang W, Zhang Z. Prediction of forest fire occurrence in Southwestern China. Forests. 2023;14(9):1797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f14091797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jolly WM, Cochrane MA, Freeborn PH, Holden ZA, Brown TJ, Williamson GJ, et al. Climate-induced variations in global wildfire danger from 1979 to 2013. Nat Commun. 2015;6(1):7537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms8537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4803474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26172867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kattel DB, Yao T, Ullah K, Rana AS. Seasonal near-surface air temperature dependence on elevation and geographical coordinates for Pakistan. Theor Appl Climatol. 2019;138:1591&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00704-019-02899-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keeley JE. Fire intensity, fire severity and burn severity: A brief review and suggested usage. Int J Wildland Fire. 2009. 10.1071/WF07049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/WF07049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutsias N, Balatsos P, Kalabokidis K. Fire occurrence zones: kernel density estimation of historical wildfire ignitions at the National level, Greece. J Maps. 2014;10(4):630&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17445647.2014.908750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurbanov E, Vorobev O, Lezhnin S, Sha J, Wang J, Li X, et al. Remote sensing of forest burnt area, burn severity, and post-fire recovery: a review. Remote Sens. 2022. 10.3390/rs14194714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs14194714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuter N, Yenilmez F, Kuter S. Forest fire risk mapping by kernel density estimation. Croatian J For Eng. 2011;32(2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Z, Bao S, Zhang W, Yan H, Duan B, Wang H. Super-resolution reconstruction of SMOS sea surface salinity from multivariate satellite observations based on deep learning. IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing. 2025. 10.1109/jstars.2025.3602684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jstars.2025.3602684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Huang D, Chen C, Liu Y, Wang J, Shao Y, et al. Prediction of forest-fire occurrence in Eastern China utilizing deep learning and spatial analysis. Forests. 2024;15(9):1672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f15091672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Zhang H, Yang G, Ding Y, Zhao J. Post-fire vegetation succession and surface energy fluxes derived from remote sensing. Remote Sens. 2018;10(7):1000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs10071000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieth H. Modeling the primary productivity of the world. Prim Productivity Biosphere. 1975;237&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Chen JM, Cihlar J, Chen W. Net primary productivity distribution in the BOREAS region from a process model using satellite and surface data. J Geophys Res Atmos. 1999;104(D22):27735&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/1999JD900768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Wang Y, Guo H, Lu Y, Xu Y, Sun Y, et al. Spatial and temporal patterns and driving factors of forest fires based on an optimal parameter-based geographic detector in the Panxi region, Southwest China. Fire Ecol. 2024;20(1):27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42408-024-00257-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu D. The potential and challenge of remote sensing-based biomass estimation. Int J Remote Sens. 2006;27(7):1297&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431160500486732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo W, Qiu H, Wei Y, Huangfu W, Yang D. A proposed method for landslide detection based on transfer learning and graph neural network. Geosci Front. 2025. 10.1016/j.gsf.2025.102171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gsf.2025.102171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancino G, Ferrara A, Padula A, Nol&#xe8; A. Cross-comparison between Landsat 8 (OLI) and Landsat 7 (ETM+) derived vegetation indices in a Mediterranean environment. Remote Sens. 2020. 10.3390/rs12020291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs12020291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannan A, Feng Z, Ahmad A, Beckline M, Saeed S, Liu J, Shah S, Amir M, Ammara U, Ullah T. CO2 emission trends and risk zone mapping of forest fires in subtropical and moist temperate forests of Pakistan. Appl Ecol Environ Res. 2017;17(2):2983&#x2013;3002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15666/aeer/1702_29833002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsushita B, Xu M, Chen J, Kameyama S, Tamura M. Estimation of regional net primary productivity (NPP) using a process-based ecosystem model: how important is the accuracy of climate data? Ecol Model. 2004;178(3&#x2013;4):371&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2004.03.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire AD, Melillo JM, Kicklighter DW, Joyce LA. Equilibrium responses of soil carbon to climate change: empirical and process-based estimates. J Biogeogr. 1995. 10.2307/2845980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2845980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehmood K, Anees SA, Luo M, Akram M, Zubair M, Khan KA, et al. Assessing Chilgoza Pine (<i>Pinus gerardiana</i>) forest fire severity: remote sensing analysis, correlations, and predictive modeling for enhanced management strategies. Trees, Forests and People. 2024. 10.1016/j.tfp.2024.100521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tfp.2024.100521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehmood K, Anees SA, Muhammad S, Shahzad F, Liu Q, Khan WR, et al. Machine learning and spatio temporal analysis for assessing ecological impacts of the billion tree afforestation project. Ecol Evol. 2025;15(2):e70736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ece3.70736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11839268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39975709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehmood K, Anees SA, Shahzad F, Muhammad S, Liu Q, Khan WR, et al. Exploring vegetation health in Southern Thailand under climate stress from temperature and water impacts between 2000 and 2023. Sci Rep. 2025. 10.1038/s41598-025-16293-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-16293-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12365072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40830191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinshausen M, Meinshausen N, Hare W, Raper SCB, Frieler K, Knutti R, et al. Greenhouse-gas emission targets for limiting global warming to 2&#xb0;C. Nature. 2009. 10.1038/nature08017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature08017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19407799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik SU, Ashraf MI, Goheer MA. Spatio-Temporal Dynamics of Greenhouse Gas Emissions from Soil in Forest Ecosystems of Pakistan. Pak J Bot. 2023;55(4). 10.30848/PJB2023-4(20).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moshiri S, Habibzadeh N, Valizadeh Kamran K, Feizizadeh B. A novel optimized spectral-based data driven approach for ecoregion burned scar detection. Int J Remote Sens. 2025;46(3):1305&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431161.2024.2429783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad S, Nizami SM, Jiang Q, Mehmood K, Hussain M, Anees SA, et al. Machine learning-based forest fire vulnerability assessment in subtropical chir pine forests of Pakistan. Fire Ecol. 2025. 10.1186/s42408-025-00408-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42408-025-00408-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myneni RB, Williams DL. On the relationship between FAPAR and NDVI. Remote Sens Environ. 1994. 10.1016/0034-4257(94)90016-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0034-4257(94)90016-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nafees M, Rashid W, Sultan H, Khan NH, Khurshid M, Ali W, et al. Occurrence, probable causes, and management of forest wildfires in the Northern Highlands of Pakistan. Environ Challenges. 2024. 10.1016/j.envc.2024.100930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envc.2024.100930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nery LM, Gomes G, de Moura AT, dos Santos AP, Toniolo BP, da Cunha e Silva DC. Adaptation of SAVI to estimate the leaf area index considering different land covers in a Brazilian Atlantic forest area. Model Earth Syst Environ. 2025;11(2):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40808-025-02300-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira SLJ, Pereira JMC, Carreiras JMB. Fire frequency analysis in Portugal (1975&#x2013;2005), using Landsat-based burnt area maps. Int J Wildland Fire. 2011;21(1):48&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/WF10131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker BM, Lewis T, Srivastava SK. Estimation and evaluation of multi-decadal fire severity patterns using Landsat sensors. Remote Sens Environ. 2015;170:340&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2015.09.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng S, Bao N, Gu N, Qian H, Han Z, Zhou B, et al. Enhanced assessment of chlorophyll-a and total nitrogen dynamics using unmanned aerial vehicle-based model and hyperspectral imagery in coastal wetland water. Environ Technol Innov. 2025. 10.1016/j.eti.2025.104521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eti.2025.104521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Cabello F, Cerd&#xe0; A, De La Riva J, Echeverr&#xed;a MT, Garc&#xed;a-Mart&#xed;n A, Ibarra P, et al. Micro-scale post-fire surface cover changes monitored using high spatial resolution photography in a semiarid environment: a useful tool in the study of post-fire soil erosion processes. J Arid Environ. 2012;76:88&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaridenv.2011.08.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potter CS, Randerson JT, Field CB, Matson PA, Vitousek PM, Mooney HA, et al. Terrestrial ecosystem production: a process model based on global satellite and surface data. Glob Biogeochem Cycles. 1993;7(4):811&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/93GB02725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Propastin P, Kappas M. Modeling net ecosystem exchange for grassland in central Kazakhstan by combining remote sensing and field data. Remote Sens. 2009;1(3):159&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs1030159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qasim M, Khlaid S, Shams DF. Spatiotemporal variations and trends in minimum and maximum temperatures of Pakistan. J Appl Environ Biol Sci. 2014;4(8S):85&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AFS, Santos L, Randerson JT, Uribe MR, Alencar AAC, Macedo MN, et al. The time since land-use transition drives changes in fire activity in the Amazon-Cerrado region. Commun Earth Environ. 2024. 10.1038/s43247-024-01248-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43247-024-01248-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy DP, Boschetti L, Trigg SN. Remote sensing of fire severity: assessing the performance of the normalized burn ratio. IEEE Geosci Remote Sens Lett. 2006. 10.1109/LGRS.2005.858485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LGRS.2005.858485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruimy A, Saugier B, Dedieu G. Methodology for the estimation of terrestrial net primary production from remotely sensed data. J Geophys Res Atmos. 1994;99(D3):5263&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/93JD03221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Running SW, Hunt ER Jr. Generalization of a forest ecosystem process model for other biomes, BIOME-BCG, and an application for global-scale models. 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Running SW, Zhao M. Daily GPP and annual NPP (MOD17A2/A3) products NASA Earth Observing System MODIS land algorithm. MOD17 User&#x2019;s Guide, 2015, 1&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed S, Ashraf MI, Ahmad A, Rahman Z. The Bela forest ecosystem of district Jhelum, a potential carbon sink. Pak J Bot. 2016;48(1):121&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sannigrahi S, Pilla F, Basu B, Basu AS, Sarkar K, Chakraborti S, et al. Examining the effects of forest fire on terrestrial carbon emission and ecosystem production in India using remote sensing approaches. Sci Total Environ. 2020. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2020.138331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2020.138331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32302833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SEINO H, UCHIJIMA Z. Agroclimatic evaluation of net primary productivity of natural vegetation (2) assessment of total net primary production in Japan. J Agric Meteorol. 1985;41(2):139&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2480/agrmet.41.139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahzad F, Mehmood K, Anees SA, Adnan M, Muhammad S, Haidar I, et al. Advancing forest fire prediction: a multi-layer stacking ensemble model approach. Earth Sci Inform. 2025;18(3):270. 10.1007/s12145-025-01782-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12145-025-01782-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahzad F, Mehmood K, Hussain K, Haidar I, Anees SA, Muhammad S, et al. Comparing machine learning algorithms to predict vegetation fire detections in Pakistan. Fire Ecol. 2024;20(1):57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42408-024-00289-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahzad F, Mehmood K, Anees SA, Adnan M, Hussain K, Khan WR, Shah M, Jamjareegulgarn P, Oliveira M, Borges JG. (2025). Understanding green house gases emission dynamics from forest fires in Thailand using predictive models. Glob Planet Change, 105236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao Y, Feng Z, Cao M, Wang W, Sun L, Yang X, et al. An ensemble model for forest fire occurrence mapping in China. Forests. 2023;14(4):704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f14040704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh RD, Gumber S, Sundriyal RC, Ram J, Singh SP. Chir pine forest and pre-monsoon drought determine spatial, and temporal patterns of forest fires in Uttarakhand Himalaya. Trop Ecol. 2024. 10.1007/s42965-023-00306-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42965-023-00306-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10240464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37362779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soomro SEH, Boota MW, Guo J, Li Y, Qin H, Meahrayen MA, et al. Drought management for long-term water sustainability and resilience. Mar Freshw Res. 2025. 10.1071/MF24210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/MF24210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soomro S, Boota MW, Soomro N, Soomro G, Guo J, Hu C, et al. Harnessing public sentiment discourse for early drought detection and water crisis response for strategic water management and resilient policy planning. Sci Total Environ. 2025. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2025.179862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2025.179862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40513443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soomro S, Wei H, Boota MW, Soomro N, Faisal M, Nazli S, et al. River basin urban flood resilience: a multi-dimensional framework for risk mitigation to adaptive management and ecosystem protection under changing climate. Ecol Inform. 2025. 10.1016/j.ecoinf.2025.103412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoinf.2025.103412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun L, Feng Z, Shao Y, Wang L, Su J, Ma T, et al. The development of a set of novel low cost and data processing-free measuring instruments for tree diameter at breast height and tree position. Forests. 2023;14(5):891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f14050891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syifa M, Panahi M, Lee C-W. Mapping of post-wildfire burned area using a hybrid algorithm and satellite data: the case of the camp fire wildfire in California, USA. Remote Sens. 2020;12(4):623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs12040623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teki&#x107; I, Fuerst-Bjeli&#x161; B, Durbe&#x161;i&#x107; A, Radeljak Kaufmann P, Cvitanovi&#x107; M. Landscape Change and Fire Risk in the Croatian Dinaric Karst: Looking Back and Moving Forward. In: Environmental Histories of the Dinaric Karst. Springer; 2024. p. 109&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Der Werf Werf GR, Randerson JT, Giglio L, Van Leeuwen Leeuwen TT, Chen Y, Rogers BM, et al. Global fire emissions estimates during 1997&#x2013;2016. Earth Syst Sci Data. 2017;9(2):697&#x2013;720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/essd-9-697-2017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasconcelos S, Fearnside PM, Gra&#xe7;a P, Nogueira EM, Oliveira L, Figueiredo EO. Forest fires in southwestern Brazilian Amazonia: estimates of area and potential carbon emissions. For Ecol Manage. 2013. 10.1016/j.foreco.2012.11.044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foreco.2012.11.044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Zhang X. Investigation of wildfire impacts on land surface phenology from MODIS time series in the Western US forests. ISPRS J Photogramm Remote Sens. 2020;159:281&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2019.11.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang N, Wu Q, Gui Y, Hu Q, Li W. Cross-modal segmentation network for Winter Wheat mapping in complex terrain using remote-sensing multi-temporal images and DEM data. Remote Sens. 2024;16(10):1775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs16101775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao F, Liu Q, Xu Y. Estimation of terrestrial net primary productivity in the Yellow River Basin of China using light use efficiency model. Sustainability. 2022. 10.3390/su14127399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su14127399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X, Akiyama H, Yagi K, Akimoto H. Global estimations of the inventory and mitigation potential of methane emissions from rice cultivation conducted using the 2006 Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change guidelines. Glob Biogeochem Cycles. 2009. 10.1029/2008GB003299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2008GB003299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Wang J, Chen Y, Huang S, Liang B. Spatiotemporal variation and prediction of NPP in Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region by coupling PLUS and CASA models. Ecol Informatics. 2024;81:102620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoinf.2024.102620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu WQ, Pan YZ, Zhang JS. Remote sensing estimation of net primary productivity of terrestrial vegetation in China. Plant Ecol. 2007;31(3):413&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu W-Q, Pan Y-Z, Zhang J-S. Estimation of net primary productivity of Chinese terrestrial vegetation based on remote sensing. Chin J Plant Ecol. 2007;31(3):413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17521/cjpe.2007.0050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>