<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41912525</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Selective solar wax refining with nanoscale zero-valent iron.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-71010-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Wax refining transforms raw wax into high-grade product by increasing the uniformity of molecular carbon-chain length and removing impurities. Conventional thermochemical approaches face inherent limitations in effectively reducing carbon-chain dispersity (&#xd0;) due to their non-selective C-C scission in feedstock waxes. This mechanistic constraint consequently necessitates energy-intensive downstream processing involving fractional distillation and purification. Here, we demonstrate a selective solar wax refining method that upgrades the raw polyethylene wax by significantly reducing its &#xd0; from 2.5 to 2.0 in one step with a reaction selectivity beyond 80%, enabled by nanoscale zero-valent iron (nZVI) catalyst and sunlight. At the nZVI-wax interface, photons activate C-H bonds to provide hydrogen atoms, while localized hot spots mediate C-C bonds cleavage via hydrogen atom transfer initiated hydrocracking and concurrent evaporative desorption of fragmented wax product, thereby achieving precise control over carbon-chain dispersity. This work exemplifies the potential in precise and efficient solar refinery.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Yifei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Green Pesticide, Engineering Research Center of Photoenergy Utilization for Pollution Control and Carbon Reduction, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry, Central China Normal University, Wuhan, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mao</LastName><ForeName>Chengliang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6577-6959</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Green Papermaking and Resource Recycling, Shanghai Engineering Research Center of Solid Waste Treatment and Resource Recovery, School of Environmental Science and Engineering, National observation and Research Station of Erhai Lake Ecosystem in Yunnan, Yunnan Dali Research Institute, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, PR China. chengliang.mao@sjtu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zou</LastName><ForeName>Yunjie</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-1047-1041</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Pollution Control and Resource Reuse, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yuqing</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Green Pesticide, Engineering Research Center of Photoenergy Utilization for Pollution Control and Carbon Reduction, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry, Central China Normal University, Wuhan, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Di</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Energy and Materials, Shanghai Polytechnic University, Shanghai, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Junzhou</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Green Papermaking and Resource Recycling, Shanghai Engineering Research Center of Solid Waste Treatment and Resource Recovery, School of Environmental Science and Engineering, National observation and Research Station of Erhai Lake Ecosystem in Yunnan, Yunnan Dali Research Institute, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pei</LastName><ForeName>Haopeng</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Green Papermaking and Resource Recycling, Shanghai Engineering Research Center of Solid Waste Treatment and Resource Recovery, School of Environmental Science and Engineering, National observation and Research Station of Erhai Lake Ecosystem in Yunnan, Yunnan Dali Research Institute, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Yanbiao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Hydraulics and Mountain River Engineering, College of Architecture and Environment, Sichuan University, Chengdu, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zipeng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Green Pesticide, Engineering Research Center of Photoenergy Utilization for Pollution Control and Carbon Reduction, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry, Central China Normal University, Wuhan, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Wendong</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5125-4834</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Green Papermaking and Resource Recycling, Shanghai Engineering Research Center of Solid Waste Treatment and Resource Recovery, School of Environmental Science and Engineering, National observation and Research Station of Erhai Lake Ecosystem in Yunnan, Yunnan Dali Research Institute, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ai</LastName><ForeName>Zhihui</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Green Pesticide, Engineering Research Center of Photoenergy Utilization for Pollution Control and Carbon Reduction, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry, Central China Normal University, Wuhan, PR China. jennifer.ai@ccnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Lizhi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6842-9167</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Green Papermaking and Resource Recycling, Shanghai Engineering Research Center of Solid Waste Treatment and Resource Recovery, School of Environmental Science and Engineering, National observation and Research Station of Erhai Lake Ecosystem in Yunnan, Yunnan Dali Research Institute, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, PR China. zhanglizhi@sjtu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41912525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-71010-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-71010-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ernst, J. K., Uwe, H. W. Natural and Synthetic Waxes: Origin, Production, Technology and Applications. Ch. 17 (Wiley-VCH, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Z. et al. Chemical upcycling of polyethylene, polypropylene, and mixtures to high-value surfactants. Science 381, 666&#x2013;671 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munyaneza, N. E. et al. Chain-length-controllable upcycling of polyolefins to sulfate detergents. Nat. Sustain. 7, 1681&#x2013;1690 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, X. et al. Efficient and selective degradation of polyethylenes into liquid fuels and waxes under mild conditions. Sci. Adv. 2, e1501591 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang, X. L. et al. Approaches for the synthesis of high-melting waxes: a review. Acta Phys.-Chim. Sin. 38, 2204045 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcnutt, J. &amp; He, Q. Development of biolubricants from vegetable oils via chemical modification. J. Ind. Eng. Chem. 26, 1&#x2013;12 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed, N. H. et al. Separation of paraffin wax using solvent fractionation. Pet. Sci. Technol. 26, 562&#x2013;574 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klippel, M. S. &amp; Martins, M. F. Physicochemical assessment of waxy products directly recovered from plastic waste pyrolysis: Review and synthesis of characterization techniques. Polym. Degrad. Stab. 204, 110090 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maziero, E. V. et al. Fractionation of polyethylene wax by pilot-scale molecular distillation: new insights on process development. Chem. Eng. Res. Des. 152, 201&#x2013;215 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, C. et al. Catalytic cracking of Fischer-Tropsch wax on different zeolite catalysts. Catalysts 13, 1223 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arandes, J. M. et al. Effect of catalyst properties on the cracking of polypropylene pyrolysis waxes under FCC conditions. Catal. Today 133, 413&#x2013;419 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sotoudehnia, F. et al. Catalytic upgrading of pyrolysis wax oil obtained from waxed corrugated cardboard using zeolite Y catalyst. Energy Fuels 35, 9450&#x2013;9461 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez, E. et al. Effect of the FCC equilibrium catalyst properties and of the cracking temperature on the production of fuel from HDPe pyrolysis waxes. Energy Fuels 33, 5191&#x2013;5199 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y. et al. Efficient methane oxidation to formaldehyde via photon-phonon cascade catalysis. Nat. Sustain. 7, 1171&#x2013;1181 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao, C. et al. Beyond the thermal equilibrium limit of ammonia synthesis with dual temperature zone catalyst powered by solar light. Chem 5, 2702&#x2013;2717 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao, Y. et al. Photothermal recycling of waste polyolefin plastics into liquid fuels with high selectivity under solvent-free conditions. Nat. Commun. 14, 4242 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C. et al. Selective oxidation of methane to C<sub>2+</sub> products over Au-CeO<sub>2</sub> by photon-phonon co-driven catalysis. Nat. Commun. 15, 7535 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H. et al. Correction: from photocatalysis to photon-phonon co-driven catalysis for methanol reforming to hydrogen and valuable by-products. Chem. Soc. Rev. 54, 2188&#x2013;2207 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An, X. et al. Sodium-directed photon-induced assembly strategy for preparing multisite catalysts with high atomic utilization efficiency. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 145, 1759&#x2013;1768 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, J. et al. Methane oxidation to ethanol by a molecular junction photocatalyst. Nature 639, 368&#x2013;374 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, P. et al. Photocatalytic ethylene production by oxidative dehydrogenation of ethane with dioxygen on ZnO-supported PdZn intermetallic nanoparticles. Nat. Commun. 15, 789 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brongersma, M. L., Halas, N. J. &amp; Nordlander, P. Plasmon-induced hot carrier science and technology. Nat. Nanotechnol. 10, 25&#x2013;34 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linic, S., Chavez, S. &amp; Elias, R. Flow and extraction of energy and charge carriers in hybrid plasmonic nanostructures. Nat. Mater. 20, 916&#x2013;924 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, R. et al. Ethylene production via photocatalytic dehydrogenation of ethane using LaMn<sub>1-x</sub>Cu<sub>x</sub>O<sub>3</sub>. Nat. Energy 9, 750&#x2013;760 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. et al. Engineered disorder in CO<sub>2</sub> photocatalysis. Nat. Commun. 13, 7205 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. et al. Selective liquid chemical production in waste polyolefin photorefinery by controlling reactive species. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 147, 5228&#x2013;5237 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mateo, D. et al. Fundamentals and applications of photo-thermal catalysis. Chem. Soc. Rev. 50, 2173&#x2013;2210 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, H. et al. Photothermal upcycling of waste polyvinyl chloride plastics. Environ. Sci. Technol. 58, 21861&#x2013;21870 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao, J. Q. et al. Sun-simulated-driven production of high-purity methanol from carbon dioxide. Nat. Commun. 16, 857 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, C. Y. et al. Size-dependent activity and selectivity of carbon dioxide photocatalytic reduction over platinum nanoparticles. Nat. Commun. 9, 1252 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, C. Y. et al. Boosting exciton dissociation and charge transfer in CsPbBr<sub>3</sub> QDs via ferrocene derivative ligation for CO<sub>2</sub> photoreduction. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 121, e2315956121 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. Photothermocatalytic wet reforming of waste plastics to Syngas. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 147, 9879&#x2013;9890 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, M. et al. Complete hydrogenolysis of mixed plastic wastes. Nat. Chem. Eng. 1, 376&#x2013;384 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, X. et al. Atomic-scale Pd on 2D titania sheets for selective oxidation of methane to methanol. ACS Catal 11, 14038&#x2013;14046 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, X. et al. Direct conversion of CO and H<sub>2</sub>O to hydrocarbons at atmospheric pressure using a TiO<sub>2&#x2212;x</sub>/Ni photothermal catalyst. Nat. Energy 9, 154&#x2013;162 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, R. et al. Catalytic oxidation of polystyrene to aromatic oxygenates over a graphitic carbon nitride catalyst. Nat. Commun. 13, 4809 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, B. et al. Synergistic ultraviolet and visible light photo-activation enables intensified low-temperature methanol synthesis over copper/zinc oxide/alumina. Nat. Commun. 11, 1615 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, T. H. et al. Unlocking the potential of the formate pathway in the photo-assisted Sabatier reaction. Nat. Catal. 3, 1034&#x2013;1043 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, M. et al. Kirkendall effect boosts phosphorylated nZVI for efficient heavy metal wastewater treatment. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 60, 17115&#x2013;17122 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, M. et al. Phosphate modification enables high efficiency and electron selectivity of nZVI toward Cr(VI) removal. Appl. Catal. B. 263, 118364 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao, M. et al. Silicate-confined hydrogen on nanoscale zerovalent iron for efficient defluorination reactions. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 147, 3402&#x2013;3411 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherepy, N. J., Liston, D. B., Lovejoy, J. A., Deng, H. &amp; Zhang, J. Z. Ultrafast studies of photoexcited electron dynamics in &#x3b3;-and &#x3b1;-Fe<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> semiconductor nanoparticles. J. Phys. Chem. B. 102, 770&#x2013;776 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakafuji, A., Murakami, Y. &amp; Shindo, D. Effect of diffraction condition on mean free path determination by EELS. Microscopy 50, 23&#x2013;28 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meijers, S. et al. FTIR study of the adsorption and transformation of allylbenzene over oxide catalysts. J. Chem. Soc., Faraday Trans. 91, 1861&#x2013;1869 (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, F. et al. Polyethylene upcycling to long-chain alkylaromatics by tandem hydrogenolysis/aromatization. Science 370, 437&#x2013;441 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christopher, P. et al. Visible-light-enhanced catalytic oxidation reactions on plasmonic silver nanostructures. Nat. Chem. 3, 467&#x2013;472 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Q. et al. Polyethylene hydrogenolysis by dilute RuPt alloy to achieve H<sub>2</sub>-pressure-independent low methane selectivity. Nat. Commun. 15, 10573 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagitova, E. A. et al. Regularity modes in Raman spectra of polyolefins: part II. Polyethylene and ethylene copolymers. Vib. Spectrosc. 84, 139&#x2013;145 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le, K. C., Henriksson, J. &amp; Bengtsson, E. Polarization effects in Raman spectroscopy of light- absorbing carbon. J. Raman Spectrosc. 52, 1115&#x2013;1122 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, Y. et al. Steam methane reforming using a regenerable antenna-reactor plasmonic photocatalyst. Nat. Catal. 7, 1339&#x2013;1349 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, L. et al. Light-driven methane dry reforming with single-atomic-site antenna-reactor plasmonic photocatalysts. Nat. Energy 5, 61&#x2013;70 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis, L. D. et al. Chemical and biological catalysis for plastics recycling and upcycling. Nat. Catal. 4, 539&#x2013;556 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janzen, E. G. &amp; Gerlock, J. L. Detection of gas phase free radicals by electron spin resonance spin trapping techniques. Nature 222, 867&#x2013;868 (1969).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo, Z., Sha, Y. &amp; Wang, R. A lost piece of the puzzle of the alkane cracking mechanism: a carbanion pathway on a solid base catalyst. RSC Adv. 14, 15071&#x2013;15084 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corma, A. V. &amp; Orchille&#xb4;s, A. V. Current views on the mechanism of catalytic cracking. Micropor. Mesopor. Mat. 35-36, 21&#x2013;30 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Y. et al. Selective Solar Wax Refining with Nanoscale Zero-Valent Iron. Figshare https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.31315522 (2026).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>