<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41867525</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Safety, Sedative, and Anxiolytic Evaluation of MECS Hard Capsules Using In Silico and In Vivo Approaches.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>15735</StartPage><EndPage>15764</EndPage><MedlinePgn>15735-15764</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.5c06824</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Insomnia and anxiety disorders have become increasingly prevalent in modern society. The formulation study of MECS hard capsules composed of the medicinal herbs <i>Mimosa pudica</i>, <i>Erythrina variegata</i>, <i>Cinnamomum iners</i>, and <i>Scoparia dulcis</i> in an optimized weight ratio (%) of 40:12:16:32 represents a traditional Vietnamese pharmaceutical preparation. These medicinal plants have long been utilized in traditional medicine for the supportive treatment of insomnia and anxiety. This study aimed to evaluate the safety, sedative, and anxiolytic effects of MECS capsules in <i>Swiss albino</i> mice, while also investigating the interaction affinity of bioactive compounds from the four herbal components through in silico approaches, including molecular docking, ADMET prediction, QSAR modeling, and molecular dynamics (MD) simulations. A total of 11 potential bioactive compounds were identified through a multicriteria decision-making system. Among these, 9 compounds were confirmed in the MECS capsule using UPLC-QToF-MS chromatographic profiling, supporting the in silico screening results. Subchronic toxicity and anxiolytic effects were assessed using the light-dark box (LDB) and elevated plus maze (EPM) behavioral models, with MECS capsules administered at doses of 346 and 692 mg/kg. A sleep recovery model using diazepam was applied to evaluate the sedative properties. Toxicological assessment indicated no adverse effects at the maximum tested dose (<i>D</i> <sub>max</sub>) of 39 g/kg of body weight. Furthermore, no deleterious effects were observed during the 60 day subacute toxicity evaluation at either dosage level. Behavioral assessments using the LDB and EPM models demonstrated that MECS capsules reduced anxiety-related behaviors. Diazepam significantly prolonged the sleep duration and shortened sleep onset latency at both doses, confirming the sedative effect of MECS capsules. The combined evidence from docking analysis, ADMET prediction, MDs simulations, and in vivo experimentation in <i>S. albino</i> mice showed the MECS hard capsules&#xe5f8;formulated from medicinal herbs with a favorable safety profile&#xe5f8;exhibited pronounced sedative and anxiolytic activities. These findings suggest that MECS capsules hold promise as a natural-origin therapeutic agent for the treatment of anxiety disorders and insomnia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hua</LastName><ForeName>Oanh Hoang</ForeName><Initials>OH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-4823-0977</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Traditional Medicine, University of Medicine and Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City, 221B Hoang Van Thu Street, Ho Chi Minh City 70000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">249295</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Minh Tu</LastName><ForeName>Pham</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acupuncture and Health Cultivation, Phu Yen Traditional Medicine Hospital, Daklak Province 67000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thi Thanh Nam</LastName><ForeName>Nguyen</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Hong Bang International University, Ho Chi Minh City 70000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Tat</LastName><ForeName>Pham</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7497-7741</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Binh Duong University, 504 Binh Duong Avenue, Ho Chi Minh City 70000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41867525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13000598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c06824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Morin C. M., Jarrin D. C.. Epidemiology of insomnia: Prevalence, course, risk factors, and public health burden. Sleep Med. Clin. 2022;17(2):173&#x2013;191. doi: 10.1016/j.jsmc.2022.03.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsmc.2022.03.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35659072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro L. S., Poyares D., Leger D., Bittencourt L., Tufik S.. Objective prevalence of insomnia in the S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil epidemiologic sleep study. Ann. Neurol. 2013;74(4):537&#x2013;546. doi: 10.1002/ana.23945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.23945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23720241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung K. F., Yeung W. F., Yu Y. M., Ho F. Y.. A population-based 2-year longitudinal study of insomnia disorder in a Chinese population in Hong Kong. Psychol. Health Med. 2018;23(5):505&#x2013;510. doi: 10.1080/13548506.2017.1363397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13548506.2017.1363397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28786296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury A. I., Ghosh S., Hasan M. F., Khandakar K. A. S., Azad F.. Prevalence of insomnia among university students in South Asian Region: A systematic review of studies. J. Prev. Med. Hyg. 2021;61(4):E525&#x2013;E529. doi: 10.15167/2421-4248/jpmh2020.61.4.1634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15167/2421-4248/jpmh2020.61.4.1634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7888398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33628956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javaheri S., Redline S.. Insomnia and Risk of Cardiovascular Disease. Chest. 2017;152(2):435&#x2013;444. doi: 10.1016/j.chest.2017.01.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2017.01.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5577359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28153671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riemann D., Espie C. A., Altena E., Arnardottir E. S., Baglioni C., Bassetti C. L. A., Bastien C., Berzina N., Bjorvatn B., Dikeos D., Dolenc Groselj L., Ellis J. G., Garcia-Borreguero D., Geoffroy P. A., Gjerstad M., Gon&#xe7;alves M., Hertenstein E., Hoedlmoser K., Hion T., Holzinger B., Janku K.. et al. The European Insomnia Guideline: An update on the diagnosis and treatment of insomnia. J. Sleep Res. 2023;32(6):e14035. doi: 10.1111/jsr.14035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jsr.14035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38016484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tom S. E., Wickwire E. M., Park Y., Albrecht J. S.. Nonbenzodiazepine Sedative Hypnotics and Risk of Fall-Related Injury. Sleep. 2016;39(5):1009&#x2013;1014. doi: 10.5665/sleep.5742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5665/sleep.5742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4835298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26943470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verster J. C., Veldhuijzen D. S., Patat A., Olivier B., Volkerts E. R.. Hypnotics and driving safety: meta-analyses of randomized controlled trials applying the on-the-road driving test. Curr. Drug Saf. 2006;1(1):63&#x2013;71. doi: 10.2174/157488606775252674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/157488606775252674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18690916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier S. M., Mattheisen M., Mors O., Mortensen P. B., Laursen T. M., Penninx B. W.. Increased mortality among people with anxiety disorders: total population study. Br. J. Psychiatry. 2016;209(3):216&#x2013;221. doi: 10.1192/bjp.bp.115.171975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.115.171975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5082973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27388572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandelow B., Michaelis S.. Epidemiology of anxiety disorders in the 21st century. Dialogues Clin. Neurosci. 2015;17(3):327&#x2013;335. doi: 10.31887/DCNS.2015.17.3/bbandelow.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31887/DCNS.2015.17.3/bbandelow</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4610617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26487813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung K. S., Hernandez M., Mao J. J., Haviland I., Gubili J.. Herbal medicine for depression and anxiety: A systematic review with assessment of potential psycho-oncologic relevance. Phytother Res. 2018;32(5):865&#x2013;891. doi: 10.1002/ptr.6033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.6033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5938102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29464801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penninx B. W., Pine D. S., Holmes E. A., Reif A.. Anxiety disorders. Lancet. 2021;397(10277):914&#x2013;927. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00359-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00359-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9248771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33581801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2016 Disease and Injury Incidence and Prevalence Collaborators. Global, regional, and national incidence, prevalence, and years lived with disability for 328 diseases and injuries for 195 countries, 1990&#x2013;2016: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2016. Lancet. 2017;390(10100):1211&#x2013;1259. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(17)32154-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(17)32154-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5605509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28919117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruscio A. M., Hallion L. S., Lim C. C. W., Aguilar-Gaxiola S., Al-Hamzawi A., Alonso J., Andrade L. H., Borges G., Bromet E. J., Bunting B., Caldas de Almeida J. M., Demyttenaere K., Florescu S., de Girolamo G., Gureje O., Haro J. M., He Y., Hinkov H., Hu C., de Jonge P., Karam E. G.. et al. Cross-sectional Comparison of the Epidemiology of DSM-5 Generalized Anxiety Disorder Across the Globe. JAMA Psychiatry. 2017;74(5):465&#x2013;475. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.0056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.0056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5594751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28297020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso J., Liu Z., Evans-Lacko S., Sadikova E., Sampson N., Chatterji S., Abdulmalik J., Aguilar-Gaxiola S., Al-Hamzawi A., Andrade L. H., Bruffaerts R., Cardoso G., Cia A., Florescu S., de Girolamo G., Gureje O., Haro J. M., He Y., de Jonge P., Karam E. G.. et al. WHO World Mental Health Survey Collaborators, Treatment gap for anxiety disorders is global: Results of the World Mental Health Surveys in 21 countries. Depress. Anxiety. 2018;35(3):195&#x2013;208. doi: 10.1002/da.22711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/da.22711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6008788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29356216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan A., Wang M., Liu J., Huang K., Dai D., Li L., Shi H., Wang P.. Efficacy and safety of acupuncture combined with Western medicine for anxiety: A systematic review protocol. Medicine. 2020;99(31):e21445. doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000021445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000021445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7402772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32756161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xf6;hler H.. The GABA system in anxiety and depression and its therapeutic potential. Neuropharmacology. 2012;62(1):42&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1016/j.neuropharm.2011.08.040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropharm.2011.08.040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21889518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberzon I., Phan K., Khan S., Abelson J. L.. Role of the GABAA Receptor in Anxiety: Evidence from animal models, molecular and clinical psychopharmacology, and brain imaging studies. Curr. Neuropharmacol. 2003;1(3):267&#x2013;283. doi: 10.2174/1570159033477071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1570159033477071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang T., Liao J., Cai Y., Fan M., Li C., Zhang X., Li H., Chen Y., Pan J.. Impairment of GABA inhibition in insomnia disorders: Evidence from the peripheral blood system. Front. Psychiatr. 2023;14:1134434. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2023.1134434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2023.1134434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9947704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36846238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy M. S., Sarkar B. K., Kundu S. K.. Site specific binding pattern of benzodiazepines with GABAA receptor and related impact on their activities in the human body: An in silico method based study. Heliyon. 2024;10(13):e33929. doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e33929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e33929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11283148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39071685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J. J., Hibbs R. E.. Direct Structural Insights into GABAA Receptor Pharmacology. Trends Biochem. Sci. 2021;46(6):502&#x2013;517. doi: 10.1016/j.tibs.2021.01.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tibs.2021.01.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8122054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33674151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thopate P. A., Todkar A. J., Sahare P., Vijapure S., Dudhate S.. Design, Molecular Docking Studies and ADMET Prediction of Benzodiazepine Derivatives as GABA Enhancer for Anticonvulsant Activity. Int. J. All Res. Educ. Sci. Methods. 2024;12(7):174&#x2013;181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Wang R., Zheng Q., Yao X., Zhang C., Fu S., Wei Z., Yun K., Guo Z.. Simulating dynamic interaction between diazepam and ethanol targeting the GABAA receptor via in silico model. Neurotoxicology. 2023;95:136&#x2013;143. doi: 10.1016/j.neuro.2023.01.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuro.2023.01.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36736785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Praveen M., Paramanik V.. Molecular docking, dynamics, and drug-likeness studies of alprazolam derivatives as a potent anxiolytic drug against GABAA receptors. Braz. J. Sci. 2024;4(1):34&#x2013;45. doi: 10.14295/bjs.v4i1.681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14295/bjs.v4i1.681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahila M., Babitha P. P., Bandaru S., Nayarisseri A., Doss V. A.. Molecular docking based screening of GABA (A) receptor inhibitors from plant derivatives. Bioinformation. 2015;11(6):280&#x2013;289. doi: 10.6026/97320630011280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6026/97320630011280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4512002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26229288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasir M., Park J., Lee Y., Han E.-T., Park W. S., Han J.-H., Kwon Y.-S., Lee H.-J., Chun W.. Discovery of GABA Aminotransferase Inhibitors via Molecular Docking, Molecular Dynamic Simulation, and Biological Evaluation. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2023;24(23):16990. doi: 10.3390/ijms242316990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms242316990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10707509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38069313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comitani F., Cohen N., Ashby J., Botten D., Lummis S. C. R., Molteni C.. Insights into the binding of GABA to the insect RDL receptor from atomistic simulations: a comparison of models. J. Comput. Aided Mol. Des. 2014;28:35&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1007/s10822-013-9704-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10822-013-9704-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3927061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24442887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasir M., Park J., Lee Y., Han E.-T., Park W. S., Han J.-H., Kwon Y.-S., Lee H.-J., Chun W.. Discovery of GABA Aminotransferase Inhibitors via Molecular Docking, Molecular Dynamic Simulation, and Biological Evaluation. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2023;24(23):16990. doi: 10.3390/ijms242316990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms242316990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10707509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38069313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou T. J., Xu X. J.. ADME Evaluation in Drug Discovery. 3. Modeling Blood-Brain Barrier Partitioning Using Simple Molecular Descriptors. J. Chem. Inf. Comput. Sci. 2003;43:2137&#x2013;2152. doi: 10.1021/ci034134i.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci034134i</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14632466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L., Zhao J., Zhang Y., Zhou W., Yin L., Wang Y., Fan Y., Chen Y., Liu H.. ADME properties evaluation in drug discovery: in silico prediction of blood-brain partitioning. Mol. Divers. 2018;22(4):979&#x2013;990. doi: 10.1007/s11030-018-9866-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11030-018-9866-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30083853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passeleu-Le Bourdonnec C., Carrupt P. A., Scherrmann J. M., Martel S.. Methodologies to Assess Drug Permeation Through the Blood-Brain Barrier for Pharmaceutical Research. Pharm. Res. 2013;30:2729&#x2013;2756. doi: 10.1007/s11095-013-1119-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11095-013-1119-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23801086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen L. T., Kaptchuk T. J., Davis R. B., Nguyen G., Pham V., Tringale S. M., Loh Y. L., Gardiner P.. The Use of Traditional Vietnamese Medicine Among Vietnamese Immigrants Attending an Urban Community Health Center in the United States. J. Altern. Complement. Med. 2016;22(2):145&#x2013;153. doi: 10.1089/acm.2014.0209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/acm.2014.0209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4761825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26630121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Yan Y., Wu Y., Yang H., Zhu P., Yan F., Zhao R., Tian P., Wang T., Fan Q., Su Z.. Medicinal herbs for the treatment of anxiety: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Pharmacol. Res. 2022;179:106204. doi: 10.1016/j.phrs.2022.106204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2022.106204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35378276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen D. D.. Exploring the Potential of Vietnamese Traditional Medicinal Herbs: Trends, Challenges, and Global Market Opportunities. Int. J. Sci. Res. Manag. 2024;12(10):7648&#x2013;7654. doi: 10.18535/ijsrm/v12i10.em10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18535/ijsrm/v12i10.em10</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi, V. V. Vietnamese Medicinal Plant Dictionary; Medical Publishing House: Hanoi, Vietnam, 2003; Vol. 1&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen T. N. T., Hua H. O.. Evaluation of the Antidepressant Effects of MECS Hard Capsule in Mice. Vietnam Med. J. 2024;542:220&#x2013;228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adurosakin O. E., Iweala E. J., Otike J. O., Dike E. D., Uche M. E., Owanta J. I., Ugbogu O. C., Chinedu S. N., Ugbogu E. A.. Ethnomedicinal uses, phytochemistry, pharmacological activities, and toxicological effects of Mimosa pudica- A review. Pharmacol. Res. 2023;7:100241. doi: 10.1016/j.prmcm.2023.100241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prmcm.2023.100241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Z., Sung J., Wang X., Zhang Y., Wang Y., Zhou H., Wen L.. A review on the phytochemistry and pharmacology of the herb Scoparia dulcis L. for the potential treatment of metabolic syndrome. RSC Adv. 2021;11(50):31235&#x2013;31259. doi: 10.1039/D1RA05090G.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D1RA05090G</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9041695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35496836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavitha S., Renugadevi J., Renganayaki P. R., Suganthy M., Meenakshi P., Raja K., Madhan K.. Phytochemical Profiling of Erythrina variegata Leaves by Gas Chromatography-Mass Spectroscopy. Agric. Sci. Dig. 2023;43(4):442&#x2013;450. doi: 10.18805/ag.D-5701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18805/ag.D-5701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustaffa F., Indurkar J., Shah M., Ismail S., Mansor S. M.. Review on pharmacological activities of Cinnamomum iners Reinw. ex Blume. Nat. Prod. Res. 2013;27(10):888&#x2013;895. doi: 10.1080/14786419.2012.678347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14786419.2012.678347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22574706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferini-Strambi L., Auer R., Bjorvatn B., Castronovo V., Franco O., Gabutti L., Galbiati A., Hajak G., Khatami R., Kitajima T., McEvoy D., Nissen C., Perlis M., Pevernagie D. A., Randerath W., Riemann D., Rizzo G., Van Someren E., Vgontzas A., Barazzoni F.. et al. European Sleep Foundation. Insomnia disorder: clinical and research challenges for the 21st century. Eur. J. Neurol. 2021;28(7):2156&#x2013;2167. doi: 10.1111/ene.14784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33619858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fong-Lores O., Berenguer-Rivas C. A., Vega-Acosta J. E. d. l., Mora-Tass&#xe9; Y., Morris-Quevedo H. J.. Repeated dose oral toxicity study of Mimosa pudica L. (Fabaceae) aerial parts in mice. J. Pharm. Pharmacogn. Res. 2025;13(2):475&#x2013;483. doi: 10.56499/jppres24.2065_13.2.475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.56499/jppres24.2065_13.2.475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herlina T., Madihah M., Deni D., Amien S.. Subchronic toxicity of methanol extract from Erythrina variegata (Leguminosae) leaves on male Wistar rats (Rattus norvegicus) Molekul. 2017;12(1):88. doi: 10.20884/1.jm.2017.12.1.349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20884/1.jm.2017.12.1.349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ieraci A., Mallei A., Popoli M.. Social Isolation Stress Induces Anxious-Depressive-Like Behavior and Alterations of Neuroplasticity-Related Genes in Adult Male Mice. Neural Plast. 2016;2016:1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1155/2016/6212983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/6212983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4736811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26881124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imaizumi M., Suzuki T., Machida H., Onodera K.. A fully automated apparatus for a light/dark test measuring anxiolytic or anxiogenic effects of drugs in mice. Nihon Shinkei Seishin Yakurigaku Zasshi. 1994;14(2):83&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7913786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain S., Gupta S.. Effects of Cinnamomum zeylanicum Bark Extract on Nociception and Anxiety-Like Behavior in Mice. Asian J. Pharm. Clin. Res. 2019;12(9):236&#x2013;241. doi: 10.22159/ajpcr.2019.v12i9.31287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22159/ajpcr.2019.v12i9.31287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalachaveedu M., Kuruvilla S., Balakrishna K.. Effect of Erythrina variegata on experimental atherosclerosis in guinea pigs. J. Pharmacol. Pharmacother. 2011;2(4):285&#x2013;287. doi: 10.4103/0976-500X.85950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0976-500X.85950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3198527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22025860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karim N., Shill L. K., Dhar R., Sakib Md.H., Ullah A., Islam S.. Sedative Properties of the Methanolic Extract of Cinnamomum cecidodaphne Barks. World J. Pharm. Pharm. Sci. 2015;4(4):316&#x2013;323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komada M., Takao K., Miyakawa T.. Elevated plus maze for mice. J. Vis. Exp. 2008;22:1088. doi: 10.3791/1088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3791/1088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19229173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar M., Kumara D., Mogana R., Dey Y. N., Singh R.. Anxiolytic activity of methanolic extract of Erythrina variegata Linn. leaves in Wistar rats. Res. Pharmacy Health Sci. 2020;05:205&#x2013;208. doi: 10.32463/RPHS.2019.v05i04.03.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32463/RPHS.2019.v05i04.03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malmberg-Aiello P., Ipponi A., Bartolini A., Schunack W.. Mouse light/dark box test reveals anxiogenic-like effects by activation of histamine H1 receptors. Pharmacol., Biochem. Behav. 2002;71(1&#x2013;2):313&#x2013;318. doi: 10.1016/S0091-3057(01)00691-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0091-3057(01)00691-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11812538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto K., Pinna G., Puia G., Guidotti A., Costa E.. Social isolation stress-induced aggression in mice: a model to study the pharmacology of neurosteroidogenesis. Stress. 2005;8(2):85&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1080/10253890500159022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10253890500159022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16019600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moniruzzaman M., Atikur Rahman M., Ferdous A.. Evaluation of Sedative and Hypnotic Activity of Ethanolic Extract of Scoparia dulcis Linn. Evid. Based Complement. Alternat. Med. 2015;2015:1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1155/2015/873954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2015/873954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4377517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25861372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adurosakin O. E., Iweala E. J., Otike J. O., Dike E. D., Uche M. E., Owanta J. I., Ugbogu O. C., Chinedu S. N., Ugbogu E. A.. Ethnomedicinal uses, phytochemistry, pharmacological activities, and toxicological effects of Mimosa pudica- A review. Pharmacol. Res. 2023;7:100241. doi: 10.1016/j.prmcm.2023.100241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prmcm.2023.100241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizwan K., Majeed I., Bilal M., Rasheed T., Shakeel A., Iqbal S.. Phytochemistry and Diverse Pharmacology of Genus Mimosa: A Review. Biomolecules. 2022;12(1):83. doi: 10.3390/biom12010083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biom12010083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8773851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35053231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A., Lingadurai S., Jain A., Barman N. R.. Erythrina variegata Linn: A review on morphology, phytochemistry, and pharmacological aspects. Pharmacogn. Rev. 2010;4(8):147&#x2013;152. doi: 10.4103/0973-7847.70908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0973-7847.70908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3249914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22228954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiaoli L., Naili W., Sau W. M., Chen A. S., Xinsheng Y.. Four new isoflavonoids from the stem bark of Erythrina variegata. Chem. Pharm. Bull. 2006;54(4):570&#x2013;573. doi: 10.1248/cpb.54.570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/cpb.54.570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16595969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifi-Rad J., Dey A., Koirala N., Shaheen S., El Omari N., Salehi B., Goloshvili T., Cirone Silva N. C., Bouyahya A., Vitalini S., Varoni E. M., Martorell M., Abdolshahi A., Docea A. O., Iriti M., Calina D., Les F., L&#xf3;pez V., Caruntu C.. Cinnamomum species: Bridging Phytochemistry Knowledge, Pharmacological Properties and Toxicological Safety for Health Benefits. Front. Pharmacol. 2021;12:600139. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2021.600139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2021.600139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8144503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34045956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salleh W. M. N. H. W., Ahmad F., Yen K. H.. Antioxidant and Anticholinesterase Activities of Essential Oils of Cinnamomum griffithii and C. macrocarpum. Nat. Prod. Commun. 2015;10(8):1934578X1501000838. doi: 10.1177/1934578X1501000838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1934578X1501000838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26434143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Z., Sung J., Wang X., Zhang Y., Wang Y., Zhou H., Wen L.. A review on the phytochemistry and pharmacology of the herb Scoparia dulcis L. for the potential treatment of metabolic syndrome. RSC Adv. 2021;11(50):31235&#x2013;31259. doi: 10.1039/D1RA05090G.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D1RA05090G</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9041695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35496836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma A. K., Singh S., Shukla P. K.. Pharmacological evaluation of Mimosa pudica for its anxiolytic potential in rodents. J. Ethnopharmacol. 2022;282:14598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen H. L., Pham T. T., Tran Q. C.. Neuropharmacological effects of Erythrina variegata extracts in experimental models. Phytomedicine. 2020;78:53306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma R. K., Gupta V.. Acute and subacute toxicity studies of Cinnamomum iners bark extract in rodents. Regul. Toxicol. Pharmacol. 2020;112:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman M. A., Sultana N., Khan M. H.. Safety evaluation and neuroprotective activity of Scoparia dulcis in animal models. BMC Complementary Med. Ther. 2021;21(1):145&#x2013;152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair A. B., Jacob S.. A simple practice guide for dose conversion between animals and human. J. Basic Clin. Pharm. 2016;7(2):27&#x2013;31. doi: 10.4103/0976-0105.177703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0976-0105.177703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4804402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27057123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter L., de Graaf C., Sieghart W., Varagic Z., M&#xf6;rzinger M., de Esch I. J. P., Ecker G. F., Ernst M.. Diazepam-bound GABAA receptor models identify new benzodiazepine binding-site ligands. Nat. Chem. Biol. 2012;8(5):455&#x2013;464. doi: 10.1038/nchembio.917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nchembio.917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3368153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22446838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daina A., Michielin O., Zoete V.. SwissADME: A free web tool to evaluate pharmacokinetics, drug-likeness, and medicinal chemistry friendliness of small molecules. Sci. Rep. 2017;7:42717. doi: 10.1038/srep42717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep42717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5335600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28256516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong G., Wu Z., Yi J., Fu L., Yang Z., Hsieh C., Yin M., Zeng X., Wu C., Lu A., Chen X., Hou T., Cao D.. ADMETlab 2.0: An integrated online platform for accurate and comprehensive predictions of ADMET properties. Nucleic Acids Res. 2021;49(W1):W5&#x2013;W14. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkab255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkab255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8262709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33893803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipinski C. A., Lombardo F., Dominy B. W., Feeney P. J.. Experimental and computational approaches to estimate solubility and permeability in drug discovery and development settings. Adv. Drug Delivery Rev. 1997;23(1&#x2013;3):3&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1016/S0169-409X(96)00423-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0169-409X(96)00423-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11259830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daina A., Zoete V.. A BOILED-Egg to predict gastrointestinal absorption and brain penetration of small molecules. ChemMedChem. 2016;11(11):1117&#x2013;1121. doi: 10.1002/cmdc.201600182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cmdc.201600182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5089604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27218427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J.. Comprehensive assessment of ADMET risks in drug discovery. Curr. Pharm. Des. 2009;15(19):2195&#x2013;2219. doi: 10.2174/138161209788682514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/138161209788682514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19601823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chemical Computing Group ULC, 2024.0601; Molecular Operating Environment (MOE): Montreal, QC, Canada, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samy A., Hassan A., Hegazi N. M., Farid M., Elshafei M.. Network pharmacology, molecular docking, and dynamics analyses to predict the antiviral activity of ginger constituents against coronavirus infection. Sci. Rep. 2024;14:12059. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-60721-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-60721-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11130167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38802394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szklarczyk D., Kirsch R., Koutrouli M., Nastou K., Mehryary F., Hachilif R., Gable A. L., Fang T., Doncheva N. T., Pyysalo S., Bork P., Jensen L. J., von Mering C.. The STRING database in 2023: Protein-protein association networks and functional enrichment analyses for any sequenced genome of interest. Nucleic Acids Res. 2023;51(D1):D638&#x2013;D646. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkac1000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkac1000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9825434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36370105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shannon P., Markiel A., Ozier O., Baliga N. S., Wang J. T., Ramage D., Amin N., Schwikowski B., Ideker T.. Cytoscape: a software environment for integrated models of biomolecular interaction networks. Genome Res. 2003;13(11):2498&#x2013;2504. doi: 10.1101/gr.1239303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/gr.1239303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC403769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14597658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klepsch F., Vasanthanathan P., Ecker G. F.. Ligand and structure-based classification models for prediction of P-glycoprotein inhibitors. J. Chem. Inf. Model. 2014;54(1):218&#x2013;229. doi: 10.1021/ci400289j.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci400289j</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3904775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24050383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
RCSB Protein Data Bank . PDB ID.https://www.rcsb.org/structure/ [Online]. (Accessed on May 18, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berman H. M., Westbrook J., Feng Z., Gilliland G., Bhat T. N., Weissig H., Bourne P. E.. The Protein Data Bank. Nucleic Acids Res. 2000;28(1):235&#x2013;242. doi: 10.1093/nar/28.1.235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/28.1.235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC102472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10592235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahila M., Babitha P. P., Bandaru S., Nayarisseri A., Doss V. A.. Molecular docking-based screening of GABA (A) receptor inhibitors from plant derivatives. Bioinformation. 2015;11(6):280&#x2013;289. doi: 10.6026/97320630011280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6026/97320630011280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4512002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26229288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>

Chen, R. J.
; 
Sharma, S.
. 
GABA Receptor, NCBI Bookshelf, 2025. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK526124/ [Online]. (Accessed on May 18, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaulton A., Hersey A., Nowotka M., Bento A. P., Chambers J., Mendez D., Mutowo P., Atkinson F., Bellis L. J., Cibrian-Uhalte E., Davies M., Dedman N., Karlsson A., Magari&#xf1;os M. P., Overington J. P., Papadatos G., Smit I., Leach A. R.. The ChEMBL database in 2017. Nucleic Acids Res. 2017;45(D1):D945&#x2013;D954. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkw1074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkw1074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5210557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27899562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quang N. M., Tran Thai H., Le Thi H., Cuong N. D., Hien N. Q., Hoang D. Q., Ngoc V. T. B., Minh V. K., Van Tat P.. Novel Thiosemicarbazone Quantum Dots in the Treatment of Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease Combining In Silico Models Using Fingerprints and Physicochemical Descriptors. ACS Omega. 2023;8(12):11076&#x2013;11099. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.2c07934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.2c07934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10061515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37008140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shenol A., Luckmann M., Trauelsen M., Lambrughi M., Tiberti M., Papaleo E., Frimurer T. M., Schwartz T. W.. Molecular dynamics-based identification of binding pathways and two distinct high-affinity sites for succinate in succinate receptor 1/GPR91. Mol. Cell. 2024;84:955&#x2013;966.e4. doi: 10.1016/j.molcel.2024.01.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molcel.2024.01.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38325379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
CompChems . GROMACS Tutorial: Molecular Dynamics
simulation
of a protein in water environment. https://www.compchems.com/gromacs-tutorial-molecular-dynamics-simulation-of-a-protein-in-water-environment/. [Online]. (Accessed on May 18, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu C., Wu C., Ghoreishi D., Chen W., Wang L., Damm W., Ross G. A., Dahlgren M. K., Russell E., Von Bargen C. D., Abel R., Friesner R. A., Harder E. D.. OPLS4: Improving Force Field Accuracy on Challenging Regimes of Chemical Space. J. Chem. Theory Comput. 2021;17(7):4291&#x2013;4300. doi: 10.1021/acs.jctc.1c00302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jctc.1c00302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34096718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zong K., Xu L., Hou Y., Zhang Q., Che J., Zhao L., Li X.. Virtual Screening and Molecular Dynamics Simulation Study of Influenza Polymerase PB2 Inhibitors. Molecules. 2021;26(22):6944. doi: 10.3390/molecules26226944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules26226944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8623395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34834044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nam M., Jo S., Kim Y.-C., Kim M.-S.. UPLC-QTOF-MS-Based Metabolomics and Antioxidant Capacity of Codonopsis lanceolata from Different Geographical Origins. Foods. 2023;12(2):267. doi: 10.3390/foods12020267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/foods12020267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9858319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36673357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Do T. H. T., Nguyen T. B. T., Nguyen T. P. T., Tran T. V. A.. Study on oral acute toxicity and anti-inflammatory effect of extract from Hibiscus mutabilis L. leaves in mice. Ho Chi Minh City J. Med. 2018;22(5):40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Do T. D.. Method for Determining Acute Toxicity of Drugs. Med. Publ. 2014;15(157):199&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health . Guidelines for Preclinical and Clinical Trials of Traditional Medicine and Herbal Drugs; Decision No. 141/QD-K2DT, Vietnam Ministry of Health, 2020, pp 6&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porwal M., Khan N. A., Maheshwari K. K.. Evaluation of Acute and Subacute Oral Toxicity Induced by Ethanolic Extract of Marsdenia tenacissima Leaves in Experimental Rats. Sci. Pharm. 2017;85(3):29. doi: 10.3390/scipharm85030029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/scipharm85030029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5620517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28825665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourin M., Hasco&#xeb;t M.. The mouse light/dark box test. Eur. J. Pharmacol. 2003;463(1&#x2013;3):55&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1016/S0014-2999(03)01274-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0014-2999(03)01274-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12600702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salaudeen M. A., Magaji M. G., Mudashir F. I., Chindo B. A., Maiha B. B.. Sedative and CNS Depressant Effect of Nymphaea lotus. FASEB J. 2020;34:1. doi: 10.1096/fasebj.2020.34.s1.04625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fasebj.2020.34.s1.04625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
National
Institute of Allergy
and Infectious Diseases . Clinical
Research Regulation for Vietnam. 2024. https://clinregs.niaid.nih.gov/country/vietnam. [Online]. (Accessed on May 18, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sattah N. G., D&#x2019;Anniballe V., Le H. T., Le L. T., Le T. N., Vu T. T., Louangpradith V., Lee W. T.. Evaluating research ethics committees in Vietnam and Laos: Results of a validated self-assessment tool. PLoS One. 2024;19(8):e0309084. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0309084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0309084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11340885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39172804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noor F.. Network pharmacology approach for medicinal plants: Review and assessment. Pharmaceuticals. 2022;15(5):572. doi: 10.3390/ph15050572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ph15050572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9143318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35631398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
The
UniProt Consortium . UniProtKB
entry: Q9BYF1 (Angiotensin-converting
enzyme 2 - Homo sapiens). 2023. https://www.uniprot.org/uniprotkb/Q9BYF1. [Online]. (Accessed on May 18, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masiulis S., Desai R., Ucha&#x144;ski T., Serna Martin I., Laverty D., Karia D., Malinauskas T., Zivanov J., Pardon E., Kotecha A.. et al. GABAA receptor signalling mechanisms revealed by structural pharmacology. Nature. 2019;565(7740):454&#x2013;459. doi: 10.1038/s41586-018-0832-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-018-0832-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6370056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30602790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y., Shi D., Zhao Q., Wang W., Liu L., Wang Z.. Combining network pharmacology and bioinformatics approaches to explore the molecular mechanism of Erdong Nourishing Heart oral solution in the treatment of anxiety disorders. Brain Behavior Immun. Integ. 2025;10:100117. doi: 10.1016/j.bbii.2025.100117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbii.2025.100117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X., Xiu J., Yang H., Han W., Jin Y.. Network pharmacology and bioinformatics study of six medicinal food homologous plants against colorectal cancer. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2025;26(3):930. doi: 10.3390/ijms26030930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms26030930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11817456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39940699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikhar Danish Ahmad A., Khan S. W., Ali S. A., Yasar Q.. Network pharmacology combined with molecular docking and experimental verification to elucidate the effect of flavan-3-ols and aromatic resin on anxiety. Sci. Rep. 2024;14:9799. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-58877-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-58877-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11058257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38684743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller B. R., McGee T. D., Swails J. M., Homeyer N., Gohlke H., Roitberg A. E.. MMPBSA.Py: An Efficient Program for End-State Free Energy Calculations. J. Chem. Theory Comput. 2012;8:3314&#x2013;3321. doi: 10.1021/ct300418h.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ct300418h</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26605738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbeil C. R., Williams C. I., Labute P.. Variability in docking success rates due to dataset preparation. Comput. Aided Mol. Des. 2012;26:775&#x2013;786. doi: 10.1007/s10822-012-9570-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10822-012-9570-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3397132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22566074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sliwoski G., Kothiwale S., Meiler J., Lowe E. W.. Computational methods in drug discovery. Pharmacol. Rev. 2014;66(1):334&#x2013;395. doi: 10.1124/pr.112.007336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1124/pr.112.007336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3880464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24381236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipinski C. A., Lombardo F., Dominy B. W., Feeney P. J.. Experimental and computational approaches to estimate solubility and permeability in drug discovery and development settings. Adv. Drug Delivery Rev. 1997;23(1&#x2013;3):3&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1016/S0169-409X(96)00423-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0169-409X(96)00423-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11259830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
D.
E. Shaw Research . Desmond Tutorial, Version 0.6, 2008. https://www.deshawresearch.com/downloads/download_desmond.cgi/Desmond_Tutorial-0.6.pdf. [Online]. (Accessed on May 18, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Schr&#xf6;dinger,
L. L. C. 
Schr&#xf6;dinger Python
API Reference. 2023. https://learn.schrodinger.com/public/. [Online]. (Accessed on May 18, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abere T. A., Okoye C. J., Agoreyo F. O., Eze G. I., Jesuorobo R. I., Egharevba C. O., Aimator P. O.. Antisickling and toxicological evaluation of the leaves of Scoparia dulcis Linn (Scrophulariaceae) BMC Compl. Alternative Med. 2015;15:414. doi: 10.1186/s12906-015-0928-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12906-015-0928-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4657272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26597857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajendran R., Krishnakumar E.. Hypolipidemic Activity of Chloroform Extract of Mimosa pudica Leaves. Avicenna J. Med. Biotechnol. 2010;2(4):215&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3558166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23408779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parasuraman S., Ching T. H., Leong C. H., Banik U.. Antidiabetic and antihyperlipidemic effects of methanolic extract of Mimosa pudica (Fabaceae) in diabetic rats, Egypt. J. Basic Appl. Sci. 2019;6(1):137&#x2013;148. doi: 10.1080/2314808X.2019.1681660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2314808X.2019.1681660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz U., Akther R., Shahriar M., Bhuiyan M. A.. In vivo pharmacological investigation of Mimosa pudica L. Int. J. Pharm. Pharm. Sci. 2014;6(2):66&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U U. A., Ozoh P. O., Ukwandu N. C., Mgbemena I. C., Okorie C. C., Onyeocha I. O.. Evaluation of Toxicological Effects Ethanol Extracts of Mimosa pudica in Adult Male Albino Rats. Int. J. Adv. Res. Biol. Sci. 2018;5(10):98&#x2013;109. doi: 10.22192/ijarbs.2018.05.10.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22192/ijarbs.2018.05.10.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed R., Nuhu D., Ibrahim H., Nuhu A., Maje I.. Toxicological assessment of aqueous and methanol leaves extracts of Scoparia dulcis Linn (Plantaginaceae) in Wistar rats. Trop. J. Nat. Prod. Res. 2019;3(3):64&#x2013;70. doi: 10.26538/tjnpr/v3i3.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26538/tjnpr/v3i3.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulsalaam I. A., Ehinmidu J. O., Igbadi E. O.. Evaluation of antibacterial properties, acute toxicity, and immuno-stimulatory potential of Scoparia dulcis. Nigerian J. Biotechnol. 2013;26(1):21&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustaffa F., Indurkar J., Ismail S., Mordi M. N., Ramanathan S., Mansor S. M.. Antioxidant capacity and toxicity screening of Cinnamomum iners standardized leaves methanolic extract. Int. J. Pharmacol. 2010;6:888&#x2013;895. doi: 10.3923/ijp.2010.888.895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3923/ijp.2010.888.895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3140111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21808545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connell K. E., Mikkola A. M., Stepanek A. M., Vernet A., Hall C. D., Sun C. C., Yildirim E., Staropoli J. F., Lee J. T., Brown D. E.. Practical murine hematopathology: a comparative review and implications for research. Comp. Med. 2015;65(2):96&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4408895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25926395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Susilawati E., Levita J., Susilawati Y., Sumiwi S. A.. Pharmacology activity, toxicity, and clinical trials of Erythrina genus plants (Fabaceae): an evidence-based review. Front. Pharmacol. 2023;14:1281150. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2023.1281150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2023.1281150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10690608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38044940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sultana S., Hossain Md. L.. Evaluation of Anxiolytic and Antibacterial Activity of Methanol Extract of Leaves of Mimosa pudica. Univers. J. Plant Sci. 2019;7(3):44&#x2013;49. doi: 10.13189/ujps.2019.070302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13189/ujps.2019.070302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patro G., Kumar Bhattamisra S., Kumar Mohanty B.. Effects of Mimosa pudica L. leaves extract on anxiety, depression, and memory. Avicenna J. Phytomed. 2016;6(6):696&#x2013;710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5206927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28078250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elayaraja A., Rahaman S. A., Kumar P. P., Krishnan M. R.. Anti-anxiety activity of hydro alcoholic extract of Scoparia dulcis Linn. assessed using different experimental anxiety models in rodents. Int. J. Pharmacol. Res. 2015;5:1521. doi: 10.7439/ijpr.v5i3.1521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7439/ijpr.v5i3.1521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitchaiah G., Shastry V., Rangappa S., Nandakumar K.. Anxiolytic and anticonvulsant activity of aqueous extract of stem bark of Erythrina variegata in rodents. Int. J. PharmTech Res. 2010;2(1):40&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu H. B., Tan Y. D., Li Y. J., Cheng B. B., Rao B. Q., Zhou L. S.. Anxiolytic and anti-depressant effects of hydroalcoholic extract from Erythrina variegata and its possible mechanism of action. Afr. Health Sci. 2019;19(3):2526&#x2013;2536. doi: 10.4314/ahs.v19i3.28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ahs.v19i3.28</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7040268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32127825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayissi Mbomo R., Gartside S., Ngo Bum E., Njikam N., Okello E., McQuade R.. Effect of Mimosa pudica (Linn.) extract on anxiety behaviour and GABAergic regulation of 5-HT neuronal activity in the mouse. J. Psychopharmacol. 2012;26(4):575&#x2013;583. doi: 10.1177/0269881111398686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269881111398686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21427203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phootha N., Yongparnichkul N., Fang Z., Gan R., Zhang P.. Plants and phytochemicals potentials in tackling anxiety: A systematic review. Phytomed. Plus. 2022;2(4):100375. doi: 10.1016/j.phyplu.2022.100375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phyplu.2022.100375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espineli D., Agoo E., Shen C., Ragasa C.. Chemical Constituents of Cinnamomum iners. Chem. Nat. Compd. 2013;49(5):932&#x2013;933. doi: 10.1007/s10600-013-0783-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10600-013-0783-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R., Wang R., Yang B.. Extraction of Essential Oils from Five Cinnamon Leaves and Identification of Their Volatile Compound Compositions. Innovative Food Sci. Emerging Technol. 2009;10:289&#x2013;292. doi: 10.1016/j.ifset.2008.12.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ifset.2008.12.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etaee F., Komaki A., Faraji N., Rezvani-Kamran A., Komaki S., Hasanein P., Taheri M., Omidi G.. The effects of cinnamaldehyde on acute or chronic stress-induced anxiety-related behavior and locomotion in male mice. Stress. 2019;22(3):358&#x2013;365. doi: 10.1080/10253890.2019.1567710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10253890.2019.1567710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30806129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fadaei S., Asle-Rousta M.. Anxiolytic and antidepressant effects of cinnamon (Cinnamomum verum) extract in rats receiving lead acetate. Sci. J. Kurdistan Univ. Med. Sci. 2018;22(6):31&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M., Kou L., Qin Y., Chen J., Bai D., Zhao L., Lin H., Jiang G.. A bibliometric analysis of the recent advances in diazepam from 2012 to 2021. Front. Pharmacol. 2022;13:1042594. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2022.1042594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.1042594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9686836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36438847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramadayanti S., Ginting I., Naldi J., Rudang S. N., Ramadayanti S.. Sedative test of ethanol extract of Putri Malu leaves (Mimosa pudica Linn.) in mice (Mus Musculus) with standardized herbal medicine Lelap as comparison. J. La Medihealtico. 2022;3(2):110&#x2013;115. doi: 10.37899/journallamedihealtico.v3i2.579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37899/journallamedihealtico.v3i2.579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratnasooriya W. D., Dharmasiri M. G.. Aqueous extract of Sri Lankan Erythrina indica leaves has sedative but not analgesic activity. Fitoterapia. 1999;70(3):311&#x2013;313. doi: 10.1016/S0367-326X(99)00027-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0367-326X(99)00027-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao S., Liu S., Yu H., Xie Y., Guo Y., Fan J., Yao W.. A Study on the Mechanism of the Sedative-hypnotic Effect of Cinnamomum camphora chvar. Borneol Essential Oil Based on Network Pharmacology. J. Oleo Sci. 2022;71(7):1063&#x2013;1073. doi: 10.5650/jos.ess21278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5650/jos.ess21278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35691835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comenencia-Ortiz E.. Phosphorylation of GABAA receptors influences receptor trafficking and neurosteroid actions. Neuropharmacology. 2014;231:3453. doi: 10.1007/s00213-014-3617-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-014-3617-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4135009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24847959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Mu&#xf1;oz R., Alamo C., Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a P.. The role of GABA neurotransmitter in the human central nervous system. Rev. M&#xe9;d. Hosp. Gen. M&#xe9;xico. 2021;22(2):67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian D., Zhang Y., Wang J., Wang C., Wang Y.. Identification of potential targets of cinnamon for treatment against Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease-related GABAergic synaptic dysfunction. Sci. Rep. 2022;12:19959. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-24378-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-24378-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9675738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36402912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vithlani M., Terunuma M., Moss S. J.. The dynamic modulation of GABAA receptor trafficking and its role in regulating the plasticity of inhibitory synapses. Physiol. Rev. 2011;91(3):1009&#x2013;1022. doi: 10.1152/physrev.00015.2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00015.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4382539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21742794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustarichie R., Saptarini N. M., Megantara S.. Molecule Attachment and Prediction of ADMET Compounds in Cinnamomum burmannii on Orexin Receptor as Anti-insomnia. Pharmacogn. J. 2022;14(3):576&#x2013;583. doi: 10.5530/pj.2022.14.74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5530/pj.2022.14.74</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>