<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41788929</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2277-9531</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of education and health promotion</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Educ Health Promot</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of nursing interventions on clinical outcomes in patients undergoing abdominal surgery: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>43</StartPage><MedlinePgn>43</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">43</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/jehp.jehp_602_25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Abdominal surgery patients remain at risk for postoperative complications despite medical advancements. Effective nursing interventions, such as pain management, early mobilization, and structured education, play a crucial role in improving recovery. However, inconsistencies in existing studies necessitate a comprehensive review. This study systematically evaluates the impact of nursing interventions to guide standardized postoperative care and enhance patient outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The systematic review and meta-analysis followed the PRISMA guidelines. A literature search was conducted across five databases (PubMed, Scopus, CINAHL, Embase, and Web of Science) for studies published between January 2019 and December 2023. Study quality was assessed using the Joanna Briggs Institute critical appraisal tools. Meta-analysis was performed to synthesize the findings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 21 studies met the inclusion criteria and were included in the final meta-analysis. Nursing interventions significantly reduced postoperative pain at 8 hours, 1 day, 2 days, 3 days, and &#x2265;4 days. Additionally, they effectively shortened the time to first bowel movement and first flatus while also improving postoperative self-care behaviors. Significant reductions in abdominal distension were observed at 1 day, 2 days, and 3 days.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Nursing interventions play a crucial role in improving postoperative outcomes for patients undergoing abdominal surgery. The findings support the implementation of evidence-based nursing strategies to minimize complications and optimize recovery, emphasizing the need for standardized nursing guidelines to improve patient care and healthcare efficiency.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Journal of Education and Health Promotion.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pongam</LastName><ForeName>Sanya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Public Health, Valaya Alongkorn Rajabhat University under the Royal Patronage, Pathum Thani, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chusak</LastName><ForeName>Thassaporn</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Public Health, Valaya Alongkorn Rajabhat University under the Royal Patronage, Pathum Thani, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Banchonhattakit</LastName><ForeName>Pannee</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Public Health, Valaya Alongkorn Rajabhat University under the Royal Patronage, Pathum Thani, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chatchumni</LastName><ForeName>Manaporn</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Adult and Elderly Nursing, School of Nursing, Rangsit University, Pathum Thani, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Educ Health Promot</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101593794</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2277-9531</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Abdominal surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nursing care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postoperative complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment outcome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41788929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12959549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jehp.jehp_602_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JEHP-15-43</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hijazi Y, Gondal U, Aziz O. A systematic review of prehabilitation programs in abdominal cancer surgery. Int J Surg. 2017;39:156&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28161527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustafsson UO, Scott MJ, Hubner M, Nygren J, Demartines N, Francis N, et al. Guidelines for perioperative care in elective colorectal surgery: Enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS&#xae;) society recommendations: 2018. World J Surg. 2019;43:659&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30426190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Kooten RT, Bahadoer RR, Peeters KCMJ, Hoeksema JHL, Steyerberg EW, Hartgrink HH, et al. Preoperative risk factors for major postoperative complications after complex gastrointestinal cancer surgery: A systematic review. Eur J Surg Oncol. 2021;47:3049&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34340874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzotta E, Villalobos-Hernandez EC, Fiorda-Diaz J, Harzman A, Christofi FL. Postoperative ileus and postoperative gastrointestinal tract dysfunction: Pathogenic mechanisms and novel treatment strategies beyond colorectal enhanced recovery after surgery protocols. Front Pharmacol. 2020;11:583422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7774512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33390950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iskander O. An outline of the management and prevention of postoperative ileus: A review. Medicine. 2024;103:e38177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11175850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38875379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sko&#x159;epa P, Ford KL, Alsuwaylihi A, O&#x2019;Connor D, Prado CM, Gomez D, et al. The impact of prehabilitation on outcomes in frail and high-risk patients undergoing major abdominal surgery: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Nutr. 2024;43:629&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38306891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju W, Ren L, Chen J, Du Y. Efficacy of relaxation therapy as an effective nursing intervention for post-operative pain relief in patients undergoing abdominal surgery: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Exp Ther Med. 2019;18:2909&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6755420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31555379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendes DIA, Ferrito CRAC, Gon&#xe7;alves MIR. Nursing interventions in the enhanced recovery after surgery&#xae;: Scoping review. Rev Bras Enferm. 2018;71:2824&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30540062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao L, Liu X, Yu L, Xiao H. Effect of nursing intervention to guide early postoperative activities on rapid rehabilitation of patients undergoing abdominal surgery: A protocol for systematic review and meta-analysis. Medicine. 2021;100:e24776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9282128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33761639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobsen DH, H&#xf8;gdall C, Seib&#xe6;k L. Postoperative mobilization as an indicator for the quality of surgical nursing care. Br J Nurs. 2021;30:S4&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33641401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y. Analysis of effect on infection factors and nursing care of postoperative incision in gynecological cancer patients. Biomed Res Int. 2021;2021:2996216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8668283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34912887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Li P, Wang H, Lv C, Han J, Lu X. Exploring elderly patients&#x2019; experiences and concerns about early mobilization implemented in postoperative care following lumbar spinal surgery: A qualitative study. BMC Nurs. 2023;22:355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10552231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37794348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nachiyunde B, Lam L. The efficacy of different modes of analgesia in postoperative pain management and early mobilization in postoperative cardiac surgical patients: A systematic review. Ann Card Anaesth. 2018;21:363&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6206788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30333328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pashaei S, Aky&#xfc;z N. Effective role of aromatherapy in reducing big little problem-postoperative nausea and vomiting: A systematic review. J Educ Health Promot. 2024;13:298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11482362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39416988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tazreean R, Nelson G, Twomey R. Early mobilization in enhanced recovery after surgery pathways: Current evidence and recent advancements. J Comp Eff Res. 2022;11:121&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35045757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atinyagrika Adugbire B, Aziato L. Surgical patients&#x2019; perspectives on nurses&#x2019; education on post-operative care and follow up in Northern Ghana. BMC Nurs. 2018;17:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6038327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30002600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannarino CN, Michelson K, Jackson L, Paquette E, McBride ME. Post-operative discharge education for parent caregivers of children with congenital heart disease: A needs assessment. Cardiol Young. 2020;30:1788&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32959751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodersen F, Wagner J, Uzunoglu FG, Petersen-Ewert C. Impact of preoperative patient education on postoperative recovery in abdominal surgery: A systematic review. World J Surg. 2023;47:937&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9971074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36641521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook DJ, Moradkhani A, Douglas KS, Prinsen SK, Fischer EN, Schroeder DR. Patient education self-management during surgical recovery: Combining mobile (iPad) and a content management system. Telemed J E Health. 2014;20:312&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3968874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24443928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reaza-Alarc&#xf3;n A, Rodr&#xed;guez-Mart&#xed;n B. Effectiveness of nursing educational interventions in managing post-surgical pain. Systematic review. Invest Educ Enferm. 2019;37:e10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7871485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31487447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah AA, Alnajib AMA, Baldaniya L, Hassan H, Kaur P, Sharma R, et al. Investigating the effectiveness of enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) protocols in improving postoperative outcomes and reducing hospital readmission rates in patients undergoing abdominal surgery. J Pharm Bioallied Sci. 2024;16:S3534&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11805166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39926912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iniesta MD, Lasala J, Mena G, Rodriguez-Restrepo A, Salvo G, Pitcher B, et al. Impact of compliance with an enhanced recovery after surgery pathway on patient outcomes in open gynecologic surgery. Int J Gynecol Cancer. 2019;29:1417&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31601647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni YX, Li Z, Zhou LL, Gong S. Factors influencing early mobilisation for patients undergoing pancreatic surgery from multiple perspectives: A qualitative descriptive study. BMJ Open. 2023;13:e077419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10711852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38056941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shauly O, Marxen T, Menon A, Swan C, Smearman E, Gould DJ. Multimodal pain control in abdominoplasty: A systematic review and algorithm of optimal pain management. Aesthet Surg J. 2024;44:S22&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39147384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker TH, Habibi N, Aromataris E, Stone JC, Leonardi-Bee J, Sears K, et al. The revised JBI critical appraisal tool for the assessment of risk of bias for quasi-experimental studies. JBI Evid Synth. 2024;22:378&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38287725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker TH, Stone JC, Sears K, Klugar M, Tufanaru C, Leonardi-Bee J, et al. The revised JBI critical appraisal tool for the assessment of risk of bias for randomized controlled trials. JBI Evid Synth. 2023;21:494&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36727247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W. Conducting meta-analyses in R with the metafor package. J Stat Soft. 2010;36:1&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327:557&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Smith GD, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ. 1997;315:629&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avci N, Oskay U. Effect of reflexology on decreasing postoperative pain and anxiety after total abdominal hysterectomy. Holist Nurs Pract. 2023;37:78&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36790422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seok Y, Suh EE, Yu S, Park J, Park H, Lee E. Effectiveness of integrated education to reduce postoperative nausea, vomiting, and dizziness after abdominal surgery under general anesthesia. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:6124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8200998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34204087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koyuncu F, Iyigun E. The effect of mobilization protocol on mobilization start time and patient care outcomes in patients undergoing abdominal surgery. J Clin Nurs. 2022;31:1298&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34346134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gungor S, Tosun B, Candir G, Ozen N. Effects of cold spray on thirst, frequency of oral care, and pain of general surgery intensive care unit patients. Sci Rep. 2024;14:9997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11063212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38693271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu Y, Szu S. Effects of gum chewing on recovery from postoperative ileus: A randomized clinical trail. J Nurs Res. 2022;30:e233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35951432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chantawong N, Charoenkwan K. Effect of elastic abdominal binder on pain and functional recovery following gynecologic cancer surgery: A randomized controlled trial. Medicina. 2021;57:481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8151580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34065997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed S, Rage KA, Memon AS, Kazi S, Samo KA, Shahid S, et al. Use of abdominal binders after a major abdominal surgery: A randomized controlled trial. Cureus. 2019;11:e5832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6827701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31754567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campagna S, Clari M, Delfino C, Rolfo M, Rizzo A, Berchialla P, et al. Impact of a preoperative video-based educational intervention on postoperative outcomes in elective major abdominal surgery: A randomized controlled trial. J Gastrointest Surg. 2020;24:2295&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32524360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaban ZS, Bulbuloglu S, Kapikiran G, Gunes H, Sahin SK, Saritas S. The effect of bed exercises following major abdominal surgery on early ambulation, mobilization, pain and anxiety: A randomized-controlled trial. Int Wound J. 2023;21:e14406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10824625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37828715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X, Li X, Tang H, Tang L, Tao F, Zhuge H. Impact of intelligent information-based perioperative care on postoperative rehabilitation, complications, and quality of life of patients undergoing gastrointestinal surgery. Medicine. 2023;102:e35977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10659636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37986341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Q, Li H, Zou Y, Hou B, Liu L. Effectiveness of a comprehensive post-operative health education program in improving quality of life after gastric cancer surgery. Ann Palliat Med. 2020;9:921&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32389006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozkan B, Cavdar I. The effect of cold therapy applied to the incision area after abdominal surgery on postoperative pain and analgesic use. Pain Manag Nurs. 2021;22:775&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33903052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wongart S. The effects of symptom management program of gynecological patients after abdominal surgery on postoperative pain and abdominal distention in Suwannaphum hospital, Roi-Et province. J Res Health Innov Dev. 2023;4:112&#x2013;25. (Thai)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaewpia T, Pakanta I, Khamboon T. The effects of planned pain management program on pain and self-practice after abdominal surgery in abdominal injuries patients. J Nurs Health Sci Res. 2023;15:68&#x2013;81. (Thai)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boonploeng K, Pratipanawatr S, Tangsiriwatthana T. Abdominal binder for improving postoperative physical function after benign gynecologic surgery: A randomized controlled trial. Thai J Obstet Gynaecol. 2021;29:10&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wongruang W, Vuttanon N, Udomkhamsuk W. Effect of gum chewing on bowel function recovery in post abdominal surgery patients. Nurs J. 2020;47:157&#x2013;67. (Thai)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worachotthaveewat N, Chamnian P, Thongthaweephokhin S, Kerdprasong N. The effects of the program early postoperative ambulation in patients after abdominal surgery, Phichit hospital. Region 4-5 Med J. 2023;42:583&#x2013;92. (Thai)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thonglor C, Thato R, Supametaporn P. Effects of cold compress using rice-berry pillow on pain after open abdominal surgery in patients with gastrointestinal disease. J Nurs Sci Chulalongkorn Univ. 2023;35:61&#x2013;74. (Thai)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoyun S, Poothawee W, Srisoy A. Effect of post-operative recovery program with the use of easy walk equipment to prevent complications in abdominal surgery patients. Srinagarind Med J. 2019;34:386&#x2013;92. (Thai)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Homvisasevongsa Y, Chuanrum J. Comparison of postoperative pain between patients received and not trained relaxing techniques that use breathing training in patients with abdominal hysterectomy. Med J Srisaket Surin Buriram Hosp. 2019;34:161&#x2013;79. (Thai)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gridana T, Nunthaitaweekul P. The effect of symptom management program combined with abdominal binder with cold compression on pain in patients with open hepatectomy. Thai J Nurs. 2023;72:21&#x2013;31. (Thai)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montgomery R, McNamara SA. Multimodal pain management for enhanced recovery: Reinforcing the shift from traditional pathways through nurse-led interventions. AORN J. 2016;104:S9&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27884220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niyonkuru E, Iqbal MA, Zhang X, Ma P. Complementary approaches to postoperative pain management: A review of non-pharmacological interventions. Pain Ther. 2025;14:121&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11751213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39681763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Small C, Laycock H. Acute postoperative pain management. Br J Surg. 2020;107:e70&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31903595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan TJ. Poorly controlled postoperative pain: Prevalence, consequences, and prevention. J Pain Res. 2017;10:2287&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5626380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29026331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil JD, Sefen JAN, Fredericks S. Exploring non-pharmacological methods for pre-operative pain management. Front Surg. 2022;9:801742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8934410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35317192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Kim Y, Lee HJ. Nurse-involved early mobilization in the intensive care unit: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Nurs Crit Care. 2025;30:e13278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11891033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39989266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Ding H, Shen C, Liu Y, Jia N. Evaluating the role of nursing interventions in enhanced recovery after surgery for minimally invasive spine surgery: A retrospective analysis. Front Surg. 2025;12:1519135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11880021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40046500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman SJ, Pericleous A, Downey C, Jayne DG. Postoperative ileus following major colorectal surgery. Br J Surg. 2018;105:797&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29469195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Y, Zhang C, Zhang H, Zhang X, Tang Y, Wu Z, et al. Effect evaluation of different preventive measures for ileus after abdominal operation: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Heliyon. 2024;10:e25412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10867618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38370213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emile SH, Horesh N, Garoufalia Z, Gefen R, Ray-Offor E, Wexner SD. Strategies to reduce ileus after colorectal surgery: A qualitative umbrella review of the collective evidence. Surgery. 2024;175:280&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38042712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willner A, Teske C, Hackert T, Welsch T. Effects of early postoperative mobilization following gastrointestinal surgery: Systematic review and meta-analysis. BJS Open. 2023;7:zrad102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10580147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37846641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debas SA, Chekol WB, Zeleke ME, Mersha AT. Delayed ambulation in adult patients after major abdominal surgery in Northwest Ethiopia: A multicenter prospective follow up study. Sci Rep. 2025;15:13382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12008419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40251300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan H, Su Y, Wang L. Impact of Ahmadi continuing nursing model on self-care ability, stoma complications and quality of life of colostomy patients. BMC Gastroenterol. 2024;24:421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11583414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39573999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranaut R, Pareek B, Samual S. Effect of nurse-led psychosocial intervention on body image distress and treatment compliance among patients undergoing treatment of cancer: A randomized controlled trial. J Educ Health Promot. 2024;13:248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11414846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39309988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bl&#xf6;ndal K, Sveinsd&#xf3;ttir H, Ingadottir B. Patients&#x2019; expectations and experiences of provided surgery-related patient education: A descriptive longitudinal study. Nurs Open. 2022;9:2495&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9374389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35666048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton LL, Duff E, Arora RC, McMillan DE. Surgery patients&#x2019; perspectives of their role in postoperative pain: A scoping review. Int J Nurs Stud Adv. 2023;5:100124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11080476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38746556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoja M, Arsalani N, Fallahi-Khoshknab M, Mohammadi-Shahboulaghi F. The barriers and facilitators to nursing care for patients with permanent colostomy in outpatient centers: A qualitative study. J Educ Health Promot. 2024;13:72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10979781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38559476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>