<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41888548</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-5403</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cell death and differentiation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cell Death Differ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Proteasome inhibition promotes Foxn1 expression in thymic epithelial cells and induces thymic regeneration in mice.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41418-026-01724-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The thymus plays a critical role in sustaining T-cell immunity, although its function is highly vulnerable to acute injury and physiologically declines with age, resulting in compromised immune responses. Impaired thymic function represents a major clinical challenge, particularly in settings of immunosuppression associated with cancer therapy and aging. Yet, effective strategies to rejuvenate the thymus remain limited. To explore novel regenerative approaches, we focused on FOXN1, a master regulator of thymic epithelial cell (TEC) development and function. By developing a custom screening platform, we tested a library of FDA-approved compounds for their ability to induce FOXN1 in TECs. Proteasome inhibition emerged as a potent and previously unrecognized mechanism for upregulating FOXN1 in both murine and human primary TECs. Among the hits identified in the screening, the antiparasitic drug nitazoxanide (NTZ) stood out for its proteasome inhibitory activity and for inducing Foxn1 expression while preserving cell viability, unlike other proteasome inhibitors. Mechanistically, NTZ-induced proteasome inhibition triggered endoplasmic reticulum stress (ER) and the adaptive unfolded protein response (UPR), ultimately engaging autophagy in TECs. In this context, the induction of autophagy acted as a compensatory mechanism to support cell survival in response to proteasome inhibition. Notably, when administered in mice, NTZ significantly accelerated functional thymic recovery after radiation-induced damage, promoting restoration of thymic architecture and cellularity of both stromal and hematopoietic compartments without disrupting physiological T-cell selection or tolerance mechanisms. Consistent with our in vitro findings, NTZ treatment induced Foxn1 and its downstream targets in TECs in vivo and conferred protection to TECs following irradiation. These findings uncover proteasome inhibition and, more broadly, modulation of ER stress and UPR pathways as a previously unrecognized mechanism regulating Foxn1 expression and position NTZ as a promising pharmacological strategy to enhance immunity in patients experiencing T-cell deficiencies due to cancer-related immunosuppression, infections, and age-related thymic atrophy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to ADMC Associazione Differenziamento e Morte Cellulare.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Genah</LastName><ForeName>Shirley</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Hematology and Oncology Research Area, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pellegrino</LastName><ForeName>Marsha</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Hematology and Oncology Research Area, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giansanti</LastName><ForeName>Manuela</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Immunology Research Area, Innate Lymphoid Cells, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mancusi</LastName><ForeName>Angelica</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-0150-9825</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Hematology and Oncology Research Area, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taviani</LastName><ForeName>Alessio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Hematology and Oncology Research Area, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cardinale</LastName><ForeName>Antonella</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Hematology and Oncology Research Area, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosichini</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Hematology and Oncology Research Area, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Immunotherapy Integrated Research Center, Division of Translational Science and Therapeutics, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Flamini</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Hematology and Oncology Research Area, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Catanoso</LastName><ForeName>Maria Luigia</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Hematology and Oncology Research Area, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giorda</LastName><ForeName>Ezio</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5875-832X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Laboratories, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Volpe</LastName><ForeName>Gabriele</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Laboratories, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piccione</LastName><ForeName>Michela</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Laboratories, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nazio</LastName><ForeName>Francesca</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Immunology Research Area, Innate Lymphoid Cells, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, University of Rome Tor Vergata, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dudakov</LastName><ForeName>Jarrod A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6220-5632</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Immunotherapy Integrated Research Center, Division of Translational Science and Therapeutics, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van den Brink</LastName><ForeName>Marcel R M</ForeName><Initials>MRM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0696-4401</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>City of Hope Los Angeles and National Medical Center, Duarte, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Billy</LastName><ForeName>Emmanuel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Catholic University of the Sacred Heart, Department of Basic Biotechnological Sciences, Intensive Care and Perioperative Clinics, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Locatelli</LastName><ForeName>Franco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7976-3654</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Hematology and Oncology Research Area, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Maternal and Child Health, Catholic University of the Sacred Heart, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Velardi</LastName><ForeName>Enrico</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8383-0453</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Hematology and Oncology Research Area, Bambino Ges&#xf9; Children's Hospital IRCCS, Rome, Italy. enrico.velardi@opbg.net.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>GR-2019-12369231</GrantID><Agency>Ministero della Salute (Ministry of Health, Italy)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>RF-2016-02364388</GrantID><Agency>Ministero della Salute (Ministry of Health, Italy)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>29932</GrantID><Agency>Associazione Italiana per la Ricerca sul Cancro (Italian Association for Cancer Research)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>27019</GrantID><Agency>Associazione Italiana per la Ricerca sul Cancro (Italian Association for Cancer Research)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>21147</GrantID><Agency>Associazione Italiana per la Ricerca sul Cancro (Italian Association for Cancer Research)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>PRIN ID 2017 WC8499_004</GrantID><Agency>Ministero dell'Istruzione, dell'Universit&#xe0; e della Ricerca (Ministry of Education, University and Research)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Cell Death Differ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9437445</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-9047</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: GS is supported by a FIRC-AIRC fellowship for Italy. RM was supported by an AIRC Fellowship for Abroad. VE was supported by grants from the Rally Foundation Investigator Award, Amy Stelzer Manasevit Research Program, the Italian Association for Cancer Research, and by the Italian Ministry of Health with &#x201c;Current Research funds. LF was supported by grants from AIRC (Special Program Metastatic disease: the key unmet need in oncology 5 per mille 2018 Project Code 21147 and Accelerator Award 2017 INCAR); Ministero dell&#x2019;Istruzione, dell&#x2019;Universit&#xe0; e della Ricerca, PRIN ID 2017 WC8499_004; Ministero della Salute, RF-2016-02364388. EdB received funding from Research (PRIN PNRR P2022JLHZZ), Ministero della Salute (GR-2019-12369231), by MIA Neri Foundation and by Heal Foundation. FN lab is supported by the &#x201c;Associazione Italiana Ricerca sul Cancro&#x201d; (My First Airc Grant -Ref. 27019), by &#x201c;CureSearch Young Investigator Awards in Pediatric Oncology Drug Development&#x201d;, by &#x201c;Fondazione Roche per la Ricerca Indipendente&#x201d;, by the Italian Ministry of University and Research (PRIN PNRR P2022JLHZZ), Ministero della Salute (GR-2019-12369231) and by MIA Neri Foundation. EV has received research funding from ToleranceBio for projects outside the submitted work. FL reports personal fees from Amgen, personal fees from Novartis, other from Bellicum Pharmaceutical, other from Neovii, personal fees from Miltenyi, personal fees from Medac, personal fees from Jazz Pharmaceutical, personal fees from Takeda, outside the submitted work. A patent application entitled &#x201c;FOXN1-activating compounds and their use in thymic regeneration&#x201d; has been filed (PCT/IT2025/050304). Ethics approval: All animals were purchased from Charles River and maintained in the Plaisant Castel Romano animal facility in Rome. Mice experiments were conducted in compliance with the EU and national ethical requirements and were approved by the Italian Health Ministry. Human thymic samples for hTEC culture were obtained from pediatric patients undergoing corrective cardiac surgery. All samples were anonymously collected in accordance with local ethical guidelines, written informed consent was obtained, and the protocol was approved by the Ethics Committee of OPBG Hospital.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41888548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41418-026-01724-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41418-026-01724-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Anderson G, Jenkinson EJ. Lymphostromal interactions in thymic development and function. Nat Rev Immunol. 2001;1:31&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11905812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/35095500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahama Y. Journey through the thymus: stromal guides for T-cell development and selection. Nat Rev Immunol. 2006;6:127&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16491137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nri1781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrie HT, Z&#xfa;&#xf1;iga-Pfl&#xfc;cker JC. Zoned out: functional mapping of stromal signaling microenvironments in the thymus. Annu Rev Immunol. 2007;25:649&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17291187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.immunol.23.021704.115715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosichini M, Bordoni V, Silvestris DA, Mariotti D, Matusali G, Cardinale A, et al. SARS-CoV-2 infection of thymus induces loss of function that correlates with disease severity. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2023;151:911&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36758836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9907790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2023.01.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velardi E, Clave E, Arruda LCM, Benini F, Locatelli F, Toubert A. The role of the thymus in allogeneic bone marrow transplantation and the recovery of the peripheral T-cell compartment. Semin Immunopathol. 2021;43:101&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33416938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00281-020-00828-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velardi E, Tsai JJ, van den Brink MRM. T cell regeneration after immunological injury. Nat Rev Immunol. 2021;21:277&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33097917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41577-020-00457-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komanduri KV, St John LS, De Lima M, McMannis J, Rosinski S, McNiece I, et al. Delayed immune reconstitution after cord blood transplantation is characterized by impaired thymopoiesis and late memory T-cell skewing. Blood. 2007;110:4543&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17671230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2234787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2007-05-092130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clave E, Lisini D, Douay C, Giorgiani G, Busson M, Zecca M, et al. A low thymic function is associated with leukemia relapse in children given T-cell-depleted HLA-haploidentical stem cell transplantation. Leukemia. 2012;26:1886&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22430571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/leu.2012.59</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf6;derstr&#xf6;m A, Vonlanthen S, J&#xf6;nsson-Vides&#xe4;ter K, Mielke S, Lindahl H, T&#xf6;rl&#xe9;n J, et al. T cell receptor excision circles are potential predictors of survival in adult allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation recipients with acute myeloid leukemia. Front Immunol. 2022;13:954716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36211398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9540498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.954716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troullioud Lucas AG, Lindemans CA, Bhoopalan SV, Dandis R, Prockop SE, Naik S, et al. Early immune reconstitution as predictor for outcomes after allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplant; a tri-institutional analysis. Cytotherapy. 2023;25:977&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37330731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10984694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcyt.2023.05.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg JD, Zheng J, Ratan R, Small TN, Lai K-C, Boulad F, et al. Early recovery of T-cell function predicts improved survival after T-cell depleted allogeneic transplant. Leuk Lymphoma. 2017;58:1859&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28073320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5454777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10428194.2016.1265113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartelink IH, Belitser SV, Knibbe CAJ, Danhof M, De Pagter AJ, Egberts TCG, et al. Immune reconstitution kinetics as an early predictor for mortality using various hematopoietic stem cell sources in children. Biol Blood Marrow Transpl. 2013;19:305&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbmt.2012.10.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Admiraal R, Chiesa R, Lindemans CA, Nierkens S, Bierings MB, Versluijs AB, et al. Leukemia-free survival in myeloid leukemia, but not in lymphoid leukemia, is predicted by early CD4+ reconstitution following unrelated cord blood transplantation in children: a multicenter retrospective cohort analysis. Bone Marrow Transpl. 2016;51:1376&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/bmt.2016.116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clave E, Lisini D, Douay C, Giorgiani G, Busson M, Zecca M et al. Thymic function recovery after unrelated donor cord blood or T-cell depleted HLA-haploidentical stem cell transplantation correlates with leukemia relapse. Front Immunol. 2013;4. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2013.00054 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maury S, Mary J, Rabian C, Schwarzinger M, Toubert A, Scieux C, et al. Prolonged immune deficiency following allogeneic stem cell transplantation: risk factors and complications in adult patients. Br J Haematol. 2001;115:630&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11736948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2141.2001.03135.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsamadou C, Gowdavally S, Platzbecker U, Sala E, Valerius T, Wagner-Drouet E, et al. Donor genetic determinant of thymopoiesis rs2204985 impacts clinical outcome after single HLA mismatched hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Bone Marrow Transpl. 2022;57:1539&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41409-022-01751-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson G, Cosway EJ, James KD, Ohigashi I, Takahama Y. Generation and repair of thymic epithelial cells. J Exp Med. 2024;221:e20230894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38980292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11232892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1084/jem.20230894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granadier D, Acenas D, Dudakov JA. Endogenous thymic regeneration: restoring T cell production following injury. Nat Rev Immunol. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41577-024-01119-0 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wertheimer T, Velardi E, Tsai J, Cooper K, Xiao S, Kloss CC, et al. Production of BMP4 by endothelial cells is crucial for endogenous thymic regeneration. Sci Immunol. 2018;3:eaal2736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29330161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5795617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciimmunol.aal2736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaidya HJ, Briones Leon A, Blackburn CC. FOXN1 in thymus organogenesis and development. Eur J Immunol. 2016;46:1826&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27378598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4988515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eji.201545814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x17d;uklys S, Handel A, Zhanybekova S, Govani F, Keller M, Maio S, et al. Foxn1 regulates key target genes essential for T cell development in postnatal thymic epithelial cells. Nat Immunol. 2016;17:1206&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27548434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5033077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ni.3537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinsella S, Evandy CA, Cooper K, Cardinale A, Iovino L, deRoos P et al. Damage-induced pyroptosis drives endogenous thymic regeneration via induction of Foxn1 by purinergic receptor activation. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1101/2023.01.19.524800 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J, Hu R, Lai KC, Zhang Z, Lai L. Recombinant FOXN1 fusion protein increases T cell generation in old mice. Front Immunol. 2024;15:1423488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39072332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11272594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2024.1423488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y, Su M, Zhu J, Di W, Liu Y, Hu R, et al. FOXN1 recombinant protein enhances T-cell regeneration after hematopoietic stem cell transplantation in mice. Eur J Immunol. 2016;46:1518&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27125859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eji.201546196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zook EC, Krishack PA, Zhang S, Zeleznik-Le NJ, Firulli AB, Witte PL, et al. Overexpression of Foxn1 attenuates age-associated thymic involution and prevents the expansion of peripheral CD4 memory T cells. Blood. 2011;118:5723&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21908422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3228493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2011-03-342097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bredenkamp N, Nowell CS, Blackburn CC. Regeneration of the aged thymus by a single transcription factor. Development. 2014;141:1627&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24715454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3978836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/dev.103614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Xiao S, Manley NR. Foxn1 is required to maintain the postnatal thymic microenvironment in a dosage-sensitive manner. Blood. 2009;113:567&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18978204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2008-05-156265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosticardo M, Yamazaki Y, Cowan J, Giardino G, Corsino C, Scalia G, et al. Heterozygous FOXN1 variants cause low TRECs and severe T cell lymphopenia, revealing a crucial role of FOXN1 in supporting early thymopoiesis. Am J Hum Genet. 2019;105:549&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31447097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6731368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajhg.2019.07.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moses A, Bhalla P, Thompson A, Lai L, Coskun FS, Seroogy CM, et al. Comprehensive phenotypic analysis of diverse FOXN1 variants. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2023;152:1273&#x2013;1291.e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37419334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11071152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2023.06.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen BM, Cowan JE, Wang Y, Tanaka Y, Zhao Y, Voisin B, et al. Identification of an intronic regulatory element necessary for tissue-specific expression of Foxn1 in thymic epithelial cells. J Immunol. 2019;203:686&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31243087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6650349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.1801540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadouri N, Givony T, Nevo S, Hey J, Ben Dor S, Damari G, et al. Transcriptional regulation of the thymus master regulator Foxn1. Sci Immunol. 2022;7:eabn8144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36026441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciimmunol.abn8144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossignol J-F. Nitazoxanide: a first-in-class broad-spectrum antiviral agent. Antivir Res. 2014;110:94&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25108173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7113776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.antiviral.2014.07.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossignol J-F, Abu-Zekry M, Hussein A, Santoro MG. Effect of nitazoxanide for treatment of severe rotavirus diarrhoea: randomised double-blind placebo-controlled trial. Lancet. 2006;368:124&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16829296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(06)68852-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossignol JA, Ayoub A, Ayers MS. Treatment of diarrhea caused by Cryptosporidium parvum: a prospective randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study of nitazoxanide. J Infect Dis. 2001;184:103&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11398117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/321008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossignol J, Ayoub A, Ayers MS. Treatment of diarrhea caused by Giardia intestinalis and Entamoeba histolytica or E. dispar: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study of nitazoxanide. J Infect Dis. 2001;184:381&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11443569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/322038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson VR, Curran MP. Nitazoxanide: a review of its use in the treatment of gastrointestinal infections. Drugs. 2007;67:1947&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17722965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00003495-200767130-00015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilles HM, Hoffman PS. Treatment of intestinal parasitic infections: a review of nitazoxanide. Trends Parasitol. 2002;18:95&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11854075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1471-4922(01)02205-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haffizulla J, Hartman A, Hoppers M, Resnick H, Samudrala S, Ginocchio C, et al. Effect of nitazoxanide in adults and adolescents with acute uncomplicated influenza: a double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 2b/3 trial. Lancet Infect Dis. 2014;14:609&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24852376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7164783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(14)70717-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc; Z, Li X, Li K, Ripani P, Shi X, Xu F, et al. Nitazoxanide and related thiazolides induce cell death in cancer cells by targeting the 20S proteasome with novel binding modes. Biochem Pharm. 2022;197:114913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35032461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bcp.2022.114913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Shi C, He M, Xiong S, Xia X. Endoplasmic reticulum stress: molecular mechanism and therapeutic targets. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2023;8:352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37709773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10502142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41392-023-01570-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hetz C, Zhang K, Kaufman RJ. Mechanisms, regulation and functions of the unfolded protein response. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2020;21:421&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32457508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8867924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41580-020-0250-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyce M, Bryant KF, Jousse C, Long K, Harding HP, Scheuner D, et al. A selective inhibitor of eIF2&#x3b1; dephosphorylation protects cells from ER stress. Science. 2005;307:935&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15705855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1101902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wortel IMN, Van Der Meer LT, Kilberg MS, Van Leeuwen FN. Surviving stress: modulation of ATF4-mediated stress responses in normal and malignant cells. Trends Endocrinol Metab. 2017;28:794&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28797581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5951684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tem.2017.07.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neill G, Masson GR. A stay of execution: ATF4 regulation and potential outcomes for the integrated stress response. Front Mol Neurosci. 2023;16:1112253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36825279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9941348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnmol.2023.1112253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Q, Nicol SA, Suen AYW, Baldwin TA. Examination of thymic positive and negative selection by flow cytometry. J Vis Exp. 2012;68:4269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Wachsmuth LP, Xiao S, Condie BG, Manley NR. Foxn1 overexpression promotes thymic epithelial progenitor cell proliferation and mTEC maintenance, but does not prevent thymic involution. Dev Camb Engl. 2023;150:dev200995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Q, Huynh LK, Coskun F, Molina E, King MA, Raj P, et al. FOXN1 compound heterozygous mutations cause selective thymic hypoplasia in humans. J Clin Invest. 2019;129:4724&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31566583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6819092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI127565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kousa AI, Jahn L, Zhao K, Flores AE, Acenas D, Lederer E, et al. Age-related epithelial defects limit thymic function and regeneration. Nat Immunol. 2024;25:1593&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39112630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11362016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-024-01915-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horie K, Namiki K, Kinoshita K, Miyauchi M, Ishikawa T, Hayama M, et al. Acute irradiation causes a long-term disturbance in the heterogeneity and gene expression profile of medullary thymic epithelial cells. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1186154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38022666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10652284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1186154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bredenkamp N, Nowell CS, Blackburn CC. Regeneration of the aged thymus by a single transcription factor. Dev Camb Engl. 2014;141:1627&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasan J, Lancaster JN, Singarapu N, Hale LP, Ehrlich LIR, Richie ER. Age-related changes in thymic central tolerance. Front Immunol. 2021;12:676236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33968086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8100025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.676236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takaba H, Takayanagi H. The mechanisms of T cell selection in the thymus. Trends Immunol. 2017;38:805&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28830733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.it.2017.07.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elyahu Y, Monsonego A. Thymus involution sets the clock of the aging T-cell landscape: Implications for declined immunity and tissue repair. Ageing Res Rev. 2021;65:101231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33248315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2020.101231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Z, Dong X, Zhang Z, Zhang Q, Zhao Y. Age-related thymic involution: mechanisms and functional impact. Aging Cell. 2022;21:e13671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35822239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9381902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acel.13671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manasanch EE, Orlowski RZ. Proteasome inhibitors in cancer therapy. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2017;14:417&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28117417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5828026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrclinonc.2016.206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Li X, Liu J, Lin X, Pei L, Boyce BF, et al. Proteasome inhibition-enhanced fracture repair is associated with increased mesenchymal progenitor cells in mice. PloS One. 2022;17:e0263839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35213543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8880819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0263839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Attarilar S, Xie K, Han C, Qingyang Liang, Huang K, et al. Carfilzomib alleviated osteoporosis by targeting PSME1/2 to activate Wnt/&#x3b2;-catenin signaling. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2022;540:111520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34838695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mce.2021.111520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caron AZ, Haroun S, Leblanc &#xc9;, Trensz F, Guindi C, Amrani A, et al. The proteasome inhibitor MG132 reduces immobilization-induced skeletal muscle atrophy in mice. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2011;12:185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21843349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3173404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2474-12-185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padrissa-Alt&#xe9;s S, Zaouali MA, Boncompagni E, Bonaccorsi-Riani E, Carbonell T, Bardag-Gorce F, et al. The use of a reversible proteasome inhibitor in a model of Reduced-Size Orthotopic Liver transplantation in rats. Exp Mol Pathol. 2012;93:99&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22475623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yexmp.2012.03.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Homsi AS, Feng Y, Duffner U, Al Malki MM, Goodyke A, Cole K, et al. Bortezomib for the prevention and treatment of graft-versus-host disease after allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Exp Hematol. 2016;44:771&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27224851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exphem.2016.05.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magenau JM, Reddy P. Proteasome: target for acute and chronic GVHD?. Blood. 2014;124:1551&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25190753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4155267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2014-07-589309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun K, Welniak LA, Panoskaltsis-Mortari A, O&#x2019;Shaughnessy MJ, Liu H, Barao I, et al. Inhibition of acute graft-versus-host disease with retention of graft-versus-tumor effects by the proteasome inhibitor bortezomib. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2004;101:8120&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15148407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">419567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0401563101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson AJ, Clegg CH, Farr AG. In vitro positive selection and anergy induction of class II-restricted TCR transgenic thymocytes by a cortical thymic epithelial cell line. Int Immunol. 1998;10:1335&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9786433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intimm/10.9.1335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neil R, Wei Q, Condie B. High efficiency transfection of thymic epithelial cell lines and primary thymic epithelial cells by Nucleofection. Nat Preced. 2011. https://doi.org/10.1038/npre.2011.6283.1 .</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>