<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41744139</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0972-9941</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of minimal access surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Minim Access Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessment of the efficacy and safety of enhanced recovery after surgery in the thoracoscopic adjuvant treatment of radical surgery for oesophageal carcinoma: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/jmas.jmas_205_24</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the efficacy and safety assessment of intensive post-operative recovery during thoracoscopic-assisted radical oesophageal carcinoma (OC) treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The meta-analysis was conducted in accordance with Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses guidelines, and English terms were searched in PubMed, Embase, Cochrane Library (2020, Issue 1) and Web of Science, and the same Chinese terms were searched in China National Knowledge Internet and Wanfang Data, with the date range set from January 2010 to January 2020. Search engines, including Google Scholar and Baidu Library, were also applied for manual searches of relevant literature. The final number of articles included was 12, 11 of which were in Chinese and one in English. The basic data of the two groups were statistically analysed. Among 1049 OC patients, 527 were treated with enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) and 522 were treated with conventional perioperative management (control group), comparing the operative time, intraoperative blood loss, self-rating anxiety scale (SAS), visual analog scale (VAS), post-operative first venting time, chest tube removal time, post-operative hospitalisation time, post-operative hospitalisation cost, combined complication rate, lung infection rate, anastomotic leak rate and gastric emptying disorder rate.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">There were statistically significant differences between the ERAS group and the control group in terms of operative day anxiety score, post-operative Visual Analogue Scale, time to first post-operative anal vent, time to chest tube removal, post-operative hospital stay, hospitalisation cost and overall complication rate (weighted mean difference [WMD] = -5.61, 95% confidence interval [CI]: -7.95 to -3.28, P &lt; 0.00001; WMD = -1.58, 95% CI: -1.58, -1.94 to -1.22, P &lt; 0.00001; standardized mean difference [SMD] = -1.86, 95% CI: -2.53 to -1.18, P &lt; 0.00001; SMD = -4.97, 95% CI: -6:73 to -3.21, P &lt; 0.00001; WMD = -3.93, 95% CI: -4.80 to -3.07, P &lt; 0.00001; WMD = -0.65, 95% CI: -0.74~-0.55, P &lt; 0.00001 and relative risk [RR] =0.41, 95% CI: 0.33-0.51, P &lt; 0.00001). ERAS reduced the incidence of pulmonary infection, anastomotic leak and impaired gastric emptying with a statistically significant difference (RR =0.45, 95% CI: 0.31-0.65, P &lt; 0.0001; RR =0.34, 95% CI: 0.16-0.74, P &lt; 0.05; RR =0.34, 95% CI: 0.16-0.73, P &lt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">ERAS is effective in patients with OC undergoing thoracoscopic-assisted radical OC treatment to improve patients' clinical symptoms and reduce the incidence of adverse effects.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Journal of Minimal Access Surgery.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Yingming</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Esophagogastric Surgery, Heping Hospital Affiliated to Changzhi Medical College, Changzhi, Shanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xi</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Science and Education Department, The Second People's Hospital of Luzhou District, Changzhi, Shanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Na</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Esophagogastric Surgery, The First Clinical College of Changzhi Medical College, Changzhi, Shanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Esophagogastric Surgery, The First Clinical College of Changzhi Medical College, Changzhi, Shanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Guotai</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Esophagogastric Surgery, The First Clinical College of Changzhi Medical College, Changzhi, Shanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Liwan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Esophagogastric Surgery, The First Clinical College of Changzhi Medical College, Changzhi, Shanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niu</LastName><ForeName>Yuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Esophagogastric Surgery, The First Clinical College of Changzhi Medical College, Changzhi, Shanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Minim Access Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101228183</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1998-3921</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enhanced recovery after surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oesophageal carcinoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thoracic laparoscopy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41744139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jmas.jmas_205_24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01413045-990000000-00226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kehlet H. Multimodal approach to control postoperative pathophysiology and rehabilitation. Surv Anesthesiol 1998;42:233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Z. Concept and development history of external science of accelerated rehabilitation. Chin J Gen Surg 2018;33:625&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L. Comparative analysis of clinical efficacy of thoracoscopic radical esophagectomy and open radical esophagectomy for esophageal cancer. Electron J Clin Med Lit 2018;5:55&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Egger M, Smith GD. Systematic reviews in health care:Investigating and dealing with publication and other biases in meta-analysis. Br Med J 2001;323:101&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C. Effect of Accelerated Rehabilitation Surgery Nursing on Anxiety and Sleep of Elderly Patients with Esophageal Cancer Surgery North Sichuan Medical College; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling FY, Xiong JW, Yu DL, Wei YP, Xu JJ, Zhang WX, et al. Application value of the concept of accelerated rehabilitation surgery in the perioperative period of minimally invasive radical esophagectomy. World Chin J Gastroenterol 2017;25:1491&#x2013;6. Available from: http://www.wjgnet.com/1009-3079/full/v25/i16/1491.htm. [Last accessed on 2024 Oct 02].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang DK, Xu Q, Zhao RH, Xiang CX, Wang HY. Application of rapid rehabilitation nursing in perioperative period of esophageal cancer combined with thoracoscopy and laparoscopy. Anhui Med J 2019;23:778&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y. Effect of rapid rehabilitation concept on postoperative recovery of thoracoscopic laparoscopic radical esophagectomy. Gen Nurs 2016;14:2228&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding W. Application of rapid rehabilitation concept in perioperative nursing of thoracoscopic and laparoscopic radical esophagectomy. Med Health Care 2014;22:124&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J. Experience of rapid rehabilitation concept in preoperative and postoperative nursing of thoracoscopic combined with esophageal cancer. Health Everyone 2015;412:2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He JH, Dong B, Zheng GF, Li JH. Application of fast track surgery strategy in thoracoscopic combined with laparoscopic esophagectomy and cervical anastomosis. West Med 2018;30:385&#x2013;9, 94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong H. Application effect of fast track surgery concept in perioperative period of total thoracic laparoscopic radical esophagectomy. Henan Med Res 2019;28:2842&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Geng Q, Wang G. Application of fast track surgery concept in perioperative nursing of total thoracic laparoscopic radical esophagectomy. S China J Natl Def Med 2017;31:811&#x2013;3, 21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu X, Zhou J, Du W, Chen G, Li W, Chen X, et al. Application of fast track surgery concept in patients undergoing thoracoscopic combined with laparoscopic esophagectomy. Hainan Med J 2018;29:349&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng G. Accelerated rehabilitation surgery for esophageal cancer. Chin J Mod Med 2019;13:237&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Zheng B, Zhang S, Chen H, Zheng W, Chen C. Feasibility and outcomes of modified enhanced recovery after surgery for nursing management of aged patients undergoing esophagectomy. J Thorac Dis 2017;9:5212&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukhtar S, Ayres BE, Issa R, Swinn MJ, Perry MJ. Challenging boundaries:An enhanced recovery program for radio cystology. Ann Royal Coll Surg Engl 2013;95:200&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B, Chen C, Chen Y, Cao W, Ning J. Application experience of accelerated rehabilitation surgery concept in perioperative period of esophageal cancer in primary hospital. Sichuan Med J 2017;38:1407&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q, Li Y, Liu X, Sun H, Zhang R, Wang Z, et al. Application of accelerated rehabilitation surgery in the treatment of elderly patients with esophageal cancer. Chin J Thorac surg 2016;3:89&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao Y, Yao Y. Meta analysis of the application of accelerated rehabilitation surgery in laparoscopic assisted distal gastrectomy for gastric cancer. Mod Med Health 2019;35:43&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Wang C. Application of accelerated rehabilitation surgery in perioperative period of esophageal cancer. Med Inf 2016;29:380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batchelor TJ, Rasburn NJ, Abdelnour-Berchtold E, Brunelli A, Cerfolio RJ, Gonzalez M, et al. Guidelines for enhanced recovery after lung surgery:recommendations of the Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS&#xae;) Society and the European Society of Thoracic Surgeons (ESTS). Eur J Cardiothorac Surg 2019;55:91&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>