<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41876684</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Application of a complex Si-Al-Fe reducing agent for the production of a nickel-containing alloy.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-45605-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To address the significant environmental challenges and technological limitations of conventional carbothermic ferronickel production, this study presents and optimizes an innovative metallothermic smelting process employing a complex silicon-aluminum-iron reducing agent (ferrosilicoaluminum, FeSiAl). For the first time, a comprehensive methodology integrating thermodynamic analysis, kinetic modeling, experimental design, and pilot-scale validation smelting has been applied to optimize the production of a nickel-containing alloy from lateritic ores of the Batamsha deposit (Kazakhstan). Thermodynamic modeling (HSC Chemistry) demonstrated that the combined use of Si and Al creates more favorable conditions for NiO reduction compared with their separate application, as evidenced by more negative &#x394;G values and higher equilibrium constants over the investigated temperature range (100-1600&#xa0;&#xb0;C). Kinetic analysis based on non-isothermal thermogravimetric and differential thermal analysis (TG-DTA) revealed a pronounced synergistic effect: the FeSiAl system exhibits the lowest apparent activation energy (16.15&#xa0;kJ mol<sup>-1</sup>, which is 57% and 68% lower than those for ferrosilicon and aluminum-containing slag, respectively. This indicates a substantially enhanced reducibility and lower kinetic limitations. Process optimization was achieved through thermodynamic modeling in FactSage combined with a second-order rotatable central composite design (CCD). This approach enabled the development of predictive response surface models and the determination of optimal process parameters: smelting temperature of 1300-1350&#xa0;&#xb0;C, FeSiAl addition of 10 wt%, and lime flux addition of 38-40 wt%. Validation smelting experiments conducted in a laboratory ore-thermal electric furnace confirmed the accuracy of the model, yielding 9.5&#xa0;kg of a multicomponent alloy with the following composition (wt%): Fe 70.0, Ni 8.0, Si 17.0, Cr 3.5, and Al 0.8. The accompanying slag exhibited a technologically favorable composition (wt%): SiO<sub>2</sub> 48.6, CaO 36.4, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> 10.2, and MgO 4.5, with a very low residual nickel oxide content (NiO 0.1%), confirming the high reduction efficiency. The recovery rates of iron and chromium into the metallic phase were 71% and 83%, respectively. The resulting Fe-Ni-Si-Cr-Al alloy is proposed as a potential master alloy for steelmaking or as a reducing agent in metallurgical processes. The developed FeSiAl-based metallothermic process represents an energy-efficient and environmentally more sustainable alternative to conventional carbothermic technology.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yessengaliyev</LastName><ForeName>Dauren</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Metallurgy and Mining, K. Zhubanov Aktobe Regional University, Aktobe, 030000, Kazakhstan. dyessengaliyev@zhubanov.edu.kz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kelamanov</LastName><ForeName>Bauyrzhan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Metallurgy and Mining, K. Zhubanov Aktobe Regional University, Aktobe, 030000, Kazakhstan. bkelamanov@zhubanov.edu.kz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zayakin</LastName><ForeName>Oleg</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vatolin institute of metallurgy of the Ural Branch of the Russian Academy of Sciences, Ekaterinburg, 620016, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sariyev</LastName><ForeName>Otegen</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Metallurgy and Mining, K. Zhubanov Aktobe Regional University, Aktobe, 030000, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mikhailova</LastName><ForeName>Lyudmila</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vatolin institute of metallurgy of the Ural Branch of the Russian Academy of Sciences, Ekaterinburg, 620016, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhuniskaliyev</LastName><ForeName>Talgat</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Science, Eurasian Technological University, Almaty, 050000, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuatbay</LastName><ForeName>Yerbol</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Metallurgy and Materials Science, Karaganda Industrial University, Temirtau, 101400, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nurgali</LastName><ForeName>Nurzhan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ERG Research and Engineering Center, Astana, 010000, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abikenova</LastName><ForeName>Gulnur</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ERG Research and Engineering Center, Astana, 010000, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdirashit</LastName><ForeName>Assylbek</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Metallurgy and Mining, K. Zhubanov Aktobe Regional University, Aktobe, 030000, Kazakhstan. aabdirashit@zhubanov.edu.kz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abilberikova</LastName><ForeName>Aigerim</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Metallurgy and Mining, K. Zhubanov Aktobe Regional University, Aktobe, 030000, Kazakhstan. a.abilberikova@tttu.edu.kz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Metallurgy and Materials Science, Karaganda Industrial University, Temirtau, 101400, Kazakhstan. a.abilberikova@tttu.edu.kz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>AP22783247</GrantID><Agency>Science Committee of the Ministry of Science and Higher Education of the Republic of Kazakhstan</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aluminum slag</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ferrosilicoaluminum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ferrosilicon</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lateritic nickel ore</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metallothermy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nickel-containing alloy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rotatable central composite design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thermodynamic modeling</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41876684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-45605-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-45605-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Norgate, T. E., Jahanshahi, S. &amp; Rankin, W. J. Assessing the environmental impact of metal production processes. J. Clean. Prod. 15, 838&#x2013;848. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2006.06.018 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudd, G. M. Global trends and environmental issues in nickel mining and processing. Ore Geol. Rev. 38, 9&#x2013;26. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oregeorev.2010.05.003 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grundwell, F., Moats, M., Ramachandran, V. &amp; Robinson, T. Extractive Metallurgy of Nickel, Cobalt and Platinum Group Metals (Elsevier, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickles, C. A., Forster, J. &amp; Elliott, R. Thermodynamic analysis of the carbothermic reduction roasting of a nickeliferous limonitic laterite ore. Miner. Eng. 65, 33&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mineng.2014.05.006 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv, X., Lv, W., You, Z., Lv, X. &amp; Bai, C. Non-isothermal kinetics study on carbothermic reduction of nickel laterite ore. Powder Technol. 340, 495&#x2013;501. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.powtec.2018.09.061 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelamanov, B. et al. Thermodynamic-diagram analysis of the Fe&#x2013;Ni&#x2013;C&#x2013;O system. Metalurgija 61, 261&#x2013;264 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalvi, A. D., Bacon, W. G. &amp; Osborne, R. C. March. The past and the future of nickel laterites. In Proceedings of the PDAC 2004 International Convention (Toronto, Canada, 7&#x2013;10 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butt, C. R. M. &amp; Cluzel, D. Nickel laterite ore deposits: Weathered serpentines. Elements 9, 123&#x2013;128. https://doi.org/10.2113/gselements.9.2.123 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elias, M. Nickel laterite deposits: Geological overview, resources and exploitation. Gondwana Res. 5, 3&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1342-937X(05)70994-0 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliot, R., Pickles, C. A. &amp; Forster, J. Thermodynamics of the reduction roasting of nickeliferous laterite ores. J. Miner. Mater. Charact. Eng. 4, 320&#x2013;346. https://doi.org/10.4236/jmmce.2016.46028 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao, M. et al. Carbothermic reduction of nickeliferous laterite ores for nickel pig iron production in China: A review. JOM 65, 1573&#x2013;1582. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11837-013-0760-7 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdirashit, A. et al. Investigation of the possibility of obtaining nickel-containing ferroalloys from lateritic nickel ores by a metallothermic method. Metals 15, 428. https://doi.org/10.3390/met15040428 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, X. et al. Effect of co-reduction conditions of nickel laterite ore and red mud on ferronickel particle size characteristics and grindability of carbothermic reduction products. Minerals 12, 357. https://doi.org/10.3390/min12030357 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelamanov, B. et al. Technological analysis of the production of nickel-containing composite materials. J. Compos. Sci. 8, 179. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcs8050179 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdirashit, A. et al. Study of nickel&#x2013;chromium-containing ferroalloy production. Processes 13, 1258. https://doi.org/10.3390/pr13041258 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salina, V. N., Zhuchkov, V. I. &amp; Zayakin, O. V. Study of nickel and iron reduction silicothermic process by thermodynamic simulation. Ferrous Metall. Bull. Sci. Tech. Econ. Inf. 76, 365&#x2013;371. https://doi.org/10.32339/0135-5910-2020-4-365-371 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shayakhmetova, R. et al. Mechanism, kinetics and thermodynamics of nickel, iron and magnesium hydrochloric acid leaching from laterite ore. Sci. Rep. 15, 41342. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-25276-x (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharipov, R. et al. Sustainable leaching of nickel and cobalt from asbestos waste using deep eutectic solvents: Kinetic modeling and recovery performance. J. Hazard. Mater. Adv. 21, 100948. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hazadv.2025.100948 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamyrbayeva, K. K. et al. Review on hydrometallurgical processing technology of lateritic nickel ore for the last 20 years in the world. Non-ferrous Met. 56, 13&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.17580/nfm.2024.01.03 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, B. et al. The effect of pre-roasting on atmospheric sulfuric acid leaching of saprolitic laterites. Hydrometallurgy 218, 106063. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hydromet.2023.106063 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zayakin, O. V. Development of Rational Composition and Production Technology of Nickel-Containing Ferroalloys from Low-Grade Oxide Nickel Ores. Candidate of Science ThesisInstitute of Metallurgy, Ural Branch of the Russian Academy of Sciences, Yekaterinburg, (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roine, A. HSC Chemistry 10.0 &#x2013; Chemical Reaction and Equilibrium Software with Extensive Thermochemical Database (Outotec, Pori, 2020).</Citation></Reference><ReferenceList><Title>23&#x2013;29. Standards</Title><Reference><Citation>GOST 22772.4&#x2013;96. Nickel Ores, Concentrates and Agglomerates. Methods for Determination of Iron and Nickel Content (Interstate Council for Standardization, Metrology and Certification, 1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GOST 22772.2&#x2013;96. Nickel Ores, Concentrates and Agglomerates. Methods for Determination of Silicon Dioxide Content. Moscow, (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GOST 22772.3&#x2013;96. Nickel Ores, Concentrates and Agglomerates. Methods for Determination of Aluminum Oxide and Magnesium Oxide Content. Moscow, (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GOST 22772.5&#x2013;96. Nickel Ores, Concentrates and Agglomerates. Methods for Determination of Chromium Oxide Content. Moscow, (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GSO 1762-93. Certified Reference Material of Nickel Ore Composition (State Service for Standard Reference Materials, 1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GSO 2296-82. Certified Reference Material of Ferroalloy Composition. Moscow, (1982).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GOST 26517-85. Refractory Materials and Products. Method for Determination of the Softening Temperature under Load (State Committee for Standards, 1985).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Vyazovkin, S. et al. ICTAC kinetics committee recommendations for performing kinetic computations on thermal analysis data. Thermochim. Acta 520, 1&#x2013;19. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tca.2011.03.034 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kissinger, H. E. Reaction kinetics in differential thermal analysis. Anal. Chem. 29, 1702&#x2013;1706 (1957).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasik, M. I. Handbook of Ferroalloys: Theory and Technology. (Elsevier, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Box, G. E. P. &amp; Hunter, J. S. Multi-factor experimental design for exploring response surfaces. Ann. Math. Stat. 28, 195&#x2013;241 (1957).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shevko, V. M. et al. Production of a siliceous ferroalloy from a mixture of amorphous rocks. Results Eng. 23, 102754. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102754 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keskinkilic, E. Nickel laterite smelting processes and possible modifications to the conventional route. Metals 9, 974. https://doi.org/10.3390/met9090974 (2019).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>