<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41700591</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0972-2327</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of Indian Academy of Neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Indian Acad Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Longitudinal Assessment of Executive and Visuospatial Function Recovery and Its Relationship with Functional Outcomes in Ischemic Stroke Patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>35</StartPage><EndPage>40</EndPage><MedlinePgn>35-40</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/aian.aian_935_25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Cognitive impairments in the executive and visuospatial domains are common after ischemic stroke and significantly affect a patient's independence. These impairments can affect problem-solving abilities, planning, decision-making, and spatial awareness, which are critical for functional recovery. Understanding the trajectory of recovery and its association with functional outcomes is essential for improving the quality of life of stroke survivors. The Objectives of the study are to evaluate the recovery patterns of executive and visuospatial functions 90 days after ischemic stroke and to examine their relationship with functional outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this longitudinal study, 401 patients with neuroimaging-confirmed ischemic stroke were assessed at admission and on Days 7, 30, and 90 post-stroke. Executive function was measured using the alternate Trail Making Test, and visuospatial function was assessed using the cube-copying and clock-drawing tests. Functional outcomes were evaluated using the modified Rankin Scale (mRS) and Barthel Index. Repeated measures ANOVA (analysis of variance) was employed to assess cognitive recovery over time, and Spearman's correlation was used to examine the relationship between cognitive and functional outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Significant improvements in executive and visuospatial functions were observed over the 90-day period, with the greatest gains noted within the first 30 days. A moderate-to-strong negative correlation between mRS and cognitive function was identified at all time points, peaking on Day 7.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Executive and visuospatial functions show dynamic recovery in the first 90 days post-stroke, particularly during the acute and subacute phases. Functional disability is closely associated with cognitive performance, underscoring the importance of early cognitive assessment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Annals of Indian Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naik</LastName><ForeName>Ashwini</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kasturba Medical College, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pai</LastName><ForeName>Aparna R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kasturba Medical College, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gorthi</LastName><ForeName>Sankar P</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Bharati Vidyapeeth Deemed University, Pune, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prabhu</LastName><ForeName>Arvind N</ForeName><Initials>AN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kasturba Medical College, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chakrabarty</LastName><ForeName>Jyothi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical-Surgical Nursing, Manipal College of Nursing, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Umakanth</LastName><ForeName>Shashikiran</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Dr. TMA Pai Hospital, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Indian Acad Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101273955</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0972-2327</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal trajectory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">executive function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional outcome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ischemic stroke</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">visuospatial function</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41700591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12962414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/aian.aian_935_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">02223306-202601000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bergqvist M, M&#xf6;ller MC, Bj&#xf6;rklund M, Borg J, Palmcrantz S. The impact of visuospatial and executive function on activity performance and outcome after robotic or conventional gait training, long-term after stroke-as part of a randomized controlled trial. PLoS One. 2023;18:e0281212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9997896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36893079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu-Ambrose T, Pang MYC, Eng JJ. Executive function is independently associated with performances of balance and mobility in community-dwelling older adults after mild stroke: Implications for falls prevention. Cerebrovasc Dis. 2007;23:203&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4492718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17143004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters S, Handy TC, Lakhani B, Boyd LA, Garland SJ. Motor and visuospatial attention and motor planning after stroke: Considerations for the rehabilitation of standing balance and gait. Phys Ther. 2015;95:1423&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4595814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25929533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laakso HM, Hietanen M, Melkas S, Sibolt G, Curtze S, Virta M, et al. Executive function subdomains are associated with post-stroke functional outcome and permanent institutionalization. Eur J Neurol. 2019;26:546&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30414288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibbotson P. The development of executive function: Mechanisms of change and functional pressures. J Cogn Dev. 2023;24:172&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P, Duan L, Ou Y, Ling Q, Cao L, Qian H, et al. The cerebellum and cognitive neural networks. Front Hum Neurosci. 2023;17:1197459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10416251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37576472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Husseini N, Katzan IL, Rost NS, Blake ML, Byun E, Pendlebury ST, et al. Cognitive impairment after ischemic and hemorrhagic stroke: A scientific statement from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Stroke. 2023;54:e272&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12723706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37125534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carey L, Walsh A, Adikari A, Goodin P, Alahakoon D, De Silva D, et al. Finding the intersection of neuroplasticity, stroke recovery, and learning: Scope and contributions to stroke rehabilitation. Neural Plast. 2019;2019:5232374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6525913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31191637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabadi MH, Rabadi FM. Comparison of the action research arm test and the Fugl-Meyer assessment as measures of upper-extremity motor weakness after stroke. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2006;87:962&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16813784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mane R, Chouhan T, Guan C. BCI for stroke rehabilitation: Motor and beyond. J Neural Eng. 2020;17:041001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32613947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine ZS, Phillips NA, B&#xe9;dirian V, Charbonneau S, Whitehead V, Collin I, et al. The montreal cognitive assessment, MoCA: A brief screening tool for mild cognitive impairment. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2005;53:695&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker-Collo S, Starkey N, Lawes CMM, Feigin V, Senior H, Parag V. Neuropsychological profiles of 5-year ischemic stroke survivors by Oxfordshire stroke classification and hemisphere of lesion. Stroke. 2012;43:50&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21998066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumming TB, Marshall RS, Lazar RM. Stroke, cognitive deficits, and rehabilitation: Still an incomplete picture. Int J Stroke. 2013;8:38&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23280268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel M, Coshall C, Rudd AG, Wolfe CD. Natural history of cognitive impairment after stroke and factors associated with its recovery. Clin Rehabil. 2003;17:158&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12625656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson CO, Nguyen M, Roth GA, Nichols E, Alam T, Abate D, et al. Global, regional, and national burden of stroke, 1990&#x2013;2016: A systematic analysis for the global burden of disease study 2016. Lancet Neurol. 2019;18:439&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6494974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30871944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavy S, Melamed E, Cahane E, Carmon A. Hypertension and diabetes as risk factors in stroke patients. Stroke. 1973;4:751&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4751086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naess H, Waje-Andreassen U, Thomassen L, Myhr KM. High incidence of infarction in the left cerebral hemisphere among young adults. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2006;15:241&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17904082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brott T, Marler JR, Olinger CP, Adams HP, Tomsick T, Barsan WG, et al. Measurements of acute cerebral infarction: Lesion size by computed tomography. Stroke. 1989;20:871&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2749847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarshayev M, Turdaliyeva B, Tanbayeva G, Makhanbetkhan S, Mussabekov M, Davletov D, et al. Demographic characteristics and treatment outcomes of intracranial atherosclerosis stenting: A retrospective case-series of 216 consecutive patients. J Clin Med. 2024;14:125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11721944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39797208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>