<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41756698</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2635-0254</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Season>Jan-Feb</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Video journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Video J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Achilles Allograft Reconstruction With V-Y Quadriceps Advancement for Chronic Patellar Tendon Insufficiency.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>26350254251375089</StartPage><MedlinePgn>26350254251375089</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">26350254251375089</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/26350254251375089</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Chronic patellar tendon insufficiency often results in loss of active knee extension, retraction of the quadriceps, and patella alta. This study outlines a surgical technique for patellar tendon reconstruction using an Achilles allograft with V-Y quadriceps advancement, in the context of failed prior mid-substance patellar tendon repair.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INDICATIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Reconstruction is indicated in patients with complete tears of the patellar tendon that are non-amenable to primary repair. Other considerations include failed prior repair or persistent functional deficits in patients with contributing patellar tendon insufficiency. V-Y quadriceps advancement may be implemented if there are concerns for quadriceps retraction, patella alta, and inability to achieve tension-free reconstruction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TECHNIQUE DESCRIPTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The V-Y quadricepsplasty was performed initially to deliver the patella inferiorly before inferior pole suture anchors were placed. The patellar tendon reconstruction consisted of an Achilles allograft with calcaneal bone block fixation at the tibial tuberosity, augmented with distal suture fixation. Medial retinacular repair via ipsilateral hamstring autograft was incorporated into the overall construct, which was fixated at the inferior patellar pole anchors and soft tissues superiorly.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">At 2 weeks postoperatively, the patient is progressing well, without complications, and the stability of the construct is maintained. Recovery of range of motion and return to full function may be expected in approximately 9 to 12 months.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION/CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study describes a patellar tendon reconstruction using an Achilles allograft and a V-Y quadriceps advancement, with concomitant medial retinacular repair, for chronic patellar insufficiency and patella alta in a 35-year-old man. The literature supports similar outcomes for several graft options and techniques to address patellar tendon reconstruction. However, the use of Achilles allograft may be superior in terms of patient-reported pain measures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENT CONSENT DISCLOSURE STATEMENT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The author(s) attests that consent has been obtained from any patient(s) appearing in this publication. If the individual may be identifiable, the author(s) has included a statement of release or other written form of approval from the patient(s) with this submission for publication.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watson</LastName><ForeName>Sarah E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-3186-6427</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wake Forest University School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gwilt</LastName><ForeName>Matthew S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-4685-486X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Atrium Health Wake Forest Baptist, Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and Rehabilitation, Winston-Salem, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marter</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-9048-1084</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wake Forest University School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perry</LastName><ForeName>Nichole M</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6251-3130</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wake Forest University School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Collon</LastName><ForeName>Kevin W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wake Forest University School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Waterman</LastName><ForeName>Brian R</ForeName><Initials>BR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wake Forest University School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Atrium Health Wake Forest Baptist, Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and Rehabilitation, Winston-Salem, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Video J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918367588406676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2635-0254</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Achilles allograft</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">V-Y quadricepsplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patella alta</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patellar tendon</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reconstruction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>One or more of the authors has declared the following potential conflict of interest or source of funding: B.R.W. receives research support from Arthrex, Inc.; is a paid consultant for FH Ortho; is an unpaid consultant for Sparta Science; is a paid presenter or speaker for Vericel; serves on committees for the American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons and the American Orthopaedic Society for Sports Medicine (AOSSM); receives publishing royalties and financial or material support from Elsevier; is an unpaid consultant and holds stock or stock options in Kaliber AI; and holds stock or stock options in Vivorte. AOSSM checks author disclosures against the Open Payments Database (OPD). AOSSM has not conducted an independent investigation on the OPD and disclaims any liability or responsibility relating thereto.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41756698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12932874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/26350254251375089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_26350254251375089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gilmore JH, Clayton-Smith ZJ, Aguilar M, Pneumaticos SG, Giannoudis PV. Reconstruction techniques and clinical results of patellar tendon ruptures: evidence today. Knee. 2015;22(3):148-155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25819155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginesin EZ, Wojnowski NM, Patel RM. Patellar tendon reconstruction for a chronic extensor mechanism deficit using an Achilles tendon allograft with hamstring autograft and suture augmentation. Arthrosc Tech. 2020;9(4):e469-e475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7189117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32368466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grondin J, Menu P, Garraud T, Mesland O, Dauty M, Fouasson-Chailloux A. Return to sport after patellar tendon rupture: a systematic review. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 2019;9(4):517-524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hahn AK, Coladonato C, Corvi JJ, et al. Outcomes and complications following chronic patellar tendon repair: a systematic review. Cureus. 2023;15(7):e41713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10414687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37575790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim WT, Kao D, O'Connell R, Patel NK, Vap A. Clinical outcomes are similar between graft types used in chronic patellar tendon reconstruction: a systematic review. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2022;4(5):e1861-e1872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9596887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36312722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spivey MG, Campbell MP, Gammon LG, Vap AR. Patellar tendon allograft reconstruction. VJSM. 2021;1(4).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11883461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40309391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volk WR, Yagnik GP, Uribe JW. Complications in brief: quadriceps and patellar tendon tears. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2014;472(3):1050-1057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3916631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24338040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>