<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41782085</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2334</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC infectious diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Factors associated with long COVID in sub-Saharan Africa: a scoping review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12879-026-12942-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Long COVID is a condition characterized by persistent symptoms of COVID-19 that continue to occur in patients after apparent recovery. Given that, these symptoms may vary from person to person due to clinical, demographic, and genetic factors as well as comorbidities, our review aims to identify and analyze risk factors associated with persistent symptoms of COVID-19 (long COVID) in the specific context of sub-Saharan Africa.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Article searches were conducted in the PubMed, Scopus, African Journals Online (AJOL), Science Direct and Google Scholar databases using the keywords "long COVID" or "long-term COVID-19" or "post-COVID condition" or "post-acute sequelae of COVID-19" and "sub-Saharan Africa" or "sub-Saharan Africans". The obtained data were entered into software for duplication checking. Two reviewers selected and extracted the data. Due to substantial heterogeneity in definitions and study designs, a narrative synthesis approach was adopted. Fifteen studies were included in this review, totaling 8,233 participants previously infected with SARS-CoV-2, with approximately 2,011 patients with long COVID from six countries. Six studies were cross-sectional, three were retrospective, three were cohort studies, two were case-control, and one was a case report.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The review found that the prevalence of long COVID in sub-Saharan Africa ranged from 2% in Ghana to 66.7% in South Africa. The persistent COVID-19 symptoms most commonly experienced by people living in sub-Saharan Africa were fatigue (reported in 12 studies, 25-66% of patients), cough (7 studies, 9-86%), chest pain (9 studies, 9%-29%), dyspnea (10 studies, 15-45%), palpitations (4 studies, 10-30%), headache (9 studies, 12-38%), and cognitive impairment (6 studies, 8-20%). The main risk factors for the occurrence of persistent COVID-19 symptoms were older age (&#x2c3; 60 years), female sex, low education level, hypertension, type 2 diabetes, cardiovascular disease, length of hospitalization during the acute episode, number of initial COVID-19 symptoms, and initial disease severity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Long COVID is a reality in sub-Saharan Africa. Fatigue and hypertension have proven to be the most common symptom and risk factor, respectively. The heterogeneity of long COVID definitions across studies limits direct prevalence comparisons. Given the socio-economic challenges, pre-existing comorbidities and differences in health systems in the sub-Saharan region, it is therefore necessary to develop new strategies for care, rehabilitation and treatment (specific to the realities of the sub-Saharan region) targeted at each persistent symptom of COVID-19 in order to resolve this emerging problem and allow patients to have a good quality of life.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL NUMBER" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Not applicable.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heugno</LastName><ForeName>Valdez Jaures Njio</ForeName><Initials>VJN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activities and Sport Physiology and Medicine Unit, University of Douala, Douala, Cameroon. valdezjauresheugno@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamdem</LastName><ForeName>Odette Linda</ForeName><Initials>OL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>INSERM, U1059, DVH team, SAINBIOSE, Jean Monnet University, Saint- Etienne, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PRESAGE Institute, Jean Monnet University, Saint-Etienne, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Same</LastName><ForeName>Estelle Geraldine Essangui</ForeName><Initials>EGE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biological Sciences Department, Faculty of Medicine and Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of Douala, Douala, Cameroon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate Training Unit for Health Sciences, Postgraduate School for Pure and Applied Sciences, University of Douala, Douala, Cameroon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lele</LastName><ForeName>Elys&#xe9;e Claude Bika</ForeName><Initials>ECB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activities and Sport Physiology and Medicine Unit, University of Douala, Douala, Cameroon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biloa</LastName><ForeName>Yves Mbama</ForeName><Initials>YM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>INSERM, U1059, DVH team, SAINBIOSE, Jean Monnet University, Saint- Etienne, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PRESAGE Institute, Jean Monnet University, Saint-Etienne, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayina</LastName><ForeName>Clarisse Ayina</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activities and Sport Physiology and Medicine Unit, University of Douala, Douala, Cameroon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guyot</LastName><ForeName>Jessica</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>INSERM, U1059, DVH team, SAINBIOSE, Jean Monnet University, Saint- Etienne, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PRESAGE Institute, Jean Monnet University, Saint-Etienne, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bongue</LastName><ForeName>Bienvenu</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>INSERM, U1059, DVH team, SAINBIOSE, Jean Monnet University, Saint- Etienne, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PRESAGE Institute, Jean Monnet University, Saint-Etienne, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Caisse Primaire d'Assurance Maladie (CPAM 42), Saint-Etienne, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mandengue</LastName><ForeName>Samuel Honore</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activities and Sport Physiology and Medicine Unit, University of Douala, Douala, Cameroon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moukoko</LastName><ForeName>Carole Else Eboumbou</ForeName><Initials>CEE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biological Sciences Department, Faculty of Medicine and Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of Douala, Douala, Cameroon. elsecarole@yahoo.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate Training Unit for Health Sciences, Postgraduate School for Pure and Applied Sciences, University of Douala, Douala, Cameroon. elsecarole@yahoo.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>ANRS283</GrantID><Agency>ANRS - Agence Nationale de la Recherche / Emerging Infectious Diseases</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2334</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long COVID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Persistent symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scoping review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sub-Saharan Africa</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41782085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-026-12942-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12879-026-12942-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cucinotta D, Vanelli M. WHO Declares COVID-19 a Pandemic. Acta Bio Med Atenei Parm. 2020;91(1):157&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Liu SM, Yu XH, Tang SL, Tang CK. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19): current status and future perspectives. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2020;55(5):105951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupia T, Scabini S, Mornese Pinna S, Di Perri G, De Rosa FG, Corcione S. 2019 novel coronavirus (2019-nCoV) outbreak: A new challenge. J Glob Antimicrob Resist. 2020;21:22&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P, Yang XL, Wang XG, Hu B, Zhang L, Zhang W, et al. A pneumonia outbreak associated with a new coronavirus of probable bat origin. Nature. 2020;579(7798):270&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Update on the ongoing Novel Coronavirus (COVID-19.) Global Epidemic, brief #146 | African Union. Disponible sur: https://au.int/en/documents/20221101/update-ongoing-novel-coronavirus-covid-19-global-epidemic-brief-146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James A, Dalal J, Kousi T, Vivacqua D, C&#xe2;mara DCP, Dos Reis IC, et al. An in-depth statistical analysis of the COVID-19 pandemic&#x2019;s initial spread in the WHO African region. BMJ Glob Health. 2022;7(4):e007295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngatchou W, Jean cyr Y, Temgoua M, Kouanfack C, Sobngwi E, Lemogoum D. Relatively low mortality rate of COVID-19 in Cameroon: what if age was the main factor? Rev Med Brux. 2021;42:26&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office of National Statistics. Prevalence of ongoing symptoms following coronavirus (COVID-19) infection in the UK - Office for National Statistics. Disponible sur: https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/conditionsanddiseases/bulletins/prevalenceofongoingsymptomsfollowingcoronaviruscovid19infectionintheuk/1april2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havervall S, Rosell A, Phillipson M, Mangsbo SM, Nilsson P, Hober S, et al. Symptoms and Functional Impairment Assessed 8 Months After Mild COVID-19 Among Health Care Workers. JAMA. 2021;325(19):2015&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montani D, Savale L, Noel N, Meyrignac O, Colle R, Gasnier M, et al. Post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Eur Respir Rev. 2022;31(163):210185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jassat W, Mudara C, Vika C, Welch R, Arendse T, Dryden M, et al. A cohort study of post-COVID-19 condition across the Beta, Delta, and Omicron waves in South Africa: 6-month follow-up of hospitalized and nonhospitalized participants. Int J Infect Dis. 2023;128:102&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly Z, Xie Y, Bowe B. High-dimensional characterization of post-acute sequelae of COVID-19. Nature. 2021;594(7862):259&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook H, Raza S, Nowell J, Young M, Edison P. Long covid&#x2014;mechanisms, risk factors, and management. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano JB, Murthy S, Marshall JC, Relan P, Diaz JV. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22(4):e102&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reese JT, Blau H, Bergquist T, Loomba JJ, Callahan T, Laraway B et al. Generalizable long COVID subtypes: findings from the NIH N3C and recover programs. medRxiv. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health Care. Overview: COVID-19 rapid guideline: managing the long-term effects of COVID-19. Guidance. NICE. NICE; 2020. Disponible sur. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/NG188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC, Long COVID, Basics. Long COVID. 2025. Disponible sur: https://www.cdc.gov/long-covid/about/index.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo W, He D, Liang C, Du S, Hua Z, Nie Q, et al. The persistence of SARS-CoV-2 in tissues and its association with long COVID symptoms: a cross-sectional cohort study in China. Lancet Infect Dis. 2024;24(8):845&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salmon C&#xe9;ron D, Davido B, Tubiana R, Linard F, Turgis CT, Oustric P, et al. Les formes prolong&#xe9;es de la COVID-19 ou COVID long: formes cliniques et prise en charge. Medicine Mal Infect Form. 2022;S2772743221000118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwasaki A, Putrino D. Why we need a deeper understanding of the pathophysiology of long COVID. Lancet Infect Dis. 2023;23(4):393&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh D, Bernstein JA, Mersha TB. COVID-19 pandemic: The African paradox. J Glob Health. 2020;10(2):020348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tcheutchoua DN, Tankeu AT, Wouna Angong DL, Agoons BB, Yanwou Nguemnang NY, Nana Djeunga HC, et al. Unexpected low burden of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) in sub-Saharan Africa region despite disastrous predictions: reasons and perspectives. Pan Afr Med J. 2020;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young F, Critchley JA, Johnstone LK, Unwin NC. A review of co-morbidity between infectious and chronic disease in Sub Saharan Africa: TB and Diabetes Mellitus, HIV and Metabolic Syndrome, and the impact of globalization. Glob Health. 2009;5(1):9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouda HN, Charlson F, Sorsdahl K, Ahmadzada S, Ferrari AJ, Erskine H, et al. Burden of non-communicable diseases in sub-Saharan Africa, 1990&#x2013;2017: results from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017. Lancet Glob Health. 2019;7(10):e1375&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katoto PDMC, Byamungu L, Brand AS, Mokaya J, Strijdom H, Goswami N, et al. Ambient air pollution and health in Sub-Saharan Africa: Current evidence, perspectives and a call to action. Environ Res. 2019;173:174&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antil A. L&#x2019;arriv&#xe9;e du COVID-19 en Afrique subsaharienne, quels sc&#xe9;narios? Paris: Ifri; 16. 1 p. (L&#x2019;Afrique en questions).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aborode AT, Hasan MM, Jain S, Okereke M, Adedeji OJ, Karra-Aly A, et al. Impact of poor disease surveillance system on COVID-19 response in africa: Time to rethink and rebuilt. Clin Epidemiol Glob Health. 2021;12:100841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naidoo S, Gitaka J, Suliman S, Baptista S, Oyedemi BM, Nepolo E, et al. Coronavirus Disease 2019 Diagnostics: Key to Africa&#x2019;s Recovery. DNA Cell Biol. 2022;41(1):30&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azevedo MJ. The State of Health System(s) in Africa: Challenges and Opportunities. In: Azevedo MJ, &#xe9;diteur. Historical perspectives on the state of health and health Systems in Africa, Volume II: the modern era. Cham: Springer International Publishing. 2017;1&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souma&#xef;la Mouleye I, Youssoufou HD, Diaw A. Effets du changement climatique sur la pauvret&#xe9; et les in&#xe9;galit&#xe9;s en Afrique subsaharienne Impact of Climate Change on Poverty and Inequality in Sub-Saharan Africa. Rev &#xc9;conomie D&#xe9;v. 2019;27:28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabutin D, Schoumaker B. The Demography of Sub-Saharan Africa in the 21st Century. Transformations Since 2000, Outlook to 2050. POPULATION. 2020;75:163&#x2013;286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bocoum FY, Kadio K, Bila A, Kouanda S, Drabo M. Connaissances et perceptions de la maladie &#xe0; coronavirus (COVID-19) dans la commune de Ouagadougou. Rev Afr Sci Soc Sant&#xe9; Publique. 2022;4(2):239&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez L, Short JR. The Pandemic City: Urban Issues in the Time of COVID-19. Sustainability. 2021;13(6):3295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouattara S, Amalaman DM. Croyances, perceptions et attitudes des populations face &#xe0; la pand&#xe9;mie du Covid-19 en Afrique de l&#x2019;Ouest: une &#xe9;tude qualitative &#xe0; Abidjan, C&#xf4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire. Rev Afr Sci Soc Sant&#xe9; Publique. 2021;3(2):117&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Africanova. M&#xe9;decine traditionnelle et biom&#xe9;decine en Afrique: compl&#xe9;mentarit&#xe9;s ou rivalit&#xe9;s ? Africanova.info. 2025. Disponible sur: https://africanova.info/medecine-traditionnelle-et-biomedecine-en-afrique-complementarites-ou-rivalites/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey H, O&#x2019;Malley L. Scoping studies: towards a methodological framework. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2005;8(1):19&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levac D, Colquhoun H, O&#x2019;Brien KK. Scoping studies: advancing the methodology. Implement Sci IS. 2010;5:69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters M, Godfrey C, McInerney P, Soares C, Khalil H, Parker D. The Joanna Briggs institute reviewers&#x2019; manual 2015: methodology for JBI scoping reviews. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moola S, Tufanaru C, Aromataris E, Sears K, Sfetc R, Currie M, et al. Chapter 7: systematic reviews of etiology and risk. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lockwood C, Munn Z, Porritt K. Qualitative research synthesis: methodological guidance for systematic reviewers utilizing meta-aggregation. JBI Evid Implement. 2015;13(3):179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. PLOS Med. 2021;18(3):e1003583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuamah HG, Oduro-Mensah E, Oliver-Commey J. Clinical presentation and persistent symptoms in patients at a post-COVID-19 clinic in Ghana. Pan Afr Med J. 2023;45:44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendelsohn AS, Nath N, De S&#xe1; A, Von Pressentin KB. Two months follow-up of patients with non-critical COVID-19 in Cape Town, South Africa. South Afr Fam Pract Off J South Afr Acad Fam Pract Care. 2022;64(1):e1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elias TP, Gebreamlak TW, Gebremeskel TT, Adde BL, Abie AS, Elias BP, et al. Determinants of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome among hospitalized severe COVID-19 patients: A 2-year follow-up study. PLoS ONE. 2024;19(5):e0298409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malambo W, Chanda D, Besa L, Engamba D, Mwiinga L, Mwitumwa M, et al. Clinical characteristics and factors associated with long COVID among post-acute COVID-19 clinic patients in Zambia, August 2020 to January 2023: A cross-sectional and longitudinal study design. PLoS ONE. 2024;19(7):e0306131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyoum AB, Tegegnework SS, Mengistu MM, Mekonnen TD, Asabel AM, Dagnaw AG, et al. Post-COVID-19 pulmonary complications among recovered COVID-19 patients: a cross-sectional study from Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. BMC Pulm Med. 2023;23(1):409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dryden M, Mudara C, Vika C, Blumberg L, Mayet N, Cohen C, et al. Post-COVID-19 condition 3 months after hospitalisation with SARS-CoV-2 in South Africa: a prospective cohort study. Lancet Glob Health. 2022;10(9):e1247&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wose Kinge C, Hanekom S, Lupton-Smith A, Akpan F, Mothibi E, Maotoe T, et al. Persistent Symptoms among Frontline Health Workers Post-Acute COVID-19 Infection. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(10):5933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruger A, Vlok M, Turner S, Venter C, Laubscher GJ, Kell DB, et al. Proteomics of fibrin amyloid microclots in long COVID/post-acute sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC) shows many entrapped pro-inflammatory molecules that may also contribute to a failed fibrinolytic system. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21(1):190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E, Venter C, Laubscher GJ, Kotze MJ, Oladejo SO, Watson LR, et al. Prevalence of symptoms, comorbidities, fibrin amyloid microclots and platelet pathology in individuals with Long COVID/Post-Acute Sequelae of COVID-19 (PASC). Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2022;21(1):148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zulu JE, Banda D, Hines JZ, Luchembe M, Sivile S, Siwingwa M, et al. Two-month follow-up of persons with SARS-CoV-2 infection-Zambia, September 2020: a cohort study. Pan Afr Med J. 2022;41:26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogoina D, James HI, Ogoinja SZ. Post-Discharge Symptoms among Hospitalized COVID-19 Patients in Nigeria: A Single-Center Study. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2021;105(3):731&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osikomaiya B, Erinoso O, Wright KO, Odusola AO, Thomas B, Adeyemi O, et al. &#xab; Long COVID &#xbb;: persistent COVID-19 symptoms in survivors managed in Lagos State, Nigeria. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21(1):304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaggwa MM, Favina A, Najjuka SM, Zeba Z, Mamun MA, Bongomin F. Excessive eating and weight gain:A rare post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2021;15(5):102252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crankson S, Pokhrel S, Anokye NK. Determinants of COVID-19-Related Length of Hospital Stays and Long COVID in Ghana: A Cross-Sectional Analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(1):527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notarte KI, de Oliveira MHS, Peligro PJ, Velasco JV, Macaranas I, Ver AT, et al. Age, Sex and Previous Comorbidities as Risk Factors Not Associated with SARS-CoV-2 Infection for Long COVID-19: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Clin Med. 2022;11(24):7314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maglietta G, Diodati F, Puntoni M, Lazzarelli S, Marcomini B, Patrizi L, et al. Prognostic Factors for Post-COVID-19 Syndrome: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Clin Med. 2022;11(6):1541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson EJ, Williams DM, Walker AJ, Mitchell RE, Niedzwiedz CL, Yang TC, et al. Long COVID burden and risk factors in 10 UK longitudinal studies and electronic health records. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):3528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi T, Ellingson MK, Wong P, Israelow B, Lucas C, Klein J, et al. Sex differences in immune responses that underlie COVID-19 disease outcomes. Nature. 2020;588(7837):315&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zemni I, Gara A, Bennasrallah C, Ezzar S, Kacem M, Chokri R, et al. Incidence and risk factors of post COVID-19 syndrome: a Tunisian cohort study. BMC Infect Dis. 2024;24(1):461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang V, Fisher M, Hou W, Zhang L, Duong TQ. Incidence of New-Onset Hypertension Post-COVID-19: Comparison With Influenza. Hypertens Dallas Tex 1979. 2023;80(10):2135&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mkoma GF, Agyemang C, Benfield T, Rostila M, Cederstr&#xf6;m A, Petersen JH, et al. Risk of long COVID and associated symptoms after acute SARS-COV-2 infection in ethnic minorities: A nationwide register-linked cohort study in Denmark. PLOS Med. 2024;21(2):e1004280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moyo E, Chimene M, Moyo P, Musuka G, Mangoya D, Murewanhema G, et al. Risk factors and clinical presentations of long COVID in Africa: A scoping review. J Infect Public Health. 2023;16(12):1982&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salukhov VV, Arutyunov GP, Tarlovskaya EI, Batluk TI, Bashkinov RA, Samus IV, et al. [The impact of carbohydrate metabolism disorders on the early and long-term clinical outcomes of patients with COVID-19 according to the AKTIV and AKTIV 2 registries]. Probl Endokrinol (Mosk). 2023;69(1):36&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yahia F, Zakhama L, Ben Abdelaziz A. COVID-19 and Cardiovascular diseases. Scoping review study. Tunis Med. 2020;98(4):283&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Fang YY, Deng Y, Liu W, Wang MF, Ma JP, et al. Clinical characteristics of novel coronavirus cases in tertiary hospitals in Hubei Province. Chin Med J (Engl). 2020;133(9):1025&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prusinski C, Yan D, Klasova J, McVeigh KH, Shah SZ, Fermo OP, et al. Multidisciplinary Management Strategies for Long COVID: A Narrative Review. Cureus. 2024;16(5):e59478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negrini S, Mills JA, Arienti C, Kiekens C, Cieza A. Rehabilitation Research Framework for Patients With COVID-19 Defined by Cochrane Rehabilitation and the World Health Organization Rehabilitation Programme. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;102(7):1424&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamdem OL, Dupre C, Heugno V, Baudot A, Essangui E, Blanquet M, et al. SPACO+: a mixed methods protocol to assessing the effectiveness of an educative intervention in patients with Long Covid. BMC Infect Dis. 2025;25(1):623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhengu KN, Naidoo P, Singh R, Mpaka-Mbatha MN, Nembe N, Duma Z, et al. Immunological Interactions between Intestinal Helminth Infections and Tuberculosis. Diagn Basel Switz. 2022;12(11):2676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker M, Federico EM, Kell DB, Dupont C, Proal A, Pretorius E. Abstract 15637: Detection and Characterization of Fibrin/Amyloid Microclots in Patients With Post-Acute Sequelae of Covid-19. Circulation. 2022;146(Suppl1):A15637&#x2013;15637.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>