<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41737372</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1178-2390</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of multidisciplinary healthcare</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Multidiscip Healthc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intestinal Rehabilitation Plan for Patients with Colorectal Cancer During the Perioperative Period: An Evidence Synthesis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>583146</StartPage><MedlinePgn>583146</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">583146</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/JMDH.S583146</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To retrieve, evaluate, and synthesize the best available evidence regarding perioperative intestinal rehabilitation programs for patients with colorectal cancer, and to provide a reference for clinical nursing practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A systematic search was conducted in BMJ Best Practice, GIN, the National Institute for Health and Care Excellence, the Registered Nurses' Association of Ontario, Medline (via PubMed), the Cochrane Library, Web of Science, China National Knowledge Infrastructure (CNKI), Wanfang Database, VIP Database, China Biology Medicine disc (CBM), and the Chinese Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition of the Chinese Medical Association. The search encompassed clinical guidelines, evidence summaries, systematic reviews, expert consensus statements, and other relevant evidence pertaining to intestinal management in patients following colorectal cancer surgery. The retrieval period spanned from the inception of each database to August 2025. Two researchers with training in evidence-based practice independently assessed the methodological quality of the included studies, followed by data extraction and thematic synthesis of the evidence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 16 articles were included, comprising 2 guidelines, 9 systematic reviews, 3 evidence summaries, and 2 expert consensus documents. The evidence was synthesized across six domains: preoperative nutritional management, prehabilitation and bowel preparation, intraoperative surgical management, postoperative nutritional support, postoperative mobility management, and management of drains and symptoms. A total of 23 evidence-based recommendations were identified and summarized.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study synthesizes the current evidence regarding intestinal rehabilitation programs for patients with colorectal cancer during the perioperative period. Nursing professionals should critically evaluate clinical contexts, apply evidence-based practices, and develop scientifically sound, individualized intestinal rehabilitation protocols. Such an approach supports the advancement of a nursing-led, multidisciplinary model of personalized rehabilitation, thereby enhancing both nursing quality and patient recovery outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Jia et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jia</LastName><ForeName>Yatian</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, Shanxi Bethune Hospital, Shanxi Academy of Medical Sciences, Third Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, Tongji Shanxi Hospital, Taiyuan, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Wenxia</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, Shanxi Bethune Hospital, Shanxi Academy of Medical Sciences, Third Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, Tongji Shanxi Hospital, Taiyuan, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, Shanxi Bethune Hospital, Shanxi Academy of Medical Sciences, Third Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, Tongji Shanxi Hospital, Taiyuan, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niu</LastName><ForeName>QingMei</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, Shanxi Bethune Hospital, Shanxi Academy of Medical Sciences, Third Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, Tongji Shanxi Hospital, Taiyuan, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Shanxi University of Chinese Medicine, Jinzhong, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Qian</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, Shanxi Bethune Hospital, Shanxi Academy of Medical Sciences, Third Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, Tongji Shanxi Hospital, Taiyuan, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Shanxi University of Chinese Medicine, Jinzhong, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Liping</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, Shanxi Bethune Hospital, Shanxi Academy of Medical Sciences, Third Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, Tongji Shanxi Hospital, Taiyuan, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Shanxi University of Chinese Medicine, Jinzhong, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>J Multidiscip Healthc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101512691</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1178-2390</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">colorectal cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">evidence summary</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intestinal management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intestinal rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutritional management</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no competing interests in this work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41737372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12927751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JMDH.S583146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">583146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Siegel RL, Miller KD, Wagle NS, Jemal A. Cancer statistics, 2023. <i>CA Cancer J Clinicians</i>. 2023;73(1):17&#x2013;11. doi: 10.3322/caac.21763</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36633525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, et al. Global cancer statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. <i>CA Cancer J Clin</i>. 2021;71(3):209&#x2013;249. doi: 10.3322/caac.21660
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heisser T, Cardoso R, Niedermaier T, Hoffmeister M, Brenner H. Making colonoscopy-based screening more efficient: a &#x201c;gateopener&#x201d; approach. <i>Int, J, Cancer</i>. 2023;152(5):952&#x2013;961. doi: 10.1002/ijc.34317
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ijc.34317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36214791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieniowski EHA, Palmer GJ, Juul T, et al. Low anterior resection syndrome and quality of life after sphincter-sparing rectal cancer surgery: a long-term longitudinal follow-up. <i>Dis Colon Rectum</i>. 2019;62(1):14&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1097/dcr.0000000000001228
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/dcr.0000000000001228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30394987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni P, Song Y, Liu WX, et al. Nursing care and therapy for postoperative diarrhea among patients undergoing sphincter-reserving surgery for low rectal cancer. <i>J Chin Med Univ</i>. 2018;47(12):1137&#x2013;1139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun R, Dai Z, Zhang Y, Lu J, Zhang Y, Xiao Y. The incidence and risk factors of low anterior resection syndrome (LARS) after sphincter-preserving surgery of rectal cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>Support Care Cancer</i>. 2021;29(12):7249&#x2013;7258. doi: 10.1007/s00520-021-06326-2
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-021-06326-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34296335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou MX, Zhao TY, Zhang GJ, et al. Symptom experiences of postoperative bowel dysfunction patients with rectal cancer: a qualitative study. <i>Milit Nur</i>. 2024;41(02):35&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Liu KX, Deng XM, et al. Expert consensus on prevention and treatment of postoperative gastrointestinal dysfunction. <i>Int J Anesthesiol Resusc</i>. 2021;42(11):1133&#x2013;1142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Jiang ZW, Gong GW. Prehabilitation strategies for intestinal function in colorectal cancer patients with intestinal obstruction under the ERAS concept[J]. <i>J Colon Anal Sur</i>. 2025;31(03):196&#x2013;199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustafsson UO, Rockall TA, Wexner S, et al. Guidelines for perioperative care in elective colorectal surgery: enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) society recommendations 2025. <i>Surgery</i>. 2025;2025:184. doi: 10.1016/j.surg.2025.109397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surg.2025.109397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40783294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saur NM, Davis BR, Montroni I, et al. The American Society of Colon and Rectal Surgeons clinical practice guidelines for the perioperative evaluation and management of frailty among older adults undergoing colorectal surgery. <i>Dis Colon Rectum</i>. 2022;65(4):473&#x2013;488. doi: 10.1097/dcr.0000000000002410
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/dcr.0000000000002410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35001046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo JT, Li JQ, Xu Y, et al. Summary of the best evidence for perioperative nutritional management in patients with colorectal cancer by the concept of enhanced recovery. <i>Chin J Oncol Prev Treat</i>. 2024;16(3):2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu YH, Chen L, Li W, et al. Summary of the best evidence to promote the recovery of gastrointestinal function in patients with colorectal cancer during perioperative period. <i>Chin Evidence-Based Nur</i>. 2022;8(2):150&#x2013;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y, Song MX, Liu YH, et al. Summary of evidence for the prevention and management of low anterior resection syndrome. <i>Journal of Nurses Training</i>. 2023;38(12):1137&#x2013;1142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MJ, Yeom S, Kim YM. Effectiveness of pelvic floor muscle training in the recovery of patients after low anterior resection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>Eur J Oncol Nurs</i>. 2025;77:102918. doi: 10.1016/j.ejon.2025.102918
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejon.2025.102918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40609367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng L, Zhang X, Ma B, Yuan Y, Yang H. Efficacy of non-pharmacological interventions for the restoration of postoperative intestinal motility of patients with colorectal cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. <i>Int J Colorectal Dis</i>. 2025;40(1):176. doi: 10.1007/s00384-025-04968-w
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00384-025-04968-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12343698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40797107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi L, Shi H, Zhang Y, Zhang X, Jia H, Tian H. The effect of acupuncture on recovery after colorectal cancer resection: a systematic review meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. <i>Rev Med</i>. 2023;102(35):e34678. doi: 10.1097/md.0000000000034678</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/md.0000000000034678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10476740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37657054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao YS, Chiu HY, Huang FH, et al. Prehabilitation interventions in patients undergoing colorectal cancer surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>J Am Geriatr Soc</i>. 2025;73(7):2262&#x2013;2277. doi: 10.1111/jgs.19425
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgs.19425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40079672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang LP, Wen SQ, Li JF, et al. Effect of chewing gum on gastrointestinal function after colorectal cancer surgery:a meta-analysis. <i>Chin J Bases Clin Gen Surg</i>. 2024;31(12):1466&#x2013;1473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song MX, Li XR. A meta-analysis of fast track surgery for laparoscopic colorectal cancer surgery in elderly patients. <i>World Chin J Dig</i>. 2015;(24):1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen ZJ, Wang WT, Mei BB, et al. Gum chewing for promoting intestinal function recovery after colorectal cancer surgery: a meta-analysis[J]. <i>World Chin J Dig</i>. 2017;25(2):147&#x2013;158. doi: 10.11569/wcjd.v25.i2.147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11569/wcjd.v25.i2.147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R, Ye XH, Wang HJ, et al. Effect of preoperative enteral nutrition on postoperative rehabilitation of patients with colorectal cancer: a meta-analysis[J]. <i>Parenteral Enteral Nutr</i>. 2021;28(3):171&#x2013;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou T, Wang S, Fan BJ, et al. Clinical efficacy of acupuncture in treating postoperative gastrointestinal dysfunction of colorectal cancer, a systematic review and meta analysis[J]. <i>Acupuncture Res</i>. 2024;49(2):208&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38413043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Electronic Journal Of Metabolism And Nutrition Of Cancer. Expert consensus on nutritional treatment for patients with colorectal cancer. <i>Electron J Metab Clin Nutr</i>. 2022;9(06):735&#x2013;740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang GH, Wang Q, Zhao LY, et al. Expert consensus on perioperative management of elderly patients with colorectal cancer in China (2020 Edition)[J]. <i>Chin J Colorectal Dis</i>. 2020;9(04):325&#x2013;334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W, Ou G, Li X, Huang J, Liu J, Wei H. Screening of the nutritional risk of patients with gastric carcinoma before operation by NRS 2002 and its relationship with postoperative results. <i>J Gastroenterol Hepatol</i>. 2010;25(4):800&#x2013;803. doi: 10.1111/j.1440-1746.2009.06198.x
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-1746.2009.06198.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20492337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi HP. Guidelines for nutritional therapy in patients undergoing chemotherapy. <i>Electron J Metab Clin Nutr</i>. 2016;3(03):158&#x2013;163. doi: 10.16689/j.cnki.cn11-9349/r.2016.03.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16689/j.cnki.cn11-9349/r.2016.03.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Vliet IMY, Gomes-Neto AW, de Jong MFC, et al. High prevalence of malnutrition both on hospital admission and predischarge. <i>Nutrition</i>. 2020;77:110814. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2020.110814
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2020.110814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32442829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi HP. Tumor nutritional therapy. <i>Chin J Clin Oncol</i>. 2014;41(18):1141&#x2013;1144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazi M, Gori J, Sasi S, et al. Prognostic nutritional index prior to rectal cancer resection predicts overall survival. <i>Nutr Cancer</i>. 2022;74(9):3228&#x2013;3235. doi: 10.1080/01635581.2022.2072906
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01635581.2022.2072906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35533003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Wang S, Gao X, et al. poor pre-operative nutritional status is a risk factor of post-operative infections in patients with gastrointestinal cancer-a multicenter prospective cohort study. <i>Front Nutr</i>. 2022;9:850063. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2022.850063
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2022.850063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9184816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35694167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Li ZY, Li XH. Optimizing the physiological function of the large intestine in TCM: insights from left- vs. right-sided colon cancer[J]. <i>Lishizhen Med Mater Med Res</i>. 2021;32(11):2718&#x2013;2719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang L, Kong C, Li J, et al. Distinct microbes, metabolites, and the host genome define the multi-omics profiles in right-sided and left-sided colon cancer[J]. <i>Microbiome</i>. 2024;12(1):274. doi: 10.1186/s40168-024-01987-7
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40168-024-01987-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11681701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39731152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Wang XY. Interpretation of guideline for clinical application of parenteral and enteral nutrition in adults patients in China(2023 edition). <i>Electron J Metab Clin Nutr</i>. 2023;10(06):718&#x2013;723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rein LKL, Dohrn N, G&#xf6;genur I, Falk Klein M. Robotic versus laparoscopic approach for left-sided colon cancer: a nationwide cohort study. <i>Colorectal Dis</i>. 2023;25(12):2366&#x2013;2377. doi: 10.1111/codi.16803
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/codi.16803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37919465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YS. From enhanced recovery after surgery to prehabilitation:the new concepts and clinical practice. <i>Chin J Pract Surg</i>. 2024;44(02):155&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang LC, Wang G, Jiang ZW. Current research status on the impact of enhanced recovery after surgery on postoperative recovery and long-term prognosis of colorectal cancer patients. <i>J Colon Anal Sur</i>. 2025;31(03):179&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Y. The ideals and realities of colorectal surgery in the past ten years. <i>Chin J Pract Surg</i>. 2024;44(04):398&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asklid D, Segelman J, Gedda C, Hjern F, Pekkari K, Gustafsson UO. The impact of perioperative fluid therapy on short-term outcomes and 5-year survival among patients undergoing colorectal cancer surgery - A prospective cohort study within an ERAS protocol. <i>Eur J Surg Oncol</i>. 2017;43(8):1433&#x2013;1439. doi: 10.1016/j.ejso.2017.04.003
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejso.2017.04.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28528188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanda M. Preoperative predictors of postoperative complications after gastric cancer resection. <i>Surg Today</i>. 2020;50(1):3&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1007/s00595-019-01877-8
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00595-019-01877-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6949209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31535226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia T. <i>Perioperative Fluid Management and PostoperativeComplications in Gastrointestinal Cancer Surgery: ARetrospective Cohort Study</i>. PLA Air Force Medical University; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su YR, Li C, He DT. Application of early postoperative oral feeding in fast track surgery for colorectal cancer. <i>China Practical Med</i>. 2021;16(02):38&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu BL, Lv Q, Zhu FF, et al. A meta-analysis of the timing of early oral feeding among colorectal cancer patients. <i>Shanghai Nur</i>. 2023;23(01):38&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JJ, Sun H, Zhao J, et al. Effect of goal-oriented early activity rehabilitation during postoperative drug treatment period in patients undergoing gastrointestinal hepatobiliary surgery. <i>Chin J Drug Abuse Prev Treat</i>. 2025;31(04):666&#x2013;669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T. Effects of soluble dietary fiber on postoperative immune function in patients with gastrointestinal cancer. Practical integrated traditional Chinese and western medicine clinical practice. 2020;20(10):38&#x2013;39. doi: 10.13638/j.issn.1671-4040.2020.10.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13638/j.issn.1671-4040.2020.10.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao MM. To explore the effect of traditional Chinese medicine characteristic nursing on postoperative patients with colorectal cancer. <i>Contemp Med Symp</i>. 2025;23(26):175&#x2013;178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu ZC, An Y, Li LX, et al. Research advances in postoperative pain and postoperative delirium. <i>J Clin Anesthesiol</i>. 2025;41(09):974&#x2013;977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu XM, Luo AL, Tian YK, et al. Expert opinion on prevention and treatment of postoperative nausea and vomiting (2012). <i>J Clin Anesthesiol</i>. 2012;28(04):413&#x2013;416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong JH, Su JY, Ma L. Research status and perspective of postoperative ileus. <i>Chin J Gen Pract</i>. 2023;21(09):1576&#x2013;1580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyon A, Payne CJ, Mackay GJ. Enhanced recovery programme in colorectal surgery: does one size fit all?
<i>World J Gastroenterol</i>. 2012;18(40):5661&#x2013;5663. doi: 10.3748/wjg.v18.i40.5661
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v18.i40.5661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3484332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23155304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>