<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41798799</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-2295</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Construction and validation of a prognostic model for clinical outcomes in patients with prolonged disorders of consciousness based on multidimensional indicators: a prospective cohort study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1738430</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1738430</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1738430</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fneur.2026.1738430</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To develop and validate a prognostic prediction model for patients with prolonged disorders of consciousness (pDoC) based on multidimensional clinical indicators, aiming to improve prognostic accuracy and provide objective support for clinical decision-making.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A prospective cohort study was conducted involving 304 patients with pDoC admitted to the First Affiliated Hospital of Nanchang University between January 2021 and October 2023. Clinical data were collected, including demographics, etiology, disease duration, behavioral assessment scores (Glasgow Coma Scale [GCS], Full Outline of UnResponsiveness [FOUR], and Coma Recovery Scale-Revised [CRS-R]), laboratory indicators, and other relevant clinical variables. Prognosis was assessed using the Glasgow Outcome Scale-Extended (GOS-E) and dichotomized into good outcome (GOS-E 3-8) and poor outcome (GOS-E 1-2). Feature selection was performed using the Boruta algorithm combined with recursive feature elimination (RFE). Prognostic models were developed using logistic regression, support vector machine (SVM), multilayer perceptron (MLP), XGBoost, and gradient boosting machine (GBM) implemented in scikit-learn. Model performance was evaluated using accuracy, receiver operating characteristic curve area under the curve (ROC-AUC), and decision curve analysis (DCA). SHapley Additive exPlanations (SHAP) were applied to interpret the optimal model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Among the developed models, the GBM model demonstrated the best predictive performance, with an AUROC of 0.954 (95% CI: 0.924-0.977) in the training set and 0.922 (95% CI: 0.847-0.979) in the test set. Decision curve analysis indicated that the GBM model yielded substantial net clinical benefit across most threshold probabilities. SHAP analysis identified CRS-R score, age, FOUR score, total GCS score, and length of hospitalization as the most influential prognostic predictors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A robust prognostic prediction model for pDoC patients was developed and validated using multidimensional clinical data and machine learning techniques. The GBM model achieved excellent discriminative performance and clinical utility, providing an objective tool for prognosis estimation and individualized treatment and rehabilitation planning. Further multi-center studies are warranted to optimize the model and confirm its generalizability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Feng and Zhang.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Zhen</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Second Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University (Xibei Hospital), Xi'an, Shanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Qiaojun</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Second Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University (Xibei Hospital), Xi'an, Shanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101546899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-2295</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">behavioral scales</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disorders of consciousness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prediction model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prognosis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41798799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12962912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2026.1738430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kondziella D, Bender A, Diserens K, van Erp W, Estraneo A, Formisano R, et al. European academy of neurology guideline on the diagnosis of coma and other disorders of consciousness. Eur J Neurol. (2020) 27:741&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1111/ene.14151,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32090418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song M, Yang Y, Yang Z, Cui Y, Yu S, He J, et al. Prognostic models for prolonged disorders of consciousness: an integrative review. Cell Mol Life Sci. (2020) 77:3945&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1007/s00018-020-03512-z,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00018-020-03512-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11104990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32306061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao G, Wu X, Feng J, Hui J, Mao Q, Lecky F, et al. Clinical characteristics and outcomes in patients with traumatic brain injury in China: a prospective, multicentre, longitudinal, observational study. Lancet Neurol. (2020) 19:670&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/s1474-4422(20)30182-4,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1474-4422(20)30182-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32702336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shilan T, Yansui X. Advances in rehabilitation outcomes and care in patients with prolonged disorders of consciousness. Chin Gen Pract. (2023) 3:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.12114/j.issn.1007-9572.2023.0088</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12114/j.issn.1007-9572.2023.0088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonardi M, Giovannetti AM, Pagani M, Raggi A, Sattin D, National Consortium Functioning And Disability In Vegetative And In Minimal Conscious State Patients . Burden and needs of 487 caregivers of patients in vegetative state and in minimally conscious state: results from a national study. Brain Inj. (2012) 26:1201&#x2013;10. doi: 10.3109/02699052.2012.667589,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/02699052.2012.667589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22571687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soeterik SM, Connolly S, Playford ED, Duport S, Riazi A. The psychological impact of prolonged disorders of consciousness on caregivers: a systematic review of quantitative studies. Clin Rehabil. (2017) 31:1374&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1177/0269215517695372,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215517695372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28933608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giacino JT, Katz DI, Schiff ND, Whyte J, Ashman EJ, Ashwal S, et al. Practice guideline update recommendations summary: disorders of consciousness: report of the guideline development, dissemination, and implementation Subcommittee of the American Academy of neurology; the American congress of rehabilitation medicine; and the National Institute on Disability, Independent Living, and Rehabilitation Research. Neurology. (2018) 91:450&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0000000000005926,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000005926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6139814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30089618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teasdale G, Jennett B. Assessment of coma and impaired consciousness. A practical scale. Lancet. (1974) 2:81&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(74)91639-0,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(74)91639-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4136544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laureys S, Bodart O, Gosseries O. The Glasgow coma scale: time for critical reappraisal? Lancet Neurol. (2014) 13:755&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/s1474-4422(14)70152-8,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1474-4422(14)70152-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25030507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijdicks EF, Bamlet WR, Maramattom BV, Manno EM, McClelland RL. Validation of a new coma scale: the four score. Ann Neurol. (2005) 58:585&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1002/ana.20611,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.20611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16178024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giacino JT, Kalmar K, Whyte J. The JFK coma recovery scale-revised: measurement characteristics and diagnostic utility. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. (2004) 85:2020&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2004.02.033,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2004.02.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15605342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodien YG, Carlowicz CA, Chatelle C, Giacino JT. Sensitivity and specificity of the coma recovery scale--revised Total score in detection of conscious awareness. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. (2016) 97:490&#x2013;2.e1. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2015.08.422,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2015.08.422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5018674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26342571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnakers C, Vanhaudenhuyse A, Giacino J, Ventura M, Boly M, Majerus S, et al. Diagnostic accuracy of the vegetative and minimally conscious state: clinical consensus versus standardized neurobehavioral assessment. BMC Neurol. (2009) 9:35. doi: 10.1186/1471-2377-9-35,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2377-9-35</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2718857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen AM, Coleman MR, Boly M, Davis MH, Laureys S, Pickard JD. Detecting awareness in the vegetative state. Science. (2006) 313:1402. doi: 10.1126/science.1130197,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1130197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16959998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giacino JT, Fins JJ, Laureys S, Schiff ND. Disorders of consciousness after acquired brain injury: the state of the science. Nat Rev Neurol. (2014) 10:99&#x2013;114. doi: 10.1038/nrneurol.2013.279,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrneurol.2013.279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24468878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Kang J, Zhong Y, Zhang J, Qiang M, Feng Z. A predictive model for awakening in patients with prolonged disorders of consciousness after craniocerebral injury. Medicine (Baltimore). (2024) 103:e36701. doi: 10.1097/md.0000000000036701,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/md.0000000000036701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10783300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38215152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gawryluk JR, D'arcy RC, Connolly JF, Weaver DF. Improving the clinical assessment of consciousness with advances in electrophysiological and neuroimaging techniques. BMC Neurol. (2010) 10:11. doi: 10.1186/1471-2377-10-11,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2377-10-11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2828440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20113490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Formisano R, D&#x2019;Ippolito M, Giustini M, Catani S, Mondello S, Piccolino I, et al. The prognostic role of candidate serum biomarkers in the post-acute and chronic phases of disorder of consciousness: a preliminary study. Brain Sci. (2024) 14:239. doi: 10.3390/brainsci14030239</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci14030239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10968965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38539627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagnato S, Boccagni C. Cerebrospinal fluid and blood biomarkers in patients with post-traumatic disorders of consciousness: a scoping review. Brain Sci. (2023) 13:364. doi: 10.3390/brainsci13020364,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci13020364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9954419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36831907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M, Laureys S. Artificial intelligence and machine learning in disorders of consciousness. Curr Opin Neurol. (2024) 37:614&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1097/WCO.0000000000001322,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000001322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39498844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haveman ME, Van Putten M, Hom HW, Van Putten MJAM, Eertman-Meyer CJ, Beishuizen A, et al. Predicting outcome in patients with moderate to severe traumatic brain injury using electroencephalography. Crit Care. (2019) 23:401. doi: 10.1186/s13054-019-2656-6,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-019-2656-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6907281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31829226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu R, Zhang H, Wu X, Fei X, Yang Q, Ma Z, et al. Outcome prediction of unconscious patients based on weighted sparse brain network construction. IEEE J Biomed Health Inform. (2023) 27:469&#x2013;79. doi: 10.1109/JBHI.2022.3218652,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JBHI.2022.3218652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36318552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Rashidy N, Sedik A, Siam AI, Ali ZH. An efficient edge/cloud medical system for rapid detection of level of consciousness in emergency medicine based on explainable machine learning models. Neural Comput Applic. (2023) 35:10695&#x2013;716. doi: 10.1007/s00521-023-08258-w,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-023-08258-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10015549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37155550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liuzzi P, Magliacano A, De Bellis F, Mannini A, Estraneo A. &lt;article-title update="added"&gt;predicting outcome of patients with prolonged disorders of consciousness using machine learning models based on medical complexity. Sci Rep. (2022) 12:13471. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-17561-w,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-17561-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9356130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35931703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alt&#x131;ntop &#xc7;G, Latifo&#x11f;lu F, Ak&#x131;n AK, &#xdc;lgey A. Quantitative electroencephalography analysis for improved assessment of consciousness levels in deep coma patients using a proposed stimulus stage. Diagnostics (Basel). (2023) 13:1383. doi: 10.3390/diagnostics13081383,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics13081383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10137534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37189484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson L, Boase K, Nelson LD, Temkin NR, Giacino JT, Markowitz AJ, et al. A manual for the Glasgow outcome scale-extended interview. J Neurotrauma. (2021) 38:2435&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1089/neu.2020.7527,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/neu.2020.7527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8390784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33740873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pencina MJ, D'agostino RB, D'agostino RB, Vasan RS. Evaluating the added predictive ability of a new marker: from area under the roc curve to reclassification and beyond. Stat Med. (2008) 27:157&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1002/sim.2929,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.2929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17569110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Ge Q, Lu H, Zhuang Y, Geng X, Chen X, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid metabolite alterations in patients with different etiologies, diagnoses, and prognoses of disorders of consciousness. Brain Behav. (2023) 13:e3070. doi: 10.1002/brb3.3070,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/brb3.3070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10454269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37421239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao B, Chen Y, Yu R, Chen L, Chen P, Weng Y, et al. Abnormal dynamic properties of functional connectivity in disorders of consciousness. Neuroimage Clin. (2019) 24:102071. doi: 10.1016/j.nicl.2019.102071,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2019.102071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6881656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31795053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saika A, Bansal S, Philip M, Devi BI, Shukla DP. Prognostic value of four and Gcs scores in determining mortality in patients with traumatic brain injury. Acta Neurochir. (2015) 157:1323&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1007/s00701-015-2469-6,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00701-015-2469-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26077394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnakers C, Giacino J, Kalmar K, Piret S, Lopez E, Boly M, et al. Does the four score correctly diagnose the vegetative and minimally conscious states? Ann Neurol. (2006) 60:744&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1002/ana.20919,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.20919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16847951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan X, Zhang T, Chen Y, Hou X, Huang Q, Li T, et al. Natural course and predictors of consciousness recovery in children with prolonged disorder of consciousness. Sci Rep. (2024) 14:17417. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-68370-2,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-68370-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11286944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39075188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>