<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41817204</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2192-5682</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Global spine journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Global Spine J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhanced Recovery After Lumbar Fusion Surgery: An International Survey on Current Practice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>21925682261434216</StartPage><MedlinePgn>21925682261434216</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">21925682261434216</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/21925682261434216</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Study DesignCross-sectional, web-based international survey study.ObjectivesTo assess spine surgeons' perspectives on the importance of Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS) components and barriers to implementing ERAS programs in degenerative lumbar fusion.MethodsIn May 2024, a web-based survey was distributed to AOSpine members. The survey covered eight ERAS components derived from the 2021 consensus statement for perioperative care in lumbar fusion. Respondents selected up to three components with the biggest perceived impact on recovery and up to three with the greatest room for improvement. Responses were summarized in a priority matrix. Demographics, perceived barriers, and implementation support needs were analyzed using descriptive statistics.ResultsThe survey was accessed by 400 individuals, yielding 322 responses (80.5%) and a 76.7% completion rate. Respondents represented academic (50.6%), private (28.9%), and local/community hospitals (20.5%) worldwide. ERAS components perceived to have the biggest impact on recovery were multimodal opioid-sparing analgesia (73.3%), early mobilization (63.8%), and preoperative education &amp; counselling (58.6%), which were also identified as having the greatest room for improvement (39.4%, 41.4%, and 62.6%, respectively). Key barriers were the absence of clear protocols and guidelines (56.2%), staff shortages (53.8%), and difficulties coordinating implementation and adherence (43.0%).ConclusionMultimodal opioid-sparing analgesia, early mobilization, and preoperative education &amp; counselling were identified as ERAS components with the biggest perceived impact on patient recovery and the greatest room for improvement. Targeted efforts in these domains may represent an important opportunity to enhance perioperative care and support the implementation of ERAS programs in lumbar spinal fusion.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jonkman</LastName><ForeName>Hein H R</ForeName><Initials>HHR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-5786-3415</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, Netherlands.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">6029</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SentryX, Utrecht, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Tol</LastName><ForeName>Floris R</ForeName><Initials>FR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SentryX, Utrecht, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Govers</LastName><ForeName>Tim M</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medip Analytics, Nijmegen, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Debets</LastName><ForeName>Silje A C A</ForeName><Initials>SACA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, Netherlands.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">6029</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wainwright</LastName><ForeName>Thomas W</ForeName><Initials>TW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedic Research Institute, Bournemouth University, Bournemouth, UK.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">6657</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy Department, University Hospitals Dorset NHS Foundation Trust, Bournemouth, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Debono</LastName><ForeName>Bertrand</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4638-1075</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre Francilien Du Dos, Clinique des Franciscaines, Versailles, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Michael M H</ForeName><Initials>MMH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4907-3510</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Neurosciences, Division of Neurosurgery, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">2129</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boer</LastName><ForeName>Hans D de</ForeName><Initials>HD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Pain Medicine and Procedural Sedation and Analgesia, Martini General Hospital, Groningen, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rovers</LastName><ForeName>Maroeska M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3095-170X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, Netherlands.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">6029</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verlaan</LastName><ForeName>Jorrit-Jan</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SentryX, Utrecht, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiotherapy, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Global Spine J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596156</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2192-5682</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AOSpine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ERAS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ERAS-DLF</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">degenerative</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">early recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lumbar fusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">questionnaire</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survey</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared the following potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article: Authors HJ, FT, and JJV are paid employees and stock owners in SentryX, a clinical-stage start-up company developing non-opioid local pain treatments for major surgery. Author TG is a paid employee and stock owner of Medip Analytics, and a former employee of the Radboud University Medical Center. The activities of Medip Analytics are unrelated to the present study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41817204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12982138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/21925682261434216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rajaee SS, Bae HW, Kanim LEA, Delamarter RB. Spinal fusion in the United States: analysis of trends from 1998 to 2008. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2012;37(1):67-76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21311399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torre M, Piazzolla A, Ciminello E, et al. Time trends in spine surgery in Italy: a nationwide, population-based study of 1,560,969 records of administrative health data from 2001 to 2019. Acta Orthop. 2025;96:256-264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11971841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40099462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mani K, Kleinbart E, Goldman SN, et al. Projections of single-level and multilevel spinal instrumentation procedure volume and associated costs for medicare patients to 2050. JAAOS: Global Research and Reviews. 2024;8(5):e24.00053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11095963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38743853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heck VJ, Klug K, Prasse T, et al. Projections from surgical use models in Germany suggest a rising number of spinal fusions in patients 75 years and older will challenge healthcare systems worldwide. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2023;481(8):1610-1619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10344528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36779601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDermott KW, Liang L. Overview of Operating Room Procedures During Inpatient Stays in U.S. Hospitals, 2018. Rockville; 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34637208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheikh SR, Thompson NR, Benzel E, et al. Can we justify it? Trends in the utilization of spinal fusions and associated reimbursement. Neurosurgery. 2020;86(2):E193-E202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31574148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerbershagen HJ, Aduckathil S, van Wijck AJM, Peelen LM, Kalkman CJ, Meissner W. Pain intensity on the first day after surgery: a prospective cohort study comparing 179 surgical procedures. Anesthesiology. 2013;118(4):934-944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23392233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan TJ. Poorly controlled postoperative pain: prevalence, consequences, and prevention. J Pain Res. 2017;10:2287-2298. Available from: https://www.dovepress.com/poorly-controlled-postoperative-pain-prevalence-consequences-and-preve-peer-reviewed-article-JPR
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5626380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29026331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devin CJ, McGirt MJ. Best evidence in multimodal pain management in spine surgery and means of assessing postoperative pain and functional outcomes. J Clin Neurosci. 2015;22(6):930-938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25766366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruskay JA, Fu M, Bohl DD, Webb ML, Grauer JN. Factors affecting length of stay after elective posterior lumbar spine surgery: a multivariate analysis. Spine J. 2015;15(6):1188-1195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24184639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang MMH, Far R, Riva-Cambrin J, Sajobi TT, Casha S. Poor postoperative pain control is associated with poor long-term patient-reported outcomes after elective spine surgery: an observational cohort study. Spine J. 2024;24(9):1615-1624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38685277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wainwright TW, Immins T, Middleton RG. Enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) and its applicability for major spine surgery. Best Pract Res Clin Anaesthesiol. 2016;30(1):91-102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27036606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debono B, Lonjon G, Galovich LA, et al. Indication variability in degenerative lumbar spine surgery: a Four-Nation Survey. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2018;43(3):185-192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28604486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber M, Chao M, Kaur S, Tran B, Dizdarevic A. A look forward and a look back: the growing role of ERAS protocols in orthopedic surgery. Anesthesiol Clin. 2024;42(2):345-356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38705681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joliat GR, Ljungqvist O, Wasylak T, Peters O, Demartines N. Beyond surgery: clinical and economic impact of enhanced recovery after surgery programs. BMC Health Serv Res. 2018;18(1):1008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6311010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30594252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauro KM, Smith C, Ibadin S, et al. Enhanced recovery after surgery guidelines and hospital length of stay, readmission, complications, and mortality. JAMA Netw Open. 2024;7(6):e2417310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11195621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38888922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaye A, Urman R, Cornett E, et al. Enhanced recovery pathways in orthopedic surgery. J Anaesthesiol Clin Pharmacol. 2019;35(5):35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6515716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31142957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu S, Qian W, Jiang C, Ye C, Chen X. Enhanced recovery after surgery for hip and knee arthroplasty: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Postgrad Med J. 2017;93(1106):736-742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5740550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28751437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietz N, Sharma M, Adams S, et al. Enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) for spine surgery: a systematic review. World Neurosurg. 2019;130:415-426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31276851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salamanna F, Contartese D, Brogini S, et al. Key components, current practice and clinical outcomes of ERAS programs in patients undergoing orthopedic surgery: a systematic review. J Clin Med. 2022;11(14):4222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9322698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35887986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debono B, Wainwright TW, Wang MY, et al. 
Consensus statement for perioperative care in lumbar spinal fusion: enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS&#xae;) society recommendations. Spine J. 2021;21(5):729&#x2013;752. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33444664/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33444664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Minh Duc NT, Luu Lam Thang T, et al. A consensus-based checklist for reporting of survey studies (CROSS). J Gen Intern Med. 2021;36(10):3179-3187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8481359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33886027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh SM, Liverpool A, Romeiser JL, Thacker J, Gan TJ, Bennett-Guerrero E. Types of surgical patients enrolled in enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) programs in the USA. Perioper Med. 2021;10(1):12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8077770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33902705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovegrove J, Tobiano G, Chaboyer W, et al. Clinicians&#x2019; perceptions of &#x201c;enhanced recovery after surgery&#x201d; (ERAS) protocols to improve patient safety in surgery: a national survey from Australia. Patient Saf Surg. 2024;18(1):18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11119013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38783341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Kim SM, Kim YC, Seo BK. Spadework for establishing integrative enhanced recovery program after spine surgery: web-based survey assessing Korean medical doctors&#x2019; perspectives. J Pain Res. 2022;15:1039-1049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9012315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35431577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debono B, Corniola MV, Pietton R, Sabatier P, Hamel O, Tessitore E. Benefits of enhanced recovery after surgery for fusion in degenerative spine surgery: impact on outcome, length of stay, and patient satisfaction. Neurosurg Focus. 2019;46(4):E6. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30933923/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30933923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae S, Alboog A, Esquivel KS, Abbasi A, Zhou J, Chui J. Efficacy of perioperative pharmacological and regional pain interventions in adult spine surgery: a network meta-analysis and systematic review of randomised controlled trials. Br J Anaesth. 2022;128(1):98-117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34774296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ntalouka MP, Brotis AG, Bareka MV, Stertsou ES, Fountas KN, Arnaoutoglou EM. Multimodal Analgesia in spine surgery: an umbrella review. World Neurosurg. 2021;149:129-139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33610874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Licina A, Silvers A, Laughlin H, Russell J, Wan C. Pathway for enhanced recovery after spinal surgery-a systematic review of evidence for use of individual components. BMC Anesthesiol. 2021;21(1):74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7944908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33691620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contartese D, Salamanna F, Brogini S, et al. Fast-track protocols for patients undergoing spine surgery: a systematic review. BMC Muscoskelet Disord. 2023;24(1):57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9869597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36683022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Yang Q, Pu M, Liao C. Efficacy of nursing interventions based on the enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) in patients with lumbar disc herniation. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):21947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12215921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40592924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braxton EE. Postoperative anesthesia and care pathways in ERAS for spine surgery. Semin Spine Surg. 2025;37:101187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo J, Tang Y, Cao J, Li W, Zheng L, Lin H. Application of an enhanced recovery after surgery care protocol in patients undergoing lumbar interbody fusion surgery: a meta-analysis. J Orthop Surg Res. 2025;20(1):154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11812206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39934844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damschroder LJ, Reardon CM, Widerquist MAO, Lowery J. The updated consolidated framework for implementation research based on user feedback. Implement Sci. 2022;17(1):75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9617234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36309746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cane J, O&#x2019;Connor D, Michie S. Validation of the theoretical domains framework for use in behaviour change and implementation research. Implement Sci. 2012;7(1):37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3483008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22530986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drew S, Judge A, Cohen R, Fitzpatrick R, Barker K, Gooberman-Hill R. Enhanced recovery after surgery implementation in practice: an ethnographic study of services for hip and knee replacement. BMJ Open. 2019;9(3):e024431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6429914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30842111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arroyo NA, Gessert T, Hitchcock M, et al. What promotes surgeon practice change? A scoping review of innovation adoption in surgical practice. Ann Surg. 2021;273(3):474-482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10777662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33055590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>