<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41639935</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1601-5223</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>163</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Hereditas</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Hereditas</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Yishen Gushu formula exerts osteoprotective effects in OVX-Induced PMOP rats: role of ferroptosis Inhibition and iron metabolism correction.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">34</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s41065-026-00642-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Postmenopausal osteoporosis (PMOP) is a common bone disease among middle-aged and elderly women. Ferroptosis, a form of programmed cell death, plays a crucial role in the regulation of bone metabolism. Yishen Gushu Formula (YSGSF), a traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) compound, has clinical potential for treating PMOP, yet its specific mechanism of action remains unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">This study aims to investigate the specific mechanism by which YSGSF treats PMOP by inhibiting ferroptosis through mediating the NCOA4/GPX4 pathway.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The rat PMOP model was established by OVX and treated with YSGSF for 12 consecutive weeks. HE staining and micro-CT were used to examine bone tissue morphology and structure. Serum levels of E2, PINP, and &#x3b2;-CTX were measured by ELISA. RNA-seq analysis was performed to explore the potential mechanism of YSGSF. Oxidative stress markers (ROS, MDA, SOD, GSH, FE) in rat serum were determined. The regulatory effects of YSGSF on NCOA4, FTH1, GPX4, and SLC7A11 were evaluated by IHC and qRT-PCR. Erastin was used in vitro to induce ferroptosis in ROS17/28 osteoblasts, with cell viability and ferroptosis-related protein levels detected by CCK8 and Western blotting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">YSGSF improved bone metabolism in OVX rats, alleviated osteoporotic morphological changes, promoted the overall structural recovery of trabecular bone, and increased bone density. RNA-seq suggested that YSGSF may exert its therapeutic effect on PMOP by inhibiting ferroptosis. Subsequent results indicated that YSGSF improved iron metabolism in bone tissue and suppressed iron-dependent oxidative damage. It reduced serum iron ion accumulation and inhibited the production of ROS and MDA. IHC and qRT-PCR confirmed that YSGSF suppressed the expression of NCOA4, upregulated FTH1, and further increased the expression levels of GPX4 and SLC7A11. In vitro cell experiments demonstrated that YSGSF ameliorates Erastin-induced ferroptosis in osteoblasts, improving the expression of related proteins and cell viability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">YSGSF ameliorates OVX-induced PMOP, potentially by inhibiting osteoblast ferroptosis through modulation of the NCOA4/GPX4 pathway.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s41065-026-00642-5.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangxi University of Chinese Medicine, Nanning, Guangxi, 530200, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangxi University of Chinese Medicine, Nanning, Guangxi, 530200, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>ZhiFeng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ruikang Hospital Affiliated to Guangxi University of Chinese Medicine, No. 10 Huadong Road, Nanning City, Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, 530011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>YongJin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangxi University of Chinese Medicine, Nanning, Guangxi, 530200, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>XiaoYun</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ruikang Hospital Affiliated to Guangxi University of Chinese Medicine, No. 10 Huadong Road, Nanning City, Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, 530011, China. Zhangxiaoyun520@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>YCSW2024428</GrantID><Agency>Innovation Project of Guangxi Graduate Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82360937</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023GXNSFAA026075</GrantID><Agency>Guangxi Natural Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023BS042</GrantID><Agency>Guangxi University of Chinese Medicine's Scientific Research Start-up Fund Project for Introducing Doctor</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Hereditas</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0374654</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0018-0661</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bone metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ferroptosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NCOA4/GPX4</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PMOP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">YSGSF</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This animal experimental protocol has been reviewed and approved by the Experimental Animal Ethics Committee of Guangxi University of Chinese Medicine, with the ethical approval number: DW20231109-234. Consent for publication: All authors have read the manuscript and agree to its publication. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41639935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12924249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41065-026-00642-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s41065-026-00642-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>De Martinis M, Sirufo MM, Polsinelli M, Placidi G, Di Silvestre D, Ginaldi L. Gender differences in osteoporosis: A Single-Center observational study. World J Men&#x2019;s Health. 2021;39(4):750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8443988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33474849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Long H, Wang J, Huang Z, Cao L. Clinical outcomes and safety of combined calcitriol and bisphosphonates in treating postmenopausal osteoporosis: a retrospective cohort study. J ORTHOP SURG RES. 2025;20(1):359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11983753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40205415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Wang Z, Zhang D, Ye D, Zhou Y, Qin J, et al. The prevalence and treatment rate trends of osteoporosis in postmenopausal women. PLoS ONE. 2023;18(9):e290289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10522039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37751427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viehweger F, Gusinde J, Leege N, Tinger L, Gorbokon N, Menz A, et al. Estrogen receptor expression in human tumors: A tissue microarray study evaluating more than 18,000 tumors from 149 different entities. HUM PATHOL. 2025;157:105757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40054585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharpe M, Noble S, Spencer CM. Alendronate DRUGS. 2001;61(7):999&#x2013;1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11434454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vahle JL, Long GG, Sandusky G, Westmore M, Ma YL, Sato M. Bone neoplasms in F344 rats given teriparatide [rhPTH(1&#x2013;34)] are dependent on duration of treatment and dose. TOXICOL PATHOL. 2004;32(4):426&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15204966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo C, Huang Q, Wang Y, Yao Y, Li J, Chen J, et al. Therapeutic application of natural products: NAD&#x2009;+&#x2009;metabolism as potential target. Phytomedicine. 2023;114:154768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36948143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P, Xu T, Yu A, Liang J, Zhou Y, Sun H, et al. The role of ferroptosis in osteoporosis and advances in Chinese herbal interventions. Biology. 2025;14(4):367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12025301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40282232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang N, Xin H, Xu P, Yu Z, Shou D. Erxian Decoction attenuates TNF-&#x3b1; induced osteoblast apoptosis by modulating the Akt/Nrf2/HO-1 signaling pathway. FRONT PHARMACOL. 2019;10:988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6748068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31551787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B, Chen Z, Zhang Z, Liu H, Han D, Yang H, et al. Zuogui pill disrupt the malignant cycle in breast cancer bone metastasis through the Piezo1-Notch-1-GPX4 pathway and active molecules fishing. Phytomedicine. 2024;123:155257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38103318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao S, Wang Y, Zhang Y, Ren J, Fan B, Deng Y, et al. Naringenin can inhibit the pyroptosis of osteoblasts by activating the Nrf2/HO-1 signaling pathway and alleviate the differentiation disorder of osteoblasts caused by microgravity. J AGR FOOD CHEM. 2024;72(46):25586&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11583372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39506307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin W, Zhu X, Yao F, Xu X, Chen X, Luo Z, et al. Cytoprotective effect of Fufang Lurong Jiangu capsule against hydrogen peroxide-induced oxidative stress in bone marrow stromal cell-derived osteoblasts through the Nrf2/HO-1 signaling pathway. BIOMED PHARMACOTHER. 2020;121:109676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31810119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao J, Bei J, Li Z, Han M, Ma B, Ma P, et al. Qing`e pill inhibits osteoblast ferroptosis via ATM Serine/Threonine kinase (ATM) and the PI3K/AKT pathway in primary osteoporosis. FRONT PHARMACOL. 2022;13:902102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9294279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35865965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Z, Qi G, He X, Yu Y, Cao Y, Zhang C, et al. Ferroptosis in osteocytes as a target for protection against postmenopausal osteoporosis. ADV SCI. 2024;11(12):2307388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10966575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38233202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei X, Qi B, Ma R, Zhang Y, Liu N, Fang S, et al. Quantitative proteomics revealed the pharmacodynamic network of Bugu Shengsui Decoction promoting osteoblast proliferation. FRONT ENDOCRINOL. 2022;12:833474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8822948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35145485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia H, Liu J, Yang W, Liu M, Luo Y, Yang Z, et al. Integrated strategy of network Pharmacological prediction and experimental validation elucidate possible mechanism of Bu-Yang herbs in treating postmenopausal osteoporosis via ESR1. FRONT PHARMACOL. 2021;12:654714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8144472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34045964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Gong H, Jiang M, Jin F, Wang G, Yan C, et al. Regulation of enzymatic lipid peroxidation in osteoblasts protects against postmenopausal osteoporosis. NAT COMMUN. 2025;16(1):758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11742680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39824794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong X, Li L, Wan W. Optimal kidney-tonifying traditional Chinese medicines for postmenopausal osteoporosis: A network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J CLIN DENSITOM. 2025;28(2):101581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40121932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Li Y, Li P, Yang L, Li H. 4-Octyl Itaconate Attenuates Postmenopausal Osteoporosis by Inhibiting Ferroptosis and Enhancing Osteogenesis via the Nrf2 Pathway. <i>INFLAMMATION</i>. 2025;48(5):3326&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12596320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39984770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y, Sun R, Yang H, Gu T, Han M, Yu C, et al. Aucubin PromotesBMSCs proliferation and differentiation of postmenopausal osteoporosis patients by regulating ferroptosis andBMP2 signalling. J CELL MOL MED. 2025;29(2):e70288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11740986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39823248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z, Xue Y, Wang J. Screening diagnostic markers of osteoporosis based on ferroptosis of osteoblast and osteoclast. Aging. 2023;15(18):9391&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10564410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37770229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Han J, Ding S, Liu S, Wang H. Identification of ferroptosis-associated biomarkers for the potential diagnosis and treatment of postmenopausal osteoporosis. FRONT ENDOCRINOL. 2022;13:986384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9464919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36105394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Xu J, Shi S, Weng Y, Guo B, Che L, et al. Identification and validation of iron metabolism genes in osteoporosis. BMC MED GENOMICS. 2024;17(1):5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10762978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38169377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long S, Li S, Li J, He Y, Tan B, Jing H, et al. Identification of osteoporosis ferroptosis-related markers and potential therapeutic compounds based on bioinformatics methods and molecular Docking technology. BMC MED GENOMICS. 2024;17(1):99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11036634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38650009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Zhang J, Tian Y, Xu X, Wang B, Huang Z, et al. Iron accumulation in ovarian microenvironment damages the local redox balance and oocyte quality in aging mice. REDOX BIOL. 2024;73:103195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11145558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38781731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conjard-Duplany A, Osseni A, Lamboux A, Mouradian S, Picard F, Moncollin V, et al. Muscle mTOR controls iron homeostasis and ferritinophagy via NRF2, HIFs and AKT/PKB signaling pathways. CELL MOL LIFE SCI. 2025;82(1):178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12037468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40293459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honari N, Sayadi M, Sajjadi SM, Solhjoo S, Sarab GA. Deferasirox improved iron homeostasis and hematopoiesis in ovariectomized rats with iron accumulation. SCI REP-UK. 2025;15(1):2449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11743768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39828810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin P, Su W, Li C, Lin L, Sheu J, Wen Z, et al. Investigating the Role of Ferroptosis-Related Genes in Ovarian Aging and the Potential for Nutritional Intervention. NUTRIENTS. 2023;15(11):2461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10255416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37299424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, Chen H, Lian H, Cai X, Xie L, Ahmed RG, et al. The role of the ferroptosis pathway in the toxic mechanism of TCDD-induced liver damage in zebrafish. Comp Biochem Physiol C: Toxicol Pharmacol. 2025;295:110213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40286831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Li C, Zhang Y, Zhang J, Yang X. Ophiopogonin B induces gastric cancer cell death by blocking the GPX4/xCT&#x2013;dependent ferroptosis pathway. ONCOL LETT. 2022;23(3):104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8822489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35154435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Xiao J, Zhou S, Wumiti T, Zhao Z, Zhao R et al. (2025). The GPR30-Mediated BMP-6/HEP/FPN Signaling Pathway Inhibits Ferroptosis in Bone Marrow Mesenchymal Stem Cells to Alleviate Osteoporosis. International Journal of Molecular Sciences 26(5): 2027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11900958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40076648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke D, Gao T, Dai H, Xu J, Ke T. RANKL promotes MT2 degradation and ROS production in osteoclast precursors through Beclin1-dependent autophagy. DIFFERENTIATION. 2025;143:100863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40267773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinohara I, Morita M, Chow SKH, Murayama M, Sususki Y, Gao Q, et al. Pathophysiology of the effects of oxidative stress on the skeletal system. J ORTHOP RES. 2025;43(6):1059&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40143581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Huang Z, Chen G, Li Y, Liu Y, Gu H, et al. Astragaloside IV alleviated bone loss in mice with ovariectomy-induced osteoporosis via modulating gut microbiota and fecal metabolism. FRONT PHARMACOL. 2025;16:1548491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12003300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40248089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Yu F, Wu W. New perspectives on postmenopausal osteoporosis: mechanisms and potential therapeutic strategies of sirtuins and oxidative stress. ANTIOXIDANTS-BASEL. 2025;14(5):605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12108454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40427485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Han Z, Wang Y, Su J, Lin Y, Cheng X, et al. Targeting ferroptosis in Bone-Related diseases: facts and perspectives. J INFLAMM RES. 2023;16:4661&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10590556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37872954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Zhang C, Chai Y, Zhou Y, Zeng H, Zhang X. Using broadly targeted plant metabolomics technology combined with network Pharmacology to explore the mechanism of action of the Yishen Gushu formula in the treatment of postmenopausal osteoporosis in vivo. J ETHNOPHARMACOL. 2024;333:118469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38914151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Zhao J, Yuan J, Ding R, Yang G, Cao J, et al. Harnessing engineered exosomes as METTL3 carriers: enhancing osteogenesis and suppressing lipogenesis in bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells for postmenopausal osteoporosis treatment. MATER TODAY BIO. 2025;32:101648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11986517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40225129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapra L, Saini C, Mishra PK, Garg B, Gupta S, Manhas V, et al. <i>Bacillus coagulans</i> ameliorates inflammatory bone loss in post-menopausal osteoporosis via modulating the Gut-Immune-Bone axis. Gut Microbes. 2025;17(1):2492378.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12036487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40275534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu G, Whitaker AL, Zhang G, Karner CM. Divergent requirements for glutathione biosynthesis during osteoclast differentiation in vitro and in vivo. ANTIOXIDANTS-BASEL. 2025;14(2):197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11851466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40002383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipbunjong C, Khimmaktong W, Hengpratom T, Thitiphatphuvanon T, Pholpramool C, Surinlert P. Glabridin alleviates oxidative Stress-Induced osteoporosis by targeting the Akt/NF-&#x138;B and Akt/GSK-3&#x3b2; pathways. Int J Mol Sci. 2025;26(7):2949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11988926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40243576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang J, Chai H, Sun C, Wang S, She C, Geng D et al. Titanium particles activate osteocytic connexin 43 to induce oxidative stress and osteoclastogenesis through the JAK-STAT pathway. ANTIOXID REDOX SIGN: 2024&#x2013;894. ANTIOXIDANTS&amp; REDOX SIGNALING. 2025;43(4-6):215&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40207369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao R, Qiao M, Wang B, Fan J, Gao F, Wang S, et al. Laboratory-based biomarkers for risk Prediction, auxiliary diagnosis and Post-operative Follow-up of osteoporotic fractures. CURR OSTEOPOROS REP. 2025;23(1):19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11978538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40199776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y, Yu Y, Yan P. The protective effects of tectoridin on bone fractures against oxidative stress via the Inhibition of NF-&#x3ba;B and apoptotic pathways in ovariectomized rats. TOXICOL APPL PHARM. 2025;500:117345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40246203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan D, Huang S, Li J, Zhou S, Deng J, Qin S, et al. Ferroptosis in endometriosis: traditional Chinese medicine interventions and mechanistic insights. Am J Chin Med. 2025;53(02):385&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40145281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv H, Wang Y, Zhen C, Liu J, Chen X, Zhang G, et al. A static magnetic field improves bone quality and balances the function of bone cells with regulation on iron metabolism and redox status in type 1 diabetes. FASEB J. 2023;37(7):e22985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37249350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing Z, Li Y, Zhang H, Chen T, Yu J, Xu X, et al. Tobacco toxins induce osteoporosis through ferroptosis. REDOX BIOL. 2023;67:102922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10571034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37826866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni S, Yuan Y, Qian Z, Zhong Z, Lv T, Kuang Y, et al. Hypoxia inhibits RANKL-induced ferritinophagy and protects osteoclasts from ferroptosis. FREE RADICAL BIO MED. 2021;169:271&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33895289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Xi X, Wu T, Lu Y, Zhong P, Hu Y, et al. Aikeqing, a kidney- and spleen-tonifying compound Chinese medicine granule, prevented ovariectomy-induced bone loss in rats via the suppression of osteoclastogenesis. BIOMED PHARMACOTHER. 2023;166:115339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37595429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang G, Zhou X, Yin J, Niu X, Zhao Y, Li X, et al. Multi-omics analysis of kidney, bone and bone marrow explored potential mechanisms of Erzhi Wan against osteoporosis with kidney-Yin deficiency. J PHARMACEUT BIOMED. 2024;246:116211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38759323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanchen F, Yali L, Xue D, Zixuan L, Yunke Z, Zhiying C, et al. Exploring the multicomponent synergy mechanism of Zuogui Wan on postmenopausal osteoporosis by a systems Pharmacology strategy. J TRADIT CHIN MED. 2024;44(3):489&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11077145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38767632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Wang Z, Chen Y, Yang Y, Shao H, Feng X, et al. Regulation of monocyte polarization through nuclear factor kappa B /inhibitor of kappa B alpha pathway by cuscuta chinensis Lam. In postmenopausal osteoporosis. J ETHNOPHARMACOL. 2025;346:119710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40154899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo B, Liang Z, Lin W, Li Y, Zhong W, Bai D, et al. Aqueous extract of rehmanniae radix praeparata improves bone health in ovariectomized rats by modulating the miR-29a-3p/NFIA/Wnt signaling pathway axis. J ETHNOPHARMACOL. 2025;344:119549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40024453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L, Wang Y, Zhu Z, Yao X, Zhang R, Xia Y, et al. Selection of the Anti-Osteoporosis active ingredients of fructus Psoraleae&#x2014;Eucommia&#x2014;Drynariae rhizoma based on Solid&#x2010;Phase Bio&#x2010;Cell chromatography AndHPLC &#x2013;MS analysis. FOOD SCI NUTR. 2025;13(1):e4604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11732702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39816481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>