<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41853187</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-2295</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation in treating patients with post-stroke motor disorders: a prospective study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1711146</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1711146</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1711146</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fneur.2026.1711146</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Although traditional rehabilitation training can partially improve motor function in patients with post-stroke motor disorders, its impact on neural plasticity remains limited. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation (taVNS), a non-invasive method targeting the auricular branch of the vagus nerve, represents a promising neuromodulatory approach. This prospective study aimed to assess the therapeutic effects of taVNS on functional recovery in this population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 147 patients with post-stroke motor disorders were consecutively enrolled between February 2023 and November 2024. After excluding 8 dropouts, 139 patients were randomly assigned via a random number table to either an electrical stimulation group (taVNS group) or a rehabilitation group (conventional training). The taVNS group initially included 73 patients, with 3 dropouts yielding a final sample of 70. The rehabilitation group initially included 74 patients, with 5 dropouts resulting in 69 participants. All participants underwent comprehensive assessments at baseline and following a 4-week intervention period. Outcome measures encompassed neuroelectrophysiological parameters (motor evoked potential latency and amplitude), clinical functional evaluations (Action Research Arm Test, Fugl-Meyer Assessment for Upper Extremity, Modified Barthel Index), serum biomarker levels (brain-derived neurotrophic factor, S100 calcium-binding protein &#x3b2;), and systematic documentation of adverse events. Based on post-treatment Fugl-Meyer Assessment-Upper Extremity (FMA-UE) scores, patients were further categorized into improvement and non-improvement subgroups for additional comparative analysis. Pearson correlation analysis was utilized to examine potential relationships between functional scores, neurophysiological data, and biomarker concentrations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Baseline characteristics were comparable between groups (<i>p</i> &gt;&#x202f;0.05). Post-intervention, the taVNS group showed significantly superior outcomes: shorter MEP latency (<i>p</i> &lt;&#x202f;0.05), higher MEP amplitude (<i>p</i> &lt;&#x202f;0.05), improved scores on ARAT, FMA-UE, and MBI (all <i>p</i> &lt;&#x202f;0.05), increased levels of BDNF (<i>p</i> &lt;&#x202f;0.05), and decreased levels of S100-&#x3b2; (<i>p</i> &lt;&#x202f;0.05). Within-group analysis indicated that MEP latency decreased only in the taVNS group, while amplitude improved in both groups. In the rehabilitation group, post-treatment MEP latency showed no significant difference from baseline (<i>p</i> &gt;&#x202f;0.05). Both groups exhibited significant post-treatment improvements in ARAT, FMA-UE, and MBI scores. However, the magnitude of improvement in clinical scores and biomarkers was substantially greater in the taVNS group after treatment. The pre-to post-treatment changes in MEP latency and MEP amplitude were larger in the taVNS group compared to the rehabilitation group (<i>p</i> &lt;&#x202f;0.001). Similarly, the changes in ARAT, FMA-UE, and MBI scores, as well as in BDNF and S100-&#x3b2;levels, were all greater in the taVNS group than (<i>p</i> &lt;&#x202f;0.001). Adverse reaction incidence did not differ significantly between groups (taVNS 11.43% vs. rehabilitation 8.70%, <i>p</i> &gt;&#x202f;0.05). ARAT, FMA-UE, and MBI scores were negatively correlated with MEP latency and S100-&#x3b2; levels, and positively correlated with MEP amplitude and BDNF levels (all <i>p</i> &lt;&#x202f;0.05). These correlations were consistent for baseline values, post-treatment values, and pre-post change values.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">taVNS is an effective and safe adjunctive therapy for post-stroke motor recovery. It enhances neuroelectrophysiological function, improves motor and daily living abilities, and favorably modulates biomarkers of neural injury and repair. The consistent correlations among functional, neurophysiological, and biochemical outcomes highlight an integrated recovery pathway, supporting the integration of taVNS into standard neurorehabilitation protocols.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Xue and Ma.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xue</LastName><ForeName>Ruiling</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chongqing Medical University, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Chongqing General Hospital, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Jingxi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chongqing Medical University, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Chongqing General Hospital, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101546899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-2295</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neural plasticity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stroke</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41853187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12992002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2026.1711146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Badran BW, Peng X, Baker-Vogel B, Hutchison S, Finetto P, Rishe K, et al. Motor activated auricular vagus nerve stimulation as a potential neuromodulation approach for post-stroke motor rehabilitation: a pilot study. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. (2023) 37:374&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1177/15459683231173357,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15459683231173357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10363288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37209010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Zhou Z, Chong K, Zhao J, Wu Y, Ren M, et al. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation for long-term post-stroke cognitive impairment: a DTI case report. Front Hum Neurosci. (2024) 18:1473535. doi: 10.3389/fnhum.2024.1473535,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2024.1473535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11497276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39444545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzolini S, Robertson AD, MacIntosh BJ, Corbett D, Anderson ND, Brooks D, et al. Effect of high-intensity interval training and moderate-intensity continuous training in people with poststroke gait dysfunction: a randomized clinical trial. J Am Heart Assoc. (2023) 12:e031532. doi: 10.1161/JAHA.123.031532,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.123.031532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10727274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37947080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao F, Wang L, Wang Z, Tian Y, Wu J, Wang M, et al. Case report: Monitoring consciousness with fNIRS in a patient with prolonged reduced consciousness following hemorrhagic stroke undergoing adjunct taVNS therapy. Front Neurosci. (2025) 19:1519939. doi: 10.3389/fnins.2025.1519939,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2025.1519939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11832507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39967804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong H, Zheng F, Niu B, Wang B, Xu L, Yang Y, et al. Auricular transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation enhances post&#x2010;stroke neurological and cognitive recovery in mice by suppressing ferroptosis through &#x3b1;7 nicotinic acetylcholine receptor activation. CNS Neurosci Ther. (2025) 31:e70439. doi: 10.1111/cns.70439,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cns.70439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12082278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40376919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haakana P, Natkynmaki A, Kirveskari E, Makela JP, Kilgard MP, Tarvainen MP, et al. Effects of auricular vagus nerve stimulation and electrical earlobe stimulation on motor-evoked potential changes induced by paired associative stimulation. Eur J Neurosci. (2024) 60:5949&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1111/ejn.16539,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ejn.16539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39258329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herr T, Kleger P, Strauss S, Szeska C, Khalil N, Badran BW, et al. Effect of non-invasive transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation on cerebral motor excitability-study protocol for a randomized, sham controlled trial. Front Neurol. (2023) 14:1341898. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2023.1341898,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2023.1341898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10811126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38283680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou N, Zhou Q, Zhang Y, Xin C, Wang Y, Claire-Marie R, et al. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation as a novel therapy connecting the central and peripheral systems: a review. Int J Surg. (2024) 110:4993&#x2013;5006. doi: 10.1097/JS9.0000000000001592,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JS9.0000000000001592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11326027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38729100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilz MJ. Transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation&#x2014;a brief introduction and overview. Auton Neurosci. (2022) 243:103038. doi: 10.1016/j.autneu.2022.103038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2022.103038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36201901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J, Li X, Zhou Y, Liu H, Ma C, Hao C, et al. Clinical advances in transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation for post-stroke disorders: state of the art and future perspectives. Front Neurol. (2025) 16:1676727. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2025.1676727,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2025.1676727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12615202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41245869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson J, Pierce D, Dixit A, Kimberley TJ, Robertson M, Tarver B, et al. Safety, feasibility, and efficacy of vagus nerve stimulation paired with upper-limb rehabilitation after ischemic stroke. Stroke. (2016) 47:143&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.115.010477,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.115.010477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4689175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26645257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim AY, Marduy A, de Melo PS, Gianlorenco AC, Kim CK, Choi H, et al. Safety of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation (taVNS): a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. (2022) 12:22055. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-25864-1,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-25864-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9772204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36543841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaniusas E, Kampusch S, Tittgemeyer M, Panetsos F, Gines RF, Papa M, et al. Current directions in the auricular vagus nerve stimulation I&#x2014;a physiological perspective. Front Neurosci. (2019) 13:854. doi: 10.3389/fnins.2019.00854,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2019.00854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6697069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31447643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurido-Soto OJ, Tan G, Nielsen SS, Huguenard AL, Donovan K, Xu I, et al. (2025) Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation reduces inflammatory biomarkers and may improve outcomes after large vessel occlusion strokes: results of the randomized clinical trial NUVISTA. <i>medRxiv</i>. Available online at: 10.1101/2025.03.06.25323500. [Epub ahead of preprint]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2025.03.06.25323500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12722435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41428140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CLH, Pokharkar Y, Venketasubramanian NCHIMES and CHIMES-E Investigators. Association between baseline NIHSS limb motor score and functional recovery after stroke: analysis based on a multicountry dataset. Cerebrovasc Dis. (2023) 52:160&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1159/000525984,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000525984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35908546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farmer AD, Strzelczyk A, Finisguerra A, Gourine AV, Gharabaghi A, Hasan A, et al. International consensus based review and recommendations for minimum reporting standards in research on transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation (version 2020). Front Hum Neurosci. (2020) 14:568051. doi: 10.3389/fnhum.2020.568051,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2020.568051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8040977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33854421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Tang H, Liu C, Ma J, Liu G, Niu L, et al. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation for post-stroke depression: a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial. J Affect Disord. (2024) 354:82&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2024.03.005,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2024.03.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38452937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Cheng X, Zhang Y, Liao W. Effect of transcranial direct current stimulation combined with transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation on poststroke cognitive impairment: a study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open. (2024) 14:e082764. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2023-082764,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2023-082764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11015246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38604630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long L, Zang Q, Jia G, Fan M, Zhang L, Qi Y, et al. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation promotes white matter repair and improves dysphagia symptoms in cerebral ischemia model rats. Front Behav Neurosci. (2022) 16:811419. doi: 10.3389/fnbeh.2022.811419,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnbeh.2022.811419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9051615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35493949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv H, Yu X, Wang P, Luo M, Luo Y, Lu H, et al. Locus coeruleus tyrosine hydroxylase positive neurons mediated the peripheral and central therapeutic effects of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation (taVNS) in MRL/lpr mice. Brain Stimul. (2024) 17:49&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1016/j.brs.2023.12.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brs.2023.12.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38145753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li SY, Xu K, Wang YX, Wang MH, Li SS, Lin F, et al. Task-specific cortical mechanisms of taVNS-paired task-oriented training for post-stroke upper extremity dysfunction under cognitive load: an fNIRS study. Front Hum Neurosci. (2025) 19:1652612. doi: 10.3389/fnhum.2025.1652612,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2025.1652612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12504255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41070188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obata H, Sekiguchi H. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation reduces error amplitude during force field learning in healthy adults. Sci Rep. (2025) 15:44466. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-28152-w,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-28152-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12739117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41444297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szulczewski MT. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation combined with slow breathing: speculations on potential applications and technical considerations. Neuromodulation. (2022) 25:380&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1111/ner.13458,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ner.13458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35396070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Midden V, Simoncic U, Pirtosek Z, Kojovic M. The effect of taVNS at 25 Hz and 100 Hz on Parkinson&#x2019;s disease gait-a randomized motion sensor study. Mov Disord. (2024) 39:1375&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1002/mds.29826,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.29826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38757756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao JJ, Li YL, Zhang JL, Ren M, Xu JJ, Wang WJ, et al. Effect of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation on the expressions of GFAP and MAP2 in ischemic penumbra of rats with middle cerebral artery ischemia. Zhen Ci Yan Jiu. (2022) 47:33&#x2013;8. doi: 10.13702/j.1000-0607.20210059,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13702/j.1000-0607.20210059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35128868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou LY, Peng LJ, Liu YF, Wang SW, Qiu Y, Chen SJ, et al. Transcutaneous auricular vagal nerve stimulation for consciousness recovery in patients with prolonged disorders of consciousness (TAVREC): study protocol for a multicenter, triple-blind, randomized controlled trial in China. BMJ Open. (2024) 14:e083888. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2024-083888,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2024-083888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11149147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38821572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moustafa EBS, Darwish MH, El-Tamawy MS, Mostafa M, Abu Elkasem ST, Khalifa HA. Plasticity biomarkers, interleukin-6 and motor performance responses to trans-auricular vagus nerve stimulation post-stroke: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. (2025). doi: 10.1097/PHM.0000000000002878,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000002878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41224215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Gao F, Dai Y, Wang Z, Liang F, Wu J, et al. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation on upper limb motor function with stroke: a functional near-infrared spectroscopy pilot study. Front Neurosci. (2023) 17:1297887. doi: 10.3389/fnins.2023.1297887,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2023.1297887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10702495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38075278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Wang Y, Wang Y, Wang F, Zhang J, Li S, et al. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulators: a review of past, present, and future devices. Expert Rev Med Devices. (2022) 19:43&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1080/17434440.2022.2020095,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17434440.2022.2020095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34937487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Zhang J, Guo C, He J, Zhang S, Wang Y, et al. The efficacy and safety of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation in patients with mild cognitive impairment: a double blinded randomized clinical trial. Brain Stimul. (2022) 15:1405&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1016/j.brs.2022.09.003,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brs.2022.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36150665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Shan AD, Wan CH, Cao XY, Yuan YS, Ye SY, et al. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation improves anxiety symptoms and cortical activity during verbal fluency task in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease with anxiety. J Affect Disord. (2024) 361:556&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2024.06.083,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2024.06.083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38925314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang MH, Wang YX, Xie M, Chen LY, He MF, Lin F, et al. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation with task-oriented training improves upper extremity function in patients with subacute stroke: a randomized clinical trial. Front Neurosci. (2024) 18:1346634. doi: 10.3389/fnins.2024.1346634,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2024.1346634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10957639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38525376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francisco GE, Engineer ND, Dawson J, Kimberley TJ, Cramer SC, Prudente CN, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with upper-limb rehabilitation after stroke: 2- and 3-year follow-up from the pilot study. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. (2023) 104:1180&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2023.02.012,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2023.02.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37001842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aderinto N, Abraham IC, Olatunji G, Kokori E, Hasan A, Uwishema O. Mapping the role of vagus nerve stimulation in post-stroke arm motor recovery. J Neuroeng Rehabil. (2025) 22:215. doi: 10.1186/s12984-025-01759-w,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12984-025-01759-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12522968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41094520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson J, Engineer ND, Prudente CN, Pierce D, Francisco G, Yozbatiran N, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation paired with upper-limb rehabilitation after stroke: one-year follow-up. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. (2020) 34:609&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1177/1545968320924361,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1545968320924361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32476617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Li L, Li S, Fang J, Zhang J, Wang J, et al. Toward diverse or standardized: a systematic review identifying transcutaneous stimulation of auricular branch of the Vagus nerve in nomenclature. Neuromodulation. (2022) 25:366&#x2013;79. doi: 10.1111/ner.13346,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ner.13346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35396069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Zheng Y, Qi X, Lin H, Zhang J, Lin F, et al. Efficacy of transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation in post-stroke upper limb dysfunction: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized trials. Front Neurol. (2025) 16:1705512. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2025.1705512</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2025.1705512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Shi W, Fan J, Wang X, Song Y, Lian Y, et al. Transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation (ta-VNS) for treatment of drug-resistant epilepsy: a randomized, double-blind clinical trial. Neurotherapeutics. (2023) 20:870&#x2013;80. doi: 10.1007/s13311-023-01353-9,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-023-01353-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10275831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36995682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>