<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41885261</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6500</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in anaesthesiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Anaesthesiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Current controversies in paediatric regional anaesthesia.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/ACO.0000000000001636</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Regional anaesthesia has well established benefits in paediatric perioperative care and acute pain interventions. This article explores current controversies and emerging evidence in paediatric regional anaesthesia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Despite rates of local anaesthetic systemic toxicity (LAST) remaining low, dosing of local anaesthetics in children remains controversial, particularly in neonates, in whom maximum safe doses can easily be exceeded. Local anaesthetics additives, such as dexamethasone, dexmedetomidine, and clonidine, are commonly used to prolong regional anaesthesia and have demonstrated good efficacy and safety, though best route of administration remains debated. Peripheral nerve catheters prolong analgesia and can be safely managed in ambulatory settings. Enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) is rapidly expanding in paediatric anaesthesia, and regional anaesthesia forms a key component. Fear of masking compartment syndrome is not supported by current literature and not a contraindication to regional anaesthesia. Studies exploring the utility of awake regional anaesthesia in children have successfully demonstrated the avoidance of general anaesthesia. Anaesthetic training increasingly demands proficiency in ultrasound-guided regional techniques.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Regional anaesthesia is a safe and effective analgesic modality in children, including in trauma patients and as part of ERAS protocols, with good evidence for use of additives and low rates of complications, including LAST.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jackson</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia, Bristol Royal Hospital for Children, University Hospitals Bristol and Weston NHS Foundation Trust, Bristol.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burton</LastName><ForeName>Zoe</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia, Sheffield Children's NHS Foundation Trust, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pearson</LastName><ForeName>Annabel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia, Bristol Royal Hospital for Children, University Hospitals Bristol and Weston NHS Foundation Trust, Bristol.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Anaesthesiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8813436</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0952-7907</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enhanced recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">local anaesthetic systemic toxicity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">paediatric anaesthesia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peripheral nerve catheters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">regional anaesthesia</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41885261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ACO.0000000000001636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001503-990000000-00409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xin A, Grobler A, Bell G, et al. Neurodevelopmental outcomes after multiple general anesthetic exposures before 5 years of age: a cohort study. Anesthesiology 2025; 142:308&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker BJ, Long JB, Sathyamoorthy M, et al.; Pediatric Regional Anesthesia Network Investigators. Complications in pediatric regional anesthesia: an analysis of more than 100,000 blocks from the pediatric regional anesthesia network. Anesthesiology 2018; 129:721&#x2013;732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trivedi SM, Wahle CF, Mao YV, et al. Long-term complications from peripheral nerve blocks after pediatric orthopaedic lower extremity procedures: a systematic review. Am J Sports Med 2025; 53:981&#x2013;987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baizhanova A, Zhailauova A, Sazonov V. Regional anesthesia for pain control in children with solid tumors-a review of case reports. Front Pediatr 2024; 11:1275531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;senberg AT, J&#xf6;hr M, Wolf AR. Pro con debate: the use of regional vs systemic analgesia for neonatal surgery. Paediatr Anaesth 2011; 21:1247&#x2013;1258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royal College of Anaesthetists. 2021 Curriculum for a CCT in anaesthetics. Royal College of Anaesthetists; 2021. https://www.rcoa.ac.uk/2021-curriculum-cct-anaesthetics. [cited 18 December 2024]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson AME, Roberts S, Turbitt LR. New blocks on the kids: core basic nerve blocks in paediatric anaesthesia. Anaesthesia 2023; 78:3&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagen JG, Kattail D, Barnett N, et al. Baby steps to mastery: building blocks for novices in pediatric regional anesthesia. Reg Anesth Pain Med 2025: rapm-2025-106434. doi: 10.1136/rapm-2025-106434. Epub ahead of print. PMID: 40169358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/rapm-2025-106434.</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivani G, Suresh S, Ecoffey C, et al. The European Society of Regional Anaesthesia and Pain Therapy and the American Society of Regional Anesthesia and Pain Medicine Joint Committee Practice Advisory on Controversial Topics in Pediatric Regional Anesthesia. Reg Anesth Pain Med 2015; 40:526&#x2013;532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taenzer AH, Herrick M, Hoyt M, et al.; PRAN Investigators. Variation in pediatric local anesthetic dosing for peripheral nerve blocks: an analysis from the Pediatric Regional Anesthesia Network (PRAN). Reg Anesth Pain Med 2020; 45:964&#x2013;969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fettiplace M, Joudeh L, Bungart B, Boretsky K. Local anesthetic dosing and toxicity of pediatric truncal catheters: a narrative review of published practice. Reg Anesth Pain Med 2024; 49:59&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B, Zhang Z, Huang X, et al. The effect of different doses of ropivacaine for caudal block in school-aged children undergoing Shang Ring circumcision. J Perianesth Nurs 2025; 40:349&#x2013;355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schweitzer-Chaput A, Callot D, Bouazza N, et al. Local anesthetics systemic toxicity in children: analysis of the French pharmacovigilance database. BMC Pediatr 2023; 23:321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mistry MM, Endlich Y. Incidents relating to paediatric regional anaesthesia in the first 8000 cases reported to webAIRS. Anaesth Intensive Care 2023; 51:408&#x2013;421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park M, Lee SH, Sohn JT. Local anesthetic systemic toxicity induced by penile nerve block: a systematic review. Medicine (Baltim) 2025; 104:e44582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zufferey PJ, Chaux R, Lachaud P-A, et al. Dose&#x2013;response relationships of intravenous and perineural dexamethasone as adjuvants to peripheral nerve blocks: a systematic review and model-based network meta-analysis. Br J Anaesth 2024; 132:1122&#x2013;1132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joe YE, Lee JH, Eum D, et al. Intravenous dexamethasone does not prolong the duration of pudendal nerve block in infants and children undergoing hypospadias surgery: a randomized clinical trial. Paediatr Anaesth 2024; 34:259&#x2013;266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reysner T, Ciftci B, Pietraszek P, et al. Effect of intravenous dexamethasone on duration of analgesia following popliteal nerve block in pediatric ankle surgery: a randomized, triple-blinded clinical trial. J Clin Anesth 2025; 109:112094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albrecht E, Renard Y, Desai N. Intravenous versus perineural dexamethasone to prolong analgesia after interscalene brachial plexus block: a systematic review with meta-analysis and trial sequential analysis. Br J Anaesth 2024; 133:135&#x2013;145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makkar JK, Singh NP, Khurana BJK, et al. Efficacy of different routes of dexamethasone administration for preventing rebound pain following peripheral nerve blocks in adult surgical patients: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Anaesthesia 2025; 80:704&#x2013;712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing M, Liang X, Li L, et al. Efficacy of caudal vs intravenous administration of &#x3b1;2 adrenoceptor agonists to prolong analgesia in pediatric caudal block: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Paediatr Anaesth 2020; 30:1322&#x2013;1330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heydinger G, Bayer EE, Roth C, et al. Safety of intrathecal clonidine as an adjuvant to spinal anesthesia in infants and children. Paediatr Anaesth 2025; 35:374&#x2013;379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen AL, He M, Agrawal U, et al. Clonidine conserves sleep spindle properties and age-dependent electroencephalogram patterns mirroring physiologic sleep in infants under spinal anesthesia. Anesth Analg 2025. doi: 10.1213/ANE.0000000000007763. Epub ahead of print. PMID: 40956769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1213/ANE.0000000000007763.</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen JB, Su LM, Zhang XQ, et al. Ropivacaine combined with dexmedetomidine in ultrasound-guided axillary brachial plexus block in children, a randomized controlled trial. Eur J Med Res 2024; 29:416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Chen XB. Comparison of intravenous and perineural dexmedetomidine in prolongation of analgesia for peripheral nerve block: a meta-analysis and systematic review. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci 2023; 27:4116&#x2013;4134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xf6;pping DM, Elia N, Marret E, et al. Clonidine as an adjuvant to local anesthetics for peripheral nerve and plexus blocks: a meta-analysis of randomized trials. Anesthesiology 2009; 111:406&#x2013;415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Cassai A, Dost B, Bugada D, et al. Safety of clonidine and dexmedetomidine in peripheral nerve blocks: a systematic review of preclinical evidence. Br J Anaesth 2026; 136:255&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang S, Liu J, Ding Z, Shan T. The effect of dexmedetomidine on emergence delirium of postanesthesia events in pediatric department: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Medicine (Baltim) 2024; 103:e39337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marrone F, Fusco P, Pilia E, et al. New insights into the use of dexamethasone-dexmedetomidine as perineural adjuvants in peripheral nerve and fascial blocks: an up-to-date narrative review. Minerva Anestesiol 2025; 91:325&#x2013;333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grape S, Andany A, Cibotto C, et al. Duration of analgesia after supraclavicular brachial plexus block with intravenous dexamethasone with or without dexmedetomidine: a randomised, placebo-controlled, triple-blind trial. Br J Anaesth 2025: S0007-0912(25)00792-5. doi: 10.1016/j.bja.2025.10.049. Epub ahead of print. PMID: 41330797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bja.2025.10.049.</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dadure C, Bringuier S, Raux O, et al. Continuous peripheral nerve blocks for postoperative analgesia in children: feasibility and side effects in a cohort study of 339 catheters. Can J Anaesth 2009; 56:843&#x2013;850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKee V, Williams M, Denker K. Remote patient monitoring for postoperative pediatric patients with peripheral nerve catheters. J. Pediatr. Surg. Nurs. 2024; 13:103&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvey A, Nigro E, Hanley J, Bouchard M. Enhancing postoperative pain management and decreasing hospital length of stay on a pediatric orthopedic unit: implementation of an ambulatory continuous peripheral nerve block program. J Perianesth Nurs 2023; 38:685&#x2013;692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie J, De Souza E, Perez F, et al. Perioperative regional anesthesia pain outcomes in children: a retrospective study of 3160 regional anesthetics in routine practice. Clin J Pain 2024; 40:72&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viscusi ER, Hugo V, Hoerauf K, Southwick FS. Neuraxial and peripheral misconnection events leading to wrong-route medication errors: a comprehensive literature review. Reg Anesth Pain Med 2021; 46:176&#x2013;181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS England. Transition to NRFit&#x2122; connectors for intrathecal and epidural procedures, and delivery of regional blocks. 31 Jananuary 2024. https://www.england.nhs.uk/publication/resources-support-safe-transition-luer-connector-nrfit-intrathecal-and-epidural-procedures-and-delivery-regional-blocks/. [cited 15 December 2025]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association of Paediatric Anaesthetists of Great Britain and Ireland; Regional Anaesthesia UK. The use of NRFit&#x2122; needles for caudal anaesthesia. APAGBI; 2024. https://www.apagbi.org.uk/downloads/news/caudal-nrfit-statement-apa-rauk-final.pdf. [cited 15 December 2024]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;nnqvist PA. Fascial plane blocks in children-scientifically supported or not? Paediatr Anaesth 2024; 34:13&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi GP, Mariano E, Elkassabany NM, et al. 2026 American Society of Anesthesiologists Practice Guideline on Perioperative Pain Management Using Local and Regional Analgesia for Cardiothoracic Surgeries, Mastectomy, and Abdominal Surgeries. Anesthesiology 2026; 144:19&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin KJ, El-Boghdadly K. Mechanisms of action of the erector spinae plane (ESP) block: a narrative review. Can J Anaesth 2021; 68:387&#x2013;408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Qin Y, She H, Ma R. Review of the injectate dispersion pattern during anterior quadratus lumborum block. Medicine (Baltim) 2022; 101:e32038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emil S, Ferreira J, Frigon C, et al. Starting on the road to pediatric enhanced recovery after surgery: strategies and themes. J Pediatr Surg Open 2024; 6:100128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier S, Borzel J, Hellner N, et al. Enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) in pediatric cardiac surgery: status quo of implementation in europe. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth 2025; 39:177&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dost B, De Cassai A, Amaral S, et al. Regional anesthesia for pediatric cardiac surgery: a review. BMC Anesthesiol 2025; 25:77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansfield SA, Kotagal M, Hartman SJ, et al. Enhanced recovery after surgery for pediatric abdominal tumor resections: a prospective multi-institution study. J Pediatr Surg 2025; 60:162046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilkington M, Pentz B, Short K, et al. Enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) consensus recommendations for opioid-minimising pharmacological neonatal pain management. BMJ Paediatr Open 2024; 8:e002824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nathanson MH, Harrop-Griffiths W, Aldington DJ, et al. Regional analgesia for lower leg trauma and the risk of acute compartment syndrome: guideline from the Association of Anaesthetists. Anaesthesia 2021; 76:1518&#x2013;1525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vecchione T, Bansal V, Shore BJ, et al. Acute compartment syndrome in pediatric patients with peripheral nerve blocks. Reg Anesth Pain Med 2025: rapm-2025-106423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heffler MA, Brant JA, Singh A, et al. Ultrasound-guided regional anesthesia of the femoral nerve in the pediatric emergency department. Pediatr Emerg Care 2023; 39:e30&#x2013;e34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulton CD, Fletcher N, Murphy J, et al. Regional anesthesia as an alternative to procedural sedation for forearm fracture reductions in the pediatric emergency department. Pediatr Emerg Care 2024; 40:83&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhamrawy A, Veneziano G, Tobias JD. Regional anesthesia and sickle cell crisis in pediatric patients: an educational-focused review. Paediatr Anaesth 2024; 34:195&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sousa B, Nunes J, Ribeiro AF. Single-centre case series report of regional anaesthesia for pain management in vaso-occlusive crisis. Indian J Anaesth. 2024; 68:394&#x2013;396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neal JM, Barrington MJ, Brull R, et al. The Second ASRA practice advisory on neurologic complications associated with regional anesthesia and pain medicine: executive summary 2015. Reg Anesth Pain Med 2015; 40:401&#x2013;430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taenzer AH, Walker BJ, Bosenberg AT, et al. Asleep versus awake: does it matter? Pediatric regional block complications by patient state: a report from the Pediatric Regional Anesthesia Network. Reg Anesth Pain Med 2014; 39:279&#x2013;283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maupain O, Delvaux B, Huynh D, et al. Regional anaesthesia for awake urgent upper limb surgery in children: a prospective cohort study. Anaesthesia 2025; 80:1065&#x2013;1073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak PD, Lakade LS, Patil KV, et al. Clinical evaluation of feasibility and effectiveness using a virtual reality device during local anesthesia and extractions in pediatric patients. Eur Arch Paediatr Dent 2023; 24:379&#x2013;386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson AME, Gill H, Ecoffey C. Regional anaesthesia for awake surgery in children: we can, but should we? Anaesthesia 2025; 80:1028&#x2013;1031.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>