<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41701530</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1539-0705</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of hospice and palliative nursing : JHPN : the official journal of the Hospice and Palliative Nurses Association</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hosp Palliat Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Foundation of Holistic Care: Nurses' Spiritual Sensitivity Levels and Experiences.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/NJH.0000000000001220</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to explore nurses' spiritual sensitivity and how it shaped their everyday clinical caregiving experiences within a holistic care framework. A mixed-method approach was employed to integrate survey findings from 213 nurses with in-depth clinical narratives obtained from 32 nurses working in different hospital settings in T&#xfc;rkiye. Quantitative data were collected using the Nurse Information Form and the Spiritual Sensitivity Scale for Nurses, while qualitative data were gathered through semistructured individual interviews. Quantitative data were analyzed using statistical package for the social sciences, and qualitative data were evaluated through content analysis. Nurses' spiritual sensitivity levels were found to be generally high, with positive correlations identified between spiritual sensitivity, job satisfaction, and belief in spirituality's role in the healing process. Qualitative findings indicated that nurses recognized patients' spiritual needs by observing their psychological and emotional states, and that supporting religious and spiritual practices contributed not only to patients' recovery but also to nurses' professional satisfaction. Spiritual sensitivity was identified as a fundamental element of patient-centered and holistic nursing care, enhancing both the quality of care and professional satisfaction. These results highlighted the clinical relevance of spiritual sensitivity as an integral component of holistic nursing practice rather than an abstract personal attribute. Health care institutions were encouraged to actively support spiritual sensitivity through clinical guidelines, education, and organizational culture to strengthen holistic patient care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by The Hospice and Palliative Nurses Association. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cihan Erdo&#x11f;an</LastName><ForeName>Banu</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8850-7460</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Banu Cihan Erdo&#x11f;an, PhD, RN, is assistant professor, Home Patient Care Program, Health Care Services Department, Cerkes Vocational School, &#xc7;ankiri Karatekin University, &#xc7;ankiri, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Do&#x11f;an</LastName><ForeName>Nevin</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-5498-0647</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nevin Do&#x11f;an, PhD, RN, is assistant professor, Department of Nursing, Faculty of Health Sciences, Siirt University, Siirt, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Hosp Palliat Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100887419</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1522-2179</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mixed-method</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nursing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spiritual care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spiritual sensitivity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41701530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NJH.0000000000001220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00129191-990000000-00267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ghorbani M, Mohammadi E, Aghabozorgi R, Ramezani M. Spiritual care interventions in nursing: an integrative literature review. Support Care Cancer. 2021;29:1165&#x2013;1181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kappes M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Silva CA, Catal&#xe1;n L, Navalle C, Diaz M, Guglielmi I. Nurses&#x2019; role in spiritual care for patients and families in intensive care units: a scoping review. Enferm Intensiva. 2025;36:100494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murgia C, Notarnicola I, Caruso R, De Maria M, Rocco G, Stievano A. Spirituality and religious diversity in nursing: a scoping review. Healthcare. 2022;10:1661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavares AP, Martins H, Pinto S, Caldeira S, Pont&#xed;fice Sousa P, Rodgers B. Spiritual comfort, spiritual support, and spiritual care: a simultaneous concept analysis. Nurs Forum. 2022;57:1559&#x2013;1566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbari O, Dehghan M, Tirgari B. Muslim nurses&#x2019; spiritual sensitivity as a higher perception and reflection toward spiritual care: a qualitative study in southeast Iran. BMC Nurs. 2022;21:270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spekkink A, Jacobs G. The development of moral sensitivity of nursing students: a scoping review. Nurs Ethics. 2021;28:791&#x2013;808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang J, Du J, Sun Y, et al. The mediating role of empathy and moral sensitivity in nurses&#x2019; spiritual health and spiritual caregiving competence: a cross-sectional study. BMC Nurs. 2025;24:646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemi SY, Jafari A, Rabiei L, Nikfarjam M, Omidi M, Masoudi R. Exploring the concept of spiritual sensitivity from the perspectives of healthcare providers. J Relig Health. 2022;61:3806&#x2013;3821.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahramnezhad F, Asgari P. Spiritual care for COVID-19 patients: a neglected necessity. Infect Dis Clin Pract. 2021;29:e63&#x2013;e63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fadlilah N, Muhith A, Setiyowati E. Nurses&#x2019; spiritual competence towards spiritual care and patient satisfaction: a systematic review. J Appl Nurs Health. 2024;6:270&#x2013;281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos FC, Macieira TG, Yao Y, et al. Spiritual interventions delivered by nurses to address patients&#x2019; needs in hospitals or long-term care facilities: a systematic review. J Palliat Med. 2022;25:662&#x2013;677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi F, Masoumi Z, Oshvandi K, Khazaei S, Bijani M. Death anxiety, moral courage, and resilience in nursing students who care for COVID-19 patients: a cross-sectional study. BMC Nurs. 2022;21:150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavakol N, Tavakol M, Daman S. Moral distress effects on spirituality determinants in nurses. BMC Nurs. 2025;24:349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly M, Timmins F. Experiences related to patients&#x2019; and families&#x2019; expression of spiritual needs or spiritual support during the COVID-19 pandemic: a scoping review. J Relig Health. 2022;61:2141&#x2013;2167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcus B, Weigelt O, Hergert J, Gurt J, Gelleri P. The use of snowball sampling for multisource organizational research: some cause for concern. Pers Psychol. 2017;70:635&#x2013;673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Buchner A, Lang AG. Statistical power analyses using G*Power 3.1: tests for correlation and regression analyses. Behav Res Methods. 2009;41:1149&#x2013;1160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tektas P, Sahan S. Nurse&#x2019;s Spiritual Sensitivity Scale (NSSS): a validity and reliability study. J Relig Health. 2024;63:3846&#x2013;3861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildirim A, Simsek H. Qualitative Research Methods in the Social Sciences. Se&#xe7;kin Publishing; 2013:78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baysal E, Demirkol H, Erol A, et al. Nurses&#x2019; perceptions of spirituality and spiritual care and influencing factors in a multicultural context. Healthcare. 2024;12:1391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elo S, Kyng&#xe4;s H. The qualitative content analysis process. J Adv Nurs. 2008;62:107&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGhee P. Cultivating ethicality in organizations through spirituality, practical wisdom, and indigeneity. J Manag Spirit Rel. 2025;22:291&#x2013;313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safri S, Nurachmah E, Setianto B, Umar J, Yona S. Nurse perception of experience in providing spiritual nursing care in the cardiovascular unit: a phenomenological study. Healthc Low Resour Settings. 2024;12:13013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Yang J, Bai D, et al. Nurses&#x2019; perceptions and competencies about spirituality and spiritual care: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nurse Educ Today. 2024;132:106006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahraki SK. The effect of spiritual care education on nurses&#x2019; empathy and professional commitment. J Mil Med. 2023;25:1730&#x2013;1738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslan H, Celik H, Kaplan F. The relationship between palliative care nurses&#x2019; frequency of providing spiritual care and their job satisfaction. J Palliat Care. 2025;40:195&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SJ, Yeom HE. Influence of spirituality and job satisfaction on compassion competence of hospice nurses. J Hosp Palliat Care. 2022;25:169&#x2013;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslan H, Celik H, Kaplan F. The relationship between palliative care nurses&#x2019; frequency of providing spiritual care and their job satisfaction: a cross-sectional study. J Palliat Care. 2025;40:195&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osei-Yeboah P, Obimpeh-Quayson E, Owusu E. Exploring the role of spirituality in healing: a case study of patients at Bekwai Municipal Hospital. E-J Relig Theol Stud. 2024;10:310&#x2013;324.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>