<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41641201</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2220-3206</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Current status and influencing factors of anxiety in patients with malignant tumors after anesthesia recovery.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>111574</StartPage><MedlinePgn>111574</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">111574</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5498/wjp.v16.i2.111574</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">General anesthesia is essential for maintaining adequate sedation, minimizing intraoperative stimuli, and ensuring smooth surgery completion. However, when faced with invasive procedures and anesthetic risks, patients often exhibit nonspecific physiological and psychological responses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the occurrence of agitation and the prevalence of anxiety during anesthesia recovery in patients with malignant tumors (MTs) and to analyze their influencing factors, providing a theoretical basis for clinical management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">An analysis was performed on 168 patients who underwent surgery for MTs and recovered from anesthesia between April 2022 and October 2023. Based on the presence or absence of agitation during general anesthesia recovery, patients were divided into agitation and non-agitation groups. The Self-Rating Anxiety Scale was distributed to patients who recovered from anesthesia for a questionnaire survey, and based on the results, they were further categorized into anxiety and non-anxiety groups. Clinical data were compared to identify factors influencing agitation and anxiety.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Agitation occurred in 41 (24.4%) of the 168 patients during recovery from general anesthesia. Compared with the non-agitation group, patients with agitation were older, had higher rates of preoperative anxiety, alcohol consumption, diabetes, operations or anesthesia lasting &gt; 3 hours, intraoperative hypothermia, and higher Visual Analog Scale (VAS) scores during recovery (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). Logistic regression analysis identified age, operative duration of &gt; 3 hours, preoperative anxiety score, and intraoperative hypothermia as independent risk factors for agitation. The mean anxiety score among all patients was 7.23 &#xb1; 2.67, with anxiety symptoms confirmed in 59 cases (35.1%). Univariate and multivariate analyses revealed significant associations between groups with age, preoperative anxiety score, education level, annual income, and VAS score during recovery (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). Preoperative anxiety score, education level, annual income, and VAS score during recovery were key factors influencing anxiety in patients who underwent MT surgery during general anesthesia recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Anxiety is common among patients recovering from anesthesia after MT surgery. Preoperative anxiety score, education level, annual income, and VAS score during recovery are major influencing factors for anxiety, whereas preoperative anxiety represents a risk factor for agitation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2026. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Da-Wei</ForeName><Initials>DW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an 710061, Shaanxi Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Du</LastName><ForeName>Hai-Liang</ForeName><Initials>HL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an 710061, Shaanxi Province, China. hailiangdu003@yeah.net.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610480</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2220-3206</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Agitation during recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anesthesia recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Malignant tumor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Visual Analog Scale</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All the authors report no relevant conflicts of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41641201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12865417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5498/wjp.v16.i2.111574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Siegel RL, Miller KD, Wagle NS, Jemal A. Cancer statistics, 2023. CA Cancer J Clin. 2023;73:17&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36633525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caruso R, Nanni MG, Riba MB, Sabato S, Grassi L. The burden of psychosocial morbidity related to cancer: patient and family issues. Int Rev Psychiatry. 2017;29:389&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28753076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shalata W, Gothelf I, Bernstine T, Michlin R, Tourkey L, Shalata S, Yakobson A. Mental Health Challenges in Cancer Patients: A Cross-Sectional Analysis of Depression and Anxiety. Cancers (Basel) 2024;16:2827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11352929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39199598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao W, Chen HD, Yu YW, Li N, Chen WQ. Changing profiles of cancer burden worldwide and in China: a secondary analysis of the global cancer statistics 2020. Chin Med J (Engl) 2021;134:783&#x2013;791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8104205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33734139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyld L, Audisio RA, Poston GJ. The evolution of cancer surgery and future perspectives. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2015;12:115&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25384943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montejano J, Jevtovic-Todorovic V. Anesthesia and Cancer, Friend or Foe? A Narrative Review. Front Oncol. 2021;11:803266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8735748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35004329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei B, Feng Y, Chen W, Ren D, Xiao D, Chen B. Risk factors for emergence agitation in adults after general anesthesia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2021;65:719&#x2013;729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33370461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eshetie D, Getinet H, Abdissa Z, Mollalign M. Incidence and associated factors of emergence agitation after general anesthesia and surgery among pediatric patients: A prospective follow-up study. Int J Surg Open. 2020;27:25&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields A, Huang J, Schroeder D, Sprung J, Weingarten T. Agitation in adults in the post-anaesthesia care unit after general anaesthesia. Br J Anaesth. 2018;121:1052&#x2013;1058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30336849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naser AY, Hameed AN, Mustafa N, Alwafi H, Dahmash EZ, Alyami HS, Khalil H. Depression and Anxiety in Patients With Cancer: A Cross-Sectional Study. Front Psychol. 2021;12:585534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8081978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33935849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capobianco L, Faija C, Husain Z, Wells A. Metacognitive beliefs and their relationship with anxiety and depression in physical illnesses: A systematic review. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0238457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7500039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32911486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivascu R, Torsin LI, Hostiuc L, Nitipir C, Corneci D, Dutu M. The Surgical Stress Response and Anesthesia: A Narrative Review. J Clin Med. 2024;13:3017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11121777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38792558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SJ, Sung TY. Emergence agitation: current knowledge and unresolved questions. Korean J Anesthesiol. 2020;73:471&#x2013;485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7714637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32209961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x130;lhan B, K&#xfc;peli &#x130;. Secondary traumatic stress, anxiety, and depression among emergency healthcare workers in the middle of the COVID-19 outbreak: A cross-sectional study. Am J Emerg Med. 2022;52:99&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8641431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34894474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gois P, Magalhaes S, Alexandre A, Barreira A, Fernandes P, Ribeiro F, Schmidt C, Santos M. Home-based cardiac rehabilitation can reduce anxiety and depression in heart failure patients. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2022;29:zwac056.028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bindu B, Bindra A, Rath G. Temperature management under general anesthesia: Compulsion or option. J Anaesthesiol Clin Pharmacol. 2017;33:306&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5672515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29109627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruetzler K, Kurz A. Consequences of perioperative hypothermia. Handb Clin Neurol. 2018;157:687&#x2013;697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30459033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott AV, Stonemetz JL, Wasey JO, Johnson DJ, Rivers RJ, Koch CG, Frank SM. Compliance with Surgical Care Improvement Project for Body Temperature Management (SCIP Inf-10) Is Associated with Improved Clinical Outcomes. Anesthesiology. 2015;123:116&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25909970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giuliano KK, Hendricks J. Inadvertent Perioperative Hypothermia: Current Nursing Knowledge. AORN J. 2017;105:453&#x2013;463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28454611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Chen B, Liu T, Luo T, Kang W, Liu W. Risk factors for delayed neurocognitive recovery in elderly patients undergoing thoracic surgery. BMC Anesthesiol. 2023;23:102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10064736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37003967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldecoa C, Bettelli G, Bilotta F, Sanders RD, Audisio R, Borozdina A, Cherubini A, Jones C, Kehlet H, MacLullich A, Radtke F, Riese F, Slooter AJ, Veyckemans F, Kramer S, Neuner B, Weiss B, Spies CD. European Society of Anaesthesiology evidence-based and consensus-based guideline on postoperative delirium. Eur J Anaesthesiol. 2017;34:192&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28187050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner D, Hooper V, Bankieris K, Johnson A. The Relationship of Postoperative Delirium and Unplanned Perioperative Hypothermia in Surgical Patients. J Perianesth Nurs. 2021;36:41&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33067117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Zhu L, Li C, Lin Y, Wang B, Lin X, Bi Y. The relationship between intraoperative hypothermia and postoperative delirium: The PNDRFAP study. Brain Behav. 2024;14:e3512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11095299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38747874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H, Li H, Zhang X, Shi G, Xu M, Ru X, Chen Y, Patel MB, Ely EW, Lin S, Zhang G, Zhou J. Association of postoperative delirium with cognitive outcomes: A meta-analysis. J Clin Anesth. 2021;75:110496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34482263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahey N, Soni A, Allison J, Vankar J, Prabhakaran A, Moore Simas TA, Byatt N, Phatak A, O'Keefe E, Nimbalkar S. Education Mitigates the Relationship of Stress and Mental Disorders Among Rural Indian Women. Ann Glob Health. 2016;82:779&#x2013;787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5485235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28283129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonanno GA, Galea S, Bucciarelli A, Vlahov D. Psychological resilience after disaster: New York City in the aftermath of the September 11th terrorist attack. Psychol Sci. 2006;17:181&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16507055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan TJ. Poorly controlled postoperative pain: prevalence, consequences, and prevention. J Pain Res. 2017;10:2287&#x2013;2298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5626380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29026331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peria&#xf1;ez CAH, Diaz MAC, Bonisson PLV, Simino GPR, Barbosa MH, Mattia ALD. Relationship of Anxiety and Preoperative Depression with Post-operative Pain. Texto Contexto - Enferm. 2020;29:e20180499.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>