<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41852759</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2347-5625</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Asia-Pacific journal of oncology nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Asia Pac J Oncol Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Application of the behavior change wheel in supporting self-management among colorectal cancer survivors: A scoping review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100916</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100916</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100916</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.apjon.2026.100916</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Self-management is a cornerstone of colorectal cancer (CRC) care; however, many interventions lack explicit grounding in behavioral theory. The Behavior Change Wheel (BCW), underpinned by the Capability-Opportunity-Motivation Behavior (COM-B) model, provides a systematic framework for designing and evaluating behavior change interventions, yet its application in CRC self-management has not been comprehensively mapped. This scoping review aimed to synthesise the existing evidence on BCW-informed studies addressing CRC self-management and screening behaviors, and to identify implications for nursing practice and future research.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This scoping review was conducted in accordance with the Joanna Briggs Institute methodology and the PRISMA-ScR guideline. PubMed, Web of Science, Google Scholar, CNKI, and Wanfang were searched for studies published between April 2011 and April 2025 that applied the BCW framework (including COM-B) to CRC-related self-management or screening behaviors. Peer-reviewed articles and relevant grey literature were eligible. Study selection and data extraction were performed independently by two reviewers using a standardized form. Data were synthesised descriptively and thematically, with intervention components mapped to COM-B determinants and BCW intervention functions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Ten studies met the inclusion criteria, comprising six intervention studies and four qualitative studies. These studies addressed behaviors across the CRC care continuum, including screening participation, perioperative self-care, postoperative recovery, and survivorship. Education, Enablement, and Persuasion were incorporated in all intervention studies (<i>n</i> = 6), often in combination with additional BCW functions and targeting multiple COM-B components, particularly psychological capability and reflective motivation. Qualitative findings further elucidated contextual barriers and facilitators influencing CRC-related self-management and screening behaviors. Reported outcomes included improvements in self-care ability, self-efficacy, adherence, symptom management, emotional adjustment, and screening participation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">BCW-informed approaches show potential for strengthening key behavioral determinants and supporting patient-centered outcomes across the CRC care continuum. Integrating explicit behavioral theory into nursing interventions may enhance their conceptual rigor, transparency, and effectiveness. Further robust, theory-driven studies are warranted to refine the application of the BCW and to evaluate its impact across diverse populations and health care settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Siyu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, University of South China, Hengyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Qian</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, University of South China, Hengyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Lizhong</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hengyang Maternal and Child Health Hospital, Hengyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoli</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Provincial People's Hospital, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Dangheng</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, University of South China, Hengyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Arteriosclerology of Hunan Province, Hunan International Scientific and Technological Cooperation Base of Arteriosclerotic Disease, Hengyang Medical School, University of South China, Hengyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Asia Pac J Oncol Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101673157</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2347-5625</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Behavior change wheel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COM-B model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Colorectal cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scoping review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-management</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41852759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12992964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apjon.2026.100916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2347-5625(26)00066-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bray F., Laversanne M., Sung H., et al. Global cancer statistics 2022: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2024;74:229&#x2013;263. doi: 10.3322/caac.21834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38572751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain M.S., Karuniawati H., Jairoun A.A., et al. Colorectal cancer: a review of carcinogenesis, global epidemiology, current challenges, risk factors, preventive and treatment strategies. Cancers (Basel) 2022;14:1732. doi: 10.3390/cancers14071732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers14071732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8996939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35406504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford C., Ju A., Kim B., Wiltink L., Acret L., White K. How consequences of colorectal cancer treatment are managed: a qualitative study of stakeholder experiences about supportive care and current practices. Support Care Cancer. 2023;31(5):255. doi: 10.1007/s00520-023-07713-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-023-07713-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10090022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37041401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju A., Wiltink L., Walker J., White K., Rutherford C. Supportive care interventions for managing gastrointestinal symptoms following treatment for colorectal cancer: a systematic review. J Cancer Surviv. 2024;18:1640&#x2013;1647. doi: 10.1007/s11764-023-01403-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-023-01403-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11424733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37280309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson A.T., Megafu O., Abdullahi D., Amajoyi R. Colorectal cancer care continuum: navigating screening, treatment, and outcomes disparities. J Surg Oncol. 2024;130:1475&#x2013;1482. doi: 10.1002/jso.27848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jso.27848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39295552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerrison R.S., McGregor L.M., Counsell N., et al. Use of two self-referral reminders and a theory-based leaflet to increase the uptake of flexible sigmoidoscopy in the English bowel scope screening program: results from a randomized controlled trial in London. Ann Behav Med. 2018;52:941&#x2013;951. doi: 10.1093/abm/kax068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/abm/kax068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6196365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30346495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huseb&#xf8; A.L.M., S&#xf8;reide J.A., K&#xf8;rner H., et al. eHealth interventions to support colorectal cancer patients' self-management after discharge from surgery: an integrative literature review. Support Care Cancer. 2024;32:11. doi: 10.1007/s00520-023-08191-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-023-08191-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10700211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38055087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Li Z.Y., Lu Q., et al. The effectiveness of a self-management program of bowel dysfunction in patients with mid and low rectal cancer after sphincter-preserving surgery: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Cancer Nurs. 2023;46:67&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1097/NCC.0000000000001065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NCC.0000000000001065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35089874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo J.Y. Huzhou University; 2019. The application of health education model based on BCW theory in patients with permanent colostomy of colorectal cancer. [Master's thesis] [in Chinese]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rastogi S., Tevaarwerk A.J., Sesto M., et al. Effect of a technology-supported physical activity intervention on health-related quality of life, sleep, and processes of behavior change in cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial. Psychooncology. 2020;29:1917&#x2013;1926. doi: 10.1002/pon.5524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.5524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7815326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32808383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rimmer B., Brown M.C., Sotire T., et al. Characteristics and components of self-management interventions for improving quality of life in cancer survivors: a systematic review. Cancers (Basel) 2023;16:14. doi: 10.3390/cancers16010014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers16010014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10777971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38201442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorig K.R., Holman H.R. Self-management education: history, definition, outcomes, and mechanisms. Ann Behav Med. 2003;26:1&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1207/S15324796ABM2601_01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/S15324796ABM2601_01</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12867348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T.J., Chang S.C., Hsu H.H., et al. Efficacy of a self-management program on quality of life in colorectal cancer patients: a randomized controlled trial. Eur J Oncol Nurs. 2023;67 doi: 10.1016/j.ejon.2023.102431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejon.2023.102431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37951069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X.Y., Zhu X.P., Wu Q. Influencing factors of adherence to exercise prehabilitation in older patients with colorectal cancer: a qualitative study. J Sichuan Univ (Med Sci) 2023;54:811&#x2013;815. [in Chinese]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10442619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37545079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu M., Wang H., Wang W., et al. Effect of self-efficacy on self-management ability for colorectal cancer patients with stoma: a path analysis. Support Care Cancer. 2024;32:725. doi: 10.1007/s00520-024-08883-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-024-08883-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39395041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S., Van Stralen M.M., West R. The behavior change wheel: a new method for characterising and designing behavior change interventions. Implement Sci. 2011;6:42. doi: 10.1186/1748-5908-6-42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-6-42</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3096582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21513547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacPherson M.M., Cranston K.D., Locke S.R., Bourne J.E., Jung M.E. Using the behavior change wheel to develop text messages to promote diet and physical activity adherence following a diabetes prevention program. Transl Behav Med. 2021;11:1585&#x2013;1595. doi: 10.1093/tbm/ibab058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tbm/ibab058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8604265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34008852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy K., Berk J., Muhwava-Mbabala L., et al. Using the COM-B model and behavior change wheel to develop a theory and evidence-based intervention for women with gestational diabetes (IINDIAGO) BMC Public Health. 2023;23:894. doi: 10.1186/s12889-023-15586-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-023-15586-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10186807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37189143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen D., Zhang H., Wu J., et al. Effects of an individualized mHealth-based intervention on health behavior change and cardiovascular risk among people with metabolic syndrome based on the behavior change wheel: Quasi-experimental study. J Med Internet Res. 2023;25 doi: 10.2196/49257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/49257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10720605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38019579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Cappellen-van Maldegem S.J.M., Mols F., Seidell J.C., De Kruif A., Van De Poll-Franse L.V., Hoedjes M. Using the behavior change wheel to identify and understand key facilitators and barriers for lifestyle care for postmenopausal breast cancer survivors: a Delphi study. Ann Behav Med. 2024;58:22&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1093/abm/kaad049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/abm/kaad049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10729788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37672352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Zhu G.L. Effect of nursing intervention based on behavior change wheel for patients after enterostomy. J Nurs. 2020;27:54&#x2013;58. doi: 10.16460/j.issn1008-9969.2020.08.054. [in Chinese]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16460/j.issn1008-9969.2020.08.054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan J., Zhou J., Zhang J. Application and effect evaluation of self-care health platform for colorectal cancer patients with enterostomy based on COM-B model. Chin J Pract Nurs. 2022;38:1847&#x2013;1853. doi: 10.3760/cma.j.cn211501-20211125-03248. [in Chinese]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3760/cma.j.cn211501-20211125-03248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ze Y. Jiangnan University; 2023. Study on the comprehensive intervention and analysis of results based on BCW theory on colonoscopy compliance in high-risk population of colorectal cancer. [Master's thesis] [in Chinese]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P., Li H., Pang X., et al. Effect of a mobile health-based remote interaction management intervention on the quality of life and self-management behavior of patients with low anterior resection syndrome: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2024;26 doi: 10.2196/53909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/53909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11350307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39137413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu T. Kunming Medical University; 2023. Application of patient self-management program based on BCW theory in outpatient colorectal polypectomy. [Master's thesis] [in Chinese]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco A.C., Lillie E., Zarin W., et al. PRISMA extension for scoping reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169:467&#x2013;473. doi: 10.7326/M18-0850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M18-0850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters M.D.J., Marnie C., Tricco A.C., et al. Updated methodological guidance for the conduct of scoping reviews. JBI Evid Synth. 2020;18(10):2119&#x2013;2126. doi: 10.11124/JBIES-20-00167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11124/JBIES-20-00167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33038124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J.P., Altman D.G., G&#xf8;tzsche P.C., et al. The Cochrane Collaboration's tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343 doi: 10.1136/bmj.d5928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.d5928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joanna Briggs Institute. Critical Appraisal Tools. JBI. Accessed December 29, 2025. https://jbi.global/critical-appraisal-tools.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christie-de Jong F., Kotzur M., Amiri R., Ling J., Mooney J.D., Robb K.A. Qualitative evaluation of a co-designed faith-based intervention for Muslim women in Scotland to encourage uptake of breast, colorectal and cervical cancer screening. BMJ Open. 2022;12 doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2021-058739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2021-058739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9109091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35568495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadd N., Lee S., Hughes J., Sharman M.J., Hoang H., Obamiro K. Barriers and enablers to bowel cancer screening participation in remote Tasmania: a qualitative study using the theoretical domains framework. Aust J Rural Health. 2024;32:1041&#x2013;1053. doi: 10.1111/ajr.13181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ajr.13181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39215396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotte M., Ringborg C.H., Wengstr&#xf6;m Y. The experience of live-remote exercise: perspectives after cancer treatment. Support Care Cancer. 2024;32:526. doi: 10.1007/s00520-024-08736-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-024-08736-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11258172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39023806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wathne H., Morken I.M., Storm M., Huseb&#xf8; A.M.L. Designing a future eHealth service for post-hospitalization self-management support in long-term illness: qualitative interview study. JMIR Hum Factors. 2023;10 doi: 10.2196/39391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/39391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9941902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36745492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page M.J., McKenzie J.E., Bossuyt P.M., et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372 doi: 10.1136/bmj.n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>