<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41739224</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7339</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Supportive care in cancer : official journal of the Multinational Association of Supportive Care in Cancer</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Support Care Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Randomized controlled trial: Synergistic effect of three-ball mindfulness breathing rehabilitation training following pulmonary lobectomy for lung cancer.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">247</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00520-026-10360-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the synergistic effect of three-ball mindfulness breathing rehabilitation training in the context of postoperative rehabilitation for patients undergoing pulmonary lobectomy for lung cancer.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 124 patients with lung cancer who underwent pulmonary lobectomy at the First Affiliated Hospital of Xiamen University from March 2024 to January 2025 were selected and randomly divided into two groups (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;62 each) using a random number table. The control group received conventional pulmonary rehabilitation training, while the observation group received three-ball mindfulness breathing rehabilitation training on top of the conventional regimen. The intervention for both groups continued until one week after discharge, during which patients performed exercises independently. Recovery indicators (primary outcomes), postoperative complications, and scores for dyspnea (mMRC), exercise tolerance (6MWT), emotional status (DASS), and fatigue (Piper Fatigue Scale, PFS)&#xa0;(secondary outcomes)&#xa0;were compared between the two groups at admission, 1&#xa0;day before surgery, 3&#xa0;days after surgery, and 1&#xa0;week after discharge.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The observation group showed shorter durations of pulmonary rales, sputum retention, and hospital stay compared to the control group (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). At postoperative day 3 and 1&#xa0;week after discharge, the mMRC scores were lower and 6MWT was higher in the observation group than in the control group (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). At 1&#xa0;day before surgery, 3&#xa0;days after surgery, and 1&#xa0;week after discharge, the DASS and PFS scores in the observation group were lower than those in the control group (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). The incidence of complications did not differ significantly between the two groups (9.68% vs 17.74%, P&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Three-ball mindfulness breathing rehabilitation training can alleviate fatigue and dyspnea in patients after pulmonary lobectomy for lung cancer, regulate psychological status, and enhance exercise tolerance. It has a synergistic effect when combined with conventional pulmonary rehabilitation training.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Hong</LastName><ForeName>Yaxian</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Department of Thoracic Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Xiamen University, Xiamen, 361000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Qing</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Department of Thoracic Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Xiamen University, Xiamen, 361000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shuqian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Department of Thoracic Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Xiamen University, Xiamen, 361000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Department of Thoracic Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Xiamen University, Xiamen, 361000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shao</LastName><ForeName>Sumin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Department of Thoracic Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Xiamen University, Xiamen, 361000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiangmei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Department of Thoracic Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Xiamen University, Xiamen, 361000, China. liuzhizhi691850@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Department of Thoracic Surgery, Fujian Province, The First Affiliated Hospital of Xiamen University, Siming District, 9Th Emergency Building, 55 Zhenhai Road, Xiamen City, 361000, China. liuzhizhi691850@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhong</LastName><ForeName>Ming</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Department of Thoracic Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Xiamen University, Xiamen, 361000, China. libaolin686030@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Department of Thoracic Surgery, Fujian Province, The First Affiliated Hospital of Xiamen University, Siming District, 9Th Emergency Building, 55 Zhenhai Road, Xiamen City, 361000, China. libaolin686030@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Support Care Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9302957</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0941-4355</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001945" MajorTopicYN="Y">Breathing Exercises</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011013" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pneumonectomy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064866" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mindfulness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011183" MajorTopicYN="N">Postoperative Complications</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017079" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Tolerance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004417" MajorTopicYN="N">Dyspnea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lung cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mindfulness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary lobectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Synergistic effect</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Three-ball device</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval: This study conformed to the Declaration of Helsinki on Human Research Ethics standards and was approvedby the Ethics Committee of the First Affiliated Hospital of Xiamen University.(Scientific Research Ethics Review No. [2024] (238)). Consent to participate: All participants provided written informed consent prior to participation. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41739224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-026-10360-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00520-026-10360-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aokage K, Suzuki K, Saji H et al (2023) Segmentectomy for ground-glass-dominant lung cancer with a tumour diameter of 3 cm or less including ground-glass opacity (JCOG1211): a multicentre, single-arm, confirmatory, phase 3 trial. Lancet Respir Med 11(6):540&#x2013;549</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(23)00041-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36893780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao MM, Wu AS (2024) Effects of flurbiprofen ester combined with propofol anesthesia on pulmonary oxygenation function, hemodynamics, and respiratory compliance in elderly patients undergoing pulmonary lobectomy for lung cancer. Clin Misdiagn Misther 37(1):99&#x2013;104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammous O, Feki W, Lotfi T et al (2023) Inspiratory muscle training, with or without concomitant pulmonary rehabilitation, for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). Cochrane Database Syst Rev 6(1):1377&#x2013;1385</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsina-Restoy X, Torres-Castro R, Caballer&#xed;a E et al (2023) Pulmonary rehabilitation in sarcoidosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Respir Med 9(15):1074&#x2013;1081</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Tang Z, Jiang J et al (2023) Therapeutic effect of three-ball breathing training device&#x2013;guided respiratory rehabilitation exercise in patients with radiation-induced lung injury. Chin Rehabil 38(10):595&#x2013;599</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansor M, Chong MC, Chui PL et al (2023) Effect of mindfulness intervention on anxiety, distress, and depression for chronic diseases: a scoping review. Psychol Health Med 28(6):1549&#x2013;1561</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13548506.2022.2124288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36120729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin KK, Yu Y, Cai HL et al (2024) Effectiveness of mindfulness-based intervention in schizophrenia: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Psychiatry Res 11(20):1158&#x2013;1164</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardoso S, Barros R, Mar&#xf4;co J et al (2024) Different MMSE domains are associated with cognitive decline and education. Appl Neuropsychol Adult 31(4):533&#x2013;539</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23279095.2022.2041018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35234096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung C, Lee JW, Lee SW et al (2024) Clinical efficacy of mobile app-based, self-directed pulmonary rehabilitation for patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: systematic review and meta-analysis. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth 4(12):4175&#x2013;4181</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chudzicka-Czupa&#x142;a A, Hapon N, Chiang SK et al (2023) Depression, anxiety and post-traumatic stress during the 2022 Russo-Ukrainian war: a comparison between populations in Poland, Ukraine, and Taiwan. Sci Rep 3(1):3602&#x2013;3610</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-28729-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natale P, Ju A, Strippoli GF et al (2023) Interventions for fatigue in people with kidney failure requiring dialysis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 8(8):1307&#x2013;1314</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi YM, Huang G, Xu Z et al (2024) Effects of mindfulness-based stress reduction combined with respiratory function training on dyspnea-fatigue-anxiety symptom cluster and lung function in lung cancer patients undergoing radiotherapy. Lab Med Clin 21(7):991&#x2013;995</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Le JR (2022) Application of mindful breathing training combined with full nursing accompaniment during MRI examination in patients with claustrophobia. Neuroinj Funct Rehabil 17(10):606&#x2013;608</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao WC, Huang JF, Jin Y et al (2024) Effect of pulmonary rehabilitation exercise on lung volume and respiratory muscle recovery in lung cancer patients undergoing lobectomy. Altern Ther Health Med 30(2):90&#x2013;96</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37883752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toohey K, Mizrahi D, Hart NH et al (2025) Exercise in cancer care for people with lung cancer: a narrative synthesis. J Sci Med Sport 28(1):16&#x2013;25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2024.08.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39155211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai FF, Mao SZ, Zhang YM (2024) Effect of self-efficacy station combined with ACBT training on pulmonary rehabilitation after thoracoscopic surgery in non-small cell lung cancer patients. Chin J Gen Pract 22(9):1584-1587,1613</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng LP, Wang H, Chen B (2022) Application effect of breathing trainer in elderly early non-small cell lung cancer patients after video-assisted thoracoscopic lobectomy. Chin J Clin Oncol Rehabil 29(6):687&#x2013;690</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balban MY, Neri E, Kogon MM et al (2023) Brief structured respiration practices enhance mood and reduce physiological arousal. Cell Rep Med 17(1):1008&#x2013;1015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu MG, Deng BB, Huang XW (2024) Mediating role of negative emotions between type-T psychology and psychosomatic status in advanced lung cancer patients. Chin J Behav Med Brain Sci 33(11):1046&#x2013;1051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulibarri-Ochoa A, Ruiz-de-Alegr&#xed;a B, L&#xf3;pez-Vivanco G et al (2023) Differences in quality of life and emotional well-being in breast, colon, and lung cancer patients during outpatient adjuvant chemotherapy: a longitudinal study. Cancer Nurs 1(2):99&#x2013;109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NCC.0000000000001070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, Zhang RZ (2024) Mood state in patients with post-traumatic stress disorder due to lung cancer: a clinical application study of intensive cognitive management. Actas Esp Psiquiatr 52(5):716&#x2013;723</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62641/aep.v52i5.1674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39403913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11474963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zdemir &#xdc;, Ta&#x15f;c&#x131; S (2023) Acupressure for cancer-related fatigue in elderly cancer patients: a randomized controlled study. Altern Ther Health Med 29(4):57&#x2013;65</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33891570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan YQ, Liu CP, Shi W et al (2024) Trajectory patterns and predictors of cancer-related fatigue in postoperative lung cancer patients receiving chemotherapy. Support Care Cancer 18(8):525&#x2013;531</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajayako HHJ, Wang JQ et al (2025) Impact of cancer-related fatigue on quality of life in lung cancer chemotherapy patients: the chain mediating effect of psychological resilience and perceived social support. Chin J Mod Nurs 31(10):1338&#x2013;1345</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu YY, Lu HB, Li YJ et al (2024) Effects of mindful breathing training combined with diary-based rehabilitation guidance in lung cancer patients undergoing surgery: a randomized controlled trial. Complement Ther Clin Pract 9(15):1018&#x2013;1026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CH, Bai XQ, Wang Y (2023) Effects of mindfulness psychological training on postoperative psychological stress response and adverse cardiac events in acute myocardial infarction patients undergoing PCI. Lab Med Clin 20(23):3551&#x2013;3554</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>