<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41800468</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2574-2167</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>OTA international : the open access journal of orthopaedic trauma</Title><ISOAbbreviation>OTA Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intramedullary nailing with absorbable antibiotic-eluting ceramic for fracture-related infection prophylaxis in high-risk open fractures: a case series and technique.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e478</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e478</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e478</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/OI9.0000000000000478</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Fracture-related infection (FRI) is a devastating complication of open fractures and remains common even with ideal open fracture care including prompt systemic antibiotics and thorough surgical debridement. There is growing interest in the use of adjuvant local antibiotics; however, traditional carriers like polymethylmethacrylate (PMMA) are limited by subtherapeutic elution, biofilm formation, and the need for secondary removal. We describe a technique of in vivo augmentation of intramedullary nailing with Cerament G, a resorbable gentamicin-eluting calcium sulfate/hydroxyapatite ceramic, delivered through the 2-CAN device for targeted antibiotic prophylaxis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Nine patients (mean age 44 years; 22% female) with Gustilo-Anderson Type II (n = 3), IIIA (n = 4), IIIB (n = 1), and IIIC (n = 1) open fractures of the tibia, femur, or humerus underwent this technique at a Level 1 trauma center by a single fellowship-trained orthopaedic traumatologist. Postoperative outcomes included FRI incidence, fracture union, complications, and functional recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">At a mean follow-up of 9.1 months (2.6-17.1 months), all fractures achieved union with no cases of FRI. Two GA IIIB/C cases required flap coverage, including one flap failure successfully revised. Self-limiting serous drainage (n = 3) resolved within 1 week. No secondary procedures for infection, implant removal, or amputations occurred.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Intramedullary nailing and intraoperative augmentation with Cerament G using the 2-CAN device offer a technically simple, time-efficient strategy for FRI prophylaxis in high-risk open fractures. The technique provides sustained local antibiotic delivery, avoids PMMA-related complications, and maximizes biomechanical stability by eliminating nail downsizing. Early results demonstrate promising infection prophylaxis, warranting further prospective trials to validate long-term efficacy and cost-effectiveness.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of the Orthopaedic Trauma Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sandilands</LastName><ForeName>Scott M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, HCA Florida JFK Hospital/University of Miami GME Consortium Orthopaedic Surgery Residency Program, Atlantis, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, HCA Florida Kendall Hospital, Miami, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Nova Southeastern University Dr. Kiran C. Patel College of Allopathic Medicine, Fort Lauderdale, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daji</LastName><ForeName>Akshay V</ForeName><Initials>AV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, HCA Florida JFK Hospital/University of Miami GME Consortium Orthopaedic Surgery Residency Program, Atlantis, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>OTA Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101770383</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2574-2167</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">absorbable antibiotic-eluting bone graft substitute</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">absorbable antibiotic-eluting ceramic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intramedullary nailing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">open fracture</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41800468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12962574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/OI9.0000000000000478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">OTAI-D-25-00062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Metsemakers WJ, Smeets B, Nijs S, et al. Infection after fracture fixation of the tibia: analysis of healthcare utilization and related costs. Injury. 2017;48:1204&#x2013;1210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28377260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgenstern M, Vallejo A, McNally MA, et al. The effect of local antibiotic prophylaxis when treating open limb fractures: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Bone Joint Res. 2018;7:447&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6076360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30123494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig J, Fuchs T, Jenks M, et al. Systematic review and meta-analysis of the additional benefit of local prophylactic antibiotic therapy for infection rates in open tibia fractures treated with intramedullary nailing. Int Orthop. 2014;38:1025&#x2013;1030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3997785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24531401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moojen DJF, Hentenaar B, Charles Vogely H, et al. In vitro release of antibiotics from commercial PMMA beads and articulating hip spacers. J Arthroplasty. 2008;23:1152&#x2013;1156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18534493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van de Belt H, Neut D, Schenk W, et al. Gentamicin release from polymethylmethacrylate bone cements and <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> biofilm formation. Acta Orthop Scand. 2000;71:625&#x2013;629.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11145392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neut D, Van de Belt H, Van Horn JR, et al. Residual gentamicin release from antibiotic-loaded polymethylmethacrylate beads after 5 years of implantation. Biomaterials. 2003;24:1829&#x2013;1831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12593965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garabano G, Del Sel H, Rodriguez JA, et al. The effectiveness of antibiotic cement-coated nails in post-traumatic femoral and tibial osteomyelitis: comparative analysis of custom-made versus commercially available nails. J Bone Joint Infect. 2021;6:457&#x2013;466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8738920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35024298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pomeroy E, et al. Intramedullary nailing with an absorbable antibiotic carrier (INaac): a simple technique using standard implants. J Orthop Sci Res. 2024;5(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton AA, Wongcharoenwatana J, Hoellwarth JS, et al. The immediate ex vivo covering and filling characteristics of antibiotic-loaded resorbable calcium sulfate paste around intramedullary nails. J Bone Joint Infect. 2024;9:261&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12042201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40308333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litrenta J, Tornetta P, III, Mehta S, et al. Determination of radiographic healing: an assessment of consistency using RUST and modified RUST in metadiaphyseal fractures. J Orthop Trauma. 2015;29:516&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26165265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriarty TF, Metsemakers WJ, Morgenstern M, et al. Fracture-related infection. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2022;8:67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36266296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iliaens J, Onsea J, Hoekstra H, et al. Fracture-related infection in long bone fractures: a comprehensive analysis of the economic impact and influence on quality of life. Injury. 2021;52:3344&#x2013;3349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34474918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conway JD, Elhessy AH, Galiboglu S, et al. Efficacy of infection eradication in antibiotic cement-coated intramedullary nails for fracture-related infections, nonunions, and fusions. Antibiot (Basel). 2022;11:709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9219703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35740117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eikani C, Hoyt A, Cho E, et al. The state of local antibiotic use in orthopedic trauma. Orthop Clin North Am. 2024;55:207&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38403367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flores MJ, Brown KE, Morshed S, et al. Evidence for local antibiotics in the prevention of infection in orthopaedic trauma. J Clin Med. 2022;11:7461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9782030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36556077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zingas N, Hannan ZD, Healey KM, et al. The use of vancomycin powder in tibial plateau fractures at lower risk of infection. J Orthop Trauma. 2023;37:282&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36729009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Major Extremity Trauma Research Consortium METRC, O'Toole RV, Joshi M, Carlini AR, et al. METRC. Effect of intrawound vancomycin powder in operatively treated high-risk tibia fractures: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Surg. 2021;156:e207259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12285540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33760010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawing CR, Lin FC, Dahners LE. Local injection of aminoglycosides for prophylaxis against infection in open fractures. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2015;97:1844&#x2013;1851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4642229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26582614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stravinskas M, Horstmann P, Ferguson J, et al. Pharmacokinetics of gentamicin eluted from a regenerating bone graft substitute: in vitro and clinical release studies. Bone Joint Res. 2016;5:427&#x2013;435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5047051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27678329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson J, Bourget-Murray J, Hotchen AJ, et al. A comparison of clinical and radiological outcomes between two different biodegradable local antibiotic carriers used in the single-stage surgical management of long bone osteomyelitis. Bone Joint Res. 2023;12:412&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10317575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37400090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson J, Athanasou N, Diefenbeck M, et al. Radiographic and histological analysis of a synthetic bone graft substitute eluting gentamicin in the treatment of chronic osteomyelitis. J Bone Joint Infect. 2019;4:76&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6470655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31011512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thonse R, Conway J. Antibiotic cement-coated interlocking nail for the treatment of infected nonunions and segmental bone defects. J Orthop Trauma. 2007;21:258&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17414554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stravinskas M, Nilsson M, Horstmann P, et al. Antibiotic-containing bone substitute in major hip surgery: a long-term gentamicin elution study. J Bone Joint Infect. 2018;3:68&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5949569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29761068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson J, Diefenbeck M, McNally M. Ceramic biocomposites as biodegradable antibiotic carriers in the treatment of bone infections. J Bone Joint Infect. 2017;2:38&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5423569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28529863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barger J, Fragomen AT, Rozbruch SR. Antibiotic-coated interlocking intramedullary nail for the treatment of long-bone osteomyelitis. JBJS Rev. 2017;5:e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28719401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowe JA, Vosburg C, Murtha YM, et al. A new technique for removing intramedullary cement. J Orthop Trauma. 2011;25:762&#x2013;766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21697739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy NS, Rajyalakshmi NR, Mohan Krishna A. Cement debonding: is it a problem with antibiotic cement-coated nails? J Orthop Surg Tech. 2020;3:143&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metsemakers WJ, Morgenstern M, McNally MA, et al. Fracture-related infection: a consensus on definition from an international expert group. Injury. 2018;49:505&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28867644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez L, Jung HS, Goulet JA, et al. Evidence-based protocol for prophylactic antibiotics in open fractures: improved antibiotic stewardship with no increase in infection rates. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2014;77:400&#x2013;524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25159242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber MA, Snyder MJ, Workman KK, et al. Comparison of Asymptomatic and Symptomatic Adverse Local Tissue Reaction in Patients With Head-Neck Taper Corrosion. J Arthroplasty. 2021;36(7S):S358&#x2013;S362. doi: 10.1016/j.arth.2020.09.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arth.2020.09.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7965776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33036841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>