<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41900711</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Multi-Metal Alloys as Catalysts for Fenton-like Oxidation: A Review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1220</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma19061220</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The persistent discharge of refractory toxic organic pollutants poses a severe threat to aquatic environmental safety, driving the urgent demand for high-efficiency water treatment technologies in environmental engineering. Fenton and Fenton-like oxidation processes have garnered extensive attention due to their robust oxidizing capacity and environmental benignity; however, traditional Fenton systems are constrained by inherent limitations, including a narrow applicable pH range, potential secondary pollution, and cumbersome catalyst recovery. To address these challenges, Fenton-like catalysts have evolved progressively from single-metal systems to multi-metal alloy configurations. This review systematically elaborates on the fundamental principles and technical bottlenecks of classical Fenton and Fenton-like reactions, while comprehensively summarizing the research progress of multi-metal alloy catalysts-encompassing binary alloys, multi-component alloys, and high-entropy alloys. Special emphasis is placed on dissecting the core mechanisms through which multi-metal alloys optimize redox cycles and enhance structural stability, leveraging intermetallic synergistic effects, unique electronic structures, and lattice distortion. Furthermore, this work synthesizes key performance enhancement strategies for such catalysts, including co-catalyst synergy, external field assistance, and supported composite modification. Ultimately, this review aims to provide a scientific foundation and technical reference for the rational design, development, and engineering application of high-performance Fenton-like catalysts in sustainable wastewater remediation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Wenjun</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Archaeological Exploration and Cultural Heritage Conservation Technology (Northwestern Polytechnical University), Ministry of Education, Xi'an 710129, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Science and Technology, Northwestern Polytechnical University, Xi'an 710129, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Bingbing</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Archaeological Exploration and Cultural Heritage Conservation Technology (Northwestern Polytechnical University), Ministry of Education, Xi'an 710129, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Policy and Administration, Northwestern Polytechnical University, Xi'an 710072, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Wenqiang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Archaeological Exploration and Cultural Heritage Conservation Technology (Northwestern Polytechnical University), Ministry of Education, Xi'an 710129, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Culture and Heritage, Northwestern Polytechnical University, Xi'an 710072, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xia</LastName><ForeName>Qixing</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Archaeological Exploration and Cultural Heritage Conservation Technology (Northwestern Polytechnical University), Ministry of Education, Xi'an 710129, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Science and Technology, Northwestern Polytechnical University, Xi'an 710129, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Culture and Heritage, Northwestern Polytechnical University, Xi'an 710072, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024YFB4608700</GrantID><Agency>NationalKey R&amp;D Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52101272</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>G2025KY06240</GrantID><Agency>Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities of Northwestern Polytechnical University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fenton-like oxidation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">catalytic mechanisms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multi-metal alloys</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">radical pathways</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">synergistic effects</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest. The funders had no role in the design of the study; in the collection, analyses, or interpretation of data; in the writing of the manuscript; or in the decision to publish the results.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41900711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13028467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma19061220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma19061220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Wang S. Reactive species in advanced oxidation processes: Formation, identification and reaction mechanism. Chem. Eng. J. 2020;401:126158. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2020.126158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2020.126158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Tang J. Fe-based Fenton-like catalysts for water treatment: Preparation, characterization and modification. Chemosphere. 2021;276:130177. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2021.130177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2021.130177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33714147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mousavi S.E., Zarean M., Yu J., Abbasi S., Kwong R.W.M. Identifying possible neurodevelopmental effects of per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS) through an adverse outcome pathway (AOP) network for human developmental neurotoxicology. Sci. Total Environ. 2026;1011:181170. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2025.181170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2025.181170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41418688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S., Yang J., Wang H., Zhang S. Enhanced photo Fenton-like AOP by N-doped and Cu-Fe loaded biochar for efficient sulfamethoxazole removal: Economic synthesis, catalytic, performance and mechanism. Chemosphere. 2025;385:144543. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2025.144543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2025.144543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40614509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez N., Plaza S., Afkhami A., Marco P., Gim&#xe9;nez J., Esplugas S. Treatment of Diphenhydramine with different AOPs including photo-Fenton at circumneutral pH. Chem. Eng. J. 2017;318:112&#x2013;120. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2016.05.127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2016.05.127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y., Chen L., Zhang X., Yu C., Wang C., Huang R., Du Q., Xu H., Feng L., Sun W. Photosynergetic bimetallic Fe-Cu codoped melem polymer for boosting Fenton-like catalytic performance: Insights into the enhancement mechanism. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2023;612:155899. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2022.155899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2022.155899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eltaweil A.S., Mohamed Gaber N., El-Subruiti G.M., Omer A.M. Dandelion-like Cu-Ni LDH-decorated biochar/aminated chitosan composite for boosting Fenton-like degradation of doxycycline: Insights into performance and mechanism. J. Mol. Liq. 2024;394:123716. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2023.123716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2023.123716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Zhong Y., Feng Y., Chen M. Nano-dendritic PdPtCu alloys for efficient dye degradation through plasmon-enhanced Fenton-like reaction. J. Alloys Compd. 2025;1044:184427. doi: 10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.184427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.184427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu E., Hu T., Al-Dhabi N.A., Soyol-Erdene T.O., Bayanjargal O., Zuo Y., Wang J., Tang W. MOF-derived Fe/Ni@C marigold-like nanosheets as heterogeneous electro-Fenton cathode for efficient antibiotic oxytetracycline degradation. Environ. Res. 2024;247:118357. doi: 10.1016/j.envres.2024.118357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2024.118357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38325782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sachan D., Singh N., Kumar U., Kuntail J., Sinha I., Singh R. Design of medium entropy oxide for photo-Fenton catalytic degradation of tetracycline. Mol. Catal. 2025;582:115187. doi: 10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mcat.2025.115187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J., Ma H., Ren J., Han X., Liu J. Z-scheme heterojunction with Fe coordinatively unsaturated metal sites for self-feeding photo-fenton process. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2025;13:116323. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2025.116323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2025.116323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y., Ran J., Mao K., Yang X., Zhong L., Yang C., Feng X., Zhang H. Recent progress in Fenton/Fenton-like reactions for the removal of antibiotics in aqueous environments. Ecotoxicol. Environ. Saf. 2022;236:113464. doi: 10.1016/j.ecoenv.2022.113464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoenv.2022.113464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35395600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K., Jia Y., Liu X., Pan L., Shi M., Pan W., Li N., Tang B. Fenton reaction-enhanced mild photothermal therapy for cancer suppression with a multifunctional platform. J. Photochem. Photobiol. B. 2025;272:113250. doi: 10.1016/j.jphotobiol.2025.113250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jphotobiol.2025.113250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40907239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garz&#xf3;n-Cucaita V., Castellanos N.J., Carriazo J.G. Particles of Cu-Co mixed oxide and Ag supported on multibranched &#x3b1;-Fe2O3 as heterogeneous Fenton-like catalysts. Surf. Interfaces. 2025;72:107272. doi: 10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Wu X., Sun J., Wei B., Ma Y., Liu H. Computational study on degradation mechanisms, efficiencies and toxicity of BPA and its analogs in UV/H2O2 and Fenton/H2O2 systems. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;526:171542. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.171542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.171542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satyam S., Patra S. Xanthine oxidase driven bio-Fenton system for advanced pollutant degradation in sustainable wastewater treatment. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2025;313:144323. doi: 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.144323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.144323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40383322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veisi P., Nasiriani T., Askari A., Dikici B., Kaseem M., Fattah-alhosseini A. Advances in Mg-based catalysts for Fenton catalysis: Structure and performance in wastewater treatment. J. Alloys Compd. 2025;1032:181071. doi: 10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.181071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.181071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaskar S., Apoorva K.V., Ashraf S., Athul Devan T. Synthesis and application of iron nanoparticles from scrap metal for triclosan degradation in water via Fenton and Sono-Fenton oxidation. Waste Manag. Bull. 2025;3:293&#x2013;300. doi: 10.1016/j.wmb.2025.01.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wmb.2025.01.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Chen K., Li Y., An Z., Li L., Zhao G. Breaking the selectivity barrier in Fenton process: Aptamer-empowered nano-Fenton system for targeted destruction of emerging contaminants in complex waters. J. Hazard. Mater. 2025;496:139161. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.139161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.139161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40644866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang N., Zheng T., Jiang J., Wang P. Cu(II)&#x2013;Fe(II)&#x2013;H2O2 oxidative removal of 3-nitroaniline in water under microwave irradiation. Chem. Eng. J. 2015;260:386&#x2013;392. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2014.09.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2014.09.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Q., Fu R., Huang L., Xie Z., Tang Y., Zhao K. Resorcinol-formaldehyde resin as co-catalyst in Fenton-like reaction: Synergistic enhancement of Fe3+/Fe2+ cycling via phenolic hydroxyl redox and conjugated-structure mediated electron transfer. J. Clean. Prod. 2025;530:146831. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.146831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.146831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan R., Qin Y., Li H., Huang H., He X. Research on Fenton-like process for removing pollutants from wastewater based on simple modified natural wolframite: Efficiency and mechanism. Environ. Technol. Innov. 2025;40:104477. doi: 10.1016/j.eti.2025.104477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eti.2025.104477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L., Lv S., Zhang H., Chen Q., Wu J. Insight into nano-confined Fenton-like oxidation based on magnetic graphite oxide catalytic membrane. Environ. Res. 2025;286:122843. doi: 10.1016/j.envres.2025.122843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2025.122843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40945893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song T., Huang H., Zhang A. Efficiency and mechanism of organic matter removal from landfill leachate via a UV-synergized CuS-activated H2O2 Fenton-like system. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2025;13:120292. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2025.120292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2025.120292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei X., Zhao H., Bai C., Geng L., Xu X. Wood-derived catalysts for green and stable Fenton-like chemistry: From basic mechanisms to catalytic modules and future inspiration. Chin. Chem. Lett. 2025;36:111550. doi: 10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y., Liu X., Li T., Zhang H., Zeng L., Geng Y., Wu H., Liu C., Li H., Wang D., et al. Fe-Si-B amorphous magnetic nanoparticles as high-efficiency Fenton-like catalysts for rapid degradation of Rhodamine B. J. Magn. Magn. Mater. 2025;634:173561. doi: 10.1016/j.jmmm.2025.173561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmmm.2025.173561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Zhao Y., Wang J. Fenton/Fenton-like processes with in-situ production of hydrogen peroxide/hydroxyl radical for degradation of emerging contaminants: Advances and prospects. J. Hazard. Mater. 2021;404:124191. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2020.124191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2020.124191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33069993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Wang J. Peroxymonosulfate activation by Co9S8@ S and N co-doped biochar for sulfamethoxazole degradation. Chem. Eng. J. 2020;385:123933. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2019.123933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2019.123933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y., Li W., Wang J., Wu D., Li N., Li Y., Fan X., Peng W. Activation potential decreasing of iron oxide/graphite felt cathode by introducing Mn in electrochemical Fenton-like reactions. Chemosphere. 2024;369:143885. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.143885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.143885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39638127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Liu Y., Wei J., Xiang Y., Wang X., Wang H., Zhang H., Lai B. New insight into the role of humic acid in Vis/Fe(III)/PDS system: Synergistic effects of complexation and photosensitization. Chin. Chem. Lett. 2025;36:110811. doi: 10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Chen S., Liu C., Yue J., Yang Z., Ye Q., Xu H., Zhang Y., Xing X., Zhang J. Enhancement of iron cycling in Fenton-like catalysis by MoO2-C: Carbon-mediated efficient electron transport. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2025;360:130921. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2024.130921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2024.130921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., Zhao Y., Ma W., Wang D., Liu H., Wang W., Peng D., Yu C.Y., Wei H. A multivalent polyphenol-metal-nanoplatform for cascade amplified chemo-chemodynamic therapy. Acta Biomater. 2024;173:389&#x2013;402. doi: 10.1016/j.actbio.2023.11.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actbio.2023.11.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37967695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen D.-W., Liu C., Lu J., Mehmood T., Ren Y.-Y. Enhanced phycocyanin and DON removal by the synergism of H2O2 and micro-sized ZVI: Optimization, performance, and mechanisms. Sci. Total Environ. 2020;738:140134. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2020.140134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2020.140134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32806387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren S., Wen X., Lu T., Zhang H., Lou Z., Xu X., Li J., Yu J. Efficient valorization of textile white mud to MIL-101(Fe) with abundant coordinatively unsaturated centers for enhanced fenton-like catalysis. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;514:163323. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.163323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.163323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L., Yuan H., Li H., Chen S., Zhao P., Zhang R., Lu Z., Chen Z. Cu-Co binary metal-organic framework nanosheets for highly efficient degradation of norfloxacin using the Fenton-like process. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2024;12:114422. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2024.114422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2024.114422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon H., Park J., Yoon S., Choi M., Lee J., Choe J.K., Bae S. Dual environmental benefits of FeS-Fe(0)@biochar: Selective Cu recovery from plating wastewater and Cu-driven Fenton-like oxidation of organic pollutants at neutral pH. Chem. Eng. J. 2026;529:172385. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.172385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.172385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;uligoj A., Trendafilova I., Maver K., Pintar A., Risti&#x107; A., Dra&#x17e;i&#x107; G., Abdelraheem W.H.M., Jagli&#x10d;i&#x107; Z., Ar&#x10d;on I., Logar N.Z., et al. Multicomponent Cu-Mn-Fe silica supported catalysts to stimulate photo-Fenton-like water treatment under sunlight. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2023;11:110369. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2023.110369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2023.110369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang M., Zhu C., Zhu F., Fang G., Zhou D. Mechanism of significant enhancement of VO2-Fenton-like reactions by oxalic acid for diethyl phthalate degradation. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2021;279:119671. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2021.119671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2021.119671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., Li S., Li X., Zeng X., Chen J., Liu Z., Yu S., Hao J. Humic acid-based Fe/Ag bimetallic Fenton-like catalysts for efficient degradation of sulfadiazine in water. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2025;321:146505. doi: 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.146505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.146505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40754092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai X., Lan X., Wang H., Zhao X., Duan X. Cu&#x2013;Co sulfides anchored on CNTs/NF cathode for wide-pH electro-Fenton-like degradation of tetracycline: Synergistic mechanism, stability, and eco-safety. J. Environ. Sci. 2025 doi: 10.1016/j.jes.2025.12.068. in press .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jes.2025.12.068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Y., Xiao Y., Zhang H., Fan H., Li Y., Yan Z., Zhang W.-H. Synthesis of magnetic biochar-supported Fe-Cu bimetallic catalyst from pulp and paper mill wastes for the Fenton-like removal of rhodamine B dye. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;477:146823. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2023.146823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.146823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keselyt&#x117; A., Denafas G., Ha T.-H., Lu M.-C. Application of Ni-Fe catalyst from fluidized-bed crystallisation reactor for treatment of RB5 azo dye using a Fenton-like system. Process Saf. Environ. Prot. 2025;196:106959. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2025.106959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2025.106959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu J.-F., Wang H., Zhou Y., Mao X.-Y., Feng X.-Q., Wang S., Zhao Y.-H. Degradation of rhodamine B by fenton-like system with Fe-Cu/HZSM-5 catalyst. J. Taiwan Inst. Chem. Eng. 2026;178:106412. doi: 10.1016/j.jtice.2025.106412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtice.2025.106412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Zhang W., Chi W., Liu Y., Chen Y., Liang Y. A stabilized Z-type NH2-MIL101(Fe, Cu)/WO3 composite enhancing photo-Fenton like degradation of levofloxacin. Opt. Mater. 2025;165:117117. doi: 10.1016/j.optmat.2025.117117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optmat.2025.117117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L., Wang J. A heterogeneous Fenton-like system with nanoparticulate zero-valent iron for removal of 4-chloro-3-methyl phenol. J. Hazard. Mater. 2011;186:256&#x2013;264. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2010.10.116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2010.10.116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21109349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caracciolo P., Sapag K., Tonc&#xf3;n C., Ramos C.P., Inchaurrondo N. Electrospun Fe-supported silica membrane for the Fenton-like oxidation of Bisphenol A. Ceram. Int. 2025;51:55884&#x2013;55896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Bai Z. Fe-based catalysts for heterogeneous catalytic ozonation of emerging contaminants in water and wastewater. Chem. Eng. J. 2017;312:79&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2016.11.118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2016.11.118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Liu S., Chen D., Xu X. Iron single-atom/clusters catalysts derived from iron-rich Enteromorpha after urea-saturation for Fenton-like reaction. Chin. Chem. Lett. 2024;35:108666. doi: 10.1016/j.cclet.2023.108666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cclet.2023.108666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao X., Zhong Q., Xu Z., Fu H., Chang J., Gao H., Chen Y., Liao Y. Three birds with one stone: Fe(III)-coordinated cross-linked antibiofouling cellulose composite membrane for synergistic photodynamic and Fenton-like water disinfection. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;499:156048. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.156048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.156048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng C., Zhang H., Liu Y., Ren Y., Zhou P., He C.-S., Xiong Z., Liu W., Dai X., Lai B. Surface structure regulation of sulfidated zero-valent iron by H2O2 for efficient pH self-regulation and proton cycle to boost heterogeneous Fenton-like reaction for pollutant control. Appl. Catal. B Environ. Energy. 2024;345:123667. doi: 10.1016/j.apcatb.2023.123667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apcatb.2023.123667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang A.-Y., Lin Z.-X., Zhang J.-Y., Zhang M.-H., Zhang C., Zhao L., Liu L., Da W., Ye L. Regulating iron center by defective MoS2 for superior Fenton-like catalysis in water purification: The key role of surface interaction and superoxide radical in accelerating metal redox-cycling. Chemosphere. 2024;364:143173. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.143173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.143173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39182728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zakharov I.I., Kudjukov K.Y., Bondar V.V., Tyupalo N.F., Minaev B.F. DFT-based thermodynamics of fenton reactions rejects the &#x2018;pure&#x2019; aquacomplex models. Comput. Theor. Chem. 2011;964:94&#x2013;99. doi: 10.1016/j.comptc.2010.12.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comptc.2010.12.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spuhler D., Andr&#xe9;s Rengifo-Herrera J., Pulgarin C. The effect of Fe2+, Fe3+, H2O2 and the photo-Fenton reagent at near neutral pH on the solar disinfection (SODIS) at low temperatures of water containing Escherichia coli K12. Appl. Catal. B Environ. 2010;96:126&#x2013;141. doi: 10.1016/j.apcatb.2010.02.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apcatb.2010.02.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H., Jiang W., Jiang N., Yu G., Guo H., Li J. Plasma photo-Fenton-like catalysis with iron-doped g-C3N4 enhances chloramphenicol degradation in an atmospheric dielectric barrier discharge system. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2024;346:127347. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Y., Wang Z., Xu P., Lai C., Qin H., He Y., Li Y., Huo X., Tian Q., Wang C. Fenton chemistry rising star: Iron oxychloride. Coord. Chem. Rev. 2024;518:216051. doi: 10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Fan Q., Wang J. Zn-Fe-CNTs catalytic in situ generation of H2O2 for Fenton-like degradation of sulfamethoxazole. J. Hazard. Mater. 2018;342:166&#x2013;176. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2017.08.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2017.08.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28826059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang J., Wang J. MOF-derived three-dimensional flower-like FeCu@C composite as an efficient Fenton-like catalyst for sulfamethazine degradation. Chem. Eng. J. 2019;375:122007. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2019.122007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2019.122007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Kong C., Liu L., Jiang X., Liu C., Liu F., Sun J., Wang Y. Progress in copper-based supported heterogeneous electro-Fenton catalysts. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;486:150217. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.150217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.150217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z., Ge X., Wang Y., Jiang S., Sun S. Enhancing the Fenton-like reactions performance of copper-iron oxide by inducing a lower valence state using oxidized g-C3N4 support. Colloids Surf. A Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2024;684:133135. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2023.133135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2023.133135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu H., Zhong J., Xu J., Su L., Chen J., Chen Z., Zhang Z., Xiong Y. Enhanced detection of copper residues on citrus surfaces: An innovative copper fenton-catalysed colorimetric approach using creatinine and molybdenum trioxide. J. Food Compos. Anal. 2024;129:106123. doi: 10.1016/j.jfca.2024.106123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfca.2024.106123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., He L., Chen J., Zhao X., Zhang Q., Li Y., Xu W., Chen Z. Cu(I)-doped nitrogen-rich g-C3N4 with enhanced Fenton-like activity for pollutant degradation. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2026;390:136998. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2026.136998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2026.136998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham A.N., Xing G., Miller C.J., Waite T.D. Fenton-like copper redox chemistry revisited: Hydrogen peroxide and superoxide mediation of copper-catalyzed oxidant production. J. Catal. 2013;301:54&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1016/j.jcat.2013.01.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcat.2013.01.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin C.-W., Chiang Y.-C., Ng H.S., Liu S.-H., Yang Y.-K. Microbial-assisted copper migration stabilizes Fe/Cu cathodes for long-term bioelectro-Fenton degradation of bisphenol A. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2026;14:121223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ain Q.U., Rasheed U., Chen Z., Tong Z. Impregnation of copper-cysteamine nanoclusters containing Cu(I) and Cu(II)-ionic species on pristine and magnetic bentonite for efficient Fenton-like catalysis and higher dye adsorption. J. Water Process Eng. 2024;59:105031. doi: 10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.105031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.105031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savale S., Bandivadekar P., Chaturbhuj G. Copper Slag as efficient catalyst for the Fenton-like reaction: Conversion of alcohols to carbonyls. Tetrahedron Lett. 2024;147:155217. doi: 10.1016/j.tetlet.2024.155217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tetlet.2024.155217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H., Wang J. Catalytic ozonation of sulfamethoxazole over Fe3O4/Co3O4 composites. Chemosphere. 2019;234:14&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2019.06.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2019.06.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31202175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Q., Song J., Lv N., Shi H., Wang J. Fully dispersed cobalt diatomic site with significantly improved Fenton-like catalysis performance for organic pollutant degradation. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2024;662:1005&#x2013;1015. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2024.02.097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2024.02.097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38387362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., He X., Li J., Ma J., Yue J., Wang Z., Chen M. Selective electrophilic attack towards organic micropollutants with superior Fenton-like activity by biochar-supported cobalt single-atom catalyst. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2024;657:155&#x2013;168. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2023.11.131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2023.11.131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38035418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling S.K., Wang S., Peng Y. Oxidative degradation of dyes in water using CO2+/H2O2 and CO2+/peroxymonosulfate. J. Hazard. Mater. 2010;178:385&#x2013;389. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2010.01.091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2010.01.091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20144502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long Y., Zhao J., Dai J., Lu G., Lin M., Li S. Atomically dispersed cobalt activator with nitrogen and sulfur co-coordination for high-efficiency Fenton-like catalysis: Insights into density-dependent activity and mechanisms. J. Hazard. Mater. 2024;469:133996. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.133996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.133996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38471377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J., Wang R., Wang J., Hu Y., Guan J., Li Y., Xu X., Zhou Q. Salt template-assisted polymer tethering strategy to achieve high dispersed cobalt single atoms/clusters on porous carbon catalysts for effective Fenton-like reactions. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2024;12:114728. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2024.114728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2024.114728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo M., Lv L., Deng G., Yao W., Ruan Y., Li X., Xu A. The mechanism of bound hydroxyl radical formation and degradation pathway of Acid Orange II in Fenton-like CO2+-HCO3&#x2212; system. Appl. Catal. A Gen. 2014;469:198&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1016/j.apcata.2013.09.045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apcata.2013.09.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ming H., Yin C., Huang Z., Xu L., Zheng Z., Liu D., Zhang L., Hou J. Trace silver doping improved the efficiency of copper-based Fenton-like catalysts cathode for wastewater treatment. Colloids Surf. A Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2024;703:135261. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camilli E., Pighin A.F., Copello G.J., Villanueva M.E. Cobalt/carbon quantum dots core-shell nanoparticles as an improved catalyst for Fenton-like reaction. Nano-Struct. Nano-Objects. 2024;37:101097. doi: 10.1016/j.nanoso.2024.101097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoso.2024.101097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F.X., Zhang Z.W., Wang F., Li Y., Zhang Z.C., Wang C.C., Yu B., Du X., Wang P., Fu H., et al. Fe-Cu bimetal metal-organic framework for efficient decontamination via Fenton-like process: Synthesis, performance and mechanism. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2023;649:384&#x2013;393. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2023.06.083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2023.06.083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37354795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Z., Yang J., Zhu L., Sun T. Bromine functionalized Fe/Cu bimetallic MOFs for accelerating Fe(III)/Fe(II) cycle and efficient degradation of phenol in Fenton-like system. Colloids Surf. A Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2023;658:130701. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2022.130701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2022.130701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia Q., Zhang D., Yao Z., Jiang Z. Investigation of Cu heteroatoms and Cu clusters in Fe-Cu alloy and their special effect mechanisms on the Fenton-like catalytic activity and reusability. Appl. Catal. B Environ. 2021;299:120662. doi: 10.1016/j.apcatb.2021.120662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apcatb.2021.120662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia Q., Zhang D., Yao Z., Jiang Z. Revealing the enhancing mechanisms of Fe-Cu bimetallic catalysts for the Fenton-like degradation of phenol. Chemosphere. 2022;289:133195. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2021.133195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2021.133195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34883124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Xie H., Chen Y., Guo D., Li B., Sun X., Turkevych V., Li C., Chen D., Wang L., et al. Fe-Cu bimetallic oxide encapsulated in ZSM-5 for efficient heterogeneous Fenton-like degradation of methylene blue. Microporous Mesoporous Mater. 2025;395:113688. doi: 10.1016/j.micromeso.2025.113688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.micromeso.2025.113688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao X., Zhang M., Wang M., Lei H., Dong C., Shen R., Zhang H., Chen C., Hu J., Wu G. Highly efficient catalytic Fenton-Like reactions of bimetallic Fe/Cu chelated on radiation functionalized nonwoven fabric for pollutant control. J. Hazard. Mater. 2024;467:133752. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.133752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.133752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38350320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T., Wu P., Owens G., Chen Z. Adsorption and fenton-like oxidation of ofloxacin in wastewater using hybrid MOF bimetallic Fe/Ni nanoparticles. Chemosphere. 2022;307:135936. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.135936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.135936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35934098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farhadirad M., Najafi H., Sharifian S., Ebrahimian Pirbazari A., Asasian-Kolur N., Harasek M. Enhanced levofloxacin degradation through Fenton-like process using Fe-silica pillared clay catalyst. Appl. Catal. O Open. 2024;190:206931. doi: 10.1016/j.apcato.2024.206931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apcato.2024.206931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Supin K.K., Amrute V., Chanda A., Vasundhara M. Unveiling complex magnetic behaviour and effective photo-Fenton catalytic activity in the mixed phases of spinel and wurtzite structures of Fe-incorporated ZnO nanocrystals. Nano-Struct. Nano-Objects. 2024;39:101308. doi: 10.1016/j.nanoso.2024.101308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoso.2024.101308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X., Feng X., Dang Y., Yun S. Urchin-like Ni-Fe-Mo sulfide: An effective electrochemical calcium sulfite activator for tetracycline degradation. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2024;12:112954. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2024.112954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2024.112954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soomro M.Y., Balouch A., Alveroglu E., Larik R., Shah K., Chang S.A. Fe/Ni bimetallic magnetic nano-alloy (INBMNA): An efficient heterogeneous catalyst for photo-Fenton-like degradation of phenol in aqueous environment. Environ. Pollut. 2024;360:124635. doi: 10.1016/j.envpol.2024.124635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envpol.2024.124635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39084593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z., Liu Q., Zhang X., Shi B., Qin D., Wang J., Zhang A., Liu Y. Degradation of phenol by Cu-Ni bimetallic-doped sludge biochar as a fenton-like catalyst: Mechanistic study and practical application. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2024;347:127554. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Huang S., Sun H.J., Liu Y., Liang L., Nan Q., Wang T., Chen Z., Tang J., Hu C., et al. Amorphous Cu-Mn hopcalite as novel Fenton-like catalyst for H2O2-activated degradation of tetracycline at circumneutral pH. J. Sci. Adv. Mater. Devices. 2023;8:100603. doi: 10.1016/j.jsamd.2023.100603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsamd.2023.100603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao T., Pan J., Mao C., Chen L., Li J., Shao H., Xu G. Enhanced decomplexation of Cu-EDTA and simultaneous removal of Cu(II) by electron beam irradiation accompanied with autocatalytic fenton-like reaction: Synergistic performance and mechanism. Chemosphere. 2023;313:137445. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.137445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.137445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36495973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C., Li Y., Bao R., Yang L., Cui M., Cheng S., Liu J., Xia J., Li H. CuxO@Cu mesh electrode with {1 1 1} facet for efficient photo-electro-Fenton reaction and low voltage robustness. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2023;626:157187. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2023.157187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2023.157187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafeez M.A., Singh B.K., Yang S.H., Kim J., Kim B., Shin Y., Um W. Recent advances in Fenton-like treatment of radioactive ion exchange resins. Chem. Eng. J. Adv. 2023;14:100461. doi: 10.1016/j.ceja.2023.100461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceja.2023.100461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X., Gou L., Tang S., Cheng F., Zhang M., Guo M. Enhanced heterogeneous Fenton-like degradation of refractory organic contaminants over Cu doped (Mg,Ni)(Fe,Al)2O4 synthesized from laterite nickel ore. J. Environ. Manag. 2021;283:111941. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2021.111941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2021.111941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33503513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee K.T., Ho K.Y., Chen W.H., Kwon E.E., Lin K.A., Liou S.R. Construction and demolition waste as a high-efficiency advanced process for organic pollutant degradation in Fenton-like reaction to approach circular economy. Environ. Pollut. 2023;335:122246. doi: 10.1016/j.envpol.2023.122246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envpol.2023.122246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37516293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Ren Y., Qi S., Ning Z., Wang X., Dong W., Wang H. Enhanced removal of Ni-EDTA by three-dimensional electro-Fenton process using Fe-N-doped biochar as catalytic particle electrodes. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;471:144717. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2023.144717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.144717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai B., Ouyang S., Fan J., Liu C., Zhang Y., Wei Z., Wang Z., Wang X., Lei H. Preparation of highly-efficient Fe, N co-doping biochar from spent coffee grounds for the degradation of antibiotics via Fenton-like reaction. J. Environ. Manag. 2025;388:126051. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.126051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.126051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40460534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu X., Dong B., He J., Duan Y., Wang P., Wang D., Yang Q., Li Z., Li X. DBD synergistic self-catalytic fenton-like system for SHA-Fe decomplexation and Fe removal: Mechanism of hydroxyl group action. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2025;379:135153. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2025.135153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2025.135153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu B.G., Zhou X., Lu Y., Quan W.Z., Li C., Cheng L., Xiao X., Yu Y.Y. Interfacial OOH* mediated Fe(II) regeneration on the single atom Co-N-C catalyst for efficient Fenton-like processes. J. Hazard. Mater. 2024;470:134214. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.134214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.134214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38603908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang W., Xiao C., Tian Y., Wang Y., Qi J., Zhou Y., Zhu Z., Yang Y., Li J. Secondary coordination sphere modulation in covalent organic framework immobilized Co single-atom for Fenton-like catalysis. Appl. Catal. B Environ. Energy. 2026;387:126516. doi: 10.1016/j.apcatb.2026.126516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apcatb.2026.126516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Zhang J., Fu H., Sun M., Zhou C., Huo X., He C., Liu Y., Zhou P., Lai B. Manganese sulfide co-catalyzed Fenton and Fenton-like oxidation for degrading organic contaminants: Manganese and sulfur as dual reactive centers for sustainable FeIII/FeII cycles. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2025;378:134760. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2025.134760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2025.134760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng H., Wei P., Liu M., Yang Y., Huang L., Tang J., Hu R. Electronic structure engineering of Fe/Co dual-atom catalysts enhances ultrafast Fenton-like reactions mediated by high-valent iron-oxygen-cobalt bridged complexes for safe pollutant removal. J. Hazard. Mater. 2025;500:140555. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.140555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.140555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41273976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huda N.U., Farooq U., Noor H., Khan M.E., Ali W., Ali S.K., Khamaj A. Interfacial design of Sn0.96Fe0.02Ni0.02O/GGAC/gamma-Al2O3/CeO2/alpha-MoO3 S-scheme heterojunction for PMS-activated photo-Fenton-like removal of phenol and hydrogen production. Environ. Res. 2025;285:122703. doi: 10.1016/j.envres.2025.122703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2025.122703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40886791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang G., Jia Y., Guo L., Yang Y., Zhi J., Li X. Tannin-functionalized Mn3O4 as support for FeNiB alloy to construct sono-Fenton-like reaction for the degradation of antibiotic pollutants in water. Colloids Surf. A Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2023;663:131088. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2023.131088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2023.131088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song S., Qin Y., Huang S., Huang H., Chen Y. Preparation of Fe/Mn/Cu/tourmaline Fenton-like catalyst and the mechanism for degrading organic phosphorous scale inhibitors in simulated electroplating wastewater. Colloids Surf. A Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2025;706:135760. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Q., Yu D., Ma T., Bao J., Wang J., Zhang J., Cheng J., Fan W., Li J. One step reduction of coral-like palladium&#x2013;gold&#x2013;copper trimetallic alloy nanoparticles (Pd&#x2013;Au&#x2013;Cu NPs) and its investigation as photothermal-enhanced fenton catalytic degradation of organic dye pollutants. Mater. Chem. Phys. 2025;332:130296. doi: 10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.130296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.130296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anuraag N.S., Kumar U., Pradhan S., Shaw S.K., Sharma A., Sinha I., Prasad N.K. Rhombohedral phase high-entropy alloy of AlMnCuZnBi as a photo-Fenton catalyst for methyl orange degradation. J. Alloys Compd. 2025;1010:177142. doi: 10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradhan S., Barick K.C., Anuraag N.S., Mutta V., Prasad N.K. Development of ferrimagnetic (Mn0.6Cr0.6Co0.6Fe0.6Al0.6)O4 high entropy oxide for photo-Fenton degradation of organic dye. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2025;688:162343. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toor Z.S., Wu R., Hashmi M.R., Lee J.A., Li X., Yuji H., Zhang H., Kim H.S. Computation- and process-based design for advanced structural high-entropy alloy development and analyses: A critical review. Prog. Mater. Sci. 2026;155:101534. doi: 10.1016/j.pmatsci.2025.101534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmatsci.2025.101534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anamu U.S., Ayodele O.O., Olorundaisi E., Babalola B.J., Odetola P.I., Ogunmefun A., Ukoba K., Jen T.C., Olubambi P.A. Fundamental design strategies for advancing the development of high entropy alloys for thermo-mechanical application: A critical review. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2023;27:4833&#x2013;4860. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2023.11.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2023.11.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kausar A., Eisa M.H., Aldaghri O., Ibnaouf K.H., Mimouni A. Nanostructured materials derived from high entropy alloys&#x2013;State-of-the-art and leading technical applications. Results Phys. 2024;62:107838. doi: 10.1016/j.rinp.2024.107838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rinp.2024.107838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anuraag N.S., Kumar U., Sinha I., Prasad N.K. Nanoparticles of MnFeNiCuBi high entropy alloy as catalyst for Fenton and photo-Fenton decomposition of p-nitrophenol. Inorg. Chem. Commun. 2024;167:112843. doi: 10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar D., Anuraag N.S., Mohapatra C., Kumar U., Sarkar D., Vasundhara M., Sinha I., Upadhyay C., Prasad N.K. r-GO coated magnetic high entropy alloy/oxide nanocomposites as highly efficient Fenton and photo-Fenton catalysts. Ceram. Int. 2024;50:12146&#x2013;12157. doi: 10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.01.118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.01.118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao Z., Chen Y., Wang X., Hu K., Ren S., Zhang J., Song Z., Ren N., Duan X. High-entropy alloys catalyzing polymeric transformation of water pollutants with remarkably improved electron utilization efficiency. Nat. Commun. 2025;16:148. doi: 10.1038/s41467-024-55627-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-55627-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11697309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39747918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Fu P., Yang C., Tan S., Liang S.-X., Yang Y. Enhanced Fenton-like catalytic performance of Fe-based metallic glass by nitrogen microalloying. Intermetallics. 2026;189:109099. doi: 10.1016/j.intermet.2025.109099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.intermet.2025.109099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y., Liu X., Tang M., Du K., Yin H., Mao X., Wang D. Waste Eggshell-derived N, P, S Tri-doped Core-shell Catalysts for Efficient Fenton-like Catalysis. Chem. Eng. J. 2022;440:135879. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2022.135879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2022.135879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou W., Li J., Wang R., Ma J., Chen Z., Duan L., Mi H., Chen H. Hydroxylamine mediated Fenton-like interfacial reaction dynamics on sea urchin-like catalyst derived from spent LiFePO4 battery. J. Hazard. Mater. 2022;431:128590. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2022.128590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2022.128590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35247735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y., Tan X., Wang E., Zhao J., Ma J. A facile strategy to convert low-activity commercial iron oxides and cobalt disulfide into high-activity Fenton-like catalysts: Spontaneous generation of 1O2 for aqueous decontamination. Mater. Today Chem. 2022;26:101106. doi: 10.1016/j.mtchem.2022.101106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtchem.2022.101106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Zhang Y., Qian J. Graphene aerogel-based catalysts in Fenton-like reactions for water decontamination: A short review. Chem. Eng. J. Adv. 2021;8:100171. doi: 10.1016/j.ceja.2021.100171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceja.2021.100171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang Y., Liu X., Li Y., Gao Y., Gao B., Xu X., Yue Q. Boosting fenton-like reaction by reconstructed single Fe atom catalyst for oxidizing organics: Synergistic effect of conjugated &#x3c0;-&#x3c0; sp2 structured carbon and isolated Fe-N4 sites. Chem. Eng. J. 2022;446:137120. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2022.137120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2022.137120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Q., Chang J., Yu B., Jiang Y., Gao B., Yang J., Li Q., Gao Y., Xu X. Co-catalysis strategy for low-oxidant-consumption Fenton-like chemistry: From theoretical understandings to practical applications and future guiding strategies. Water Res. 2024;267:122488. doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2024.122488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2024.122488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39306932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng X., Yang Y., Wang J., Yuan W., Guo Y., Hu W., Yang X. Cu/Fe co-modified nitrogen self-doped biochar as a heterogeneous Fenton-like catalyst for degradation of organic pollutants: Synthesis, performance, and mechanistic study. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2023;11:110866. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2023.110866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2023.110866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Jiang H., Wang H., Show P.L., Ivanets A., Luo D., Wang C. MXenes as heterogeneous Fenton-like catalysts for removal of organic pollutants: A review. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2022;10:108954. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2022.108954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2022.108954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu J., Liu Z., Jiang L., Cai F., Sun C., Kong A., Ding H. Coordination polymers-derived core-shell Co@N&#x2013;C nanostructures as efficient dual functional catalysts for nitrate electroreduction and Fenton-like catalytic dye degradation. J. Solid State Chem. 2022;315:123485. doi: 10.1016/j.jssc.2022.123485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jssc.2022.123485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y., Li X., Jie B., Zheng Z., Li J., Zhu C., Wang S., Xu J., Zhang X. Electron structure modulation and bicarbonate surrounding enhance Fenton-like reactions performance of Co-Co PBA. J. Hazard. Mater. 2022;437:129372. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2022.129372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2022.129372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35728314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Zhang X., Wang S., Yu P., Xu Y., Sun Y. Highly enhanced heterogeneous photo-Fenton process for tetracycline degradation by Fe/SCN Fenton-like catalyst. J. Environ. Manag. 2022;312:114856. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2022.114856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2022.114856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35325739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin J., Zhang H., Luo M., Zhao J., Zhou X., Wang F., Zhou H., Yuan Y., Liu Y., Shi Y., et al. Electro-Fenton process for wastewater treatment: From selective H2O2 generation to efficient &#x2022;OH conversion. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;507:160709. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.160709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.160709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fashi A., Delavar A.F., Zamani A., Noshiranzadeh N., Mohammadi M. Comparative study of UVC irradiation and heat treatment on Fenton-like oxidation of corn starch in a continuous flow system: Performance and greenness. Polymer. 2025;327:128418. doi: 10.1016/j.polymer.2025.128418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymer.2025.128418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng L., Gu Y., Hua B., Fu J., Li F. Hierarchical porous melamine sponge@MIL-101-Fe-NH2 composite as Fenton-like catalyst for efficient and rapid tetracycline hydrochloride removal. Chemosphere. 2022;307:135728. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.135728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.135728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35850219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y., Zhao R., Li S., Lv Z., He J., Song J. Mass transfer and energy conversion in electrochemical process assisted by external fields. Energy Convers. Manag. 2024;321:119069. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2024.119069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2024.119069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Peng B., Wang L., Guo C., Wang Q. Sustainable and high-quality synthesis of carbon nanospheres with excellent dispersibility via synergistic external pressure- and PSSMA-assisted hydrothermal carbonization. Adv. Powder Technol. 2021;32:2449&#x2013;2456. doi: 10.1016/j.apt.2021.05.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apt.2021.05.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P., Yang Y., Ren W., Li X., Zhang Y., Lai B., Wang S., Duan X. Molecular and kinetic insights to boron boosted Fenton-like activation of peroxymonosulfate for water decontamination. Appl. Catal. B Environ. 2022;319:121916. doi: 10.1016/j.apcatb.2022.121916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apcatb.2022.121916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma S., Yang D., Guan Y., Yang Y., Zhu Y., Zhang Y., Wu J., Sheng L., Liu L., Yao T. Maximally exploiting active sites on Yolk@shell nanoreactor: Nearly 100% PMS activation efficiency and outstanding performance over full pH range in Fenton-like reaction. Appl. Catal. B Environ. 2022;316:121594. doi: 10.1016/j.apcatb.2022.121594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apcatb.2022.121594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu D., Liu Y., Zhu H., Gan Y., Zhang B., Yang W., Hao J. Magnetic porphyrin-based metal organic gel for rapid RhB removal and enhanced antibacterial activity by heterogeneous Photo-Fenton reaction under visible light. Chemosphere. 2022;303:135114. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.135114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.135114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35623427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Z., Du X., Zhu X., Huang E., Liu L., An Y. Regulate the behaviors of photo-generated carriers in CuFe-LDH/TiO2 based on positive bias voltage to enhance the capability of photo-Fenton on nitrobenzene degradation. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2022;602:154312. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2022.154312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2022.154312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S.-L., Chu X., Dong H.-L., Hou H.-Y., Liu Y. Recent advances in augmenting Fenton chemistry of nanoplatforms for enhanced chemodynamic therapy. Coord. Chem. Rev. 2023;479:215004. doi: 10.1016/j.ccr.2022.215004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccr.2022.215004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu L., Zhao X., Tang Z., Wu F., Wang J., Lei Q., Liang W., Wang X., Teng M., Zhang X. One-Step mechanochemical preparation of magnetic covalent organic framework for the degradation of organic pollutants by heterogeneous and homogeneous Fenton-like synergistic reaction. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2022;294:121145. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2022.121145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2022.121145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziembowicz S., Kida M. Limitations and future directions of application of the Fenton-like process in micropollutants degradation in water and wastewater treatment: A critical review. Chemosphere. 2022;296:134041. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.134041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.134041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35189198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S., Sudhaik A., Sonu, Raizada P., Ahamad T., Thakur S., Van Le Q., Selvasembian R., Nguyen V.-H., Mishra A.K., et al. Critical review on the tetracycline degradation using photo-Fenton assisted g-C3N4-based photocatalysts: Modification strategies, reaction parameters, and degradation pathway. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2024;12:112984. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2024.112984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2024.112984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Liu M., Dai Y., Cui J., Jamil A., Liu W., Li J., Wang J. Construction of self-cleaning C3N4/Bi2MoO6/PVDF membrane and coupling with photo-Fenton-like reaction for sustainable removal of antibiotics in wastewater. J. Environ. Manag. 2024;366:121928. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39029171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian M., Zhu Y., Chen Y., Liu X., Yang Y., Gao S. Template-assisted self-activation of mesoporous carbon with active nitrogen/oxygen configurations for sustainable triboelectric nanogenerator powered electro-Fenton degradation. Nano Energy. 2021;83:105825. doi: 10.1016/j.nanoen.2021.105825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2021.105825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Z.-L., Qian X.-F. Porous carbons for use in electro-Fenton and Fenton-like reactions. New Carbon Mater. 2022;37:180&#x2013;195. doi: 10.1016/S1872-5805(22)60578-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1872-5805(22)60578-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang D., Lu S., Ma Y., Zhao L. Synergistic photocatalysis-fenton reaction of flower-shaped CeO2/Fe3O4 magnetic catalyst for decolorization of high concentration congo red dye. Colloids Surf. A Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2022;647:129021. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2022.129021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2022.129021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadjltaief H.B., Bairq Z.A.S., Shi C., Benzina M. Evaluation of sono-assisted solar/Fenton process for indigo carmine degradation over magnetic ZnO-Fe3O4 supported Tunisian kaolinite clay. Surf. Interfaces. 2021;26:101395. doi: 10.1016/j.surfin.2021.101395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surfin.2021.101395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Zhang Z., Han H., Zhang M., Wang H., Song H., Chen Y. Effective removal of organic dyes using the ultrasonic-assisted hydrothermal synthesis of NaP zeolite doping Cu or Fe in Fenton-like oxidation systems. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2022;299:121767. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2022.121767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2022.121767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui S., Zhang J., Wang X., Fu Z., Lu C., Wang Y. Construction of Fe/Co bimetallic nitrogen-doped porous carbon self-supporting electrode for efficiently electro-fenton degradation of organic pollutants across pH 3.0&#x2013;9.0. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2026;728:166044. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2026.166044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2026.166044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang J., Liu L., Yang H., Du H. Applications of Fenton/Fenton-like photocatalytic degradation in g-C3N4 based composite materials. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2024;12:114153. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2024.114153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2024.114153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Zhao M., Hou C., Chen W., Li S., Ren R., Li Z. Efficient degradation of perfluorooctanoic acid by solar photo-electro-Fenton like system fabricated by MOFs/carbon nanofibers composite membrane. Chem. Eng. J. 2021;414:128940. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2021.128940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2021.128940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling L., Liu Y., Pan D., Lyu W., Xu X., Xiang X., Lyu M., Zhu L. Catalytic detoxification of pharmaceutical wastewater by Fenton-like reaction with activated alumina supported CoMnAl composite metal oxides catalyst. Chem. Eng. J. 2020;381:122607. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2019.122607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2019.122607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren B., Miao J., Wang S., Xu Y., Zhai Z., Dong X., Liu Z. Facilely synthesized porous 3D coral-like Fe-based N-doped carbon composite as effective Fenton catalyst in methylene blue degradation. Colloids Surf. A Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2021;618:126439. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2021.126439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2021.126439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong P., Wu Z., Yang D., Zhang K., He J., Li Y., Xie C., Yang W., Yang Y., Kong L., et al. Efficient generation of singlet oxygen (1O2) by hollow amorphous Co/C composites for selective degradation of oxytetracycline via Fenton-like process. Chem. Eng. J. 2021;421:129594. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2021.129594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2021.129594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Yang W., Xie L., Li Y., Liu Y., Sun Y., Bu Y., Mi X., Zhan S., Hu W. Prominent role of oxygen vacancy for superoxide radical and hydroxyl radical formation to promote electro-Fenton like reaction by W-doped CeO2 composites. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2021;549:149262. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2021.149262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2021.149262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Y., He X., Zhou H., Tian X., Nie Y., Zhou Z., Yang C., Li Y. Efficient fenton-like degradation of ofloxacin over bimetallic Fe-Cu@Sepiolite composite. Chemosphere. 2020;257:127209. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2020.127209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2020.127209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32502736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Q., Jing L., Lan Y., He M., Xu Y., Xu H., Li H. Construction 3D rod-like Bi3.64Mo0.36O6.55/CuBi2O4 photocatalyst for enhanced photocatalytic activity via a photo-Fenton-like Cu2+/Cu+ redox cycle. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2021;254:117546. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2020.117546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2020.117546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen C.H., Tran M.L., Van Tran T.T., Juang R.-S. Efficient removal of antibiotic oxytetracycline from water by Fenton-like reactions using reduced graphene oxide-supported bimetallic Pd/nZVI nanocomposites. J. Taiwan Inst. Chem. Eng. 2021;119:80&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1016/j.jtice.2021.02.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtice.2021.02.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen L.H., Van H.T., Ngo Q.N., Thai V.N., Hoang V.H., Hai N.T.T. Improving Fenton-like oxidation of Rhodamin B using a new catalyst based on magnetic/iron-containing waste slag composite. Environ. Technol. Innov. 2021;23:101582. doi: 10.1016/j.eti.2021.101582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eti.2021.101582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H., Liu G., Dong B., Jin R., Zhou J. Synergistic catalytic Fenton-like degradation of sulfanilamide by biosynthesized goethite-reduced graphene oxide composite. J. Hazard. Mater. 2021;415:125704. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2021.125704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2021.125704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33773243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y., Wang X., Tong W., Hu W., Li P., Dai L., Wang Y., Zhang Y. FexP/biochar composites induced oxygen-driven Fenton-like reaction for sulfamethoxazole removal: Performance and reaction mechanism. Chem. Eng. J. 2020;396:125321. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2020.125321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2020.125321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soufi A., Hajjaoui H., Boumya W., Elmouwahidi A., Baill&#xf3;n-Garc&#xed;a E., Abdennouri M., Barka N. Recent trends in magnetic spinel ferrites and their composites as heterogeneous Fenton-like catalysts: A review. J. Environ. Manag. 2024;367:121971. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39074433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>