<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41848229</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Knee surgery, sports traumatology, arthroscopy : official journal of the ESSKA</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A rehabilitation programme performed in darkness after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction reduces the risk of secondary injuries.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ksa.70378</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate whether integrating partial visual deprivation during the reathletization phase after anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction improves proprioceptive recovery and reduces the risk of graft failure or contralateral injuries.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a retrospective, single-centre cohort study including patients aged older than 16 years who underwent ACL reconstruction with autograft and concomitant anterolateral ligament reconstruction between November 2017 and March 2020. Patients voluntarily chose between two reathletization programmes starting from the fourth postoperative month: Group 1 (Conventional): exercises performed exclusively in a well-lit environment (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;372). Group 2 (Darkness): exercises alternating between well-lit and controlled dark conditions (&lt;10&#x2009;lux) (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;131). Primary outcome was ACL graft re-rupture; secondary outcomes included contralateral ACL rupture, functional scores (International Knee Documentation Committee [IKDC] Subjective Knee Form, Knee Injury and Osteoarthritis Outcome Score [KOOS], Lysholm, ACL-Return to Sport after Injury [ACL-RSI]) and return-to-sport level (Tegner Activity Scale). A minimum follow-up of 5 years was required. Groups were matched for age, sex, graft type, baseline sports level and associated meniscal lesions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 446 patients (mean follow-up: 5.8&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.7 years) were analysed. The overall re-rupture rate was 5.4% and tended to be lower in the Darkness group (3.2%) compared to the Conventional group (7.1%; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.18). Contralateral ACL ruptures were significantly less frequent in the Darkness group (5.7% vs. 13.1%; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01). Functional scores (IKDC, KOOS, Lysholm, ACL-RSI) showed no significant differences between groups. However, the final return-to-sport level was significantly higher in the Darkness group (Tegner 6.0 vs. 5.3; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.04).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A reathletization programme incorporating partial visual deprivation after ACL reconstruction may reduce the risk of contralateral injuries, despite no significant difference in functional scores. This simple, feasible approach warrants further evaluation in prospective controlled studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level III.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 European Society of Sports Traumatology, Knee Surgery and Arthroscopy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wein</LastName><ForeName>Frank</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3685-078X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chirurgie des Articulations et du Sport (ARTICS), Essey-les-Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinique Louis Pasteur, Essey-les-Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leclerc</LastName><ForeName>Eliott</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0547-8508</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CHRU, Centre Chirurgical Emile-Gall&#xe9;, Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Richard</LastName><ForeName>Julia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-5487-7753</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CHRU, Centre Chirurgical Emile-Gall&#xe9;, Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goetzmann</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5215-1017</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chirurgie des Articulations et du Sport (ARTICS), Essey-les-Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinique Louis Pasteur, Essey-les-Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walbron</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chirurgie des Articulations et du Sport (ARTICS), Essey-les-Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinique Louis Pasteur, Essey-les-Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9314730</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0942-2056</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">contralateral ACL injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">proprioception</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reathletization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">visual deprivation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41848229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.70378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Webster KE, Taylor NF, Feller JA. Return to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of the state of play. Br J Sports Med. 2011;45(7):596&#x2013;606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bizzini M, Hancock D, Impellizzeri F. Suggestions from the field for return to sports participation following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: soccer. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2012;42(4):304&#x2013;312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blakeney WG, Ouanezar H, Rogowski I, Vigne G, Guen ML, Fayard J&#x2010;M, et al. Validation of a composite test for assessment of readiness for return to sports after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: the K&#x2010;STARTS test. Sports Health. 2018;10(6):515&#x2013;522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busch A, Blasimann A, Mayer F, Baur H. Alterations in sensorimotor function after ACL reconstruction during active joint position sense testing. A systematic review. PLoS One. 2021;16(6):e0253503. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0253503</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cambieri C, Iacovelli E, Gori MC, Onesti E, Ceccanti M, Frasca V, et al. Effects of visual deprivation on primary motor cortex excitability: a study on healthy subjects based on repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation. Exp Brain Res. 2017;235(7):2059&#x2013;2067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dauty M, Collon S, Dubois C. Change in posture control after recent knee anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction? Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2010;30(3):187&#x2013;191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dingenen B, Gokeler A. Optimization of the return&#x2010;to&#x2010;sport paradigm after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a critical step back to move forward. Sports Med. 2017;47(8):1487&#x2013;1500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutt K, Redding E. The effect of an eyes&#x2010;closed dance&#x2010;specific training program on dynamic balance in elite pre&#x2010;professional ballet dancers: a randomized controlled pilot study. J Dance Med Sci. 2014;18(1):3&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jandaghi S, Tahan N, Akbarzadeh Baghban A, Zoghi M. Stroke patients showed improvements in balance in response to visual restriction exercise. Phys Ther Res. 2021;24(3):211&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H&#x2010;J, Lee J&#x2010;H, Lee D&#x2010;H. Proprioception in patients with anterior cruciate ligament tears: a meta&#x2010;analysis comparing injured and uninjured limbs. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45(12):2916&#x2013;2922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y&#x2010;W, Moon S&#x2010;J. Effects of treadmill training with the eyes closed on gait and balance ability of chronic stroke patients. J Phys Ther Sci. 2015;27(9):2935&#x2013;2938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokmeyer D, Wahoff M, Mymern M. Suggestions from the field for return&#x2010;to&#x2010;sport rehabilitation following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: alpine skiing. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2012;42(4):313&#x2013;325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CCH, Ardern CL, Feller JA, Webster KE. Eighty&#x2010;three per cent of elite athletes return to preinjury sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review with meta&#x2010;analysis of return to sport rates, graft rupture rates and performance outcomes. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(2):128&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lephart SM, Pincivero DM, Giraido JL, Fu FH. The role of proprioception in the management and rehabilitation of athletic injuries. Am J Sports Med. 1997;25(1):130&#x2013;137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Melick N, Senorski EH, Kr&#xf3;likowska A, Prill R. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction rehabilitation: decades of change. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33(4):1178&#x2013;1182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merabet LB, Hamilton R, Schlaug G, Swisher JD, Kiriakopoulos ET, Pitskel NB, et al. Rapid and reversible recruitment of early visual cortex for touch. PLoS One. 2008;3(8):e3046. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0003046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myer GD, Sugimoto D, Thomas S, Hewett TE. The influence of age on the effectiveness of neuromuscular training to reduce anterior cruciate ligament injury in female athletes: a meta&#x2010;analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41(1):203&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zalt&#x131;n GE, Talu B, Bay&#x131;nd&#x131;r T. The effect of proprioceptive vestibular rehabilitation on sensory&#x2010;motor symptoms and quality of life. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2024;82(11):001&#x2013;010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterno MV, Rauh MJ, Schmitt LC, Ford KR, Hewett TE. Incidence of second ACL injuries 2 years after primary ACL reconstruction and return to sport. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42(7):1567&#x2013;1573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radziun D, Ehrsson HH. Short&#x2010;term visual deprivation boosts the flexibility of body representation. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):6284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risberg MA, M&#xf8;rk M, Jenssen HK, Holm I. Design and implementation of a neuromuscular training program following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2001;31(11):620&#x2013;631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstegen M, Falsone S, Orr R, Smith S. Suggestions from the field for return to sports participation following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: American football. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2012;42(4):337&#x2013;344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vuillerme N, Nougier V, Prieur JM. Can vision compensate for a lower limbs muscular fatigue for controlling posture in humans? Neurosci Lett. 2001;308(2):103&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waters E. Suggestions from the field for return to sports participation following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: basketball. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2012;42(4):326&#x2013;336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wein F, Peultier&#x2010;Celli L, van Rooij F, Saffarini M, Perrin P. No significant improvement in neuromuscular proprioception and increased reliance on visual compensation 6 months after ACL reconstruction. J Exp Orthop. 2021;8(1):19.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>