<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41651020</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2093-7482</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Asian nursing research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Asian Nurs Res (Korean Soc Nurs Sci)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring the Effects of Nurse-Led Health Education on Parental Knowledge and Child Health Outcomes in Congenital Heart Surgery: A Quasi-Experimental Study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1976-1317(26)00008-3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.anr.2025.12.006</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">In developing countries, delayed diagnosis and limited access to treatment often complicate the post-operative course for children with congenital heart disease, who require complex care to optimize cardiac function. Effective recovery depends on collaboration between healthcare providers and parents, with health education serving as a critical support mechanism. However, research in these settings has faced limitations restricting generalizability, and the role of nurses in health education remains underutilized. This study aimed to evaluate the effectiveness of a nurse-led health education program for parents of children undergoing congenital heart surgery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A quasi-experimental design was employed in a Vietnamese pediatric cardiac facility. Eligible parent-child dyads were assigned to control or intervention groups based on enrollment period, separated by a washout period. The intervention group received five teaching sessions facilitated by teach-back plus standard care, while the control group received standard care only. Data were collected at admission, discharge, first and second outpatient appointments. Co-primary outcomes were parental knowledge and child weight.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">One hundred thirty-eight dyads were recruited (control: n = 74; intervention: n = 64). Primary caregivers were mothers (92.8%) in their 30s, with high school the most common education level. Children's median age: 6 months (IQR = [2.43, 14.47]), with 50% (n = 69) undergoing low-to-moderate risk surgical procedures. Compared to controls, the intervention group showed significantly greater parental knowledge (b = -3.24, 95% CI [-3.79, -2.70], p&lt;.001), increased child weight (b = -0.07, 95% CI [-0.11, -0.04], p&lt;.001), lower risk of abnormal oxygen saturation (RR = 2.53, 95% CI [1.14, 5.59], p = .022).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Nurse-led health education can enhance parental knowledge and improve child growth and cardiac function, highlighting its potential implications in routine pediatric cardiac care, particularly in resource-constrained settings. Further research should confirm long-term effects and broader applicability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ACTRN12623000388617p (18/04/2023).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026. Published by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tran</LastName><ForeName>Huong Thi Mai</ForeName><Initials>HTM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Centre for Healthcare Transformation, Queensland University of Technology, 149 Victoria Park Rd, Kelvin Grove QLD 4059, Australia; Heart Center, Vietnam National Children's Hospital, No18/879 La Thanh, Lang Thuong, Dong Da, Hanoi, Vietnam 100000.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramsbotham</LastName><ForeName>Joanne</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Centre for Healthcare Transformation, Queensland University of Technology, 149 Victoria Park Rd, Kelvin Grove QLD 4059, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>Debbie</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Centre for Healthcare Transformation, Queensland University of Technology, 149 Victoria Park Rd, Kelvin Grove QLD 4059, Australia; Pediatric Intensive Care Unit, Queensland Children's Hospital, 501 Stanley St, South Brisbane QLD 4101, Australia. Electronic address: da.long@qut.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Asian Nurs Res (Korean Soc Nurs Sci)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101321326</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1976-1317</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Child</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heart defects</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nurses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">congenital</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41651020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anr.2025.12.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1976-1317(26)00008-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>