<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41851831</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2229</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC plant biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Plant Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Transcriptome-based investigation of the response and repair mechanisms in the photosynthetic system of Cycas panzhihuaensis under dual high-temperature and drought stress.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12870-026-08554-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Cycas panzhihuaensis, as a national first-class protected plant, has long been threatened by dual high-temperature and drought stress. Photosynthesis is a key target of dual high-temperature and drought stress. However, the specific processes underlying post-injury recovery remain poorly characterized. Utilizing chlorophyll fluorescence parameters, chloroplast ultrastructure and transcriptome sequencing techniques, this investigation analyzes the photosynthetic damage of C. panzhihuaensis under dual high-temperature and drought stress and the repair mechanism of photosynthetic system after rehydration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The results showed that the maximum quantum yield of photosystem II decreased by 51.2% compared with the CK., the thylakoid structure disintegrated, the osmiophilic particles increased sharply, and the photosynthetic function was seriously damaged under the combined stress. Key genetic components responsible for the function of Photosystem I and II, ATP synthase and multiple photosynthesis-related transcription factors NAC, bHLH, WRKY, MYB, and ERF were synergistically down-regulated. Rewatering repair showed a sequential strategy of ' rapid water absorption&#x2009;&#x2192;&#x2009;light protection priority&#x2009;&#x2192;&#x2009;structural reconstruction ': when rewatering for 3&#xa0;days, the leaf relative water content showed ' overcompensation '-a transient excess water uptake beyond the pre-stress level, but the photosynthetic function was further deteriorated, and the light protection mechanism was preferentially activated; after 7&#xa0;days of rewatering, the grana thylakoids overlapped, osmiophilic particles decreased, the maximum quantum yield recovered to 0.689, the core photosystem genes and transcription factors were up-regulated, and the photosynthetic function was partially restored. A key observation was the delayed recovery of the LHCB gene family, particularly LHCB1 and LHCB2 homologs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoqian</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Forest Resources Conservation and Utilizationin the Southwest Mountains of China, Ministry of Education, Southwest Forestry University, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yunnan Academy of Biodiversity, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Forest Disaster Warning and Control Yunnan Province, Southwest Forestry University, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Chaotian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Forest Resources Conservation and Utilizationin the Southwest Mountains of China, Ministry of Education, Southwest Forestry University, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yunnan Academy of Biodiversity, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Forest Disaster Warning and Control Yunnan Province, Southwest Forestry University, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Sijing</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Forest Resources Conservation and Utilizationin the Southwest Mountains of China, Ministry of Education, Southwest Forestry University, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yunnan Academy of Biodiversity, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Forest Disaster Warning and Control Yunnan Province, Southwest Forestry University, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xian</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Forest Resources Conservation and Utilizationin the Southwest Mountains of China, Ministry of Education, Southwest Forestry University, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yunnan Academy of Biodiversity, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Forest Disaster Warning and Control Yunnan Province, Southwest Forestry University, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yongqiong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>, Administration Bureau of Panzhihua Cycas National Nature Reserve, Panzhihua 617000, Sichuan, China. 596370772@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Yanling</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Forest Resources Conservation and Utilizationin the Southwest Mountains of China, Ministry of Education, Southwest Forestry University, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China. flashingzyl@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yunnan Academy of Biodiversity, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China. flashingzyl@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Forest Disaster Warning and Control Yunnan Province, Southwest Forestry University, Kunming, Yunnan, 650224, China. flashingzyl@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>XDYC-QNRC-2022-0221</GrantID><Agency>Yunnan Revitalization Talent Support Program Young Talent Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Plant Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967807</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2229</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">C. panzhihuaensis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dual high-temperature and drought stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LHCB gene family</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Photosynthetic damage repair</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transcriptome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The C. panzhihuaensis plant materials were provided by the Panzhihua National Nature Reserve Administration, with all experimental treatments and sampling procedures conducted under the institution's official approval. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41851831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12870-026-08554-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12870-026-08554-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hlahla JM, Mafa MS, Van Der Merwe R, Moloi MJ. Exploring edamame survival mechanisms under combined drought and heat stress: photosynthesis efficiency and carbohydrate accumulation. Plant Stress. 2024;14:100616. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stress.2024.100616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumari S, Basu S, Kumar G. A systematic review on the implications of concurrent heat and drought stress in modulating floral development in plants. Plant Sci. 2024;349:112248. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plantsci.2024.112248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zha Q, Xi X, He Y, Jiang A. Transcriptomic analysis of the leaves of two grapevine cultivars under high-temperature stress. Sci Hortic. 2020;265:109265. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scienta.2020.109265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelhakim LOA, Zhou R, Ottosen C-O. Physiological responses of plants to combined drought and heat under elevated CO2. Agronomy. 2022;12:2526. https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy12102526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maraun D, Schiemann R, Oss&#xf3; A, Jury M. Changes in event soil moisture-temperature coupling can intensify very extreme heat beyond expectations. Nat Commun. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56109-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu W, Chen L, Liang R, Huang S, Li X, Huang B, et al. The role of light in regulating plant growth, development and sugar metabolism: a review. Front Plant Sci. 2025. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2024.1507628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayford RK, Serba DD, Xie S, Ayyappan V, Thimmapuram J, Saha MC, et al. Global analysis of switchgrass (panicum virgatum L.) transcriptomes in response to interactive effects of drought and heat stresses. BMC Plant Biol. 2022. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12870-022-03477-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Vinocur B, Altman A. Plant responses to drought, salinity and extreme temperatures: towards genetic engineering for stress tolerance. Planta. 2003;218:1&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00425-003-1105-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittler R. Abiotic stress, the field environment and stress combination. Trends Plant Sci. 2006;11:15&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tplants.2005.11.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priya M, Farooq M, Siddique KHM. Enhancing tolerance to combined heat and drought stress in cool-season grain legumes: Mechanisms, genetic insights, and future directions. Plant, Cell &amp; Environment. https://doi.org/10.1111/pce.15382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Qiu S, Chen Y, Li J, Xu T, Zhong P, et al. Integrated transcriptomics and metabolomics provides insights into the nicotiana tabacum response to heat stress. Front Plant Sci. 2024. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2024.1425944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato H, Mizoi J, Shinozaki K, Yamaguchi-Shinozaki K. Complex plant responses to drought and heat stress under climate change. Plant J. 2024;117:1873&#x2013;92. https://doi.org/10.1111/tpj.16612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matile P, H&#xf6;rtensteiner S, Thomas H. Chlorophyll degradation. Annu Rev Plant Biol. 1999;50(1):67&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.arplant.50.1.67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zafar S, Khan MK, Aslam N, Hasnain Z. Impact of different stresses on morphology, physiology, and biochemistry of plants. In: Shahid M, Gaur R, editors. Molecular Dynamics of Plant Stress and its Management. Singapore: Springer Nature; 2024. p. 67&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1699-9_4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S, Kaushal N, Nayyar H, Gaur P. Abscisic acid induces heat tolerance in chickpea (cicer arietinum L.) seedlings by facilitated accumulation of osmoprotectants. Acta Physiol Plant. 2012;34:1651&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11738-012-0959-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W, Wuyun T, Chen J, Yu S, Zhang X, Zhang L. Responses of trollius chinensis to drought stress and rehydration: from photosynthetic physiology to gene expression. Plant Physiol Biochem. 2023;201:107841. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plaphy.2023.107841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansson S, Pichersky E, Bassi R, Green BR, Ikeuchi M, Melis A, et al. A nomenclature for the genes encoding the chlorophylla/b-binding proteins of higher plants. Plant Mol Biol Rep. 1992;10:242&#x2013;53. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF02668357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou R, Kan X, Chen J, Hua H, Li Y, Ren J, et al. Drought-induced changes in photosynthetic electron transport in maize probed by prompt fluorescence, delayed fluorescence, P700 and cyclic electron flow signals. Environ Exp Bot. 2019;158:51&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envexpbot.2018.11.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller KR, Staehelin LA. Analysis of the thylakoid outer surface. Coupling factor is limited to unstacked membrane regions. J Cell Biol. 1976;68:30&#x2013;47. https://doi.org/10.1083/jcb.68.1.30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson B, Anderson JM. Lateral heterogeneity in the distribution of chlorophyll-protein complexes of the thylakoid membranes of spinach chloroplasts. Biochim Biophys Acta (BBA) - Bioenerg. 1980;593:427&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1016/0005-2728(80)90078-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vayghan HS, Nawrocki WJ, Schiphorst C, Tolleter D, Hu C, Douet V, et al. Photosynthetic light harvesting and thylakoid organization in a CRISPR/Cas9 arabidopsis thaliana LHCB1 knockout mutant. Front Plant Sci. 2022. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2022.833032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Wang Y, Song X, Yang Y, Li Y, Zhu Z, et al. BcLhcb2.1, a light-harvesting chlorophyll a/b-binding protein from wucai, plays a positive regulatory role in the response to abiotic stress. Sci Hortic. 2025;339:113759. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scienta.2024.113759.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan Y, Song Y, Zhao F, Cao Y, Luo D, Qiao D, et al. Phylogenetic, structural and functional evolution of the LHC gene family in plant species. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24:488. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms24010488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao S, Gao H, Luo J, Wang H, Dong Q, Wang Y, et al. Genome-wide analysis of the light-harvesting chlorophyll a/b-binding gene family in Apple (malus domestica) and functional characterization of MdLhcb4.3, which confers tolerance to drought and osmotic stress. Plant Physiol Biochem. 2020;154:517&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plaphy.2020.06.022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klimmek F, Sj&#xf6;din A, Noutsos C, Leister D, Jansson S. Abundantly and rarely expressed lhc protein genes exhibit distinct regulation patterns in plants. Plant Physiol. 2006;140:793&#x2013;804. https://doi.org/10.1104/pp.105.073304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Q, Xu Z-S, Wang F, Li M-Y, Ma J, Xiong A-S. Effects of abiotic stresses on the expression of Lhcb1 gene and photosynthesis of oenanthe javanica and apium graveolens. Biol Plant. 2014;58:256&#x2013;64. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10535-014-0396-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu ZH, Zhang N, Qin ZY, Li JW, Tao JP, Yang N, et al. Circadian rhythm response and its effect on photosynthetic characteristics of the lhcb family genes in tea plant. BMC Plant Biol. 2024;24:333. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12870-024-04958-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue T, Wan H, Chen J, He S, Lujin C, Xia M, et al. Genome-wide identification and expression analysis of the chlorophyll a/b binding protein gene family in oilseed (Brassica napus L.) under salt stress conditions. Plant Stress. 2024;11:100339. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stress.2023.100339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballottari M, Girardon J, Dall&#x2019;Osto L, Bassi R. Evolution and functional properties of photosystem II light harvesting complexes in eukaryotes. Biochim Biophys Acta (BBA) - Bioenerg. 2012;1817:143&#x2013;57. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbabio.2011.06.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrova N, Todinova S, Paunov M, Kov&#xe1;cs L, Taneva S, Krumova S. Thylakoid membrane unstacking increases LHCII thermal stability and lipid phase fluidity. J Bioenerg Biomembr. 2018;50:425&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10863-018-9783-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awasthi R, Gaur P, Turner NC, Vadez V, Siddique KHM, Nayyar H. Effects of individual and combined heat and drought stress during seed filling on the oxidative metabolism and yield of chickpea (cicer arietinum) genotypes differing in heat and drought tolerance. Crop Pasture Sci. 2017;68:823. https://doi.org/10.1071/CP17028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Shi M, Zhang R, Wang Y, Zhang W, Qin S, et al. Dynamics of physiological and biochemical effects of heat, drought and combined stress on potato seedlings. Chem Biol Technol Agric. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40538-024-00639-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima-Melo Y, Gollan PJ, Tikkanen M, Silveira JAG, Aro E-M. Consequences of photosystem-I damage and repair on photosynthesis and carbon use in arabidopsis thaliana. Plant J. 2019;97:1061&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1111/tpj.14177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burleigh JG, Barbazuk WB, Davis JM, Morse AM, Soltis PS. Exploring diversification and genome size evolution in extant gymnosperms through phylogenetic synthesis. J Bot. 2012;2012:1&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1155/2012/292857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coiro M, Allio R, Mazet N, Seyfullah LJ, Condamine FL. Reconciling fossils with phylogenies reveals the origin and macroevolutionary processes explaining the global cycad biodiversity. New Phytol. 2023;240:1616&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.19010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling Z, Jiang A, Hu M, Peng X, Zheng Y. Lipid metabolism in cycas panzhihuaensis exposed to combined stress of drought and high temperatures and subsequent recovery. Plant Physiol Biochem. 2025;223:109808. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plaphy.2025.109808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B, Zhao X, Dong Y, Xiong D, Li X. Morphological characteristics and influencing factors of gully headwall scour holes in yuanmou dry-hot valley region, southwestern China. CATENA. 2025;249:108721. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.catena.2025.108721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J, Wang F, Jiang A, Hu M, Zheng Y. Chlorophyll fluorescence characteristics and lipid metabolism in endangered cycas panzhihuaensis exposed to drought, high temperature and their combination1. Plant Physiol Biochem. 2025;223:109858. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plaphy.2025.109858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhanassova K, Kurmanbayeva A, Gadilgereyeva B, Yermukhambetova R, Iksat N, Amanbayeva U, et al. ROS status and antioxidant enzyme activities in response to combined temperature and drought stresses in barley. Acta Physiol Plant. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11738-021-03281-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carneiro JdaS, Nogueira RM, Martins MA, Vallad&#xe3;o DMdeS, Pires EM. The oven-drying method for determination of water content in brazil nut. Biosci J. 2018. https://doi.org/10.14393/bj-v34n3a2018-37726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Wang Z, Zhu R, Wang F, Cheng Y, Liu Y. Three differential expression analysis methods for RNA sequencing: limma, EdgeR, DESeq2. J Visualized Exp. 2021. https://doi.org/10.3791/62528-v.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Fang X, Han S, Zhu T, Zhu H. Differential proteome analysis of hybrid bamboo (bambusa pervariabilis&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;dendrocalamopsis grandis) under fungal stress (arthrinium phaeospermum). Sci Rep. 2019;9:18681. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-55229-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao X, Khaliq A, Lu S, Xie M, Ma Z, Mao J, et al. Genome-wide identification and characterization of the BES1 gene family in apple (malus domestica). Plant Biol. 2020;22:723&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.1111/plb.13109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vera&#x2010;Vives AM, Novel P, Zheng K, Tan S, Schwarzl&#xe4;nder M, Alboresi A, et al. Mitochondrial respiration is essential for photosynthesis-dependent ATP supply of the plant cytosol. New Phytol. 2024;243:2175&#x2013;86. https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.19989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Didion&#x2010;Gency M, Gessler A, Buchmann N, Gisler J, Schaub M, Grossiord C. Impact of warmer and drier conditions on tree photosynthetic properties and the role of species interactions. New Phytol. 2022;236:547&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.18384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chotewutmontri P, Barkan A. Localization of proteins involved in the biogenesis of the photosynthetic apparatus to thylakoid subdomains in arabidopsis. bioRxiv - Plant Biology. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.06.21.600055.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Liu L, Zhao H, Jiang Z, Cai J. Differences in near isohydric and anisohydric behavior of contrasting poplar hybrids (I-101 (Populus alba L.) &#xd7; 84K (Populus alba L. &#xd7; Populus glandulosa Uyeki)) under drought-rehydration treatments. Forests. 2020;11:402. https://doi.org/10.3390/f11040402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Didaran F, Kordrostami M, Ghasemi-Soloklui AA, Pashkovskiy P, Kreslavski V, Kuznetsov V, et al. The mechanisms of photoinhibition and repair in plants under high light conditions and interplay with abiotic stressors. J Photochem Photobiol B Biol. 2024;259:113004. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphotobiol.2024.113004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortunel C, Stahl C, Coste S, Ziegler C, Derroire G, Levionnois S, et al. Thresholds for persistent leaf photochemical damage predict plant drought resilience in a tropical rainforest. New Phytol. 2023;239:576&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.18973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor NL, Heazlewood JL, Day DA, Millar AH. &lt;article-title update="added"&gt;Differential impact of environmental stresses on the pea mitochondrial proteome. Mol Cell Proteomics. 2005;4:1122&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.1074/mcp.M400210-MCP200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suetsugu K, Sugita R, Yoshihara A, Okada H, Akita K, Nagata N, et al. Aerial roots of the leafless epiphytic orchid taeniophyllum are specialized for performing crassulacean acid metabolism photosynthesis. New Phytol. 2023;238:932&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.18812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey J, Devadasu E, Saini D, Dhokne K, Marriboina S, Raghavendra AS, et al. Reversible changes in structure and function of photosynthetic apparatus of pea (pisum sativum) leaves under drought stress. Plant J. 2022;113:60&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1111/tpj.16034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisz DA, Johnson VM, Niedzwiedzki DM, Shinn MK, Liu H, Klitzke CF, et al. A novel chlorophyll protein complex in the repair cycle of photosystem II. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2019;116:21907&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1909644116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X, Khan R, Gao H, Liu H, Zhang J, Ma X. Low light alters the photosynthesis process in cigar tobacco via modulation of the chlorophyll content, chlorophyll fluorescence, and gene expression. Agriculture. 2021;11:755. https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture11080755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cong Y, Chen X, Xing J, Li X, Pang S, Liu H. Frontiers | nitric oxide signal is required for glutathione-induced enhancement of photosynthesis in salt-stressed solanum lycopersicum L. Front Plant Sci. 2024;15. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2024.1413653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez&#x2010;Prieto MA, Foster C, Watson&#x2010;Lazowski A, Ghannoum O, Chen M. Comparative analysis of thylakoid protein complexes in the mesophyll and bundle sheath cells from C3 , C4 and C3 -C4 paniceae grasses. Physiol Plant. 2019;166:134&#x2013;47. https://doi.org/10.1111/ppl.12956.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hura T, Hura K, Ostrowska A, Gadzinowska J, Fiust A. Water stress-induced flag leaf senescence may be accelerated by rehydration. J Plant Physiol. 2019;236:109&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jplph.2019.01.013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi A, Fan J, Hu Z, Wang G, Amombo E, Fu J, et al. Differential acclimation of enzymatic antioxidant metabolism and photosystem II photochemistry in tall fescue under drought and heat and the combined stresses. Front Plant Sci. 2016;7. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2016.00453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T, Zhang H, Zeng R, Wang X, Huang L, Wang L, et al. Shade effects on peanut yield associate with physiological and expressional regulation on photosynthesis and sucrose metabolism. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:5284. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms21155284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bressan M, Bassi R, Dall&#x2019;Osto L. Light harvesting complex I is essential for photosystem II photoprotection under variable light conditions in arabidopsis thaliana. Environ Exp Bot. 2018;154:89&#x2013;98. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envexpbot.2018.03.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jan R, Kim N, Asaf S, Lubna, Asif S, Du XX, et al. OsCM regulates rice defence system in response to UV light supplemented with drought stress. Plant Biology. 2023;25:902-14. https://doi.org/10.1111/plb.13564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solymosi D, Nikkanen L, Muth-Pawlak D, Fitzpatrick D, Vasudevan R, Howe CJ, et al. Cytochrome c M decreases photosynthesis under photomixotrophy in synechocystis sp. PCC 6803. Plant Physiol. 2020;183:700&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1104/pp.20.00284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Liu Y, Jia Y, Yuan Z. Investigation into the mechanisms of photosynthetic regulation and adaptation under salt stress in lavender. Plant Physiol Biochem. 2025;219:109376. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plaphy.2024.109376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Deng L, Last RL, Hua W, Liu J. Psb28 protein is indispensable for stable accumulation of PSII core complexes in arabidopsis. Plant J. 2024;119:1226&#x2013;38. https://doi.org/10.1111/tpj.16844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen L, Ren F, Wang Y-C, Li Z, Zheng M, Li X, et al. Structure and function of a huge photosystem I&#x2013;fucoxanthin chlorophyll supercomplex from a coccolithophore. Science. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adv2132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y, Zhu Y, Cui Y, Qian H, Yuan Q, Chen R, et al. Identification of natural allelic variation in TTL1 controlling thermotolerance and grain size by a rice super pan-genome. J Integr Plant Biol. 2023;65:2541&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1111/jipb.13568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang G, Zhang H, Li X, Ai Q, Yu D. bHLH transcription factor bHLH115 regulates iron homeostasis in arabidopsis thaliana. J Exp Bot. 2017;68:1743&#x2013;55. https://doi.org/10.1093/jxb/erx043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karve R, Su&#xe1;rez-Rom&#xe1;n F, Iyer-Pascuzzi AS. The transcription factor NIN-LIKE PROTEIN7 controls border-like cell release. Plant Physiol. 2016;171:2101&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.1104/pp.16.00453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J-Y, Yang C, Xu J, Lu H-P, Liu J-X. The hot science in rice research: how rice plants cope with heat stress. Plant Cell Environ. 2023;46:1087&#x2013;103. https://doi.org/10.1111/pce.14509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Wang H, Kalve S, Wolabu TW, Nakashima J, Golz JF, et al. Control of leaf blade outgrowth and floral organ development by LEUNIG, ANGUSTIFOLIA3 and WOX transcriptional regulators. New Phytol. 2019;223:2024&#x2013;38. https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.15921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Tian B, Wang Y, Wang J, Zhang H, Wang L, et al. The transcription factor MYB37 positively regulates photosynthetic inhibition and oxidative damage in arabidopsis leaves under salt stress. Front Plant Sci. 2022. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2022.943153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng K, Hou X-L, Xing G-M, Liu J-X, Duan A-Q, Xu Z-S, et al. Advances in AP2/ERF super-family transcription factors in plant. Crit Rev Biotechnol. 2020;40:750&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.1080/07388551.2020.1768509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo A, Yang C, Yao Z-W, Zhang L-L, Ye H, Xu J-H, et al. Transcription factors ERF74/77/108/125 enhance thermotolerance in rice by regulating common and distinct heat-responsive gene expression. Plant Biotechnol J. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1111/pbi.70262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albanese P, Manfredi M, Re A, Marengo E, Saracco G, Pagliano C. Thylakoid proteome modulation in pea plants grown at different irradiances: quantitative proteomic profiling in a non&#x2010;model organism aided by transcriptomic data integration. Plant J. 2018;96:786&#x2013;800. https://doi.org/10.1111/tpj.14068.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Li J, Xiao T, Yu J, Zheng Y. Transcriptome and metabolome analysis of cycas bifida response to low-temperature stress. BMC Plant Biol. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12870-025-07602-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo JY, Choi HN, Ko KS, Fanata WID, Harmoko R, Kim SH, et al. IRE1 coordinates UPR and ERAD pathways to maintain protein homeostasis under ER stress in arabidopsis. Plant Physiol Biochem. 2025;228:110321. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plaphy.2025.110321.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>