<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41690952</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Safe formation scaling and motion planning for heterogeneous UAV-UGV teams in cluttered environments.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9127</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-37211-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Heterogeneous UAV-UGV formations offer significant potential for autonomous missions; however, achieving stable three-dimensional (3-D) formation control with collision-free navigation in dense obstacle environments remains challenging due to heterogeneous dynamics, unknown external disturbances, and strict real-time computational constraints. This paper proposes a distributed rigid graph-based adaptive safe artificial potential field (RG-ASAPF) framework that tightly integrates formation control and motion planning for heterogeneous multi-UAV-UGV systems. The proposed framework addresses three key challenges: (i) maintaining continuous formation integrity during obstacle avoidance, thereby avoiding the conventional disassembly-recovery process; (ii) enabling vertical coordination between UAV and UGV layers with prescribed inter-layer spacing; and (iii) supporting dynamic formation reconfiguration through time-varying scaling to safely navigate narrow passages. A backstepping-based adaptive formation controller is developed using rigid graph theory to enforce distance consensus under Euler-Lagrange dynamics, explicitly accounting for underactuated UAVs and nonholonomic UGVs. An adaptive safe artificial potential field with Widrow-Hoff-based online repulsion tuning generates smooth, collision-free trajectories while respecting formation footprint constraints. Rigorous Lyapunov analysis establishes exponential convergence of formation errors and global uniform ultimate boundedness (GUUB) of tracking errors in the presence of bounded disturbances. Furthermore, a safety-certified fallback mechanism with corridor-aware rerouting enhances robustness when clearance constraints are violated. Extensive simulations involving sparse and dense obstacle environments, formation scaling maneuvers, dynamic obstacles, and formation maneuvers featuring more agents demonstrate that the proposed framework outperforms model predictive control, particle swarm optimization, and conventional artificial potential field methods in terms of computational efficiency, trajectory smoothness, formation stability, and energy consumption. These results highlight the effectiveness of the proposed approach for heterogeneous multi-domain robotic applications such as disaster response, surveillance, and cooperative logistics.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Qian</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Business School, University of Shanghai for Science and Technology, Shanghai, 200093, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Industrial Internet of Things and Networked Control, Ministry of Education, Chongqing University of Posts and Telecommunications, Chongqing, 400065, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xiufeng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Technology, Management and Economics, Technical University of Denmark, 2800, Kongens Lyngby, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nie</LastName><ForeName>Wendi</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Industrial Internet of Things and Networked Control, Ministry of Education, Chongqing University of Posts and Telecommunications, Chongqing, 400065, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Haibing</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Shanghai University of Engineering Science, Shanghai, 201620, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pang</LastName><ForeName>Wen</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, University of Shanghai for Science and Technology, Shanghai, 200093, China. wpang0708@usst.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>62303325</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>23YF1429700</GrantID><Agency>Shanghai Science and Technology Innovation Action Plan Morning Star Project (Sail Special)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022FF06</GrantID><Agency>Open Fund Project of Key Laboratory of Industrial Internet of Things &amp; Networked Control of the Ministry of Education of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>GZC20231677</GrantID><Agency>Postdoctoral Fellowship Program of CPSF</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023M742372</GrantID><Agency>China Postdoctoral Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptive safe artificial potential field</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Graph theory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heterogeneous UAV&#x2013;UGV cooperation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Motion planning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Time-varying formation control</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41690952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12996549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-37211-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-37211-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dandapat, J., Gupta, N., Agarwal, S. &amp; Darshi, S. Service duration maximization for continuous coverage in UAV-assisted communication system. <i>IEEE Commun. Lett.</i><b>26</b>, 2445&#x2013;2449 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LCOMM.2022.3189692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodaverdian, M., Najafi, M., Kazemifar, O. &amp; Rahmanian, S. Fault-tolerant model predictive sliding mode control for trajectory replanning of multi-uav formation flight. <i>Appl. Math. Comput.</i><b>487</b>, 129073 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Q. et al. Robustly string stable longitudinal control for vehicle platoons under communication failures: A generalized extended state observer-based control approach. <i>IEEE Trans. Intell. Veh.</i><b>8</b>, 159&#x2013;171 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIV.2022.3153472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makavita, C. D., Jayasinghe, S. G., Nguyen, H. D. &amp; Ranmuthugala, D. Experimental comparison of two composite MRAC methods for UUV operations with low adaptation gains. <i>IEEE J. Ocean. Eng.</i><b>45</b>, 227&#x2013;246 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JOE.2018.2869508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, Z., Zhang, C., Xia, Y., Xiong, H. &amp; Shao, X. An improved artificial potential field method for path planning and formation control of the multi-UAV systems. <i>IEEE Trans. Circuits Syst. II: Express Briefs</i><b>69</b>, 1129&#x2013;1133 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, H. &amp; Chen, Y. Dynamic event-triggered distributed MPC for heterogeneous UAVs&#x2013;UGVs against DoS attacks. <i>IEEE Trans. Aerosp. Electron. Syst.</i><b>60</b>, 7931&#x2013;7944 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TAES.2024.3422158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J., Zhang, G., Shan, Q. &amp; Zhang, W. A novel cooperative design for USV&#x2013;UAV systems: 3-D mapping guidance and adaptive fuzzy control. <i>IEEE Trans. Control Netw. Syst.</i><b>10</b>, 564&#x2013;574 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCNS.2022.3220705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, J., Lin, J., Yang, X., Chen, C. &amp; Guan, X. Cooperation detection and tracking of underwater target via aerial-surface-underwater vehicles. <i>IEEE Trans. Autom. Control</i><b>70</b>, 1068&#x2013;1083 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TAC.2024.3447976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, W. et al. 3U: Joint design of UAV-USV-UUV networks for cooperative target hunting. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>72</b>, 4085&#x2013;4090 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2022.3220856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J., Zhang, X., Xin, B. &amp; Fang, H. Coordination between unmanned aerial and ground vehicles: A taxonomy and optimization perspective. <i>IEEE Trans. Cybernet.</i><b>46</b>, 959&#x2013;972 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCYB.2015.2418337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25898328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, Y., Jiang, B., Wang, J. &amp; Gong, J. Adaptive fault-tolerant formation control for heterogeneous UAVs-UGVs systems with multiple actuator faults. <i>IEEE Trans. Aerosp. Electron. Syst.</i><b>59</b>, 6705&#x2013;6716 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Liu, Y., Zhu, L. &amp; Guo, Y. Fault-tolerant formation control of heterogeneous multi-agent systems with unknown inputs and external disturbances. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 20773 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-07625-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12218570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40594605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue, Y. &amp; Chen, W. Multi-agent deep reinforcement learning for uavs navigation in unknown complex environment. <i>IEEE Trans. Intell. Veh.</i><b>9</b>, 2290&#x2013;2303 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIV.2023.3298292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju, C. &amp; Son, H. I. A hybrid systems-based hierarchical control architecture for heterogeneous field robot teams. <i>IEEE Trans. Cybernet.</i><b>53</b>, 1802&#x2013;1815 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCYB.2021.3133631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34936565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J. A consensus control for a multi-agent system with unknown time-varying communication delays. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>9</b>, 55844&#x2013;55852 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3070388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y., Xiao, Y. &amp; Li, T. A survey of autonomous underwater vehicle formation: Performance, formation control, and communication capability. <i>IEEE Commun. Surv. Tutor.</i><b>23</b>, 815&#x2013;841 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/COMST.2021.3059998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naderolasli, A., Shojaei, K. &amp; Chatraei, A. Leader-follower formation control of Euler-Lagrange systems with limited field-of-view and saturating actuators: A case study for tractor-trailer wheeled mobile robots. <i>Eur. J. Control</i><b>75</b>, 100903 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejcon.2023.100903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teli, T. A. &amp; Wani, M. A. A fuzzy based local minima avoidance path planning in autonomous robots. <i>Int. J. Inf. Technol.</i><b>13</b>, 33&#x2013;40 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, C., Huang, B. &amp; Fr&#xe4;nti, P. A review of motion planning algorithms for intelligent robots. <i>J. Intell. Manuf.</i><b>33</b>, 387&#x2013;424 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10845-021-01867-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghaderi, F., Toloei, A. &amp; Ghasemi, R. Formation control with obstacle avoidance for heterogeneous multi-flying robots: connectivity preservation. <i>Int. J. Aeronaut. Space Sci.</i><b>25</b>, 1050&#x2013;1066 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42405-024-00709-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le-Dung, N., Huynh-Lam, P., Hoang-Giap, N. &amp; Tan-Luy, N. Event-triggered distributed robust optimal control of nonholonomic mobile agents with obstacle avoidance formation, input constraints and external disturbances. <i>J. Franklin Inst.</i><b>360</b>, 5564&#x2013;5587 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfranklin.2023.02.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munasinghe, I., Perera, A. &amp; Deo, R. C. A comprehensive review of UAV&#x2013;UGV collaboration: Advancements and challenges. <i>J. Sensor Actuator Netw.</i><b>13</b>, 81 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jsan13060081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang, W., Zhu, D., Chu, Z. &amp; Chen, Q. Distributed adaptive formation reconfiguration control for multiple auvs based on affine transformation in three-dimensional ocean environments. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>72</b>, 7338&#x2013;7350 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2023.3242657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghommam, J. &amp; Saad, M. Adaptive leader-follower formation control of underactuated surface vessels under asymmetric range and bearing constraints. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>67</b>, 852&#x2013;865 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2017.2760367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, Z. et al. Robust output formation tracking for heterogeneous multiagent systems with multiple leaders: Theory and application. <i>IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron.</i>10.1109/TIE.2025.3589420 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2025.3589420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, W., Zhang, K. &amp; Jiang, B. Hierarchical structure-based fixed-time optimal fault-tolerant time-varying output formation control for heterogeneous multiagent systems. <i>IEEE Trans. Syst. Man Cybernet. Syst.</i><b>53</b>, 4856&#x2013;4866 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSMC.2023.3257426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedele, G., D&#x2019;Alfonso, L. &amp; Gazi, V. A generalized Gazi-Passino model with coordinate-coupling matrices for swarm formation with rotation behavior. <i>IEEE Trans. Control Netw. Syst.</i><b>9</b>, 1227&#x2013;1237 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCNS.2022.3141012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang, W., Zhu, D., Chu, Z. &amp; Chen, Q. Distributed adaptive formation reconfiguration control for multiple auvs based on affine transformation in three-dimensional ocean environments. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>72</b>, 7338&#x2013;7350 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2023.3242657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Huang, P., Zhang, F. &amp; Zhao, Y. Distributed formation control using artificial potentials and neural network for constrained multiagent systems. <i>IEEE Trans. Control Syst. Technol.</i><b>28</b>, 697&#x2013;704 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCST.2018.2884226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, T. et al. Digital twin-driven formation control of ROVs: An integral reinforcement learning-based solution. <i>IEEE Trans. Ind. Inform.</i><b>20</b>, 14277&#x2013;14286 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TII.2024.3449989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabelo, M. F. S., Brand&#xe3;o, A. S. &amp; Sarcinelli-Filho, M. Landing a UAV on static or moving platforms using a formation controller. <i>IEEE Syst. J.</i><b>15</b>, 37&#x2013;45 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSYST.2020.2975139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, W., Liu, H., Wan, Y. &amp; Lin, Z. Data-driven formation control for multiple heterogeneous vehicles in air-ground coordination. <i>IEEE Trans. Control Netw. Syst.</i><b>9</b>, 1851&#x2013;1862 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCNS.2022.3181254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, Y. et al. Cooperative fault-tolerant formation tracking control for heterogeneous air-ground systems using a learning-based method. <i>IEEE Trans. Aerosp. Electron. Syst.</i><b>60</b>, 1505&#x2013;1518 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TAES.2023.3336638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong, J., Jiang, B., Ma, Y. &amp; Mao, Z. Distributed adaptive fault-tolerant formation-containment control with prescribed performance for heterogeneous multiagent systems. <i>IEEE Trans. Cybernet.</i><b>53</b>, 7787&#x2013;7799 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCYB.2022.3218377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36355722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babazadeh, R. &amp; Selmic, R. R. Directed distance-based formation control of nonlinear heterogeneous agents in 3-D space. <i>IEEE Trans. Aerosp. Electron. Syst.</i><b>59</b>, 3405&#x2013;3415 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TAES.2022.3219039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maboudi, M. et al. A review on viewpoints and path planning for UAV-based 3-D reconstruction. <i>IEEE J. Sel. Top. Appl. Earth Observations Remote Sens.</i><b>16</b>, 5026&#x2013;5048 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSTARS.2023.3276427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Y. et al. A survey of trajectory planning methods for autonomous driving-part I: Unstructured scenarios. <i>IEEE Trans. Intell. Veh.</i><b>9</b>, 5407&#x2013;5434 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIV.2023.3337318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, R., He, B., Wang, Y., Ma, W. &amp; Yang, S. Recent advances in path planning for underwater gliders: A comprehensive review. <i>Ocean Eng.</i><b>299</b>, 117166 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oceaneng.2024.117166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gil, K., Yuk, J. &amp; Shin, J. Integrated path planning and control for autonomous vehicle platooning. <i>Control Eng. Pract.</i><b>164</b>, 106470 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conengprac.2025.106470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Q., Sun, D.J., Xia, J., Xiu, X. &amp; An, C. String stable and robust optimal longitudinal control for vehicle platoons: a finite time disturbance observer-based tube MPC. <i>Nonlinear Dyn</i>.<b>113</b>, 16593-16610 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zammit, C. &amp; van Kampen, E.-J. Real-time 3d uav path planning in dynamic environments with uncertainty. <i>Unmanned Syst.</i><b>11</b>, 203&#x2013;219 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S2301385023500073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, S., Hu, J., Bhowmick, P., Ding, Z. &amp; Arvin, F. Distributed motion planning for safe autonomous vehicle overtaking via artificial potential field. <i>Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst.</i><b>23</b>, 21531&#x2013;21547 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TITS.2022.3189741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu, G., Wu, L., Gao, Y. &amp; Pun, M. O. Unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV)-assisted path planning for unmanned ground vehicles (UGVs) via disciplined convex-concave programming. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>71</b>, 6996&#x2013;7007 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2022.3168574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding, Y., Xin, B., Dou, L., Chen, J. &amp; Chen, B. M. A memetic algorithm for curvature-constrained path planning of messenger UAV in air-ground coordination. <i>IEEE Trans. Autom. Sci. Eng.</i><b>19</b>, 3735&#x2013;3749 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TASE.2021.3135044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y., Wu, S. &amp; Hu, X. Cooperative path planning of UAVs &amp; UGVs for a persistent surveillance task in urban environments. <i>IEEE Internet Things J.</i><b>8</b>, 4906&#x2013;4919 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2020.3030240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacheti, V. P., Brand&#xe3;o, A. S. &amp; Sarcinelli-Filho, M. A path-following controller for a UAV&#x2013;UGV formation performing the final step of last-mile-delivery. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>9</b>, 142218&#x2013;142231 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3120347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adderson, R. &amp; Pan, Y. J. Continuously varying formation for heterogeneous multi-agent systems with novel potential field avoidance. <i>IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron.</i><b>72</b>, 1774&#x2013;1783 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2024.3429620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, B., Rao, Z., Gao, C., Yang, B. &amp; Wang, T. Methods for Formation Control and Path Planning for UAVs and UGVs Swarm. In<i>Proc. International Conference on Autonomous Unmanned Systems (4th ICAUS 2024)</i>, 114&#x2013;124 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y., Liang, T., Gou, J., Tao, C. &amp; Wang, H. Heterogeneous mission planning for multiple UAV formations via metaheuristic algorithms. <i>IEEE Trans. Aerosp. Electron. Syst.</i><b>59</b>, 3924&#x2013;3940 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TAES.2023.3234455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, B., Ni, J., Zhong, Y., Yu, D. &amp; Wang, Z. Collision-free formation control for heterogeneous multiagent systems under DoS attacks. <i>IEEE Trans. Cybernet.</i><b>54</b>, 6244&#x2013;6255 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCYB.2024.3418973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39052460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong, S.-X., Xie, X.-P. &amp; Jiang, G.-P. Fully distributed optimal tracking control for UAV&#x2013;UGV formation against Byzantine attacks. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>74</b>, 14707&#x2013;14719 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2025.3565765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Q., Lu, X., Wang, Y. &amp; Wei, Y. A hierarchical cross-domain formation strategy for heterogeneous UGV&#x2013;UAVs with uncertainties. <i>IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron.</i>10.1109/TIE.2025.3594438 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2025.3594438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, L., Xiao, J., Teo, C. W. R., Li, J. &amp; Feroskhan, M. Air-ground collaborative control for angle-specified heterogeneous formations. <i>IEEE Trans. Intell. Veh.</i><b>10</b>, 1483&#x2013;1497 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIV.2024.3420408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Rozas, S., Alejo, D., Caballero, F. &amp; Merino, L. Path and trajectory planning of a tethered UAV&#x2013;UGV marsupial robotic system. <i>IEEE Robot. Autom. Lett.</i><b>8</b>, 6475&#x2013;6482 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LRA.2023.3301292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian, L., Wang, X. &amp; Chen, H. Heterogeneous formation tracking for fixed-wing UAVs and nonholonomic UGVs with different asymmetric constraints. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>74</b>, 13350&#x2013;13360 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2025.3558892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X., Wen, C. &amp; Chen, C. Adaptive formation control of networked robotic systems with bearing-only measurements. <i>IEEE Trans. Cybernet.</i><b>51</b>, 199&#x2013;209 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCYB.2020.2978981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32217493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang, W., Zhu, D. &amp; Sun, C. Multi-AUV formation reconfiguration obstacle avoidance algorithm based on affine transformation and improved artificial potential field under ocean currents disturbance. <i>IEEE Trans. Autom. Sci. Eng.</i><b>21</b>, 1469&#x2013;1487 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TASE.2023.3245818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, B. S. &amp; Yoo, S. J. Time-varying formation control with moving obstacle avoidance for input-saturated quadrotors with external disturbances. <i>IEEE Trans. Syst. Man Cybernet. Syst.</i><b>54</b>, 3270&#x2013;3282 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSMC.2024.3358345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramazani, S., Selmic, R. &amp; de Queiroz, M. Rigidity-based multiagent layered formation control. <i>IEEE Trans. Cybernet.</i><b>47</b>, 1902&#x2013;1913 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCYB.2016.2568164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27249843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, X. &amp; Queiroz, M. Adaptive rigidity-based formation control for multirobotic vehicles with dynamics. <i>IEEE Trans. Control Syst. Technol.</i><b>23</b>, 389&#x2013;396 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCST.2014.2321664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil, H. K. <i>Nonlinear Systems</i> (Prentice Hall, 2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge, S. S. &amp; Cui, Y. J. New potential functions for mobile robot path planning. <i>IEEE Trans. Robot. Autom.</i><b>16</b>, 615&#x2013;620 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/70.880813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szczepanski, R. Safe artificial potential field-novel local path planning algorithm maintaining safe distance from obstacles. <i>IEEE Robot. Autom. Lett.</i><b>8</b>, 4823&#x2013;4830 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LRA.2023.3290819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, Z., Liu, J. &amp; Shimamoto, S. Traffic-aware energy optimizing strategies for multi-cell coordinated green cellular networks. <i>IEEE Trans. Green Commun. Netw.</i><b>2</b>, 418&#x2013;431 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TGCN.2018.2807795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>