<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41826682</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Improved muscle recovery after omega-3 supplementation is associated with increased oxylipin availability.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-44339-1</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miranda-Fuentes</LastName><ForeName>Claudia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences Institute, Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, School of Physical Therapy, Universidad Andres Bello, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rehbein</LastName><ForeName>Carlos O</ForeName><Initials>CO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Optimization and Rehabilitation Laboratory, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Mansfield, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campos</LastName><ForeName>Cristian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences Institute, Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, School of Physical Therapy, Universidad Andres Bello, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toporowicz</LastName><ForeName>Yael</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences Institute, Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, School of Physical Therapy, Universidad Andres Bello, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arredondo</LastName><ForeName>Joseline</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences Institute, Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, School of Physical Therapy, Universidad Andres Bello, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gutierrez</LastName><ForeName>Sebasti&#xe1;n</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences Institute, Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, School of Physical Therapy, Universidad Andres Bello, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nu&#xf1;ez</LastName><ForeName>Oscar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences Institute, Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, School of Physical Therapy, Universidad Andres Bello, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uribe-Cerda</LastName><ForeName>Sofia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences Institute, Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, School of Physical Therapy, Universidad Andres Bello, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castillo</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cl&#xed;nica de la Universidad de los Andes, Universidad de los Andes, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diaz-Le&#xf3;n</LastName><ForeName>Mat&#xed;as</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Ciencias de la Salud, Universidad de O'Higgins, Rancagua, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quintero-Soto</LastName><ForeName>Delia</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Ciencias de la Salud, Universidad de O'Higgins, Rancagua, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Del Canto-Cruz</LastName><ForeName>Antonia</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Ciencias de la Salud, Universidad de O'Higgins, Rancagua, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Winter</LastName><ForeName>Tanja</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Food and Human Nutritional Sciences, Canadian Centre for Agri-Food Research in Health and Medicine, University of Manitoba, St Boniface Hospital Albrechtsen Research Centre, Winnipeg, MB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Far&#xed;as</LastName><ForeName>Camila</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Faculty of Medicine, University of Chile, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krause</LastName><ForeName>Bernardo J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Ciencias de la Salud, Universidad de O'Higgins, Rancagua, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valenzuela</LastName><ForeName>Rodrigo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Faculty of Medicine, University of Chile, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aukema</LastName><ForeName>Harold M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Food and Human Nutritional Sciences, Canadian Centre for Agri-Food Research in Health and Medicine, University of Manitoba, St Boniface Hospital Albrechtsen Research Centre, Winnipeg, MB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valladares-Ide</LastName><ForeName>Denisse</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Ciencias de la Salud, Universidad de O'Higgins, Rancagua, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pe&#xf1;ailillo</LastName><ForeName>Luis</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences Institute, Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, School of Physical Therapy, Universidad Andres Bello, Santiago, Chile. luis.penailillo@unab.cl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jannas-Vela</LastName><ForeName>Sebasti&#xe1;n</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Ciencias de la Salud, Universidad de O'Higgins, Rancagua, Chile. sebastian.jannas@uoh.cl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>1241959</GrantID><Agency>Fondo Nacional de Desarrollo Cient&#xed;fico y Tecnol&#xf3;gico</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>1211962</GrantID><Agency>Fondo Nacional de Desarrollo Cient&#xed;fico y Tecnol&#xf3;gico</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>11220333</GrantID><Agency>Fondo Nacional de Desarrollo Cient&#xed;fico y Tecnol&#xf3;gico</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise-induced muscle damage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxylipins</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Specialized pro-resolving mediators</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41826682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-44339-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-44339-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Clarkson, P. M. &amp; Hubal, M. J. Exercise-induced muscle damage in humans. Am. J. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 81, S52-69 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owens, D. J., Twist, C., Cobley, J. N., Howatson, G. &amp; Close, G. L. Exercise-induced muscle damage: What is it, what causes it and what are the nutritional solutions?. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 19, 71&#x2013;85 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;ailillo, L., Blazevich, A. J., Numazawa, H. &amp; Nosaka, K. Metabolic and muscle damage profiles of concentric versus repeated eccentric cycling. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 45, 1773&#x2013;81 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quindry, J. et al. Muscle-fiber type and blood oxidative stress after eccentric exercise. Int. J. Sport Nutr. Exerc. Metab. 21, 462&#x2013;470 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwiete, C., Roth, C., Mester, J., Broich, H. &amp; Behringer, M. Overlaps of skeletal muscle fatigue and skeletal muscle damage: The muscle injury continuum. Sports Med. 11, 73 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jannas-Vela, S. et al. The role of omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids and their lipid mediators on skeletal muscle regeneration: A narrative review. Nutrients https://doi.org/10.3390/nu15040871 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Souza, L. C., Moris, J. M., Gordon, P. M., Heileson, J. L. &amp; Funderburk, L. K. From fish oil to resolution: A narrative review on the potential of SPM-enriched marine oil for exercise-induced muscle damage recovery. Nutrients 17, 2014 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barquilha, G. et al. Fish oil supplementation improves the repeated-bout effect and redox balance in 20-30-Year-old men submitted to strength training. Nutrients 15, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyriakidou, Y., Wood, C., Ferrier, C., Dolci, A. &amp; Elliott, B. The effect of omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acid supplementation on exercise-induced muscle damage. J. Int. Soc. Sports Nutr. 18, 9 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanDusseldorp, T. A. et al. Impact of varying dosages of fish oil on recovery and soreness following eccentric exercise. Nutrients 12, (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchiya, Y., Yanagimoto, K., Nakazato, K., Hayamizu, K. &amp; Ochi, E. Eicosapentaenoic and docosahexaenoic acids-rich fish oil supplementation attenuates strength loss and limited joint range of motion after eccentric contractions: A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group trial. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 116, 1179&#x2013;1188 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jouris, K. B., McDaniel, J. L. &amp; Weiss, E. P. The effect of omega-3 fatty acid supplementation on the inflammatory response to eccentric strength exercise. J. Sports Sci. Med. 10, 432&#x2013;438 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heileson, J. L. et al. Long-chain omega-3 fatty acid supplementation and exercise-induced muscle damage: EPA or DHA?. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 56, 476&#x2013;485 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackay, J. et al. Fish oil supplementation fails to modulate indices of muscle damage and muscle repair during acute recovery from eccentric exercise in trained young males. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 23, 1666&#x2013;1676 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiLorenzo, F. M., Drager, C. J. &amp; Rankin, J. W. Docosahexaenoic acid affects markers of inflammation and muscle damage after eccentric exercise. J. Strength Cond. Res. 28, 2768&#x2013;2774 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray, P., Chappell, A., Jenkinson, A. M. E., Thies, F. &amp; Gray, S. R. Fish oil supplementation reduces markers of oxidative stress but not muscle soreness after eccentric exercise. Int. J. Sport Nutr. Exerc. Metab. 24, 206&#x2013;214 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenn, J. et al. The effects of fish oil and isoflavones on delayed onset muscle soreness. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 34, 1605&#x2013;1613 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthony, R., Macartney, M. J. &amp; Peoples, G. E. The influence of long-chain omega-3 fatty acids on eccentric exercise-induced delayed muscle soreness: Reported outcomes are compromised by study design issues. Int. J. Sport Nutr. Exerc. Metab. 31, 143&#x2013;153 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlory, C. et al. Omega-3 fatty acid supplementation attenuates skeletal muscle disuse atrophy during two weeks of unilateral leg immobilization in healthy young women. FASEB J. 33, 4586&#x2013;4597 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerling, C. J. et al. Incorporation of omega-3 fatty acids into human skeletal muscle sarcolemmal and mitochondrial membranes following 12 weeks of fish oil supplementation. Front. Physiol. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2019.00348 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson, A. C., Chalil, A., Aristizabal Henao, J. J., Streit, I. T. &amp; Stark, K. D. Omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acid blood biomarkers increase linearly in men and women after tightly controlled intakes of 0.25, 0.5, and 1 g/d of EPA + DHA. Nutr. Res. 35, 1040&#x2013;1051 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlory, C., Calder, P. C. &amp; Nunes, E. A. The influence of Omega-3 fatty acids on skeletal muscle protein turnover in health, disuse, and disease. Front. Nutr. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2019.00144 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tartibian, B., Maleki, B. H. &amp; Abbasi, A. Omega-3 fatty acids supplementation attenuates inflammatory markers after eccentric exercise in untrained men. Clin. J. Sport Med. Off J. Can. Acad. Sport Med. 21, 131&#x2013;137 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhan, C. N. et al. Expert consensus report on lipid mediators: Role in resolution of inflammation and muscle preservation. FASEB J. 38, e23699 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieman, D. C. et al. Blueberry intake elevates post-exercise anti-inflammatory oxylipins: A randomized trial. Sci. Rep. 13, 11976 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markworth, J. F., Maddipati, K. R. &amp; Cameron-Smith, D. Emerging roles of pro-resolving lipid mediators in immunological and adaptive responses to exercise-induced muscle injury. Exerc. Immunol. Rev. 22, 110&#x2013;134 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbs, M., Leng, S., Devassy, J. G., Monirujjaman, M. &amp; Aukema, H. M. Advances in our understanding of oxylipins derived from dietary PUFAs. Adv. Nutr. 6, 513&#x2013;540 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy, B. D., Clish, C. B., Schmidt, B., Gronert, K. &amp; Serhan, C. N. Lipid mediator class switching during acute inflammation: Signals in resolution. Nat. Immunol. 2, 612&#x2013;619 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleh, R. N. M. et al. APOE genotype modifies the plasma oxylipin response to Omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acid supplementation in healthy individuals. Front. Nutr. 8, 723813 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbs, M., Zahradka, P., Taylor, C. G. &amp; Aukema, H. M. Time course and sex effects of &#x3b1;-linolenic acid-rich and DHA-rich supplements on human plasma oxylipins: A randomized double-blind crossover trial. J. Nutr. 151, 513&#x2013;522 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penner, A. L. et al. Oxylipin profiles and levels vary by skeletal muscle type, dietary fat and sex in young rats. Appl. Physiol. Nutr. Metab. 46, 1378&#x2013;1388 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stupka, N., Tarnopolsky, M. A., Yardley, N. J. &amp; Phillips, S. M. Cellular adaptation to repeated eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. J. Appl. Physiol. 91, 1669&#x2013;1678 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema, R. et al. Muscle length influence on rectus femoris damage and protective effect in knee extensor eccentric exercise. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 31, 597&#x2013;609 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalchat, E. et al. Appropriateness of indirect markers of muscle damage following lower limbs eccentric-biased exercises: A systematic review with meta-analysis. PLoS One 17, e0271233 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton, J. P. et al. Reliability of maximal muscle force and voluntary activation as markers of exercise-induced muscle damage. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 94, 541&#x2013;548 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-L&#xe1;zaro, D. et al. Omega-3 fatty acid supplementation on post-exercise inflammation, muscle damage, oxidative response, and sports performance in physically healthy adults-A systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Nutrients https://doi.org/10.3390/nu16132044 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake, J. M., Neubauer, O., Della Gatta, P. A. &amp; Nosaka, K. Muscle damage and inflammation during recovery from exercise. J. Appl. Physiol. 122, 559&#x2013;570 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka, K., Newton, M. &amp; Sacco, P. Delayed-onset muscle soreness does not reflect the magnitude of eccentric exercise&#x2010;induced muscle damage. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports. 12, 337&#x2013;346 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, T. C., Lin, M.-J., Chen, H.-L., Yu, H.-I. &amp; Nosaka, K. Contralateral repeated bout effect of the knee flexors. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 50, 542&#x2013;550 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, T. C., Chen, H.-L., Lin, M.-J., Yu, H.-I. &amp; Nosaka, K. Contralateral repeated bout effect of eccentric exercise of the elbow flexors. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 48, 2030&#x2013;2039 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markworth, J. F. et al. Resolvin D1 supports skeletal myofiber regeneration via actions on myeloid and muscle stem cells. JCI Insight 5(18), e137713 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klingel, S. L. et al. EPA and DHA have divergent effects on serum triglycerides and lipogenesis, but similar effects on lipoprotein lipase activity: A randomized controlled trial. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. https://doi.org/10.1093/ajcn/nqz234 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, M. et al. Characterization and biological effects of di-hydroxylated compounds deriving from the lipoxygenation of ALA. J. Lipid Res. 54, 2083&#x2013;2094 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egawa, D., Itoh, T. &amp; Yamamoto, K. Characterization of covalent bond formation between PPAR&#x3b3; and oxo-fatty acids. Bioconjug. Chem. 26, 690&#x2013;698 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy, R. C. Specialized pro-resolving mediators: Do they circulate in plasma?. J. Lipid Res. 56, 1641&#x2013;1642 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markworth, J. F. et al. Human inflammatory and resolving lipid mediator responses to resistance exercise and ibuprofen treatment. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 305, R1281-1296 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vella, L. et al. Intramuscular inflammatory and resolving lipid profile responses to an acute bout of resistance exercise in men. Physiol. Rep. 7, e14108 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurado-Fasoli, L. et al. Acute and long-term exercise differently modulate plasma levels of oxylipins, endocannabinoids, and their analogues in young sedentary adults: A sub-study and secondary analyses from the ACTIBATE randomized controlled-trial. EBioMedicine 85, 104313 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Signini, &#xc9;. F., Nieman, D. C., Silva, C. D., Sakaguchi, C. A. &amp; Catai, A. M. Oxylipin response to acute and chronic exercise: A systematic review. Metabolites 10, 264 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espino-Gonzalez, E. et al. Impaired skeletal muscle regeneration in diabetes: From cellular and molecular mechanisms to novel treatments. Cell Metab. 36, 1204&#x2013;1236 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hateley, C. et al. Multi-tissue profiling of oxylipins reveal a conserved up-regulation of epoxide:diol ratio that associates with white adipose tissue inflammation and liver steatosis in obesity. EBioMedicine 103, 105127 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchida, K. &amp; Sakiyama, N. 9-Hydroxyoctadecadienoic acid plays a crucial role in human skin photoaging. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 679, 75&#x2013;81 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanford, K. I. et al. 12,13-diHOME: An Exercise-Induced Lipokine that Increases Skeletal Muscle Fatty Acid Uptake. Cell. Metab. 27, 1111&#x2013;1120e3 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;ailillo, L., Blazevich, A. &amp; Nosaka, K. Energy expenditure and substrate oxidation during and after eccentric cycling. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 114, 805&#x2013;814 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuchardt, J. P. et al. Effect of DHA supplementation on oxylipin levels in plasma and immune cell stimulated blood. Prostaglandins Leukot. Essent. Fatty Acids 121, 76&#x2013;87 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. et al. Metabolomics revealed decreased level of omega-3 &lt;Emphasis Type=&#x201c;SmallCaps&#x201d;&gt;PUFA&lt;/Emphasis&gt; &#x2010;derived protective eicosanoids in pregnant women with pre&#x2010;eclampsia. Clin. Exp. Pharmacol. Physiol. 705&#x2013;710 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kundu, S. et al. Metabolic products of soluble epoxide hydrolase are essential for monocyte chemotaxis to MCP-1 in vitro and in vivo. J. Lipid Res. 436&#x2013;447 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen, G., Mikkelsen, U. R., Raastad, T. &amp; Peake, J. M. Leucocytes, cytokines and satellite cells: What role do they play in muscle damage and regeneration following eccentric exercise?. Exerc. Immunol. Rev. 42&#x2013;97 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brancaccio, P., Maffulli, N. &amp; Limongelli, F. M. Creatine kinase monitoring in sport medicine. Br. Med. Bull. 209&#x2013;230 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhurandhar, N. V. et al. Energy balance measurement: When something is not better than nothing. Int. J. Obes. 1109&#x2013;1113 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markus, I. et al. Age differences in recovery rate following an aerobic-based exercise protocol inducing muscle damage among amateur, male athletes. Front. Physiol. 916924 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes, J., Lamb, K. &amp; Twist, C. Exercise-induced muscle damage and recovery in young and middle-aged males with different resistance training experience. Sports 7, 132 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlory, C. et al. Temporal changes in human skeletal muscle and blood lipid composition with fish oil supplementation. Prostaglandins Leukot. Essent. Fatty Acids 199&#x2013;206 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth, M. Assessment of physical activity: An international perspective. Res. Q. Exerc. Sport 71, 114&#x2013;120 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beltz, N. M. et al. Graded exercise testing protocols for the determination of VO<sub>2</sub> max: historical perspectives, progress, and future considerations. J. Sports Med. https://doi.org/10.1155/2016/3968393 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Highton, J. M., Twist, C. &amp; Eston, R. G. The effects of exercise-induced muscle damage on agility and sprint running performance. J. Exerc. Sci. Fit. 7, 24&#x2013;30 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka, K. &amp; Clarkson, P. M. Muscle damage following repeated bouts of high force eccentric exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 27, 1263&#x2013;9 (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall, L. M. &amp; Murphy, R. C. Electrospray mass spectrometric analysis of 5-hydroperoxy and 5-hydroxyeicosatetraenoic acids generated by lipid peroxidation of red blood cell ghost phospholipids. J. Am. Soc. Mass Spectrom. 9, 527&#x2013;532 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferdouse, A., Leng, S., Winter, T. &amp; Aukema, H. M. Dietary n-6 and n-3 PUFA alter the free oxylipin profile differently in male and female rat hearts. Br. J. Nutr. 122, 252&#x2013;261 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bligh, E. G. &amp; Dyer, W. J. A rapid method of total lipid extraction and purification. Can. J. Biochem. Physiol. 37, 911&#x2013;917 (1959).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison, W. R. &amp; Smith, L. M. Preparation of fatty acid methyl esters and dimethylacetals from lipids with boron fluoride-methanol. J. Lipid Res. 5, 600&#x2013;608 (1964).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vega-Tapia, F., Pe&#xf1;aloza, E. &amp; Krause, B. J. Specific arterio-venous transcriptomic and ncRNA-RNA interactions in human umbilical endothelial cells: A meta-analysis. iScience 24, 102675 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause, B. J. et al. Maternal obesity and high leptin levels prime pro-inflammatory pathways in human cord blood leukocytes. Placenta 142, 75&#x2013;84 (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>