<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41660297</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2325-9671</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Orthopaedic journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Orthop J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Progressive Bilateral Alterations in Gait Biomechanics Within 2 Years After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23259671251386457</StartPage><MedlinePgn>23259671251386457</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23259671251386457</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/23259671251386457</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Bilateral gait biomechanics change over time after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction (ACLR) and have been suggested to contribute to the development of osteoarthritis. However, few studies have investigated the longitudinal changes in bilateral gait biomechanics in the same cohort within 24 months after ACLR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To evaluate the longitudinal changes in bilateral gait biomechanics compared with the healthy control cohort within 24 months after ACLR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Controlled laboratory study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 24 patients who underwent primary unilateral ACLR surgery with autologous hamstring tendon grafts and 24 matched healthy participants were included. Also, 3-dimensional knee gait and ground-reaction forces (GRF) information were collected at 3, 6, 12, and 24 months after ACLR. Linear mixed-effects models were used to assess the influence of time and limb in ACLR participants and their interaction effect on each variable of interest. Two-way analysis of variance was used to compare intergroup and interleg dependent variables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Three months after ACLR, most biomechanical parameters of the operated limb (peak knee extension angle [pKEA]; peak knee extension moment [pKEM]; peak knee flexion moment [pKFM]; and vertical ground-reaction force [vGRF]) were lower than both the contralateral limb and healthy controls, and gradually increased over time. By 24 months postoperation, the pKEA and the pKEM returned to normal levels. The operated limb showed significantly reduced pKEA and pKEM compared with contralateral and control groups at 3 and 6 months (all <i>P</i>&#x2264; .001), with no clinically meaningful differences at 12 and 24 months. pKFM analysis revealed significant between-group effects (ACLR group vs control group) without limb or interaction effects from 3 to 24 months, indicating bilateral compensatory reduction. Regarding vGRF, GRF_peak1 demonstrated bilateral compensatory reduction at 3 months (resolved by 6 months), while GRF_peak2 showed operated limb reduction at 3 months progressing to bilateral compensation at 6 months (resolved at 12 months). Notably, both vGRF parameters exhibited bilateral compensatory reductions again at 24 months postoperation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Three months after ACLR, sagittal plane biomechanical parameters of the operated knee (pKEA, pKFM, pKEM) and GRF_peak1/2 were significantly lower than those of controls, except pKFA, which showed no intergroup difference. Longitudinal analysis revealed partial recovery patterns: GRF_peak1 was normalized by 6 months, while GRF_peak2, pKEA, and pKEM reached control levels by 12 months. However, a secondary decline emerged at 24 months, with GRF_peak1/2 values again significantly lower than those of the controls, and the pKFM remained persistently lower than that of the controls throughout the 24-month follow-up. Early postoperative gait retraining and neuromuscular control training are recommended, with sustained interventions maintained for at least 24 months.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL RELEVANCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Bilateral gait retraining and neuromuscular control training are recommended as early as possible and should be maintained for at least 24 months after surgery.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Yiqun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4791-2264</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Peking University Third Hospital, Institute of Sports Medicine of Peking University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Sports Injuries, Engineering Research Center of Sports Trauma Treatment Technology and Devices, Ministry of Education, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Zhengye</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8711-9183</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Peking University Third Hospital, Institute of Sports Medicine of Peking University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Sports Injuries, Engineering Research Center of Sports Trauma Treatment Technology and Devices, Ministry of Education, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Mengting</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-9217-1957</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peking University School of Medicine, School of Clinical Medicine, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Hua</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9103-4796</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center of Clinical Epidemiology, Peking University Third Hospital, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Hongjie</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5300-4652</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Peking University Third Hospital, Institute of Sports Medicine of Peking University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Sports Injuries, Engineering Research Center of Sports Trauma Treatment Technology and Devices, Ministry of Education, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Si</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5980-5979</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Peking University Third Hospital, Institute of Sports Medicine of Peking University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Sports Injuries, Engineering Research Center of Sports Trauma Treatment Technology and Devices, Ministry of Education, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miao</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-8381-3292</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Peking University Third Hospital, Institute of Sports Medicine of Peking University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Sports Injuries, Engineering Research Center of Sports Trauma Treatment Technology and Devices, Ministry of Education, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Yuanyuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6179-521X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Peking University Third Hospital, Institute of Sports Medicine of Peking University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Sports Injuries, Engineering Research Center of Sports Trauma Treatment Technology and Devices, Ministry of Education, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jianing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1933-3043</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Peking University Third Hospital, Institute of Sports Medicine of Peking University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Sports Injuries, Engineering Research Center of Sports Trauma Treatment Technology and Devices, Ministry of Education, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Hongshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4965-1333</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Peking University Third Hospital, Institute of Sports Medicine of Peking University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Sports Injuries, Engineering Research Center of Sports Trauma Treatment Technology and Devices, Ministry of Education, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Shuang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9644-6434</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Peking University Third Hospital, Institute of Sports Medicine of Peking University, Beijing Key Laboratory of Sports Injuries, Engineering Research Center of Sports Trauma Treatment Technology and Devices, Ministry of Education, Beijing, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Orthop J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101620522</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2325-9671</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gait</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ground-reaction force</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee angle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee moment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>One or more of the authors has declared the following potential conflict of interest or source of funding: Financial support for this study was provided by the Beijing Municipal Natural Science Foundation (grant 7232354), the National Natural Science Foundation of China (82202821, 31900943), the Clinical Key Projects of Peking University Third Hospital (BYSY2022058), the Innovation and Transformation Fund Project of Peking University Third Hospital (HDCXZHKC2022219), the 2023 Medical Science Research Project of Hebei Province, precise injection of shoulder joint under ultrasonic guidance of platelet-rich plasma for rotator cuff injury (20230257), and the University-Industry Collaborative Education Program (230807186101349). AOSSM checks author disclosures against the Open Payments Database (OPD). AOSSM has not conducted an independent investigation on the OPD and disclaims any liability or responsibility relating thereto.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41660297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12881305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671251386457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_23259671251386457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Blackburn JT, Pietrosimone B, Harkey MS, Luc BA, Pamukoff DN. Quadriceps function and gait kinetics after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(9):1664-1670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27128669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackburn JT, Pietrosimone B, Spang JT, Goodwin JS, Johnston CD. Somatosensory function influences aberrant gait biomechanics following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Res. 2020;38(3):620-628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31608488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulgheroni P, Bulgheroni MV, Andrini L, Guffanti P, Giughello A. Gait patterns after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 1997;5(1):14-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9127848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis-Wilson HC, Pfeiffer SJ, Johnston CD, et al. Bilateral gait at 6 and 12 months post-anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction compared with controls. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52(4):785-794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7078064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31809411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erhart-Hledik JC, Chu CR, Asay JL, Andriacchi TP. Longitudinal changes in knee gait mechanics between 2 and 8 years after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Res. 2018;36(5):1478-1486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5889359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28984381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia SA, Brown SR, Koje M, Krishnan C, Palmieri-Smith RM. Gait asymmetries are exacerbated at faster walking speeds in individuals who have undergone acute anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Res. 2022;40(1):219-230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8651805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34101887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia SA, Pamukoff DN, Johnson AK, Palmieri-Smith RM. Joint and limb loading during gait in adults with ACL reconstruction: comparison between single-step and cumulative load metrics. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2023;55(9):1706-1716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10524219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37126038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgoulis AD, Ristanis S, Moraiti CO, et al. ACL injury and reconstruction: clinical related in vivo biomechanics. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2010;96(8)(suppl):S119-S128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21036116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetschius J, Hertel J, Saliba SA, Brockmeier SF, Hart JM. Gait biomechanics in anterior cruciate ligament-reconstructed knees at different time frames postsurgery. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018;50(11):2209-2216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29933346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong X, Jiang D, Wang YJ, et al. Second-look arthroscopic evaluation of chondral lesions after isolated anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: single- versus double-bundle reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41(10):2362-2367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23868525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart HF, Culvenor AG, Collins NJ, et al. Knee kinematics and joint moments during gait following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(10):597-612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26265562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail SA, Button K, Simic M, Van Deursen R, Pappas E. Three-dimensional kinematic and kinetic gait deviations in individuals with chronic anterior cruciate ligament deficient knee: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Biomech (Bristol, Avon). 2016;35:68-80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27132248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito N, Capin JJ, Khandha A, Buchanan TS, Snyder-Mackler L. Identifying gait pathology after ACL reconstruction using temporal characteristics of kinetics and electromyography. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2022;54(6):923-930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9117412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35184098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jerosch J, Prymka M. Knee joint proprioception in normal volunteers and patients with anterior cruciate ligament tears, taking special account of the effect of a knee bandage. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 1996;115(3-4):162-166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8861583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadaba MP, Ramakrishnan HK, Wootten ME. Measurement of lower extremity kinematics during level walking. J Orthop Res. 1990;8(3):383-392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2324857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur M, Ribeiro DC, Theis JC, Webster KE, Sole G. Movement patterns of the knee during gait following ACL reconstruction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2016;46(12):1869-1895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26936269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DK, Park G, Kadir K, Kuo LT, Park WH. Comparison of knee stability, strength deficits, and functional score in primary and revision anterior cruciate ligament reconstructed knees. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):9186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6003945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29907841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knoll Z, Kocsis L, Kiss RM. Gait patterns before and after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2004;12(1):7-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14586491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konishi Y, Fukubayashi T, Takeshita D. Mechanism of quadriceps femoris muscle weakness in patients with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2002;12(6):371-375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12453165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosy JD, Mandalia VI. Anterior cruciate ligament mechanoreceptors and their potential importance in remnant-preserving reconstruction: a review of basic science and clinical findings. J Knee Surg. 2018;31(8):736-746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29228403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki R, Korakakis V, King E, et al. Aspetar clinical practice guideline on rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(9):500-514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11785408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36731908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z. Efficacy of repair for ACL injury: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Sports Med. 2022;43(13):1071-1083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9713465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35100655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisee C, Lepley AS, Birchmeier T, O&#x2019;Hagan K, Kuenze C. Quadriceps strength and volitional activation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Health. 2019;11(2):163-179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6391557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30638441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao X, Huang HS, Hu XQ, et al. [Changes of electroencephalography power spectrum during joint position perception test after anterior cruciate ligament rupture]. Beijing Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban. 2021;53(5):871-876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8517662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34650287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrosimone B, Loeser RF, Blackburn JT, et al. Biochemical markers of cartilage metabolism are associated with walking biomechanics 6 months following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Res. 2017;35(10):2288-2297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5540809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28150869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrosimone B, Seeley MK, Johnston C, et al. Walking ground reaction force post-ACL reconstruction: analysis of time and symptoms. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(2):246-254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6335151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30157111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren S, Liang Z, Zhang S, et al. Correlation of isokinetic thigh muscle asymmetry with gait asymmetry at one year after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Chin J Traumatol. 2022;25(6):592-599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren S, Yu Y, Shi H, et al. Three dimensional knee kinematics and kinetics in ACL-deficient patients with and without medial meniscus posterior horn tear during level walking. Gait Posture. 2018;66:26-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30142451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts D, Frid&#xe9;n T, Stomberg A, Lindstrand A, Moritz U. Bilateral proprioceptive defects in patients with a unilateral anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a comparison between patients and healthy individuals. J Orthop Res. 2000;18(4):565-571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11052492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roewer BD, Di Stasi SL, Snyder-Mackler L. Quadriceps strength and weight acceptance strategies continue to improve two years after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Biomech. 2011;44(10):1948-1953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3124616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21592482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi H, Ren S, Huang H, et al. Bilateral alterations in isokinetic strength and knee biomechanics during side-cutting 1 year after unilateral ACL reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2022;50(11):2961-2971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35914270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi H, Ren S, Miao X, et al. The effect of cognitive loading on the lower extremity movement coordination variability in patients with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Gait Posture. 2021;84:141-147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33321410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slater LV, Hart JM, Kelly AR, Kuenze CM. Progressive changes in walking kinematics and kinetics after anterior cruciate ligament injury and reconstruction: a review and meta-analysis. J Athl Train. 2017;52(9):847-860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5634233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28985125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suner Keklik S, G&#xfc;zel N, &#xc7;obano&#x11f;lu G, et al. Evaluation of proprioception in patients who underwent ACL reconstruction: measurement in functional position. Turk J Med Sci. 2021;51(4):2036-2042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8569732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33957722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Melick N, van Cingel RE, Brooijmans F, et al. Evidence-based clinical practice update: practice guidelines for anterior cruciate ligament rehabilitation based on a systematic review and multidisciplinary consensus. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(24):1506-1515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27539507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LJ, Zeng N, Yan ZP, Li JT, Ni GX. Post-traumatic osteoarthritis following ACL injury. Arthritis Res Ther. 2020;22(1):57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32209130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, McClelland JA, Palazzolo SE, Santamaria LJ, Feller JA. Gender differences in the knee adduction moment after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Br J Sports Med. 2012;46(5):355-359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21508075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams JR, Neal K, Alfayyadh A, et al. Patellofemoral contact forces and knee gait mechanics 3 months after ACL reconstruction are associated with cartilage degradation 24 months after surgery. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2023;31(1):96-105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9771964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36252943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>