<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41824863</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>105</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dysphagia rehabilitation methods using kinesiology taping: A systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e47929</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e47929</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e47929</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000047929</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Kinesiology taping (KT) has recently been reported as a novel therapeutic method for improving swallowing function. However, the clinical evidence supporting use of KT in dysphagia rehabilitation remains unclear. This study aimed to systematically review the clinical studies on applying KT in dysphagia rehabilitation and application guidelines.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This systematic review conducted a literature search across 4 databases to identify relevant studies published on using KT in swallowing rehabilitation between 2010 and 2023. A total of 14 studies were selected based on the type of KT intervention, outcome measures, and critical findings. These studies were then organized according to patient, intervention, comparison, and outcome (PICO), and methodological quality was assessed using the Downs and Black checklist.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">This review included 14 articles, comprising 8 randomized controlled trials, 5 one-group pre-post, and 1 case study. KT was applied to the orbicularis oris and masseter muscles in the oral phase, as well as the suprahyoid and infrahyoid muscles in the pharyngeal phase, to improve swallowing function. Findings indicated increased activation of the suprahyoid muscle, improved sucking and lip-closure function, decreased drooling, increased movement of the larynx during swallowing, decreased airway aspiration, and improved quality of life related to swallowing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Dysphagia rehabilitation utilizing KT presents a promising novel therapeutic approach expected to positively impact the recovery of larynx movement, muscle activity, muscle hypertrophy, and swallowing function.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shim</LastName><ForeName>Sun-Hwa</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Therapy, College of Medical Science, Jeonju University, Jeonju, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheon</LastName><ForeName>Hye-Won</ForeName><Initials>HW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dental Hygiene, College of Health Science, Howon University, Gunsan, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Jong-Bae</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5778-5257</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Therapy, Chosun University, Gwangju, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoon</LastName><ForeName>Tae-Hyung</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-8387-2835</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Therapy, Dongseo University, Busan, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>This research was supported by the Regional Innovation System &amp; Education(RISE) program through the (Gwangju RISE Center), funded by the Ministry of Education(MOE) and the (Gwangju Metropolitan City), Republic of Korea. 2025-RISE-05-013</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003680" MajorTopicYN="Y">Deglutition Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055052" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Tape</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003679" MajorTopicYN="N">Deglutition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018953" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kinesiology, Applied</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dysphagia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kinesiology taping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">swallowing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41824863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12991612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000047929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202603130-00060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Robertson J, Chadwick D, Baines S, Emerson E, Hatton C. People with intellectual disabilities and dysphagia. Disabil Rehabil. 2018;40:1345&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28286961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logemann JA, Kahrilas PJ, Cheng J, et al. Closure mechanisms of laryngeal vestibule during swallow. Am J Physiol. 1992;262(2 Pt 1):G338&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1539666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silbergleit AK, Schultz L, Jacobson BH, Beardsley T, Johnson AF. The dysphagia handicap index: development and validation. Dysphagia. 2012;27:46&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21424584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JS, Oh DH, Hwang NK, Lee JH. Effects of neuromuscular electrical stimulation combined with effortful swallowing on post-stroke oropharyngeal dysphagia: a randomised controlled trial. J Oral Rehabil. 2016;43:426&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26969528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo HS, Park SH, Jung MY, Yoo EY, Park JH. The effects of cranio-cervical flexion on activation of swallowing-related muscles. J Oral Rehabil. 2012;39:805&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22816736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JS, Jung YJ, Kim HH, Lee G. A novel method using kinesiology taping for the activation of suprahyoid muscles in healthy adults: a preliminary research. Dysphagia. 2020;35:636&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31620860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espi-Lopez GV, Serra-Ano P, Cobo-Pascual D, et al. Effects of taping and balance exercises on knee and lower extremity function in amateur soccer players: a randomized controlled trial. J Sport Rehabil. 2019;29:626&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31094640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang YC, Chang KH, Liou TH, Cheng CW, Lin LF, Huang SW. Effects of Kinesio taping for stroke patients with hemiplegic shoulder pain: a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled study. J Rehabil Med. 2017;49:208&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28233009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CL, Wu WT, Chang KV, Lin HY, Chou LW. Application of Kinesio Taping method for newborn swallowing difficultly: a case report and literature review. Medicine (Baltimore). 2016;95:e4458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4979834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27495080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toprak Celenay S, Kaya DO. Immediate effects of kinesio taping on pain and postural stability in patients with chronic low back pain. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2019;23:206&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30691754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Gramage J, Merino-Ramirez MA, Amer-Cuenca JJ, Lison JF. Effect of Kinesio Taping on gastrocnemius activity and ankle range of movement during gait in healthy adults: a randomized controlled trial. Phys Ther Sport. 2016;18:56&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25959707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung YJ, Kim HJ, Choi JB, Park JS, Hwang NK. Effect of dysphagia rehabilitation using kinesiology taping on oropharyngeal muscle hypertrophy in post-stroke patients: a double blind randomized placebo-controlled trial. Healthcare (Basel, Switzerland). 2020;8:411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7712247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33086705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho YS, Yoon TH, Park JS. Effects of suprahyoid muscle strengthening exercise using kinesiology taping on muscle activation and thickness in community-dwelling elderly: a randomized controlled trial. Medicine (Baltimore). 2023;102:e35166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10508572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37713858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HH, Park JS. Effects of effortful swallowing against kinesiology taping resistance on the swallowing function in patients with poststroke dysphagia: a randomized controlled trial. Medicine (Baltimore). 2024;103:e38344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11124620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38788044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heo SY, Kim KM. Immediate effects of Kinesio Taping on the movement of the hyoid bone and epiglottis during swallowing by stroke patients with dysphagia. J Phys Ther Sci. 2015;27:3355&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4681904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26696697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang JH, Oh HR, Gwak MJ, et al. The feasibility of kinesio taping as a self-administered bedside training method for improving laryngeal excursion in dysphagia: a prospective pilot study. J Int Acad Phys Ther Res. 2023;14:2788&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;elik TO, Borman P, Tayman C, Kavak&#xe7;i M, &#xc7;elebi F, Ya&#x15f;ar E. Effects of kinesiology taping on swallowing functions in newborns with swallowing difficulties: a randomized controlled pilot study. Rev Assoc Med Bras. 2023;69:e20230383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10561914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37820176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong JY, Oh DH, Park JS, Jung YJ. Effect of kinesiology taping on hyolaryngeal complex movement in stroke patient with dysphagia. J Int Acad Phys Ther Res. 2020;11:2052&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf6;yler AK, Arslan SS, Demir N, Kiylio&#x11f;lu N. Surface electromyographic activity of submental muscles during different types of swallow-specific tasks: a comparative study. J Oral Rehabil. 2023;50:580&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36932464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pervez R, Naz S, Babur N, Mumtaz N. Effects of kinesio taping compared with manipulation therapy on drooling and speech intelligibility in children with oral dysphagia: a pilot study. Altern Ther Health Med. 2022;28:48&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35180096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Choi HS, Kown YH. The effect of kinesiology taping on suprahyoid muscle acivity in community-dwelling elderly people. J Int Acad Phys Ther Res. 2021;12:2338&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee ML, Kim JU, Oh DH, Lee KJ. Effect of suprahyoid muscle resistance exercise using kinesio taping on suprahyoid muscle thickness in patients with dysphagia after subacute stroke. J Int Acad Phys Ther Res. 2020;11:2135&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;le&#xe7; A, Albayrak I, Erdur O, &#xd6;zt&#xfc;rk K, Levendoglu F. Effect of swallowing rehabilitation using traditional therapy, kinesiology taping and neuromuscular electrical stimulation on dysphagia in post-stroke patients: a randomized clinical trial. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2021;211:107020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34781221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akaltun MS, Umay E, Altindag O, Karaahmet OZ. Effectiveness of kinesiotape and sham kinesiotape application in children with cerebral palsy with dysphagia: a randomized controlled study. Turk J Phys Med Rehabil. 2023;69:434&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11099860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38766591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downs SH, Black N. The feasibility of creating a checklist for the assessment of the methodological quality both of randomised and non-randomised studies of health care interventions. J Epidemiol Commun Health. 1998;52:377&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1756728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9764259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andr&#xfd;skov&#xe1; A, Lee JH. The guidelines for application of kinesiology tape for prevention and treatment of sports injuries. Healthcare (Basel). 2020;8:144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32466467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Merletti R, Enoka RM. The extraction of neural strategies from the surface EMG. J Appl Physiol (Bethesda, Md. : 1985). 2004;96:1486&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15016793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rau G, Schulte E, Disselhorst-Klug C. From cell to movement: to what answers does EMG really contribute? J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2004;14:611&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15301779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheeler KM, Chiara T, Sapienza CM. Surface electromyographic activity of the submental muscles during swallow and expiratory pressure threshold training tasks. Dysphagia. 2007;22:108&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17294298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JS, Oh DH, Chang MY, Kim KM. Effects of expiratory muscle strength training on oropharyngeal dysphagia in subacute stroke patients: a randomised controlled trial. J Oral Rehabil. 2016;43:364&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26803525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>