<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41811648</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Redefining the Paradigm: Advancing Evidence-Based Return-to-Sport Criteria Following Isolated Posterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction: A Scoping Review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-026-02409-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Acute posterior cruciate ligament (PCL) injuries occur during high-impact sports including American Football, soccer, and skiing. While many of these injuries can be managed nonsurgically, surgery is necessary in some cases, particularly in cases of instability. Clear and standardized return-to-sport (RTS) criteria during rehabilitation following PCL reconstruction (PCL-R) are lacking.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This scoping review aims to identify and analyze existing RTS guidelines for PCL-R and propose improvements on the basis of frameworks from anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction, laying the groundwork for future research.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Following the PRISMA-ScR guidelines, studies were included if they evaluated RTS criteria after isolated PCL-R in adult athletes. The search strategy involved a three-step approach, including initially limited searches, keyword identification, and a final comprehensive search of five electronic databases (MEDLINE, Embase, CINAHL, SCOPUS, and PEDro). The inclusion criteria encompassed studies involving athletes aged&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;18 with isolated PCL-R. Exclusion criteria were studies involving multi-ligament injuries, revision surgeries, or nonEnglish publications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 13 studies met the inclusion criteria, reporting diverse RTS criteria. RTS timelines were mentioned in four studies (31%), generally ranging from less than 6 up to 12&#xa0;months. Clinical criteria, including range of motion (ROM) and pain, were reported in eight studies (63%). Full knee extension and near-complete flexion recovery were generally required before RTS, although specific flexion thresholds were not consistently defined. In addition, the absence of pain or the presence of only minimal pain was commonly expected before clearance. Strength assessments were included in five studies (38%), and were frequently assessed via isokinetic testing, with only one study adopting a limb symmetry index (LSI)&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;90% as a clearance criterion. Performance criteria, such as hop tests, were used in four studies (31%), often employing a LSI threshold of over 90%. Patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs) were assessed in 11 studies (85%). Scores such as the IKDC and Lysholm demonstrated significant postsurgical improvements, often exceeding 90 and 85, respectively, at the time of RTS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This review highlights the absence of standardized RTS criteria following PCL-R. Clinicians should consider integrating objective criteria when assessing RTS, including full ROM recovery, minimal or no pain, quadriceps and hamstring strength symmetry of&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;90% LSI, performance-based tests such as hop tests (commonly using an LSI&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;90%), and PROMs (e.g., IKDC&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;90, Lysholm&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;85).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tortoli</LastName><ForeName>Emanuele</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9470-4903</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Health Science "Vincenzo Tiberio", University of Molise, Campobasso, Italy. emanuele.tortoli@unimol.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gerini</LastName><ForeName>Alice</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>, Turin, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pellicciari</LastName><ForeName>Leonardo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9521-3759</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IRCCS Istituto delle Scienze Neurologiche di Bologna, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gokeler</LastName><ForeName>Alli</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6427-4225</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Neuroscience in Sports and Exercise, Institute of Sports Medicine, University of Paderborn, Paderborn, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Amsterdam University of Applied Science, Faculty Health, Amsterdam, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflicts of interest: There are no known conflicts of interest associated with this publication. Availability of data and materials: All authors guarantee that all data and materials support their published claims and comply with field standards.&#xa0;No datasets were generated for this scoping review and all data were obtained from previously published studies. Ethics approval: Not applicable. Author contributions: All authors contributed to the design, analyses, and reporting for this manuscript. Each author reviewed and approved the final submitted version of the manuscript. Consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Code availability: All data are reported in the manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41811648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-026-02409-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-026-02409-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lind M, Nielsen TG, Behrndtz K. Both isolated and multi-ligament posterior cruciate ligament reconstruction results in improved subjective outcome: results from the Danish Knee Ligament Reconstruction Registry. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2017. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00167-017-4577-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-017-4577-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28547586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders TL, Pareek A, Barrett IJ, et al. Incidence and long-term follow-up of isolated posterior cruciate ligament tears. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2017;25:3017&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26922055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-016-4052-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz MS, Russe K, Weiler A, et al. Epidemiology of posterior cruciate ligament injuries. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2003;123:186&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12734718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00402-002-0471-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owesen C, Sivertsen EA, Engebretsen L, et al. Patients with isolated PCL injuries improve from surgery as much as patients with ACL injuries after 2 years. Orthop J Sports Med. 2015;3:2325967115599539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26535391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4622308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967115599539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H-M, Cheng C-K, Liau J-J. Correlation between proprioception, muscle strength, knee laxity, and dynamic standing balance in patients with chronic anterior cruciate ligament deficiency. Knee. 2009;16:387&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19239988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2009.01.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavanaugh JT, Saldivar A, Marx RG. Postoperative rehabilitation after posterior cruciate ligament reconstruction and combined posterior cruciate ligament reconstruction-posterior lateral corner surgery. Oper Tech Sports Med. 2015;23:372&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.otsm.2015.08.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaquero-Picado A, Rodr&#xed;guez-Merch&#xe1;n EC. Isolated posterior cruciate ligament tears: an update of management. EFORT Open Rev. 2017;2:89&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28507781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5420825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/2058-5241.2.160009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundblad M, H&#xe4;gglund M, Thome&#xe9; C, et al. Epidemiological data on LCL and PCL injuries over 17 seasons in men&#x2019;s professional soccer: the UEFA Elite Club Injury Study. Open Access J Sports Med. 2020;11:105&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32494208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7231769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/OAJSM.S237997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedi A, Musahl V, Cowan JB. Management of posterior cruciate ligament injuries: an evidence-based review. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2016;24:277&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27097125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5435/JAAOS-D-14-00326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chahla J, Nitri M, Civitarese D, et al. Anatomic double-bundle posterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Arthrosc Tech. 2016;5:e149-156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27284530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4886264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eats.2015.10.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montgomery SR, Johnson JS, McAllister DR, et al. Surgical management of PCL injuries: indications, techniques, and outcomes. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2013;6:115&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23430587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3702782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12178-013-9162-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler PW, Zsidai B, Wagala NN, et al. Evolving evidence in the treatment of primary and recurrent posterior cruciate ligament injuries, part 2: surgical techniques, outcomes and rehabilitation. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2021;29:682&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33125531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-020-06337-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler PW, Hughes JD, Irrgang JJ, et al. Posterior cruciate ligament injuries: what do we really know? Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2021;29:669&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7917039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-020-06425-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker EH, Watson JD, Dreese JC. Investigation of multiligamentous knee injury patterns with associated injuries presenting at a level I trauma center. J Orthop Trauma. 2013;27:226&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22955332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BOT.0b013e318270def4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosgarea AJ, Jay PR. Posterior cruciate ligament injuries: evaluation and management. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2001;9:297&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11575909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5435/00124635-200109000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garofalo R, Jolles BM, Moretti B, et al. Double-bundle transtibial posterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with a tendon-patellar bone-semitendinosus tendon autograft: clinical results with a minimum of 2 years&#x2019; follow-up. Arthrosc J Arthrosc Relat Surg. 2006;22:1331-1338.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2006.08.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goudie EB, Will EM, Keating JF. Functional outcome following PCL and complex knee ligament reconstruction. Knee. 2010;17:230&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19796955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2009.08.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DW, Kim JG, Yang SJ, et al. Return to sports and clinical outcomes after arthroscopic anatomic posterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with remnant preservation. Arthrosc J Arthrosc Relat Surg. 2019;35:2658-2668.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2019.03.061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C-H, Chen W-J, Shih C-H. Arthroscopic reconstruction of the posterior cruciate ligament: a comparison of quadriceps tendon autograft and quadruple hamstring tendon graft. Arthrosc J Arthrosc Relat Surg. 2002;18:603&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/jars.2002.32208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C-H, Chen AC-Y, Yuan L-J, et al. Arthroscopic reconstruction of the posterior cruciate ligament by using a quadriceps tendon autograft: a minimum 5-year follow-up. Arthrosc J Arthrosc Relat Surg. 2007;23:420&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2006.12.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee BK, Nam SW. Rupture of posterior cruciate ligament: diagnosis and treatment principles. Knee Surg Relat Res. 2011;23:135&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22570824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3341837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5792/ksrr.2011.23.3.135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroven W, Vles G, Verhaegen J, et al. Operative management of isolated posterior cruciate ligament injuries improves stability and reduces the incidence of secondary osteoarthritis: a systematic review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2022;30:1733&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34505176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-021-06723-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owesen C, Sandven-Thrane S, Lind M, et al. Epidemiology of surgically treated posterior cruciate ligament injuries in Scandinavia. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2017;25:2384&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26387121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-015-3786-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Melick N, Van Cingel REH, Brooijmans F, et al. Evidence-based clinical practice update: practice guidelines for anterior cruciate ligament rehabilitation based on a systematic review and multidisciplinary consensus. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:1506&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27539507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logerstedt DS, Scalzitti D, Risberg MA, et al. Knee stability and movement coordination impairments: knee ligament sprain revision 2017: clinical practice guidelines linked to the international classification of functioning, disability and health from the orthopaedic section of the American Physical Therapy Association. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2017;47:A1&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29089004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2017.0303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senese M, Greenberg E, Todd Lawrence J, et al. Rehabilitation following isolated posterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a literature review of published protocols. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2018;13:737&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30140567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6088114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/ijspt20180737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters MDJ, Marnie C, Tricco AC, et al. Chapter 11: Scoping reviews (2020 version). In: Aromataris E, Munn Z, editors. JBI manual for evidence synthesis; JBI; 2020. https://doi.org/10.11124/JBIES-20-00167 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, et al. PRISMA extension for scoping reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169:467&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M18-0850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouzzani M, Hammady H, Fedorowicz Z, et al. Rayyan&#x2014;a web and mobile app for systematic reviews. Syst Rev. 2016;5:210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27919275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5139140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13643-016-0384-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, The PRISMA, et al. statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2020;2021:n71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A coefficient of agreement for nominal scales. Educ Psychol Meas. 1960;20:37&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/001316446002000104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutefnouchet T, Bentayeb M, Qadri Q, et al. Long-term outcomes following single-bundle transtibial arthroscopic posterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Int Orthop. 2013;37:337&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00264-012-1609-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermans S, Corten K, Bellemans J. Long-term results of isolated anterolateral bundle reconstructions of the posterior cruciate ligament: a 6- to 12-year follow-up study. Am J Sports Med. 2009;37:1499&#x2013;507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19451096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546509333479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C-J, Chen H-S, Huang T-W. Outcome of arthroscopic single bundle reconstruction for complete posterior cruciate ligament tear. Injury. 2003;34:747&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14519354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0020-1383(02)00197-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong T, Wang C-J, Weng L-H, et al. Functional outcomes of arthroscopic posterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: comparison of anteromedial and anterolateral trans-tibia approach. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2009;129:315&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19034466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00402-008-0787-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J, Xiaoqiao H, He Y, et al. Sandwich-style posterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Arthrosc J Arthrosc Relat Surg. 2008;24:650&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2008.01.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross MJ, Powell JF. Long-term followup of posterior cruciate ligament rupture: a study of 116 cases. Am J Sports Med. 1984;12:292&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6476188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/036354658401200409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu C-C, Yao H-I, Fan T-Y, et al. Twelve weeks of a staged balance and strength training program improves muscle strength, proprioception, and clinical function in patients with isolated posterior cruciate ligament injuries. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:12849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34886588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8657930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph182312849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipscomb AB, Anderson AF, Norwig ED, et al. Isolated posterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: long-term results. Am J Sports Med. 1993;21:490&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8368406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/036354659302100402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao S, Meng J, Zeng C, et al. Management of posterior cruciate ligament injuries: an expert consensus from 17 countries. Int J Surg Lond Engl. 2025;111:4080&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JS9.0000000000002416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kew ME, Cavanaugh JT, Elnemer WG, et al. Return to play after posterior cruciate ligament injuries. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2022;15:606&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36447081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9789230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12178-022-09794-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce CM, O&#x2019;Brien L, Griffin LW, et al. Posterior cruciate ligament tears: functional and postoperative rehabilitation. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2013;21:1071&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22484415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-012-1970-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montalvo AM, Shaefer H, Rodriguez B, et al. Retrospective injury epidemiology and risk factors for injury in CrossFit. J Sports Sci Med. 2017;16:53&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28344451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5358031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagelli CV, Hewett TE. Should return to sport be delayed until 2 years after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction? Biological and functional considerations. Sports Med Auckl NZ. 2017;47:221&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0584-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLean CL, Taunton JE, Clement DB, et al. Eccentric kinetic chain exercise as a conservative means of functionally rehabilitating chronic isolated insufficiency of the posterior cruciate ligament. Clin J Sport Med. 1999;9:142&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10512342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00042752-199907000-00005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dommelen BA, Fowler PJ. Anatomy of the posterior cruciate ligament. A review. Am J Sports Med. 1989;17:24&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2648873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/036354658901700104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escamilla RF. Knee biomechanics of the dynamic squat exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:127&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11194098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200101000-00020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesfar W, Shirazi-Adl A. Knee joint biomechanics in open-kinetic-chain flexion exercises. Clin Biomech Bristol Avon. 2008;23:477&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2007.11.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thome&#xe9; R. A comprehensive treatment approach for patellofemoral pain syndrome in young women. Phys Ther. 1997;77:1690&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9413448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/77.12.1690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirokawa S, Solomonow M, Lu Y, et al. Anterior-posterior and rotational displacement of the tibia elicited by quadriceps contraction. Am J Sports Med. 1992;20:299&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1636861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/036354659202000311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgi CR, Peters S, Ardern CL, et al. Which criteria are used to clear patients to return to sport after primary ACL reconstruction? A scoping review. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53:1154&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30712009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-099982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki A, Korakakis V, Graham-Smith P, et al. Vertical and horizontal hop performance: contributions of the hip, knee, and ankle. Sports Health Multidiscip Approach. 2021;13:128&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738120976363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki A, Van Rossom S, Whiteley R, et al. Single leg vertical jump performance identifies knee function deficits at return to sport after ACL reconstruction in male athletes. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56:490&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35135826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9016240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2021-104692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myer GD, Schmitt LC, Brent JL, et al. Utilization of modified NFL combine testing to identify functional deficits in athletes following ACL reconstruction. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2011;41:377&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21289456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3439811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2011.3547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelen-van Melick N, Van Cingel REH, Tijssen MPW, et al. Assessment of functional performance after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review of measurement procedures. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2013;21:869&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22581194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-012-2030-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abed V, Kapp S, Nichols M, et al. Lysholm and KOOS QoL demonstrate high responsiveness in patients undergoing anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Am J Sports Med. 2024;52:3161&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38352999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465231219966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyland J, Greene J, Carter S, et al. Return to sports bridge program improves outcomes, decreases ipsilateral knee re-injury and contralateral knee injury rates post-ACL reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2020;28:3676&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32699921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-020-06162-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabr A, Haddad FS. A comparison of preoperative scores prior to anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with optimal preinjury scores and final scores at two-year follow up. Bone Jt Open. 2023;4:46&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36692122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9887339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/2633-1462.41.BJO-2022-0090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Feller JA, Lambros C. Development and preliminary validation of a scale to measure the psychological impact of returning to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Phys Ther Sport. 2008;9:9&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19083699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2007.09.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suneja A, Deshpande SV, Wamborikar H, et al. Outcome analysis of posterior cruciate ligament injuries: a narrative review. Cureus. 2023. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.47410 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.47410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38226087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10788317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zech A, H&#xfc;bscher M, Vogt L, et al. Neuromuscular training for rehabilitation of sports injuries: a systematic review. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:1831&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19727032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181a3cf0d</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellis E, Mademli L, Patikas D, et al. Neuromuscular interactions around the knee in children, adults and elderly. World J Orthop. 2014;5:469&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25232523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4133453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5312/wjo.v5.i4.469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frid&#xe9;n T, Roberts D, Ageberg E, et al. Review of knee proprioception and the relation to extremity function after an anterior cruciate ligament rupture. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2001;31:567&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11665744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2001.31.10.567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#x105;czkowicz D. Assessment of neuromuscular control in patients after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Ortop Traumatol Rehabil. 2013;15:2&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5604/15093492.1058410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira HM, de Campos TF, Santos MB, et al. Influence of knee position on the postural stability index registered by the Biodex Stability System. Gait Posture. 2008;28:668&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18573663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2008.05.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myer GD, Ford KR, Palumbo JP, et al. Neuromuscular training improves performance and lower-extremity biomechanics in female athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19:51&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15705045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewett TE, Stroupe AL, Nance TA, et al. Plyometric training in female athletes. Decreased impact forces and increased hamstring torques. Am J Sports Med. 1996;24:765&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8947398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/036354659602400611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Glasgow P, Schneiders A, et al. 2016 consensus statement on return to sport from the First World Congress in Sports Physical Therapy, Bern. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:853&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27226389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devitt BM, Dissanayake R, Clair J, et al. Isolated posterior cruciate reconstruction results in improved functional outcome but low rates of return to preinjury level of sport: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Orthop J Sports Med. 2018;6:2325967118804478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30386804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6204629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967118804478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>