<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41664082</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Bile acid profiles reflect metabolic adaptability to rapid weight loss in boxers.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01462-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This exploratory pilot study investigated serum bile acids (BAs) as metabolic regulators in boxers, focusing on their dynamic responses to rapid weight loss (RWL) and recovery across different training levels. A developmental control group of young athletes served as a physiological reference.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Serum samples from 13 male boxers (5 elite, 8 national-level) and 10 young athletes were collected at baseline, post-RWL, and after 24&#xa0;h recovery. Targeted liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry (LC-MS/MS) quantified 82 BA species. Multivariate (OPLS-DA), univariate, and KEGG pathway analyses assessed phase- and level-dependent differences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Elite boxers showed higher baseline concentrations of conjugated and regulatory BAs (e.g., taurolithocholic acid [TLCA], glycohyocholic acid [GHCA]) and faster post-RWL restoration of BA balance. Non-elite athletes exhibited stronger shifts toward unconjugated secondary BAs (e.g., deoxycholic acid [DCA], lithocholic acid [LCA]) and incomplete recovery. Compared with young athletes, trained boxers displayed enhanced BA conjugation and FXR/TGR5-linked regulation. KEGG analysis indicated RWL-related disturbances in bile secretion and peroxisomal pathways, while elite profiles reflected greater hepatic-intestinal resilience.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">BA composition may serve as a biochemical marker of metabolic adaptability in combat athletes. Elite boxers maintained tighter BA homeostasis through weight cycles, whereas non-elite athletes exhibited transient hepatic stress. Findings are preliminary and should be interpreted cautiously due to small subgroup sizes and unstandardized diet and microbiome control.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Kun</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Psychology, Southwest University, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Mou</LastName><ForeName>Di</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xinjiang Research Center of Sports Science, Urumqi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Xiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Psychology, Southwest University, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Qingyuan</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xinjiang Research Center of Sports Science, Urumqi, China. xjtks_qingyuan@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2025D01B143</GrantID><Agency>Natural&#x2002;Science&#x2002;Foundation&#x2002;of&#x2002;Xinjiang&#x2002;Uygur&#x2002;Autonomous&#x2002;Region</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>KY2024095</GrantID><Agency>Basic operating funds for public welfare research institutions in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bile acids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Boxing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elite athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LC&#x2013;MS/MS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rapid weight loss</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval was obtained from the Ethics Committee of Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region Sports Scientific Research Center (Approval No. 20250428&#x2013;03). All participants provided written informed consent. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41664082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01462-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01462-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chaab&#xe8;ne H, Tabben M, Mkaouer B, et al. Amateur boxing: physical and physiological attributes. Sports Med. 2015;45(3):337&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco I, Bishop C, Ramirez-Campillo R, et al. Optimum power loads for elite boxers: case study with the Brazilian National Olympic Team. Sports. 2018;6(3):103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Laval I, Sitko S, Mu&#xf1;iz-Pardos B, Cirer-Sastre R, Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J. Relationship between bench press strength and punch performance in male professional boxers. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(2):308&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang L, Saunders C, Sanossian N. Food, gut barrier dysfunction, and related diseases: a new target for future individualized disease prevention and management. Food Sci Nutr. 2023;11(4):1671&#x2013;704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Fu B, Gao Y. Effects of simulated high-altitude living on low-altitude training on the exercise abilities of adolescent boxers. Sci Sports. 2024;39(4):384&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morville T, Sahl RE, Moritz T, Helge JW, Clemmensen C. Plasma metabolome profiling of resistance exercise and endurance exercise in humans. Cell Reports. 2020;33(6):108554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang JYL, Ferrell JM. Bile acids as metabolic regulators and nutrient sensors. Annu Rev Nutr. 2019;39:175&#x2013;200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang JYL, Ferrell JM. Bile acid receptors FXR and TGR5 signaling in fatty liver diseases and therapy. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2020;318(3):G554&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velazquez-Villegas LA, Perino A, Lemos V, et al. TGR5 signalling promotes mitochondrial fission and beige remodelling of white adipose tissue. Nat Commun. 2018;9(1):245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuchs CD, Simbrunner B, Baumgartner M, Campbell C, Reiberger T, Trauner M. Bile acid metabolism and signalling in liver disease. J Hepatol. 2025;82(1):134&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia W, Xie G, Jia W. Bile acid&#x2013;microbiota crosstalk in gastrointestinal inflammation and carcinogenesis. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2018;15(2):111&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang D, Chen X, Kang R, Kroemer G. Ferroptosis: molecular mechanisms and health implications. Cell Res. 2021;31(2):107&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X, Zhang Y, Zhang L, et al. Taurolithocholic acid protects against viral haemorrhagic fever via inhibition of ferroptosis. Nat Microbiol. 2024;9(10):2583&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop DJ, Botella J, Genders AJ, et al. High-intensity exercise and mitochondrial biogenesis: current controversies and future research directions. Physiology. 2019;34(1):56&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Chiang JYL. Bile acid signaling in metabolic disease and drug therapy. Pharmacol Rev. 2014;66(4):948&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xed;tek L, Haluz&#xed;k M. The role of bile acids in metabolic regulation. J Endocrinol. 2016;228(3):R85-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke SF, Murphy EF, O&#x2019;Sullivan O, et al. Exercise and associated dietary extremes impact on gut microbial diversity. Gut. 2014;63(12):1913&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;ger R, Mohr AE, Carpenter KC, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: probiotics.&#xa0;J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2019;16:62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakicevic N, Reale R, D&#x2019;Antona G, et al. Disturbing weight-cutting behaviors in young combat sports athletes: a cause for concern. Front Nutr. 2022;9:842262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Ca&#xf1;averas JC, Donato MT, Castell JV, Lahoz A. Targeted profiling of circulating and hepatic bile acids in human, mouse, and rat using a UPLC-MRM-MS-validated method. J Lipid Res. 2012;53(10):2231&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Bathena SPR, Csanaky IL, Alnouti Y. Simultaneous characterization of bile acids and their sulfate metabolites in mouse liver, plasma, bile, and urine using LC&#x2013;MS/MS. J Pharm Biomed Anal. 2011;55(5):1111&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>John C, Werner P, Worthmann A, et al. A liquid chromatography&#x2013;tandem mass spectrometry-based method for the simultaneous determination of hydroxy sterols and bile acids. J Chromatogr A. 2014;1371:184&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perwaiz S, Tuchweber B, Mignault D, Gilat T, Yousef IM. Determination of bile acids in biological fluids by LC&#x2013;ESI&#x2013;MS/MS. J Lipid Res. 2001;42(1):114&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyer P, Ranjan A, Chatterjee C. The role of TGR5 in metabolic regulation: implications for energy homeostasis and inflammation. J Endocrinol. 2010;207(2):161&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broadhurst D, Kell DB. Statistical strategies for avoiding false discoveries in metabolomics and related experiments. Metabolomics. 2006;2:171&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broadhurst DI, Goodacre R, Reinke SN, et al. &lt;article-title update="added"&gt;Guidelines and considerations for the use of system suitability and quality control samples in mass spectrometry assays applied in untargeted clinical metabolomic studies. Metabolomics. 2018;14(6):72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinken A, Ravcheev DA, Baldini F, et al. Systematic assessment of bile acid metabolism in the human gut microbiome reveals distinct metabolic phenotypes. Gut Microbes. 2019;10(3):311&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.1080/19490976.2018.1559685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahlstr&#xf6;m A, Sayin SI, Marschall HU, B&#xe4;ckhed F. Intestinal crosstalk between bile acids and microbiota and its impact on host metabolism. Cell Metab. 2016;24(1):41&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spicer R, Salek RM, Moreno P, Canueto D, Steinbeck C. Navigating freely available software tools for metabolomics analysis. Metabolomics. 2017;13:106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumner LW, Aharoni A, Barrett D, et al. Proposed minimum reporting standards for chemical analysis. Metabolomics. 2007;3:211&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velazquez H, Xu F, Ponzio T. TGR5 signaling and its role in metabolism and inflammation. Endocr Rev. 2018;39(4):187&#x2013;219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleishman JS, Kumar S. Bile acid metabolism and signaling in health and disease: molecular mechanisms and therapeutic targets. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2024;9(1):97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheffer DL, Latini A. Exercise-induced immune system response: anti-inflammatory status on peripheral and central organs. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta (BBA). 2020;1866(10):165823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jebabli N, Boujabli M, Mariem K, Ouerghi N, Bouassida AN, Abderrahman A, et al. Beta frequency binaural beats combined with preferred music enhance combat performance and recovery responses in amateur kickboxers: a randomized crossover trial. Front Psychol. 2025;16:1636856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noakes TD, Prins PJ, Volek JS, D&#x2019;Agostino DP, Koutnik AP. Low-carbohydrate high-fat ketogenic diets on the exercise crossover point and glucose homeostasis. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1150265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardig&#xf2; LP, Palermi S, Padulo J, Dhahbi W, Russo L, Linetti S, et al. External responsiveness of the SuperOp&#x2122; device to assess recovery after exercise: a pilot study. Front Sports Act Living. 2020;2:67.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>