<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41772710</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2050-2974</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of eating disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Eat Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Can methods that focus on eating behaviour and individual agency improve success rates in eating disorder recovery?</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">59</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40337-026-01537-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Success rates in eating disorder treatments are disappointing, and many calls have been made in recent research literature for innovative approaches to improve outcomes. This Comment article offers an argument for the importance of behaviour and agency in supporting eating disorder recovery, where behaviour encompasses eating and other everyday actions and habits and agency is an individual's capacity to set priorities and intentions, generate insights, draw conclusions, make decisions, and perform actions. Current treatments often deprioritize eating and other behaviours as well as individual agency for the patient/client, with lower importance often attributed to behavioural change than to physiological or psychological change. Reasons for deprioritizing behaviour may include beliefs about the therapeutic alliance, the intellectual appeal of psychological exploration, and the ready measurability of physiological factors. Reasons for deprioritizing personal agency may relate to an only partial shift away from the paternalistic model of medicine, influenced by the physical severity of EDs and by gender dynamics between clinician and client/patient. Drawing on principles and practices from solution-focused coaching and solution-focused brief therapy, we argue that low-agency forms of healthcare are likely to perform poorly in general, given the problematic effects that typically result from the giving and following of advice. Low-agency and low-behaviour approaches are also likely to work poorly for EDs in particular, thanks to both the centrality of eating behaviours and the fact that EDs are often experienced as initially egosyntonic exercises of personal agency. We describe how a high-agency-high-behaviour model of ED treatment could help improve recovery rates by scaffolding a process of progressive empowerment in which the affected individual identifies how personal agency has been lost in the experience of their ED and decides whether, why, and how they wish to reassert it. We survey existing applications of solution-focused methods in the ED domain and suggest ways of testing the proposed ideas. We conclude by sketching broader ways for the field to continue its evolution towards higher-behaviour and higher-agency methods, as part of a general shift to forms of healthcare that are truly responsive to the individual and firmly grounded in the realities of practical change.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Troscianko</LastName><ForeName>Emily</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Oxford, Oxford, UK. emily.troscianko@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leon</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of California, Irvine, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016422">Letter</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Eat Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610672</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-2974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Advice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Behaviour</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eating disorder treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Medical paternalism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Personal agency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Solution-focused brief therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Solution-focused coaching</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41772710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12952008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40337-026-01537-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40337-026-01537-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Westmoreland P, Mehler PS. Caring for patients with severe and enduring eating disorders (SEED): Certification, harm reduction, palliative care, and the question of futility. J Psychiatr Pract. 2016;22(4):313&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PRA.0000000000000160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27427843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downs J, Ayton A, Collins L, Baker S, Missen H, Ibrahim A. Untreatable or unable to treat? Creating more effective and accessible treatment for long-standing and severe eating disorders. Lancet Psychiatry. 2023;10(2):146&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(22)00400-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36697122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali Z, Couturier J. Psychopharmacology review for eating disorders among children, adolescents, and adults. Focus (Am psychiatr Publ). 2024 22:307&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11231477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38988472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank GK. Pharmacotherapeutic strategies for the treatment of anorexia nervosa&#x2013;too much for one drug? Expert Opin Pharmacother. 2020;21(9):1045&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14656566.2020.1748600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32281881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troscianko ET, Leon M. Treating eating: A dynamical systems model of eating disorders. Front Psychol. 2020;11:1801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.01801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7394184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32793079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Berg E, Houtzager L, de Vos J, Daemen I, Katsaragaki G, Karyotaki E, Cuijpers P, Dekker J. Meta-analysis on the efficacy of psychological treatments for anorexia nervosa. Eur Eat Disorders Rev. 2019;27(4):331&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/erv.2683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31124215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteleone AM, Pellegrino F, Croatto G, Carfagno M, Hilbert A, Treasure J, Wade T, Bulik CM, Zipfel S, Hay P, Schmidt U. Treatment of eating disorders: A systematic meta-review of meta-analyses and network meta-analyses. Neurosci Biobehavioral Reviews. 2022;142:104857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2022.104857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9813802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36084848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Boer K, Johnson C, Wade TD, Radunz M, Fernando AN, Babb J, Stafrace S, Sharp G. A systematic review and meta-analysis of intensive treatment options for adults with eating disorders. Clin Psychol Rev. 2023;26:102354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37926059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalsa SS, Portnoff LC, McCurdy-McKinnon D, Feusner JD. What happens after treatment? A systematic review of relapse, remission, and recovery in anorexia nervosa. J Eat Disorders. 2017;5:1&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5470198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28630708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keel PK, Dorer DJ, Franko DL, Jackson SC, Herzog DB. Postremission predictors of relapse in women with eating disorders. Am J Psychiatry. 2005;162(12):2263&#x2013;8. 10.1176/appi.ajp.162.12.2263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.162.12.2263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16330589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter JC, Mercer-Lynn KB, Norwood SJ, Bewell-Weiss CV, Crosby RD, Woodside DB, Olmsted MP. A prospective study of predictors of relapse in anorexia nervosa: implications for relapse prevention. Psychiatry Res. 2012;200:518&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2012.04.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22657951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sala M, Keshishian A, Song S, Moskowitz R, Bulik CM, Roos CR, Levinson CA. Predictors of relapse in eating disorders: A meta-analysis. J Psychiatr Res. 2023;158:281&#x2013;99. 10.1016/j.jpsychires.2023.01.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2023.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36623362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJong H, Broadbent H, Schmidt U. A systematic review of dropout from treatment in outpatients with anorexia nervosa. Int J Eat Disord. 2012;45(5):635&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eat.20956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22684990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinchenzo C, Lawrence V, McCombie C. Patient perspectives on premature termination of eating disorder treatment: A systematic review and qualitative synthesis. J Eat Disorders. 2022;10(1):39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40337-022-00568-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8928624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35296356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fassino S, Pier&#xf2; A, Tomba E, Abbate-Daga G. Factors associated with dropout from treatment for eating disorders: A comprehensive literature review. BMC Psychiatry. 2009;9:67. 10.1186/1471-244X-9-67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-244X-9-67</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2765944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19818137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubert T, Pioggiosi P, Huas C, Wallier J, Maria AS, Apfel A, Curt F, Falissard B, Godart N. Drop-out from adolescent and young adult inpatient treatment for anorexia nervosa. Psychiatry Res. 2013;209(3):632&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2013.03.034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23639255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linardon J, Hindle A, Brennan L. Dropout from cognitive-behavioral therapy for eating disorders: A meta&#x2010;analysis of randomized, controlled trials. Int J Eat Disord. 2018;51(5):381&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eat.22850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29493805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rienecke RD. Treatment dropout in a family-based partial hospitalization program for eating disorders. Eating and Weight Disorders-Studies on Anorexia. Bulimia Obes. 2019;24(1):163&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30027396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miskovic-Wheatley J, Bryant E, Ong SH, Vatter S, Le A, Touyz S, Maguire S. Eating disorder outcomes: Findings from a rapid review of over a decade of research. J Eat Disorders. 2023;11(1):85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40337-023-00801-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10228434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37254202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guinhut M, Godart N, Benadjaoud MA, Melchior JC, Hanachi M. Five-year mortality of severely malnourished patients with chronic anorexia nervosa admitted to a medical unit. Acta Psychiatrica Scandinavica. 2021;143(2):130&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acps.13261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33247947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hoeken D, Hoek HW. Review of the burden of eating disorders: mortality, disability, costs, quality of life, and family burden. Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2020;33(6):521&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/YCO.0000000000000641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7575017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32796186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arcelus J, Mitchell AJ, Wales J, Nielsen S. Mortality rates in patients with anorexia nervosa and other eating disorders: a meta-analysis of 36 studies. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2011;68(7):724&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archgenpsychiatry.2011.74</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21727255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solmi M, Wade TD, Byrne S, Del Giovane C, Fairburn CG, Ostinelli EG, De Crescenzo F, Johnson C, Schmidt U, Treasure J, Favaro A. Comparative efficacy and acceptability of psychological interventions for the treatment of adult outpatients with anorexia nervosa: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8(3):215&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(20)30566-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33600749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaidesoja M, Cooper Z, Fordham B. Cognitive behavioral therapy for eating disorders: A map of the systematic review evidence base. Int J Eat Disord. 2023;56(2):295&#x2013;313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eat.23831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10092269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36315392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grilo CM. Treatment of eating disorders: Current status, challenges, and future directions. Annu Rev Clin Psychol. 2024;20(1):97&#x2013;123. 10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-080822-043256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-080822-043256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38211625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabuenca K, Crowe DE, Gillis AJ, Kabiling C, Saccacio B, Velkova AV, Murray SB. Updates in the treatment of eating disorders in 2024: A year in review in <i>Eating Disorders: The Journal of Treatment &amp; Prevention</i>. Eat Disord. 2025;8:1&#x2013;17. 10.1080/10640266.2025.2497750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40340727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Streatfeild J, Hickson J, Austin SB, Hutcheson R, Kandel JS, Lampert JG, Myers EM, Richmond TK, Samnaliev M, Velasquez K, Weissman RS. Social and economic cost of eating disorders in the United States: Evidence to inform policy action. Int J Eat Disord. 2021;54(5):851&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eat.23486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33655603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deloitte. Social and economic cost of eating disorders in the United States of America: Report for the Strategic Training Initiative for the Prevention of Eating Disorders and the Academy for Eating Disorders. 2020. https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/striped/report-economic-costs-of-eating-disorders/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deloitte / Butterfly Foundation. Paying the Price, Second Edition. The economic and social impact of eating disorders in Australia. 2024. https://butterfly.org.au/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/deloitte-au-eco-paying-the-price-second-edition-180724-new-Oct-24.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kritz F. How much does it cost to treat eating disorders, and how can I pay for it? GoodRX health blog. 2021. https://www.goodrx.com/conditions/eating-disorders/eating-disorders-treatment-costs</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller M, De La Rosa-Cohen M. How much does it cost to treat eating disorders? 2023. https://www.usenourish.com/blog/cost-to-treat-eating-disorders</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Project Heal. Cost of eating disorder treatment as a barrier to healing. https://www.theprojectheal.org/cost-of-treatment</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf6;dersten P, Bergh C, Leon M, Brodin U, Zandian M. Cognitive behavior therapy for eating disorders versus normalization of eating behavior. Physiol Behav. 2017;174:178&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physbeh.2017.03.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28322911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waller G, Raykos B. Behavioral interventions in the treatment of eating disorders. Psychiatric Clin. 2019;42(2):181&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31046921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waller G. Putting the B back into CBT for eating disorders. In: British Association for Behavioural and Cognitive Psychotherapies annual workshops and conference; 2011; Guildford.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geller J, Fernandes A, Kelly AC, Samson L, Srikameswaran S. Collaborative care in eating disorders treatment: Exploring the role of clinician distress, self-compassion, and compassion for others. J Eat Disorders. 2023;11(1):57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40337-023-00741-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10080953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37024928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalle Grave R. The implications of the disease model and psychological model on eating disorder treatment. Eating and weight Disorders-Studies on anorexia. Bulimia Obes. 2023;28(1):7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9922214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36773167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairburn CG. Cognitive behavior therapy and eating disorders. Guilford Press; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The American Psychiatric Association practice guideline for the treatment of patients with eating disorders (4th edn). American Psychiatric Association Publishing. 2023. 10.1176/appi.books.9780890424865.eatingdisorder03.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kells M, Kelly-Weeder S. Nasogastric tube feeding for individuals with anorexia nervosa: an integrative review. J Am Psychiatr Nurses Assoc. 2016;22(6):449&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1078390316657872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27519612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resnicow K, McMaster F. Motivational interviewing: Moving from why to how with autonomy support. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Activity. 2012;9:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1479-5868-9-19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3330017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22385702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulkens S, de Vos C, de Graaff A, Waller G. To deliver or not to deliver cognitive behavioral therapy for eating disorders: replication and extension of our Understanding of why therapists fail to do what they should do. Behav Res Ther. 2018;106:57&#x2013;63. 10.1016/j.brat.2018.05.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2018.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29763767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graves TA, Tabri N, Thompson-Brenner H, Franko DL, Eddy KT, Bourion&#x2010;Bedes S, Brown A, Constantino MJ, Fl&#xfc;ckiger C, Forsberg S, Isserlin L. A meta&#x2010;analysis of the relation between therapeutic alliance and treatment outcome in eating disorders. Int J Eat Disord. 2017;50(4):323&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eat.22672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28152196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emanuel EJ, Emanuel LL. Four models of the physician-patient relationship. JAMA. 1992;267(16):2221&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.1992.03480160079038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1556799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drolet BC, White CL. Selective paternalism. AMA J Ethics. 2012;14(7):582&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/virtualmentor.2012.14.7.oped2-1207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23351298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers J. Coaching skills: The definitive guide to being a coach. 4th ed. Maidenhead (UK): McGraw-Hill Education; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halmi KA. Perplexities of treatment resistence in eating disorders. BMC Psychiatry. 2013;13:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-244X-13-292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3829659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24199597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy H, Paul T, Jain E, Loh H, Kazmi SH, Dua R, Rodriguez R, Naqvi SA, Bidika E. A clinical overview of anorexia nervosa and overcoming treatment resistance. Avicenna J Med. 2023;13(01):003&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0042-1758859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10038755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36969350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strober M, Johnson C. The need for complex ideas in anorexia nervosa: W hy biology, environment, and psyche all matter, why therapists make mistakes, and why clinical benchmarks are needed for managing weight correction. Int J Eat Disord. 2012;45(2):155&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eat.22005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22287383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregertsen EC, Mandy W, Serpell L. The egosyntonic nature of anorexia: an impediment to recovery in anorexia nervosa treatment. Front Psychol. 2017;8:2273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2017.02273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5743910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29312100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The economics of thinness. The Economist. 2022 Dec. https://www.economist.com/christmas-specials/2022/12/20/the-economics-of-thinness</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant AM, Cavanagh MJ. The solution-focused approach to coaching. The complete handbook of coaching. 2014;14:51&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passmore J. The coaches&#x2019; handbook: the complete practitioner guide for professional coaches. Abingdon (UK): Routledge; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trepper TS, McCollum E, De Jong P, Korman H, Gingerich W, Franklin C. Solution-focused therapy treatment manual for working with individuals. Solution-focused brief therapy: A multicultural approach. 2010;15:14&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Halloran MS. Family involvement in the treatment of anorexia nervosa: A solution-focused approach. Family J. 1999;7(4):384&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1066480799074011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontaine KR. &#x201c;How I practice&#x201d; Solution-Focused brief therapy of a binge eater. Eat Disord. 1996;4(3):266&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10640269608251182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slavin K, Kim JS. SFBT in action: Eating disorders. In: Kim J, Kelly M, Franklin C, editors. Solution-Focused Brief Therapy in Schools: A 360-Degree View of the Research and Practice Principles. 2nd ed. New York: Oxford University Press; 2017; pp. 179&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob F. Solution focused recovery from eating distress. London: BT; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troscianko E. The gap between insight and action. Psychology Today. 2022. https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/a-hunger-artist/202209/the-gap-between-insight-and-action</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>