<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41832311</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A perturbation-recovery generative autoencoder for heterogeneous graphs with attributes missing.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-44190-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Heterogeneous graphs are widely employed in applications such as social networks, recommendation systems, and bioinformatics. However, node attributes in real-world heterogeneous graphs are often missing or corrupted, which substantially degrades representation quality and downstream task performance. Existing approaches typically rely on deterministic imputation or static masking schemes, limiting their ability to model the uncertainty induced by attribute missingness and the complex multi-relational dependencies present in real-world heterogeneous graphs. To address these challenges, we propose HGGAE (Heterogeneous Graph Generative Autoencoder), a generative autoencoder framework based on a perturbation-recovery paradigm for heterogeneous graphs with incomplete attributes. HGGAE explicitly models attribute missingness as a controllable perturbation process, and performs progressive attribute restoration and representation learning through the joint design of a schedulable noise generator and relation-specific structural perturbation modules. Unlike traditional masking-based methods, HGGAE adaptively adjusts perturbation intensity during training, enabling more effective modeling of the stochastic nature of attribute degradation. To improve training efficiency, HGGAE adopts a sparse-target objective and a local reconstruction design, which reduce the supervision and gradient-accumulation cost of attribute reconstruction, while the overall computation remains dominated by full-graph message passing in the encoder. Experiments on four benchmark heterogeneous graph datasets demonstrate that HGGAE achieves overall strong and competitive performance on node classification, achieving up to 7.8% Macro-F1 and 8.5% Micro-F1 gains on IMDB, while delivering competitive or superior performance on Yelp, ACM, and DBLP. These results validate the effectiveness, robustness, and generalization capability of HGGAE under attribute-missing scenarios.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Quan</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Intelligent Education Technology and Application of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang Normal University, Jinhua, 321000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shao</LastName><ForeName>Xinru</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Intelligent Education Technology and Application of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang Normal University, Jinhua, 321000, China. 17854337260@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaodi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computing Mathematics and Engineering, Charles Sturt University, Albury, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adversarial training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Attribute missing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Graph autoencoder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heterogeneous graph</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41832311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-44190-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-44190-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xia, R. et al. Incomplete graph learning: A comprehensive survey. Neural Netw. 190, 107682. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neunet.2025.107682 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, R. et al. Efficient learning for billion-scale heterogeneous information networks. IEEE Trans. Big Data 11, 748&#x2013;760. https://doi.org/10.1109/TBDATA.2024.3428331 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, H., Zheng, V. W. &amp; Chang, K.C.-C. A comprehensive survey of graph embedding: Problems, techniques, and applications. IEEE Trans. Knowl. Data Eng. 30, 1616&#x2013;1637 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, X., Zhang, J., Meng, Z. &amp; King, I. Magnn: Metapath aggregated graph neural network for heterogeneous graph embedding. In Proceedings of the Web Conference (WWW), 2331&#x2013;2341 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zitnik, M. &amp; Leskovec, J. Predicting multicellular function through multi-layer tissue networks. Bioinformatics 33, i190&#x2013;i198 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, D., Huo, C., Liang, C. &amp; Yang, L. Heterogeneous graph neural network via attribute completion. In Proc. World Wide Web Conf. (WWW), 391&#x2013;400 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou, Z. et al. Graphmae: Self-supervised masked graph autoencoders. In Proceedings of the ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD), 594&#x2013;604 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. et al. Heterogeneous graph attention network. In Proc. World Wide Web Conf. (WWW), 2022&#x2013;2032 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, C. et al. Reconciling attribute and structural anomalies for improved graph anomaly detection. IEEE Trans. Neural Netw. Learn. Syst. 36, 16661&#x2013;16674. https://doi.org/10.1109/TNNLS.2025.3561172 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, K., Yu, Y., Huang, C., Zhao, Z. &amp; Dong, J. Heterogeneous graph neural network for attribute completion. Knowl.-Based Syst. 251, 109171 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strahl, J., Peltonen, J., Mamitsuka, H. &amp; Kaski, S. Scalable probabilistic matrix factorization with graph-based priors. Proc. AAAI Conf. Artif. Intell. 34, 5851&#x2013;5858 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>You, J., Ma, X., Ding, D.&#xa0;Y., Kochenderfer, M.&#xa0;J. &amp; Leskovec, J. Handling missing data with graph representation learning. In Proc. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 19075&#x2013;19087 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, G. et al. Autoac: Towards automated attribute completion for heterogeneous graph neural network. In Proceedings of the IEEE 39th International Conference on Data Engineering (ICDE), 2808&#x2013;2821 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha, A. &amp; Kumar, O. Gmlm: Bridging graph neural networks and language models for heterophilic node classification. arXiv:2503.05763 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian, Y., Dong, K., Zhang, C., Zhang, C. &amp; Chawla, N. V. Heterogeneous graph masked autoencoders. Proc. AAAI Conf. Artif. Intell. 37, 9997&#x2013;10005 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei, Y., Mo, Y., Ji, L. &amp; Zhu, X. Dual consistency constraint-based self-supervised representation learning for heterogeneous graphs with missing attributes. IEEE Trans. Neural Netw. Learn. Syst. 36, 14508&#x2013;14521 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ankner, Z., Saphra, N., Blalock, D., Frankle, J. &amp; Leavitt, M.&#xa0;L. Dynamic masking rate schedules for mlm pretraining. arXiv:2305.15096 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, C. et al. Masked feature prediction for self-supervised visual pre-training. In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 14668&#x2013;14678 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, G., Hu, D., Liu, Z., Zhang, X. &amp; Lyu, H. Semantic reshuffling with llm and heterogeneous graph auto-encoder for enhanced rumor detection. In Proceedings of the 31st International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING), 8557&#x2013;8572 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, Q. et al. Efficient mae towards large-scale vision transformers. In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 606&#x2013;615 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Z., Liu, Z., Wang, Y., Yang, D. &amp; Che, W. Ra-hgnn: Attribute completion of heterogeneous graph neural networks based on residual attention mechanism. Expert. Syst. Appl. 243, 122945 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. What&#x2019;s behind the mask: Understanding masked graph modeling for graph autoencoders. In Proceedings of the 29th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining, KDD &#x2019;23, 1268&#x2013;1279 (Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, J. et al. Heterogeneous graph structure learning for graph neural networks. Proc. AAAI Conf. Artif. Intell. 35, 4697&#x2013;4705. https://doi.org/10.1609/aaai.v35i5.16600 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>You, Y. et al. Graph contrastive learning with augmentations. In Larochelle, H., Ranzato, M., Hadsell, R., Balcan, M. &amp; Lin, H. (eds.) Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, vol.&#xa0;33, 5812&#x2013;5823 (Curran Associates, Inc., 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakoor, S. et al. Large-scale representation learning on graphs via bootstrapping. empharXiv:2102.06514 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Y. et al. Variational graph autoencoder for heterogeneous information networks with missing and inaccurate attributes. In Proceedings of the 31st ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining V.1, KDD &#x2019;25, 2067&#x2013;2078 (Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, Y., Chawla, N.&#xa0;V. &amp; Swami, A. metapath2vec: Scalable representation learning for heterogeneous networks. In Proceedings of the ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD), 135&#x2013;144, https://doi.org/10.1145/3097983.3098036 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Y. &amp; Han, J. Mining Heterogeneous Information Networks: Principles and Methodologies, vol.&#xa0;3 of Synthesis Lectures on Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery (Morgan &amp; Claypool, 2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, Y., Shi, C., Hu, L. &amp; Liu, Z. Relation structure-aware heterogeneous information network embedding. In Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 4456&#x2013;4463 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veli&#x10d;kovi&#x107;, P. et al. Graph attention networks. arXiv:1710.10903 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo, J., Jeon, H., Jung, J. &amp; Kang, U. Accurate node feature estimation with structured variational graph autoencoder. In Proceedings of the ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD), 2336&#x2013;2346 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, C., Kim, D., Han, J. &amp; Yu, H. Unsupervised attributed multiplex network embedding. In Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 5371&#x2013;5378 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, G., Zhu, Y., Liu, J. K. &amp; Li, X. Hegcl: Advance self-supervised learning in heterogeneous graph-level representation. IEEE Trans. Neural Netw. Learn. Syst. 35, 13914&#x2013;13925 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. et al. Hgber: Heterogeneous graph neural network with bidirectional encoding representation. IEEE Trans. Neural Netw. Learn. Syst. 35, 9340&#x2013;9351. https://doi.org/10.1109/TNNLS.2022.3232709 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, D. et al. Analyzing heterogeneous networks with missing attributes by unsupervised contrastive learning. IEEE Trans. Neural Netw. Learn. Syst. 35, 4438&#x2013;4450. https://doi.org/10.1109/TNNLS.2022.3149997 (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>