<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41684105</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1466-187X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical teacher</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Teach</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Turning struggles into strengths: A qualitative exploration of academic difficulty in medical school.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>16</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-16</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/0142159X.2025.2610404</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Academic difficulty in medical education has potentially negative impacts on students, faculties, and healthcare institutions. A traditional deficit view of the phenomenon offers a limited perspective that narrows student support opportunities and neglects intrapersonal strengths and successes arising from student adversity and struggle. This study explores the lived experiences of medical students and junior doctors who surmounted academic difficulties in medical school, to provide a positive lens on the transformative personal and professional potential of these struggles.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A constructivist, phenomenological approach and integrated, strengths-based perspective shaped this qualitative study. Semi-structured participant interviews were conducted with participants at two Australian medical schools. In-depth interview transcripts were analysed using Reflexive Thematic Analysis and Interpretive Phenomenological Analysis to capture participants' in-depth, nuanced experiences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Eighteen medical students and eight junior doctors participated. An iterative analysis process identified three themes: 'In a dark place,' 'Rising out of the ashes,' and 'Becoming a better person and a better doctor.' The first theme captured the emotional toll of academic failure. The second theme described a turning point, where participants intentionally shifted their mindset towards a purpose and achievement possibilities that helped them re-engage with learning. This transformation activated intrapersonal and interpersonal skills, including increased confidence, self-efficacy, and peer support, contributing to academic recovery that did not appear to be related to gendered differences. In the third theme, participants reflected on the longer-term personal and professional benefits that emerged from adversity. Enhanced character traits such as perseverance, motivation, and empathy not only supported their academic success but also enriched their clinical practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The study findings challenge the prevailing deficit narrative and demonstrate the transformative potential of academic struggles. With appropriate support and a strengths-based educational framework, students can overcome feelings of despair and low confidence, emerging as capable, compassionate, and resilient healthcare professionals.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDonald</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8255-7253</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine and Dentistry, James Cook University, Townsville, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Larkins</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7561-3202</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine and Dentistry, James Cook University, Townsville, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turner</LastName><ForeName>Richard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2276-8999</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malau-Aduli</LastName><ForeName>Bunmi S</ForeName><Initials>BS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6054-8498</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine and Dentistry, James Cook University, Townsville, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Newcastle, Newcastle, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Med Teach</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7909593</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0142-159X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Academic difficulty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">junior doctors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical students</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strengths-based approach</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41684105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0142159X.2025.2610404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>