<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41913251</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1743-7075</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrition &amp; metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutr Metab (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Metabolic inflexibility mediates the association between type 2 diabetes and impaired post-exercise heart rate recovery: a mediation analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12986-026-01114-3</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yutao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiac Rehabilitation Center, Department of Cardiology, Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, 100029, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Hubei No. Hubei No.3 Peoples Hospital of Jianghan University, Hubei Province, Wuhan, 430033, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Jiahui</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiac Rehabilitation Center, Department of Cardiology, Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, 100029, P.R. China. wujiahui1998@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Nan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiac Rehabilitation Center, Department of Cardiology, Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, 100029, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Suhui</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiac Rehabilitation Center, Department of Cardiology, Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, 100029, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiac Rehabilitation Center, Department of Cardiology, Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, 100029, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiac Rehabilitation Center, Department of Cardiology, Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, 100029, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shao</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiac Rehabilitation Center, Department of Cardiology, Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, 100029, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. BJZYYB-2023-22</GrantID><Agency>Beijing Municipal Science and Technology Development Fund for TCM</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nutr Metab (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101231644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-7075</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary vascular disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heart rate recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolic inflexibility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory exchange ratio</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted following the &#x201c;Declaration of Helsinki&#x201d; by the World Medical Association and the strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology (STROBE) statement checklist (available in Supplementary file). Approval and informed consent was waived by the &#x201c;Clinical Research Ethics Committee of Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University&#x201d; as the patient identity information has been concealed. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41913251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12986-026-01114-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12986-026-01114-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Roth GA, Mensah GA, Johnson CO, Addolorato G, Ammirati E, Baddour LM, et al. Global burden of cardiovascular diseases and risk factors, 1990&#x2013;2019: update from the GBD 2019 study. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76:2982&#x2013;3021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunardi M, Gao C, Hara H, Ono M, Kawashima H, Wang R, Wijns W, Serruys PW, Onuma Y. Coronary interventions in 2020: the year in review. EuroIntervention. 2021;16:e1215&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann F, Sousa-Uva M, Ahlsson A, Alfonso F, Banning AP, Benedetto U, et al. 2018 ESC/EACTS guidelines on myocardial revascularization. Eur Heart J. 2019;40:87&#x2013;165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher GF, Ades PA, Kligfield P, Arena R, Balady GJ, Bittner VA, Coke LA, Fleg JL, Forman DE, Gerber TC, Gulati M, Madan K, Rhodes J, Thompson PD, Williams MA. Exercise standards for testing and training: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2013;128:873&#x2013;934.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maron DJ, Hochman JS, Reynolds HR, Bangalore S, O&#x2019;Brien SM, Boden WE, et al. Initial invasive or conservative strategy for stable coronary disease. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:1395&#x2013;407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi PH, de Lemos JA. Diagnosis and management of stable angina: a review. JAMA. 2021;325:1765&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarwar N, Gao P, Seshasai SRK, Gobin R, Kaptoge S, Di Angelantonio E, et al. Diabetes mellitus, fasting blood glucose concentration, and risk of vascular disease: a collaborative meta-analysis of 102 prospective studies. Lancet. 2010;375:2215&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosentino F, Grant PJ, Aboyans V, Bailey CJ, Ceriello A, Delgado V, et al. 2019 ESC guidelines on diabetes, pre-diabetes, and cardiovascular diseases developed in collaboration with the EASD. Eur Heart J. 2020;41:255&#x2013;323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia G, Hill MA, Sowers JR. Diabetic cardiomyopathy: an update of mechanisms contributing to this clinical entity. Circ Res. 2018;122:624&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennells L, Kaptoge S, Wood A, Sweeting M, Zhao X, White I, et al. Equalization of four cardiovascular risk algorithms after systematic recalibration: individual-participant meta-analysis of 86 prospective studies. Eur Heart J. 2019;40:621&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vivekananthan DP, Blackstone EH, Pothier CE, Lauer MS. Heart rate recovery after exercise is a predictor of mortality, independent of the angiographic severity of coronary disease. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2003;42:831&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole CR, Blackstone EH, Pashkow FJ, Snader CE, Lauer MS. Heart-rate recovery immediately after exercise as a predictor of mortality. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:1351&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu S, Cai X, Sun Z, Li L, Zuegel M, Steinacker JM, et al. Heart rate recovery and risk of cardiovascular events and all-cause mortality: a meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies. J Am Heart Assoc. 2017;6(5):e005505. https://doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.117.005505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurl S, Jae SY, Voutilainen A, Hagnas M, Laukkanen JA. Exercise heart rate reserve and recovery as risk factors for sudden cardiac death. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2021;68:7&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karjalainen JJ, Kiviniemi AM, Hautala AJ, Piira O, Lepojarvi ES, Peltola MA, Ukkola OH, Hedberg PSM, Huikuri HV, Tulppo MP. Determinants and prognostic value of cardiovascular autonomic function in coronary artery disease patients with and without type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2014;37:286&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng YJ, Lauer MS, Earnest CP, Church TS, Kampert JB, Gibbons LW, Blair SN. Heart rate recovery following maximal exercise testing as a predictor of cardiovascular disease and all-cause mortality in men with diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2003;26:2052&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RL, Soeters MR, Wust RCI, Houtkooper RH. Metabolic flexibility as an adaptation to energy resources and requirements in health and disease. Endocr Rev. 2018;39:489&#x2013;517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battista F, Belligoli A, Neunhaeuserer D, Gasperetti A, Bettini S, Compagnin C, Marchese R, Quinto G, Bergamin M, Vettor R, Busetto L, Ermolao A. Metabolic Response to Submaximal and Maximal Exercise in People with Severe Obesity, Prediabetes, and Diabetes. Obes Facts. 2021;14:415&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imai J, Katagiri H. Regulation of systemic metabolism by the autonomic nervous system consisting of afferent and efferent innervation. Int Immunol. 2022;34:67&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassett DRJ. International physical activity questionnaire: 12-country reliability and validity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:1396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross RM. ATS/ACCP statement on cardiopulmonary exercise testing. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2003;167:1451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Blair SN, Arena R, Church TS, Despres JP, Franklin BA, Haskell WL, Kaminsky LA, Levine BD, Lavie CJ, Myers J, Niebauer J, Sallis R, Sawada SS, Sui X, Wisloff U. Importance of Assessing Cardiorespiratory Fitness in Clinical Practice: A Case for Fitness as a Clinical Vital Sign: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2016;134:e653&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewar A, Kass L, Stephens RCM, Tetlow N, Desai T. Heart rate recovery assessed by cardiopulmonary exercise testing in patients with cardiovascular disease: relationship with prognosis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(6):4678. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph20064678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtis JM, Horton ES, Bahnson J, Gregg EW, Jakicic JM, Regensteiner JG, Ribisl PM, Soberman JE, Stewart KJ, Espeland MA. Prevalence and predictors of abnormal cardiovascular responses to exercise testing among individuals with type 2 diabetes: the Look AHEAD (Action for Health in Diabetes) study. Diabetes Care. 2010;33:901&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chacko KM, Bauer TA, Dale RA, Dixon JA, Schrier RW, Estacio RO. Heart rate recovery predicts mortality and cardiovascular events in patients with type 2 diabetes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40:288&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pop-Busui R, Evans GW, Gerstein HC, Fonseca V, Fleg JL, Hoogwerf BJ, Genuth S, Grimm RH, Corson MA, Prineas R. Effects of cardiac autonomic dysfunction on mortality risk in the Action to Control Cardiovascular Risk in Diabetes (ACCORD) trial. Diabetes Care. 2010;33:1578&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada T, Yoshitama T, Makino K, Lee T, Saeki F. Heart rate recovery after exercise is a predictor of silent myocardial ischemia in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2011;34:724&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Xu A, Niu L, Li J. Effect of percutaneous coronary intervention on heart rate recovery in patients with coronary artery disease. Coron Artery Dis. 2015;26:442&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacre JW, Jellis CL, Jenkins C, Haluska BA, Baumert M, Coombes JS, Marwick TH. A six-month exercise intervention in subclinical diabetic heart disease: effects on exercise capacity, autonomic and myocardial function. Metabolism. 2014;63:1104&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao SC, Chai A, Kligfield P. Heart rate recovery response to symptom-limited treadmill exercise after cardiac rehabilitation in patients with coronary artery disease with and without recent events. Am J Cardiol. 2002;90:763&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley DE, He J, Menshikova EV, Ritov VB. Dysfunction of mitochondria in human skeletal muscle in type 2 diabetes. Diabetes. 2002;51:2944&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RL, Soeters MR, Wust R, Houtkooper RH. Metabolic flexibility as an adaptation to energy resources and requirements in health and disease. Endocr Rev. 2018;39:489&#x2013;517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corpeleijn E, Saris WH, Blaak EE. Metabolic flexibility in the development of insulin resistance and type 2 diabetes: effects of lifestyle. Obes Rev. 2009;10:178&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turinese I, Marinelli P, Bonini M, Rossetti M, Statuto G, Filardi T, Paris A, Lenzi A, Morano S, Palange P. Metabolic and cardiovascular response to exercise in patients with type 1 diabetes. J Endocrinol Invest. 2017;40:999&#x2013;1005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodpaster BH, Sparks LM. Metabolic flexibility in health and disease. Cell Metabol. 2017;25:1027&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boon H, Blaak EE, Saris WHM, Keizer HA, Wagenmakers AJM, van Loon LJC. Substrate source utilisation in long-term diagnosed type 2 diabetes patients at rest, and during exercise and subsequent recovery. Diabetologia. 2007;50:103&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monferrer-Marin J, Roldan A, Helge JW, Blasco-Lafarga C. Metabolic flexibility and resting autonomic function in active menopausal women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024;124:3649&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hargreaves M, Spriet LL. Skeletal muscle energy metabolism during exercise. Nat Metab. 2020;2:817&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imai K, Sato H, Hori M, Kusuoka H, Ozaki H, Yokoyama H, Takeda H, Inoue M, Kamada T. Vagally mediated heart rate recovery after exercise is accelerated in athletes but blunted in patients with chronic heart failure. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1994;24:1529&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroco JL, Arrais I, Silvestre T, Pinto M, Laranjo S, Magalhaes J, Santa-Clara H, Fernhall B, Melo X. Post-acute exercise cardiovagal modulation in older male adults with and without type 2 diabetes. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024;124:1475&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros WM, de Luca FA, de Figueredo Junior AR, Mendes FAR, Gun C. Heart rate recovery improvement in patients following acute myocardial infarction: exercise training, &#x3b2;-blocker therapy or both. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2018;38:351&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racine N, Blanchet M, Ducharme A, Marquis J, Boucher J, Juneau M, White M. Decreased heart rate recovery after exercise in patients with congestive heart failure: effect of &#x3b2;-blocker therapy. J Card Fail. 2003;9:296&#x2013;302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guazzi M, Arena R. The impact of pharmacotherapy on the cardiopulmonary exercise test response in patients with heart failure: a mini review. Curr Vasc Pharmacol. 2009;7:557&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanderson JE, Yeung LY, Chan S, Tomlinson B, Kay R, Woo KS, et al. Effect of &#x3b2;-blockade on baroreceptor and autonomic function in heart failure. Clin Sci Lond. 1999;96:137&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pousset F, Copie X, Lechat P, Jaillon P, Boissel JP, Hetzel M, et al. Effects of bisoprolol on heart rate variability in heart failure. Am J Cardiol. 1996;77:612&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo B, Menduni M, Borboni P, Picconi F, Frontoni S. Autonomic nervous system in obesity and insulin-resistance-the complex interplay between leptin and central nervous system. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(10):5187. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms22105187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guarino D, Nannipieri M, Iervasi G, Taddei S, Bruno RM. The Role of the Autonomic Nervous System in the Pathophysiology of Obesity. Front Physiol. 2017;8:665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberger JJ, Arora R, Buckley U, Shivkumar K. Autonomic Nervous System Dysfunction: JACC Focus Seminar. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;73:1189&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman EL, Callaghan BC, Pop-Busui R, Zochodne DW, Wright DE, Bennett DL, et al. Diabetic neuropathy. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2019;5:41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spallone V, Ziegler D, Freeman R, Bernardi L, Frontoni S, Pop-Busui R, Stevens M, Kempler P, Hilsted J, Tesfaye S, Low P, Valensi P. Cardiovascular autonomic neuropathy in diabetes: clinical impact, assessment, diagnosis, and management. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2011;27:639&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spallone V. Update on the Impact, Diagnosis and Management of Cardiovascular Autonomic Neuropathy in Diabetes: What Is Defined, What Is New, and What Is Unmet. Diabetes Metab J. 2019;43:3&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galgani JE, Moro C, Ravussin E. Metabolic flexibility and insulin resistance. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2008;295:E1009&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Wang J, Tao S, Liang Z, Xie R, Liu N, et al. Mitochondrial damage-associated molecular patterns: a new insight into metabolic inflammation in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2024;40:e3733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szendroedi J, Phielix E, Roden M. The role of mitochondria in insulin resistance and type 2 diabetes mellitus. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2011;8:92&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X, Lu M, Yuan D, Xu D, Yao P, Ji W, et al. Mitochondrial dysfunction in neural injury. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calcada D, Vianello D, Giampieri E, Sala C, Castellani G, de Graaf A, Kremer B, van Ommen B, Feskens E, Santoro A, Franceschi C, Bouwman J. The role of low-grade inflammation and metabolic flexibility in aging and nutritional modulation thereof: a systems biology approach. Mech Ageing Dev. 2014;136&#x2013;137:138&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregor MF, Hotamisligil GS. Inflammatory mechanisms in obesity. Annu Rev Immunol. 2011;29:415&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hummasti S, Hotamisligil GS. Endoplasmic reticulum stress and inflammation in obesity and diabetes. Circ Res. 2010;107:579&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akash MSH, Rehman K, Chen S. Role of inflammatory mechanisms in pathogenesis of type 2 diabetes mellitus. J Cell Biochem. 2013;114:525&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Entezari M, Hashemi D, Taheriazam A, Zabolian A, Mohammadi S, Fakhri F, et al. AMPK signaling in diabetes mellitus, insulin resistance and diabetic complications: a pre-clinical and clinical investigation. Biomed Pharmacother. 2022;146:112563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjobsted R, Munk-Hansen N, Birk JB, Foretz M, Viollet B, Bjornholm M, et al. Enhanced muscle insulin sensitivity after contraction/exercise is mediated by AMPK. Diabetes. 2017;66:598&#x2013;612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Kobayashi K, Kogure Y, Yamanaka H, Yamamoto S, Yagi H, et al. Negative regulation of TRPA1 by AMPK in primary sensory neurons as a potential mechanism of painful diabetic neuropathy. Diabetes. 2018;67:98&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>