<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41694052</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0019-5545</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Indian journal of psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Indian J Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical practice guidelines for management of schizophrenia in India: A comprehensive overview.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>94</StartPage><EndPage>121</EndPage><MedlinePgn>94-121</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/indianjpsychiatry_1341_25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Schizophrenia is a chronic, severe mental disorder associated with significant disability, caregiver burden, and public health impact, particularly in low- and middle-income countries such as India. While multiple international clinical practice guidelines (CPGs) exist, contextual differences in illness presentation, sociocultural factors, health-care infrastructure, and resource availability necessitate region-specific guidance. This CPG provides a comprehensive, stage-based overview of the assessment and management of schizophrenia, with an emphasis on applicability to the Indian context. The document synthesizes available evidence, existing guideline recommendations, and expert clinical consensus to outline pragmatic approaches across the illness trajectory, including the prodromal phase, first-episode psychosis, multiepisode relapsing-remitting course, and treatment-resistant schizophrenia. Detailed recommendations are provided for clinical assessment, use of standardized rating scales, physical and laboratory investigations, and identification of comorbid medical and psychiatric conditions at each stage. Pharmacological strategies emphasize rational antipsychotic use, including early intervention principles, maintenance treatment, long-acting injectable antipsychotics, therapeutic drug monitoring-particularly for clozapine-and evidence-based augmentation approaches in treatment resistance. The guideline also addresses emergency management, antipsychotic switching strategies, and the judicious use of combination and adjuvant psychotropic therapies. Equally, it highlights the critical role of psychological and psychosocial interventions, family involvement, community-based care, and rehabilitation services in achieving functional recovery. Special attention is given to implementation challenges and adaptations relevant to Indian clinical settings, including cost, accessibility, family structures, and public mental health systems. Overall, this guideline aims to support clinicians in delivering individualized, evidence-informed, and contextually appropriate care for persons with schizophrenia, thereby improving long-term outcomes and quality of life.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Indian Journal of Psychiatry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sahoo</LastName><ForeName>Swapnajeet</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sreeraj</LastName><ForeName>Vanteemar S</ForeName><Initials>VS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, National Institute of Mental Health and Neurosciences, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gopalakrishnan</LastName><ForeName>Ganesan</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, MVJ Medical College and Research Hospital, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ameen</LastName><ForeName>Shahul</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, St. Thomas Hospital, Changanacherry, Kerala, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cholera</LastName><ForeName>Rashmin M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Dr. D. Y. Patil Hospital and Medical College, Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Venkatasubramanian</LastName><ForeName>Ganesan</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, National Institute of Mental Health and Neurosciences, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malhotra</LastName><ForeName>Savita</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Senior Consultant Psychiatrist, Fortis Hospital, Mohali, Punjab, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Acronym>WT_</Acronym><Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Indian J Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0013255</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0019-5545</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical practice guidelines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">India</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">schizophrenia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">update</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41694052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12900051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/indianjpsychiatry_1341_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IJPsy-68-94</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agius M, Goh C, Ulhaq S, McGorry P. The staging model in schizophrenia, and its clinical implications. Psychiatr Danub. 2010;22:211&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20562749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulhara P, Shah R, Grover S. Is the course and outcome of schizophrenia better in the &#x2018;developing&#x2019; world? Asian J Psychiatry. 2009;2:55&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23051029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keith SJ, Matthews SM. The diagnosis of schizophrenia: A review of onset and duration issues. Schizophr Bull. 1991;17:51&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2047789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breitborde NJK, Srihari VH, Woods SW. Review of the operational definition for first-episode psychosiseip. Early Interv Psychiatry. 2009;3:259&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4451818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22642728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundin NB, Blouin AM, Cowan HR, Moe AM, Wastler HM, Breitborde NJ. Identification of psychosis risk and diagnosis of first-episode psychosis: Advice for clinicians. Psychol Res Behav Manag. 2024;17:1365&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10962362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38529082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization  . World Health Organization (WHO) Geneva: World Health Organization; 2022. International Classification of Diseases, Eleventh Revision (ICD-11) Available from: https://icd.who.int/browse11/l-m/en#/http://id.who.int/icd/entity/1706773916 . [Last cited on 2022 Oct 25]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howes OD, McCutcheon R, Agid O, de Bartolomeis A, van Beveren NJ, Birnbaum ML, et al. Treatment-resistant schizophrenia: Treatment response and resistance in psychosis (TRRIP) working group consensus guidelines on diagnosis and terminology. Am J Psychiatry. 2017;174:216&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6231547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27919182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaebel W. Status of psychotic disorders in ICD-11. Schizophr Bull. 2012;38:895&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3446222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22987845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller TJ, McGlashan TH, Woods SW, Stein K, Driesen N, Corcoran CM, et al. Symptom assessment in schizophrenic prodromal states. Psychiatr Q. 1999;70:273&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10587984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller TJ, McGlashan TH, Rosen JL, Cadenhead K, Cannon T, Ventura J, et al. Prodromal assessment with the structured interview for prodromal syndromes and the scale of prodromal symptoms: Predictive validity, interrater reliability, and training to reliability. Schizophr Bull. 2003;29:703&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14989408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vollmer-Larsen A, Handest P, Parnas J. Reliability of measuring anomalous experience: The Bonn Scale for the Assessment of Basic Symptoms. Psychopathology. 2007;40:345&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17657133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yung AR, Phillips LJ, McGorry PD, McFarlane CA, Francey S, Harrigan S, et al. Prediction of psychosis. A step towards indicated prevention of schizophrenia. Br J Psychiatry Suppl. 1998;172:14&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9764121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riecher-R&#xf6;ssler A, Aston J, Ventura J, Merlo M, Borgwardt S, Gschwandtner U, et al. [The Basel Screening Instrument for Psychosis (BSIP): Development, structure, reliability and validity] Fortschr Neurol Psychiatr. 2008;76:207&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18393134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrivastava A, Shah N, Johnston M, Stitt L, Thakar M, Chinnasamy G. Effects of duration of untreated psychosis on long-term outcome of people hospitalized with first episode schizophrenia. Indian J Psychiatry. 2010;52:164&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2927888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20838506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen HG, Speyer H, Starzer M, Albert N, Hjorth&#xf8;j C, Eplov LF, et al. Clinical recovery among individuals with a first-episode schizophrenia an updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Schizophr Bull. 2023;49:297&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10016416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36029094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseka LN, Woo BK. Social media and schizophrenia: An update on clinical applications. World J Psychiatry. 2022;12:897&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9331455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36051600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tebartz van Elst L, Runge K, Meyer PT, Urbach H, Venhoff N, Pr&#xfc;ss H. The Neuropsychiatric checklist for Autoimmune psychosis: A narrative review. Biol Psychiatry. 2025;98:654&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39987981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui X, McGrath JJ, Burne TH, Eyles DW. Vitamin D and schizophrenia: 20 years on. Mol Psychiatry. 2021;26:2708&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8505257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33500553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajith KR, Krishnakumar P, Danish E, Dhanasooraj D, Ranjitha M, Midhun S. Serum vitamin D level in patients with schizophrenia: A community-based study. Indian J Med Res. 2022;156:157&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9903383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36510910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krivoy A, Onn R, Vilner Y, Hochman E, Weizman S, Paz A, et al. Vitamin D Supplementation in chronic schizophrenia patients treated with clozapine: A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial. EBioMedicine. 2017;26:138&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5832639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29226809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molden E. Therapeutic drug monitoring of clozapine in adults with schizophrenia: A review of challenges and strategies. Expert Opin Drug Metab Toxicol. 2021;17:1211&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34461790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DD, Fleming F, Holman TL, Perry PJ. Plasma clozapine concentrations as a predictor of clinical response: A follow-up study. J Clin Psychiatry. 1994;55:117&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7961554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiemke C, Bergemann N, Clement HW, Conca A, Deckert J, Domschke K, et al. Consensus guidelines for therapeutic drug monitoring in neuropsychopharmacology: Update 2017. Pharmacopsychiatry. 2018;51:9&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28910830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flanagan RJ, Gee S, Belsey S, Couchman L, Lally J. Therapeutic monitoring of plasma clozapine and N-desmethylclozapine (norclozapine): Practical considerations. BJPsych Adv. 2023;29:92&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall M, Rathbone J. Early intervention for psychosis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2011;6:CD004718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4163966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21678345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Morinigo JD, Leucht S, Arango C. Pharmacological treatment of early-onset schizophrenia: A critical review, evidence-based clinical guidance and unmet needs. Pharmacopsychiatry. 2022;55:233&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9458343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35777418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fusar-Poli P, De Micheli A, Signorini L, Baldwin H, Salazar de Pablo G, McGuire P. Real-world long-term outcomes in individuals at clinical risk for psychosis: The case for extending duration of care. EClinicalMedicine. 2020 28.100578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7700893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33294806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei C, van der Gaag M, Nelson B, Smit F, Yuen HP, Berger M, et al. Preventive interventions for individuals at ultra high risk for psychosis: An updated and extended meta-analysis. Clin Psychol Rev. 2021;86:102005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33810885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosnjak Kuharic D, Kekin I, Hew J, Rojnic Kuzman M, Puljak L. Interventions for prodromal stage of psychosis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;2019:CD012236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6823626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31689359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas SP, Nandhra HS, Singh SP. Pharmacologic treatment of first-episode schizophrenia: A review of the literature. Prim Care Companion CNS Disord. 2012;14 PCC.11r01198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3357581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22690369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salimi K, Jarskog LF, Lieberman JA. Antipsychotic drugs for first-episode schizophrenia: A comparative review. CNS Drugs. 2009;23:837&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19739694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keating D, McWilliams S, Schneider I, Hynes C, Cousins G, Strawbridge J, et al. Pharmacological guidelines for schizophrenia: A systematic review and comparison of recommendations for the first episode. BMJ Open. 2017;7:e013881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5223704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28062471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCutcheon RA, Pillinger T, Varvari I, Halstead S, Ayinde OO, Crossley NA, et al. INTEGRATE: International guidelines for the algorithmic treatment of schizophrenia. Lancet Psychiatry. 2025;12:384&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40179920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh MS, Dana T, Selph S, Devine EB, Cantor A, Bougatsos C, et al. Updating the comparative evidence on second-generation antipsychotic use with schizophrenia. Psychiatr Res Clin Pract. 2020;2:76&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9175869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36101867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kane JM, Agid O, Castle DJ, Citrome L, Fagiolini A, Kishimoto T, et al. The use of long-acting injectables for people with schizophrenia: Consensus panel recommendations for overcoming barriers and implementing treatment. Neurol Ther. 2025;14:2551&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12623523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41057718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Wu T, Li J, Du C, Chi R, Jiang K, et al. Effect of long-acting injectable antipsychotics on treatment adherence and healthcare utilization in Chinese patients with schizophrenia: A mirror-image study. Ther Adv Psychopharmacol. 2025;15:20451253251360400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12374043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40860989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moncrieff J, Horowitz MA. Helping people to discontinue antipsychotics: If, when and how. Schizophrenia. 2025;11:149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12711913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41407750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogers JP. Antipsychotic treatment in schizophrenia: Balancing relapse prevention and functional recovery. Schizophrenia. 2025;11:154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12712057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41408066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horowitz MA, Murray RM, Taylor D. Tapering antipsychotic treatment. JAMA Psychiatry. 2021;78:125&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32777027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correll CU, Rubio JM, Kane JM. Benefits and risks of antipsychotic discontinuation in people with first and multi-episode psychotic disorders or with schizophrenia: Why, when, how and in whom? Schizophrenia. 2025;11:151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12712082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41407745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommer IE, Horowitz M, Allott K, Speyer H, Begemann MJ. Antipsychotic maintenance treatment versus dose reduction: How the story continues. Lancet Psychiatry. 2022;9:602&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35753324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostuzzi G, Vita G, Bertolini F, Tedeschi F, De Luca B, Gastaldon C, et al. Continuing, reducing, switching, or stopping antipsychotics in individuals with schizophrenia-spectrum disorders who are clinically stable: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Lancet Psychiatry. 2022;9:614&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35753323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siskind D, Orr S, Sinha S, Yu O, Brijball B, Warren N, et al. Rates of treatment-resistant schizophrenia from first-episode cohorts: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Psychiatry. 2022;220:115&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35049446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samara M, Lappas AS, Pinioti E, Glarou E, Fober I, Christogiannis C, et al. Efficacy and tolerability of pharmacological interventions for schizophrenia non-responsive to prior treatment: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2025;84:103291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12173738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40535000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grover S, Sarkar S, Sahoo S. Augmentation strategies for clozapine resistance: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Acta Neuropsychiatr. 2023;35:65&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36380513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grover S, Sahoo S, Rabha A, Koirala R. ECT in schizophrenia: A review of the evidence. Acta Neuropsychiatr. 2019;31:115&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30501675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause M, Zhu Y, Huhn M, Schneider-Thoma J, Bighelli I, Nikolakopoulou A, et al. Antipsychotic drugs for patients with schizophrenia and predominant or prominent negative symptoms: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2018;268:625&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29368205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huhn M, Nikolakopoulou A, Schneider-Thoma J, Krause M, Samara M, Peter N, et al. Comparative efficacy and tolerability of 32 oral antipsychotics for the acute treatment of adults with multi-episode schizophrenia: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Lancet. 2019;394:939&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6891890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31303314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabe M, Zhao N, Crippa A, Kaiser S. Antipsychotics for negative and positive symptoms of schizophrenia: Dose-response meta-analysis of randomized controlled acute phase trials. NPJ Schizophr. 2021;7:43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8438046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34518532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galderisi S, Kaiser S, Bitter I, Nordentoft M, Mucci A, Sab&#xe9; M, et al. EPA guidance on treatment of negative symptoms in schizophrenia. Eur Psychiatry. 2021;64:e21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8057437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33726883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howes O, Fusar-Poli P, Osugo M. Treating negative symptoms of schizophrenia: Current approaches and future perspectives. Br J Psychiatry J Ment Sci. 2023;223:332&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37272623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chesney E, Oliver D, Sarma A, Lamper AD, Slimani I, Lloyd M, et al. Does cannabidiol reduce the adverse effects of cannabis in schizophrenia? A randomised, double-blind, cross-over trial. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2025;50:1759&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12518716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40702165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu L, Fang X, Chen Y, Wang Y, Wang D, Zhang C. Efficacy of transcranial direct current stimulation in ameliorating negative symptoms and cognitive impairments in schizophrenia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Schizophr Res. 2020;224:2&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33129639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi C, Yu X, Cheung EF, Shum DH, Chan RC. Revisiting the therapeutic effect of rTMS on negative symptoms in schizophrenia: A meta-analysis. Psychiatry Res. 2014;215:505&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4127383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24411074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharani R, Goyal N, Mukherjee A, Umesh S. Adjuvant high-definition transcranial direct current stimulation for negative symptoms in schizophrenia: A pilot study. J ECT. 2021;37:195&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33661184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varambally S, Holla B, Venkatasubramanian G, Mullapudi T, Raj P, Shivakumar V, et al. Clinical effects of a yoga-based intervention for patients with schizophrenia-A six-month randomized controlled trial. Schizophr Res. 2024;269:144&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38795661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao NP, Ramachandran P, Jacob A, Joseph A, Thonse U, Nagendra B, et al. Add on yoga treatment for negative symptoms of schizophrenia: A multi-centric, randomized controlled trial. Schizophr Res. 2021;231:90&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33831770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stetson SR, Osser DN. Psychopharmacology of agitation in acute psychotic and manic episodes. Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2022;35:171&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35579871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan A, Falkai P, Wobrock T, Lieberman J, Glenthoj B, Gattaz WF, et al. World Federation of Societies of Biological Psychiatry (WFSBP) Guidelines for Biological Treatment of Schizophrenia, part 1: Update 2012 on the acute treatment of schizophrenia and the management of treatment resistance. World J Biol Psychiatry. 2012;13:318&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22834451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bak M, van Os J, Marcelis M. Rapid tranquillisation; review of the literature and recommendations. Tijdschr Voor Psychiatr. 2011;53:727&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21989751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olivola M, Bassetti N, Parente S, Arienti V, Civardi SC, Topa PA, et al. Cognitive effects of lurasidone and cariprazine: A mini systematic review. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2023;21:2431&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10616918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37519001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siskind D, McCartney L, Goldschlager R, Kisely S. Clozapine v. first- and second-generation antipsychotics in treatment-refractory schizophrenia: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Psychiatry J Ment Sci. 2016;209:385&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27388573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samara MT, Dold M, Gianatsi M, Nikolakopoulou A, Helfer B, Salanti G, et al. Efficacy, acceptability, and tolerability of antipsychotics in treatment-resistant schizophrenia: A network meta-analysis. JAMA Psychiatry. 2016;73:199&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26842482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi H, Kantor N, Uchida H, Suzuki T, Remington G. Immediate vs gradual discontinuation in antipsychotic switching: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Schizophr Bull. 2017;43:862&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5472156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28044008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortiz-Orendain J, Castiello-de Obeso S, Colunga-Lozano LE, Hu Y, Maayan N, Adams CE. Antipsychotic combinations for schizophrenia. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;2017:CD009005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6481822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28658515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galling B, Rold&#xe1;n A, Hagi K, Rietschel L, Walyzada F, Zheng W, et al. Antipsychotic augmentation vs. monotherapy in schizophrenia: Systematic review, meta-analysis and meta-regression analysis. World Psychiatry. 2017;16:77&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5269492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28127934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner E, L&#xf6;hrs L, Siskind D, Honer WG, Falkai P, Hasan A. Clozapine augmentation strategies - a systematic meta-review of available evidence. Treatment options for clozapine resistance. J Psychopharmacol Oxf Engl. 2019;33:423&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30696332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leucht S, Cipriani A, Spineli L, Mavridis D, Orey D, Richter F, et al. Comparative efficacy and tolerability of 15 antipsychotic drugs in schizophrenia: A multiple-treatments meta-analysis. Lancet. 2013;382:951&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23810019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veznedaroglu B, Dilbaz N, Uzun O, Isik E. TARC: Turkish aripiprazole consensus report- Aripiprazole use and switching from other antipsychotics to aripiprazole- consensus recommendations by a Turkish multidisciplinary panel. Ther Adv Psychopharmacol. 2018;8:271&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6130089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30210778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE); 2014. Psychosis and schizophrenia in adults: Prevention and management. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK555203/ . [Last cited on 2025 Oct 9]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32207892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correll CU, Citrome L, Haddad PM, Lauriello J, Olfson M, Calloway SM, et al. The use of long-acting injectable antipsychotics in schizophrenia: Evaluating the evidence. J Clin Psychiatry. 2016;77:1&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27732772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keks N, Schwartz D, Hope J. Stopping and switching antipsychotic drugs. Aust Prescr. 2019;42:152&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6787301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31631928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kishi T, Matsuda Y, Iwata N. Memantine add-on to antipsychotic treatment for residual negative and cognitive symptoms of schizophrenia: A meta-analysis. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 2017;234:2113&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28508107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#x103;p&#x103;&#x21b;&#xee;n&#x103; OO, Miclu&#x21b;ia IV, Fadgyas-St&#x103;nculete M. Current perspectives in treating negative symptoms of schizophrenia: A narrative review (review) Exp Ther Med. 2021;21:276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7851661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33603883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh TC, Correll CU, Yang FC, Chen MH, Tseng PT, Hsu CW, et al. Pharmacological and nonpharmacological augmentation treatments for clozapine-resistant schizophrenia: A systematic review and network meta-analysis with normalized entropy assessment. Asian J Psychiatry. 2023;79:103375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36470132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stroup TS, Gerhard T, Crystal S, Huang C, Tan Z, Wall MM, et al. Comparative effectiveness of adjunctive psychotropic medications in patients with schizophrenia. JAMA Psychiatry. 2019;76:508&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6495353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30785609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitehead C, Moss S, Cardno A, Lewis G, Furtado VA. Antidepressants for people with both schizophrenia and depression. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2002;2002:CD002305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6669259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12076447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helfer B, Samara MT, Huhn M, Klupp E, Leucht C, Zhu Y, et al. Efficacy and safety of antidepressants added to antipsychotics for schizophrenia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Psychiatry. 2016;173:876&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27282362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Citrome L, Levine J, Allingham B. Changes in use of valproate and other mood stabilizers for patients with schizophrenia from 1994 to 1998. Psychiatr Serv. 2000;51:634&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10783182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leucht S, Helfer B, Dold M, Kissling W, McGrath JJ. Lithium for schizophrenia. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;2015:CD003834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6984626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26509923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miron AA, Petric PS, Teodorescu A, Ifteni P, Chele G, Szalontay AS. Benzodiazepines and mood stabilizers in schizophrenia patients treated with oral versus long-acting injectable antipsychotics&#x2014;an observational study. Brain Sci. 2023;13:173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9953951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36831716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson SK, Schwarzkopf SB, Palumbo D, Badgley-Fleeman J, Smirnow AM, Light GA. Efficacy and tolerability of low-dose donepezil in schizophrenia. Clin Neuropharmacol. 2005;28:179&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16062097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Iorio G, Baroni G, Lorusso M, Montemitro C, Spano MC, di Giannantonio M. Efficacy of memantine in schizophrenic patients: A systematic review. J Amino Acids. 2017;2017:7021071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5294374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28243470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarris J, Ravindran A, Yatham LN, Marx W, Rucklidge JJ, McIntyre RS, et al. Clinician guidelines for the treatment of psychiatric disorders with nutraceuticals and phytoceuticals: The World Federation of Societies of Biological Psychiatry (WFSBP) and Canadian Network for Mood and Anxiety Treatments (CANMAT) Taskforce. World J Biol Psychiatry. 2022;23:424&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35311615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morein-Zamir S, Turner DC, Sahakian BJ. A review of the effects of modafinil on cognition in schizophrenia. Schizophr Bull. 2007;33:1298&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2779875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17634412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozzatello P, Novelli R, Montemagni C, Rocca P, Bellino S. Nutraceuticals in psychiatric disorders: A systematic review. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25:4824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11084672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38732043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fornaro M, Caiazza C, Billeci M, Berk M, Marx W, Balanz&#xe1;-Mart&#xed;nez V, et al. Nutraceuticals and phytoceuticals in the treatment of schizophrenia: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Res Sq. 2024 rs.3.rs-3787917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39026098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park EJ, Amatya S, Kim MS, Park JH, Seol E, Lee H, et al. Long-acting injectable formulations of antipsychotic drugs for the treatment of schizophrenia. Arch Pharm Res. 2013;36:651&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23543652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grover S, Sahoo S, Bn S, Malhotra N, Dua D, Avasthi A. Attitude and perceptions of patients towards long acting depot injections (LAIs) Asian J Psychiatry. 2019;44:200&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31419737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajatovic M, Ross R, Legacy SN, Correll CU, Kane JM, DiBiasi F, et al. Identifying patients and clinical scenarios for use of long-acting injectable antipsychotics - expert consensus survey part 1. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2018;14:1463&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5997124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29922062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervone A, D&#x2019;Onghia A, Ferrara M, Massaro CR. Efficacy of LAI in first episode psychosis: An observational study--clinical reports. Psychiatr Danub. 2015;27:S348&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26417794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur R, Sidana A, Malhotra N, Tyagi S. Oral versus long-acting injectable antipsychotic in first episode schizophrenia: A 12 weeks interventional study. Indian J Psychiatry. 2023;65:404&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10263095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37325092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etienne M, Verdoux H. Impact of long-acting injectable antipsychotics in early psychosis: An umbrella review. Schizophr Res. 2025;277:140&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40068445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caliskan AM, Karaaslan M, Inanli I, Caliskan S, Arslan M, Esra Cicek I, et al. The effects of adding long-acting injectable antipsychotic drugs to clozapine on relapse and hospitalization in patients with treatment-resistant schizophrenia: A mirror-image retrospective study. Int Clin Psychopharmacol. 2021;36:30&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33044315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakrabarti S. Clozapine resistant schizophrenia: Newer avenues of management. World J Psychiatry. 2021;11:429&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8394694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34513606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oloyede E, Dima A, Taylor D, Cheung H, Dzahini O, Shergill S, et al. Clozapine augmentation with long-acting antipsychotic injections: A case series and systematic review. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2023;148:538&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37899506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grover S, Singla H, Chakrabarti S, Avasthi A. Olanzapine pamoate use for schizophrenia: Retrospective records based study from a Tertiary Care Hospital. Indian J Psychol Med. 2020;42:162&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7173656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32346258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markowicz-Piasecka M, Kubisiak M, Asendrych-Wicik K, Ko&#x142;odziejczyk M, Grzeli&#x144;ska J, Fabija&#x144;ska M, et al. Long-acting injectable antipsychotics&#x2014;a review on formulation and in vitro dissolution. Pharmaceutics. 2023;16:28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10820045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38258037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatterjee S, Naik S, John S, Dabholkar H, Balaji M, Koschorke M, et al. Effectiveness of a community-based intervention for people with schizophrenia and their caregivers in India (COPSI): A randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2014;383:1385&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4255067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24612754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadda RK. Influence of the new mental health legislation in India. BJPsych Int. 2020;17:20&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8277537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34287412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera SN, Sarac C, Phili A, Gorman J, Martin L, Lyallpuri R, et al. Psychoeducation for individuals at clinical high risk for psychosis: A scoping review. Schizophr Res. 2023;252:148&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9974813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36652831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia J, Merinder LB, Belgamwar MR. Psychoeducation for schizophrenia. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2011;2011:CD002831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4170907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21678337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakrabarti S. Family interventions in schizophrenia: Issues of relevance for Asian countries. World J Psychiatry. 2011;1:4&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3782168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24175161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almerie MQ, Okba Al Marhi M, Jawoosh M, Alsabbagh M, Matar HE, Maayan N, et al. Social skills programmes for schizophrenia. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;2015:CD009006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7033904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26059249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopelowicz A, Liberman RP, Zarate R. Recent advances in social skills training for schizophrenia. Schizophr Bull. 2006;32(Suppl 1):S12&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2632540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16885207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avasthi A, Sahoo S, Grover S. Clinical practice guidelines for cognitive behavioral therapy for psychotic disorders. Indian J Psychiatry. 2020;62(Suppl 2):S251&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7001360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32055067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lejeune JA, Northrop A, Kurtz MM. A meta-analysis of cognitive remediation for schizophrenia: Efficacy and the role of participant and treatment factors. Schizophr Bull. 2021;47:997&#x2013;1006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8266668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33772310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowda GS, Isaac MK. Models of care of schizophrenia in the community-an international perspective. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2022;24:195&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8967793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35230610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangalore NG, Varambally S. Yoga therapy for Schizophrenia. Int J Yoga. 2012;5:85&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3410202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22869990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimhy D, Ospina LH, Messer S, Sharma V, Datta SS, Stroup TS. Psychosocial telemedicine interventions for schizophrenia. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2024;2024:CD015260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thara R, Mohan G, Rao S. Making early intervention for psychosis feasible in India: Lessons from two decades of SCARF&#x2019;s first episode psychosis program. Indian J Psychiatry. 2025;67:903&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12468813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41019258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood L, Williams C, Billings J, Johnson S. A systematic review and meta-analysis of cognitive behavioural informed psychological interventions for psychiatric inpatients with psychosis. Schizophr Res. 2020;222:133&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32586627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitko K, Bewick BM, Owens D, Masterson C. Meta-analysis and meta-regression of cognitive behavioral therapy for psychosis (CBTp) across time: The effectiveness of CBTp has improved for delusions. Schizophr Bull Open. 2020;1:sgaa023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melville G, Hoffman M, Pollock A, Kurtz MM. Do metacognitive therapies for schizophrenia-spectrum disorders work? A meta-analytic investigation. Psychol Med. 2024;54:1510&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38509837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allott K, van-der-El K, Bryce S, Parrish EM, McGurk SR, Hetrick S, et al. Compensatory interventions for cognitive impairments in psychosis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Schizophr Bull. 2020;46:869&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7345816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32052837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Hu N, Chai J, Huang W, Yang H, Zhou X, et al. The efficacy of social skills training (SST) and social cognition and interaction training (SCIT) for negative symptoms: A meta-analysis. Eur J Psychiatry. 2024;38:100246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner DT, McGlanaghy E, Cuijpers P, van der Gaag M, Karyotaki E, MacBeth A. A meta-analysis of social skills training and related interventions for psychosis. Schizophr Bull. 2018;44:475&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5890475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29140460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Winter L, Couwenbergh C, van Weeghel J, Sanches S, Michon H, Bond GR. Who benefits from individual placement and support? A meta-analysis. Epidemiol Psychiatr Sci. 2022;31:e50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9281491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35815640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lean M, Fornells-Ambrojo M, Milton A, Lloyd-Evans B, Harrison-Stewart B, Yesufu-Udechuku A, et al. Self-management interventions for people with severe mental illness: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Psychiatry. 2019;214:260&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6499726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30898177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodann-Caudevilla RM, D&#xed;az-Silveira C, Burgos-Juli&#xe1;n FA, Santed MA. Mindfulness-based interventions for people with schizophrenia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:4690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7369977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32629764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabe M, Kaiser S, Sentissi O. Physical exercise for negative symptoms of schizophrenia: Systematic review of randomized controlled trials and meta-analysis. Gen Hosp Psychiatry. 2020;62:13&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31751931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arahanthabailu P, Purohith AN, Kanakode R, Praharaj SK, Bhandary RP, Venkata Narasimha Sharma PS. Modified assertive community treatment program for patients with schizophrenia: Effectiveness and perspectives of service consumers from a South Indian setting. Asian J Psychiatry. 2022;73:103102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35452965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barlati S, Nibbio G, Vita A. Evidence-based psychosocial interventions in schizophrenia: A critical review. Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2024;37:131&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10990032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38410981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pantoji M, Balachander S, Prajapati P, Arumugham SS, Venkatasubramanian G, Thirthalli J. Does adjunctive electro-convulsive therapy improve the speed of treatment response in schizophrenia? A systematic review and week-by-week meta-analyses of controlled clinical trials. Schizophr Res. 2025;285:114&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40966965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thirthalli J, Sinha P, Sreeraj VS. Clinical practice guidelines for the use of electroconvulsive therapy. Indian J Psychiatry. 2023;65:258&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10096214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37063631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi S, Wang Q, Wang W, Hong C, Ren Z. Efficacy of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) on negative symptoms and cognitive functioning in schizophrenia: An umbrella review of systematic reviews and meta-analyses. Psychiatry Res. 2024;333:115728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38232567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blyth SH, Cruz Bosch C, Raffoul JJ, Chesley J, Johnson B, Borodge D, et al. Safety of rTMS for schizophrenia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Schizophr Bull. 2025;51:392&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11908856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39278637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tikka SK, Siddiqui MA, Garg S, Pattojoshi A, Gautam M. Clinical practice guidelines for the therapeutic use of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation in neuropsychiatric disorders. Indian J Psychiatry. 2023;65:270&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10096206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37063630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal SM, Shivakumar V, Bose A, Subramaniam A, Nawani H, Chhabra H, et al. Transcranial direct current stimulation in schizophrenia. Clin Psychopharmacol Neurosci. 2013;11:118&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3897759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24465247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuchl&#xed;kov&#xe1; Z, Kl&#xed;rov&#xe1; M. A literature mini-review of transcranial direct current stimulation in schizophrenia. Front Psychiatry. 2022;13:874128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9069055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35530026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valiengo LD, Goerigk S, Gordon PC, Padberg F, Serpa MH, Koebe S, et al. Efficacy and safety of transcranial direct current stimulation for treating negative symptoms in schizophrenia: A randomized clinical trial. JAMA Psychiatry. 2020;77:121&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6802484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31617873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreeraj VS, Arumugham SS, Venkatasubramanian G. Clinical practice guidelines for the use of transcranial direct current stimulation in psychiatry. Indian J Psychiatry. 2023;65:289&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10096202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37063621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Egea E, McCutcheon RA. Clozapine monitoring requirements: Is it time for an update? Br J Psychiatry J Ment Sci. 2025;226:1&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39359180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdoux H, Bittner RA, Hasan A, Qubad M, Wagner E, Lepetit A, et al. The time has come for revising the rules of clozapine blood monitoring in Europe. A joint expert statement from the European Clozapine Task Force. Eur Psychiatry. 2025;68:e17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11822956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39788917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berardelli I, Rogante E, Sarubbi S, Erbuto D, Lester D, Pompili M. The importance of suicide risk formulation in schizophrenia. Front Psychiatry. 2021;12:779684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8716825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34975579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkhel S, Vijayakumar V, Vijayakumar L. Clinical practice guidelines for management of suicidal behaviour. Indian J Psychiatry. 2023;65:124&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10096207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37063624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bornheimer LA. Suicide prevention in schizophrenia spectrum disorders. Lancet Psychiatry. 2025;12:162&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12291174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39827887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faden J, Citrome L. A systematic review of clozapine for aggression and violence in patients with schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder. Schizophr Res. 2024;268:265&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38290941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huf G, Alexander J, Gandhi P, Allen MH. Haloperidol plus promethazine for psychosis-induced aggression. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;2016:CD005146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27885664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe4;lim&#xe4;ki M, Lantta T, Kontio R. Risk assessment for aggressive behaviour in schizophrenia. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2024;2024:CD012397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11064887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38695777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patchan K, Vyas G, Hackman AL, Mackowick M, Richardson CM, Love RC, et al. Clozapine in reducing aggression and violence in forensic populations. Psychiatr Q. 2018;89:157&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5930356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28643049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautam S, Gautam M, Yadav KS, Chaudhary J, Jain A. Clinical practice guidelines for assessment and management of aggressive and assaultive behaviour. Indian J Psychiatry. 2023;65:131&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10096211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37063635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neyra A, Parro-Torres C, Ros-Cucurull E, Carrera I, Echarri E, Torrens M. Management of schizophrenia and comorbid substance use disorders: Expert review and guidance. Ann Gen Psychiatry. 2024;23:40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11526640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39478536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers JP, Oldham MA, Fricchione G, Northoff G, Ellen Wilson J, Mann SC, et al. Evidence-based consensus guidelines for the management of catatonia: Recommendations from the British Association for Psychopharmacology. J Psychopharmacol Oxf Engl. 2023;37:327&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10101189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37039129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak H, Susan Varghese S, Suhas S, Gunasekaran DM, Gowda GS, Muliyala KP, et al. Risk factors for catatonia relapse in psychotic and affective disorders. JAMA Psychiatry. 2025;82:1015&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12311818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40737013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosolov SN. Diagnosis and treatment depression in schizophrenia. Consort Psychiatr. 2020;1:29&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11240135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39006901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puranen A, Koponen M, L&#xe4;hteenvuo M, Tanskanen A, Tiihonen J, Taipale H. Real-world effectiveness of antidepressant use in persons with schizophrenia: Within-individual study of 61,889 subjects. Schizophr Heidelb Ger. 2023;9:34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10220047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37236980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao YM, Zhang MD. Augmentation with antidepressants in schizophrenia treatment: Benefit or risk. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2015;11:701&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4370910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25834445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lintunen J, Taipale H, Tanskanen A, Mittendorfer-Rutz E, Tiihonen J, L&#xe4;hteenvuo M. Long-term real-world effectiveness of pharmacotherapies for schizoaffective disorder. Schizophr Bull. 2021;47:1099&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8266596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33533399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rey Souto D, Pinz&#xf3;n Espinosa J, Vieta E, Benabarre Hern&#xe1;ndez A. Clozapine in patients with schizoaffective disorder: A systematic review. Rev Psiquiatr Salud Ment (Engl Ed) 2021;14:148&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34400122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma LP, Reddy YC. Obsessive-compulsive disorder comorbid with schizophrenia and bipolar disorder. Indian J Psychiatry. 2019;61(Suppl 1):S140&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6343407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30745688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grover S, Sahoo S, Surendran I. Obsessive-compulsive symptoms in schizophrenia: A review. Acta Neuropsychiatr. 2019;31:63&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30558683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simoila L, Isomets&#xe4; E, Gissler M, Suvisaari J, Halmesm&#xe4;ki E, Lindberg N. Schizophrenia and pregnancy: A national register-based follow-up study among Finnish women born between 1965 and 1980. Arch Womens Ment Health. 2020;23:91&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6987069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30762149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grover S, Avasthi A. Clinical practice guidelines for the management of schizophrenia in children and adolescents. Indian J Psychiatry. 2019;61(Suppl 2):277&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6345123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30745703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeste DV, Maglione JE. Treating older adults with schizophrenia: Challenges and opportunities. Schizophr Bull. 2013;39:966&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3756792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23552180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautam S, Jain A, Gautam M, Gautam A. Clinical practice guideline for management of psychoses in elderly. Indian J Psychiatry. 2018;60(Suppl 3):S363&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5840910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29535470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi N, Ito M. Epilepsy in patients with schizophrenia: Pathophysiology and basic treatments. Epilepsy Behav. 2022;127:108520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34999502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kedare JS, Baliga SP. Management of psychiatric disorders in patients of epilepsy. Indian J Psychiatry. 2022;64(Suppl 2):S319&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9122168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35602355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal N, Mula M. Treatment of psychoses in patients with epilepsy: An update. Ther Adv Psychopharmacol. 2019;9:2045125319862968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6620723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31316747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon V, Ransing R, Praharaj SK. Management of psychiatric disorders in patients with hepatic and gastrointestinal diseases. Indian J Psychiatry. 2022;64(Suppl 2):S379&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9122174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35602369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunther M, Dopheide JA. Antipsychotic safety in liver disease: A narrative review and practical guide for the clinician. J Acad Consult-Liaison Psychiatry. 2023;64:73&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36180017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalal PK, Kar SK, Agarwal SK. Management of psychiatric disorders in patients with chronic kidney diseases. Indian J Psychiatry. 2022;64(Suppl 2):S394&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9122172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35602366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anjana RM, Unnikrishnan R, Deepa M, Pradeepa R, Tandon N, Das AK, et al. Metabolic non-communicable disease health report of India: The ICMR-INDIAB national cross-sectional study (ICMR-INDIAB-17) Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2023;11:474&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37301218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misra A, Chowbey P, Makkar BM, Vikram NK, Wasir JS, Chadha D, et al. Consensus statement for diagnosis of obesity, abdominal obesity and the metabolic syndrome for Asian Indians and recommendations for physical activity, medical and surgical management. J Assoc Physicians India. 2009;57:163&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19582986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganeshalingam AA, Uhrenholt N, Arnfred S, G&#xe6;de P, D&#xfc;ring S, Stenager EN, et al. Semaglutide treatment of antipsychotic-treated patients with schizophrenia, prediabetes, and obesity: The HISTORI randomized clinical trial. JAMA Psychiatry. 2025;82:1065&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12409653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40900607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mental Health Care Act 2017. Section I. New Delhi: Government of India; 2017. The Gazette of India Extraordinary Part II.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malhotra S, Srivastava S, Gowda MR, Sharma N, Gopalan MR, Watve VG, et al. Amend the Mental Health Care Act 2017: A Survey of Indian Psychiatrists (Paper 1) Indian J Psychiatry. 2024;66:829&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11534133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39502587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malhotra S, Srivastava S, Jayaprakashan KP, Gowda MR, Sharma N, Gopalan MR, et al. Amend the Mental Health Care Act 2017: A survey of Indian psychiatrists (Part 2) Indian J Psychiatry. 2024;66:1024&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11708964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39790354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>