<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41841096</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Postoperative Pain Trajectories, Predictors of Severe Pain, and Satisfaction After Bariatric Surgery: A Prospective Multicenter Cohort Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103542</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103542</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103542</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103542</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Postoperative pain remains a clinical priority in bariatric surgery because of its impact on recovery, patient satisfaction, and postoperative complications. However, pain management after bariatric surgery is challenging because of inherent risks, such as respiratory complications, particularly in patients with obstructive sleep apnea (OSA).&#xa0;Current pain management strategies in bariatric surgery remain insufficient, with moderate-to-severe pain reported in 30-50% of patients within 24 hours postoperatively and up to 75% in those using intravenous (IV) patient-controlled analgesia (PCA) after&#xa0;post-anesthesia care unit (PACU) discharge, despite multimodal approaches. Objectives To identify perioperative predictors of severe postoperative pain and patient satisfaction after bariatric surgery. This study aimed to characterize the postoperative pain trajectory and guide future interventional trials in bariatric patients.&#xa0; Methods In this prospective multicenter observational cohort study, 420 adults undergoing bariatric surgery under general anesthesia were followed for the first 48 hours. Data collected included patient demographics, perioperative predictors of postoperative pain, and postoperative pain outcomes at multiple time points from the PACU through 48 hours postoperatively. Pain intensity was measured using the Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) from 0-10, and severe pain was defined as a&#xa0;pain score of &gt;7/10 within the first 24 hours. Patient satisfaction (0-10) and overall pain relief (0-100) were recorded. Secondary outcomes included other pain outcomes during the first 48 hours after surgery. Multivariate logistic regression was used to identify independent predictors of severe postoperative pain, and linear regression analysis was used to identify predictors of patient satisfaction. Results Preliminary findings indicate that 153 of 420 patients (36.4%) experienced severe pain during the first 24 hours. Mean satisfaction was 7.14+1.75, and overall pain relief at 24 hours was 7.14+1.752. Predictors of severe pain included preoperative anxiety, female gender, smoking, preoperative chronic pain, worst postoperative pain, and a greater need for analgesics (all P &lt; 0.05). The strongest predictor of severe pain was uncontrolled early worst pain (regression coefficient = +2.41, OR = 11.13 for worst pain, and P &lt;0.001). The area under the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve (AUC) = 0.81 for severe pain, and it had a pseudo&#x2011;R&#xb2; of 0.18. The strongest predictor of high satisfaction was effective pain relief (regression coefficient = +1.2, and P &lt;0.001). Other predictors of higher satisfaction included preoperative patient education, local anesthetic (LA) infiltration, the use of postoperative regional anesthesia (RA), and PCA (OR 0.055-0.056 for RA/PCA). An R&#xb2; value of 0.855 for satisfaction indicates that 85.5% of the variance in satisfaction scores is explained by the predictors. Conclusions In this multicenter cohort, severe postoperative pain remained prevalent after bariatric surgery. Targeting modifiable perioperative predictors, such as preoperative anxiety, preexisting pain, and uncontrolled early postoperative pain, may reduce the incidence of severe pain. Furthermore, adopting multimodal analgesia strategies, including pre-incisional LA infiltration, postoperative RA, PCA, and structured patient education, may improve overall outcomes and enhance patient satisfaction.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, EL-Tallawy et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Tallawy</LastName><ForeName>Salah N</ForeName><Initials>SN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesia and Pain Management, King Abdulaziz and King Khalid University Hospitals, College of Medicine, King Saud University, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesia and Pain Management, Faculty of Medicine, Minia University, Minia, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pain Management, National Cancer Institute (NCI) Cairo University, Giza, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pergolizzi</LastName><ForeName>Joseph V</ForeName><Initials>JV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pain Management, NEMA Research Inc, Naples, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alsubaie</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah T</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesia and Pain Management, King Abdulaziz University Hospital, King Saud University Medical City, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Rania S</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Alfaisal University College of Medicine, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yousef</LastName><ForeName>Elsayed A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesia and Pain Management, King Abdulaziz University Hospital, College of Medicine, King Saud University, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alsaeed</LastName><ForeName>Khalid M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesia and Pain Management, King Khalid University Hospital, King Saud University Medical City, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amlih</LastName><ForeName>Haneen F</ForeName><Initials>HF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesia and Pain Management, King Khalid University Hospital, King Saud University Medical City, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hetta</LastName><ForeName>Hassan M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesia, ICU, Pain Management, Faculty of Medicine, Minia University, Minia, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdelzaher</LastName><ForeName>Tarek A</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesia, ICU, Pain Management, Faculty of Medicine, Minia University, Minia, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baaj</LastName><ForeName>Jumanna M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesia and Pain Management, King Khalid University Hospital, King Saud University Medical City, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagiub</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, College of Medicine, Badr University, Badr City, New Cairo, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaheen</LastName><ForeName>Issam S</ForeName><Initials>IS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesia and Pain Management, King Khalid University Hospital, King Saud University Medical City, Riyadh, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Radwa H</ForeName><Initials>RH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Pathology Department, Faculty of Medicine, Assiut University, Assiut, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Wegdan A</ForeName><Initials>WA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesia, ICU, Pain Management, Faculty of Medicine, Minia University, Minia, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bariatric surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">esp</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fascial plane block</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pain management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient satisfaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postoperative pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">predictors of severe postoperative pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleeve gastrectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tap</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. College of Medicine, King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia issued approval Ref. No. 18/0443/IRB. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41841096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12989204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Horn R, Hendrix JM, Kramer J. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island: StatPearls Publishing; 2025. Postoperative pain control.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31335018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Advances in the management of acute postsurgical pain: a review. Paladini A, Rawal N, Coca Martinez M, et al. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10475855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37671225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of postoperative pain: a clinical practice guideline from the American Pain Society, the American Society of Regional Anesthesia and Pain Medicine, and the American Society of Anesthesiologists' Committee on Regional Anesthesia, Executive Committee, and Administrative Council. Chou R, Gordon DB, de Leon-Casasola OA, et al. J Pain. 2016;17:131&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26827847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The prevalence of pain in the first 24 hours after surgery: a multicenter study. Yaz&#x131;c&#x131; G, Y&#x131;lmaz K, Bulut H, &#xd6;mer Ka&#x15f;&#x131;k&#xe7;&#x131; H, Palteki T, Karabulut AB, Memi&#x15f;o&#x11f;lu K. J Perianesth Nurs. 2022;37:122&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34865966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peri-operative pain in patients experiencing bariatric surgery. Kumar N, Soekarman D, Singh R, Bashah MM, Abou Samra AB, Marcus MA. Med Clin Arch. 2017;1:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enhanced recovery after surgery in bariatric surgery. Huh YJ, Kim DJ. J Metab Bariatr Surg. 2021;10:47&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9847637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36683671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute pain management in patients with severe obesity. Budiansky AS, Eipe N. BJA Educ. 2024;24:318&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11368600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39234153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Identifying predictors of early postoperative pain and patient satisfaction following day surgery: insights from an observational study. El-Tallawy SN, Alsubaie AT, Yousef EA, et al. Cureus. 2025;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12265008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40671990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Identifying risk factors for chronic postsurgical pain and preventive measures: a comprehensive update. Pergolizzi JV Jr, LeQuang JA, Magnusson P, Varrassi G. Expert Rev Neurother. 2023;23:1297&#x2013;1310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37999989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Disparities in postoperative pain management: a scoping review of prescription practices and social determinants of health. Snell A, Lobaina D, Densley S, et al. Pharmacy (Basel) 2025;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11932221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40126307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postoperative pain trajectories and pain chronification-an empirical typology of pain patients. Althaus A, Arr&#xe1;nz Becker O, Moser KH, Lux EA, Weber F, Neugebauer E, Simanski C. Pain Med. 2018;19:2536&#x2013;2545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29800281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correlation between postoperative pain trajectories and recovery after day surgery: a protocol for a prospective cohort study. Yang D, Wang X, Li X, Su S, Yang L, Fan D. BMJ Open. 2025;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12458868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40973381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE): explanation and elaboration. Vandenbroucke JP, von Elm E, Altman DG, et al. Ann Intern Med. 2007;147:0&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17938389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preventive analgesia for postoperative pain control: a broader concept. Vadivelu N, Mitra S, Schermer E, Kodumudi V, Kaye AD, Urman RD. Local Reg Anesth. 2014;7:17&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4012350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24872720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regional anesthesia in bariatric surgery. De Cassai A, Tulgar S, Carron M, Navalesi P. Curr Opin Anaesthesiol. 2025;38:611&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12382722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40407104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association between smoking and opioid requirement and pain intensity in the early postoperative period: a meta-analysis. Szilagyi IS, Ullrich T, Klivinyi C, Lang-Illievich K, Brenna CT, Messerer B, Bornemann-Cimenti H. Pain Ther. 2026;15:341&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12804480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41389119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feasibility and efficacy of erector spinae plane block versus transversus abdominis plane block in laparoscopic bariatric surgery: a randomized comparative trial. Elshazly M, El-Halafawy YM, Mohamed DZ, Wahab KA, Mohamed TM. Korean J Anesthesiol. 2022;75:502&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9726464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35581710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erector spinae plane block for postoperative pain. Schnabel A, Weibel S, Pogatzki-Zahn E, Meyer-Frie&#xdf;em CH, Oostvogels L. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2023;10:13763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10561350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37811665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison between erector spinae plane block at T9 level and transversus abdominis plane block for postoperative analgesia and recovery in patients with obesity undergoing laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy: a randomized controlled trial. Mu T, Chen K, Xu Y, Hao Y, Liu D, Wei K. Obes Surg. 2025;35:2249&#x2013;2263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40377814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erector spinae block reduces intraoperative and postoperative opioid consumption in patients undergoing laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy: a randomized controlled trial. Ul Huda A, Alshahrani AS, Yasir M, Sawilah A, Alharthi AA. Qatar Med J. 2024;2024:58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11816789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39944209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A risk factor prediction model for moderate-to-severe postoperative pain in patients undergoing laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy. Yang Y, Zhang C, Chi W, et al. Medicine (Baltimore) 2025;104:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11813011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39928828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk factors for acute postsurgical pain: a narrative review. Liu QR, Dai YC, Ji MH, Liu PM, Dong YY, Yang JJ. J Pain Res. 2024;17:1793&#x2013;1804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11122256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38799277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perioperative pain correlates and prolonged postoperative pain predictors: demographic and psychometric questionnaires. MacLachlan C, Shipton EA, Wells JE. Pain Ther. 2015;4:119&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4470970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26037628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pain management strategies and patient satisfaction in post-operative care. Al Huraiz KH, Alhuraiz SH. Saudi J Med Pharm Sci. 2015;1:124&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk factors for moderate to severe pain during the first 24 hours after laparoscopic bariatric surgery while receiving intravenous patient-controlled analgesia. Iamaroon A, Tangwiwat S, Nivatpumin P, Lertwacha T, Rungmongkolsab P, Pangthipampai P. Anesthesiol Res Pract. 2019;2019:6593736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6794962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31687018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Predicting factors that determine patients' satisfaction with post-operative pain management following abdominal surgeries at Komfo Anokye Teaching Hospital, Kumasi, Ghana. Tano PF, Apiribu F, Tano EK, Boamah Mensah AB, Dzomeku VM, Boateng I. PLoS One. 2021;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8148314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patient satisfaction with post-operative pain management and associated factors among surgical patients at Tikur Anbessa Specialized Hospital: cross-sectional study. Buli B, Gashaw A, Gebeyehu G, Abrar M, Gerbessa B. Ann Med Surg (Lond) 2022;79:104087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9289483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35860062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical practice guidelines for postoperative pain management in adults. Chen X, Chu Q, Peng Y, et al. J Anesth Transl Med. 2025;4:161&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Implementation of a standardized multimodal pain regimen significantly reduces postoperative inpatient opioid utilization in patients undergoing bariatric surgery. Tan WH, Ford J, Kindel T, Higgins RM, Lak K, Gould JC. Surg Endosc. 2023;37:3103&#x2013;3112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35927346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comprehensive review on personalized pain assessment and multimodal interventions for postoperative recovery optimization. Xu J, Liu X, Zhao J, Zhao J, Li H, Ye H, Ai S. J Pain Res. 2025;18:2791&#x2013;2804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12147818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40491876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postoperative pain management: evaluating the role of multimodal analgesia. Gautam A, Pande C, Pande M. J Pharm Bioallied Sci. 2025;17:0&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12156663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40511097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obstructive sleep apnea and postoperative hyperalgesia in bariatric surgery: a prospective observational cohort study. Zhong Z, Lu X, Zhang Q, Zhang Y. J Pain Res. 2025;18:4527&#x2013;4538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12415099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40927033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of age on postoperative complications following bariatric surgery. Ahmed AE, Alanazi WR, ALuqbil BI, AlJohi WA, AlRasheed BA, AlBuraikan DA, Ahmed RA. Qatar Med J. 2019;2019:11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6883749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31819857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>