<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41824224</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-3645</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of medical humanities</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Humanit</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Injury Studies: Setting the Agenda for a Critical Medical Humanities Approach to the Control, Perception, Representation, and Experience of Injuries.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10912-026-10009-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This article describes a new and expanding field in the health humanities: injury studies. Following a recent international conference sponsored by the U.S. National Endowment for the Humanities, the members of the Injury Studies Network have stitched together disciplines across the humanities, social sciences, medicine, and the creative arts to examine how we live with and make meaning out of injuries. This article explains how this research program extends beyond conventional injury prevention, which tends to define injuries as measurable and theoretically controllable public health outcomes. Drawing on the critical medical humanities, we retheorize injuries as pivotal events for individuals and communities and as powerful lenses for interpreting physical and mental trauma, sociocultural experiences of risk and safety, and the body. Injuries, we contend, are complex events that disrupt the lives of their casualties and fuel broader social and creative processes. These processes extend outward from the moment of injury, reshaping the presents, remembered pasts, and possible futures of injured and uninjured people. This article critically reviews five themes from the literature on injuries and analyzes a series of case studies to lay out this framework for current and future investigators. We also offer a set of cross-cutting research questions on the perception, control, representation, and experience of injuries. Overall, we make the case for injury studies as a site for innovative medical humanities research with the potential to bring together siloed work on injuries, accidents, safety, trauma, risk, recovery, and disability; to enhance graduate and undergraduate education; and to inform interdisciplinary approaches to public health, clinical medicine, and health policy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parry</LastName><ForeName>Alexander I</ForeName><Initials>AI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Humanities and Bioethics, University of Rochester Medical Center, Rochester, United States. alexander_parry@urmc.rochester.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Slobogin</LastName><ForeName>Christine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Humanities and Bioethics, University of Rochester Medical Center, Rochester, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Filippaki</LastName><ForeName>Iro</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of English Language and Literature, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RZ-292795-23</GrantID><Agency>U.S. National Endowment for the Humanities</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Humanit</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8917478</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1041-3545</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Accidents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Critical medical humanities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Safety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Trauma</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing Interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41824224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10912-026-10009-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10912-026-10009-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Adams, Annmarie. 1996. Architecture in the family way: Doctors, houses, and women, 1870&#x2013;1900. Montreal: McGill-Queen&#x2019;s University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/9780773565869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agree, Emily M. 2014. The potential for technology to enhance independence for those aging with a disability. Disability and Health Journal 7(1): S33&#x2013;S39. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dhjo.2013.09.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dhjo.2013.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberti, Samuel J. M. M. 2014. War, art and surgery: The works of Henry Tonks and Julia Midgley. London: Royal College of Surgeons of England.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albrecht, Gary L., Katherine D. Seelman, and Michael Bury, eds. 2003. Handbook of disability studies. Newbury Park: Sage Publishing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldrich, Mark. 2006. Death rode the rails: American railroad accidents and safety, 1828&#x2013;1965. Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldrich, Mark. 1997. Safety first: Technology, labor, and business in the building of American work safety, 1870&#x2013;1939. Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Gas Association (AGA). 2025. Using natural gas safely. American Gas Association. https://www.aga.org/natural-gas/safety/using-natural-gas-safely/ . Accessed 24 April 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson, Julie. 2011. War, disability and rehabilitation in Britain: &#x201c;Soul of a nation.&#x201d; Manchester: Manchester University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apple, Rima D. 2006. Perfect motherhood: Science and childrearing in America. New Brunswick: Rutgers University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aronowitz, Robert. 2015. Risky medicine: Our quest to cure fear and uncertainty. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7208/chicago/9780226049854.001.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ataria, Yochai, et al., eds. 2016. Interdisciplinary handbook of trauma and culture. New York: Springer.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austen, Jane. 2008 [1818]. Persuasion. Ed. W. H. Galperin. New York: Pearson/Longman.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachynski, Kathleen. 2019. No game for boys to play: The history of youth football and the origins of a public health crisis. Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5149/northcarolina/9781469653709.001.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakay, Louis. 1971. The treatment of head injuries in the Thirty Years&#x2019; War (1618&#x2013;1648): Joannes Scultetus and his age. Springfield: C. C. Thomas.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballard, James G. 1973. Crash. London: Jonathan Cape.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bate, Jason. 2020. Bonds of kinship and care: RAMC photographic albums and the making of &#x201c;other&#x201d; domestic lives. Social History of Medicine 33(3): 772&#x2013;797. https://doi.org/10.1093/shm/hky120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/shm/hky120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baudrillard, Jean. 1991. Jean Baudrillard: Two essays &#x2013; simulacra and science fiction / Ballard&#x2019;s Crash. Trans. Arthur B. Evans. Science Fiction Studies 18(3): 313&#x2013;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck, Ulrich. 1992. Risk society: Towards a new modernity. Trans. Mark Ritter. London: SAGE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck, Ulrich. 1999. World risk society. Cambridge: Polity Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrman, Joanna. 2017. Domesticating physics: Introductory physics textbooks for women in home economics in the United States, 1914&#x2013;1955. History of Education Quarterly 46(2): 193&#x2013;209. https://doi.org/10.1080/0046760X.2016.1273404</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0046760X.2016.1273404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger, Elena, and Sergey Glyantsev. 2019. Wounded: &#x201c;They had no fever&#x2026;&#x201d; Ambroise Par&#xe9; (1510&#x2013;1590) and his method of gunshot wounds management. Science Museum Group Journal Spring. https://doi.org/10.15180/191105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry, Sarah L., and Erin Gentry Lamb. 2024. Health humanities baccalaureate programs in the United States and Canada. Case Western Reserve University. https://case.edu/medicine/bioethics/education/health-humanities . Accessed 6 September 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berson, M. I. 1948. Atlas of plastic surgery. New York: Grune &amp; Stratton.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biehler, Dawn Day. 2013. Pests in the city: Flies, bedbugs, cockroaches, and rats. Seattle: University of Washington Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/9780295804866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biernoff, Suzannah. 2012. Medical archives and digital culture. Photographies 5(2): 179&#x2013;202. https://doi.org/10.1080/17540763.2012.702680</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17540763.2012.702680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biernoff, Suzannah. 2016. Picturing pain. In The Edinburgh companion to the critical medical humanities, eds. Anne Whitehead, Angela Woods, Jane Macnaughton, and Jennifer Richards, 163&#x2013;185. Edinburgh: Edinburgh University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/9781474400053-012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blandford, Edward D., and Scott D. Sagan, eds. 2016. Learning from a disaster: Improving nuclear safety and security after Fukushima. Redwood City: Stanford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnie, Richard J., and Bernard Guyer. 2002. Injury as a field of public health: Achievements and controversies. Journal of Law, Medicine, and Ethics 30(2): 267&#x2013;280. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1748-720X.2002.tb00393.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-720X.2002.tb00393.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borden, Mary. 1929. The forbidden zone. London: William Heinemann Limited.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouk, Dan. 2015. How our days became numbered: Risk and the rise of the statistical individual. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7208/chicago/9780226259208.001.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke, Joanna. 1996. Dismembering the male: Men&#x2019;s bodies, Britain and the Great War. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks, Gwendolyn. 1953. Home. In Maud Martha. Chicago: Harper &amp; Brothers.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, Kate. 2013. Plutopia: Nuclear families, atomic cities, and the Great Soviet and American plutonium disasters. New York: Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, Michael. 2022. Emotions and surgery in Britain, 1793&#x2013;1912. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/9781108877237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, Michael. 2020. Wounds and wonder: Emotion, imagination and war in the cultures of Romantic surgery. Journal for Eighteenth-Century Studies 43(2): 239&#x2013;259. https://doi.org/10.1111/1754-0208.12684</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1754-0208.12684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckland, R. 2025. Narratives of injury: Nineteenth-century coalfields fiction. New York: Routledge. https://doi.org/10.4324/9781003478973</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4324/9781003478973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnham, John C. 2009. Accident prone: A history of technology, psychology, and misfits of the Machine Age. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7208/chicago/9780226081199.001.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnham, John C. 1996. Why did the infants and toddlers die? Shifts in Americans&#x2019; ideas of responsibility for accidents&#x2014;from blaming Mom to engineering. Journal of Social History 29(4): 817&#x2013;837. https://doi.org/10.1353/jsh/29.4.817</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/jsh/29.4.817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler, Judith. 2004. Precarious life: The powers of mourning and violence. London: Verso.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campkin, Ben, and Rosie Cox, eds. 2007. Dirt: New geographies of cleanliness and contamination. London: I. B. Tauris.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canning, Charlotte. 2005. Feminist theatres in the USA: Staging women&#x2019;s experience. London: Routledge.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4324/9780203991466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capcom. 2021. Resident evil village [PS4].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carden-Coyne, Ana. 2014. The politics of wounds: Military patients and medical power in&#xa0;the First World War. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casper, Stephen T. 2022. Punch-Drunk slugnuts: Violence and the vernacular history of disease. Isis 113(2): 266&#x2013;288. https://doi.org/10.1086/719720</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/719720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cha, Amy E., and Xun Wang. 2023. Activity-limiting injury in adults: United States, 2020&#x2212;2021. National Center for Health Statistics Data Brief 476. https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/products/databriefs/db476.htm . Accessed 17 March 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Champaneria, Manish C., et al. 2014. Sushruta: Father of plastic surgery. Annals of Plastic Surgery 73(1): 2&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1097/SAP.0b013e31827ae9f5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SAP.0b013e31827ae9f5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Injury Research and Policy (CIRP). 2024. About. Johns Hopkins Center for Injury Research and Policy. https://publichealth.jhu.edu/center-for-injury-research-and-policy/about . Accessed 20 September 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). 2024. Injury Center research priorities. CDC.Gov. https://www.cdc.gov/injury-violence-prevention/programs/research-priorities.html . Accessed 6 September 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). 2025. Injury Control Research Centers. CDC.Gov. https://www.cdc.gov/injury-icrc/php/centers/index.html . Accessed 17 March 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centre for Injury Studies, Imperial College London (CIS). 2025. About the Centre. Imperial. https://www.imperial.ac.uk/injury-studies/about-the-centre/ . Accessed 24 March 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chambers, Emma. 2009. Fragmented identities: Reading subjectivity in Henry Tonks&#x2019; surgical portraits. Art History 32(3): 578&#x2013;607.&#xa0; https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8365.2009.00684.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-8365.2009.00684.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Changing Faces. 2025. I am not your villain: Equal representation of visible difference in film. Changing Faces. https://www.changingfaces.org.uk/get-involved/campaign-with-us/i-am-not-your-villian/ . Accessed 25 June 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cock, Emily. 2019. Rhinoplasty and the nose in early modern British medicine and culture. Manchester: University of Manchester Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7765/9781526137173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen, Lizabeth. 2003. A consumers&#x2019; republic: The politics of mass consumption in postwar America. New York: Vintage Books.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooter, Roger. 1990. Medicine and the goodness of war. Canadian Bulletin of Medical History 7(2): 147&#x2013;159. https://doi.org/10.3138/cbmh.7.2.147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3138/cbmh.7.2.147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooter, Roger. 1993. Surgery and society in peace and war: Orthopedics and the organization of modern medicine, 1880&#x2013;1948. Basingstoke: Macmillan Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-137-10235-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooter, Roger, and Bill Luckin, eds. 1997. Accidents in history: Injuries, fatalities and social relations. Atlanta: Rodopi.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowan, Ruth Schwartz. 1983. More work for mother: The ironies of household technology from the open hearth to the microwave. New York: Basic Books.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cresswell, Rosemary. 2020. The &#x201c;British Red Cross still exists,&#x201d; 1947&#x2013;74: Finding a role after the Second World War. In The Red Cross Movement: Myths, Practices and Turning Points, eds. Neville Wylie, Melanie Oppenheimer, and James Crossland, 148&#x2013;163. Manchester: Manchester University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Criado Perez, Caroline. 2019. Invisible women: Data bias in a world designed for men. New York: Abrams Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crook, Tom, and Mike Esbester, eds. 2016. Governing risks in modern Britain: Danger, safety and accidents, c. 1800&#x2013;2000. London: Palgrave Macmillan.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullinane, Susannah, et al. 10 January 2022. Space heater sparked fire in the Bronx that killed 17 people, including 8 children. CNN. https://edition.cnn.com/2022/01/10/us/nyc-bronx-apartment-fire-monday . Accessed 24 April 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Health Humanities and Bioethics, University of Rochester Medical Center (URMC). 2023. Beyond observation: Developing clinical competencies at the art gallery. Five question protocol: Art and observation at the University of Rochester. https://medhum.digitalscholar.rochester.edu/ . Accessed 1 June 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luck, Patricia, Zonia Ali, and Christopher J. Mooney. 2025. Small but mighty: The Photo/Tiny Story, a tool for reflection in medical education. Academic Medicine. https://doi.org/10.1093/acamed/wvaf028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devine, Shauna. 2014. Learning from the wounded: The Civil War and the rise of American medical science. Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas, Mary. 1966. Purity and danger: An analysis of concepts of pollution and taboo. London: Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas, Mary, and Aaron B. Wildavsky. 1982. Risk and culture: An essay on the selection of technical and environmental dangers. Berkeley: University of California Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durham University Institute for Medical Humanities. 2025. Mapping the global medical humanities. Discovery Research Platform for Medical Humanities. https://medhumsplatform.org/global-medical-humanities-map/ . Accessed 1 June 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards, M. L. 2019. Pittsburgh&#x2019;s Freedom House Ambulance Service: The origins of emergency medical services and the politics of race and health. Journal of the History of Medicine and Allied Sciences 74: 440-466. https://doi.org/10.1093/jhmas/jrz041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jhmas/jrz041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekins, Ashley, and Elizabeth Stewart, eds. 2011. War wounds: Medicine and the trauma of conflict. Wollombi: Exisle Publishing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engel, George L. 1977. The need for a new medical model: A challenge for biomedicine. Science 196(4286): 129&#x2013;136. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.847460</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.847460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esbester, Mike, Karen Baker, and James King. 2025. Home. Railway Work, Life and Death Project. https://www.railwayaccidents.port.ac.uk/ . Accessed 2 June 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esbester, Mike. 2018. Transformative propaganda: Opening the archives of the British Safety Council. London: Routledge.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4324/9780429429132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esbester, Mike, and Jameson M. Wetmore, eds. 2015. (Auto)mobility, accidents, and danger. Technology and Culture 56(2): 307&#x2013;497. https://doi.org/10.1353/tech.2015.0059</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ewen, Shane, Jonathan Reinarz, Aaron Andrews, and Rebecca Wynter. 2023. Home. Forged by Fire. https://forged-by-fire.wixsite.com/home . Accessed 14 April 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallon, Cara Kiernan. 2019. Husbands&#x2019; hearts and women&#x2019;s health: Gender, age, and heart disease in twentieth-century America. Bulletin of the History of Medicine 93(4): 577&#x2013;609. https://doi.org/10.1353/bhm.2019.0073</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippaki, Iro. 2021. The poetics of post&#x2011;traumatic stress disorder in postmodern literature. New York: Palgrave Macmillan.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-67630-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgerald, Des, and Felicity Callard. 2016. Entangling the medical humanities. In The Edinburgh companion to the critical medical humanities, eds. Anne Whitehead and Angela Woods, 35-49. Edinburgh: Edinburgh University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/9781474400053-004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleishman, Ian. 2018. An aesthetics of injury: The narrative wound from Baudelaire to Tarantino. Evanston: Northwestern University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/j.ctv47wb3z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foucault, Michel. 1982. The subject and power. Critical Inquiry 8(4): 777&#x2013;795. https://doi.org/10.1086/448181</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/448181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frattaroli, Shannon, et al. 2020. Extreme risk protection orders in King County, Washington: The epidemiology of dangerous behaviors and an intervention response. Injury Epidemiology 7(44): 1&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40621-020-00270-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40621-020-00270-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frieden, Thomas. 2010. A framework for public health action: The health impact pyramid. American Journal of Public Health 100(4): 590&#x2013;595. https://doi.org/10.2105/AJPH.2009.185652</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2009.185652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriadze, Levan (Director). 2014. Unfriended [Film]. Universal Pictures.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geertz, Clifford. 1973. The interpretation of cultures. New York: Basic Books.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerber, David A. 2012. Disabled veterans in history. Ann Arbor: University of Michigan Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3998/mpub.3874458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert, Mark. 2010. Saving faces. MarkGilbert.Co.UK. http://www.markgilbert.co.uk/index.php?/project/saving-faces/ . Accessed 25 June 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giles, Audrey, Michelle E. E. Bauer, and Janet Jull. 2020. Equity as the fourth &#x201c;E&#x201d; in the &#x201c;3 E&#x2019;s&#x201d; approach to injury prevention. Injury Prevention 26(1): 82&#x2013;84. https://doi.org/10.1136/injuryprev-2019-043407</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/injuryprev-2019-043407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillies, Harold D. 1920. Plastic surgery of the face: Based on selected cases of war injuries of the face, including burns, with original illustrations. London: Oxford University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00000658-192012000-00015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilligan, Carol. 2015. The listening guide method of psychological inquiry. Qualitative Psychology 2(1): 69&#x2013;77. https://doi.org/10.1037/qup0000023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleason, Mona. 2005. From &#x201c;disgraceful carelessness&#x201d; to &#x201c;intelligent precaution&#x201d;: Accidents and the public child in English Canada, 1900&#x2013;1950. Journal of Family History 30(2): 230&#x2013;241. https://doi.org/10.1177/0363199004270785</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363199004270785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glickman, Lawrence B. 2019. Free enterprise: An American history. New Haven: Yale University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/j.ctvmd85bc</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein, Carolyn M. 2012. Creating consumers: Home economists in twentieth-century America. Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5149/9780807872383_goldstein</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene, Jeremy. 2008. Prescribing by numbers: Drugs and the definition of disease. Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/book.3313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guarnieri, Michael. 1992. Landmarks in the history of safety. Journal of Safety Research 23: 151&#x2013;158. https://doi.org/10.1016/0022-4375(92)90018-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-4375(92)90018-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guly, Henry. 2005. A history of accident and emergency medicine, 1948&#x2013;2004. New York: Palgrave Macmillan.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1057/9780230000742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall, Alice. 2016. Literature and disability. London: Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haller, John S. 2011. Battlefield medicine: A history of the military ambulance from the Napoleonic Wars through World War I. Carbondale: Southern Illinois University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampton, Jameel. 2016. Disability and the welfare state in Britain: Changes in perception and policy 1948-79. Bristol: Policy Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.56687/9781447316435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanaway, Joseph, and John H. Burgess. 2016. The General: A history of the Montreal General Hospital. Montreal: McGill-Queen&#x2019;s University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/9780773598645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harpman, Jacqueline. 2019 [1995]. I who have never known men. London: Vintage.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartnell, Jack. 2017. Wording the wound man. In British art studies: Invention and imagination in British art and architecture, 600&#x2013;1500, eds. Jessica Berenbeim and Sandy Heslop. New Haven: Yale University Press. https://britishartstudies.ac.uk/issues/06/_assets/downloads/publication-wound-man.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartnell, Jack. 2025. Wound man: The many lives of a surgical image. Princeton: Princeton University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/9780691274454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayden, Dolores. 2002. Redesigning the American dream: Gender, housing, and family life. New York: W. W. Norton &amp; Company.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haytock, Jennifer, ed. 2021. War and American literature. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hevey, David. 1992. The creatures time forgot: Photography and disability imagery. London: Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, Charlotte. 2022. In times as troubled as these, can we still believe in tragedy? The Guardian. https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2022/jan/15/tragedy-pandemics-climate-crisis-algorithms-tech-drama . Accessed 25 June 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilton, Matthew. 2009. Prosperity for all: Consumer activism in an era of globalization. Ithaca: Cornell University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman, Beatrix. 2006. Emergency rooms: The reluctant safety net. In History and health policy: Bringing the past back in, eds. Rosemary Stevens, Charles Rosenberg, and Lawton R. Burns, 250&#x2013;272. New Brunswick: Rutgers University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman, Beatrix. 2012. Health care for some: Rights and rationing in the United States since 1930. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7208/chicago/9780226348056.001.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horowitz, Andy. 2022. Katrina: A history, 1915&#x2013;2015. Cambridge: Harvard University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huyler, Frank. 1999. The blood of strangers: Stories from emergency medicine. Berkeley: University of California Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1525/9780520950726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain, S. Lochlann. 2006. Injury: The politics of product design and safety law in the United States. Princeton: Princeton University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/9780691190242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jasanoff, Sheila. 1986. Risk management and political culture. New York: Russell Sage Foundation.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, Marian Moser. 2013. The American Red Cross from Clara Barton to the New Deal. Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ionescu, Arleen, and Maria Margaroni, eds. 2020. Arts of healing: Cultural narratives of trauma. New York: Rowman &amp; Littlefield International.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kafka, Franz. 2020 [1919]. In the penal colony. Trans. Ian Johnston. Franz Kafka Online. https://www.kafka-online.info/in-the-penal-colony.html . Accessed 1 June 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keeling, Arlene, and Barbra Mann Wall, eds. 2015. Nurses and disasters: Global, historical case studies. New York: Springer.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keesey, Douglas. 2002. &#x201c;Your legs must be singing grand opera&#x201d;: Masculinity, masochism, and Stephen King&#x2019;s Misery. American Imago 59(1): 53&#x2013;71. https://doi.org/10.1353/aim.2002.0005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/aim.2002.0005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kember, Joe. 2016. Face value: The rhetoric of facial disfigurement in American film and popular culture, 1917&#x2013;1927. Journal of War and Culture Studies 10(1): 43&#x2013;65. https://doi.org/10.1080/17526272.2016.1224034</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17526272.2016.1224034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendi, Sadiqa, and Michelle Macy. 2023. The injury equity framework&#x2014;establishing a unified approach for addressing inequities. New England Journal of Medicine 388(9): 774&#x2013;776. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMp2212378</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMp2212378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King, Stephen. 1987. Misery. New York: Viking.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowles, Scott Gabriel. 2011. The disaster experts: Mastering risk in modern America. Philadelphia: University of Pennsylvania Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9783/9780812207996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraft, James P. 2021. Havoc and reform: Workplace disasters in modern America. Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/book.82801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurtz, J. Roger, ed. 2018. Trauma and literature. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakoff, Andrew. 2017. Unprepared: Global health in a time of emergency. Berkeley: University of California Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1525/9780520968417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerman, Nina E., Ruth Oldenziel, and Arwen P. Mohun, eds. 2003. Gender and technology: A reader. Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy, Jonathan. 2014. Freaks of fortune: The emerging world of capitalism and risk in America. Cambridge: Harvard University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linker, Beth. 2013. On the borderland of medical and disability history: A survey of the fields. Bulletin of the History of Medicine 87(4): 499&#x2013;535. https://doi.org/10.1353/bhm.2013.0074</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/bhm.2013.0074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linker, Beth. 2011. War&#x2019;s waste: Rehabilitation in World War I America. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7208/chicago/9780226482552.001.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowell, Robert. 1977. Home after three months away. In Selected Poems: Expanded Edition, 127&#x2013;128. New York: Farrar, Straus and Giroux.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luckhurst, Roger. 2008. The trauma question. Abingdon: Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupton, Deborah. 2013. Risk. London: Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lytvynova, Polina. 2025. 5 Ukrainian women wounded in war appear in latest edition of Playboy. NPR. https://www.npr.org/2025/05/13/nx-s1-5394929/5-ukrainian-women-wounded-in-war-appear-in-latest-edition-of-playboy . Accessed 25 June 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mace, Sharon E., et al. 2001. Injury prevention and control in children. Annals of Emergency Medicine 38(4): 405&#x2013;414. https://doi.org/10.1067/mem.2001.115882</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maines, Rachel. 2005. Asbestos and fire: Technological trade-offs and the body at risk. New Brunswick: Rutgers University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majno, Guido. 1975. The healing hand: Man and wound in the ancient world. Cambridge: Harvard University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markowitz, Gerald, and David Rosner, eds. 1987. Dying for work: Workers&#x2019; safety and health in twentieth-century America. Bloomington: Indiana University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markowitz, Gerald, and David Rosner. 2013. Lead wars: The politics of science and the fate of America&#x2019;s children. Berkeley: University of California Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masco, Joseph. 2014. The theater of operations: National security affect from the Cold War to the War on Terror. Durham: Duke University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1215/9780822375999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matheson, Richard (Writer), and Jacques Tourneur (Director). 7 February 1964. Night call (Season 5, Episode 19) [TV series episode]. In The Twilight Zone. CBS.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew, Emily. 2013. Wounded: A new history of the Western Front in World War I. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKevitt, Andrew C. 2023. Gun country: Gun capitalism, culture, and control in Cold War America. Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/book.114451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyers, Todd, and Stefanos Geroulanos. 2018. The human body in the age of catastrophe: Brittleness, integration, science, and the Great War. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7208/chicago/9780226556628.001.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michael, Jeffrey P., et al. 2023. A safe system guide for transportation: Sharing this approach to lead your community to action. Washington: AAA Foundation for Traffic Safety. https://aaafoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/202311-AAAFTS-Safe-System-Approach.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millett-Gallant, Ann. 2010. The disabled body in contemporary art. New York: Palgrave Macmillan.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1057/9780230109971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millett-Gallant, Ann, and Elizabeth Howie, eds. 2017. Disability and art history. London: Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohun, Arwen P. 2013. Risk: Negotiating safety in American society. Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mooney, Graham. 2015. Intrusive interventions: Public health, domestic space, and infectious disease surveillance in England, 1840&#x2013;1914. Rochester: University of Rochester Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/9781580468893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss, David A. 2002. When all else fails: Government as the ultimate risk manager. Cambridge: Harvard University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray, Stuart. 2023. Medical humanities and disability studies: In/disciplines. London: Bloomsbury.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5040/9781350172203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy, Michelle. 2006. Sick building syndrome and the problem of uncertainty: Environmental politics, technoscience, and women workers. Durham: Duke University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11smh9f</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Commission on Product Safety (NCPS). 1970. Hearings, volume IX: Washington, March 1970. New York: Law-Arts Publishers.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Safety Council (NSC). 2025. All injuries. Injury Facts. https://injuryfacts.nsc.org/all-injuries/overview/ . Accessed 17 March 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Safety Council (NSC). 1926. Essentials of a community safety program. Chicago: National Safety Council.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols, Charles A. (Director) and Jack Kinney and Bill Berg (Writers). 8 July 1956. How to have an accident at home. Walt Disney Productions.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols, Charles A. (Director) and Jack Kinney and Bill Berg (Writers). 2 September 1959. How to have an accident at work. Walt Disney Productions.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfc;nning, Ansgar. 2012. Narrativist approaches and narratological concepts for the study of culture. In Travelling concepts for the study of culture, eds. Birgit Neumann and Ansgar N&#xfc;nning, 145&#x2013;184. New York: De Gruyter.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/9783110227628.145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien, Tim. 1990. The things they carried. New York: Houghton Mifflin.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oden, Derek. 2017. Harvest of hazards: Family farming, accidents, and expertise in the Corn Belt, 1940&#x2013;1975. Iowa City: University of Iowa Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/j.ctt20q2378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parry, Alexander I. 2025. Making homemakers responsible for safety: Housework, laundry equipment, and the unequal burdens of accident prevention, c. 1910&#x2013;80. Technology and Culture 66(2): 411&#x2013;447. https://doi.org/10.1353/tech.2025.a956850</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearl, Sharrona. 2017. Face/on: Face transplants and the ethics of the other. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7208/chicago/9780226461533.001.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrow, Charles. 1984. Normal accidents: Living with high-risk technologies. New York: Basic Books.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puar, Jasbir. 2017. The right to maim: Debility, capacity, disability. Durham: Duke University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/j.ctv11314kc</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puskar, Jason R. 2012. Accident society: Fiction, collectivity, and the production of chance. Stanford: Stanford University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/j.ctvqsf1cb</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajabi, Samira. 2021. All my friends live in my computer: Trauma, tactical media, and meaning. New Brunswick: Rutgers University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36019/9781978818996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinarz, Jonathan, Shane Ewen, Rebecca Wynter, and Aaron Andrews, eds. 2021. Forged by fire: An illustrated history of burns in the 20th century. London: Arts and Humanities Research Council.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remes, Jacob A. C., and Andy Horowitz, eds. 2021. Critical disaster studies. Philadelphia: University of Pennsylvania Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts, Jr., Samuel Kelton. 2009. Infectious fear: Politics, disease, and the health effects of segregation. Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5149/9780807894071_roberts</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose, Sarah F. 2017. No right to be idle: The invention of disability, 1840s&#x2013;1930s. Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5149/northcarolina/9781469624891.001.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg, Charles E. 1989. Disease in history: Frames and framers. Milbank Quarterly 67(1): 1&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.2307/3350182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/3350182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg, Charles E. 1987. The care of strangers: The rise of America&#x2019;s hospital system. New York: Basic Books.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth, Sarah, et al., eds. 2023. Injury. Tendon 6. https://hopkinsmedicalhumanities.org/tendon-magazine/injury/ . Accessed 2 June 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarathy, Brinda, Janet Farrell Brodie, and Vivien Hamilton, eds. 2018. Inevitably toxic: Historical perspectives on contamination, exposure, and expertise. Pittsburgh: University of Pittsburgh Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savoia, Paolo. 2019. Gaspare Tagliacozzi and early modern surgery: Faces, men, and pain. London: Routledge.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4324/9780429259944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlich, Thomas. 2002. Surgery, science and industry: A revolution in fracture care, 1950s&#x2013;1990s. London: Palgrave Macmillan.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1057/9780230513280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Science Museum. 2018. Wounded: Conflict, casualties and care. ScienceMuseum.Org.UK. https://www.sciencemuseum.org.uk/what-was-on/wounded-conflict-casualties-and-care . Accessed 25 July 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sears, Roebuck and Company. 1975. Sears Roebuck Catalogs, 1896&#x2013;1993 251C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seltzer, Mark. 1997. Wound culture: Trauma in the pathological public sphere. October 80: 3&#x2013;26. https://doi.org/10.2307/778805</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shields, Wendy C., et al. 2020. Child housing assessment for a safe environment (CHASE): A new tool for injury prevention inside the home. Injury Prevention 26: 215&#x2013;220. https://doi.org/10.1136/injuryprev-2018-043054</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/injuryprev-2018-043054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siebers, Tobin. 2010. Disability aesthetics. Ann Arbor: University of Michigan Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3998/mpub.1134097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silber, Norman I. 1983. Test and protest: The influence of Consumers Union. New York: Holmes &amp; Meier.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer, Jessie. 2022. There are no accidents: The deadly rise of injury and disaster &#x2013; who profits and who pays the price. New York: Simon &amp; Schuster.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleet, David A., et al. 2011. Injury prevention, violence prevention, and trauma care: Building the scientific base. MMWR Supplements 60: 78&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleet, David A., et al. 2012. History of injury and violence as public health problems and emergence of the National Center for Injury Prevention and Control at CDC.&#x201d; Journal of Safety Research 43: 233&#x2013;247. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsr.2012.09.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsr.2012.09.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slobogin, Christine. 2025. Putting plastic surgery on paper: How art and archives defined Second World War reconstructive surgery in Britain. Rochester: University of Rochester Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7722/KJPA1129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sneiderman, Phil, and Lisa Ercolano. 2015. Tamper-proof pill bottle could help curb prescription painkiller misuse, abuse. Johns Hopkins University Hub. https://hub.jhu.edu/2015/06/18/tamper-resistant-bottle-prescription-painkillers/ . Accessed 17 March 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomou, Georgios, et al. 2024. Decompressive craniectomy in trauma: What you need to know. Journal of Trauma and Acute Care Surgery 97(4): 490&#x2013;496. https://doi.org/10.1097/TA.0000000000004357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TA.0000000000004357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sontag, Susan. 2001. Illness as metaphor and AIDS and its metaphors. New York: Picador.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinberg, Ted. 2006. Acts of god: The unnatural history of natural disaster in America. New York: Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stove fumes fatal to child. 3 January 1950. Oakland Tribune (Oakland, CA).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser, Susan. 1982. Never done: A history of American housework. New York: Pantheon Books.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szanton, Susan, et al. 2011. Community aging in place, advancing better living for elders: A bio-behavioral-environmental intervention to improve function and health-related quality of life in disabled older adults. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society 59(12): 2314&#x2013;2320. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1532-5415.2011.03698.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2011.03698.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sze, Julie. 2007. Noxious New York: The racial politics of urban health and environmental justice. Cambridge: MIT Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talley, Heather Laine. 2014. Saving face: Disfigurement and the politics of appearance. New York: New York University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarr, Joel A., and Mark Tebeau. 1997. Housewives as home safety managers: The changing perception of the home as a place of hazard and risk, 1870&#x2013;1940. In Accidents in history: Injuries, fatalities and social relations, eds. Roger Cooter and Bill Luckin, 196&#x2013;233. Amsterdam: Rodopi.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1163/9789004418516_012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomes, Nancy. 1998. The gospel of germs: Men, women, and the microbe in American life. Cambridge: Harvard University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tracy, Larissa, and Kelly DeVries, eds. 2015. Wounds and wound repair in medieval culture. Leiden: Brill.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>University of Michigan School of Public Health (UM). 1953. Investigation and application of home injury survey data in development of prevention procedures, February 1, 1952 &#x2013; January 31, 1953. Ann Arbor: University of Michigan Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>University of Texas at Austin (UT). 2024. US health humanities graduate programs. Humanities, Health and Medicine Program. https://liberalarts.utexas.edu/humanities-health-medicine/hhm-resources/us-health-humanities-graduate-programs.html . Accessed</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC). 1975. Hazard analysis: Space heaters, February 1975. Washington: Government Printing Office.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC). 1974. Space heater [Film]. Bethesda: Consumer Product Safety Commission.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Bureau of Mines, Department of the Interior. 1927. Carbon monoxide: The unseen danger [Film]. Pittsburgh: Pittsburgh Experiment Station.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Bergen, Leo. 2018. Surgery and war: The discussions about the usefulness of war for medical progress. In The Palgrave handbook of the history of surgery, ed. Thomas Schlich, 389&#x2013;407. London: Palgrave.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermeulen, Pieter, et al. 2014. The biopolitics of trauma. In The future of trauma theory: Contemporary literary criticism, eds. Gert Buelens, Samuel Durrant, and Robert Eaglestone, 141&#x2013;155. New York: Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira, Ryan. 2016. Rethinking the history of the risk society: Accident reporting, the social order and the London daily press, 1800&#x2013;30. In Governing risks in modern Britain: Danger, safety and accidents, c. 1800&#x2013;2000, eds. Tom Crook and Mike Esbester, 55&#x2013;76. London: Palgrave Macmillan.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinsel, Lee. 2019. Moving violations: Automobiles, experts, and regulations in the United States. Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/book.77088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vuong, Ocean. 2016. Seventh circle of Earth. In Night sky with exit wounds, 41&#x2013;42. Rochester: Copper Canyon Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wailoo, Keith. 2022. Patients are humans too: The emergence of medical humanities. Daedalus 151(3): 194&#x2013;205. https://doi.org/10.1162/daed_a_01938</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1162/daed_a_01938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waller, Julian A. 1994. Reflections on a half century of injury control. American Journal of Public Health 84(4): 664&#x2013;670. https://doi.org/10.2105/ajph.84.4.664</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/ajph.84.4.664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallis, Faith. 2018. Pre-modern surgery: Wounds, words, and the paradox of &#x201c;Tradition.&#x201d; In The Palgrave handbook of the history of surgery, ed. Thomas Schlich, 49&#x2013;70. London: Palgrave.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1057/978-1-349-95260-1_3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welke, Barbara. 2014. The cowboy suit tragedy: Spreading risk, owning hazard in the modern American consumer economy. Journal of American History 101(1): 97&#x2013;101. https://doi.org/10.1093/jahist/jau336</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jahist/jau336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitehead, Anne, Angela Woods, et al., eds. 2016. The Edinburgh companion to the critical medical humanities. Edinburgh: Edinburgh University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson, Bess. 2019. Accessible America: A history of disability and design. New York: New York University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson, Hall T. 2016. Marx&#x2019;s critical/dialectical procedure. London: Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woody Collins, Jennifer. 2019. Achieving engagement in injury and violence prevention research. Injury Prevention 25: 472&#x2013;475. https://doi.org/10.1136/injuryprev-2019-043257</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). 2024. Injuries and violence. World Health Organization Newsroom. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/injuries-and-violence . Accessed 10 October 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zevin, Gabrielle. 2022. Tomorrow, and tomorrow, and tomorrow. London: Vintage.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zink, Brian J. 2005. Anyone, anything, anytime: A history of emergency medicine. Philadelphia: Mosby.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zola, Emile. 1890. La b&#xea;te humaine. Middlesex: Penguin Books.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>