<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41829582</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>SOP: Selective Orthogonal Projection for Composed Image Retrieval.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1621</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26051621</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The proliferation of intelligent sensor networks in urban surveillance and remote sensing has triggered the explosive growth of unstructured visual sensor data. Accurately retrieving targets from these massive streams based on complex cross-modal user intents remains a critical bottleneck for efficient intelligent perception. Composed Image Retrieval (CIR) addresses this by enabling retrieval via a multi-modal query that combines a reference image with semantic control signals. However, existing methods often struggle with abstract instructions in real-world scenarios. Consequently, models often suffer from feature distribution shifts due to focus ambiguity, as well as semantic erosion caused by highly entangled visual and textual features. To address these challenges, we propose a geometry-based Selective Orthogonal Projection Network (SOP). First, the Selective Focus Recovery module quantifies instruction uncertainty via information entropy and calibrates shifted query features to the true target distribution using structural consistency regularization. Second, to ensure data fidelity, we introduce Orthogonal Subspace Projectionand Geometric Composition Fidelity. These mechanisms employ Gram-Schmidt orthogonalization to decouple features into a constant visual base and an orthogonal modification increment, restricting semantic modifications to the null space. Extensive experiments on FashionIQ, Shoes, and CIRR datasets demonstrate that SOP significantly outperforms SOTA methods, offering a novel solution for efficient large-scale sensor data retrieval and analysis.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Su</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Integrated Circuits, Shandong University, Jinan 250101, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Guoyang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5879-809X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Integrated Circuits, Shandong University, Jinan 250101, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shenzhen Research Institute of Shandong University, Shenzhen 518000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. 62401342</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. ZR2024QF092, ZR2024LZH007, and ZR2025ZD24</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Shandong Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 2025A1515011826</GrantID><Agency>the Guangdong Basic and Applied Basic Research Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. JCYJ20250604124702003</GrantID><Agency>the Shenzhen Fundamental Research Program</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. YYZN-2025-11</GrantID><Agency>the Sichuan Provincial Key Laboratory of Philosophy and Social Science for Language Intelligence in Special Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 2024YFC2418300 and 2024YFC2418303</GrantID><Agency>the National Key Research and Development Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. SCCl2025YB02</GrantID><Agency>and the Key Laboratory of Social Computing and Cognitive Intelligence (Dalian University of Technology), Ministry of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">composed image retrieval</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cross-modal information retrieval</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">semantic alignment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41829582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12986979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26051621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26051621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hou K., Tong Q., Yan N., Liu X., Hou S. MCFA: Multi-Scale Cascade and Feature Adaptive Alignment Network for Cross-View Geo-Localization. Sensors. 2025;25:4519. doi: 10.3390/s25144519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25144519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12299452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40732647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang J., Jeon M., Kim J. Multimodal latent representation learning for video moment retrieval. Sensors. 2025;25:4528. doi: 10.3390/s25144528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25144528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12299152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40732655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Y., Sun Z., Chen J. Learning Hierarchically Consistent Disentanglement with Multi-Channel Augmentation for Public Security-Oriented Sketch Person Re-Identification. Sensors. 2025;25:6155. doi: 10.3390/s25196155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25196155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12527006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41094977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong X., Liu G., Dong X., Li C., Li H., Cui H., Zhou W. Automatic seizure detection based on stockwell transform and transformer. Sensors. 2023;24:77. doi: 10.3390/s24010077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24010077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10781173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38202939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Hu Y., Fu Z., Li Z., Huang J., Huang Q., Wei Y. INTENT: Invariance and Discrimination-aware Noise Mitigation for Robust Composed Image Retrieval; Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence; Singapore. 20&#x2013;27 January 2026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwak J., Inhar R.M.I., Yun S.Y., Lee S.J. QuRe: Query-Relevant Retrieval through Hard Negative Sampling in Composed Image Retrieval. arXiv. 20252507.12416</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Hu Y., Chen Z., Zhang S., Huang Q., Fu Z., Wei Y. HABIT: Chrono-Synergia Robust Progressive Learning Framework for Composed Image Retrieval; Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence; Singapore. 20&#x2013;27 January 2026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang H., Wang J., Peng Y., Meng G., Luo R., Chen B., Chen L., Wang Y., Xia S.T. Proceedings of the 63rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics. ACL; Stroudsburg, PA, USA: 2025. Modeling uncertainty in Composed Image Retrieval via probabilistic embeddings; pp. 1210&#x2013;1222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen H., Song X., Yin J., Wu J., Guan W., Nie L. Self-Training Boosted Multi-Factor Matching Network for Composed Image Retrieval. IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell. 2023;46:3665&#x2013;3678. doi: 10.1109/TPAMI.2023.3346434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2023.3346434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38145530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Chen Z., Wen H., Fu Z., Hu Y., Guan W. ENCODER: Entity Mining and Modification Relation Binding for Composed Image Retrieval; Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence; Burlingame, CA, USA. 31 March&#x2013;2 April 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge H., Jiang Y., Sun J., Yuan K., Liu Y. LLM-Enhanced Composed Image Retrieval: An Intent Uncertainty-Aware Linguistic-Visual Dual Channel Matching Model. ACM Trans. Inf. Syst. 2025;43:1&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1145/3699715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3699715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X., Liu Y., Khan S., Khan F., Zuo W., Goh R.S.M., Feng C.M. Sentence-level Prompts Benefit Composed Image Retrieval; Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR 2024); Vienna, Austria. 7 May 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Hu Y., Chen Z., Huang Q., Qiu G., Fu Z., Liu M. ReTrack: Evidence Driven Dual Stream Directional Anchor Calibration Network for Composed Video Retrieval; Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence; Singapore. 20&#x2013;27 January 2026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y., Li Z., Chen Z., Huang Q., Fu Z., Xu M., Nie L. REFINE: Composed Video Retrieval via Shared and Differential Semantics Enhancement. ACM Trans. Multimed. Comput. Commun. Appl. 2026 doi: 10.1145/3796712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3796712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natha S., Ahmed F., Siraj M., Lagari M., Altamimi M., Chandio A.A. Deep BiLSTM attention model for spatial and temporal anomaly detection in video surveillance. Sensors. 2025;25:251. doi: 10.3390/s25010251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25010251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11723474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39797042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain V., Wu Z., Zou Q., Florentin L., Turbell H., Siddhartha S., Timofte R., Gao Q., Jiang L., Luo Q., et al. NTIRE 2025 challenge on video quality enhancement for video conferencing: Datasets, methods and results; Proceedings of the Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Conference; Shanghai, China. 15&#x2013;18 October 2025; pp. 1184&#x2013;1194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q., Meng X., Zhang S., Li X., Shao F. A temporally insensitive spatio-temporal fusion method for remote sensing imagery via semantic prior regularization. Inf. Fusion. 2025;117:102818. doi: 10.1016/j.inffus.2024.102818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inffus.2024.102818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu K., Zhang Y., Ru L., Dang B., Lao J., Yu L., Luo J., Zhu Z., Sun Y., Zhang J., et al. A semantic-enhanced multi-modal remote sensing foundation model for Earth observation. Nat. Mach. Intell. 2025;7:1235&#x2013;1249. doi: 10.1038/s42256-025-01078-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42256-025-01078-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapania S., Wang R., Li T.J.J., Li T., Shen H. &#x2019;I&#x2019;m Categorizing LLM as a Productivity Tool&#x2019;: Examining Ethics of LLM Use in HCI Research Practices. Proc. ACM -Hum.-Comput. Interact. 2025;9:1&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1145/3711000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3711000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boonprakong N., Tag B., Goncalves J., Dingler T. How Do HCI Researchers Study Cognitive Biases? A Scoping Review; Proceedings of the 2025 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems; Yokohama, Japan. 26 April&#x2013;1 May 2025; pp. 1&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radford A., Kim J.W., Hallacy C., Ramesh A., Goh G., Agarwal S., Sastry G., Askell A., Mishkin P., Clark J., et al. Proceedings of the 38th International Conference on Machine Learning. PMLR; Breckenridge, CO, USA: 2021. Learning transferable visual models from natural language supervision; pp. 8748&#x2013;8763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Li D., Xiong C., Hoi S. Proceedings of the International Conference on Machine Learning. PMLR; Breckenridge, CO, USA: 2022. Blip: Bootstrapping language-image pre-training for unified vision&#x2013;language understanding and generation; pp. 12888&#x2013;12900.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen H., Zhang X., Song X., Wei Y., Nie L. Proceedings of the 31st ACM International Conference on Multimedia. ACM; New York, NY, USA: 2023. Target-guided Composed Image Retrieval; pp. 915&#x2013;923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., He C., Liu X., Zhou J.T., Peng X., Hu P. 2025 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) IEEE; Piscataway, NJ, USA: 2025. Learning with Noisy Triplet Correspondence for Composed Image Retrieval; pp. 19628&#x2013;19637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Hu Y., Li Z., Fu Z., Wen H., Guan W. Proceedings of the 33rd ACM International Conference on Multimedia. ACM; New York, NY, USA: 2025. HUD: Hierarchical Uncertainty-Aware Disambiguation Network for Composed Video Retrieval; pp. 6143&#x2013;6152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian L., Zhao J., Hu Z., Yang Z., Li H., Jin L., Wang Z., Li X. 2025 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) IEEE; Piscataway, NJ, USA: 2025. CCIN: Compositional Conflict Identification and Neutralization for Composed Image Retrieval; pp. 3974&#x2013;3983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Hu Y., Li Z., Fu Z., Song X., Nie L. Proceedings of the 33rd ACM International Conference on Multimedia. ACM; New York, NY, USA: 2025. OFFSET: Segmentation-based Focus Shift Revision for Composed Image Retrieval; pp. 6113&#x2013;6122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Huang W., Yuan C. Proceedings of the Thirty-Ninth AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Thirty-Seventh Conference on Innovative Applications of Artificial Intelligence and Fifteenth Symposium on Educational Advances in Artificial Intelligence. Volume 39. AAAI Press; Washington, DC, USA: 2025. Aligning Composed Query with Image via Discriminative Perception from Negative Correspondences; pp. 8078&#x2013;8086.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Fu Z., Hu Y., Chen Z., Wen H., Nie L. FineCIR: Explicit Parsing of Fine-Grained Modification Semantics for Composed Image Retrieval. arXiv. 20252503.21309</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Z., Li Z., Chen Z., Wang C., Song X., Hu Y., Nie L. ICASSP 2025&#x2014;2025 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) IEEE; Piscataway, NJ, USA: 2025. PAIR: Complementarity-guided Disentanglement for Composed Image Retrieval; pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Q., Chen Z., Li Z., Wang C., Song X., Hu Y., Nie L. ICASSP 2025&#x2014;2025 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) IEEE; Piscataway, NJ, USA: 2025. MEDIAN: Adaptive Intermediate-grained Aggregation Network for Composed Image Retrieval; pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldrati A., Bertini M., Uricchio T., Del Bimbo A. Effective conditioned and Composed Image Retrieval combining clip-based features; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; New Orleans, LA, USA. 18&#x2013;24 June 2022; pp. 21466&#x2013;21474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X., Liu D., Zhang H., Luo Y., Wang C., Zhang J. Decomposing Semantic Shifts for Composed Image Retrieval; Proceedings of the AAAI; Vancouver, BC, Canada. 20&#x2013;27 February 2024; pp. 6576&#x2013;6584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vo N., Jiang L., Sun C., Murphy K., Li L., Fei-Fei L., Hays J. 2019 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) IEEE; Piscataway, NJ, USA: 2019. Composing Text and Image for Image Retrieval&#x2014;An Empirical Odyssey; pp. 6439&#x2013;6448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Gong S., Bazzani L. 2020 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) IEEE; Piscataway, NJ, USA: 2020. Image Search With Text Feedback by Visiolinguistic Attention Learning; pp. 2998&#x2013;3008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z., Opazo C.R., Teney D., Gould S. 2021 IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) IEEE; Piscataway, NJ, USA: 2021. Image Retrieval on Real-life Images with Pre-trained Vision-and-Language Models; pp. 2105&#x2013;2114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldrati A., Bertini M., Uricchio T., Del Bimbo A. 2022 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Workshops (CVPRW) IEEE; Piscataway, NJ, USA: 2022. Conditioned and Composed Image Retrieval combining and partially fine-tuning clip-based features; pp. 4959&#x2013;4968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z., Sun W., Hong Y., Teney D., Gould S. Bi-Directional Training for Composed Image Retrieval via Text Prompt Learning; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV); Waikoloa, HI, USA. 3&#x2013;8 January 2024; pp. 5753&#x2013;5762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen F., Tang J. Imagpose: A unified conditional framework for pose-guided person generation. Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst. 2024;37:6246&#x2013;6266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan Y., Zou G., Zhang B. Composed Image Retrieval: A survey on recent research and development. Appl. Intell. 2025;55:482. doi: 10.1007/s10489-025-06372-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10489-025-06372-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang X., Wang Y., Li M., Wu Y., Hu B., Qian X. Proceedings of the 47th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval. ACM; New York, NY, USA: 2024. Cala: Complementary association learning for augmenting comoposed image retrieval; pp. 2177&#x2013;2187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodol&#xe0; E., Cosmo L., Litany O., Bronstein M.M., Bronstein A.M., Audebert N., Ben Hamza A., Boulch A., Castellani U., Do M.N., et al. Eurographics Workshop on 3D Object Retrieval. The Eurographics Association; Eindhoven, The Netherlands: 2017. SHREC&#x2019;17: Deformable shape retrieval with missing parts.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chun S., Oh S.J., De Rezende R.S., Kalantidis Y., Larlus D. Probabilistic embeddings for cross-modal retrieval; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Nashville, TN, USA. 20&#x2013;25 June 2021; pp. 8415&#x2013;8424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Li D., Savarese S., Hoi S. Proceedings of the 40th International Conference on Machine Learning. PMLR; Breckenridge, CO, USA: 2023. Blip-2: Bootstrapping language-image pre-training with frozen image encoders and large language models; pp. 19730&#x2013;19742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Zheng Z., Ji W., Qu L., Chua T.S. Composed Image Retrieval with text feedback via multi-grained uncertainty regularization. arXiv. 2024 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2211.07394.2211.07394</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2211.07394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imtiaz A., Pathirana N., Saheel S., Karunanayaka K., Trenado C. A Review on the Influence of Deep Learning and Generative AI in the Fashion Industry. J. Future Artif. Intell. Technol. 2024;1:201&#x2013;216. doi: 10.62411/faith.3048-3719-29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62411/faith.3048-3719-29</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H., Gao Y., Guo X., Al-Halah Z., Rennie S., Grauman K., Feris R. Fashion iq: A new dataset towards retrieving images by natural language feedback; Proceedings of the CVPR; Nashville, TN, USA. 20&#x2013;25 June 2021; pp. 11307&#x2013;11317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X., Wu H., Cheng Y., Rennie S., Tesauro G., Feris R.S. Dialog-based Interactive Image Retrieval; Proceedings of the NeurIPS; Montreal, QC, Canada. 3&#x2013;8 December 2018; Cambridge, MA, USA: MIT Press; 2018. pp. 676&#x2013;686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delmas G., de Rezende R.S., Csurka G., Larlus D. ARTEMIS: Attention-based Retrieval with Text-Explicit Matching and Implicit Similarity; Proceedings of the International Conference on Learning Representations; Virtual. 25&#x2013;29 April 2022; pp. 1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ventura L., Yang A., Schmid C., Varol G. CoVR: Learning composed video retrieval from web video captions; Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence; Vancouver, BC, Canada. 26&#x2013;27 February 2024; pp. 5270&#x2013;5279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ventura L., Yang A., Schmid C., Varol G. CoVR-2: Automatic Data Construction for Composed Video Retrieval. IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell. 2024;46:11409&#x2013;11421. doi: 10.1109/TPAMI.2024.3463799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2024.3463799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39302778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvaraju R.R., Cogswell M., Das A., Vedantam R., Parikh D., Batra D. Grad-cam: Visual explanations from deep networks via gradient-based localization; Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision; Venice, Italy. 22&#x2013;29 October 2017; pp. 618&#x2013;626.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>