<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41660321</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2229-5097</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Surgical neurology international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Surg Neurol Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Transorbital neuro-endoscopic surgical resection of right orbital cyst and frontal sinus reconstruction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>28</StartPage><MedlinePgn>28</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">28</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.25259/SNI_1086_2025</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This video illustrates a minimally invasive neuroendoscopic transorbital technique used for the removal of a right orbital cyst accompanied by frontal sinus reconstruction. The approach enables a direct and efficient corridor to orbital and anterior skull base lesions, reducing the need for brain retraction while ensuring both functional and aesthetic benefits.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE DESCRIPTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A 38-year-old male patient presented with progressive exophthalmos, double vision, and elevated intraocular pressure caused by a right orbital cyst. Radiological evaluation reveals a thick-walled cystic formation with hyperintense signal intensity on T1- and T2-weighted images. IV contrast-enhanced magnetic resonance &#x131;maging was performed. No contrast enhancement was observed in the lesion. The lesion measures 35 &#xd7; 30 &#xd7; 26 mm and appears to be connected to the frontal sinus. Preoperative images showed that the lesion destroyed the frontal sinus and was connected to it. Eyebrow incision was preferred for intraoperative assessment of the frontal sinus to facilitate resection of the lesion within the frontal sinus and surgical maneuvers and reconstruction within the frontal sinus. Through a transorbital endoscopic route, the surgical team performed orbital rim drilling, complete cyst excision, and frontal sinus reconstruction using autologous fat graft material. Orbital rim drilling was performed at the orbital entrance within the skin incision margins, with the bone resection amount not exceeding 5 mm. The purpose of orbital rim drilling is to widen the endoscopic field of view and facilitate the maneuverability of surgical instruments. This did not cause any cosmetic problems. A 0&#xb0; rigid endoscope and standard endoscopic endonasal surgical instruments were used. The postoperative period was uneventful, and the patient experienced immediate correction of exophthalmos. The histopathological evaluation was reported as an epidermoid cyst with hemorrhage. At the 4-week follow-up, eye movements and intraocular pressure were normal, and diplopia had completely resolved.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The transorbital endoscopic approach represents a safe, efficient, and cosmetically favorable option for treating orbital cystic lesions. It provides excellent visualization of the surgical field with minimal invasiveness, allowing for rapid recovery and optimal cosmetic outcomes. This experience underlines the versatility and clinical usefulness of this technique in properly selected cases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Surgical Neurology International.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kar&#x131;mzada</LastName><ForeName>Gardashkhan</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Hitit University, Erol Ol&#xe7;ok Training and Research Hospital, Corum, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehdiyev</LastName><ForeName>Royal</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Ege Hospital, Baku, Azerbaijan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mammadov</LastName><ForeName>Tabriz</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Central Military Hospital of the Armed Forces, Baku, Azerbaijan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Evleksiz</LastName><ForeName>Demet</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Hitit University, Erol Ol&#xe7;ok Training and Research Hospital, Corum, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dogan</LastName><ForeName>Adem</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, &#x15e;ehitKamil State Hospital, Gaziantep, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ezgu</LastName><ForeName>Mehmet Can</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Health Sciences, G&#xfc;lhane Training and Research Hospital, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G&#xfc;ng&#xf6;r</LastName><ForeName>Abuzer</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Istinye University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Surg Neurol Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101535836</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2152-7806</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endoscopic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Orbit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Skull base</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transorbital</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of &#x131;nterest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41660321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12875227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25259/SNI_1086_2025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.25259/SNI_1086_2025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Almeida JP, Omay SB, Shetty SR, Chen YN, RuizTrevi&#xf1;o AS, Liang B, et al. Transorbital endoscopic eyelid approach for resection of sphenoorbital meningiomas with predominant hyperostosis: Report of 2 cases. J Neurosurg. 2018;128:1885&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28862553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balakrishnan K, Moe KS. Applications and outcomes of orbital and transorbital endoscopic surgery. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2011;144:815&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21493355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borghei-Razavi H, Truong HQ, Fernandes-Cabral DT, Celtikci E, Chabot JD, Stefko ST, et al. Minimally &#x131;nvasive approaches for anterior skull base meningiomas: Supraorbital eyebrow, endoscopic endonasal, or a combination of both? Anatomic study, limitations, and surgical application. World Neurosurg. 2018;112:e666&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29378344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corrivetti F, De Notaris M, Di Somma A, Dallan I, Ense&#xf1;at J, Topczewski T, et al. &#x201c;Sagittal Crest&#x201d;: Definition, stepwise dissection, and clinical &#x131;mplications from a transorbital perspective. Oper Neurosurg. 2022;22:e206&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35239519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Notaris M, Kong DS, Di Somma A, Ense&#xf1;at J, Hong CK, Moe K, et al. Superior eyelid transorbital approaches: A modular classification system. J Neurosurg. 2024;141:278&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38626472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Notaris M, Sacco M, Corrivetti F, Grasso M, Corvino S, Piazza A, et al. The transorbital approach, a game-changer in neurosurgery: A guide to safe and reliable surgery based on anatomical principles. J Clin Med. 2023;12:6484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10607762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37892624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai R, Chavez-Herrera VR, Zeldin S, Gel G, Godfrey KJ, Schwartz TH. Lateral transorbital endoscope-assisted resection of anterior temporal lobe neoplasm: 2-dimensional operative video. Oper Neurosurg. 2024;27:668&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38717138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Somma A, Andaluz N, Cavallo LM, De Notaris M, Dallan I, Solari D, et al. Endoscopic transorbital superior eyelid approach: Anatomical study from a neurosurgical perspective. J Neurosurg. 2018;129:1203&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29243982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kar&#x131;mzada G, Evleksiz Kar&#x131;mzada D, Erol G, G&#xfc;lsuna B, Kuzucu P, G&#xfc;ng&#xf6;r A, et al. Transorbital neuroendoscopic surgery for treatment of sphenoid wing meningiomas extending to the cavernous sinus: Clinical implications and a technical illustration. Neurosurg Focus. 2024;56:E8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38560930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong DS, Young SM, Hong CK, Kim YD, Hong SD, Choi JW, et al. Clinical and ophthalmological outcome of endoscopic transorbital surgery for cranioorbital tumors. J Neurosurg. 2018;131:667&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30215555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maghalashvili E, Corrivetti F, Shalamberidze B, Corvino S, Chkhikvishvili T, De Notaris M. Endoscopic transorbital resection of temporal pole cavernoma: 2-dimensional operative video. Oper Neurosurg. 2025;28:442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38967457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moe KS, Kim LJ, Bergeron CM. Transorbital endoscopic repair of cerebrospinal fluid leaks. Laryngoscope. 2011;121:13&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21181981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz TH, Henderson F, Jr, Di Somma A, Kong DS, De Notaris M, Ense&#xf1;at J, et al. Endoscopic transorbital surgery: Another leap of faith? World Neurosurg. 2022;159:54&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35007891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoia C, Mastantuoni C, Solari D, De Notaris M, Corrivetti F, Spena G, et al. Transorbital and supraorbital uniportal multicorridor approach to the orbit, anterior, middle and posterior cranial fossa: Anatomic study. Brain Spine. 2023;4:102719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10753433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38163002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>