<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41921352</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-3336</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>508</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of hazardous materials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hazard Mater</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integrating soil heavy metal risk into ecological quality assessment: The pollution-enhanced remote sensing ecological index.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>141862</StartPage><MedlinePgn>141862</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2026.141862</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0304-3894(26)00840-X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Soil contamination by hazardous heavy metals (e.g., As, Hg, Cd, Cu, Ni, Pb, and Zn) in polymetallic mining areas poses severe risks to ecosystem integrity and human health. Conventional Remote Sensing Ecological Indices (e.g., RSEI) rely primarily on physical surface features, thus failing to capture the "invisible" chemical toxicity and site-specific ecological risk (RI) associated with heavy metals. To overcome this disconnect between spectral indices and soil geochemical hazards, this study proposes a Pollution-Enhanced Remote Sensing Ecological Index (PE-RSEI). Using the Shizhuyuan mining area as a case study, a Remote Sensing Potential Ecological Risk Index (RRI) was first constructed by coupling 94 field soil samples with long-term multispectral imagery (1997-2024) via Random Forest regression. The RRI model achieved high accuracy (R&#xb2; = 0.86) in reflecting the spatiotemporal distribution of surface heavy metal risks, but it remains a data-driven index and does not directly quantify absolute concentrations or chemical speciation. Subsequently, the RRI was integrated into the RSEI framework to generate the PE-RSEI, allowing for a dynamic assessment of ecological quality partially constrained by heavy metal pollution. Results indicate that while the overall ecological condition showed slight recovery, high-risk degradation zones remain concentrated in active mining and built-up areas (16&#x202f;km&#xb2;). Compared to the traditional RSEI, PE-RSEI demonstrated superior robustness, with a 21.6% increase in information density and reduced temporal variance, although its reliability depends on sampling density, heavy metal types, and regression methods.This study provides a novel, scalable, and quantitative framework for preliminary monitoring of hazardous material risks in mining regions, offering critical data support for pollution control and land reclamation, and providing a scientific basis for informed ecological management in areas affected by heavy metal contamination.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hui</LastName><ForeName>Jiawei</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Geosciences and Info-Physics, Central South University, Changsha 410083, China; Key Laboratory of Metallogenic Prediction of Nonferrous Metals and Geological Environment Monitoring, Ministry of Education, Central South University, Changsha 410083, China; Hunan Key Laboratory of Nonferrous Resources and Geological Disaster Exploration, Changsha 410083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Yongsheng</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Geosciences and Info-Physics, Central South University, Changsha 410083, China; Key Laboratory of Metallogenic Prediction of Nonferrous Metals and Geological Environment Monitoring, Ministry of Education, Central South University, Changsha 410083, China; Hunan Key Laboratory of Nonferrous Resources and Geological Disaster Exploration, Changsha 410083, China. Electronic address: yscheng@csu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Yao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Geosciences and Info-Physics, Central South University, Changsha 410083, China; Key Laboratory of Metallogenic Prediction of Nonferrous Metals and Geological Environment Monitoring, Ministry of Education, Central South University, Changsha 410083, China; Hunan Key Laboratory of Nonferrous Resources and Geological Disaster Exploration, Changsha 410083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Shiyu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Geosciences and Info-Physics, Central South University, Changsha 410083, China; Key Laboratory of Metallogenic Prediction of Nonferrous Metals and Geological Environment Monitoring, Ministry of Education, Central South University, Changsha 410083, China; Hunan Key Laboratory of Nonferrous Resources and Geological Disaster Exploration, Changsha 410083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Hazard Mater</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9422688</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0304-3894</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mining ecological monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PE-RSEI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Potential Ecological Risk Index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Shizhuyuan mining</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surface heavy metal pollution</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41921352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2026.141862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0304-3894(26)00840-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>