<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41732150</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2772-7246</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Drug and alcohol dependence reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Drug Alcohol Depend Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinicians' experiences of delivering online Community Reinforcement and Family Training (CRAFT) for families affected by substance use in rural Australia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100416</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100416</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100416</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.dadr.2026.100416</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Interventions that support family members or concerned significant others (CSOs) of people with alcohol or drug dependence can enhance recovery, strengthen family functioning, and reduce recurrence rates. Yet factors influencing successful implementation of CSO-focused online programs, especially in rural Australia remain poorly understood. This study explored the implementation experiences of clinicians delivering online Community Reinforcement and Family Training (CRAFT).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This exploratory descriptive qualitative study involved semi-structured interviews with seven clinicians who delivered CRAFT. Data were analysed thematically using the RE-AIM (Reach, Effectiveness, Adoption, Implementation, Maintenance) framework.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">CRAFT was perceived as well-structured, feasible, and compatible with routine clinical practice, enhancing clinicians' confidence and enabling CSOs to develop skills in self-care, positive communication, problem-solving, and supporting healthy behaviours among loved ones. Successful implementation depended on clinician enthusiasm, flexible delivery modes (online as well as in-person), tailored content, and ongoing feedback, while challenges included CSO emotional overwhelm, competing responsibilities, limited digital literacy, and insufficient alcohol and drug services for loved ones. Socio-cultural factors, including reluctance to discuss alcohol or substance dependence, also limited engagement. Clinicians intended to retain key program components in practice but time constraints, telehealth limitations, and rural service gaps hindered sustained integration. Suggested improvements included cultural adaptation and structured opportunities for family-service collaboration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Online CRAFT is a promising, practice-ready intervention for supporting and empowering rural families affected by alcohol and drug use. Its integration into health services will depend on addressing workforce capacity, digital access, and rural service inequities, alongside policy-level commitment to family-focused programs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">ACTRN12623000796684 (registered 26 July 2023).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thapa</LastName><ForeName>Subash</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rural Health Research Institute, Charles Sturt University, Orange, NSW 2800, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gray</LastName><ForeName>Heidi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rural Health Research Institute, Charles Sturt University, Orange, NSW 2800, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Snowdon</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rural Health Research Institute, Charles Sturt University, Orange, NSW 2800, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Serna</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Serna Solutions, Santa Fe, NM, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jacobson</LastName><ForeName>Brianna</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Serna Solutions, Santa Fe, NM, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Allan</LastName><ForeName>Julaine</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rural Health Research Institute, Charles Sturt University, Orange, NSW 2800, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Drug Alcohol Depend Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918350383506676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2772-7246</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community reinforcement and family training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Implementation science</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Positive communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rural mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Substance-related disorders</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41732150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12925573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dadr.2026.100416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2772-7246(26)00009-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Allan J., Snowdon N. Rural Health Research Institute, Charles Sturt University; Orange, Australia: 2024. Family Empowerment Program brief facilitator guide.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allan J., Snowdon N., Thapa S., Ahmed K.Y. Study protocol for the family empowerment program: a randomized waitlist-controlled trial to evaluate the effectiveness of online Community Reinforcement and Family Training (CRAFT) on the wellbeing of family members with a relative experiencing substance dependence and mental illness. BMC Psychiatry. 2024;24(1):43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10782775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38200508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archer M., Harwood H., Stevelink S., Rafferty L., Greenberg N. Community reinforcement and family training and rates of treatment entry: a systematic review. Addiction. 2020;115(6):1024&#x2013;1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31770469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ariss T., Fairbairn C.E. The effect of significant other involvement in treatment for substance use disorders: a meta-analysis. J. Consult Clin. Psychol. 2020;88(6):526&#x2013;540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32162930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Australian Institute of Health and Welfare Preval. Impact Ment. Illn. Aust. 2022 &#x2329;https://www.aihw.gov.au/mental-health/overview/mental-illness&#x232a; Accessed 26 January 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrnes H.F., Miller B.A., Aalborg A.E., Plasencia A.V., Keagy C.D. Implementation fidelity in adolescent family-based prevention programs: relationship to family engagement. Health Educ. Res. 2010;25(4):531&#x2013;541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2905922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20142414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabria B., Clifford A., Rose M., Shakeshaft A.P. Tailoring a family-based alcohol intervention for Aboriginal Australians, and the experiences and perceptions of health care providers trained in its delivery. BMC Public Health. 2014;14(1):322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3996136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24708838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabria B., Shakeshaft A.P., Clifford A., Stone C., Clare P.J., Allan J., Bliss D. Reducing drug and alcohol use and improving well-being for Indigenous and non-Indigenous Australians using the Community Reinforcement Approach: a feasibility and acceptability study. Int J. Psychol. 2020;55(1):88&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31273788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dopp A.R., Manuel J.K., Breslau J., Lodge B., Hurley B., Kase C., Osilla K.C. Value of family involvement in substance use disorder treatment: aligning clinical and financing priorities. J. Subst. Abus. Treat. 2022;132</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34742609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edgren R., P&#xf6;rtfors P., Raisamo S., Castr&#xe9;n S. Treatment for the concerned significant others of gamblers: a systematic review. J. Behav. Addict. 2022;11(1):1&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9109622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35044325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geijer-Simpson E., Kaner E., Lingam R., McArdle P., McGovern R. Effectiveness of family-involved interventions in reducing co-occurring alcohol use and mental health problems in young people Aged 12&#x2013;17: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2023;20(19):6890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10572317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37835160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giri S., Ross N., Kornhaber R., Ahmed K.Y., Thapa S. The effects of parental adverse childhood experiences (ACEs) and childhood threat and deprivation on adolescent depression and anxiety: an analysis of the longitudinal study of Australian children. Epidemiol. Psychiatr. Sci. 2025;34</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12555079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41051324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glasgow R.E., Harden S.M., Gaglio B., Rabin B., Smith M.L., Porter G.C., Ory M.G., Estabrooks P.A. RE-AIM planning and evaluation framework: adapting to new science and practice with a 20-year review. Front Public Health. 2019;7:64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30984733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray H., Ivory N., Snowdon N., Ahmed K.Y., Thomas M., Allan J. Online community reinforcement and family training (CRAFT) for rural concerned significant others: A randomized controlled trial. J. Subst. Use Addict. Treat. 2026;182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41443343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griswold M.G., Karriker-Jaffe K.J. Alcohol's health burden: secondhand harms matter. Lancet Public Health. 2025;10(9):e723&#x2013;e724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40883035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health A.I.O., Welfare . AIHW; Canberra: 2023. Alcohol and other drug treatment services in Australia: early insights.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellum R., Bilberg R., Bischof G., Nielsen A.S. How concerned significant others experience Community Reinforcement and Family Training (CRAFT) &#x2013; a qualitative study. BMC Fam. Pract. 2021;22(1):241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8641252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34861827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellum R., Bilberg R., Nielsen A.S. A qualitative study of the therapists' experiences of working with community reinforcement and family training. Couns. Psychother. Res. 2023;23(4):1084&#x2013;1096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtrop J.S., Rabin B.A., Glasgow R.E. Qualitative approaches to use of the RE-AIM framework: rationale and methods. BMC Health Serv. Res. 2018;18(1):177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5851243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29534729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter D., McCallum J., Howes D. Defining exploratory-descriptive qualitative (EDQ) research and considering its application to healthcare. J. Nurs. Health Care. 2019;4(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohlhoff J., Cibralic S., Horswood D., Turnell A., Maiuolo M., Morgan S. Feasibility and acceptability of internet-delivered parent-child interaction therapy for rural Australian families: a qualitative investigation. Rural Remote Health 20(1) 5306. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31917594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindt N., van Berkel J., Mulder B.C. Determinants of overburdening among informal carers: a systematic review. BMC Geriatr. 2020;20(1):304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7448315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32847493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCann T.V., Polacsek M., Lubman D.I. Experiences of family members supporting a relative with substance use problems: a qualitative study. Scand. J. Caring Sci. 2019;33(4):902&#x2013;911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31033023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy J.M., Wood A.J., Shinners M.G., Heinrich H., Weiss R.D., Mueser K.T., Meyers R.J., Carol E.E., Hudson J.I., &#xd6;ng&#xfc;r D. Pilot development and feasibility of telehealth Community Reinforcement and Family Training (CRAFT) for early psychosis and substance use. Psychiatry Res. 2022;317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10127150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36030701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihan R., Mousavi S.B., Khodaie Ardakani M.R., Rezaei H., Hosseinzadeh S., Nazeri Astaneh A., Alikhani R. Comparison of caregivers' burden among family members of patients with severe mental disorders and patients with substance use disorder. Iran. J. Psychiatry. 2023;18(2):183&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10293690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37383957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orford J., Copello A., Velleman R., Templeton L. Family members affected by a close relative's addiction: the stress-strain-coping-support model. Drugs Education Prevention Policy. 2010;17(sup1):36&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto R., Can&#xe1;rio C., Leijten P., Rodrigo M.J., Cruz O. Implementation of parenting programs in real-world community settings: a scoping review. Clin. Child Fam. Psychol. Rev. 2024;27(1):74&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10920434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38062309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose, M., Calabria, B., Allan, J., Clifford, A., Shakeshaft, A.P., 2014. Aboriginal-specific Community Reinforcement and Family Training (CRAFT) Manual.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowe C., Rigter H., Henderson C., Gantner A., Mos K., Nielsen P., Phan O. Implementation fidelity of multidimensional family therapy in an international trial. J. Subst. Abus. Treat. 2013;44(4):391&#x2013;399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23085040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith J.E., Meyers R.J. Guilford Publications; 2022. The CRAFT treatment manual for substance use problems: Working with family members.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teesson M., Hall W., Slade T., Mills K., Grove R., Mewton L., Baillie A., Haber P. Prevalence and correlates of DSM-IV alcohol abuse and dependence in Australia: findings of the 2007 National Survey of Mental Health and Wellbeing. Addiction. 2010;105(12):2085&#x2013;2094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20707771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa S., Ahmed K.Y., Ross A.G. Beyond statistics: health inequities in rural and remote communities of Australia. Lancet Public Health. 2023;8(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37898513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versace V.L., Skinner T.C., Bourke L., Harvey P., Barnett T. National analysis of the Modified Monash Model, population distribution and a socio-economic index to inform rural health workforce planning. Aust. J. Rural Health. 2021;29(5):801&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34672057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward B., Reupert A., McCormick F., Waller S., Kidd S. Family-focused practice within a recovery framework: practitioners&#x2019; qualitative perspectives. BMC Health Serv. Res. 2017;17(1):234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5364722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28340614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>