<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41698018</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1078-6791</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Alternative therapies in health and medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Altern Ther Health Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Application Value of Fast-track Rehabilitation Nursing in Patients with Acute Cervical Spinal Cord Injury Undergoing Surgery.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">AT10617</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study evaluates the efficacy of fast-track rehabilitation nursing in surgical patients with acute cervical spinal cord injury.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Fifty-four patients with acute cervical spinal cord injury who underwent surgery at our hospital from July 2016 to July 2020 were selected and randomly divided into a control group and an experimental group, with 27 patients in each group. The control group received routine perioperative nursing care, including preoperative guidance, intraoperative monitoring, postoperative pain management, and prevention of complications. The experimental group received fast-track rehabilitation nursing in addition to the routine care. The key components of the fast-track approach included preoperative health education and psychological counseling, early postoperative mobilization and assisted lower limb function training, resumption of oral intake within 24 hours after surgery, enhanced pain management, and preventive measures against complications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The experimental group had a significantly shorter time to first voluntary movement and first oral intake after surgery, compared to the control group (both P &lt; .05). The postoperative VAS pain score was also significantly lower in the experimental group than in the control group (P &lt; .05). Regarding ASIA grading improvement, in the control group, 4 of 12 patients with grade B improved to grade C, 3 improved to grade D, 5 of 13 patients with grade C improved to grade D, 6 improved to grade E, and 2 patients with grade D all improved to grade E, with an overall improvement rate of 74.07%. The improvement rate was significantly higher in the experimental group, reaching 96.30% (P &lt; .05). The experimental group had significantly higher ADL scores (P &lt; .05) and lower SAS and SDS scores (P &lt; .05) than the control group. The in-hospital complication rate was 25.93% in the experimental group and 59.26% in the control group, with a significant difference (P &lt; .05), while the follow-up complication rates were not significantly different between the two groups (P &gt; .05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Fast-track rehabilitation nursing significantly improves surgical outcomes in patients with acute cervical spinal cord injury. This approach enhances ASIA grading, accelerates postoperative recovery, improves daily living activities, reduces negative emotions, and lowers the risk of complications. This nursing model is an ideal application for this patient population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="KEYWORDS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Fast-track rehabilitation nursing, Acute cervical spinal cord injury, Surgery, Application value Fast-track rehabilitation nursing, Acute cervical spinal cord injury, Surgery, Application value.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, The First Affiliated Hospital of Hebei North University, Zhangjiakou, Hebei China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Liwen</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, The First Affiliated Hospital of Hebei North University, Zhangjiakou, Hebei China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Guoqing</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, The First Affiliated Hospital of Hebei North University, Zhangjiakou, Hebei China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Jianhua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, The First Affiliated Hospital of Hebei North University, Zhangjiakou, Hebei China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xue</LastName><ForeName>Yinghui</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, The First Affiliated Hospital of Hebei North University, Zhangjiakou,Hebei China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Maili</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, The First Affiliated Hospital of Hebei North University, Zhangjiakou, Hebei China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xinming</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, The First Affiliated Hospital of Hebei North University, Zhangjiakou, Hebei China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Altern Ther Health Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9502013</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1078-6791</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41698018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">AT10617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>