<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41856909</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2044-8341</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Psychology and psychotherapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Psychol Psychother</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Health care personnel factors affecting recovery after a suicide attempt: Population study of professionals and users in Colombia.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/papt.70053</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To examine the associations between workload overload, stigma towards mental disorders, cultural competence and the use of coercive practices in people who seek help for a suicide attempt in the Department of Caldas, Colombia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">A quantitative cross-sectional study with correlational scope using regression models. A total of 155 dyads were formed between individuals who consulted for suicide attempts and the primary health care professionals who participated in their care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Based on a population-based study of suicidal behaviour in Colombia, individuals who reported coercive practices in health care services were matched with health care professionals who provided their care. Users completed instruments assessing depressive symptoms, subjective well-being, adherence and out-of-pocket expenses. Health care personnel were surveyed on workload overload, cultural competence, attitudes towards mental disorders and use of coercive measures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the 155 users analysed, 28.4% reported at least one coercive practice during mental health care for a suicide attempt. Perceived coercive practices were associated (adjusted R<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.699) with cultural competence and stigma, and related to depressive symptoms, lower sense of community, and higher health service spending. Users with a greater perception of the use of coercion were treated by professionals with higher levels of emotional exhaustion and depersonalization, along with lower levels of personal fulfilment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Professional and institutional factors significantly influence subjective well-being outcomes, highlighting the need to strengthen cultural competence training and reduce workload overload in mental health services. Due to the cross-sectional design, findings indicate associations rather than causality.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The British Psychological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agudelo-Hern&#xe1;ndez</LastName><ForeName>Felipe</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8356-8878</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidad de Manizales, Manizales, Caldas, Colombia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rojas-Echeverry</LastName><ForeName>Mariana</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-3435-0609</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidad de Caldas, Manizales, Caldas, Colombia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Plata-Casas</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0375-8875</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Superintendency of Health of Colombia, Bogot&#xe1;, Colombia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Psychol Psychother</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101135751</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1476-0835</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">burnout, professional</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coercion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cultural competence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health services</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">suicide, attempted</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41856909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/papt.70053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal, N. K., Cede&#xf1;o, K., Guarnaccia, P., Kleinman, A., &amp; Lewis&#x2010;Fern&#xe1;ndez, R. (2016). Clinician descriptions of communication strategies to improve treatment engagement by racial/ethnic minorities in mental health services: A systematic review. Psychiatric Services, 67(10), 1090&#x2013;1099. https://doi.org/10.1176/appi.ps.201500333</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agudelo&#x2010;Hern&#xe1;ndez, F., Mej&#xed;a&#x2010;Chaves, M., Acu&#xf1;a&#x2010;Mej&#xed;a, P. A., Plata&#x2010;Casas, L. I., &amp; Cuadrado, L. (2025). Types of coercive practices, disability and days in crisis in people with suicide attempts in Latin American. Community Mental Health Journal, 62(1), 67&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10597&#x2010;025&#x2010;01503&#x2010;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agudelo&#x2010;Hern&#xe1;ndez, F., &amp; Murillo&#x2010;Alzate, L. (2026). Catastrophic health expenditure in mental health as coercion in post&#x2013;suicide attempt care: A population&#x2010;based study in Latin America. The International Journal of Social Psychiatry. https://doi.org/10.1177/00207640261426477. Advance online publication.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agudelo&#x2010;Hern&#xe1;ndez, F., &amp; Rojas&#x2010;Andrade, R. (2023). Mental health Services in Colombia: A National Implementation Study. International Journal of Social Determinants of Health and Health Services, 53(4), 424&#x2013;433. https://doi.org/10.1177/27551938231156023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agudelo&#x2010;Hern&#xe1;ndez, F., V&#xe9;lez&#x2010;Botero, H., &amp; Guapacha&#x2010;Montoya, M. (2025). Human rights engagement, stigma and attitudes towards mental health among Colombian social work and medical students. Advances in Health Sciences Education, 30(4), 1085&#x2013;1100. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10459&#x2010;024&#x2010;10377&#x2010;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agudelo&#x2010;Hern&#xe1;ndez, F., V&#xe9;lez&#x2010;Botero, H., &amp; Rojas&#x2010;Andrade, R. (2023). Translation and adaptation of the Alberta mental health services continuum scale in a Latin American context. Revista Chilena de Neuro&#x2010;Psiquiatr&#xed;a, 61(3), 258&#x2013;269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker, A. B., &amp; de Vries, J. D. (2020). Job demands&#x2013;resources theory and self&#x2010;regulation: New explanations and remedies for job burnout. Anxiety, Stress, and Coping, 34(1), 1&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1080/10615806.2020.1797695</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bautista&#x2010;Espinel, G. O., Velandia&#x2010;Galvis, M. L., Ortega&#x2010;Cadena, N., Chaves, C. A., Ure&#xf1;a&#x2010;Molina, M. D. P., &amp; Gonzales&#x2010;Escobar, D. S. (2022). Cultural adaptation and validation of the EMCC&#x2010;14 instrument for cultural competence in Colombian health professionals. Index de Enfermer&#xed;a, 31(2), 120&#x2013;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera&#x2010;Mendoza, B., Fries, G. R., Polimanti, R., &amp; Suicide Working Group of the Latin American Genomics Consortium. (2025). The landscape of suicide risk factors in Latin America. Psychiatry Research, 351, 116597. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psychres.2025.116597</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calleja, N., Mason, T. A., &amp; P&#xe9;rez, O. G. (2022). Subjective well&#x2010;being scale, short version (EBS&#x2010;8): Revalidation, measurement invariance, and item response theory. Acta Colombiana de Psicolog&#xed;a, 25(1), 203&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassiani&#x2010;Miranda, C. A., Cuadros&#x2010;Cruz, A. K., Torres&#x2010;Pinz&#xf3;n, H., Scoppetta, O., Pinz&#xf3;n&#x2010;Tarrazona, J. H., L&#xf3;pez&#x2010;Fuentes, W. Y., Paez, A., Cabanzo&#x2010;Arenas, D. F., Ribero&#x2010;Marulanda, S., &amp; Llanes&#x2010;Amaya, E. R. (2021). Validity of the patient health Questionnaire&#x2010;9 (PHQ&#x2010;9) for depression screening in adult primary care users in Bucaramanga, Colombia. Revista Colombiana de Psiquiatr&#xed;a, 50(1), 11&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rcp.2019.09.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xf3;rdoba, L., Tamayo, J. A., Gonz&#xe1;lez, M. A., Mart&#xed;nez, M. I., Rosales, A., &amp; Barbato, S. H. (2024). Adaptation and validation of the Maslach burnout inventory&#x2010;human services survey in Cali, Colombia. Colombia M&#xe9;dica, 42(3), 286&#x2013;293. https://doi.org/10.25100/cm.v42i3.874</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson, L. (2025). Swinging the pendulum from &#x2018;a necessary evil&#x2019; to &#x2018;the dignity of risk&#x2019;: Can new UN legislative guidance help to end psychiatric coercion? International Journal of Law and Psychiatry, 102, 102102. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijlp.2025.102102</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edge, D., &amp; Lemetyinen, H. (2019). Psychology across cultures: Challenges and opportunities. Psychology and Psychotherapy, 92(2), 261&#x2013;276. https://doi.org/10.1111/papt.12229</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbanna, M. F., Thomas, M. R., Patel, P. R., &amp; McHenry, M. S. (2023). Cultivating cultural humility to address the healthcare burnout epidemic&#x2010;why it matters. Global Advances in Integrative Medicine and Health, 12, 27536130231162350. https://doi.org/10.1177/27536130231162350</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin, B., Baker, J., Vogt, K. S., Rich, J., &amp; Johnson, J. (2025). Service users' experiences of restrictive practices in adult inpatient mental health services. A systematic review and meta&#x2010;ethnography of qualitative studies. Journal of Mental Health, 34(5), 624&#x2013;640. https://doi.org/10.1080/09638237.2025.2478372</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerrero, E., Barrios, M., Sampietro, H. M., Aza, A., Guilera, G., &amp; G&#xf3;mez&#x2010;Benito, J. (2025). Recovery in mental health: An international Delphi study from a recovery&#x2010;oriented professional perspective. Social Science &amp; Medicine, 381, 118302. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2025.118302</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez&#x2010;Bello, L. S., De La Hoz Restrepo, F. P., &amp; Cogollo&#x2010;Milan&#xe9;s, Z. (2024). Social determinants of health: An alternative explanatory proposal to the biomedical approach to suicidal behavior. Revista de Salud P&#xfa;blica, 26(1), 1&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.15446/rsap.V26n1.116420</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimmieson, N. L., Tucker, M. K., &amp; Walsh, A. J. (2016). Interaction effects among multiple job demands: An examination of healthcare workers across different contexts. Anxiety, Stress, and Coping, 30(3), 317&#x2013;332. https://doi.org/10.1080/10615806.2016.1229471</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lange, S., Kim, K. V., Jiang, H., Shield, K. D., Rehm, J., Hennis, A. J. M., &amp; Oliveira e Souza, R. (2024). Forecasting the impact of means restriction on the suicide mortality rate in the region of the Americas: An ecological modeling study. The Lancet Regional Health &#x2010; Americas, 36, 100831. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lana.2024.100831</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawson&#x2010;Boyd, E., &amp; Lloyd, S. (2025). &#x201c;A bit damaged, but not broken&#x201d;: Seed containers, care, and safe spaces for suicidality. Culture, Medicine, and Psychiatry: An International Journal of Cross&#x2010;Cultural Health Research, 49(4), 1106&#x2013;1125. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11013&#x2010;025&#x2010;09921&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maslach, C., &amp; Leiter, M. P. (2016). Understanding the burnout experience: Recent research and its implications for psychiatry. World Psychiatry, 15(2), 103&#x2013;111. https://doi.org/10.1002/wps.20311</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer, O. L., Saw, A., Cho, Y. I., &amp; Fancher, T. L. (2015). Disparities in assessment, treatment, and recommendations for specialty mental health care: Patient reports of medical provider behavior. Health Services Research, 50, 750&#x2013;767. https://doi.org/10.1111/1475&#x2010;6773.12261</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morisky, D. E., Green, L. W., &amp; Levine, D. M. (1986). Concurrent and predictive validity of a self&#x2010;reported measure of medication adherence. Medical Care, 24(1), 67&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1097/00005650&#x2010;198601000&#x2010;00007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moro, M. F., Gyimah, L., Susser, E., Ansong, J., Kane, J., Amissah, C., Gureje, O., Osei, A., Norcini Pala, A., Taylor, D., Drew, N., Kofie, H., Baingana, F., Ohene, S. A., Addico, N. L., Fatawu, A., Atzeni, M., D'Oca, S., Carta, M. G., &amp; Funk, M. (2024). Evaluating the psychometric properties of three WHO instruments to assess knowledge about human rights, attitudes toward persons with mental health conditions and psychosocial disabilities, and practices related to substitute decision&#x2010;making and coercion in mental health. Frontiers in Psychiatry, 15, 1435608. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2024.1435608</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan American Health Organization. (2021a). Suicide prevention. PAHO/WHO. https://www.paho.org/es/temas/prevencion&#x2010;suicidio</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan American Health Organization. (2021b). Construir la salud a lo largo del curso de vida. Conceptos, implicaciones y aplicaci&#xf3;n en la salud p&#xfa;blica. Organizaci&#xf3;n Panamericana de la Salud. https://iris.paho.org/handle/10665.2/54490</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterkin, D., Rogers, M. L., Lawrence, O. C., Richards, J., Zheng, S., Astudillo&#x2010;Garc&#xed;a, C. I., Apter Levy, Y., Barzilay, S., Blum, Y., Chistopolskaya, K., &#xc7;inka, E., Dudeck, M., Husain, M. I., Jim&#xe9;nez, A., Kantas Yilmaz, F., Ku&#x15b;mirek, O., Lee, M.&#x2010;B., Menon, V., Peper&#x2010;Nascimento, J., &#x2026; Galynker, I. (2025). Rates and reasons for concealing suicidal ideation from clinicians: A cross&#x2010;national examination. Suicide and Life&#x2010;Threatening Behavior, 55(4), e70039. https://doi.org/10.1111/sltb.70039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phelan, S. M., Salinas, M., Pankey, T., Cummings, G., Allen, J.&#x2010;S. P., Waniger, A., Miller, N. E., Lebow, J., Dovidio, J. F., van Ryn, M., &amp; Doubeni, C. A. (2023). Patient and health care professional perspectives on stigma in integrated behavioral health: Barriers and recommendations. The Annals of Family Medicine, 21(Suppl 2), S56&#x2013;S60. https://doi.org/10.1370/afm.2924</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto &#xc1;lvarez, M. (2020). Characterization of the stigmatization of mental illness in some areas of Bogot&#xe1;. Pontificia Universidad Javeriana. https://hdl.handle.net/10554/48020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeleman, C., Suurmond, J., &amp; Stronks, K. (2009). Cultural competence: A conceptual framework for teaching and learning. Medical Education, 43(3), 229&#x2013;237. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365&#x2010;2923.2008.03269.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slade, M., Amering, M., Farkas, M., Hamilton, B., O'Hagan, M., Panther, G., Perkins, R., Shepherd, G., Tse, S., &amp; Whitley, R. (2014). Uses and abuses of recovery: Implementing recovery&#x2010;oriented practices in mental health systems. World Psychiatry: Official Journal of the World Psychiatric Association (WPA), 13(1), 12&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1002/wps.20084</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soleimani, M., &amp; Yarahmadi, S. (2023). Cultural competence in critical care nurses and its relationships with empathy, job conflict, and work engagement: A cross&#x2010;sectional descriptive study. BMC Nursing, 22, 113. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12912&#x2010;023&#x2010;01285&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speyer, H., Roe, D., &amp; Slade, M. (2025). Recovery&#x2010;oriented psychiatry: Oxymoron or catalyst for change? The Lancet Psychiatry, 12, 795&#x2013;802. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2215&#x2010;0366(25)00045&#x2010;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szmukler, G. (2019). &#x201c;Capacity&#x201d;, &#x201c;best interests&#x201d;, &#x201c;will and preferences&#x201d; and the UN convention on the rights of persons with disabilities. World Psychiatry, 18(1), 34&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1002/wps.20584</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taranu, S. M., Ilie, A. C., Turcu, A. M., Stefaniu, R., Sandu, I. A., Pislaru, A. I., Alexa, I. D., Sandu, C. A., Rotaru, T. S., &amp; Alexa&#x2010;Stratulat, T. (2022). Factors associated with burnout in healthcare professionals. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 19(22), 14701. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph192214701</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesh, N. (2024). Williams's integrity objection as a psychological problem. Topoi, 43(2), 491&#x2013;501. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11245&#x2010;023&#x2010;09966&#x2010;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villatoro&#x2010;Rodr&#xed;guez, S. N., Hern&#xe1;ndez&#x2010;Herrera, G. N., &amp; Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;Garc&#xed;a, H. I. (2025). Validation of the pediatric ACEs and related life events screener (PEARLS) questionnaire to identify exposure to adverse childhood experiences in schoolchildren in Medell&#xed;n. Revista Colombiana de Psiquiatr&#xed;a.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walkowska, A., Przymusza&#x142;a, P., Marciniak&#x2010;St&#x119;pak, P., Nowosadko, M., &amp; Baum, E. (2024). To be culturally competent is to be willing to learn about the differences and to acknowledge them&#x2014;A qualitative study on Polish medical students' attitudes towards cross&#x2010;cultural competence development. BMC Medical Education, 24, 833. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12909&#x2010;024&#x2010;05830&#x2010;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, A. R. (2016). Opportunities in reform: Bioethics and mental health ethics. Bioethics, 30(4), 221&#x2013;226. https://doi.org/10.1111/bioe.12210</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood, E., Ohlsen, S., Long, J., Lumley, E., Senek, M., Hulin, J., Finn, R., Ryan, T., &amp; Weich, S. (2025). Realist evaluation of factors affecting the retention of the mental health workforce: Building a realist programme theory. BMJ Open, 15(8), e102161. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen&#x2010;2025&#x2010;10216</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2021). Quality Rights: WHO quality and rights tool. Pan American Health Organization https://www.paho.org/es/documentos/qualityrights&#x2010;instrumento&#x2010;calidad&#x2010;derechos&#x2010;oms. pp. 1&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2025). Mental health atlas 2024. World Health Organization. http://apps.who.int/iris</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wykes, T., &amp; Molloy, N. (2025). How to write the &#x201c;involving people with lived experience&#x201d; section of an article. Journal of Mental Health (Abingdon, England), 34(5), 511&#x2013;514. https://doi.org/10.1080/09638237.2025.2558502</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanting, A., Frambach, J. M., Meershoek, A., &amp; Krumeich, A. (2025). Exploring the implicit meanings of &#x2018;cultural diversity&#x2019;: A critical conceptual analysis of commonly used approaches in medical education. Advances in Health Sciences Education, 30(4), 859&#x2013;877. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10459&#x2010;024&#x2010;10371&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>