<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41680049</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-8422</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cardiothoracic and vascular anesthesia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Superficial Parasternal Intercostal Plane Block for Analgesia After Cardiac Surgery: An Updated Meta-analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials With Meta-regression and Trial Sequential Analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1053-0770(26)00043-1</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1053/j.jvca.2026.01.017</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Effective postoperative pain control is essential for enhanced recovery after cardiac surgery, yet optimal multimodal strategies continue to evolve. The superficial parasternal intercostal plane (S-PIP) block has been proposed as a simple and safe technique for median sternotomy analgesia; however, current evidence remains fragmented, and its clinical impact is unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials assessing the analgesic efficacy and safety of the S-PIP block in adult cardiac surgery. PubMed, Embase, CENTRAL, Web of Science, Scopus, ClinicalTrials.gov, and gray literature were searched through September 2025. Trials comparing S-PIP with standard or placebo analgesia were pooled using a random-effects model. The primary outcome was 24-hour opioid use (morphine milligram equivalents). Trial sequential analysis, meta-regression, and Grades of Recommendation, Assessment, Development, and Evaluation were applied to evaluate the robustness and certainty of evidence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-seven randomized controlled trials (1,760 patients) met the inclusion criteria. S-PIP block significantly reduced 24-hour opioid use compared with control (mean difference, -8.53 mg; 95% CI, -14.39 to -2.68), although the reduction was below the minimal clinically important difference and demonstrated substantial heterogeneity (I<sup>2</sup> = 98.1%). Trial sequential analysis confirmed statistical significance, but the required sample size was not achieved. The block also lowered early pain scores, reduced rescue analgesic use, and shortened extubation time and intensive care unit stay. No meaningful differences were observed in hospital stay, postoperative nausea and vomiting, or chronic postsurgical pain. The certainty of the evidence ranged from moderate to very low.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">S-PIP provides modest early analgesic benefits after cardiac surgery. Further high-quality multicenter trials are required to clarify its overall clinical value.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dost</LastName><ForeName>Burhan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Reanimation, Ondokuz Mayis University Faculty of Medicine, Samsun, T&#xfc;rkiye. Electronic address: burhandost@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karapinar</LastName><ForeName>Yunus Emre</ForeName><Initials>YE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Reanimation, Istanbul University-Cerrahpasa Faculty of Medicine, Istanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turunc</LastName><ForeName>Esra</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Reanimation, Ondokuz Mayis University Faculty of Medicine, Samsun, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beldagli</LastName><ForeName>Muzeyyen</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Reanimation, Samsun Training and Research Hospital, Samsun, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turan</LastName><ForeName>Engin &#x130;hsan</ForeName><Initials>E&#x130;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Reanimation, Health Science University, Istanbul Kanuni Sultan S&#xfc;leyman Education and Training Hospital, Istanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Cassai</LastName><ForeName>Alessandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine (DIMED), University of Padua, Padua, Italy; Institute of Anesthesia and Intensive Care Unit, University Hospital of Padua, Padua, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9110208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1053-0770</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiac parasternal block meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postoperative surgery</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41680049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.jvca.2026.01.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1053-0770(26)00043-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>