<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41933346</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1472-6955</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Interventions supporting cognitive recovery after surgery: a scoping review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12912-026-04614-y</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guenna Holmgren</LastName><ForeName>Amina</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, Care Sciences and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Alfred Nobels All&#xe9; 23, C3 | 141 83, Huddinge, Sweden. amina.guenna.holmgren@ki.se.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nilsson</LastName><ForeName>Ulrica</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, Care Sciences and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Alfred Nobels All&#xe9; 23, C3 | 141 83, Huddinge, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eckerblad</LastName><ForeName>Jeanette</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, Care Sciences and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Alfred Nobels All&#xe9; 23, C3 | 141 83, Huddinge, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saarij&#xe4;rvi</LastName><ForeName>Markus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, Care Sciences and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Alfred Nobels All&#xe9; 23, C3 | 141 83, Huddinge, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Danderyd Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gothenburg Centre for Person-Centred Care (GPCC), University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kedzierska</LastName><ForeName>Agnieszka</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, Care Sciences and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Alfred Nobels All&#xe9; 23, C3 | 141 83, Huddinge, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bergman</LastName><ForeName>Lina</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, Care Sciences and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Alfred Nobels All&#xe9; 23, C3 | 141 83, Huddinge, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nymark</LastName><ForeName>Carolin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, Care Sciences and Society, Karolinska Institutet, Alfred Nobels All&#xe9; 23, C3 | 141 83, Huddinge, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088683</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6955</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multimodal interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postoperative</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scoping review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41933346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-026-04614-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12912-026-04614-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nilsson U, Gruen R, Myles PS. Postoperative recovery: The importance of the team. Anaesthesia. 2020;75:e158&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evered L, Silbert B, Knopman DS, Scott DA, DeKosky ST, Rasmussen LS, Oh ES, Crosby G, Berger M, Eckenhoff R. Recommendations for the nomenclature of cognitive change associated with anaesthesia and surgery&#x2014;2018. Anesthesiology. 2018;129:872&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migirov A, Chahar P, Maheshwari K. Postoperative delirium and neurocognitive disorders. Curr Opin Crit Care. 2021;27(6):686&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dilmen OK, Meco BC, Evered LA, Radtke FM. Postoperative neurocognitive disorders: A clinical guide. J Clin Anesth. 2024;92:111320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong H, Xu LM, Wang DX. Perioperative neurocognitive disorders: A narrative review focusing on diagnosis, prevention, and treatment. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2022;28(8):1147&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plas M, Rotteveel E, Izaks GJ, Spikman JM, van der Wal-Huisman H, van Etten B, Absalom AR, Mourits MJE, de Bock GH, van Leeuwen BL. Cognitive decline after major oncological surgery in the elderly. Eur J Cancer. 2017;86:394&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evered LA, Silbert BS. Postoperative cognitive dysfunction and noncardiac surgery. Anesth Analg. 2018;127(2):496&#x2013;505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Relander K, Hietanen M, Rantanen K, R&#xe4;m&#xf6; J, Vento A, Saastamoinen KP, Roine RO, Soinne L. Postoperative cognitive change after cardiac surgery predicts long-term cognitive outcome. Brain Behav. 2020;10(9):e01750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao MZ, Liu CX, Zhou LG, Yang Y, Wang Y. Postoperative delirium, neuroinflammation, and influencing factors of postoperative delirium: A review. Med (Baltim). 2023;102(8):e32991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldecoa C, Bettelli G, Bilotta F, Sanders RD, Aceto P, Audisio R, Cherubini A, Cunningham C, Dabrowski W, Forookhi A, et al. Update of the European Society of Anaesthesiology and Intensive Care Medicine evidence-based and consensus-based guideline on postoperative delirium in adult patients. Eur J Anaesthesiol. 2024;41(2):81&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suraarunsumrit P, Srinonprasert V, Kongmalai T, Suratewat S, Chaikledkaew U, Rattanasiri S, McKay G, Attia J, Thakkinstian A. Outcomes associated with postoperative cognitive dysfunction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Age Ageing 2024;53(7).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H, Li H, Zhang X, Shi G, Xu M, Ru X, Chen Y, Patel MB, Ely EW, Lin S. Association of postoperative delirium with cognitive outcomes: a meta-analysis. J Clin Anesth. 2021;75:110496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Au E, Saripella A, Kapoor P, Yan E, Wong J, Tang-Wai DF, Gold D, Riazi S, Suen C, et al. Postoperative outcomes in older surgical patients with preoperative cognitive impairment: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Anesth. 2022;80:110883.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtis MS, Forman NA, Donovan AL, Whitlock EL. Postoperative delirium: why, what, and how to confront it at your institution. Curr Opin Anaesthesiol. 2020;33(5):668&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YQ, Jinling. Modified frailty index independently predicts postoperative delirium and delayed neurocognitive recovery after elective total joint arthroplasty. J Arthroplast. 2021;36(2):449&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng H, Ling Y, Li Q, Li X, Tang Y, Guo J, Li J, Wang Z, Ming WK, Lyu J. Association between modified frailty index and postoperative delirium in patients after cardiac surgery: A cohort study of 2080 older adults. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2024;30(6):e14762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leslie M. The post-op brain. Science. 2017;356 (6341);898&#x2013;900.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Dohan D, Smith AK, Whitlock EL. It was a great brain, and I miss it&#x2019;: lay perspectives on postoperative cognitive dysfunction. Br J Anaesth. 2023;130(5):567&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amirpour A, Bergman L, Markovic G, Liander K, Nilsson U, Eckerblad J. Understanding neurocognitive recovery in older adults after total hip arthroplasty-neurocognitive assessment, blood biomarkers and patient experiences: a mixed-methods study. BMJ Open. 2025;15(1):e093872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergman L, Guenna Holmgren A, Nilsson U, Amirpour A, Conte H, Eckerblad J. The bumpy road to recovery: older adults&#x2019; experiences during the first year after hip replacement surgery - a longitudinal qualitative study. BMC Geriatr. 2025;25(1):483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deiner S, Liu X, Lin H-M, Jacoby R, Kim J, Baxter MG, Sieber F, Boockvar K, Sano M. Does postoperative cognitive decline result in new disability after surgery? Ann Surg. 2021;274(6).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falk A, Stenman M, K&#xe5;hlin J, Hultgren R, Nymark C. Suffering in silence - Cardiac surgery patients recalling hypoactive delirium a qualitative descriptive study. Intensive Crit Care Nurs. 2023;79:103493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen CL, Atkins KJ, Evered LA, Silbert BS, Scott DA. Examining Subjective Psychological Experiences of Postoperative Delirium in Older Cardiac Surgery Patients. Anesth Analg. 2023;136(6):1174&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau KT, Chiu LCS, Fong JSY, Chan AKM, Ho KM, Lee A. Preoperative cognitive training for the prevention of postoperative delirium and cognitive dysfunction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Perioper Med (Lond). 2024;13(1):113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao L, Guo Y, Zhou X, Mao W, Li L. Preoperative cognitive training improves postoperative cognitive function: a meta-analysis and systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Front Neurol. 2023;14:1293153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R, Zhu C, Chen S, Tian F, Huang P, Chen Y. Effects of cognitive training on cognitive function in patients after cardiac surgery: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Med (Baltim). 2024;103(44):e40324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munn Z, Peters MDJ, Stern C, Tufanaru C, McArthur A, Aromataris E. Systematic review or scoping review? Guidance for authors when choosing between a systematic or scoping review approach. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2018;18(1):143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters MDJ, Godfrey C, McInerney P, Munn Z, Tricco AC, Khalil H, Lockwood C, Porritt K, Pilla B, Jordan Z, Aromataris E. Scoping reviews. In: Aromataris E, Lockwood C, Porritt K, Pilla B, Jordan Z, editors. JBI manual for evidence synthesis. Joanna Briggs Institute; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGowan J, Straus S, Moher D, Langlois EV, O&#x2019;Brien KK, Horsley T, Aldcroft A, Zarin W, Garitty CM, Hempel SJJCE. Reporting scoping reviews-PRISMA ScR extension. J Clin Epidemiol. 2020;123(177):e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramer W, Bain P. Updating search strategies for systematic reviews using EndNote. J Med Libr Assoc. 2017;105(3):285&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark JM, Sanders S, Carter M, Honeyman D, Cleo G, Auld Y, Booth D, Condron P, Dalais C, Bateup S, et al. Improving the translation of search strategies using the Polyglot Search Translator: a randomized controlled trial. J Med Libr Assoc. 2020;108(2):195&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glanville J, Dooley G, Wisniewski S, Foxlee R, Noel-Storr A. Development of a search filter to identify reports of controlled clinical trials within CINAHL Plus. Health Info Libr J. 2019;36(1):73&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collaboration TC. Cochrane Highly Sensitive Search Strategy for identifying randomized trials in MEDLINE: sensitivity- and precision-maximizing version In. The Cochrane Collaboration; 2008. https://training.cochrane.org/handbook/current/chapter-04-technical-supplement-searching-and-selecting-studies#section-3-6-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popay J, Roberts H, Sowden A, Petticrew M, Arai L, Rodgers M, Britten N, Roen K, Duffy S. Guidance on the conduct of narrative synthesis in systematic reviews. Prod ESRC methods programme Version. 2006;1(1):b92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butz M, Gerriets T, Sammer G, El-Shazly J, Tschernatsch M, Braun T, Meyer R, Schramm P, Doeppner TR, B&#xf6;ning A, et al. Twelve-month follow-up effects of cognitive training after heart valve surgery on cognitive functions and health-related quality of life: a randomised clinical trial. Open Heart. 2023;10(2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butz M, Gerriets T, Sammer G, El-Shazly J, Tschernatsch M, Huttner HB, Braun T, Boening A, Mengden T, Choi YH, et al. Effects of postoperative cognitive training on neurocognitive decline after heart surgery: a randomized clinical trial. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2022;62(5).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butz M, Gerriets T, Sammer G, El-Shazly J, Tschernatsch M, Schramm P, Doeppner TR, Braun T, Boening A, Mengden T, et al. The impact of postoperative cognitive training on health-related quality of life and cognitive failures in daily living after heart valve surgery: A randomized clinical trial. Brain Behav. 2023;13(3):e2915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greaves D, Astley J, Psaltis PJ, Lampit A, Davis DH, Ghezzi ES, Smith AE, Bourke A, Worthington MG, Valenzuela MJ, et al. The effects of computerised cognitive training on post-CABG delirium and cognitive change: A prospective randomised controlled trial. Delirium (Bielef). 2023;1:67976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang CK, Chu CS, Hsu YH, Chou MY, Wang YC, Lin YT, Renn JH, Liu TY, Yang CC. Effects of modified version of the Hospital Elder Life Program on post-discharge cognitive function and activities of daily living among older adults undergoing total knee arthroplasty. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2021;93:104284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbone E, Vianello E, Carretti B, Borella E. Working Memory Training for Older Adults After Major Surgery: Benefits to Cognitive and Emotional Functioning. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2019;27(11):1219&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarasova I, Trubnikova O, Kukhareva I, Syrova I, Sosnina A, Kupriyanova D, Barbarash O. A comparison of two multi-tasking approaches to cognitive training in cardiac surgery patients. Biomedicines. 2023;11(10).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trubnikova OA, Tarasova IV, Moskin EG, Kupriyanova DS, Argunova YA, Pomeshkina SA, Gruzdeva OV, Barbarash OL. Beneficial Effects of a Short Course of Physical Prehabilitation on Neurophysiological Functioning and Neurovascular Biomarkers in Patients Undergoing Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting. Front Aging Neurosci. 2021;13:699259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajtahed SS, Rezapour T, Etemadi S, Moradi H, Habibi Asgarabad M, Ekhtiari H. Efficacy of Neurocognitive Rehabilitation After Coronary Artery Bypass Graft Surgery in Improving Quality of Life: An Interventional Trial. Front Psychol. 2019;10:1759.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;etinkaya F, Diri MA, G&#xfc;l M. Effect of simple calculation and reading aloud on cognitive function and depression in postoperative older adults. Psychogeriatrics. 2022;22(5):605&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Tournay-Jett&#xe9; E, Dupuis G, Denault A, Cartier R, Bherer L. The benefits of cognitive training after a coronary artery bypass graft surgery. J Behav Med. 2012;35(5):557&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y, Xie Y, Fang P, Shang Z, Chen L, Zhou J, Yang C, Zhu W, Hao X, Ding J, et al. Cognitive Training for Reduction of Delirium in Patients Undergoing Cardiac Surgery: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2024;7(4):e247361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulason K, Nouchi R, Hoshikawa Y, Noda M, Okada Y, Kawashima R. The Beneficial Effects of Cognitive Training With Simple Calculation and Reading Aloud (SCRA) in the Elderly Postoperative Population: A Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial. Front Aging Neurosci. 2018;10:68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Gara BP, Mueller A, Gasangwa DVI, Patxot M, Shaefi S, Khabbaz K, Banner-Goodspeed V, Pascal-Leone A, Marcantonio ER, Subramaniam B. Prevention of Early Postoperative Decline: A Randomized, Controlled Feasibility Trial of Perioperative Cognitive Training. Anesth Analg. 2020;130(3):586&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ros-Nebot B, Rodiera-Oliv&#xe9; J, Verdera-Roig M, Tril-Queralt C, Pradas-Abad&#xed;a A, Juli&#xe1;n-Gonz&#xe1;lez S, Falc&#xf3;-Pegueroles A. Cognitive Training to Reduce Memory Disturbance Associated With Postoperative Cognitive Impairment After Elective Noncardiac Surgery: An Experimental Study. J Perianesth Nurs. 2024;39(4):558&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y, Cui X, Zhang Y, Gao H, Cai Q, Mu Z. Home-Based Computerized Cognitive Training for Postoperative Cognitive Dysfunction After Lung Transplantation in Elderly Population: A Randomized Controlled Trial. J Nerv Ment Dis. 2019;207(8):693&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watne LO, Torbergsen AC, Conroy S, Engedal K, Frihagen F, Hjorthaug GA, Juliebo V, Raeder J, Saltvedt I, Skovlund E, et al. The effect of a pre- and postoperative orthogeriatric service on cognitive function in patients with hip fracture: randomized controlled trial (Oslo Orthogeriatric Trial). BMC Med. 2014;12:63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olotu C, Ascone L, Wiede J, Manthey J, Kuehn S, Scherwath A, Kiefmann R. The effect of delirium preventive measures on the occurrence of postoperative cognitive dysfunction in older adults undergoing cardiovascular surgery. The DelPOCD randomised controlled trial. J Clin Anesth. 2022;78:110686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shyu YI, Tseng MY, Liang J, Tsai WC, Wu CC, Cheng HS. Interdisciplinary intervention decreases cognitive impairment for older Taiwanese with hip fracture: 2-year follow-up. Int J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2013;28(12):1222&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YY, Yue JR, Xie DM, Carter P, Li QL, Gartaganis SL, Chen J, Inouye SK. Effect of the Tailored, Family-Involved Hospital Elder Life Program on Postoperative Delirium and Function in Older Adults: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Intern Med. 2020;180(1):17&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao N, Xue F, Cai W, Li J. Effects of nurse-led home-based telephone support or home visits on cognitive function. Clin Transl Sci. 2022;15(3):741&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen JL, Hang LY, He F, Xu X, Sun HP. Clinical Effect of Application of Interventional Treatment Models for Improvement of Quality of Postoperative Recovery in Elderly Patients with Total Hip Arthroplasty. Int J Gen Med. 2022;15:8343&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pengelly J, Royse C, Williams G, Bryant A, Clarke-Errey S, Royse A, El-Ansary D. Effects of 12-Week Supervised Early Resistance Training (SEcReT) Versus Aerobic-Based Rehabilitation on Cognitive Recovery Following Cardiac Surgery via Median Sternotomy: A Pilot Randomised Controlled Trial. Heart Lung Circ. 2022;31(3):395&#x2013;406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahiri NK, Vuckovic N, Sidhu AS, Li J, Sun Y, Naiken S, Curtis SJ, Bisch E, Bolda R, Nagra PS, et al. Patterns of prevention effectiveness in postoperative neurocognitive disorder and delayed neurocognitive recovery research: a systematic review with meta-regression of randomised trials. Br J Anaesth. 2025;135(2):340&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung S, Kim BR, Moon S, Kim GH. Effects of a 12-Week Hybrid Analog-Digital Cognitive Training on Cognitively Unimpaired Older Adults: A Pilot Single-Blind Randomized Controlled Trial. Dement Neurocogn Disord. 2025;24(4):301&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin X, Xu G, Zhao M, Jiang Y. Efficacy of different digital interventions in patients with mild cognitive impairment or dementia: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Int J Nurs Stud. 2025;169:105129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gates NJ, Vernooij RW, Di Nisio M, Karim S, March E, Mart&#xed;nez G, Rutjes AW. Computerised cognitive training for preventing dementia in people with mild cognitive impairment. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;3(3):Cd012279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsson U, Amirpour A, Lampi M, Guenna Holmgren A, Markovic G, Zecevic E, N&#xf6;mm M, Drakenberg A, Claesson Lingehall H, Dam&#xe9;n T, et al. Older patients&#x2019; postoperative neurocognitive recovery: a narrative review. Clin Interv Aging. 2025;20:2579&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaustov L, Fleet A, Brenna CTA, Orser BA, Choi S. Perioperative Neurocognitive Screening Tools for At-Risk Surgical Patients. Neurol Clin Pract. 2022;12(1):76&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson N, Leach L, Murphy KJ. A re-examination of Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MoCA) cutoff scores. Int J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2018;33(2):379&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murkin JM, Newman SP, Stump DA, Blumenthal JA. Statement of consensus on assessment of neurobehavioral outcomes after cardiac surgery. Ann Thorac Surg. 1995;59(5):1289&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skivington K, Matthews L, Simpson SA, Craig P, Baird J, Blazeby JM, Boyd KA, Craig N, French DP, McIntosh E, et al. A new framework for developing and evaluating complex interventions: update of Medical Research Council guidance. Int J Nurs Stud. 2024;154:104705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Yin Y. Dual roles of anesthetics in postoperative cognitive dysfunction: Regulation of microglial activation through inflammatory signaling pathways. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1102312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safavynia SA, Goldstein PA. The Role of Neuroinflammation in Postoperative Cognitive Dysfunction: Moving From Hypothesis to Treatment. Front Psychiatry. 2018;9:752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan X-x, Sun QL-L. Research progress on the role of inflammatory mechanisms in the development of postoperative cognitive dysfunction. Biomed Res Int. 2021;2021(1):3883204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishizawa Y. Preoperative Cognitive Optimization and Postoperative Cognitive Outcomes: A Narrative Review. Clin Interv Aging. 2025;20:395&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz N, Kastaun S, Schoenburg M, Kaps M, Gerriets T. Subjective impairment after cardiac surgeries: the relevance of postoperative cognitive decline in daily living. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2013;43(6):e162&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kastaun S, Gerriets T, Schwarz NP, Yeniguen M, Schoenburg M, Tanislav C, Juenemann M. The Relevance of Postoperative Cognitive Decline in Daily Living: Results of a 1-Year Follow-up. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2016;30(2):297&#x2013;303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association AP. Diagnostic and statistical manual of mental disorders: DSM-5. Volume 5. American psychiatric association Washington, DC; 2013.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>