<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41928276</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1478-4491</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Human resources for health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Hum Resour Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>"Words fail to describe what has been done": understanding the lived experiences of health professionals during war and siege.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12960-026-01061-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The surge in armed conflicts since the mid-2000s has significantly disrupted healthcare systems, leading to humanitarian crises and profound economic and infrastructure damage. This study explores the experiences of healthcare professionals to examine the impact of the war in Tigray on the healthcare system, professionals' livelihoods, community health, and healthcare services.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A qualitative study using a phenomenological approach was conducted in Tigray Regional State, Ethiopia, involving in-depth interviews with health professionals. Participants were selected through purposive sampling, focusing on those with clinical and administrative roles during the war. Data collection occurred between February and March 2022, with interviews conducted in Tigrigna.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The war has devastated Tigray's healthcare infrastructure, leading to a collapse of health services and a significant decrease in healthcare professionals' quality of life. The community's health has deteriorated due to reduced healthcare access and increased disease prevalence. Key themes identified include the perils of war on a thriving health system, a community hanging by a thread, and resilience and hopes for recovery. The study highlights the urgent need for focused interventions to mitigate the conflict's impacts and foster long-term recovery in the region.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The Tigray war had a profound impact on the healthcare system, professionals, and community health. The findings underscore the necessity of urgent, coordinated efforts to rebuild the health sector, support affected professionals, and enhance community health resilience. This study provides crucial insights into the challenges faced by healthcare systems in conflict zones and the importance of safeguarding these systems against the ravages of war.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kidane</LastName><ForeName>Samuel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MERQ Consultancy PLC, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. samizkmd@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HAQI Foundation, Mekelle, Tigray, Ethiopia. samizkmd@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rujema</LastName><ForeName>Diana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MERQ Consultancy PLC, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zerihun</LastName><ForeName>Zenawi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Mekelle University, Mekelle, Tigray, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HAQI Foundation, Mekelle, Tigray, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Araya</LastName><ForeName>Firehiwot</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MERQ Consultancy PLC, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amdeselasie</LastName><ForeName>Fasika</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Mekelle University, Mekelle, Tigray, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HAQI Foundation, Mekelle, Tigray, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mulugeta</LastName><ForeName>Afework</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Mekelle University, Mekelle, Tigray, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teklu</LastName><ForeName>Alula</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MERQ Consultancy PLC, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HAQI Foundation, Mekelle, Tigray, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Hum Resour Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101170535</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1478-4491</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Attacks on health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health in Fragile and conflict-affected settings (FCAS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Human resources for health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Humanitarian crisis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tigray</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval was obtained from the Institutional Review Board (IRB) of the Tigray Health Research Institute (IRB No: 4031/0799/2014). Permission was also obtained from the Regional Health and Education Bureaus and local authorities. Informed consent was acquired from every study participant, and a clear explanation was given to the study participants about the objectives of the study and their right to withdraw from participation at any time. The data collectors were trained to observe the signs of emotional distress of the participants, during which they were instructed to stop the interview and only resume if the participants wished to do so. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interest: The authors declare no competing interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41928276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12960-026-01061-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12960-026-01061-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cederman L, Pengl Y. Global conflict trends and their consequences. United Nations, Department of Economics and Social Affairs working paper. 2019. https://www.un.org/development/desa/dpad/wp-content/uploads/sites/45/publication/SDO_BP_Cederman_Pengl.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunne JP, Hoeffler A, Mack A. Armed conflicts. In: Lomborg B, editor. Global problems, smart solutions: costs and benefits. New York: Cambridge University Press for Copenhagen Consensus; 2013. p. 21&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations. Capping three-day humanitarian segment, economic and social council adopts text urging better protection of people trapped in crisis, aid workers. 2016. https://www.un.org/press/en/2016/ga11870.doc.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Committee of the Red Cross. Geneva Conventions of 1949 and Additional Protocols, and their commentaries [Internet]. 2016 [cited 2023 Jun 17]. https://www.icrc.org/applic/ihl/ihl.nsf/vwTreaties1949.xsp.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siem FF. Leaving them behind: healthcare services in situations of armed conflict. Tidsskr Nor Legeforen. 2017;137(17):1341&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruk ME, Freedman LP, Anglin GA, Waldman RJ. Rebuilding health systems to improve health and promote statebuilding in post-conflict countries: a theoretical framework and research agenda. Soc Sci Med. 2010;70:89&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Bank. East Timor. PID report 8817. Washington DC: World Bank; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyer O. Poor security is the biggest impediment to health care in Iraq. BMJ. 2003;326(7399):1107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comtesse H, Powell S, Soldo A, et al. Long-term psychological distress of Bosnian war survivors: an 11-year follow-up of former displaced persons, returnees, and stayers. BMC Psychiatry. 2019;19(1):1. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12888-018-1996-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bou-Karroum L, El-Harakeh A, Kassamany I, Ismail H, El Arnaout N, Charide R, et al. Health care workers in conflict and post-conflict settings: systematic mapping of the evidence. PLoS ONE. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0233757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhadi M, Msherghi A, Elgzairi M, Alhashimi A, Bouhuwaish A, Biala M, et al. Psychological status of healthcare workers during the civil war and COVID-19 pandemic: a cross-sectional study. J Psychosom Res. 2020;137:110221. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychores.2020.110221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steel Z, Chey T, Silove D, Marnane C, Bryant RA, Van Ommeren M. Association of torture and other potentially traumatic events with mental health outcomes among populations exposed to mass conflict and displacement: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA. 2009;302(5):537&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cocker F, John N. Compassion fatigue among healthcare, emergency and community service workers: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2016;13:618. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph1306061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeyemo SO, Omoaregba JO, Aroyewun BA, Modebe VO, James BO, Uteh BE, et al. Experiences of violence, compassion fatigue and compassion satisfaction on the professional quality of life of mental health professionals at a tertiary psychiatric facility in Nigeria. Open Sci J Clin Med. 2015;3(2):69&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner Z, Heft-Neal S, Wise PH, Black RE, Burke M, Boerma T, et al. Women and children living in areas of armed conflict in Africa: a geospatial analysis of mortality and orphanhood. Lancet Glob Health. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2214-109X(19)30407-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agadjanian V, Prata N. Civil war and child health: regional and ethnic dimensions of child immunization and malnutrition in Angola. Soc Sci Med. 2003;56(12):2515&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinyoki DK, Moloney GM, Uthman OA, Kandala NB, Odundo EO, Noor AM, et al. Conflict in Somalia: impact on child undernutrition. BMJ Glob Health. 2017. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjgh-2016-000262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostby G, Urdal H, Tollefsen AF, Kotsadam A, Belbo R, Ormhaug C. Organized violence and institutional child delivery: micro-level evidence from sub-Saharan Africa, 1989-2014. Demography. 2018;55(4):1295&#x2013;316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandrasekhar S, Gebreselassie T, Jayaraman A. Maternal health care seeking behavior in a post-conflict HIPC: the case of Rwanda. Popul Res Policy Rev. 2011;30(1):25&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brentlinger PE, S&#xe1;nchez-P&#xe9;rez HJ, Cede&#xf1;o MA, Morales LG, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Micek MA, et al. Pregnancy outcomes, site of delivery, and community schisms in regions affected by the armed conflict in Chiapas, Mexico. Soc Sci Med. 2005;61(5):1001&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco S, Suarez C, Naranjo C, B&#xe1;ez L, Rozo P. The effects of the armed conflict on the life and health in Colombia. Cien Saude Colet. 2006. https://doi.org/10.1590/S1413-81232006000200013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesesew H, Berhane K, Siraj ES, Siraj D, Gebregziabher M, Gebre YG, et al. The impact of war on the health system of the Tigray region in Ethiopia: an assessment. BMJ Glob Health. 2021;6:e007328. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjgh-2021-007328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebregziabher M, Amdeselassie F, Esayas R, et al. Geographical distribution of the health crisis of war in the Tigray region of Ethiopia. BMJ Glob Health. 2022;7(4):e008475. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjgh-2022-008475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weledegebriel MG, Nigusse AT, Gebru T, et al. Outcome of HIV patients on ART during the war and siege in a tertiary hospital in Northern Ethiopia: a cross-sectional study. Sci Rep. 2025;15:6434. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-90848-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;decins sans Fronti&#xe8;res. People were left with few healthcare options in Tigray as facilities were looted, and destroyed. 2021. https://www.msf.org/health-facilities-targeted-tigray-region-ethiopia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legesse AY, Hadush Z, Teka H, et al. Lived experience of healthcare providers amidst war and siege: a phenomenological study of Ayder Comprehensive Specialized Hospital of Tigray, Northern Ethiopia. BMC Health Serv Res. 2024;24:292. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12913-024-10655-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations. Ethiopia: Peace agreement between government and Tigray &#x2018;a critical first step&#x2019;: Guterres. Geneva: United Nations; 2022. https://news.un.org/en/story/2022/11/1130137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendrix N, Warkaye S, Tesfaye L, Woldekidan MA, Arja A, Sato R, et al. Estimated travel time and staffing constraints to accessing the Ethiopian health care system: a two-step floating catchment area analysis. J Glob Health. 2023;13:04008. https://doi.org/10.7189/jogh.13.04008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woldemichael A, Takian A, Akbari Sari A, et al. Inequalities in healthcare resources and outcomes threatening sustainable health development in Ethiopia: panel data analysis. BMJ Open. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2018-022923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terefe B, Alemu TG, Techane MA, Wubneh CA, Assimamaw NT, Belay GM, et al. Spatial distribution and associated factors of community-based health insurance coverage in Ethiopia: further analysis of Ethiopian demography and health survey, 2019. BMC Public Health. 2022;22(1):1523. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-022-13950-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2019 Ethiopia Subnational-Level Disease Burden Initiative Collaborators. Progress in health among regions of Ethiopia, 1990-2019: a subnational country analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019. Lancet. 2022;399(10332):1322&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02868-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Central Statistical Agency of Ethiopia. The 2006 Ethiopian national statistics report. Addis Ababa: Central Statistical Agency of Ethiopia; 2006. http://www.csa.gov.et/text_files/national_statistics_2005/Population.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gates S, Hegre H, Nyg&#xe5;rd HM, Strand H. Development consequences of armed conflict. World Dev. 2012;40(9):1713&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNICEF. Tigray&#x2019;s children in crisis and beyond reach, after months of conflict. 2021. https://news.un.org/en/story/2021/01/1083102#:~:text='70%2C000%20children%20at%20risk'&amp;text=According%20to%20UNICEF%2C%20within%20Tigray,%E2%80%9D%2C%20Ms.%20Fore%20maintained.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raad II, Chaftari AM, Dib RW, Graviss EA, Hachem R. Emerging outbreaks associated with conflict and failing healthcare systems in the Middle East. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol. 2018;39(10):1230&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar MA, Law R, Winkler V. Health consequences of an armed conflict in Zamboanga, Philippines using a syndromic surveillance database. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2018;15(12):2690. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph15122690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kherallah M, Alahfez T, Sahloul Z, Eddin KD, Jamil G. Heath care in Syria before and during the crisis. Avicenna J Med. 2012;2:51&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell V, M&#xe9;ndez F, Mart&#xed;nez C, Palma PP, Bosch M. Characteristics of the Colombian armed conflict and the mental health of civilians living in active conflict zones. Confl Health. 2012;6(1):10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Jong JTVM, Komproe IH, Van Ommeren M, El Masri M, Araya M, Khaled N. Lifetime events and posttraumatic stress disorder in 4 post conflict settings. JAMA. 2001;286(5):555&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford S, Saleh S. Rebuilding health post-conflict: case studies, reflections and a revised framework. Health Policy Plan. 2019;34(3):230&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martineau T, McPake B, Theobald S, Raven J, Ensor T, Fustukian S, et al. Leaving no one behind: lessons on rebuilding health systems in conflict-and crisis-affected states. BMJ Glob Health. 2017. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjgh-2017-000327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan JM, Mahoney PF, Macnab C. Conflict recovery and intervening in hospitals. BMJ. 2005;331(7511):278&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayatissa R, Bekele A, Kethiswaran A, De Silva AH. Community-based management of severe and moderate acute malnutrition during emergencies in Sri Lanka: challenges of implementation. Food Nutr Bull. 2012;33(4):251&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1177/156482651203300405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tappis H, Doocy S, Haskew C, Wilkinson C, Oman A, Spiegel P. United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees feeding program performance in Kenya and Tanzania: a retrospective analysis of routine Health Information System data. Food Nutr Bull. 2012;33(2):150&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1177/156482651203300209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe. Principles to guide health system recovery and transformation in Ukraine. Copenhagen: World Health Organization; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lis J, Eliades MJ, Benishi D, Koci B, Gettle D, Vanrooyen MJ. Post-war Kosovo: Part 3 development and rehabilitation of emergency services. Prehosp Disaster Med. 2001;16:275. https://doi.org/10.1017/S1049023X00043429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanier VK, Vanrooyen MJ, Lis J, Eliades MJ. Post-war Kosovo: Part l assessment of prehospital emergency services. Prehosp Disaster Med. 2001;16:263. https://doi.org/10.1017/S1049023X00043405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustafa M, Berisha M, Lenjani B. Reforms and challenges of post-conflict Kosovo health system. Mater Sociomed. 2014;26(2):125&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newbrander W, Waldman R, Shepherd&#x2010;Banigan M. Rebuilding and strengthening health systems and providing basic health services in fragile states. Disasters. 2011;35(4):639&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavignani E, Colombo S. Analysing disrupted health sectors: a modular manual. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Hanlon KP, Budosan B. Post-disaster recovery: a case study of human resource deployment in the health sector in post-conflict Kosovo. Prehosp Disaster Med. 2011;26(1):7&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raven J, Wurie H, Idriss A, Bah AJ, Baba A, Nallo G, et al. How should community health workers in fragile contexts be supported: qualitative evidence from Sierra Leone, Liberia and Democratic Republic of Congo. Hum Resour Health. 2020;18(1):1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wurie HR, Samai M, Witter S. Retention of health workers in rural Sierra Leone: findings from life histories. Hum Resour Health. 2016;14(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gariba EB. Post-conflict development in Liberia: governance, security, capacity building and a developmental approach. Afr J Confl Resolut. 2011;11(2):105&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>