<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41673317</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sequential model predictive direct speed control of PMSM.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8226</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-39256-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Finite control set model predictive control (FCS-MPC) has emerged as a powerful strategy for permanent magnet synchronous motor (PMSM) drives. However, its performance strongly depends on appropriately chosen weighting factors, which directly affect control quality and, in some cases, may even lead to instability. Despite the crucial role of weighting factors, there is no systematic or generally accepted procedure for selecting their values, which limits the robustness and practical applicability of conventional FCS-MPC methods. To overcome this limitation, this paper presents the experimental validation of a sequential direct speed predictive control strategy for PMSM. The individual cost functions are evaluated sequentially, thereby tuning is simplified and weighting factors are reduced. Experimental results show that the original version of sequential direct speed control, as proposed in the literature, exhibits promising dynamic performance but suffers from instability and current ripples under certain conditions. To address these issues, an enhanced version of the sequential direct speed predictive control is proposed in the paper. It effectively suppresses instabilities and enhances the speed dynamic response of the drive. The proposed approach was experimentally validated using the OP 5600 rapid control prototyping platform running RT-LAB software and a 1.1 kW PMSM machine.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pancur&#xe1;k</LastName><ForeName>Luk&#xe1;&#x161;</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Informatics, Dept. of Electrical Engineering and Mechatronics, Technical University of Ko&#x161;ice, 042 00, Ko&#x161;ice, Slovak Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horv&#xe1;th</LastName><ForeName>Kriszti&#xe1;n</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Informatics and Electrical Engineering, Dept. of Electrical Engineering and Infocommunications, Sz&#xe9;chenyi Istv&#xe1;n University, 9026, Gy&#x151;r, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kyslan</LastName><ForeName>Karol</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Informatics, Dept. of Electrical Engineering and Mechatronics, Technical University of Ko&#x161;ice, 042 00, Ko&#x161;ice, Slovak Republic. karol.kyslan@tuke.sk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>VEGA 1/0363/23</GrantID><Agency>Scientific Grant Agency of the Ministry of Education, Science, Research and Sport of the Slovak Republic and Slovak Academy of Sciences (VEGA)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>09I05-03-V02-00018</GrantID><Agency>EU NextGenerationEU Recovery and Resilience Plan for Slovakia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>EK&#xd6;P-24-4-II-SZE-89</GrantID><Agency>University Research Fellowship Program of the Ministry for Culture and Innovation from the source of the National Research, Development and Innovation Fund</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Finite control set</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Model predictive control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Permanent magnet synchronous machine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sequential control</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41673317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12963593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-39256-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-39256-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Preindl, M. &amp; Bolognani, S. Model predictive direct speed control with finite control set of PMSM drive systems. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>28</b>, 1007&#x2013;1015. 10.1109/TPEL.2012.2204277 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2012.2204277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, F., Zhang, Z., Mei, X., Rodr&#xed;guez, J. &amp; Kennel, R. Advanced control strategies of induction machine: Field oriented control, direct torque control and model predictive control. <i>Energies</i><b>11</b>, 10.3390/en11010120 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtz, J. Advanced PWM and predictive control-An overview. <i>IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron.</i><b>63</b>, 3837&#x2013;3844. 10.1109/TIE.2015.2504347 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2015.2504347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, T. et al. Finite-control-set model predictive control of permanent magnet synchronous motor drive systems-An overview. <i>IEEE/CAA Journal of Automatica Sinica</i><b>9</b>, 2087&#x2013;2105. 10.1109/JAS.2022.105851 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JAS.2022.105851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vazquez, S., Rodriguez, J., Rivera, M., Franquelo, L. G. &amp; Norambuena, M. Model predictive control for power converters and drives: Advances and trends. <i>IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron.</i><b>64</b>, 935&#x2013;947. 10.1109/TIE.2016.2625238 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2016.2625238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes, P., Kazmierkowski, M. P., Kennel, R. M., Quevedo, D. E. &amp; Rodriguez, J. Predictive control in power electronics and drives. <i>IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron.</i><b>55</b>, 4312&#x2013;4324. 10.1109/TIE.2008.2007480 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2008.2007480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez, J. &amp; Cortes, P. <i>Model Predictive Control</i>, vol.&#xa0;1, chap.&#xa0;3, 31&#x2013;39 (John Wiley &amp; Sons, 2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Z., Wang, Z., Wang, X. &amp; Cheng, M. Predictive current control method for dual three-phase PMSM drives with reduced switching frequency and low-computation burden. <i>IET Electric Power Applications</i><b>14</b>, 668&#x2013;677. 10.1049/iet-epa.2019.0529 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/iet-epa.2019.0529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M, D., Samithas, D., Kumar B, P. &amp; Shitharth. Experimental analysis of enhanced finite set model predictive control and direct torque control in SRM drives for torque ripple reduction. <i>Scientific Reports</i><b>14</b>, 10.1038/s41598-024-65202-1 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11263375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39039123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, R. &amp; Cao, Y. Hybrid flux predictor-based predictive flux control of permanent magnet synchronous motor drives. <i>IET Electric Power Applications</i><b>16</b>, 472&#x2013;482. 10.1049/elp2.12168 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/elp2.12168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu, W., Luo, G., Chen, Z., Cui, L. &amp; Kennel, R. Predictive cascaded speed and current control for PMSM drives with multi-timescale optimization. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>34</b>, 11046&#x2013;11061. 10.1109/TPEL.2019.2897746 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2019.2897746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, W., Song, Z., Xiao, X., Guo, Y. &amp; Mo, Y. Sliding mode speed control for PMSM based on model predictive current. <i>Electronics</i><b>13</b>, 10.3390/electronics13132561 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, V., Sharma, V., Naresh, R. &amp; Arya, Y. A novel predictive optimal control strategy for renewable penetrated interconnected power system. <i>Optimal Control Applications and Methods</i><b>45</b>, 2190&#x2013;2205. 10.1002/oca.3144 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oca.3144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z., Liu, Y., Liang, X., Guo, H. &amp; Zhuang, X. Robust Model Predictive Current Control of PMSM Based on Nonlinear Extended State Observer. <i>IEEE Journal of Emerging and Selected Topics in Power Electronics</i><b>11</b>, 862&#x2013;873. 10.1109/JESTPE.2022.3192064 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JESTPE.2022.3192064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z., Wang, X. &amp; Xu, J. Robust Amplitude Control Set Model Predictive Control With Low-Cost Error for SPMSM Based on Nonlinear Extended State Observer. <i>IEEE Transactions on Power Electronics</i><b>39</b>, 7016&#x2013;7028. 10.1109/TPEL.2024.3380577 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2024.3380577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z., Guo, H. &amp; Liu, Y. DC-Link Voltage Constraint Strategy for DC Power Supply Film-Capacitor Drive System Based on Improved Model Predictive Control. <i>IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics</i><b>69</b>, 9849&#x2013;9859. 10.1109/TIE.2022.3150105 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2022.3150105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, M., Chan, K. W., Hu, J., Xu, W. &amp; Rodriguez, J. Model predictive direct speed control with torque oscillation reduction for PMSM drives. <i>IEEE Trans. Ind. Informat.</i><b>15</b>, 4944&#x2013;4956. 10.1109/TII.2019.2898004 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TII.2019.2898004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, X., Abdelrahem, M., Hackl, C.&#xa0;M., Zhang, Z. &amp; Kennel, R. Direct predictive speed control with a sliding manifold term for PMSM drives. <i>IEEE Trans. Emerg. Sel. Topics Power Electron.</i><b>8</b>, 1258&#x2013;1267, 10.1109/JESTPE.2019.2923285 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pancur&#xe1;k, L., Jure, T. &amp; Kyslan, K. Finite control set model predictive direct speed control of PMSM. In <i>EDPE</i>, 2023 International Conference on Electrical Drives and Power Electronics, 396&#x2013;401, 10.1109/EDPE58625.2023.10274055 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahid, M. et al. Optimal weighting factor design based on entropy technique in finite control set model predictive torque control for electric drive applications. <i>Scientific Reports</i><b>14</b>, 10.1038/s41598-024-63694-5 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11150273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38834768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Rub, H., Malinowski, M. &amp; Al-Haddad, K. <i>Model Predictive Speed Control of Electrical Machines</i>, vol.&#xa0;1, chap.&#xa0;19, 608&#x2013;629 (Wiley-IEEE Press, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anilkumar, M., Padhiyar, N. &amp; Moudgalya, K. Lexicographic optimization based MPC: Simulation and experimental study. <i>Computers &amp; Chemical Engineering</i><b>88</b>, 135&#x2013;144. 10.1016/j.compchemeng.2016.02.002 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compchemeng.2016.02.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahid, M. B. et al. Hysteresis based predictive torque control without weighting factors for induction motor drives. <i>IET Control Theory &amp; Applications</i><b>18</b>, 2675&#x2013;2692. 10.1049/cth2.12681 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/cth2.12681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norambuena, M. et al. A very simple strategy for high-quality performance of AC machines using model predictive control. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>34</b>, 794&#x2013;800. 10.1109/TPEL.2018.2812833 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2018.2812833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Zhang, B., Yang, H., Norambuena, M. &amp; Rodriguez, J. Generalized sequential model predictive control of IM drives with field-weakening ability. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>34</b>, 8944&#x2013;8955. 10.1109/TPEL.2018.2886206 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2018.2886206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, K. et al. Tolerant sequential model predictive direct torque control of permanent magnet synchronous machine drives. <i>IEEE Trans. Transport. Electrific.</i><b>6</b>, 1167&#x2013;1176. 10.1109/TTE.2020.3008828 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TTE.2020.3008828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davari, S. A., Norambuena, M., Nekoukar, V., Garcia, C. &amp; Rodriguez, J. Even-handed sequential predictive torque and flux control. <i>IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron.</i><b>67</b>, 7334&#x2013;7342. 10.1109/TIE.2019.2945274 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2019.2945274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Z. et al. Weighting-factor-less model predictive control with multiobjectives for three-level hybrid ANPC inverter drives. <i>IEEE Trans. Emerg. Sel. Topics Power Electron.</i><b>11</b>, 4726&#x2013;4738, 10.1109/JESTPE.2023.3297191 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, Y., Xu, W., Dong, D., Liu, Y. &amp; Ismail, M. M. Low-complexity multistep sequential model predictive current control for three-level inverter-fed linear induction machines. <i>IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron.</i><b>70</b>, 5537&#x2013;5548. 10.1109/TIE.2022.3192688 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2022.3192688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, T., Yao, X., Wang, J. &amp; Ma, C. Efficient two-vector-based sequential model predictive control for IM drives. <i>IEEE Trans. Emerg. Sel. Topics Power Electron.</i><b>12</b>, 903&#x2013;912, 10.1109/JESTPE.2023.3334468 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zerdali, E., Rivera, M. &amp; Wheeler, P. A review on weighting factor design of finite control set model predictive control strategies for AC electric drives. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>39</b>, 9967&#x2013;9981. 10.1109/TPEL.2024.3370550 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2024.3370550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zerdali, E., Kilic, C., Riccio, J., Rivera, M. &amp; Wheeler, P. Sequential direct speed predictive control without weighting factors. In <i>PEMD 2024</i>, vol. 2024 of <i>13th International Conference on Power Electronics, Machines and Drives</i>, 167&#x2013;171, 10.1049/icp.2024.2153 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karamanakos, P. &amp; Geyer, T. Guidelines for the design of finite control set model predictive controllers. <i>IEEE Transactions on Power Electronics</i><b>35</b>, 7434&#x2013;7450. 10.1109/TPEL.2019.2954357 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2019.2954357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pancur&#xe1;k, L. &amp; Kyslan, K. Sensitivity analysis of sequential direct speed predictive control of PMSM. In <i>2025 International Conference on Electrical Drives and Power Electronics (EDPE)</i>, 293&#x2013;298, 10.1109/EDPE66853.2025.11224112 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henwood, N., Malaiz&#xe9;, J. &amp; Praly, L. A robust nonlinear Luenberger observer for the sensorless control of SM-PMSM: Rotor position and magnets flux estimation. In <i>IECON 2012 - 38th Annual Conference on IEEE Industrial Electronics Society</i>, 1625&#x2013;1630 10.1109/IECON.2012.6388732 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, T., Sun, X., Yao, M., Guo, D. &amp; Sun, Y. Improved finite control set model predictive current control for permanent magnet synchronous motor with sliding mode observer. <i>IEEE Trans. Transport. Electrific.</i><b>10</b>, 699&#x2013;710. 10.1109/TTE.2023.3293510 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TTE.2023.3293510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong, C., Hu, Y., Ni, K., Liu, J. &amp; Gao, J. SM load torque observer-based FCS-MPDSC with single prediction horizon for high dynamics of surface-mounted PMSM. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>35</b>, 20&#x2013;24. 10.1109/TPEL.2019.2929714 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2019.2929714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, L., Song, H. &amp; Liang, D. High performance sensorless control of PMSM with sliding mode load torque observer. In <i>2020 4th International Conference on HVDC (HVDC)</i>, 1060&#x2013;1065, 10.1109/HVDC50696.2020.9292881 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes, P., Rodriguez, J., Silva, C. &amp; Flores, A. Delay compensation in model predictive current control of a three-phase inverter. <i>IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics</i><b>59</b>, 1323&#x2013;1325. 10.1109/TIE.2011.2157284 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2011.2157284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>