<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41917956</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1746-6148</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC veterinary research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Vet Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of the effects of a single bolus of cisatracurium as part of an anesthetic protocol in cats undergoing orthopedic surgery.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12917-026-05327-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Non-depolarizing neuromuscular blocking agents (NMBAs) are commonly used in human anesthesia but remain uncommon in veterinary medicine. This study evaluated the effects of 0.5&#xa0;mg/kg cisatracurium IV on muscle relaxation, cardiovascular variables and postoperative pain in cats undergoing orthopedic surgery. Twenty-four cats were randomly assigned to a control group (Group C) or a treatment group receiving cisatracurium (Group M) immediately after induction. Neuromuscular function was monitored using a calibrated train-of-four (TOF) device. Postoperative pain was assessed with the short form of the Glasgow Feline Composite Measure Pain Scale (CMPS-Feline). The mean time to suppression of muscle contraction was 2.6&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.8&#xa0;min, with peak suppression (90%) at 3.0&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.7&#xa0;min, a mean duration of 23.3&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.4&#xa0;min, and complete recovery at 27.3&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;8.6&#xa0;min. Group M required lower sevoflurane concentrations to maintain anesthesia compared to Group C (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) and had a shorter mean surgical time (25.3&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;3&#xa0;min vs. 31.5&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4&#xa0;min; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Pain scores were also lower in Group M (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01). These findings demonstrate that cisatracurium effectively induces neuromuscular block (NMB) and improves surgical conditions, resulting in lower postoperative pain scores in cats undergoing femoral fracture repair.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Interlandi</LastName><ForeName>Claudia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Sciences, University of Messina, Via Palatucci Annunziata, Messina, 98100, Italy. cinterlandi@unime.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tabb&#xec;</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Sciences, University of Messina, Via Palatucci Annunziata, Messina, 98100, Italy. marco.tabbi@unime.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iannelli</LastName><ForeName>Nicola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Sciences, University of Messina, Via Palatucci Annunziata, Messina, 98100, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinica Veterinaria Camagna, Via Fortunato Licandro 13, Vetpartners Reggio Calabria, 84124, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iannelli</LastName><ForeName>Diego</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinica Veterinaria Camagna, Via Fortunato Licandro 13, Vetpartners Reggio Calabria, 84124, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barillaro</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CVSG (Clinica Veterinaria San Giorgio), Via Vecchia Pentimele, 63, Reggio Calabria, 89121, RC, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zappone</LastName><ForeName>Viola</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Sciences, University of Messina, Via Palatucci Annunziata, Messina, 98100, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Pietro</LastName><ForeName>Simona</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Sciences, University of Messina, Via Palatucci Annunziata, Messina, 98100, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Macr&#xec;</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Sciences, University of Messina, Via Palatucci Annunziata, Messina, 98100, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Vet Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101249759</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1746-6148</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anesthesia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cat</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cisatracurium</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromuscular blockade</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sevoflurane</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participant: The protocol and procedures were approved by the Ethics Committee of the Department of Veterinary Medicine and Animal Production, University of Messina, Italy (prot.no. 074/2022). Written informed consent was obtained from the owner of each cat prior to the inclusion of the cat in the study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41917956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12917-026-05327-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12917-026-05327-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Yang H, Li M, Peng H, Guo W, Li M. Effect of oral administration of Gabapentin on the minimum alveolar concentration of isoflurane in cats. Front Vet Sci. 2023;10:1117313. https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2023.1117313. PMID: 36865443; PMCID: PMC9972096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendes GM, Selmi AL, Barbudo-Selmi GR, Lins BT, Figueiredo JP. Clinical use of dexmedetomidine as premedicant in cats undergoing propofol-sevoflurane anaesthesia. J Feline Med Surg. 2003;5(5):265&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1098-612X(03)00053-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgson DS, Dunlop CI, Chapman PL, Grandy JL. Cardiopulmonary effects of anesthesia induced and maintained with isoflurane in cats. Am J Vet Res. 1998;59(2):182-5. PMID: 9492933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullen LK. Muscle relaxants and neuromuscular block. In: Lumb &amp; Jones: Textbook of&#x2019; Veterinary Anesthesia. 3th edition. Philadelphia: Williams &amp; Wilkins; 1996. p. 337&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keegan R. Muscle Relaxants and Neuromuscular Blockade: The Fifth Edition of Lumb and Jones 2017. https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119421375.ch14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryson HM, Faulds D. Cisatracurium besilate. A review of its pharmacology and clinical potential in anaesthetic practice. Drugs. 1997;53(5):848&#x2013;66.https://doi.org/10.2165/00003495- 199753050-00012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruintjes MH, van Helden EV, Braat AE, Dahan A, Scheffer GJ, van Laarhove CJ, et al. Deep neuromuscular block to optimize surgical space conditions during laparoscopic surgery: a system-atic review and meta-analysis. Br J Anaesth. 2017;118(6):834&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1093/bja/aex116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams WA, Robinson KJ, Mark Senior J, Jones RS. The use of the nondepolarizing neuromuscular blocking drug cis-atracurium in dogs. Vet Anaesth Analg. 2001;28(3):156&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1467-2987.2001.00045.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kastrup MR, Marsico FF, Ascoli FO, Becker T, Soares JH, Gomez de Segura IA. Neuromuscular blocking properties of atracurium during sevoflurane or propofol anaesthesia in dogs. Vet Anaesth Analg. 2005;32(4):222&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-2995.2005.00240.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams WA, Mark Senior J, Jones RS, Williams JM, Gleed RD. Cis-Atracurium in dogs with and-without porto-systemic shunts. Vet Anaesth Analg. 2006;33(1):17&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-2995.2005.00231.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagahama S, Nishimura R, Mochizuki M, Sasaki N. The effects of propofol, isoflurane and sevoflurane on vecuronium in-fusion rates for surgical muscle relaxation in dogs. Vet Anaesth An-alg. 2006;33(3):169&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-2995.2005.00252.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carregaro AB, Freitas GC, Ferreira da Cruz FS, Machado M, Tognoli GK, Pippi NL. Cardiopulmo-nary effects and eyeball centralization with low-dose atracurium in spontaneously breathing, anes-thetized dogs. Cienc Rural. July 2010;40(7). https://doi.org/10.1590/S0103-84782010005000118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ida KK, Van-Wijnsberghe AS, Tutunaru A, Limpens V, Sauvage A, Serteyn D, et al. Onset and duration of cis-atracurium neuromuscular block during fentanyl and lidocaine infusions in isoflurane-anaesthetised dogs. Vet Rec. 2020;187(5):e33. https://doi.org/10.1136/vr.105522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interlandi C, Di Pietro S, Costa GL, Spadola F, Iannelli NM, Macr&#xec; D, et al. Ef-fects of Cisatracurium in Sevoflurane and Propofol Requirements in Dog-Undergoing-Mastectomy Surgery. Animals (Basel). 2022;12(22):3134. https://doi.org/10.3390/ani12223134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driessen JJ, van Egmond J, van der Pol F, Crul JF. Effects of two benzodiazepines and a benzodiazepine antagonist on neuromuscular Blockade in the anaesthetized Cat. Arch Int Pharmacodyn Ther. 1987;286(1):58&#x2013;70. PMID: 2884940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wastila WB, Maehr RB, Turner GL, et al. Comparative pharmacology of cisatracurium (51W89), atracurium, and five isomers in cats. Anesthesiology. 1996;85:169&#x2013;77. https://doi.org/10.1097/00000542-199607000-00023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auer U, Mosing M. A clinical study of the effects of rocuronium in isoflurane-anaesthetized cats. Vet Anaesth Analg. 2006;33(4):224&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-2995.2005.00262.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galluzzi F, De Rensis F, Menozzi A, Spattini G. Effect of intraurethral administration of atracu-rium besylate in male cats with urethral plugs. J Small Anim Pract. 2012;53(7):411&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1748-5827.2012.01239.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-Flores M, Sakai DM, Portela DA, Borlle L, Campoy L, Gleed RD. Prevention of laryn-gospasm with rocuronium in cats: a dose-finding study. Vet Anaesth Analg. 2016;43(5):511&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1111/vaa.12342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Wijnsberghe AS, Ida KK, Dmitrovic P, Tutunaru A, Sandersen C. Neuromuscular blockade ef-fects of cisatracurium in 11 cats undergoing ophthalmological surgery anaesthetized with isoflu-rane. J Feline Med Surg. 2022;24(4):402&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1177/1098612X211021829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa GL, Leonardi F, Interlandi C, Spadola F, Fisichella S, Macr&#xec; F, et al. Levo-bupivacaine combined with cisatracurium in peribulbar anaesthesia in cats undergoing corneal and lens surgery. Animals (Basel). 2023;13(1):170. https://doi.org/10.3390/ani13010170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-Flores M, Sakai DM, Campoy L, Gleed RD. Recovery from neuromuscular block in dogs: restoration of spontaneous ventilation does not exclude residual blockade. Vet Anaesth Analg. 2014;41(3):269&#x2013;77. https://doi.org/10.1111/vaa.12109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones RS, Auer U, Mosing M. Reversal of neuromuscular block in companion animals. Vet Anaesth Analg. 2015;42(5):455&#x2013;71. https://doi.org/10.1111/vaa.12272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakai DM, Tseng CT, Militana EA, Martin-Flores M. The train-of-four or double-burst ratios can-not reliably exclude residual neuromuscular block in cats. Res Vet Sci. 2020;133:131&#x2013;5. Epub 2020 Sep 2. PMID: 32979745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-Flores M. Neuromuscular block: Monitoring, reversal, and residual Blockade in small animals. Vet Ophthalmol. 2025;28(1):88&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1111/vop.13112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes R. Atracurium: an overview. Br J Anaesth. 1986;58(Suppl 1):2S-5S. https://doi.org/10.1093/bja/58.suppl_1.2s.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watkins J. Histamine release and atracurium. Br J Anaesth. 1986;58(Suppl 1):S19&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1093/bja/58.suppl_1.19s.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter JM, Eastwood NB, Boyd AH, Parker CJ. Pharmacokinetics of 51W89: preliminary data. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand Suppl. 1995;106:94. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1399-6576.1995.tb04318.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen IY, Tamogi H, Wei Y, Kato K, Itami T, Sano T, Yamashita K. Effects of sevoflurane, Propofol or alfaxalone on neu-romuscular Blockade produced by a single intravenous bolus of Rocuronium in dogs. Vet Anaesth Analg. 2022;49(1):36&#x2013;. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vaa.2021.10.002. Epub 2021 Oct 30. PMID: 34893432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-Flores M, Gleed RD, Basher KL, Scarlett JM, Campoy L, Kopman AF. TOF-Watch(R) monitor: failure to calculate the train-of-four ratio in the absence of baseline calibration in anaes-thetized dogs. Br J Anaesth. 2012;108(2):240&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.1093/bja/aer378. Epub 2011 Nov 21. PMID: 22106378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kisor DF, Schmith VD, Wargin WA, Lien CA, Ornstein E, Cook DR. Importance of the organ- in-dependent elimination of cisatracurium. Anesth Analg. 1996;83(5):1065&#x2013;71. https://doi.org/10.1097/00000539-199611000-00029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unger M, Montavon PM, Heim UF. Classification of fractures of long bones in the dog and cat: introduction and clinical application. Vet Comp Orthop Traumatol. 1990;03:41&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0038-1633228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakai DM, Romano M, Tseng CT, Flanders A, Martin-Flores M. Bias, limits of agreement, and percent errors between acceleromyography and mechanomyography in anesthetized dogs. Vet J. 2018;233:3&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tvjl.2017.12.020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zurita M, Craig A. Feline diaphyseal fractures: management and treatment options. J Feline Med Surg. 2022;24(7):662&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1177/1098612X221106354. PMID: 35775308; PMCID: PMC11107983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interlandi C, Bruno F, Tabb&#xec; M, Macr&#xec; F, Di Pietro S, Giudice E, et al. Intraoperative Isoflurane End-Tidal Concentration during Infusion of Fentanyl, Tra-madol, or Fentanyl-Tramadol Combination in Cats. Vet Sci. 2024;11(3):125. https://doi.org/10.3390/vetsci11030125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid J, Scott EM, Calvo G, Nolan AM. Definitive Glasgow acute pain scale for cats: validation and intervention level. Vet Rec. 2017;180(18):449.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steagall PV, Monteiro BP. Acute pain in cats: recent advances in clinical assessment. J Feline Med Surg. 2019;21(1):25&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.1177/1098612X18808103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mota-Rojas D, Whittaker AL, Coria-Avila GA, Mart&#xed;nez-Burnes J, Mora-Medina P, Dom&#xed;nguez-Oliva A, et al. How facial expressions reveal acute pain in domestic animals with facial pain scales as a diagnostic tool. Front Vet Sci. 2025;12:1546719. https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2025.1546719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyd AH, Eastwood NB, Parker CJR, Hunter JM. Comparison of the pharmacodynamics and pharmocokinetics of an infusion of cis-atracurium (51W89) or atracurium in critically ill patients undergoing mechanical ventilation inaninten-sivetherapyunit. Br J Anaesth. 1996;76:382&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1093/bja/76.3.382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennis PJ, Fahey MR, Canfell PC, Shi WZ, Miller RD. Pharmacology of laudanosine in dogs. An-esthesiology. 1986;65(1):56&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1097/00000542-198607000-00009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eastwood NB, Boyd AH, Parker CJR, Hunter JM. Pharmoco kinetics of 1R-cis 1&#x2019;R-cis- atracurium besylate (51W89) and plasma laudanosine concentrations in health and chronic renal failure. Br J Anaesth. 1995;75:431&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.1093/bja/75.4.431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lien CA, Belmont MR, Abalos A, Eppich L, Quessy S, Abou-Donia MM, Savarese JJ. The cardi-ovascular effects and histamine-releasing properties of 51W89 in patients receiving nitrous ox-ide/opioid/barbiturate anesthesia. Anesthesiology. 1995;82(5):1131&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1097/00000542-199505000-00007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson SA, Gogolski SM, Pascoe P, Shafford HL, Sager J, Griffenhagen GM. AAFP feline anesthesia guidelines. J Feline Med Surg. 2018;20(7):602&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.1177/1098612X18781391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steagall PV, Analgesia. Small Anim Pract. What Makes Cats Different/Challenging and What Is Critical for Cats? Vet Clin North Am.&#xa0;2020;50(4):749&#x2013;67. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cvsm.2020.02.002.&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wulf H, Kahl M, Ledowski T. Augmentation of the neuromuscular blocking effects of cisatracu-rium during desflurane, sevoflurane, isoflurane or total i.v. anaesthesia. Br J Anaesth. 1998;80(3):308&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.1093/bja/80.3.308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin AM, Mohammad MY, Ibrahim MF. Comparative study of neuromuscular blocking and he-modynamic effects of rocuronium and cisatracurium under sevoflurane or total intravenous anes-thesia. Middle East J Anaesthesiol. 2009;20(1):39&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>