<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41705029</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2451-943X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Veterinary and animal science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Vet Anim Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Advancing climate-resilient livestock systems: Next-generation emission mitigation strategies and integrated technological innovations.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100588</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100588</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100588</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.vas.2026.100588</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Livestock production significantly contributes to global greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions, particularly methane (CH&#x2084;), nitrous oxide (N&#x2082;O), and carbon dioxide (CO&#x2082;), posing challenges to climate change mitigation and environmental sustainability. This review explores advanced, system-wide approaches to reduce emissions from livestock systems while enhancing productivity, resilience, and resource efficiency. It covers short-term mitigation strategies such as dietary interventions-including methane inhibitors, microbial modulators, and natural compounds-that target enteric fermentation. Long-term solutions involve genetic and breeding innovations, such as microbiome-genome interaction analyses, CRISPR-based editing, and low-methane phenotyping, supported by genomic selection and precision phenotyping tools. The review also assesses advanced manure management technologies like anaerobic digesters and nutrient recovery systems, and examines precision livestock farming tools, including real-time sensors, machine learning models, UAVs, and IoT-based monitoring systems. Emerging digital tools, blockchain, augmented reality, and AI-assisted diagnostics are highlighted for enhancing traceability and decision-making. The potential of integrated energy systems, such as microbial fuel cells, hydrogen electrolysis, algae-based bioenergy, and thermal gasification, is discussed alongside traditional renewables, enabling livestock farms to become clean energy hubs. Circularity is emphasized through silvopasture, algal bioremediation, insect bioconversion, and integrated crop-livestock systems. Environmental assessment tools and the socio-political dimensions of technology adoption, including policy, education, and farmer behavior, are also considered. Future research directions, such as atmospheric methane oxidation, 4D-printed feed additives, and quantum modeling, are proposed. Overall, the review calls for a transdisciplinary, integrated approach to transform livestock systems into climate-smart, low-emission food production networks.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghavi Hossein-Zadeh</LastName><ForeName>Navid</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Science, Faculty of Agricultural Sciences, University of Guilan, Rasht 41635-1314, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>figshare</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>10.6084/m9.figshare.21779036</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Vet Anim Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101694897</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2451-943X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Climate-smart agriculture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Emission reduction technologies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Greenhouse gas mitigation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Livestock sustainability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Precision livestock farming</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41705029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12907504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vas.2026.100588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2451-943X(26)00023-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ababio I.B., Bieniek J., Rahouti M., Hayajneh T., Aledhari M., Verma D., Chehri A. A blockchain-assisted federated learning framework for secure and self-optimizing digital twins in industrial IoT. Future Internet. 2025;17(1):13. doi: 10.3390/fi17010013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fi17010013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalla H., Abdallah M., Fattah K.P., Salem N. Struvite recovery from microbial fuel cells treating different nutrient-rich wastewaters. Journal of Water Process Engineering. 2024;60 doi: 10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.105179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.105179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd El Tawab A.M., Liu Q., Xu G., Han X. Feed additives strategies to control methanogenesis in ruminants, Review. Archiva Zootechnica. 2024;27(2):90&#x2013;125. doi: 10.2478/azibna-2024-0017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/azibna-2024-0017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abouemara K., Shahbaz M., McKay G., Al-Ansari T. The review of power generation from integrated biomass gasification and solid oxide fuel cells: Current status and future directions. Fuel. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2023.130511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2023.130511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullin I.N., Sungatullin R.G. Drones in agriculture: How drones are changing the approach to agronomy. &#xc8;konomika i Upravlenie: Problemy, Re&#x161;eni&#xe2;. 2024;11/9(152):104&#x2013;111. doi: 10.36871/ek.up.p.r.2024.11.09.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36871/ek.up.p.r.2024.11.09.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adhikary M., Pant A. Women&#x2019;s concerns in promoting climate-resilient agricultural practices for sustainable livelihoods and food security from the social inclusion perspective: The case of Koshi River Basin, Nepal. Global Journal of Agricultural and Allied Sciences. 2024;5(S1):5&#x2013;6. doi: 10.35251/gjaas.2024.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.35251/gjaas.2024.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adhikari, S., Mahmud, M.A.P., Moon, E.M., &amp; Timms, W. (2024). Assessing the environmental benefits of biochar application in agriculture: Insights from lifecycle assessment. 10.5194/egusphere-egu24-13751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/egusphere-egu24-13751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adigun O.A., Falola B.O., Esebre S.D., Wada I., Adewuyi A.T., Olajide T.D., Oladokun P. Enhancing carbon markets with fintech innovations: The role of artificial intelligence and blockchain. World Journal of Advanced Research and Reviews. 2024;23(2):579&#x2013;586. doi: 10.30574/wjarr.2024.23.2.2387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30574/wjarr.2024.23.2.2387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adlan, C.A., Wicke, B., Hanssen, S.V., &amp; Hendriks, C. (2024). Spatially-explicit greenhouse gas footprints of agricultural commodities from around the world. 10.5194/egusphere-egu24-13479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/egusphere-egu24-13479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adnane I., Taoumi H., Elouahabi A., Lahrech K., Oulmekki A. Valorization of crop residues and animal wastes: Anaerobic co-digestion technology. Heliyon. 2024;10 doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e26440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e26440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10909651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38439870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal, A., Saxena, S., &amp; Arora, S. (2024). CRISPR/Cas technology: A climate saviour or a genetic Pandora&#x2019;s box? (pp. 735&#x2013;773). 10.1007/978-981-99-8529-6_26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-99-8529-6_26</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agiomavriti, A.A., Nikolopoulou, M.P., Bartzanas, T., Chorianopoulos, N., Demestichas, K., &amp; Gelasakis, A.&#x399;. (2024). Spectroscopy-based methods and supervised machine learning applications for milk chemical analysis in dairy ruminants. 10.20944/preprints202411.0204.v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20944/preprints202411.0204.v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahern, D. (2025). The new anticipatory governance culture for innovation: Regulatory foresight, regulatory experimentation and regulatory learning. 10.48550/arxiv.2501.05921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arxiv.2501.05921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed &#x130;., Riaz R., S&#x131;zmaz &#xd6;. Sustainable livestock farming with oil seed crop and its by-products. Ankara Universitesi Veteriner Fakultesi Dergisi. 2024 doi: 10.33988/auvfd.1426643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33988/auvfd.1426643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed N., Deng L., Wang C., Shah Z.H., Deng L., Li Y., Li J., Chachar S., Chachar Z., Hayat F., Bozdar B., Ansari F., Gong L., Tu P. Advancements in biochar modification for enhanced phosphorus utilization in agriculture. Land. 2024 doi: 10.3390/land13050644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/land13050644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtisham, M., &amp; Obaid, Z. (2025). Harnessing epigenetic mechanisms for crop resilience: A comprehensive review of plant responses to biotic and abiotic stresses. 10.70389/pjpb.100007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70389/pjpb.100007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahuja V., Sharma C., Paul D., Dasgupta D., Saratale G.D., Banu J.R., Yang Y., Bhatia S.K. Unlocking the power of synergy: Cosubstrate and coculture fermentation for enhanced biomethane production. Biomass &amp; Bioenergy. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.biombioe.2023.106996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biombioe.2023.106996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x410;&#x43d;&#x443;&#x444;&#x440;&#x438;&#x458;&#x435;&#x432; &#x410;., Da&#x161;i&#x107; G. Innovative strategic financial instruments for the development of circular business models. Ekonomija. 2024;17(1):61&#x2013;81. doi: 10.5937/etp2401061a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5937/etp2401061a</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajayi F., Ademola O.M., Amuda K.F., Alade B. AI-driven decarbonization of buildings: Leveraging predictive analytics and automation for sustainable energy management. World Journal of Advanced Research and Reviews. 2024;24(1):061&#x2013;079. doi: 10.30574/wjarr.2024.24.1.2997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30574/wjarr.2024.24.1.2997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akash M.A.H., Hossain M.S., Islam M.M., Islam K.S., Islam M.N., Sony S.Y. Optimization of methane production in anaerobic digestion: A hybrid approach using experimental analysis, process simulation and machine learning. Results in Engineering. 2025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbar I., Tahir F., Haider M.N., Boopathy R. Integration of algae-based carbon capture with major carbon emission systems. Algae Biotechnology. 2026:17&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1016/B978-0-443-34063-5.00002-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-443-34063-5.00002-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akintan O., Gebremedhin K.G., Uyeh D.D. Animal feed formulation&#x2013;Connecting technologies to build a resilient and sustainable system. Animals. 2024;14(10):1497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11117273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38791714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akintan O.A., Gebremedhin K.G., Uyeh D.D. Linking animal feed formulation to milk quantity, quality, and animal health through data-driven decision-making. Animals. 2025;15(2):162. doi: 10.3390/ani15020162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani15020162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11758612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39858162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akintuyi O.B. Adaptive AI in precision agriculture: A review: Investigating the use of self-learning algorithms in optimizing farm operations based on real-time data. Open Access Research Journal of Multidisciplinary Studies. 2024 doi: 10.53022/oarjms.2024.7.2.0023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.53022/oarjms.2024.7.2.0023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akter A., Li X., Grey E., Wang S.C., Kebreab E. Replacement of cottonseed with an extruded flaxseed-based supplement alters milk fatty acid profile without affecting yield or methane emissions in Holstein dairy cows. Journal of Dairy Science. 2025 doi: 10.3168/jds.2025-26862. S0022-0302(25)00969-5Advance online publication.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2025-26862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41317859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alabi J.O., Anotaenwere C.C., Adelusi O.O., Wuaku M., Oderinwale O.A., Enikuomehin J.M., Okedoyin D.O., Ike K.A., Anele U.Y. PSX-21 Supplementing essential oil blend and fumaric acid in calf feed influenced rumen fermentation and greenhouse gases emission. Journal of Animal Science. 2024;102(Supplement_3):751&#x2013;752. doi: 10.1093/jas/skae234.848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skae234.848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alagendran S., Mounika C., Ashoka P., Singh V., Voruganti C., Gourkhede P.H., Niharika M. Carbon-based nanomaterials for soil amendment: A paradigm shift in agriculture practices. Journal of Experimental Agriculture International. 2024;46(12):833&#x2013;849. doi: 10.9734/jeai/2024/v46i123192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/jeai/2024/v46i123192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alanezi M.A., Shahriar M.S., Hasan M.B., Ahmed S., Sha&#x2019;aban Y.A., Bouchekara H.R. Livestock management with unmanned aerial vehicles: A review. IEEE Access. 2022;10:45001&#x2013;45028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alege, F.P., Miito, G.J., Tao, H., &amp; Ndegwa, P. (2023). Co-pelletization of dairy manure compost and fishmeal for soil amendment and environmental management. Available at SSRN 4442949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alem W.T. Effect of herbal extracts in animal nutrition as feed additives. Heliyon. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e24973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e24973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10845724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38322944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alem D., Aklilu H. Balancing genetic improvement with conservation of biodiversity a review. Bioprocess Engineering. 2025;9(1):36&#x2013;43. doi: 10.11648/j.be.20250901.14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11648/j.be.20250901.14</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alipoursarbani, M., Tideman, J., L&#xf3;pez, M.S., &amp; Abendroth, C. (2025). Bioaugmentation in anaerobic digesters: A systematic review. 10.1101/2025.01.22.634285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2025.01.22.634285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41634849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Meslamani A.Z. Barriers to digital endpoints in data collection in low and middle-income countries. Expert Review of Pharmacoeconomics &amp; Outcomes Research. 2024 doi: 10.1080/14737167.2024.2331047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14737167.2024.2331047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38480011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alqarni, A.S., Bahattab, M.A., Alqahtani, M.H.M., Almater, A., Abaalkheel, I., &amp; Aldhuwaile, A.A.A. (2024). Development of anti-dust nanostructured silicon dioxide coating for solar cells. 10.20944/preprints202412.0469.v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20944/preprints202412.0469.v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Smadi T., Al Sawalha A., Al Smadi K. Energy-efficient storage system optimization and recent trends in enhancing energy management and access microgrid: A review. Social Science Research Network. 2025 doi: 10.2139/ssrn.5019393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.5019393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemu S.W., Bilton T.P., Johnson P.L., Perry B.J., Henry H., Dodds K.G., McEwan J.C., Rowe S.J. Improving genomic prediction accuracy for methane emission and feed efficiency in sheep: Integrating rumen microbial PCA with host genomic variation using neural network GBLUP (NN-GBLUP) Genetics Selection Evolution. 2025;57(1):41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12273308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40676527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsayed A.R., Permana A.D. Bacteriophages therapy: Exploring their promising role in microbiome modulation and combatting antibiotic resistance. OBM Genetics. 2024;08(02):1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.21926/obm.genet.2402237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21926/obm.genet.2402237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altikat A., Alma M.H., Altikat A., Bilgili M., Altikat S. A comprehensive study of biochar yield and quality concerning pyrolysis conditions: A multifaceted approach. Sustainability. 2024 doi: 10.3390/su16020937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su16020937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altshuler Y., Chebach T.C., Cohen S., Gatica J. Analysis of the impact of five methane mitigating feed additives on milk production and associated parameters across multiple commercial dairy farms. bioRxiv. 2025 doi: 10.1101/2025.02.04.636425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2025.02.04.636425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altshuler Y., Chebach T.C., Cohen S., Gatica J. AI-driven precision agriculture for enteric methane mitigation: Cross-farm validation with an essential oil-based feed additive. Frontiers in Sustainable Food Systems. 2025;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwahab A., Maharani P.T., Nur K W.O.M., Ahmad L.O.A.I., Alimin A., Zaeni A. Optimization of biogas liquid waste from livestock manure as a source of renewable energy through microbial fuel cell (MFC) technology. Advance Sustainable Science, Engineering and Technology (ASSET) 2024;6(2) doi: 10.26877/asset.v6i2.17931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26877/asset.v6i2.17931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amancio B.R., da Silva T.H., Cortinhas C., Carvalho V.V., Tamassia L.F., Branco R.H., de Paula E.M. PSXIII-14 Evaluation of two levels of 3-nitrooxypropanol (3-NOP) as feed additive on methane emission, rumen microbiome, animal performance, dry matter intake and digestibility, of Nellore cattle in a feedlot. Journal of Animal Science. 2025;103(Supplement_3):621&#x2013;622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amshavalli R.S., Murugesan K., Oliver A.S., Priyanka N., Jayalakshmi P., da Silva A.S. Advances in computer and electrical engineering book series. IGI Global; 2024. Virtual reality for environmental engineering and sustainability; pp. 223&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/979-8-3693-5613-5.ch013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An Z., Yu H., Kim K., Ahn Y., Feng Q., Song Y. Continuous augmentation of anaerobic digestion with electroactive microorganisms: Performance and stability. Bioresource Technology. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.biortech.2024.131523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2024.131523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39343178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andhale V.T. Insect meal in poultry nutrition: A review. Acta Scientific Veterinary Sciences. 2024:28&#x2013;32. doi: 10.31080/asvs.2024.06.0882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31080/asvs.2024.06.0882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreoulaki I., Papapostolou A., Marinakis V. Evaluating the barriers to blockchain adoption in the energy sector: A multicriteria approach using the analytical hierarchy process for group decision making. Energies. 2024 doi: 10.3390/en17061278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en17061278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angellotti M., Lindberg M., Ramin M., Krizsan S.J., Danielsson R. Asparagopsis taxiformis supplementation to mitigate enteric methane emissions in dairy cows &#x2013; effects on performance and metabolism. Journal of Dairy Science. 2025 doi: 10.3168/jds.2024-25258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2024-25258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39778806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angerer V., Sabia E., K&#xf6;nig von Borstel U., Gauly M. Environmental and biodiversity effects of different beef production systems. Journal of Environmental Management. 2021;289 doi: 10.1016/J.JENVMAN.2021.112523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.JENVMAN.2021.112523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33839605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ar&#x131;soy A., A&#xe7;&#x131;kg&#xf6;zo&#x11f;lu E. Optimizing soil fertility through machine learning: Enhancing agricultural productivity and sustainability. Bilge International Journal of Science and Technology Research. 2024;8(2):124&#x2013;133. doi: 10.30516/bilgesci.1532645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30516/bilgesci.1532645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arivukkumar N., Shanmugam P.M., Kannan B., Sumathi C.S., Prahadeeshwaran M., Sangeetha S., Raghavi G. Assessing the carbon footprint of marginal and smallholders farming systems: A typology driven approach. Plant Science Today. 2024;11(sp4) doi: 10.14719/pst.5213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14719/pst.5213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arndt C., Hristov A.N., Price W.J., McClelland S.C., Pelaez A.M., Cueva S.F., Oh J., Dijkstra J., Bannink A., Bayat A.R., Crompton L.A., Eug&#xe8;ne M.A., Enahoro D., Kebreab E., Kreuzer M., McGee M., Martin C., Newbold C.J., Reynolds C.K., Schwarm A.&#x2026;Yu Z. Full adoption of the most effective strategies to mitigate methane emissions by ruminants can help meet the 1.5&#x2009;&#xb0;C target by 2030 but not 2050. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 2022;119(20) doi: 10.1073/pnas.2111294119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2111294119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9171756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35537050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora C.H., Autade S.D., Avhad A.M., Deokar R.D. Smart cattle care: An IOT based monitoring and management system. International Journal of Innovative Science and Research Technology. 2024 doi: 10.38124/ijisrt/ijisrt24apr1600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.38124/ijisrt/ijisrt24apr1600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arru B., Cisilino F., Sau P., Furesi R., Pulina P., Madau F.A. The economic and environmental sustainability dimensions of agriculture: A trade-off analysis of Italian farms. Frontiers in Sustainable Food Systems. 2024;8 doi: 10.3389/fsufs.2024.1474903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsufs.2024.1474903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arshad M.F., Burrai G.P., Varcasia A., Sini M.F., F A., Lai G., Polinas M., Antuofermo E., Tamponi C., Cocco R., Corda A., Parpaglia M.L.P. The groundbreaking impact of digitalization and artificial intelligence in sheep farming. Research in Veterinary Science. 2024;170 doi: 10.1016/j.rvsc.2024.105197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rvsc.2024.105197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38395008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arulmozhi E., Deb N.C., Tamrakar N., Kang D.Y., Kang M.Y., Kook J., Basak J.K., Kim H.T. From reality to virtuality: Revolutionizing livestock farming through digital twins. Agriculture. 2024;14(12):2231. doi: 10.3390/agriculture14122231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture14122231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arya A., Sharma P., Trivedi M.M., Modi R.J., Patel Y.G. A look at genomic selection techniques for climate change adaptation and production in livestock. Journal of Scientific Research and Reports. 2024 doi: 10.9734/jsrr/2024/v30i62059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/jsrr/2024/v30i62059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aryanfar Y., El Haj Assad M., Garc&#xed;a Alcar&#xe1;z J.L., Blanco-Fern&#xe1;ndez J., Awad M.M., Ahmad S., Bouabidi A., Ke&#xe7;eba&#x15f; A. Elsevier BV; 2024. Technologies review for solar thermal integrated photovoltaic desalination; pp. 59&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-443-13392-3.00003-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askari S., Giri B.S., Basheer F., Izhar T., Ahmad S.A., Mumtaz N. Enhancing sequencing batch reactors for efficient wastewater treatment across diverse applications: A comprehensive review. Environmental Research. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.envres.2024.119656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2024.119656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39034021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashworth A.J., Amorim H.C.S., Drescher G.L., Moore P., Rojas M.G., Morales-Ramos J.A., Donoghue A.M. Insect frass fertilizer as soil amendment for improved forage and soil health in circular systems. Dental Science Reports. 2025;15(1) doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-87075-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-87075-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11757723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39849045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assan N. Breeding for a greener future: Selective breeding and crossbreeding approaches to minimize methane emissions in ruminant livestock. International Journal of Research and Scientific Innovation. 2025;XII(VIII):200&#x2013;233. doi: 10.51244/ijrsi.2025.120800019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.51244/ijrsi.2025.120800019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assaye Y.M. Agricultural waste for energy storage, conversion and agricultural applications. American Journal of Modern Energy. 2024;10(3):38&#x2013;41. doi: 10.11648/j.ajme.20241003.11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11648/j.ajme.20241003.11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assis, N.R., &amp; Batista, B.G. (2024). eCattle: A platform for traceability and management of livestock transactions using smart contracts. 1&#x2013;9. 10.1109/iisa62523.2024.10786693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/iisa62523.2024.10786693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aviso K.B. Elsevier BV; 2024. Overview of LCA&#x2013;History, concept, and methodology.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-323-90386-8.00113-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awoke M.D., L&#xf6;hr K., Kimaro A., Lana M., Soh Wenda B.D., Buabeng K., Hafner J., Sieber S. Exploring gender dynamics in climate-smart agriculture adoption: A study in semi-arid Dodoma, Tanzania. Frontiers in Sustainable Food Systems. 2025;8 doi: 10.3389/fsufs.2024.1507540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsufs.2024.1507540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badzmierowski, M.J., Hegde, S., &amp; Searchinger, T. (2025). Analysis and recommendations to mitigate greenhouse gas emissions from U.S. manure management. 10.46830/wriwp.24.00108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46830/wriwp.24.00108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae B., Pope L., Park K., Lee C. Effects of nitrate in combination with lactate on rumen fermentation and methane production in an in vitro batch culture. Animal Bioscience. 2025;38(8):1672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12229902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40241583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baguer P., Municio E., Garc&#xed;a-Aviles G., Costa-P&#xe9;rez X. Enabling beyond-visual-line-of-sight drones operation over open RAN 5G networks with slicing. IEEE Network. 2024;1 doi: 10.1109/mnet.2024.3420085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/mnet.2024.3420085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey B. (Invited) Electrolysis of liquid dairy cow manure into clean reusable water. Meeting Abstracts. 2024;MA2024-01(28):1485. doi: 10.1149/ma2024-01281485mtgabs.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1149/ma2024-01281485mtgabs</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baklaga L. Synergizing AI and blockchain: Innovations in decentralized carbon markets for emission reduction through intelligent carbon credit trading. Journal of Computer Science and Technology Studies. 2024;6(2):111&#x2013;120. doi: 10.32996/jcsts.2024.6.2.13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32996/jcsts.2024.6.2.13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakti A.I., Laoh M.A., Mosey H.I.R., Lumembang M.M., Suoth V.A. Sistem monitoring Suhu, Kelembaban dan Kadar CO2 di udara berbasis internet of things. Jurnal MIPA. 2024;13(2):94&#x2013;98. doi: 10.35799/jm.v13i2.56234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.35799/jm.v13i2.56234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balasubramanian A., Anjali K.S., Swathiga G., Abbas G., Krishnan S.N. Springer International Publishing; 2024. Soil nutrient dynamics and cycling under agroforestry; pp. 109&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-99-7282-1_6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basak J.K., Paudel B., Deb N.C., Kang D.Y., Salam M.A., Sonet S.S., Kim H.T. Application of machine learning models for predicting methane concentrations in pig barns using biophysical data. Water, Air, &amp; Soil Pollution. 2025;236(5):1&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashar M.K., Sarker N.R., Sultana N., Hossain S.M.J. Assessment of GHG emissions in dairy production systems based on existing feed resources through the GLEAM model under different climatic zones of Bangladesh and their mitigation options. Journal of Advanced Veterinary and Animal Research. 2024;11(3):664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11590580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39605766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bature, I., Wu, X., Yang, F., Zhong, L., Chen, Y., Liu, J., Sun, X., &amp; Ding, X. (2024). The roles of phytogenic feed additives on mitigating ruminant methane emission. 10.20944/preprints202406.0347.v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20944/preprints202406.0347.v1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11622700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39649683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazzo, C.O.G., Kamali, B., Vianna, M.D.S., Behrend, D., Hueging, H., Jahanbakhshi, F., Schleip, I., Mosebach, P., &amp; Gaiser, T. (2024). Innovative methods in grassland monitoring: Integrating UAV data for ecosystem assessment. 10.5194/egusphere-egu24-15919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/egusphere-egu24-15919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck M.R., Gunter S.A., Friend E., Moffet C.A. 7 Environmental sustainability of livestock systems in the southeastern U.S.: Opportunities and research gaps. Journal of Animal Science. 2024 doi: 10.1093/jas/skae019.046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skae019.046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behjat M., Svanstr&#xf6;m M., Peters G. Environmental assessment of phosphorus recovery from dairy sludge: A comparative LCA study. Waste Management. 2024;187:50&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1016/j.wasman.2024.06.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wasman.2024.06.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38996619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell, C., Olukemi, A., &amp; Gracias, A. (2024). Integration of solar energy and agriculture: Agrivoltaic systems for sustainable food and energy production. 10.20944/preprints202408.0025.v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20944/preprints202408.0025.v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benchaar C., Hassanat F. Diet supplementation with a mixture of essential oils: Effects on enteric methane emissions, apparent total-tract nutrient digestibility, nitrogen utilization, and lactational performance. Journal of Dairy Science. 2025;108(4):3560&#x2013;3572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39788195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benga L., Rehm A., Gougoula C., Westhoff P., Wachtmeister T., Benten W.P.M., Engelhardt E., Weber A.P.M., K&#xf6;hrer K., Sager M., Janssen S. The host genotype actively shapes its microbiome across generations in laboratory mice. Microbiome. 2024;12(1) doi: 10.1186/s40168-024-01954-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40168-024-01954-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11619136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39639355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benites-Pariente J.S., Samolski I., Lude&#xf1;a Y., Villena G.K. CRISPR/Cas9 mediated targeted knock-in of eglA gene to improve endoglucanase activity of Aspergillus fumigatus LMB-35Aa. Dental Science Reports. 2024;14(1) doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-70397-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-70397-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11344075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39179646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benni S., Garcia C.A.P., Bovo M., Barbaresi A., Tinti F., Loris A., Acosta-Pazmi&#xf1;o I.P., Bakalis P., Tassinari P., Torreggiani D. A smart heating system based on integrated renewable energy sources for swine nursery buildings. Energies. 2025;18(6):1393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensalmi W., Belhani A., Bouzid-Daho A. Exploring advanced methodologies for hybrid energy system sizing through artificial intelligence techniques: A comprehensive review. Revue Des &#xc9;nergies Renouvelables. 2024 doi: 10.54966/jreen.v1i3.1296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.54966/jreen.v1i3.1296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergougui B., Do&#x11f;an B., Ghosh S., Ayad H. Impact of environmental technology, economic complexity, and geopolitical risk on carbon emission inequality in developed and developing countries: Evidence from a PVAR-GMM approach. Environment, Development and Sustainability. 2024 doi: 10.1007/s10668-024-05715-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10668-024-05715-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhalerao O., Mohan A. Water quality monitoring and prediction using machine learning models. Social Science Research Network. 2024 doi: 10.2139/ssrn.4487070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.4487070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharanidharan R., Tomple B.M., Lee J., Ibidhi R., Oh J., Hong W.H., Huh S., Kim K.H. PSXIII-27 Effects of long-term dietary supplementation of nitrate on enteric methane production and performance of Hanwoo steers. Journal of Animal Science. 2024;102(Supplement_3):794&#x2013;795. doi: 10.1093/jas/skae234.893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skae234.893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12137904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40231431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharanidharan R., Tomple B.M., Lee J., Nirmal Athauda A.A.K., Huh S., Hong W., Kim N.Y., Lim D.H., Kim J.G., Kim K.H.&#x2026;Oh J. Effects of dietary supplementation of nitrate on enteric methane production, performance, and rumen microbiome of Hanwoo steers. Journal of Animal Science. 2025;103:skaf109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12137904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40231431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhati P., Saikia A.R., Chaudhary S., Bahadur R., Nengparmoi T., Talukdar N., Hazarika S. Integrated farming systems for environment sustainability: A comprehensive review. Journal of Scientific Research and Reports. 2024 doi: 10.9734/jsrr/2024/v30i11834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/jsrr/2024/v30i11834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharya, I.N., Sahiba, M.S., &amp; Suhag, M. (2024). Sustainable agricultural waste management practices and approaches: An overview (pp. 156&#x2013;166). 10.58532/v3bcag2p2ch3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.58532/v3bcag2p2ch3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattarai S., Janaswamy S. Biodegradable films from the lignocellulosic residue of switchgrass. Resources Conservation and Recycling. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.resconrec.2023.107322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2023.107322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binisha X.M., Sharmila J., Umadevi G., Mathumitha A. Smart system for monitoring and controlling harmful gases in avian farming using IOT. FiTUA. 2024 doi: 10.36548/jismac.2024.2.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36548/jismac.2024.2.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bissadu, K., Hossain, G., &amp; Vajpayee, P. (2024). Agriculture 5.0 cybersecurity: Monitoring agricultural cyber threats with digital twin technology. 10.1109/aiiot61789.2024.10579017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/aiiot61789.2024.10579017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boakye-Yiadom K.A., Ilari A., Bisinella V., Duca D. Environmental impact of poultry manure gasification technology for energy and ash valorization. Sustainability. 2024;16(22):9941. doi: 10.3390/su16229941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su16229941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boggio G.M., Monteiro H.F., Lima F.S., Figueiredo C.C., Bisinotto R.S., Santos J.E.P., Mion B., Schenkel F.S., Ribeiro E.S., Weigel K.A., Rosa G.J.M., Pe&#xf1;agaricano F. Revealing host genome&#x2013;microbiome networks underlying feed efficiency in dairy cows. Dental Science Reports. 2024;14(1) doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-77782-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-77782-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11522680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39472728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogut A., Kolodziejek A.M., Minnich S.A., Hovde C.J. CRISPR/Cas systems as diagnostic and potential therapeutic tools for enterohemorrhagic Escherichia coli. Archivum Immunologiae Et Therapiae Experimentalis. 2025;73(1) doi: 10.2478/aite-2025-0003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/aite-2025-0003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39773393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonannella, C. (2024). Spatiotemporal modeling of vegetation dynamics in a changing environment: Combining earth observation and machine learning. 10.18174/655208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18174/655208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borthakur, P.P. (2025). Harnessing agricultural waste for sustainable biodiesel production: A comprehensive review. 10.20944/preprints202501.0348.v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20944/preprints202501.0348.v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouazzaoui, A., &amp; Abdellatif, A.A.H. (2024). Vaccine delivery systems and administration routes: Advanced biotechnological techniques to improve the immunization efficacy. 10.1016/j.jvacx.2024.100500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jvacx.2024.100500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11170481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38873639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulay A.M., Drastig K., Chapagain A., Charlon V., Civit B., DeCamillis C., De Souza M., Hess T., Hoekstra A.Y., Ibidhi R., Lathuilli&#xe8;re M.J., Manzardo A., McAllister T., Morales R.A., Motoshita M., Palhares J.C.P., Pirlo G., Ridoutt B., Russo V., Salmoral G., Singh R., Vanham D., Wiedemann S., Zheng W., Pfister S. Building consensus on water use assessment of livestock production systems and supply chains: Outcome and recommendations from the FAO LEAP Partnership. Ecological Indicators. 2021;124</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouregba H., Hachemi M., Samatar A.M., Mekhilef S., Stojcevski A., Seyedmahmoudian M., Hamidat A. Feasibility study of a grid-connected PV/wind hybrid energy system for an urban dairy farm. Heliyon. 2024;10(23)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11650295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39691197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunetti H.B., Oliveira P.P., Pezzopane J.R., Bernardi A.C.D.C., Garcia A.R., Berndt A., Pedroso A., de F., Lelis A.L.J.&#x2026;Medeiros S.R. Silvopastoral system as a climate-smart alternative for beef production: Enteric methane emission neutralization and animal thermal comfort increase. Agricultural Systems. 2025;225</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bumharter, C. (2024). Harnessing agricultural waste for energy: Improving decentralised anaerobic digestion for energy self-sufficiency. 10.20868/upm.thesis.84403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20868/upm.thesis.84403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burlet E., Thomas N., Carwell S., Gershman B.W., Morefield G.L. Formulation Attributes impact immune profile of an oral and thermostable COVID-19 subunit vaccine. Vaccines. 2024;12(10):1087. doi: 10.3390/vaccines12101087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vaccines12101087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11511547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39460254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns M., Tang H., Larson R.A., Qin M. Bioelectrochemically-assisted ammonia recovery from dairy manure. Water Research. 2024;252 doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2024.121243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2024.121243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38330718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera V.E., Bewley J.M., Breunig M., Breunig T., Cooley W., De Vries A., Fourdraine R.H., Giordano J.O., Gong Y., Greenfield R., Hu H., Lenkaitis A., Niu M., Noronha E.A., Sullivan M.B. Data integration and analytics in the dairy industry: Challenges and pathways forward. Animals. 2025;15(3):329. doi: 10.3390/ani15030329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani15030329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11816260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39943099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cairone S., Hasan S.W., Choo K., Li C., Zorpas A.A., Ksibi M., Zarra T., Belgiorno V., Naddeo V. Enhancing membrane fouling control in wastewater treatment processes through artificial intelligence modeling: Research progress and future perspectives. Euro-Mediterranean Journal for Environmental Integration. 2024 doi: 10.1007/s41207-024-00659-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41207-024-00659-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callegari A., Tucci M., Aulenta F., Viggi C.C., Capodaglio A.G. Anaerobic sludge digestion enhancement with bioelectrochemical and electrically conductive materials augmentation: A state of the art review. Chemosphere. 2025;372 doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2025.144101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2025.144101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39798721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao T., Yang Y., Li X., Liu L., Fei X., Zhao Y., Zhang L., L&#xfc; Y., Zhou D. In-situ rapid cultivation of aerobic granular sludge in A/O bioreactor by using Ca(ClO)2 pretreating sludge. Bioresource Technology. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.biortech.2024.131278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2024.131278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39151572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao H.X., Vu G.T.H., Gailing O. Elsevier BV; 2024. CRISPR/Cas genome editing and applications in forest tree breeding; pp. 343&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-443-18444-4.00001-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardoso T.F., Bruscadin J.J., Afonso J., Conteville L.C., Andrade B.G.N., Malheiros J.M., Fernandes, A.C., Diniz, W.J.S., Banerjee, P., de Oliveira, P.S.N., Zerlotini, A., Mour&#xe3;o, G.B., Coutinho, L.L&#x2026;Regitano L.C.D.A. Exploring genome, transcriptome, and microbiome interactions related to feed efficiency and methane emissions in Bos indicus through multi-omics network analysis. Mammalian Genome. 2025;36(4):1153&#x2013;1172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40999243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrazco A.V., Rocha A.S., Ross E.G., Zhao Y., Pan Y., Pandey P.K., Castillo A.R., DePeters E.J., Mitloehner F.M. Effect of a tannin and saponin blend feed additive on greenhouse gas and ammonia emissions from lactating dairy cows. Journal of Dairy Science. 2025;108(8):8582&#x2013;8593. doi: 10.3168/jds.2025-26410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2025-26410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40447091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro J., Alcaraz-Segura D., Baltzer J.L., Amor&#xf3;s L., Morales-Rueda F., Tabik S. Automated precise seeding with drones and artificial intelligence: A workflow. Restoration Ecology. 2024 doi: 10.1111/rec.14164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/rec.14164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty U., Kaushik A., Chaudhary G.R., Mishra Y.K. Emerging nano-enabled gas sensor for environmental monitoring&#x2013;Perspectives and open challenges. Current Opinion in Environmental Science &amp; Health. 2024;37</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chanthakett A., Arif M.T., Khan M.M.K., Subhani M. Elsevier BV; 2024. Hydrogen production from municipal solid waste using gasification method; pp. 103&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-443-15329-7.00012-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatterjee B., Mazumder D. Valorization of fruit and vegetable waste in a novel three-stage hybrid anaerobic digester for enhanced biogas production: Performance study and microbial community analysis. Biochemical Engineering Journal. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.bej.2024.109403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bej.2024.109403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary V., Awadakkam S., Borugadda V.B., Dalai A.K. A critical review on the production and upgradation of sustainable biocrude from hydrothermal liquefaction of Canadian-grown agricultural biomass. Sustainable Energy &amp; Fuels. 2024;8(23):5305&#x2013;5328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chavan A.R., Pathak M.C., Purohit H.J., Khardenavis A.A. Bentham Science Publishers; 2024. Modulating the gut microbiome through genome editing for alleviating gut dysbiosis; pp. 45&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/9789815165678124010006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X., Xiao J., Zhao W., Li J., Zhao W., Zhang W., Xin L., Han Z., Wang L., Aschalew N.D., Zhang X., Wang L., Qin G., Zhang T., Zhen Y. Mechanistic insights into rumen function promotion through yeast culture (Saccharomyces cerevisiae) metabolites using in vitro and in vivo models. Frontiers in Microbiology. 2024;15 doi: 10.3389/fmicb.2024.1407024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2024.1407024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11287897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39081884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, T., Cheng, X., Yan, Y., Wang, S., Su, L., &amp; TAN, C. (2025a). From waste leachate to fertilizer: Nutrients recovery via magnesium ammonium phosphate precipitation in a pilot continuous reactor. 10.2139/ssrn.5091889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.5091889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M., Li H., Zhang Z., Ren R., Wang Z., Feng J., Cao R., Hu G., Liu Z. Real-time pig weight assessment and carbon footprint monitoring based on computer vision. Animals. 2025;15(17):2611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12427334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40941406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chenavaz R., Dimitrov S. From waste to wealth: Policies to promote the circular economy. Journal of Cleaner Production. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheong K.L., Li G., Wang M., Yang Y., Zhong S. Unraveling the chemical identification and biological potential of the genus Asparagopsis: A comprehensive review. Frontiers in Marine Science. 2024 doi: 10.3389/fmars.2024.1360425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmars.2024.1360425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chibanda C., Thobe P., Almadani M.I., van Horne P., Deblitz C., Wieck C. Improving broiler farm competitiveness in Ghana and Senegal: Insights from comparative analysis with Germany and the Netherlands. Agriculture &amp; Food Security. 2024;13(1):65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinnasamy, P., Ayyasamy, R.K., Tiwari, V.N., Dhanasekaran, S., Kumar, B.S., &amp; Sivaprakasam, T. (2024). Blockchain enabled privacy-preserved supply-chain management for tracing the food goods. 10.1109/icstem61137.2024.10560589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/icstem61137.2024.10560589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiodini M.E., Costantini M., Zoli M., Bacenetti J., Aspesi D., Poggianella L., Acutis M. Real-scale study on methane and carbon dioxide emission reduction from dairy liquid manure with the commercial additive SOP LAGOON. Sustainability. 2023;15(3):1803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi Y., Lee W., Kwon J.G., Kang A.N., Kwak M.J., Eor J.Y., Kim Y.H. The current state of phage therapy in livestock and companion animals. Journal of Animal Science and Technology. 2024 doi: 10.5187/jast.2024.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5187/jast.2024.e5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11007465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38618037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhary K., Palsaniya V.K. Impact of climate change on livestock sector. International Journal of Research in Agronomy. 2024 doi: 10.33545/2618060x.2024.v7.i3sa.382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33545/2618060x.2024.v7.i3sa.382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuayboon S., Abanades S. Green iron and syngas production via continuous solar-driven agricultural waste biomass gasification combined with iron (III) oxide reduction. Energy. 2024;306</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuenchart W., Timilsina A.P., Ge J., Shah A. Advances in biorefinery of cattle manure for value-added products. Fermentation. 2024 doi: 10.3390/fermentation10110568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fermentation10110568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S., Plumlee C.R., Engels L.G.J.B., Mai D., Murray T.A., Jahn A.N., Alexander B., Delahaye J.L., Cross L., Maciag K., Schrader S., Durga K., Gold E.S., Aderem A., Gerner M.Y., Gern B.H., Diercks A., Urdahl K.B. Host and pathogen genetic diversity shape vaccine-mediated protection to Mycobacterium tuberculosis. Frontiers in Immunology. 2024;15 doi: 10.3389/fimmu.2024.1427846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2024.1427846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11239334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39007152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costantini M., Provolo G., Bacenetti J. The effects of incorporating renewable energy into the environmental footprint of beef production. Energy. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2023.129960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.129960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contaxis N. Hidden ethical challenges in health data infrastructure. Hastings Center Report. 2024;54(1):15&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1002/hast.1564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hast.1564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38390677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooke R.F., Eloy L.R., Bosco S.C., Lasmar P.V.F., de Simas J.M.C., Leiva T., de Medeiros S.R. An updated meta-analysis of the anti-methanogenic effects of monensin in beef cattle. Translational Animal Science. 2024 doi: 10.1093/tas/txae032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tas/txae032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11003526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38595989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costigan H., Shalloo L., Egan M., Kennedy M., Dwan C., Walsh S., Hennessy D., Walker N., Zihlmann R., Lahart B. The impact of twice daily 3-nitroxypropanol supplementation on enteric methane emissions in grazing dairy cows. Journal of Dairy Science. 2024 doi: 10.3168/jds.2024-24772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2024-24772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38851571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Martinez, P.Y., Cruz-Rivero, L., Mar-Orozco, C.E., Lince-Olgu&#xed;n, E., Hern&#xe1;ndez, E.A., &amp; L&#xf3;pez Garc&#xed;a, S.A. (2024). Life cycle analysis in the dairy industry: Literature review. 10.20944/preprints202409.0637.v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20944/preprints202409.0637.v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui L., Watanabe S., Miyanaga K., Kiga K., Sasahara T., Aiba Y., Tan X.E., Veeranarayanan S., Thitiananpakorn K., Nguyen H.M., Wannigama D. A comprehensive review on phage therapy and phage-based drug development. Antibiotics. 2024 doi: 10.3390/antibiotics13090870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics13090870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11428490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39335043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui H., Hou S.N., Wang X.Y., Zhu H. Greenhouse gas emissions in a microbial fuel cell-assisted composting system: Microbial insights into bacterial structures and genetic functions. Environmental Research. 2025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40780531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culqui Molina, W.P., Pinta Riofrio, M.D., Jim&#xe9;nez Espinosa, P.M., &amp; Su&#xe1;rez Jurado, M.A. (2024). Phage therapy against multiresistant bacteria. 10.59471/ijhsc202491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.59471/ijhsc202491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai X. Electron-transfer-driven spatial optimisation of anaerobic consortia for efficient methanogenesis: Neglected inductive effect of conductive materials. Bioresource Technology. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.biortech.2024.130856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2024.130856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38763204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalk&#x131;l&#x131;&#xe7;, K., &amp; U&#x11f;urlu, A. (2024). Enhancement of biogas production from cattle manure in a combined microbial electrolysis cell and anaerobic digestion system. 10.22541/au.170669417.79141701/v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22541/au.170669417.79141701/v1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40316821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis S.C., Maynard F.G., Jenkins D., Herman T., Reza M.T. Potential for improving nutrient use efficiencies of human food systems with a circular economy of organic wastes and fertilizer. Environmental Research Letters. 2024 doi: 10.1088/1748-9326/ad6617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-9326/ad6617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debnath R., Singh A., Saini A., Seni K., Sharma A., Bisht D.S., Sharma K., Goel H., Chawla V., Chawla P.A. Cutting edge nanoplatforms with smart bio-sensing applications: Paving the way for sustainable green approaches. Current Nanomaterials. 2024;10 doi: 10.2174/0124054615342051241002061227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/0124054615342051241002061227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Ondarza M.B., Souza V.C., Kebreab E., Tric&#xe1;rico J.M. Understanding potential opportunities and risks associated with feeding supplemental rumen available fats to mitigate enteric methane emissions in lactating dairy cows. Journal of Dairy Science. 2024 doi: 10.3168/jds.2023-24528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2023-24528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38825101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delpitiya, D.M.M.L., &amp; Ariyarathna, S.M.W.T.P.K. (2024). Review on biochar for enhancing biogas production from anaerobic digestion of food waste. 136&#x2013;151. 10.31705/iserme.2024.24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31705/iserme.2024.24</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>del Prado A., Vibart R., Bilotto F., Faver&#xed;n C., Gir&#xe1;ldez Garc&#xed;a F.J., Henrique F.L., Granja Doril&#xea;o Leite F., Mancebo Mazzetto A., Ridoutt B.G., Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Ru&#xed;z D.R., Bannink A. Feed additives for methane mitigation: Assessment of feed additives as a strategy to mitigate enteric methane from ruminants&#x2013;Accounting; How to quantify the mitigating potential of using antimethanogenic feed additives. Journal of Dairy Science. 2024;108(1):411&#x2013;429. doi: 10.3168/jds.2024-25044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2024-25044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39725505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devnath B., Khanal S., Shah A., Reza M.T. Influence of hydrothermal carbonization (HTC) temperature on hydrochar and process liquid for poultry, swine, and dairy manure. Environments. 2024;11(7):150. doi: 10.3390/environments11070150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/environments11070150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xed;az de Ot&#xe1;lora X., del Prado A., Dragoni F., Balaine L., Pardo G., Winiwarter W., Sandrucci A., Ragaglini G., Kabelitz T., Kieronczyk M., J&#xf8;rgensen G., Estell&#xe9;s F., Amon B. Modelling the effect of context-specific greenhouse gas and nitrogen emission mitigation options in key European dairy farming systems. Agronomy for Sustainable Development. 2024 doi: 10.1007/s13593-023-00940-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13593-023-00940-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding J., Zhen F., Hu Y., Zhang Y., Gong L. Effect of biochar in modulating anaerobic digestion performance and microbial structure community of different inoculum sources. Fermentation. 2024 doi: 10.3390/fermentation10030151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fermentation10030151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinh T.T.N., Allen K.D. Toward the Use of Methyl-Coenzyme M Reductase for Methane Bioconversion Applications. Accounts of Chemical Research. 2024;57(18):2746&#x2013;2757. doi: 10.1021/acs.accounts.4c00413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.accounts.4c00413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11411713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39190795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xe8;nech-Gil, G., Duc, N.T., Wikner, J., Eriksson, J., Puglisi, D., &amp; Bastviken, D. (2024). Efficient methane monitoring with low-cost chemical sensors and machine learning. 10.3390/proceedings2024097079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/proceedings2024097079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xed;nguez-Casta&#xf1;o P. Heritability estimates and genome-wide association study of methane emission traits in Nellore cattle. Journal of Animal Science. 2024 doi: 10.1093/jas/skae182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skae182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11282363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38967061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doultani, S., Hadiya, K.K., George, L., &amp; Highland, H. (2024). Overview of marker-assisted selection in animal breeding. 10.9734/jabb/2024/v27i5790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/jabb/2024/v27i5790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dressler E.A., Bormann J.M., Weaber R.L., Rolf M.M. Use of methane production data for genetic prediction in beef cattle: A review. Translational Animal Science. 2024;8 doi: 10.1093/tas/txae014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tas/txae014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10872685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38371425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Q., Wei Y., Zhang Q., Ren D., Gao J., Dong X., Bai L.P., Li J. An improved CRISPR and CRISPR interference (CRISPRi) toolkit for engineering the model methanogenic archaeon Methanococcus maripaludis. Microbial Cell Factories. 2024;23(1) doi: 10.1186/s12934-024-02492-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12934-024-02492-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11373211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39227830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du X., Xing R., Lin Y., Chen M., Chen Z., Zhou S. Reduced greenhouse gas emission by reactive oxygen species during composting. Bioresource Technology. 2024;404</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38821423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Urso F., Broccolo F. Applications of artificial intelligence in microbiome analysis and probiotic interventions&#x2013;An overview and perspective based on the current state of the art. Applied Sciences. 2024;14(19):8627. doi: 10.3390/app14198627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app14198627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwarampudi, A., &amp; Yogi, M.K. (2024). Application of federated learning for smart agriculture system. 10.55529/ijitc.43.36.48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55529/ijitc.43.36.48</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x17e;ermeikait&#x117; K., &#x160;idlauskait&#x117; M., Antanaitis R., Anskien&#x117; L. Enhancing genomic selection in dairy cattle through artificial intelligence: integrating advanced phenotyping and predictive models to advance health, climate resilience, and sustainability. Dairy. 2025;6(5):50. doi: 10.3390/dairy6050050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/dairy6050050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eason C., Fennessy P.F. Methane reduction, health and regulatory considerations regarding Asparagopsis and bromoform for ruminants. New Zealand Journal of Agricultural Research. 2023 doi: 10.1080/00288233.2023.2248948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00288233.2023.2248948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eason C.T., Fennessy P.F. Methane reduction, health and regulatory considerations regarding Asparagopsis and bromoform for ruminants. New Zealand Journal of Agricultural Research. 2025;68(1):1&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ejairu, U., Aderamo, A.T., Olisakwe, H.C., Esiri, A.E., Adanma, U.M., &amp; Solomon, N.O. (2024). Eco-friendly wastewater treatment technologies (concept): Conceptualizing advanced, sustainable wastewater treatment designs for industrial and municipal applications. 2(1), 083&#x2013;104. 10.57219/crret.2024.2.1.0063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.57219/crret.2024.2.1.0063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Attar, N.E., &amp; Elmashad, Y. (2024). Artificial intelligence models for genomics analysis: Review article. 134&#x2013;150. 10.17048/am.2023.134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17048/am.2023.134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elegbeleye I., Oguntona O., Elegbeleye F. Green hydrogen: pathway to net zero green house gas emission and global climate change mitigation. Hydrogen. 2025;6(2):29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elser J.J., Call D.F., Deaver J.A., Duckworth O.W., Mayer B.K., McLamore E.S., Rittmann B.E., Mahmood M., Westerhoff P. The phosphorus challenge: Biotechnology approaches for a sustainable phosphorus system. Current Opinion in Biotechnology. 2024;90 doi: 10.1016/j.copbio.2024.103197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.copbio.2024.103197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39299060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erku&#x15f; F.&#x15e;., Tuncay K. Anaerobic co-digestion of cattle manure with ruminal waste to increase biogas production. Turkish Journal of Agriculture: Food Science and Technology. 2024;12(5):884. doi: 10.24925/turjaf.v12i5.884-884.6827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24925/turjaf.v12i5.884-884.6827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esiri A.E., Babayeju O.A., Ekemezie I.O. Standardizing methane emission monitoring: A global policy perspective for the oil and gas industry. Engineering Science &amp; Tecnology Journal. 2024;5(6):2027&#x2013;2038. doi: 10.51594/estj.v5i6.1220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.51594/estj.v5i6.1220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eswaran S., Anand A., Lairenjam G., Mohan G., Sharma N., Khare A., Bhargavi A. Climate change impacts on agricultural systems mitigation and adaptation strategies: A review. Journal of Experimental Agriculture International. 2024;46(11):1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.9734/jeai/2024/v46i113021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/jeai/2024/v46i113021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everaert, M., Faes, W., Maselyne, J., &amp; Lecompte, S. (2023). Economical and ecological optimization of renewable energy solutions for thermal demands of livestock farms. 10.52202/069564-0139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52202/069564-0139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everaert M., Maselyne J., Tassenoy R., Van Nieuwenhuyse J., Lecompte S. Assessing renewable energy installations in pig farms from a financial and environmental perspective: A case study in the EU. Renewable Energy. 2026;256</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eyo-Udo, N., Agho, M.O., Onukwulu, E.C., Sule, A.K., &amp; Azubuike, C.U. (2024). Advances in green finance solutions for combating climate change and ensuring sustainability. 2(6), 338&#x2013;375. 10.51594/gjabr.v2i6.53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.51594/gjabr.v2i6.53</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eze F., Egbo M., Anuta U.J., Ntiriwaa O.B.R., Ogola J., Mwabora J. A review on solar water heating technology: Impacts of parameters and techno-economic studies. Bulletin of the National Research Centre. 2024;48(1):29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahmy, A.F.M. (2024). Microbiome and human health: Recent insights and future directions. 1. 10.70389/pjph.100002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70389/pjph.100002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faizan M. Enteric methane production in ruminants: Its effect on global warming and mitigation strategies-a review. Pakistan Journal of Science. 2024 doi: 10.57041/pjs.v76i01.1084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.57041/pjs.v76i01.1084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falope, T., Lao, L., Hanak, D., &amp; Huo, D. (2024). Hybrid energy system integration and management for solar energy: A review. 10.1016/j.ecmx.2024.100527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecmx.2024.100527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO . FAO; 2023. Pathways towards lower emissions&#x2013;A global assessment of the greenhouse gas emissions and mitigation options from livestock agrifood systems. Rome.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4060/cc9029en</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farghali M., Chen Z., Osman A.I., Ali I., Hassan D., Ihara I., Rooney D.W., Yap P. Strategies for ammonia recovery from wastewater: A review. Environmental Chemistry Letters. 2024 doi: 10.1007/s10311-024-01768-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10311-024-01768-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedorec, A.J.H. (2024). Synthetic microbial ecology: Engineering habitats for modular consortia. 10.1093/jambio/lxae158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jambio/lxae158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38936824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng J., Li Y., Strathmann T.J., Guest J.S. Characterizing the opportunity space for sustainable hydrothermal valorization of wet organic wastes. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 2024 doi: 10.1021/acs.est.3c07394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.3c07394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10851424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38266239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finzi A., Vazifehkhoran A.H., Dinuccio E., Ambrosini R., Provolo G. Acidification of livestock slurry and digestate to reduce NH3 emissions: Predicting needed H2SO4 dosage and pH trends over time based on their chemical-physical composition. Biosystems Engineering. 2024;240:1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foggi G., Terranova M.S., Daghio M., Amelchanka S.L., Conte G., Ineichen S., Agnolucci M., Viti C., Mantino A., Buccioni A., Kreuzer M., Mele M. Evaluation of ruminal methane and ammonia formation and microbiota composition as affected by supplements based on mixtures of tannins and essential oils using Rusitec. Journal of Animal Science and Biotechnology. 2024;15 doi: 10.1186/s40104-024-01005-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40104-024-01005-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10986001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38561832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseca A., Kenney S., Van Syoc E., Bierly S.A., Dini-Andreote F., Silverman J., Boney J., Ganda E. Investigating antibiotic free feed additives for growth promotion in poultry - effects on performance and microbiota. Poultry Science. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.psj.2024.103604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psj.2024.103604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10951610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38484563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fouts J.Q., Honan M.C., Roque B.M., Tricarico J.M., Kebreab E. Enteric methane mitigation interventions. Translational Animal Science. 2022;6(2) doi: 10.1093/tas/txac041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tas/txac041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9071062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35529040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowoyo P.T. Phage therapy: Clinical applications, efficacy, and implementation hurdles. The Open Microbiology Journal. 2024;18(1) doi: 10.2174/0118742858281566231221045303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/0118742858281566231221045303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fresco S., Sanchez M.P., Boichard D., Fritz S., Martin P. Sequence-based GWAS reveals genes and variants associated with predicted methane emissions in French dairy cows. Genetics Selection Evolution. 2025;57(1):32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12172362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40528185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontini, F. (2024). Building integrated photovoltaic products and systems. 393&#x2013;406. 10.1002/9781119578826.ch24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9781119578826.ch24</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu X., Shen Y. Synthetic genomics: Repurposing biological systems for applications in engineering biology. ACS Synthetic Biology. 2024;13(5):1394&#x2013;1399. doi: 10.1021/acssynbio.4c00006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssynbio.4c00006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11106769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38757697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu C., Cheema W.A., Mobashar M., Shah A.A., Alqahtani M.M. Insects as sustainable feed: Enhancing animal nutrition and reducing livestock environmental impression. Journal of Animal Physiology and Animal Nutrition. 2024 doi: 10.1111/jpn.14055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jpn.14055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39382117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galar, D., &amp; Kumar, U. (2024). Digital twins: Definition, implementation and applications (pp. 79&#x2013;106). 10.1007/978-981-99-9122-8_7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-99-9122-8_7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesan A.R., Mohan K., Kandasamy S., Surendran P., Kumar R., Rajan D.K., Rajarajeswaran J. Food waste-derived black soldier fly (Hermetia illucens) larval resource recovery: A circular bioeconomy approach. Process Safety and Environmental Protection. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2024.01.084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2024.01.084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganguly R.K., Chakraborty S.K. Elsevier BV; 2024. Role of biochar in removal of contaminants from organic wastes; pp. 135&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-443-13585-9.00009-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao F., Ren S., Gao D., Shu Z. Cryopreservation and biobanking of gametes, embryos, and reproductive tissues. Biopreservation and Biobanking. 2024;22(1):1&#x2013;3. doi: 10.1089/bio.2024.29132.editorial.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/bio.2024.29132.editorial</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38393689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a Alvaro, A., Ru&#xed;z Palomar, C., Mu&#xf1;oz Torre, R., Hermosilla Redondo, D., &amp; de Godos Crespo, I. (2023). Hybridization of anaerobic digestion with solar energy: A solution for isolated livestock farms. 10.1016/j.ecmx.2023.100488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecmx.2023.100488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Ascolani M.E., Tarnonsky F., Roskopf S., Podversich F., Silva G.M., Schulmeister T.M., Ruiz-Moreno M., Hackmann T.J., Dubeux J.C.B., DiLorenzo N. Supplementation with avian-derived polyclonal antibodies against Methanobrevibacter gottschalkii and M. ruminantium decreases ex vivo methane production and modifies ruminal fermentation in Angus crossbred steers. Journal of Animal Science. 2024 doi: 10.1093/jas/skae213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skae213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11415294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39120483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghavi Hossein-Zadeh N. Estimates of the genetic contribution to methane emission in dairy cows: A meta-analysis. Scientific reports. 2022;12(1) doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-16778-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-16778-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9296463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35853993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghavi Hossein-Zadeh N. A meta-analysis of the genetic contribution to greenhouse gas emission in sheep. Journal of Animal Breeding and Genetics = Zeitschrift fur Tierzuchtung und Zuchtungsbiologie. 2023;140(1):49&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1111/jbg.12744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jbg.12744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36263924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghavi Hossein-Zadeh N. An overview of recent technological developments in bovine genomics. Veterinary and Animal Science. 2024;25 doi: 10.1016/J.VAS.2024.100382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.VAS.2024.100382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11334705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39166173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghavi Hossein-Zadeh N. Artificial intelligence in veterinary and animal science: Applications, challenges, and future prospects. Computers and Electronics in Agriculture. 2025;235 doi: 10.1016/J.COMPAG.2025.110395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.COMPAG.2025.110395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghimire S., Subedi K., Zhang X., Wu C. Efficacy of Bacillus subtilis probiotic in preventing necrotic enteritis in broilers: A systematic review and meta analysis. Avian Pathology. 2024:1&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1080/03079457.2024.2359596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03079457.2024.2359596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38776185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghiotto G., Detman-Ignatowska A., Chojnacka A., Orellana E., De Bernardini N., Fraulini S., Treu L., Sikora A., Campanaro S. Decipher syntrophies within C2-C4 organic acids-degrading anaerobic microbiomes: A multi-omic exploration. Chemical Engineering The Journal. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.151390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.151390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giagnoni G., Lund P., Johansen M., Weisbjerg M.R. Effect of dietary fat source and concentration on feed intake, enteric methane and milk production in dairy cows. Journal of Dairy Science. 2024 doi: 10.3168/jds.2024-25446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2024-25446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39477056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giangeri G., Tsapekos P., Gaspari M.M.F., Ghofrani-Isfahani P., Treu L., Kougias P., Campanaro S., Angelidaki I. A bioaugmentation strategy to recover methane production under sulfate-stressed conditions: Highlights on targeted sulfate-reducing bacteria and DIET-related species. Applied Energy. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.122940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.122940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gingrich S., Theurl M.C., Erb K., Le No&#xeb; J., Magerl A., Bauernschuster S., Krausmann F., Lauk C. Livestock increasingly drove global agricultural emissions growth from 1910-2015. Environmental Research Letters. 2024 doi: 10.1088/1748-9326/ad1cb6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-9326/ad1cb6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giovinazzo S., Romano E., Bisaglia C., Calcante A., Naldi E., Oberti R., Filisetti A., Rozzoni G., Brambilla M. Design of a sensory device for the characterization of the volatile organic compounds fingerprint in the breath of dairy cattle. AgriEngineering. 2025;7(3):55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godara A.S., Saresh N.V., Bijarniya A.L., Godara R., Kumar D., Meena D.K., Kumar M. Integrating livestock with crops and forestry for sustainability. International Journal of Enviornment and Climate Change. 2024;14(11):83&#x2013;90. doi: 10.9734/ijecc/2024/v14i114530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/ijecc/2024/v14i114530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes J., Hoque I., Tanzin P., Mansoor N. Springer International Publishing; 2024. AgriChain: Blockchain-enabled food traceability; pp. 121&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-99-8111-3_12</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez M., Zegarra O. Decarbonization of materials and construction processes editorial note. Revista Ingenier&#xed;a de Construcci&#xf3;n. 2024;39:I&#x2013;IV. doi: 10.7764/ric.00135.21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7764/ric.00135.21</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez, L.D., Mills, C., Mungu&#xed;a-L&#xf3;pez, A. del C., &amp; Zavala, V.M. (2024). Sustainable production of fertilizers via photosynthetic recovery of nutrients in livestock waste. 10.69997/sct.147417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.69997/sct.147417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez Quintero R., Garc&#xed;a E.H., Florez F., Burkart S., Arango J. A case study on enhancing dairy cattle sustainability: The impact of silvopastoral systems and improved pastures on milk carbon footprint and farm economics in Cauca department, Colombia. Agroforestry Systems. 2024;98(8):3001&#x2013;3018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goracci, J., &amp; Camilli, F. (2024). Agroforestry and animal husbandry. 10.5772/intechopen.1006711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5772/intechopen.1006711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goswami P., Ohura T., Suzuki R., Koike N., Watanabe M., Guruge K.S. Hazardous implications of halogenated polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons in feedstuff: Congener specificity and toxic levels in feed ingredients and feeds. Science of The Total Environment. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.169855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.169855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38185150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene J.M., Wallace J., Williams R.B., Leytem A.B., Bock B.R., McCully M., Kaffka S., Rotz C.A., Quinn J.C. National greenhouse gas emission reduction potential from adopting anaerobic digestion on large-scale dairy farms in the United States. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 2024 doi: 10.1021/acs.est.4c00367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.4c00367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38953529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gronwald F., Wang L. Advancing renewable energy: The prospects of hydrothermal liquefaction (HTL) for biomass into bio-oil conversion. International Journal of Environment, Engineering and Education. 2024;6(3):132&#x2013;144. doi: 10.55151/ijeedu.v6i3.138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55151/ijeedu.v6i3.138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gropp, J., Bill, M., Lloyd, M.K., Stein, R., Nayak, D.D., &amp; Stolper, D.A. (2024). CRISPR-enabled control of gene expression sets the isotopic composition of microbial methane. 10.1101/2024.10.28.620722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2024.10.28.620722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40811556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grygiel I., Bajrak O., W&#xf3;jcicki M., Krusiec K., Jo&#x144;czyk-Matysiak E., G&#xf3;rski A., Majewska J., Letkiewicz S. Comprehensive approaches to combatting acinetobacter baumannii biofilms: From biofilm structure to phage-based therapies. Antibiotics. 2024;13(11):1064. doi: 10.3390/antibiotics13111064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics13111064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11591314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39596757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan L.L. 432 Genomic strategies to improve the efficiency of rumen function. Journal of Animal Science. 2024;102(Supplement_3):182&#x2013;183. doi: 10.1093/jas/skae234.214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skae234.214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guebsi R., Mami S., Chokmani K. Drones in precision agriculture: A comprehensive review of applications, technologies, and challenges. Drones. 2024;8(11):686. doi: 10.3390/drones8110686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones8110686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guisiano, J.E., Lauvaux, T., Tzompa Sosa, Z., Moulines, &#xc9;., &amp; Sublime, J. (2024). Artificial intelligence for dynamic and intelligent methane inventory. 10.5194/egusphere-egu24-19625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/egusphere-egu24-19625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo J., Zhang Z., Guan L.L., Yoon I., Plaizier J.C., Khafipour E. Postbiotics from Saccharomyces cerevisiae fermentation stabilize microbiota in rumen liquid digesta during grain-based subacute ruminal acidosis (SARA) in lactating dairy cows. Journal of Animal Science and Biotechnology. 2024;15(1) doi: 10.1186/s40104-024-01056-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40104-024-01056-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11293205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39085941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo P., Qin W., Song W., Chen H. Spatial multi-omics analysis of the qianqiu goat gut microbiome and metabolome. International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 2025;26(24)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12732871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41465245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta S.P. The integration of renewable energy sources in food production. Advances in Environmental Engineering and Green Technologies Book Series. 2025:63&#x2013;86. doi: 10.4018/979-8-3693-8342-1.ch005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/979-8-3693-8342-1.ch005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurgan, I. (2025). Methane capture and conversion into higher value chemicals via microbial consortium. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. The PennState University, USA. Available at: Https://etda.libraries.psu.edu/catalog/34779ivg5123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haq, Z., Irshad, S., Khan, A.A., Ahmad, S.F., &amp; Bashir, S.M. (2024). Advances in managing nitrogen and phosphorus emissions in ruminants: A holistic approach. 10.5772/intechopen.1006578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5772/intechopen.1006578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han J., Zhang H., Ning K. Techniques for learning and transferring knowledge for microbiome-based classification and prediction: Review and assessment. Briefings in Bioinformatics. 2024;26(1) doi: 10.1093/bib/bbaf015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bib/bbaf015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11737891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39820436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Z., Wang K., Dai L., Li K., Wang X. Recent application of heat pump systems for environmental control in livestock facilities&#x2013;A review. Agriculture. 2024;14(12):2309. doi: 10.3390/agriculture14122309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture14122309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan F.M., Thomson P.C., Islam M.R., Clark C.E., Chlingaryan A., Lomax S. Monitoring cattle liveweight using a mobile, in-paddock weigh platform: Validation, attendance and utility. Smart Agricultural Technology. 2024;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan Q., Algburi S.S., Sameen A.Z., Salman H.M., Jaszczur M. A review of hybrid renewable energy systems: Solar and wind-powered solutions: Challenges, opportunities, and policy implications. Results in Engineering. 2023 doi: 10.1016/j.rineng.2023.101621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rineng.2023.101621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassen, A., Tesfamariam, E.H., Pepeta, B.N., &amp; Tesfamariam, E.H. (2024). The potential of strategies used to mitigate enteric methane emissions in nutrition studies of ruminants: A review. 10.20944/preprints202401.0284.v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20944/preprints202401.0284.v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Y., Zhou Z., Wu B., Xiao K., Wang C., Cheng X. Game-theoretic incentive mechanism for collaborative quality control in blockchain-enhanced carbon emissions verification. IEEE Transactions on Network Science and Engineering. 2024:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1109/tnse.2024.3456116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tnse.2024.3456116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herizal H., Rassanjani S., Afrijal A., Muhkrijal M., Wance M. Systematic literature review: The evolution of adaptive governance and practice in the context of the environmental crisis. Jurnal Ilmu Lingkungan (Program Studi Magister Ilmu Lingkungan, Program Pascasarjana Universitas Diponegoro. 2024;22(5):1326&#x2013;1337. doi: 10.14710/jil.22.5.1326-1337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14710/jil.22.5.1326-1337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez-Robles I.A. Hot water flow and temperature measurement to verify CO2 emission reductions using solar water heating. Measurement: Energy. 2025;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Himu H.A., Raihan A. An overview of precision livestock farming (PLF) technologies for digitalizing animal husbandry toward sustainability. Global Sustainability Research. 2024;3(3):1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.56556/gssr.v3i3.954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.56556/gssr.v3i3.954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodge I., Quille P., O&#x2019;Connell S. A review of potential feed additives intended for carbon footprint reduction through methane abatement in dairy cattle. Animals. 2024 doi: 10.3390/ani14040568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani14040568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10885959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38396536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holden N.J. Data sharing considerations to maximise use of pathogen biological and genomics resources data for public health. Journal of Applied Microbiology. 2024 doi: 10.1093/jambio/lxae204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jambio/lxae204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39113269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes B. Cleaning up cow burps to combat global warming. Knowable Magazine. 2024 doi: 10.1146/knowable-061024-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/knowable-061024-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horrillo A., Gaspar P., Rodr&#xed;guez-Ledesma A., Escribano M. Assessment of greenhouse gas emissions and carbon sequestration in dairy goat farming systems in Northern Extremadura, Spain. Animals. 2024;14(23):3501. doi: 10.3390/ani14233501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani14233501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11640683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39682466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;rtenhuber S., Seiringer M., Theurl M.C., Gr&#xf6;&#xdf;bacher V., Piringer G., Kral I., Zollitsch W. Implementing an appropriate metric for the assessment of greenhouse gas emissions from livestock production: A national case study. Animal. 2022;16(10) doi: 10.1016/j.animal.2022.100638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.animal.2022.100638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36182718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoshino N. Water splitting for hydrogen: A promising way to slow down greenhouse gas emissions. Science Insights. 2025;46(2):1729&#x2013;1731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu G., Do D.N., Davoudi P., Miar Y. Emerging roles of noncoding RNAs in the feed efficiency of livestock species. Genes. 2022;13:297. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8872339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35205343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Z., Boschiero C., Li C.J., Connor E.E., Baldwin R.L., Liu G.E. Unraveling the genetic basis of feed efficiency in cattle through integrated DNA methylation and CattleGTEx analysis. Genes. 2023;14(12):2121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10742843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38136943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X. The promotion of anaerobic digestion technology upgrades in waste stream treatment plants for circular economy in the context of &#x201c;Dual carbon&#x201d;: Global status, development trend, and future challenges. Water. 2024;16(24):3718. doi: 10.3390/w16243718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w16243718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Y., &amp; Khabusi, S.P. (2024). AIoT advances in aquaculture: A review. 10.20944/preprints202412.0456.v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20944/preprints202412.0456.v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, X., Gan, C., Zhang, M., Qiu, L., Gong, A., &amp; Dong, Y. (2024a). Development status and research progress of wet phosphoric acid extraction technology. 10.13374/j.issn2095-9389.2024.02.19.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13374/j.issn2095-9389.2024.02.19.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H., Peramaiah K., Huang K.W. Rethinking nitrate reduction: Redirecting electrochemical efforts from ammonia to nitrogen for realistic environmental impacts. Energy &amp; Environmental Science. 2024;17(8):2682&#x2013;2685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husien H.M., Saleh A.A., Hassanine N.N.A.M., Rashad A.M.A., Sharaby M.A., Mohamed A., Abdel-Halim H., Hafez E.S.E.H., Essa M.O.A., Adam S.Y., Chen N., Wang M. The evolution and role of molecular tools in measuring diversity and genomic selection in livestock populations (Traditional and up-to-date insights): A comprehensive exploration. Veterinary Sciences. 2024;11(12):627. doi: 10.3390/vetsci11120627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vetsci11120627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11680231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39728967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussein S.M., Aguerre M.J., Jenkins T.C., Bridges W.C., Lascano G.J. Screening dietary fat sources and concentrations included in low- and high-forage diets using an in vitro gas production system. Fermentation. 2024;10(10):506. doi: 10.3390/fermentation10100506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fermentation10100506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xfc;tt C., Isselstein J., Komainda M., Sch&#xf6;ttker O., Sturm A. UAV LiDAR-based grassland biomass estimation for precision livestock management. Journal of Applied Remote Sensing. 2024;18(1) -017502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iakovidis D., Gadanakis Y., Campos-Gonzalez J., Park J. Optimising decision support tools for the agricultural sector. Environment, Development and Sustainability. 2024 doi: 10.1007/s10668-024-04743-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10668-024-04743-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idris I., Yassaanah F. Advancing wireless sensor network security through the implementation of homomorphic encryption for secure and private image processing. International Journal for Science Technology and Engineering. 2024;12(1):1464&#x2013;1474. doi: 10.22214/ijraset.2024.58180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22214/ijraset.2024.58180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ignesti, G., Moroni, D., &amp; Martinelli, M. (2024). Towards the actual deployment of robust, adaptable, and maintainable AI models for sustainable agriculture. 40, 33&#x2013;39. 10.15439/2024f2991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15439/2024f2991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikpe A., Ekanem K.R., Bassey M. Experimental investigation of biogas yielding rate from anaerobic co-digestion of multiple organic feedstocks using a bio-digester. Journal of Advances in Environmental Health Research. 2024;12(4):228&#x2013;239. doi: 10.34172/jaehr.1354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34172/jaehr.1354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilavenil, K.K., &amp; Senthilkumar, V. (2024). Smart farming with IoT: Enhancing agricultural productivity (pp. 10&#x2013;18). 10.58532/v3biai12p1ch2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.58532/v3biai12p1ch2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilyas H., Afzal A., Abbas Z., Noor S., Ullah I., Rafique R.S., Abbas Z., Ishaq M.U.B. Commands of synthetic biology to modernize and re-design the biological systems. Advances in Life Sciences. 2024 doi: 10.62940/als.v11i3.2658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62940/als.v11i3.2658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Indugu N., Narayan K.S., Stefenoni H., Hennessy M.L., Vecchiarelli B., Bender J.S., Shah R., Dai G., Garapati S., Yarish C., Welchez S.C., R&#xe4;is&#xe4;nen S.E., Wasson D., Lage C.F.A., Melgar A., Hristov A.N., Pitta D. Microbiome-informed study of the mechanistic basis of methane inhibition by Asparagopsis taxiformis in dairy cattle. mBio. 2024 doi: 10.1128/mbio.00782-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/mbio.00782-24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11323727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38953639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingole K., Padole D.V. Developing an Internet of Things (IoT) compatibility framework for efficient farming. Nanotechnology Perceptions. 2024 doi: 10.62441/nano-ntp.v20is5.71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62441/nano-ntp.v20is5.71</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jab&#x142;o&#x144;ski S.J., &#x141;ukaszewicz M., Ku&#x142;a&#x17c;y&#x144;ski M. Manure processing as energy efficient fertilizer production technology. Clean Technologies and Environmental Policy. 2024 doi: 10.1007/s10098-024-03051-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10098-024-03051-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafir M., Abbas M., Irfan M., Zia-Ur-Rehman M. Advances and technology development in greenhouse gases: Emission, capture and conversion: Greenhouse gases emissions and climate change. Elsevier; 2024. Greenhouse gases emission from edible insect species; pp. 205&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-443-19231-9.00007-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagadale, M., Jadhav, M., Kumar, T.N., Shrivastava, P.S., &amp; Kumar, N. (2024). Hydrothermal liquefaction as a sustainable strategy for integral valorization of agricultural waste. 175&#x2013;200. 10.1002/9781394174805.ch7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9781394174805.ch7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jawalkar, S., Shende, R., Selokar, R., Sendre, S., &amp; Vairagde, R. (2024). Carbon credit transfer system using blockchain. 1&#x2013;6. 10.1109/incos59338.2024.10527749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/incos59338.2024.10527749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayanarasimhan A., Pathak R.M., Shivapuji A.M., Rao L. Tar formation in gasification systems: A holistic review of remediation approaches and removal methods. ACS Omega. 2024;9:2060&#x2013;2079. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.3c04425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c04425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10795124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38250394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins J.G., Negangard E.M., Sheldon M.D. Using blockchain, non-fungible tokens, and smart contracts to track and report greenhouse gas emissions. The Accounting Review. 2025;100(3):277&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon S., Yang H.S., Park C.Y., Kim S.Y., Park J.H. Medical device database: Scoping lifecycle review. &#xbcf4;&#xac74;&#xc815;&#xbcf4;&#xd1b5;&#xacc4;&#xd559;&#xd68c;&#xc9c0;. 2024;49(3):216&#x2013;223. doi: 10.21032/jhis.2024.49.3.216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21032/jhis.2024.49.3.216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong J., Yu C., Kang R., Kim M., Park T. Application of propionate-producing bacterial consortium in ruminal methanogenesis inhibited environment with bromoethanesulfonate as a methanogen direct inhibitor. Frontiers in Veterinary Science. 2024;11 doi: 10.3389/fvets.2024.1422474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fvets.2024.1422474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11497462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39444738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeyaraj S.G., Hemavarshini S., Kavitha S.G.G., Aravind J. Biochar-mediated removal of various pollutants from the environment. Physical Sciences Reviews. 2024 doi: 10.1515/psr-2023-0043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/psr-2023-0043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jhariya M.K., Meena R.S., Banerjee A., Kumar S., Raj A. Elsevier BV; 2024. Agroforestry for carbon and ecosystem management; pp. 3&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-323-95393-1.00031-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang N., Zhu X.G. Modern phenomics to empower holistic crop science, agronomy, and breeding research. Journal of Genetics and Genomics = Yi Chuan Xue Bao. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.jgg.2024.04.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jgg.2024.04.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38734136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang A., Liu Z., Lv X., Zhou C., Ran T., Tan Z. Prospects and challenges of bacteriophage substitution for antibiotics in livestock and poultry production. Biology. 2024;13(1) doi: 10.3390/biology13010028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biology13010028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10812986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38248459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, L., Gu, Y., Yu, W., &amp; Dai, J. (2024b). A blockchain-based greenhouse gas emission tracking system (Gets) for climate-related disclosures. 10.2139/ssrn.4804018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.4804018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao L., Tan Y. Social equity and renewable energy access in developing countries. MEDAAD. 2024;2024:27&#x2013;33. doi: 10.70470/medaad/2024/005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70470/medaad/2024/005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordon, M.W., Buffet, J.C., Dungait, J.A.J., Galdos, M.V., Garnett, T., Lee, M.R.F., Lynch, J., R&#xf6;&#xf6;s, E., Searchinger, T., Smith, P., &amp; Godfray, H.C.J. (2024). A restatement of the natural science evidence base concerning grassland management, grazing livestock and soil carbon storage. 291. 10.1098/rspb.2023.2669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rspb.2023.2669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10806435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38264781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jujjavarapu, S.E., Kumar, T., &amp; Gupta, S. (2024). Computational fluid dynamics: Fundamentals and applications in the design and optimization of various bioreactors (pp. 1&#x2013;33). 10.1007/978-981-99-7129-9_1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-99-7129-9_1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akshaya K., Selvasembian R. Potential and opportunities of waste biomass valorization toward sustainable biomethane production. ChemBioEng Reviews. 2024 doi: 10.1002/cben.202400004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cben.202400004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadam R., Jo S., Lee J., Khanthong K., Jang H., Park J.I. A review on the anaerobic co-digestion of livestock manures in the context of sustainable waste management. Energies. 2024 doi: 10.3390/en17030546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en17030546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadigi J.H., Muzzo B.I., Schreiber S.J. Potential benefits of tannins on ruminant health, production and environmental sustainability. European Journal of Nutrition &amp; Food Safety. 2024;16(10):13&#x2013;24. doi: 10.9734/ejnfs/2024/v16i101552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/ejnfs/2024/v16i101552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaistha S.D., Devi P.A., Sharma N., Sagar S. Navigating regulatory frameworks and compliances for bacteriophages as therapeutic agents. Current Pharmaceutical Biotechnology. 2025:26. doi: 10.2174/0113892010347488250113171505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/0113892010347488250113171505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39844559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaleeckal B.V., Schideman L., OBrien K., Gioja L., Wilken G., Hazlebeck D., Larimore R., Prause S., McCann J.C., Hazlebeck D., Britt R., Frischknecht J., Becker P. Large-scale algae cultivation for carbon capture &amp;amp; utilization, and waste-water treatment. Social Science Research Network. 2025 doi: 10.2139/ssrn.5069536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.5069536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamau K., Thorpe B., Meier K.E., Endres M.I., Salfer I.J. Comparisons of feed bunk nutrient consistency, milk production and cow behavior between herds using automated milking systems with or without automated feeding robots. Animals. 2025;15(8):1103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12024159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40281938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanchana K., Krishna T.M., Yuvaraj T., Babu T.S. Enhancing smart microgrid resilience under natural disaster conditions: Virtual power plant allocation using the jellyfish search algorithm. Sustainability. 2025;17(3):1043. doi: 10.3390/su17031043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su17031043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandpal N., Singhal N., Lavaniya H.V., Jain R., Singh R., Gaur A. Advances in environmental engineering and green technologies book series. IGI Global; 2025. Utilizing artificial intelligence and machine learning for enhanced recycling efforts; pp. 65&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/979-8-3693-7282-1.ch004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang H.Y., Lee J.Y., Kim G.Y., Hwang Y.W., Park K.H., Lee D.J. Analyzing the environmental impact of livestock manure recycling process using life cycle assessment. Journal of Korean Society of Environmental Engineers. 2024;46(10):582&#x2013;591. doi: 10.4491/ksee.2024.46.10.582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4491/ksee.2024.46.10.582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karanjikar P.N., Patange M.J., Belagalla N., Negi V., Ks S., Bisht P. Integration of renewable energy solutions in agricultural operations. Journal of Geography, Environment and Earth Science International. 2024 doi: 10.9734/jgeesi/2024/v28i11835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/jgeesi/2024/v28i11835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsen V.B., Dinamarca C. Electrochemical and bioelectrochemical sulphide removal: A review. Reviews in Environmental Science and Bio/Technology. 2024 doi: 10.1007/s11157-024-09708-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11157-024-09708-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur U. 463 Cyber-physical systems with robots and AI for precision dairy farming. Journal of Animal Science. 2024;102(Supplement_3):297&#x2013;298. doi: 10.1093/jas/skae234.340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skae234.340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur G., Basak N., Kumar S. State-of-the-art techniques to enhance biomethane/biogas production in thermophilic anaerobic digestion. Process Safety and Environmental Protection. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2024.03.123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2024.03.123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazembe I., Mkandawire M.M. AI driven animal farming and livestock management system. International Journal of Advanced Research in Science, Communication and Technology. 2024:23&#x2013;27. doi: 10.48175/ijarsct-22604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48175/ijarsct-22604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keerthi M.M. Harnessing the power of biochar: A sustainable solution for agriculture and climate change mitigation. Environmental Reports. 2024;6(2):5&#x2013;7. doi: 10.51470/er.2024.6.2.05.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.51470/er.2024.6.2.05</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan I.M., Nassar N., Chang H., Khan S., Cheng M., Wang Z., Xiang X. The microbiota: A key regulator of health, productivity, and reproductive success in mammals. Frontiers in Microbiology. 2024 doi: 10.3389/fmicb.2024.1480811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2024.1480811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11616035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39633815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan F.A., Ali A., Wu D., Huang C., Zulfiqar H., Ali M., Ahmed B., Yousaf M.R., Putri E.M., Negara W., Imran M., Pandupuspitasari N.S. Editing microbes to mitigate enteric methane emissions in livestock. World Journal of Microbiology and Biotechnology. 2024;40(10):300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39134917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaowdang S., Suriyachai N., Imman S., Suwannahong K., Wongcharee S., Kreetachat T. Application of internet of things technology for ventilation and environmental control in conventional open-air pig housing systems in Thailand. AgriEngineering. 2025;7(6):165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khejornsart P., Juntanam T., Gunun P., Gunun N., Cherdthong A. Effect of high-tannin and -polyphenol plant material supplement on rumen fermentation, nitrogen partitioning and nutrient utilization in beef cattle. Animals. 2024;14(21):3092. doi: 10.3390/ani14213092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani14213092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11545557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39518815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kichamu N., Astuti P.K., Kusza S. The role of insect-based feed in mitigating climate change: Sustainable solutions for ruminant farming. Insects. 2025;16(5):516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12111986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40429229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim T.H., Cho B., Lee D. Synthetic biology-driven microbial therapeutics for disease treatment. Journal of Microbiology and Biotechnology. 2024 doi: 10.4014/jmb.2407.07004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4014/jmb.2407.07004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11540606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39233526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S., Cha H., Lee T., Kim J.Y., Lee J., Jang S.H., Kwon E.E. Suppression of carbon footprint through the CO2-assisted pyrolysis of livestock waste. Science of the Total Environment. 2025;964</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39862505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King, K., Thornton, C., &amp; Roopaei, M. (2024). Smart feeding: Integrating deep learning into dairy farm practices. 10.1109/aiiot61789.2024.10579035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/aiiot61789.2024.10579035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klingstr&#xf6;m T., Zonabend K&#xf6;nig E., Zwane A.A. Beyond the hype: Using AI, big data, wearable devices, and the internet of things for high-throughput livestock phenotyping. Briefings in Functional Genomics. 2024 doi: 10.1093/bfgp/elae032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bfgp/elae032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11735752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39158344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko, C., Ko, H.S., Liu, A.C., Yang, P., &amp; Chang, F. (2024). Methane production from the anaerobic co-digestion of lignocellulosic materials. 10.2139/ssrn.4751404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.4751404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocabiyik O., Amlashi P., Vo A.L., Suh H., Rodriguez-Aponte S.A., Dalvie N.C., Love J.C., Andrabi R., Irvine D.J. Vaccine targeting to mucosal lymphoid tissues promotes humoral immunity in the gastrointestinal tract. Science Advances. 2024;10(22) doi: 10.1126/sciadv.adn7786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.adn7786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11135404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38809992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko&#x10d;etkovs V., Zvirbule A. Chicken manure as closed-loop circular economy product of poultry industry. Engineering for Rural Development. 2025;24 doi: 10.22616/erdev.2025.24.tf177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22616/erdev.2025.24.tf177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koki&#x107; B., Rakita S., Vujeti&#x107; J. Impact of using oilseed industry byproducts rich in linoleic and alpha-linolenic acid in ruminant nutrition on milk production and milk fatty acid profile. Animals. 2024 doi: 10.3390/ani14040539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani14040539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10886360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38396507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komyshev D., Kapral A., Drebot O., Sakharnatska L., Karpyk J. Advancing waste reduction and resource conservation through circular economy practices: A rational review. Grassroots Journal of Natural Resources. 2024;7(3):s173&#x2013;s190. doi: 10.33002/nr2581.6853.0703ukr09.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33002/nr2581.6853.0703ukr09</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kou X., Yang X., Zheng R. Challenges and opportunities of phage therapy for Klebsiella pneumoniae infections. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2024 doi: 10.1128/aem.01353-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/aem.01353-24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11497816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39345202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krexner T., Bauer A., Gronauer A., Mikovits C., Schmidt J., Kral I. Environmental life cycle assessment of a stilted and vertical bifacial crop-based agrivoltaic multi land-use system and comparison with a mono land-use of agricultural land. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews. 2024;196</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, L., Chaudhary, S., Karir, S.R., D&#xed;az-Ravi&#xf1;a, M., Choudhary, A.K., &amp; Kumar, S.G. (2024). The prologue to precision livestock farming (pp. 179&#x2013;190). 10.58532/v3bcag21p2ch11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.58532/v3bcag21p2ch11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumari, S., &amp; Agarwal, V.K. (2024). Blockchain technology&#x2013;Adoption, opportunities, and challenges for a sustainable agricultural ecosystem. 191&#x2013;210. 10.1002/9781394242962.ch11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9781394242962.ch11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Corte D., Maddaloni M., Vahidzadeh R., Domini M., Bertanza G., Ansari S., Marchionni M., Tola V., Artioli N. Recovered ammonia as a sustainable energy carrier: Innovations in recovery, combustion, and fuel cells. Energies. 2025;18(3):508. doi: 10.3390/en18030508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en18030508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahart B., Shalloo L., Walsh S., Walker N., Costigan H. Evaluating the impact of 3-nitroxypropanol supplementation on enteric methane emissions in pregnant non-lactating dairy cows offered grass silage. JDS Communications. 2024 doi: 10.3168/jdsc.2024-0591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jdsc.2024-0591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11770311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39877165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laplacette C.M., Berone G.D., Utsumi S.A., Insua J.R. Calibration of an unmanned aerial vehicle for prediction of herbage mass in temperate pasture. Agriculture. 2025;15(5):492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lashkari S., Weisbjerg M.R., Foldager L., B&#xf8;rsting C.F. Fat supplement for dairy cows during early lactation &#x2013; potentials, challenges, and risks&#x2013;A meta-analysis. Journal of Applied Animal Research. 2024 doi: 10.1080/09712119.2024.2323625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09712119.2024.2323625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lathief A., Manjusha W.A. Bioactive potential of probiotic bacteria&#x2013;A comprehensive review. Food Science and Engineering. 2024:391&#x2013;403. doi: 10.37256/fse.5220244592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37256/fse.5220244592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambo M.T., Ma H., Liu R., Dai B. Review: Mechanism, effectiveness, and the prospects of medicinal plants and their bioactive compounds in lowering ruminants&#x2019; enteric methane emission. Animal. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.animal.2024.101134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.animal.2024.101134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38593679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan X., Dlugokencky E.J. Atmospheric constraints on changing Arctic CH4 emissions. Frontiers in Environmental Science. 2024 doi: 10.3389/fenvs.2024.1382621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenvs.2024.1382621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langley-Randall J., Jones D.L., Cotton J., Williams J.R., Chadwick D.R. Slurry acidification is as effective as slurry injection at reducing ammonia emissions without increasing N2O emissions: A short-term mesocosm study. Geoderma Regional. 2024;37</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, J., Yun, J.H., Yang, Y., Jung, J.C., Lee, Y.K., Yuan, J., Ding, W., Freeman, C., &amp; Kang, H. (2024). Positive feedback to global warming linked to indirect nitrogen attenuation of Arctic tundra CH4 oxidation. 10.22541/au.170669460.01391780/v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22541/au.170669460.01391780/v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C.G., Kang G.C., Jang J.K., Yun S.W., Moon J.P., Mun H.S., Lagua E.B. Efficacy of hybrid photovoltaic&#x2013;thermal and geothermal heat pump system for greenhouse climate control. Energies. 2025;18(20):5386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leishman E.M., Jahnel R.E., Harlander A., Willems O.W., Wood B.J., Barbut S., Schenkel F.S., Miglior F., Gervais R., Stothard P., Baes C.F. 301 Leveraging genomics to advance the breeding of Canadian livestock. Journal of Animal Science. 2024;102(Supplement_3):178. doi: 10.1093/jas/skae234.208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skae234.208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leitner, S.M., Carbonell, V., Mhindu, R., Zhu, Y., Mutuo, P.M., Butterbach-Bahl, K., &amp; Merbold, L. (2024). Greenhouse gas emissions from cattle enclosures in semi-arid sub-Saharan Africa: The case of a rangeland in South-Central Kenya. 10.1016/j.agee.2024.108980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agee.2024.108980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G., Yao J. A review of algae-based carbon capture, utilization, and storage (Algae-based CCUS) Gases. 2024;4(4):468&#x2013;503. doi: 10.3390/gases4040024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gases4040024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Y., Zou Y., Wang P., Yang H., Cui H. Efficiency, economic and environmental analysis of solar utilization with high-performance phase change material composites. Journal of Energy Storage. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.est.2024.110930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2024.110930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao W., Liu M., Bian Y., Wang W., Gao Z. Towards greenhouse gases mitigation for liquid pig slurry management with solid-liquid separation technologies. Journal of Environmental Management. 2025;395</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41187680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberty J.T., Poudel B.H., Ihedioha O.C., Lin H., Habanabakize E., Gao Z., Adesoji A.T., Liberty S.J. Gene editing technology: Shaping international standards for health and food safety assurance. Trends in Biotechnology. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.tibtech.2024.09.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tibtech.2024.09.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39424445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling-Chin J., Simpson R., Cairns A., Wu D., Xie Y., Song D., Kashkarov S., Molkov V., Moutzouris I., Wright L., Tricoli P., Dansoh C., Panesar A., Chong K., Liu P., Roy D., Wang Y., Smallbone A., Roskilly A.P. Research and innovation identified to decarbonise the maritime sector. Green Energy and Sustainability. 2024 doi: 10.47248/ges2404010001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47248/ges2404010001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Q., Lei, S., Zhao, M., Li, M., Cong, Y., Kang, F., Gao, X., Zhang, L., Zhu, C., Zheng, L., &amp; Liu, J. (2024). Potential to reduce methane production of using cultivated seaweeds supplementation to reshape the community structure of rumen microorganisms. 10.2139/ssrn.4793518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.4793518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38925466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llonch L., Mart&#xed; S., Verge G., Riera J., Mediny&#xe0; C., Cucurull J., P&#xe9;rez A., Fern&#xe1;ndez B., Devant M. PSIX-21 Can seeds rich in polyunsaturated fatty acids reduce methane emissions when substituting palm oil on dairy beef calves fed high-concentrate diets? In vitro screening. Journal of Animal Science. 2024;102(Supplement_3):735&#x2013;736. doi: 10.1093/jas/skae234.829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skae234.829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logeswaran, T., Johinth, P., V, M., Manivashagan, A., Prem, S., &amp; Suresh, M. (2024). Smart cow care: IoT-driven automatic feeding and temperature control. 231&#x2013;235. 10.1109/icses63445.2024.10763195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/icses63445.2024.10763195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes R., Prasad M.K. Beyond the promise: Evaluating and mitigating off-target effects in CRISPR gene editing for safer therapeutics. Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology. 2024 doi: 10.3389/fbioe.2023.1339189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2023.1339189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10883050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38390600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo L., Karimirad R., Wong J.W.C. Enhanced anaerobic co-digestion of food waste and sewage sludge by co-application of biochar and nano-Fe3O4. Journal of Environmental Management. 2024;370 doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39405862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupo, V., Roomans, C., Royen, E., Ongena, L., Jacquemin, O., Mullender, C., Kerff, F., &amp; Baurain, D. (2024). Identification and characterization of archaeal pseudomurein biosynthesis genes through pangenomics. 10.1101/2024.11.07.622503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2024.11.07.622503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11915815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39936904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma P., Jin M., Zhang D., Lv L., Zhang G., Ren Z. Surface engineering-based S, N co-doped biochar for improved anaerobic digestion: Enhancing microbial-pollutant and inter-microbial electron transfer synergistic EPS protection. Journal of Hazardous Materials. 2024;480 doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.136217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.136217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39437466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma W., Ji X., Ding L., Yang S.X., Guo K., Li Q. Automatic monitoring methods for greenhouse and hazardous gases emitted from ruminant production systems: A review. Sensors. 2024;24(13):4423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11244603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39001201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macena I.A., Orrico A.C.A., Ota &#xc9;.D.C., Gimenes R.M.T., Souza S.V., de Vargas F.M., Leite B.K.V., Orrico M.A.P. Economic feasibility of solid&#x2013;liquid separation and hydraulic retention time in composting or anaerobic digestion systems for recycling dairy cattle manure. AgriEngineering. 2025;7(9):306. doi: 10.3390/agriengineering7090306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriengineering7090306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madheswaran D.K., Saravanan J., Jegadheeswaran S., Subramanian V. Harnessing biogas in India: A sustainable pathway for sustainable energy development. Green and Low-Carbon Economy. 2024 doi: 10.47852/bonviewglce42021762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47852/bonviewglce42021762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnolo, F., Candel, J., &amp; Speelman, S. (2024). Biomethane from manure in the repowereu: A critical perspective on the scale-up of renewable energy production from waste of the livestock sector. 10.2139/ssrn.4688631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.4688631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magro S., De Marchi M., Cassandro M., Finocchiaro R., Fabris A., Marusi M., Costa A. Blood parameters predicted from milk spectra are candidate indicator traits of hyperketonemia&#x2013;A retrospective study in the Italian Holstein population. Journal of Dairy Science. 2024 doi: 10.3168/jds.2024-25170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2024-25170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39647615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahale R., Patange K., Phad S., More A., Chavan V. Applied soft computing techniques. Apple Academic Press; 2025. Drone-enabled precision agriculture: Revolutionizing crop management and yield optimization; pp. 205&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maigaard M., Weisbjerg M.R., Hellwing A.L.F., Larsen M., Andersen F.B., Lund P. The acute effects of rumen pulse-dosing of hydrogen acceptors during methane inhibition with nitrate or 3-nitrooxypropanol in dairy cows. Journal of Dairy Science. 2024;107(8):5681&#x2013;5698. doi: 10.3168/jds.2023-24343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2023-24343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38608947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majumder D., Fahad S., Hossain A. Elsevier BV; 2024. Biochar versus soil health under changing climate; pp. 35&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-443-21562-9.00002-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makinde P., Obikoya E. Implementation of solar system for electricity generation for rural farmers: A review. World Journal of Advanced Research and Reviews. 2024;22(3):458&#x2013;471. doi: 10.30574/wjarr.2024.22.3.1705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30574/wjarr.2024.22.3.1705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malyugina S., Holik S., Hork&#xfd; P. Mitigation strategies for methane emissions in ruminant livestock: A comprehensive review of current approaches and future perspectives. Frontiers in Animal Science. 2025;6 doi: 10.3389/fanim.2025.1610376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fanim.2025.1610376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangate L., Alabdeli H., Agarwal R., Saravanan T., Janakiraman V., Sherje N., Naidu K. Adaptive energy management system for enhancing efficiency and reliability in hybrid renewable energy systems. E3S Web of Conferences. 2024;591 doi: 10.1051/e3sconf/202459101015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/e3sconf/202459101015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcos C., Carro M.D., Guti&#xe9;rrez-Rivas M., Atxaerandio R., Goiri I., Garc&#xed;a-Rodr&#xed;guez A., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Recio O. Ruminal microbiome changes across lactation in primiparous Holstein cows with varying methane intensity: Heritability assessment. Journal of Dairy Science. 2024 doi: 10.3168/jds.2023-24552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2023-24552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38788852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin, N., Durlinger, B., Blonk, H., &amp; Mitloehner, F. (2017). Towards the global reference for Feed LCA data: The global feed LCA institute..</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez G., Denman S.E., Walker N., Kindermann M., McSweeney C.S. Programming rumen microbiome development in calves with the anti-methanogenic compound 3-NOP. Animal Microbiome. 2024;6(1) doi: 10.1186/s42523-024-00343-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42523-024-00343-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11515290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39449033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-&#xc1;lvaro M., Mattock J., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Recio &#xd3;., Sabor&#xed;o-Montero A., Weng Z., Duthie C.A., Dewhurst R.J., Cleveland M.A., Watson M., Roehe R. Including microbiome information in a multi-trait genomic evaluation: A case study on longitudinal growth performance in beef cattle. Genetics Selection Evolution. 2024;56 doi: 10.1186/s12711-024-00887-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12711-024-00887-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10943865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38491422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matabane, D.M., Ng`ambi, J.W., Mabelebele, M., Gunya, B., &amp; Manyelo, T.G. (2024). The role of secondary metabolites on methane reduction in small ruminants. 10.5772/intechopen.1005461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5772/intechopen.1005461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAllister T.A., Thomas K., Gruninger R.J., Elshahed M.S., Li Y., Cheng Y. International symposium on ruminant physiology: Rumen fungi, archaea and their interactions. Journal of Dairy Science. 2025 doi: 10.3168/jds.2024-25713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2024-25713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39824485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMeniman, J.P., McCarthy, S.G., Mcleod, D.N., &amp; Platts, S.V. (2025). Automated feedlot bunk management 1: Development and evaluation of a lidar and pose technology-based prototype for feed quantity estimation in beef cattle feedlots. Available at SSRN 5096169..</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McQuilkin, J., Ricketts, H., &amp; Allen, G. (2024). From novelty to norm: Towards standardising drone quantification of gas emissions. 10.5194/egusphere-egu24-932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/egusphere-egu24-932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrotra R. Ai-driven circularity index: A comprehensive metric for evaluating product lifecycle sustainability. International Journal of Advanced Research. 2024;12(08):1491&#x2013;1498. doi: 10.21474/ijar01/19395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21474/ijar01/19395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei C., Cheng M., Xie M., Yang R., Liu T., Huang Z., Zhou T., Zhao Y., Liu Z., Li B. Recent advances in thermochemical conversion technology for anaerobic digestate from food waste. Bioresource Technology. 2024;413 doi: 10.1016/j.biortech.2024.131527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2024.131527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39326531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;it&#xe9; R., Artner-Nehls A., Uthes S. Farm adaptation to stricter nutrient management legislation and the implications for future livestock production: A review. Nutrient Cycling in Agroecosystems. 2024 doi: 10.1007/s10705-024-10341-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10705-024-10341-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meshram P.G., Shaniware Y., Bhondave G.P., Zol D.M., Pandey P. Precision agriculture: UAV-based soil mapping and remote sensing applications. Asian Research Journal of Agriculture. 2024 doi: 10.9734/arja/2024/v17i4598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/arja/2024/v17i4598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michla, J.R.J., Kishan, K.V.S.N.S., Harsha, B.V.S.S., Sudeep, P.V.S., Sindhu, S., &amp; Rukmini, B.V.S. (2024). Carbon footprint calculator with sustainability suggestions. 1&#x2013;5. 10.1109/icccnt61001.2024.10724579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/icccnt61001.2024.10724579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miji&#x107; D., Vico G., Popovi&#x107; B.V., Popovi&#x107; N., Ljubojevi&#x107; M., Savi&#x107; M. OPTIMILK: A web-based tool for least-cost dairy ration optimization using linear programming. Agriculture. 2024;14(9):1580. doi: 10.3390/agriculture14091580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture14091580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda E.S., Vilas Boas e Silva Y.R., Cabral L.D.S., Oliveira J.C.A.D., Lopes M., Lopes da Rosa e Silva P.I.J., Negr&#xe3;o F.D.M. Urea and nitrate poisoning as a source of non-protein nitrogen in ruminant diets: A review. Caderno Pedag&#xf3;gico. 2024;21(7):e5518. doi: 10.54033/cadpedv21n7-062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.54033/cadpedv21n7-062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra S., Banerjee A., Chattaraj S., Samantaray A., Panigrahi S., Bauri K.P., Thatoi H. Microbial process in anaerobic digestion of food wastes for biogas production: A review. Systems Microbiology and Biomanufacturing. 2025;5(2):531&#x2013;549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra, K., &amp; Sonal, D. (2024). Role of IoT-based solutions in smart farming (pp. 43&#x2013;49). 10.58532/v3bbio9p2ch1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.58532/v3bbio9p2ch1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittu, B., Sharma, R., Singh, M., &amp; Singh, N. (2024). Integrating AI with near-infrared spectroscopy (NIRS) for real-time industry. 316&#x2013;328. 10.1201/9781032633602-16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1201/9781032633602-16</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mkilima T. Hydrothermal liquefaction of wastewater as part of tailoring biocrude composition for a circular bioeconomy: A review. Biofuels, Bioproducts and Biorefining. 2025;19(6):2581&#x2013;2608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moeller A., Wang S., Jin S. Electrochemical ammonia recovery from manure wastewater integrated with electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction. Meeting Abstracts. 2024;MA2024-01(37):2242. doi: 10.1149/ma2024-01372242mtgabs.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1149/ma2024-01372242mtgabs</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed A.A.R., Ali A.E., Hassouna M.S.E.D., Elhusseiny A.F., He Z., Moustafa H. Efficacy of bioelectrochemical and electrochemical systems in ammonia recovery from slaughterhouse wastewater. Applied Water Science. 2025;15(2) doi: 10.1007/s13201-024-02355-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13201-024-02355-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D., Liberati A., Tetzlaff J., Altman D.G., Group PRISMA. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: The PRISMA statement. PLoS Medicine. 2009;6(7) doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1000097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1000097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan, M.Y., Bryan, E., &amp; Elias, M. (2024). Women&#x2019;s leadership in climate-resilient agrifood systems: Defining a future research agenda. 10.1088/2752-5295/ad3fdd.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2752-5295/ad3fdd</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris A.H., Bohannan B.J.M. Estimates of microbiome heritability across hosts. Nature Microbiology. 2024 doi: 10.1038/s41564-024-01865-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41564-024-01865-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39548346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mouhib E., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Solas &#xc1;., P&#xe9;rez-Higueras P.J., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Oca&#xf1;a A.M., Micheli L., Almonacid F., Fern&#xe1;ndez E.F. Enhancing land use: Integrating bifacial PV and olive trees in agrivoltaic systems. Applied Energy. 2024;359</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moutaouakil, K., &amp; Falih, N. (2024). A new approach to animal behavior classification using recurrent neural networks. 10.1109/iraset60544.2024.10549544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/iraset60544.2024.10549544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mrutu R.I., Abdussamad A.M., Umar K.M., Abdulhamid A., Farny N.G. Mitigating methane emissions and promoting acetogenesis in ruminant livestock. Frontiers in Animal Science. 2025;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mshary G.S., Castillo C., Hern&#xe1;ndez Berm&#xfa;dez J., Mu&#xed;&#xf1;o R. Impact of zootechnical additive of the nitrooxypropanol to minimize methane emission in cattle: A review. Diyala Agricultural Sciences Journal. 2024;16(2):27&#x2013;39. doi: 10.52951/dasj.24160203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52951/dasj.24160203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mshary G.S., Castillo C., Hern&#xe1;ndez Berm&#xfa;dez J., Mu&#xed;&#xf1;o R. Mini review: The strategic approach of saponin to reducing methane emissions. Kufa Journal for Veterinary Medical Sciences. 2024;15(2):9&#x2013;17. doi: 10.36326/kjvs/2024/v15i216715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36326/kjvs/2024/v15i216715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munim, K.Md., &amp; Islam, M.N. (2024). An IoT and blockchain-based framework for sustainable vertical farming. 2, 1&#x2013;6. 10.1109/iatmsi60426.2024.10503428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/iatmsi60426.2024.10503428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munir N., Safi S.Z., Sarwar Z., Arshad M., Hasnain M., Haq R. Climate changes mitigation and sustainable bioenergy harvest through animal waste: Sustainable environmental implications of animal waste. Springer Nature Switzerland; Cham: 2023. Techniques and strategies for bioenergy production from manure; pp. 125&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munir N., Sarwar Z., Abideen Z., Saleem F., Hasanuzzaman M., Siddiqui Z.S., El-Keblawy A. Algae-based bioremediation of soil, water, and air: A solution to polluted environment. Environmental Science and Pollution Research. 2025:1&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40952577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munonye W.C., Ajonye G.O. Urban policy and governance for a circular economy: Opportunities and challenges. Journal of Environmental Science Studies. 2024;7(2):47. doi: 10.20849/jess.v7i2.1470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20849/jess.v7i2.1470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muntari M., Arciero B.R., Seekford Z.K., Adcock Z., Bickmeier J., Sullivan J., Radulovic, Z., McGrath, C., Allen, C., Fitch, L.E., Spoonamore, J., Adolfsen, K.J., Pohler, K.G., Carstens, G.E., &amp; Lamb, C.C&#x2026;Dunn M.R. 271 Effects of vaccination on enteric methane emissions, growth performance, and feeding behavior of beef cattle. Journal of Animal Science. 2025;103(Supplement_3):241&#x2013;242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murali D., Acosta-Pazmi&#xf1;o I.P., Loris A., Garc&#xed;a A.C., Benni S., Tinti F., Gomes J. Experimental assessment of a solar photovoltaic-thermal system in a livestock farm in Italy. Solar Energy Advances. 2024;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy D.J. Elsevier BV; 2024. Sustainable vegetable oils; pp. 31&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-443-15327-3.00011-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadagouda M.N., Varshney G., Varshney V., Hejase C.A. Recent advances in technologies for phosphate removal and recovery: A review. ACS Environmental Au. 2024 doi: 10.1021/acsenvironau.3c00069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsenvironau.3c00069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11583102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39582759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagarajan A., Goyette B., Raghavan V., Poulin-Laprade D., Rajagopal R. Integrating anaerobic digestion with struvite production for enhanced nutrient recovery, pathogen reduction, and circularity in manure management. The Journal of Sustainable Agriculture and Environment. 2024 doi: 10.1002/sae2.70018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sae2.70018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakayasu Y., Nakano H., Umetsu M., Yokoyama K., Takahashi H., Tada C. Methanogen biocathode microbial fuel cell system that simultaneously achieves cattle-barn wastewater treatment and carbon dioxide utilization. Energy Technology. 2024 doi: 10.1002/ente.202401558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ente.202401558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narasimha, S., Zackria, R., Chadha, R., Gheriani, A., Johnson, L., Pattison, R., Kim, A., Chen, G.Q., Ryan, J., &amp; Shih, D.Q. (2024). The various healthcare applications of the genus Lactobacillus. 10.5772/intechopen.115299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5772/intechopen.115299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narnaware S.L., Panwar N.L. Springer Nature; 2024. Air&#x2013;steam gasification of wheat straw for bio-hydrogen production; pp. 11&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-99-6616-5_2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasir M., Rodr&#xed;guez-Prado M., Simoni M., Mart&#xed;n-Or&#xfa;e S.M., P&#xe9;rez J.F., Calsamiglia S. Optimizing essential oil mixtures: Synergistic effects on cattle rumen fermentation and methane emission. Animals. 2025;15(14):2105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12291954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40723567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navajas E.A., De Barbieri I., Ravagnolo O., Pravia M.I., Aguilar I., Lema M., Devincenzi T., Peraza P., Vera B., Carracelas B., Ciappesoni G. Genetic selection and livestock sustainability. Agrociencia Uruguay. 2025;29(NE2):e1480. doi: 10.31285/agro.29.1480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31285/agro.29.1480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nayak J.K., Gautam R., Guan C., Ghosh U.K. Elsevier BV; 2024. Algae-based bio-electrochemical systems for carbon sequestration, bioremediation, and cogeneration of valuable chemicals: Challenges and future prospects; pp. 77&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-323-91023-1.00011-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazarov D., Sulimin V., Shvedov V., &#x41b;&#x430;&#x440;&#x438;&#x43e;&#x43d;&#x43e;&#x432;&#x430; &#x41d;.&#x418;. Renewable energy sources for the agricultural sector. E3S Web of Conferences. 2024;541 doi: 10.1051/e3sconf/202454101002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/e3sconf/202454101002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazim M., Ghafoor A., Hussain A., Tabassum M., Nawaz A., Ahmad M., Muhammad M., Ali M. Biochar as a climate-smart agricultural practice: Reducing greenhouse gas emissions and promoting sustainable farming. Phyton. 2025;94(1):65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazir A., Hussain F.H.N., Raza A. Advancing microbiota therapeutics: The role of synthetic biology in engineering microbial communities for precision medicine. Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology. 2024;12 doi: 10.3389/fbioe.2024.1511149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2024.1511149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11652149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39698189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neethirajan S. Adapting a large-scale transformer model to decode chicken vocalizations: A non-invasive ai approach to poultry welfare. AI. 2025;6(4):65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#x2019;guessan A.R., Tra Bi Y.C., Yapo E.G.A.S., Koffi A.R.H., Yebouet F.O., Campitelli A., Aka B., Djeni N.D.T. Enhanced biogas production and pathogen reduction from pig manure through anaerobic digestion: A sustainable approach for urban waste management in Abidjan, C&#xf4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire. Clean Technologies. 2025;7(4):89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngo T.T.M., Khudur L.S., Hassan S., Jansriphibul K., Ball A.S. Enhancing microbial viability with biochar for increased methane production during the anaerobic digestion of chicken manure. Fuel. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni G., Wang M., Walker N., Muetzel S., Schmidt O., Fischer A., Stemmler R.T., Leung P.M., Zhang X., Li Q., Jain S., Jespersen M., Grinter R., Archer S.D.J., Pacheco D., Lowe K., Pope P.B., M..ller V., Pitta D.W., Janssen P.H., Greening C. Methanogenesis inhibition remodels microbial fermentation and stimulates acetogenesis in ruminants. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 2025;122(41)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12541428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41052332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen F.K., Hansen R.J., Muurmann A.T., Bahrndorff S., Eriksen N.T. Metabolic performance of mealworms and black soldier fly larvae reared on food and agricultural waste and by-products. Animals. 2025;15(2):233. doi: 10.3390/ani15020233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani15020233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11759143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39858233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning S., Yan T., Luo W., Tao S., Zou X., Li Y., Shangguan Z., Wu Y., Zhang Z., He J. Aridity-dependent resistance but strong resilience of grassland aboveground net primary productivity: Evidence from long-term naturally occurring extreme precipitation events. Journal of Plant Ecology. 2024 doi: 10.1093/jpe/rtae084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jpe/rtae084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu T., Zhu H., Shutes B., He C. Gaseous carbon and nitrogen emissions from microbial fuel cell-constructed wetlands with different carbon sources: Microbiota-driven mechanisms. Journal of Cleaner Production. 2024;435</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nnadikwe, J., Akujuru, K., &amp; James, R.V. (2024). Exploring integrated biogas solutions for industrial processes: An advanced approach towards renewable energy. 10.20944/preprints202401.1803.v2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20944/preprints202401.1803.v2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble K., Huaccho Huatuco L., Van Dyke A.L., Green J.M.H. Springer Nature; 2024. The environmental impacts of cultured meat production: A systematic literature review; pp. 91&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-99-8159-5_8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolasco, I., Moummad, I., Stowell, D., &amp; Benetos, E. (2024). Acoustic identification of individual animals with hierarchical contrastive learning. 10.48550/arxiv.2409.08673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arxiv.2409.08673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nugrahaeningtyas E., Park K.H., Lee J. Greenhouse gas emissions from livestock: Sources, estimation, and mitigation. Journal of Animal Science and Technology. 2024 doi: 10.5187/jast.2024.e86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5187/jast.2024.e86</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11647415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39691613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obuseh E., Eyenubo O.J., Alele J., Okpare A., Oghogho I. A systematic review of barriers to renewable energy integration and adoption. Journal of Asian Energy Studies. 2025;9:26&#x2013;45. doi: 10.24112/jaes.090002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24112/jaes.090002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor S., Noonan F., Savage D., Walsh J. Advancements in real-time monitoring of enteric methane emissions from ruminants. Agriculture. 2024;14(7):1096. doi: 10.3390/agriculture14071096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture14071096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odongo E.E., Bbosa W.K., Kahunde P.K. Black soldier fly (BSF): A sustainable solution for protein, waste management, and a circular bio-economy. European Journal of Theoretical and Applied Sciences. 2024;2(3):822&#x2013;834. doi: 10.59324/ejtas.2024.2(3).64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.59324/ejtas.2024.2(3).64</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oghoghorie O., Erhinyodavwe O., Orhorhoro E.K. Anaerobic co-digestion of cow manure and food waste: An investigation of biogas yield from feedstock percentage variation. Discovery. 2024;60(336):1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.54905/disssi.v60i336.e24d1453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.54905/disssi.v60i336.e24d1453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogungbuyi M.G., Mohammed C., Fischer A., Turner D., Whitehead J.M., Harrison M.T. Integration of drone and satellite imagery improves agricultural management agility. Remote Sensing. 2024;16(24):4688. doi: 10.3390/rs16244688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs16244688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunniyan, O. (2024). Modeling and techno-economic optimization of microwave assisted ammonia synthesis processes. 10.33915/etd.12565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33915/etd.12565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okpara M., Ozuo U.K. Understanding the impact of diet, host genetics and early life interventions on rumen microbiome. Nigerian Journal of Animal Production. 2024:1847&#x2013;1850. doi: 10.51791/njap.vi.7354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.51791/njap.vi.7354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olorunlowu S., Sidoruk P., Sznajder J.I., Szczesny J., Lechniak D., Pawlak P., Ryczek M., Huang H., Li L., Irawan A., Komisarek J., Szumacher-Strabel M., Cie&#x15b;lak A. Effects of a multi-strain lactic and propionic acid bacteria inoculant on silage quality, methane emissions, milk composition, and rumen microbiome. Animals. 2025;15(18):2740. doi: 10.3390/ani15182740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani15182740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12466352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41007984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orner K.D., Cornejo P.K., Camacho D.R., Alvarez M., Alvarez M., Camacho-C&#xe9;spedes F. Improving life cycle economic and environmental sustainability of animal manure management in marginalized farming communities through resource recovery. Environmental Engineering Science. 2021;38(5):310&#x2013;319. doi: 10.1089/EES.2020.0262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/EES.2020.0262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8165466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34079204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osman A.I., Nasr M., Aniagor C.O., Farghali M., Huang M., Chin B.L.F., Sun Z., Lock S.S.M., L&#xf3;pez-Maldonado E.A., Yiin C.L., Chinyelu C.E., Farooqi A.S., Chen Z., Yap P. Synergistic technologies for a circular economy: Upcycling waste plastics and biomass. Frontiers of Chemical Science and Engineering. 2024;19(1) doi: 10.1007/s11705-024-2507-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11705-024-2507-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal M., Dass R., Nehra V. Viability assessment of solar photovoltaic systems for dairy cattle farms in India. Next Research. 2025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan T., Zhang X., Liao X., Wang D., Bayin D., Safarov M.S., Okhonniyozov M. Estimating aboveground biomass of grassland in central Asia mountainous areas using unmanned aerial vehicle vegetation indices and image textures&#x2013;&#x2013; A case study of typical grassland in Tajikistan. Environmental and Sustainability Indicators. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.indic.2024.100345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.indic.2024.100345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panchadi, A., Bastakoti, B., Raghava, P., &amp; Jha, P.K. (2024). Digital twins: A next-gen solution for agricultural sustainability. 10.1002/csan.21374..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/csan.21374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey A., Sharma Y.C. Advancements in biomass valorization in integrated biorefinery systems. Biofuels, Bioproducts and Biorefining. 2024 doi: 10.1002/bbb.2670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bbb.2670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pangesti R.T., Jayanegara A., Laconi E.B. Effects of level and type of essential oils on rumen methanogenesis and fermentation: A meta-analysis of in vitro experiments. Journal of Animal and Feed Sciences. 2024 doi: 10.22358/jafs/178215/2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22358/jafs/178215/2024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pankaj P.K., Prasad J.V.N.S., Singh V., Nirmala G., Reddy K.S. Elsevier BV; 2024. Climate resilient livestock farming systems; pp. 159&#x2013;178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-323-98385-3.00003-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park N., Kim M., Jung J., Ji S., Kim W. New strategy to maximize phosphorus utilization of sewage sludge incineration ash for struvite crystallization. Water. 2024;16(12):1682. doi: 10.3390/w16121682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w16121682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J.Y., Lee J.Y., Kim Y., Kim B.M., Kim B.K., Choi S. Biosafety characteristics and antibacterial activity of probiotic strains against Streptococcus mutans, Aggregatibacter actinomycetemcomitans, and Porphyromonas gingivalis. Annals of Microbiology. 2025;75(1) doi: 10.1186/s13213-024-01790-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13213-024-01790-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parmar, P., Bi, H., &amp; Neethirajan, S. (2024). Artificial intelligence driven benchmarking tool for emission reduction in Canadian dairy farms. 10.1101/2024.05.29.596461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2024.05.29.596461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parmentier F.W., Thornton B.F., Silyakova A., Christensen T.R. Vulnerability of Arctic-Boreal methane emissions to climate change. Frontiers in Environmental Science. 2024;12 doi: 10.3389/fenvs.2024.1460155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenvs.2024.1460155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parrillo A., Sa&#x144;chez G. Coproduction of silicon nitride &amp; oxynitride whiskers and precipitated silica from industrial rice husk ash. Sustainable Materials and Technologies. 2024;40 doi: 10.1016/j.susmat.2024.e00871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.susmat.2024.e00871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons I.L., Brennan J.R., Menendez H.M., Velasquez Moreno E.R., Huseman A., Dotts H. 456 Allocating distribution of pasture utilization across the grazing landscape in grazing steers equipped with virtual fencing collars. Journal of Animal Science. 2024;102(Supplement_3):319. doi: 10.1093/jas/skae234.363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skae234.363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pata, B.A., &amp; Patel, S. (2024). Optimizing livestock farm waste management: Effective strategies for efficiency and sustainability (pp. 138&#x2013;154). 10.58532/v3bcag21p2ch8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.58532/v3bcag21p2ch8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel, P. (2024). A way to gather valuable fertilizers from manure. 10.1021/cen-10201-leadcon.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/cen-10201-leadcon</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel, S., &amp; Pata, B.A. (2024). Implementing nutritional strategies to reduce methanogenesis in livestock (pp. 155&#x2013;164). 10.58532/v3bcag21p2ch9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.58532/v3bcag21p2ch9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patharkar A., Cai F., Al-Hindawi F., Wu T. Predictive modeling of biomedical temporal data in healthcare applications: Review and future directions. Frontiers in Physiology. 2024;15 doi: 10.3389/fphys.2024.1386760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2024.1386760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11519529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39473609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peddibhotla, U., Kumar, R., Sobin, C.C., Kumar, P., Javeed, D., &amp; Islam, A.K.M.N. (2024). Securing agricultural communications: Blockchain integration in UAV networks for smart farming. 1443&#x2013;1449. 10.1109/iccworkshops59551.2024.10615542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/iccworkshops59551.2024.10615542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedrini C.A., Machado F.S., Niehues M.B., Perdig&#xe3;o A., Carvalho V.V.V.D., Acedo T.S., Kindermann M., Tamassia L.M., Walker N., Gandra J. PSXIV-3 3-nitrooxypropanol dosages to reduce methane emission by feedlot beef cattle. Journal of Animal Science. 2023 doi: 10.1093/jas/skad281.652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skad281.652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedrini C.A., Machado F.S., Fernandes A.R.M., C&#xf4;nsolo N.R.B., Ocampos F.M.M., Colnago L.A., Perdig&#xe3;o A., Carvalho V.V.V.D., Acedo T.S., Tamassia L.M., Kindermann M., Gandra J. Performance, meat quality and meat metabolomics outcomes: Efficacy of 3-nitrooxypropanol in feedlot beef cattle diets. Animals. 2024;14 doi: 10.3390/ani14172576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani14172576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11394267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39272361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei S., Fan X., Qiu C., Liu N., Li F., Li J., Li Q., Wang S. Effect of biochar addition on the anaerobic digestion of food waste: Microbial community structure and methanogenic pathways. Water Science and Technology. 2024 doi: 10.2166/wst.2024.199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wst.2024.199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39141040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelaez-Samaniego M.R., Mood S.H., Cisneros J.F., Fajardo-Seminario J., Yadama V., Garcia-Perez T. Aqueous byproducts from biomass wet thermochemical processing: Valorization into fuels, chemicals, fertilizers, and biomaterials. Energy Conversion and Management. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2024.118360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2024.118360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelton R.E.O., Kazanski C.E., Keerthi S., Racette K., Gennet S., Springer N.P., Yacobson E., Wironen M., Ray D.K., Johnson K., Schmitt J. Greenhouse gas emissions in US beef production can be reduced by up to 30% with the adoption of selected mitigation measures. Nature Food. 2024;5(9):787&#x2013;797. doi: 10.1038/s43016-024-01031-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43016-024-01031-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11420059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39215094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pence I., Kuma&#x15f; K., Cesmeli M.S., Aky&#xfc;z A. Future prediction of biogas potential and CH4 emission with boosting algorithms: The case of cattle, small ruminant, and poultry manure from Turkey. Environmental Science and Pollution Research. 2024;31(16):24461&#x2013;24479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10998781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38441735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng C., Wang X., Xiong X., Wang Y. Assessing carbon emissions from animal husbandry in China: Trends, regional variations and mitigation strategies. Sustainability. 2024 doi: 10.3390/su16062283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su16062283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng H., Chen I.A., Qimron U. Engineering phages to fight multidrug-resistant bacteria. Chemical Reviews. 2024 doi: 10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11758799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39680919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pepeta B.N., Hassen A., Tesfamariam E.H. Quantifying the impact of different dietary rumen modulating strategies on enteric methane emission and productivity in ruminant livestock: A meta-analysis. Animals. 2024;14 doi: 10.3390/ani14050763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani14050763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10931330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38473148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Bernal, M.F., Magdalena, J.A., Trably, E., &amp; Bernet, N. (2024). Microbial electrochemical technologies: Coupling wastewater treatment with resource recovery (pp. 195&#x2013;213). 10.1007/978-3-031-54306-7_10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-031-54306-7_10</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perillo G. Digital and circular economy models. Journal of Civil Engineering and Environmental Sciences. 2024;10(2):061&#x2013;062. doi: 10.17352/2455-488x.000085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17352/2455-488x.000085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Place S.E. 8 Opportunities in enteric methane emissions mitigation in beef cattle. Journal of Animal Science. 2024;102(Supplement_1):41. doi: 10.1093/jas/skae019.047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skae019.047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Politi E., Purucker P., Larsen M., Dos Reis R.J., Rajan R.T., Penna S.D., Boer J.F., Rodosthenous P., Dimitrakopoulos G., Varlamis I., H&#xf6;&#xdf; A. Enabling technologies for the navigation and communication of UAS operating in the context of BVLOS. Electronics. 2024 doi: 10.3390/electronics13020340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics13020340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasetiyo D.H.T., Sanata A., Sholahuddin I., Nashrullah M.D., Nanlohy H.Y., Panithasan M.S. Comprehensive analysis of tar reduction method in biomass gasification for clean energy production: A review. Mechanical Engineering for Society and Industry. 2024;4(3):556&#x2013;569. doi: 10.31603/mesi.12712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31603/mesi.12712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premalatha, S., Rajapandian, B., Swathi, K., Ahisri, M., Rajeswari, N., &amp; Rupashri, K.R. (2024). Biogas monitoring system. 1&#x2013;4. 10.1109/icpects62210.2024.10780028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/icpects62210.2024.10780028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proskynitopoulou V., Garagounis I., Vourros A., Dimopoulos Toursidis P., Lorentzou S., Zouboulis A., Panopoulos K. Nutrient recovery from digestate: Pilot test experiments. Journal of Environmental Management. 2024;353 doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.120166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.120166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38280247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Przymus P., Rykaczewski K., Mart&#xed;n-Segura A., Truu J., Carrillo de Santa Pau E., Kolev M., Naskinova I., Gruca A., Sampri A., Frohme M., Nechyporenko A. Deep learning in microbiome analysis: A comprehensive review of neural network models. Frontiers in Microbiology. 2025;15 doi: 10.3389/fmicb.2024.1516667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2024.1516667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11794229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39911715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psarianos M., Baliota G.V., Rumbos C.I., Athanassiou C.G., Ojha S., Schl&#xfc;ter O. Elsevier BV; 2024. Insect processing for chitin production; pp. 129&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-323-95594-2.00014-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purdy P.H. Elsevier BV; 2024. Germplasm preservation for rare domestic animal breeds.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-443-21477-6.00024-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qadri Q.R., Lai X., Zhao W., Zhang Z., Zhao Q., Ma P., Pan Y., Wang Q. Exploring the interplay between the hologenome and complex traits in bovine and porcine animals using genome-wide association analysis. International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 2024;25(11):6234. doi: 10.3390/ijms25116234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms25116234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11172659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38892420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qazi, A.A., Razzaq, T., &amp; Iqbal, A. (2024). AnimalFormer: Multimodal vision framework for behavior-based precision livestock farming. 7973&#x2013;7982. 10.1109/cvprw63382.2024.00795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/cvprw63382.2024.00795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian H., Zhang Q., Alsenani T.R., Bouzgarrou S., Alturise F. Integration of biomass gasification and O2/H2 separation membranes for H2 production/separation with inherent CO2 capture: Techno-economic evaluation and artificial neural network based multi-objective optimization. Renewable Energy. 2024;224</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin C., Xu Y., Fu Y., Li R., Liu Q., Shi D. Multi-omics reveals the mechanism of rumen microbiome and its metabolome together with host metabolome participating in the regulation of milk production traits in dairy buffaloes. Frontiers in Microbiology. 2024;15 doi: 10.3389/fmicb.2024.1301292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2024.1301292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10959287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38525073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahic E., Kelly D., Karsten H.D., de Lima Casseres dos Santos L., Costello C. Integrating continuous cover, manure management, and anaerobic digestion strategies on a pennsylvania dairy farm: A life cycle assessment. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 2025;59(49):26514&#x2013;26525. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.5c04797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.5c04797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12713728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41324509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman M.A., Emon M.M.H., Khan T., Hamid A.B.A., Yaakub N.I. Advances in environmental engineering and green technologies book series. IGI Global Scientific Publishing; 2024. Eco-intelligence; pp. 31&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/979-8-3693-9879-1.ch002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramakrishna, S., &amp; Brindha, R. (2024). Life cycle assessment and tools (pp. 31&#x2013;64). 10.1007/978-981-97-0589-4_2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-97-0589-4_2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramasamy S., Pakshirajan K. Springer International Publishing; 2024. Metabolic engineering and synthetic biology in biohydrogen production; pp. 149&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-031-49818-3_7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rani N.U. Food spoilage detection monitoring and alerting system. International Journal for Science Technology and Engineering. 2024;12(12):1328&#x2013;1334. doi: 10.22214/ijraset.2024.66037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22214/ijraset.2024.66037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rani A., Pundir A., Verma M., Joshi S., Verma G., Andjelkovi&#x107; S., Babi&#x107; S., Milenkovi&#x107; J., Mitra D. Methanotrophy: A biological method to mitigate global methane emission. Microbiology Research. 2024;15(2):634&#x2013;654. doi: 10.3390/microbiolres15020042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microbiolres15020042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjan C., Srinivas J., Balaji P.S., Kumar K. Advances in environmental engineering and green technologies book series. IGI Global; 2025. Precision agriculture; pp. 175&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/979-8-3693-7483-2.ch007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao M.A., Javied S., Aslam A., Alamri S., Zaman Q.U., Hassan A., Noor N. Optimizing biogas production and digestive stability through waste co-digestion. Sustainability. 2024 doi: 10.3390/su16073045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su16073045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashidi N., Nurgali K., Apostolopoulos V., Davidson M. Elsevier BV; 2024. The application of nanoparticle-based delivery systems in vaccine development; pp. 243&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-443-18564-9.00001-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rastogi S., Sethi P., Pandey H.K., Panwar N., Yadav P., &#x41c;&#x430;&#x434;&#x430;&#x43d; &#x410;.&#x41a;. Advances in environmental engineering and green technologies book series. IGI Global; 2025. The role of robotics and automated systems in refining waste separation processes; pp. 441&#x2013;490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/979-8-3693-7282-1.ch019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawal S.B., Kaur H., Bhathan S., Mittal D., Kaur G., Ali S.A. Springer International Publishing; 2024. Ruminant gut microbiota: Interplay, implications, and innovations for sustainable livestock production; pp. 205&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-031-54372-2_7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recktenwald E.B., Ehrhardt R.A. Greenhouse gas emissions from a diversity of sheep production systems in the United States. Agricultural Systems. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.agsy.2024.103915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agsy.2024.103915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reehana, N., Mohamed Imran, M.Y., Fathima, T.S., &amp; Thajuddin, N. (2024). Bioremediation of wastewater employing microalgae. 145&#x2013;164. 10.1002/9783527843367.ch8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9783527843367.ch8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rend&#xf3;n-Correa M.E., Posada Ochoa S.L., Rosero Noguera R. Evaluaci&#xf3;n in vitro de una fuente de nitrato protegido para rumiantes: Efecto sobre la degradaci&#xf3;n de la materia seca y producci&#xf3;n de metano. Revista Mexicana de Ciencias Pecuarias. 2024;15(4):979&#x2013;990. doi: 10.22319/rmcp.v15i4.6402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22319/rmcp.v15i4.6402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rengarajan H.J., Detchanamurthy S., Panneerselvan L., Palanisami T. Current and future perspectives of a microalgae based circular bioeconomy to manage industrial wastewater&#x2013;A systematic review. Physiologia Plantarum. 2024 doi: 10.1111/ppl.14184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ppl.14184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resetarits H.M., Dishon G., Agarwal V., Smith J.E. The effects of temperature and CO2 enrichment on the red seaweed Asparagopsis taxiformis from Southern California with implications for aquaculture. Journal of Phycology. 2024 doi: 10.1111/jpy.13526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jpy.13526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11670279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39616619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riau V., Morey L., C&#xe1;ceres R., Cerrillo M., Bonmat&#xed; Blasi A., Robles &#xc1;. Burleigh Dodds Science Publishing Limited; 2024. Optimizing livestock manure as a biofertilizer and bioenergy source; pp. 141&#x2013;178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19103/as.2023.0120.11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricci S., Petri R.M., Pac&#xed;fico C., Castillo-Lopez E., Rivera-Chacon R., Sener-Aydemir A., Reisinger N.N.N., Zebeli Q., Kreuzer-Redmer S. Characterization of presence and activity of microRNAs in the rumen of cattle hints at possible host-microbiota cross-talk mechanism. Scientific Reports. 2022;12(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9378797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35970850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera-Orellana, S., Yeager, J., Tejera, E., &amp; L&#xf3;pez-Cort&#xe9;s, A. (2024). NeoPhAR: Next-generation phage therapy for antimicrobial resistance. 10.1101/2024.12.27.630320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2024.12.27.630320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues B., Fox W.E., Dudak J., Winkler T., McCoy C., Tolleson D.R. PSXII-14 Fecal near infrared reflectance spectroscopy for indirect prediction of methane emissions from grazing cattle. Journal of Animal Science. 2024;102(Supplement_3):728&#x2013;729. doi: 10.1093/jas/skae234.820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skae234.820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romantseva Y.N., Bodur A. Digital solutions for calculating carbon footprint in agriculture. &#xc8;konomika i Upravlenie: Problemy, Re&#x161;eni&#xe2;. 2024;11/15(152):150&#x2013;159. doi: 10.36871/ek.up.p.r.2024.11.15.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36871/ek.up.p.r.2024.11.15.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roskam E., Kenny D.A., Kelly A.K., Hayes M., Palevich N., Maclean P.H., O'Flaherty V., Biswas A., Waters S.M. Effects of dietary supplementation with linseed oil, Ascophyllum nodosum or treated A. nodosum on animal performance, gaseous emissions, ruminal fermentation and microbiota, and meat quality in growing dairy-beef bulls. Journal of Animal Science. 2025;103:skaf032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11956689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39913259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi C.A.S., Grossi S., Dell&#x2019;Anno M., Compiani R., Rossi L. Effect of a blend of essential oils, bioflavonoids and tannins on in vitro methane production and in vivo production efficiency in dairy cows. Animals. 2022;12(6):728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8944839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35327125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rousset C., Segura C., Gilgen A., Alfaro M., Mendes L.A., Dodd M., Dashpurev B., Bastidas M., Rivera J.E., Merbold L., V&#xe1;zquez E. What evidence exists relating the impact of different grassland management practices to soil carbon in livestock systems? A systematic map protocol. Environmental Evidence. 2024;13(1) doi: 10.1186/s13750-024-00345-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13750-024-00345-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11344701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39188311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy A. Green monetary policy to combat climate change: Theory and evidence of selective credit control. The Journal of Climate Finance. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.jclimf.2024.100035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclimf.2024.100035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusanowska P., Zieli&#x144;ski M., Kisielewska M., Dudek M., Paukszto &#x141;., D&#x119;bowski M. Methane production, microbial community, and volatile fatty acids profiling during anaerobic digestion under different organic loading. Energies. 2025;18(3):575. doi: 10.3390/en18030575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en18030575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo R.O. Mitigating methane emissions from husbandry: A brief review. International Journal of Life Science and Agriculture Research. 2024;03(06) doi: 10.55677/ijlsar/v03i6y2024-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55677/ijlsar/v03i6y2024-11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan C.V., Pabiou T., Purfield D.C., Berry D.P., Conroy S.B., Murphy C.P., Evans R.D. Exploring definitions of daily enteric methane emission phenotypes for genetic evaluations using a population of indoor-fed multi-breed growing cattle with feed intake data. Journal of Animal Science. 2024 doi: 10.1093/jas/skae034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skae034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10889735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38323901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan C.V., Pabiou T., Purfield D.C., Kelly D.N., Murphy C.P., Evans R.D. Genetic correlations between enteric methane and traits of economic importance in a beef finishing system. Journal of Animal Science. 2025;103:skaf162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12132798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40355361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryu Y., Yang H., Ko K.H., Kim G. Effects of low-methane functional feed on parity-specific milk productivity and quality traits in dairy cows. Food and Life. 2025 doi: 10.5851/fl.2500023. (Online)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5851/fl.2500023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabaria S. Harnessing machine learning for metagenomics: Discovering the invisible microbial world. Communications on Applied Nonlinear Analysis. 2024 doi: 10.52783/cana.v31.1462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52783/cana.v31.1462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabia E., Pacelli C., Di Trana A., Coppola A., Cosentino C., Freschi P., Paolino R.&#x2026;Braghieri A. Carbon neutrality and beef production in the marginal areas: A case study of Podolian cattle system. Agricultural Systems. 2025;230 doi: 10.1016/j.agsy.2025.104451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agsy.2025.104451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safour, R.A. (2024). Electrochemical nitrogen reduction: Towards efficient ammonia production. 2024, 1&#x2013;3. 10.70470/khwarizmia/2024/001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70470/khwarizmia/2024/001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saidova M., Namozov N., Tursinbaev M., Teshabaev B., Kuchimova M. Methods of increasing the productivity of desert pasture soils. E3S Web of Conferences. 2024;563 doi: 10.1051/e3sconf/202456303041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/e3sconf/202456303041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salaria, A., &amp; Rakhra, M. (2024). Analysis on future of farming: Smart energy systems in agriculture. 1&#x2013;5. 10.1109/icrito61523.2024.10522415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/icrito61523.2024.10522415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salhein, K., Alghennai Salheen, S., Annekaa, A.M., Hawsawi, M., Alhawsawi, E.Y., Kobus, C.J., &amp; Zohdy, M. (2024). A comprehensive review of geothermal heat pump systems. 10.20944/preprints202411.1699.v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20944/preprints202411.1699.v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salim R. Enhancing microalgal biomass and chemical composition for sustainable wastewater treatment. International Innovations Journal of Applied Science. 2024;1(spc) doi: 10.61856/kzb87p57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.61856/kzb87p57</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salleh M.Z., Nasir M., Bohari Z.H., Sulaima M.F., Ahmad E.Z., Baharom M.F., Soh P.J. Integrating micro-hydro and solar pv in rainwater harvesting: A hybrid generation approach. Journal of Advanced Research in Fluid Mechanics and Thermal Sciences. 2024;121(2):106&#x2013;131. doi: 10.37934/arfmts.121.2.106131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37934/arfmts.121.2.106131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samad H.A., Kumar Eshwaran V., Muquit S.P., Sharma L., Arumugam H., Kant L., Fatima, Z., Sharun, K., Aradotlu Parameshwarappa, M., Latheef, S.K., Chouhan, V.S., Maurya, V.P., Singh, G, Kaniyamattam K. Sustainable livestock solutions: Addressing carbon footprint challenges from Indian and global perspectives. Sustainability. 2025;17(5):2105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samoraj M., &#xc7;al&#x131;&#x15f; D., Trzaska K., Mironiuk M., Chojnacka K. Advancements in algal biorefineries for sustainable agriculture: Biofuels, high-value products, and environmental solutions. Biocatalysis and Agricultural Biotechnology. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.bcab.2024.103224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bcab.2024.103224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Hern&#xe1;ndez J.C., Megharaj M. Insect farming: A bioeconomy-based opportunity to revalorize plastic wastes. Environmental Science &amp; Ecotechnology. 2024;23 doi: 10.1016/j.ese.2024.100521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ese.2024.100521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11758129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39867963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sant&#x2019;Anna G.S.L., de Carvalho L.A.L., da Silva M.S.R.D.A., Gon&#xe7;alves J.V.D.S., Pinheiro D.G., Zonta E., Coelho I.D.S. Short-Term effects of poultry litter and cattle manure on soil&#x2019;s chemical properties and bacterial community. Agronomy. 2024;14(7):1382. doi: 10.3390/agronomy14071382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy14071382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos W.M.D., Martins L.D.C.D.S., Bezerra A.C., Ferraz Jardim A.M.R., Silva M.V.D., Souza C.A.A.D. Use of unmanned aerial vehicles for monitoring pastures and forages in agricultural sciences: A systematic review. Drones. 2024 doi: 10.3390/drones8100585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones8100585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sara G., Pinna D., Todde G., Caria M. Augmented reality glasses applied to livestock farming: Potentials and perspectives. AgriEngineering. 2024;6(2):1859&#x2013;1869. doi: 10.3390/agriengineering6020108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriengineering6020108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravanan T.S., Shnain A.H., Sharma H., Naveena S.S., Rajurkar A., Sherje N., Nathan S.R. Hydrogen production via electrolyzers: Enhancing efficiency and reducing costs. E3S Web of Conferences. 2024;591 doi: 10.1051/e3sconf/202459106003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/e3sconf/202459106003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraswathi, P., Prabha, M., Dhiyanesh, B., Akchay Kumar, R., Ahamed, J., &amp; Ismail, M. (2024). IoT-powered solution for proactive air quality management. 13, 754&#x2013;758. 10.1109/icipcn63822.2024.00130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/icipcn63822.2024.00130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seidu, I., Salisu, S., Mas&#x2019;ud, A.A., Musa, U., Jabire, A.H., Muhammad-Sukki, F., &amp; Masud, I.A. (2024). An overview of current optimization approaches for hybrid energy systems combining solar photovoltaic and wind technologies. 10.22541/au.173251808.85610527/v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22541/au.173251808.85610527/v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah P.B., Gurumurthy J., Segaran G., Sathiavelu M. Elsevier BV; 2024. Anaerobic fermentation for biogas production; pp. 165&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-323-95076-3.00013-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahzad M.A., Asim Z., Khan S.J., Almomani F., Mahmoud K.A., Mustafa M.R.U., Rasool K. Thermochemical and biochemical conversion of agricultural waste for bioenergy production: An updated review. Discover Environment. 2024;2(1) doi: 10.1007/s44274-024-00171-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44274-024-00171-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shams A., Fischer A., Bodnar A., Kliegman M. Perspectives on genetically engineered microorganisms and their regulation in the United States. ACS Synthetic Biology. 2024 doi: 10.1021/acssynbio.4c00048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssynbio.4c00048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11106772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38669097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanmugha Mary A., Patil M., Kundu G., Rajaram K. Machine learning mediated advanced phage and antimicrobial therapy&#x2013;A futuristic approach. Highlights in BioScience. 2023 doi: 10.36462/h.biosci.202304. (Online)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36462/h.biosci.202304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A., Chhabra V. A review on the applications of biochar in agricultural farms: A low carbon emission technology. Journal of Advances in Biology &amp; Biotechnology. 2024;27(7):480&#x2013;492. doi: 10.9734/jabb/2024/v27i71009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/jabb/2024/v27i71009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheriff, I.M.M., &amp; Aravindhar, D.J. (2024). Integrated blockchain-based agri-food traceability and deep learning for profit-optimized supply chain management in agri-food supply chains. 1&#x2013;6. 10.1109/icaect60202.2024.10469024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/icaect60202.2024.10469024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi K., Feng S., Zhao L., Chen J., Song W., Jia Y., Qu X., Liu Z., Jia W., Du S., Liao M. N-glycosylation on hemagglutinin head reveals inter-branch antigenic variability of avian influenza virus H5-subtypes. International Journal of Biological Macromolecules. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.132901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.132901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38848854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi R., Wang Y., van Middelaar C.E., Ducro B., Oosting S.J., Hou Y., Wang Y., van der Linden A. Balancing farm profit and greenhouse gas emissions along the dairy production chain through breeding indices. Journal of Cleaner Production. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y., Shi Y., Niu H., Liu J., Sun P. Structure optimization and data processing method of electronic nose bionic chamber for detecting ammonia emissions from livestock excrement fermentation. Sensors. 2024;24(5):1628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10934082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38475164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoyombo, A.J., Popoola, M.A., Kuusu, D.J., Yisah, L.J., Adebayo, O.M., Yakubu, H., Ndiomu, E.P., &amp; Moses, A.A. (2024). Computational approaches in livestock breeding: A review. 1&#x2013;5. 10.1109/seb4sdg60871.2024.10630145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/seb4sdg60871.2024.10630145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shpirer J., Livshits L., Kamer H.A., Alon T., Portnik Y., Moallem U. Effects of the palmitic to oleic ratio in the form of calcium salts of fatty acids on the production and digestibility in high-yielding dairy cows. Journal of Dairy Science. 2024 doi: 10.3168/jds.2023-24382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2023-24382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38754825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shukla S., Abiha U., Bhutani R., Kapoor N., Shukla S.K. Microbial biocontrol techniques: Importance in ensuring food security. Springer Nature Singapore; Singapore: 2025. Blockchain technology for environmental conservation; pp. 323&#x2013;362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shulzhyk, Y., Soltysik, O., Danyliuk, M., &amp; Oslikovsky, V.V. (2024). Application of immersive technologies in the agricultural sector. 216&#x2013;228. 10.69635/978-1-0690482-1-9-ch29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.69635/978-1-0690482-1-9-ch29</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sikiru A.B., Makinde O.J., Koura B., Acheneje S.S.E., Alabi J.O., Shipandeni M.N.T., Akinsola O.M. Bibliometric mapping of academic research focusing on animal production and climate change in association with methane emissions and animal productivity. Ruminants. 2024 doi: 10.3390/ruminants4010010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ruminants4010010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva T.H., Amancio B.R., Magnani E., Meurer G.W., Reolon H.G., Timm T.G., Cappellozza B.I., Branco R.H., Paula E.M. Evaluation of direct-fed microbials on in vitro ruminal fermentation, gas production kinetic, and greenhouse gas emissions in different ruminants&#x2019; diet. Frontiers in Animal Science. 2024 doi: 10.3389/fanim.2024.1320075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fanim.2024.1320075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva I., Lapa N., Ribeiro H., Duarte E. Pig slurry anaerobic digestion: The role of biochar as an additive towards biogas and digestate improvement. Applied Sciences. 2025;15(3):1037. doi: 10.3390/app15031037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app15031037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A., Aiman Bin Abu Sofian A.D., Chan Y.J., Chakrabarty A., Selvarajoo A., Abakr Y.A., Show P.L. Hydrothermal carbonization: Sustainable pathways for waste-to-energy conversion and biocoal production. GCB Bioenergy. 2024 doi: 10.1111/gcbb.13150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gcbb.13150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh P., Dogra P., Kalamdhad A.S. Sugarcane bagasse and cow dung pelletization in varied food-to-microorganism ratios for biogas generation. Industrial Crops and Products. 2024;210</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh N., Chandrakar P., M.T M., Taye T., Singh I.P., Singh V.P., Bara S., Vithalrao U.S. Environmental impact and mitigation approaches in livestock production systems: A review. Archives of Current Research International. 2025;25(8):351&#x2013;364. doi: 10.9734/acri/2025/v25i81423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/acri/2025/v25i81423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirilakshmi Y., Gogoi B.P., Ashwini T., Dkhara D. A review on carbon foot printing in sustainable agriculture as a cutting-edge approach to environmental responsibility. International Journal of Enviornment and Climate Change. 2024;14(10):261&#x2013;269. doi: 10.9734/ijecc/2024/v14i104485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/ijecc/2024/v14i104485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitaraman S. AI-driven diagnostics and imaging: Transforming early detection and precision in healthcare. International Journal of Scientific Research in Computer Science, Engineering and Information Technology. 2024;10(6):1258&#x2013;1267. doi: 10.32628/cseit241061167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32628/cseit241061167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siyanbola, K.F., Ejiohuo, O., Ade-adekunle, O.A., Adekunle, F.O., Onyeaka, H., Furr, C.L.L., Hodges, F.E., Carvalho, P., &amp; Oladipo, E.K. (2024). Bacteriophages: Sustainable and effective solution for climate-resilient agriculture. 10.1093/sumbio/qvae025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sumbio/qvae025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slimani H., El Mhamdi J., Jilbab A. Real-time greenhouse management using IoT, digital twin, and augmented reality for optimal control and decision-making. Acta IMEKO. 2025;14(2):1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sniatala B., Al-Hazmi H., Sobotka D., Zhai J., M&#x105;kinia J. Advancing sustainable wastewater management: A comprehensive review of nutrient recovery products and their applications. Science of the Total Environment. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.173446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.173446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38788940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solona O., Lisovyi D. Prediction and monitoring of animal health using artificial intelligence. V&#xec;brac&#xec;&#xef; v Tehn&#xec;c&#xec; Ta Tehnolog&#xec;&#xe2;h. 2024;2(113):33&#x2013;42. doi: 10.37128/2306-8744-2024-2-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37128/2306-8744-2024-2-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza S.V., de Oliveira J.D., Gimenes R.M.T., Orrico A.C.A., J&#xfa;nior M.F.B. Eco-efficiency of rural biodigesters: Mono- and co-digestion of agricultural waste. AgriEngineering. 2025;7(9):311. doi: 10.3390/agriengineering7090311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriengineering7090311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xf8;ckler A.H., Kamp J.N., Feilberg A., Dalby F., Hafner S.D., Pedersen J. Greenhouse gas emissions from storage of untreated pig slurry, digestate and the corresponding liquid fractions after solid-liquid separation. Journal of Environmental Management. 2025;390</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40580859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su J., Tan B.E., Jiang Z., Wu D., Nyachoti C.M., Kim S.W., Yin Y.&#x2026;Wang J. Accelerating precision feeding with the internet of things for livestock: From concept to implementation. Science Bulletin. 2024;69(14):2156&#x2013;2160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38538461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A. Emerging roles of bacteriophage-based therapeutics in combating antibiotic resistance. Frontiers in Microbiology. 2024;15 doi: 10.3389/fmicb.2024.1384164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2024.1384164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11257900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39035437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian K., Suresh K. Anaerobes and waste conversion technologies. Springer Nature Singapore; Singapore: 2024. Metabolic and biochemical pathways for anaerobic digestion; pp. 3&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suganthi, R.U. (2024). Phytogenic alternatives to antibiotics for broiler chicken meat production (pp. 208&#x2013;216). 10.58532/v3bcag23ch16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.58532/v3bcag23ch16</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumathi Y., Dong C.D., Singhania R.R., Chen C., Gurunathan B., Patel A.K. Advancements in nano-enhanced microalgae bioprocessing. Bioresource Technology. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.biortech.2024.130749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2024.130749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38679239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Supraja K.V., Kachroo H., Viswanathan G., Verma V., Behera B., Doddapaneni T.R.K.C., Kaushal P.J., Ahammad S.Z., Singh V., Awasthi M.K., Jain R. Biochar production and its environmental applications: Recent developments and machine learning insights. Bioresource Technology. 2023 doi: 10.1016/j.biortech.2023.129634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2023.129634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37573981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Susanto, I., Rahmadani, M., Pangesti, R.T., Wiryawan, K.G., Laconi, E.B., &amp; Jayanegara, A. (2024). Effects of various plant-based condensed tannin on rumen microbiome population: A meta-analysis. 1341, 012061. 10.1088/1755-1315/1341/1/012061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1755-1315/1341/1/012061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swami, S., Suthar, S., Addula, S.R., Saini, V.K., &amp; Lande, A. (2024). IoT-based smart solution for biogas plant operation. 1&#x2013;5. 10.1109/icsd60021.2024.10751324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/icsd60021.2024.10751324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinfield, T., Shrikanth, S., Bull, J.W., Madhavapeddy, A., &amp; zu Ermgassen, S. (2024). Nature-based credit markets at a crossroads. 10.33774/coe-2023-pl9xv-v3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33774/coe-2023-pl9xv-v3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Symeon G., Akamati K., Dotas V., Karatosidi D., Bizelis I., Laliotis G.P. Manure management as a potential mitigation tool to eliminate greenhouse gas emissions in livestock systems. Sustainability. 2025;17(2):586. doi: 10.3390/su17020586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su17020586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahmid, M., Choi, H., Ganapavarapu, S.T., Scott, J.K., &amp; Hatzell, M.C. (2024). Concentrating nitrogen waste with electrodialysis for fertilizer production. 10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-p6rkv.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-p6rkv</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11636197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39678708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka K., Collins S., Polkoff K., Fellner V. Inhibiting methanogenesis by targeting thermodynamics and enzymatic reactions in mixed cultures of rumen microbes in vitro. Frontiers in Microbiology. 2024;15 doi: 10.3389/fmicb.2024.1322207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2024.1322207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11349738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39206376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang S., Huang S., Si B., Wang Z., Lu H., Jiang W., Zhang Y. Interspecies electron transfer regulation in a stage-separated anaerobic digestion system: The role of inoculum strategies, activated carbon integration, and organic loading rate adjustment. Chemical Engineering Journal. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.152206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.152206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarafdar, A., Sirohi, R., &amp; Singh, U. (2025). Thermo-chemical processes for food waste treatment. 40&#x2013;48. 10.1201/9781032706030-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1201/9781032706030-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taye T., Vithalrao U.S., Borah S., Kumar M., Singh A.K., M.T M., Kanwar B.P.S., Chincholikar M. Scientific advances in climate-resilient livestock production with emphasis on sustainability: A review. Journal of Experimental Agriculture International. 2025;47(8):744&#x2013;757. doi: 10.9734/jeai/2025/v47i83716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/jeai/2025/v47i83716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tereshkov M., Dontsova T., Saruhan B., Kr&#xfc;ger S. Metal oxide-based sensors for ecological monitoring: Progress and perspectives. Chemosensors. 2024 doi: 10.3390/chemosensors12030042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/chemosensors12030042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur S., Das B., Das S. Elsevier BV; 2024. Microbial electrosynthesis of fatty acids and industrial chemicals through carbon sequestration; pp. 279&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-443-18820-6.00014-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorsteinsson M., Sch&#xf6;nherz A.A., Noel S.J., Cai Z., Niu Z., Hellwing A.L.F., Lund P., Weisbjerg M.R.&#x2026;Nielsen M.O. A preliminary study on the effects of red Bonnemaisonia hamifera seaweed on methane emissions from dairy cows. JDS Communications. 2025;6(2):217&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12094049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40405999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thote, D., Lanjewar, V., Sharma, V., Agrawal, P., &amp; Soni, V.K. (2024). IoT and machine learning-based smart soil irrigation farming systems. 1&#x2013;6. 10.1109/sceecs61402.2024.10482246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/sceecs61402.2024.10482246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiong Y.W., Tian H., Sharma P., Yan M., Lam H.T., Lee J.T.E., Zhang J., Tong Y.W. Enhancing food waste anaerobic digestion efficiency with biochar as a sustainable technology in decentralized real-world systems. ACS ES&amp;T Engineering. 2024 doi: 10.1021/acsestengg.4c00575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsestengg.4c00575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipan-Torres, C. (2024). Evaluaci&#xf3;n del impacto ambiental de los sistemas intensivos de producci&#xf3;n animal seg&#xfa;n la literatura reciente. 2(4), 40&#x2013;54. 10.70881/mcj/v2/n4/5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70881/mcj/v2/n4/5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toda M., Peixoto L., S&#xf8;rensen H., Tariq A., Br&#xe6;ndholt A., Hansen L.V., Abalos, D., Ntinyari, W., Pullens, J.W.M., Bruun, S., Jensen, L.S., Olesen, J.E&#x2026;Petersen S.O. Site-specific effects of nitrification inhibitors on N2O emissions from manure and urea ammonium nitrate. Agriculture, Ecosystems &amp; Environment. 2026;396</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tort R., Bagger A., Westhead O., Kondo Y., Khobnya A., Winiwarter A., Davies B.J.V., Katayama Y., Yamada Y., Ryan M.P., Titirici M., Stephens I.E.L. Nitrogen reduction to ammonia: Drawing a path toward energy efficiency. Meeting Abstracts. 2024;MA2024-01(39):2312. doi: 10.1149/ma2024-01392312mtgabs.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1149/ma2024-01392312mtgabs</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathy S., Rawat A., Lenka M.R., Swain A.R. Proceedings of the 2025 international conference on emerging systems and intelligent computing (ESIC) IEEE; 2025. Towards a sustainable future: Blockchain in carbon emission tracking and reduction; pp. 338&#x2013;343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truong N.H., Kim J., Lim J., Shin H. Electrochemical reduction of nitrate to Ammonia: Recent progress and future directions. Chemical Engineering Journal. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.153108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.153108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseten T., Sanjorjo R.A., Son J.W., Baik K.S., Berdos J.I., Kim S.H., Yoon, S. H., Kang, M. K., Kwon, M., Lee, S. S&#x2026;Kim S.W. Reduction of enteric methane emission using methanotroph-based probiotics in Hanwoo steers. Animal Microbiome. 2025;7(1):19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11846464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39987198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsui L., Halley S., Garz&#xf3;n F.H., Smith J.A., Ian R., Agi K. A combined mixed potential sensor, machine learning, and Iot platform for methane emissions detection and flare monitoring. Meeting Abstracts. 2024;MA2024-02(65):4356. doi: 10.1149/ma2024-02654356mtgabs.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1149/ma2024-02654356mtgabs</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ugwu O.P., Alum E.U., Okon M.B., Obeagu E.I. Mechanisms of microbiota modulation: Implications for health, disease, and therapeutic interventions. Medicine. 2024:103. doi: 10.1097/md.0000000000038088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/md.0000000000038088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11081615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38728472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ugwuanyi E.D., Nwokediegwu Z.Q.S., Dada M.A., Majemite M.T., Obaigbena A. The role of algae-based wastewater treatment systems: A comprehensive review. World Journal of Advanced Research and Reviews. 2024 doi: 10.30574/wjarr.2024.21.2.0521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30574/wjarr.2024.21.2.0521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ungerfeld E., Pitta D. Review: Biological consequences of the inhibition of rumen methanogenesis. Animal. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.animal.2024.101170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.animal.2024.101170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38772773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vadlamudi D.P., Pecchi M., Sudibyo H., Tester J.W. Direct and two-stage hydrothermal liquefaction of chicken manure: Impact of reaction parameters on biocrude oil upgradation. ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. 2024;12(10):4300&#x2013;4313. doi: 10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c08579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c08579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vakulchuk, R., &amp; Overland, I. (2024). The failure to decarbonize the global energy education system: Carbon lock-in and stranded skill sets. 10.1016/j.erss.2024.103446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.erss.2024.103446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valiveti C.K., Rajput M., Thakur N., Momin T., Bhowmik M., Tummala H. A polysaccharide-based oral-vaccine delivery system and adjuvant for the influenza virus vaccine. Vaccines. 2024 doi: 10.3390/vaccines12101121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vaccines12101121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11511251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39460287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valverde-Orozco, V., Gavilanes-Ter&#xe1;n, I., Idrovo-Novillo, J., Romero, S., Valverde-Quiroz, D., Idrovo-Gavilanes, J., &amp; Paredes, C. (2024). Approach to the circular economy through agro-livestock waste composting with heat recovery and agricultural use of the resulting compost. 10.2139/ssrn.4807506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.4807506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Gucht T., Peiren N., Kindermann M., Rijnders D., Ampe B., Vandaele L. Effect of 3-nitrooxypropanol supplementation combined with 6-hour grazing on enteric methane emissions and milk production characteristics. Journal of Dairy Science. 2025;108(11):12148&#x2013;12163. doi: 10.3168/JDS.2025-26603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/JDS.2025-26603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40752612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Gastelen S., Burgers E.E.A., Dijkstra J., de Mol R., Muizelaar W., Walker N., Bannink A. Long-term effects of 3-nitrooxypropanol on methane emission and milk production characteristics in Holstein Friesian dairy cows. Journal of Dairy Science. 2024 doi: 10.3168/jds.2023-24198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2023-24198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38395398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Lingen H.J., Fadel J.G., Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Ruiz D.R., Kindermann M., Kebreab E. Inhibited methanogenesis in the rumen of cattle: Microbial metabolism in response to supplemental 3-nitrooxypropanol and nitrate. Frontiers in Microbiology. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8353594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34385990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Mullem J., Van Wesemael D., Ampe B., Fievez V., Vandaele L., Peiren N. Methane mitigation in practically applicable dairy diets: Impact of diet composition and extruded linseed. Livestock Science. 2025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verhaagh M. Comparison of the competitiveness for Danish, Dutch, and German Piglet producers under consideration of country-specific methods of piglet castration with anesthesia. Agriculture. 2024;14(11):1943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma, A., &amp; Goswami, P. (2024). Integration of solar energy in agriculture leads to green energy and golden crop production. 10.53555/kuey.v30i7.6626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.53555/kuey.v30i7.6626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viaene, J. (2024). Application of biochar to anaerobic digestion versus digestate: Effects on N emissions and C stability. 10.5281/zenodo.10461739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5281/zenodo.10461739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38232844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vignesh, B., Chandrakumar, M., Divya, K., Mockaisamy, P., &amp; Vanitha, G. (2024). Blockchain technology in agriculture: Ensuring transparency and traceability in the food supply chain. 10.20944/preprints202409.1443.v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20944/preprints202409.1443.v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VijayKumar R., Tiwari P., Daniel S., Kumar K.R., Mishra I., Aneesh K.S., Shah D.G. Agroforestry systems: A pathway to resilient and productive landscapes. International Journal of Enviornment and Climate Change. 2024;14(12):177&#x2013;193. doi: 10.9734/ijecc/2024/v14i124617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/ijecc/2024/v14i124617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vingerhoets, R. (2024). Circular nutrient management in livestock-dense regions: Insights from substance flows and cost-benefit analysis. 10.63028/10067/2091140151162165141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.63028/10067/2091140151162165141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinyard J.R., Johnson M.L., Salas-Solis G., Vicente A.S., Siregar M., Sarmikasoglou E., Hammond, C., Alves, K. S., Ma, S. W., Girardin, L., Kelln, B., Dreger, R., Arce-Cordero, J. A&#x2026;Faciola A.P. Effects of a flaxseed and pea matrix on in vitro ruminal fermentation, nutrient degradability, and methane emissions. Journal of Dairy Science. 2025;108(6):5754&#x2013;5764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40221041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlaicu P.A., Gras M.A., Untea A.E., Lefter N.A., Rotar M.C. Advancing livestock technology: Intelligent systemization for enhanced productivity, welfare, and sustainability. AgriEngineering. 2024;6(2):1479&#x2013;1496. doi: 10.3390/agriengineering6020084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriengineering6020084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanapat M., Prachumchai R., Dagaew G., Matra M., Phupaboon S., Sommai S., Suriyapha C. Potential use of seaweed as a dietary supplement to mitigate enteric methane emission in ruminants. Science of the Total Environment. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.173015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.173015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38710388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K., Du C., Guo X., Xiong B., Yang L., Zhao X. Crop byproducts supplemented in livestock feeds reduced greenhouse gas emissions. Journal of Environmental Management. 2024;355 doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.120469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.120469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38432010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W., Wei Z., Li Z., Ren J., Song Y.J., Xu J., Liu A., Li X., Ma W., Fan H., Jin L., Niyazbekova Z., Wang W., Gao Y., Jiang Y., Yao J., Li F., Wu S., Wang Y. Integrating genome- and transcriptome-wide association studies to uncover the host&#x2013;microbiome interactions in bovine rumen methanogenesis. iMeta. 2024;3(5) doi: 10.1002/imt2.234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/imt2.234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11487568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39429883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R., Yang K., Wong C., Aguirre-Villegas H., Larson R., Brushett F., Qin M., Jin S. Electrochemical ammonia recovery and co-production of chemicals from manure wastewater. Nature Sustainability. 2024;7(2):179&#x2013;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waters, S.M., Roskam, E., Smith, P.E., Kenny, D.A., Popova, M., Eug&#xe8;ne, M., &amp; Morgavi, D.P. (2024). The role of rumen microbiome in the development of methane mitigation strategies for ruminant livestock. 10.3168/jds.2024-25778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2024-25778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39890073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson C.A., Topp C.F.E., Mead A., Fraser F., Fernandez-Huarte M., Horne J., Paton, G.I., Hallett, P.D., Norton, G., Graham, R.I&#x2026;Walker R.L. Future proofing a long-term agricultural experiment for decades to come: Relocation and redesign. European Journal of Agronomy. 2024;158</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Week, B., Ralph, P.L., Tavalire, H.F., Cresko, W.A., &amp; Bohannan, B.J.M. (2024). Quantitative genetics of microbiome mediated traits. 10.1101/2024.12.16.628599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2024.12.16.628599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12620654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40880099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittig S., Berchet A., Pison I., Saunois M., Thanwerdas J., Martinez A., Paris, J.-D., Machida, T., Sasakawa, M., Worthy, D.E.J., Lan, X., Thompson, R.L., Sollum, E&#x2026;Arshinov M. Estimating methane emissions in the Arctic nations using surface observations from 2008 to 2019. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics. 2023;23(11):6457&#x2013;6485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wodrich, M.D., Hall, S.J., &amp; Zhu-Barker, X. (2026). Acidification and nitrification inhibition of manure alters greenhouse gas emissions and nitrogen cycling in diverse agricultural soils (Vol. 55, No. 1, p. e70123)..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12703222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41392608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wongsirichot P. Development and future potential of Computation Fluid Dynamics for improved biomass hydrolysis. Chemical Engineering Journal. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.149032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.149032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worku D. Unraveling the genetic basis of methane emission in dairy cattle: A comprehensive exploration and breeding approach to lower methane emissions. Animal Biotechnology. 2024;35(1) doi: 10.1080/10495398.2024.2362677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10495398.2024.2362677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12674316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38860914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wrzeci&#x144;ska M., Czerniawska-Pi&#x105;tkowska E., Mylostyvyi R., &#x427;&#x435;&#x440;&#x43d;&#x435;&#x43d;&#x43a;&#x43e; &#x41e;.&#x41c;., Ara&#xfa;jo J.P., Kowalczyk A., Kowalewska-&#x141;uczak I., G&#x105;czarzewicz D., Stefaniak W., Rzewucka-W&#xf3;jcik E. Selection indexes in terms of functional features in modern dairy cattle breeding in Europe. The Journal of Agricultural Science. 2024:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1017/s0021859624000388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/s0021859624000388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S., Liang Z., Zhang J., Lei X., Bai H., Liang G., Chen X., Wang P.T., Wang Y., Guan L., Yao J. Multi-omics reveal mechanisms of high enteral starch diet mediated colonic dysbiosis via microbiome-host interactions in young ruminant. Microbiome. 2024;12 doi: 10.1186/s40168-024-01760-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40168-024-01760-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10893732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38395946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L., Shen Z., Zhou Y., Zuo J. Ammonia recovery from landfill leachate using gas-permeable membranes: Comparison of membrane fibers and expanded membrane tubes in both in-situ and shell-tube configurations. Chemical Engineering Journal. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.149255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.149255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xavier T.P., Malar P. Self-cleaning hydrophobic coating composed of micro/nano-imprinted polydimethylsiloxane with enhanced light in-coupling capabilities. ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. 2024;16(33):44114&#x2013;44126. doi: 10.1021/acsami.4c10614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.4c10614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39121340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia C.R. Fusing multi-model climate risk assessment and insurance profitability prediction: A machine learning-based cross-country comparative analysis. Highlights in Business, Economics and Management. 2024;45:693&#x2013;701. doi: 10.54097/zwpzb031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.54097/zwpzb031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao C., Albrecht E., Dannenberger D., Kong W., Gu H., Hammon H.M., Maak S. Effects of supplementation with essential fatty acids and conjugated linoleic acids on muscle structure and fat deposition in lactating holstein cows. Agriculture. 2024;14(10):1720. doi: 10.3390/agriculture14101720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture14101720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, F. (2024). Ruminant gastrointestinal Methanomassiliicoccales metagenome-assembled genomes. 10.6084/m9.figshare.21779036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6084/m9.figshare.21779036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie X., Cao Y., Li Q., Li Q., Yang X., Wang R., Zhang X., Tan Z., Lin B., Wang M. Mitigating enteric methane emissions: An overview of methanogenesis, inhibitors and future prospects. Animal Nutrition. 2025;21:84&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1016/J.ANINU.2025.02.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.ANINU.2025.02.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12124728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40453237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y. Application of controlled release mechanisms in vaccine delivery. Deleted Journal. 2024;2(2):14&#x2013;20. doi: 10.62051/ijphmr.v2n2.03.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62051/ijphmr.v2n2.03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xuan T., Zheng T., Li T., Wu B., Li T., Bao W., Qin W. The effects of different doses of 3-NOP on ruminal fermentation parameters, methane production, and the microbiota of lambs in vitro. Fermentation. 2024;10(9):440. doi: 10.3390/fermentation10090440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fermentation10090440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue X., Zhang W., Zhang X.S., Choi J. Spatially explicit life cycle global warming and eutrophication potentials of confined dairy production in the contiguous US. Environments. 2024;11(11):230. doi: 10.3390/environments11110230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/environments11110230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav A., Shivani S., Manda V.K., Sangwan V., &#x414;&#x435;&#x43c;&#x43a;&#x456;&#x432; &#x410;. Blockchain technology for ecological and environmental applications. Ecological Questions. 2024;35(4):1&#x2013;20. doi: 10.12775/eq.2024.050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12775/eq.2024.050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X., Ying Y., Li K., Zhang Q., Wang K. A review of mitigation technologies and management strategies for greenhouse gas and air pollutant emissions in livestock production. Journal of Environmental Management. 2024;352 doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.120028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.120028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38219668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang K., Qin M. Enhancing selective ammonium transport in membrane electrochemical systems. Water Research. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2024.121668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2024.121668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38692262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Lu Q. Cultivation of endogenous algal consortia for aquaculture wastewater remediation as a strategy toward net-zero carbon emission: From laboratory research to practical application. Frontiers in Nutrition. 2025;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12450980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40989797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z., Chen X., Yu M., Jing R., Bao L., Zhao L., Pan K., Chao B., Qu M. Metagenomic sequencing identified microbial species in the rumen and cecum microbiome responsible for niacin treatment and related to intramuscular fat content in finishing cattle. Frontiers in Microbiology. 2024 doi: 10.3389/fmicb.2024.1334068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2024.1334068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10961399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38529181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z., Zheng Y., Liu S., Xie T., Wang Q., Wang Z., Li S., Wang W. Rumen metagenome reveals the mechanism of mitigation methane emissions by unsaturated fatty acid while maintaining the performance of dairy cows. Animal Nutrition. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.aninu.2024.06.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aninu.2024.06.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11402312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39281050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, M., Luo, S., Yuan, R., Hou, R., Zhou, B., &amp; Chen, H. (2025). Cathode materials and novel strategies for improving bioenergy production in microbial electrolysis cell: A review. 10.1016/j.jece.2025.115718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2025.115718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanza Y.R., Szumacher-Strabel M., Lechniak D., &#x15a;lusarczyk S., Ko&#x142;odziejski P., Patra A.K., V&#xe1;radyov&#xe1; Z., Lisiak D., Vazirigohar M., Cieslak A. Dietary Coleus amboinicus Lour. decreases ruminal methanogenesis and biohydrogenation, and improves meat quality and fatty acid composition in longissimus thoracis muscle of lambs. Journal of Animal Science and Biotechnology. 2022;13(1) doi: 10.1186/s40104-021-00654-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40104-021-00654-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8765733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao M., Yi B., Wang L., Wei J., Ma Y., Zhou L., Chen M., Gong J. Recovering phosphorus as struvite microspheres with multiple excellent application performance via crystallization method. Separation and Purification Technology. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao J., Sun Y., Shi P., Liu Y. Phosphorous acid separation and recovery from glyphosate mother liquor by two-stage bipolar membrane electrodialysis. Separation and Purification Technology. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2024.126700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2024.126700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu G., Beauchemin K.A., Dong R. A review of 3-nitrooxypropanol for enteric methane mitigation from ruminant livestock. Animals. 2021;11(12):3540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8697901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34944313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan M., Li Z., Teng Z. Progress and prospects of recycling technology for carbon fiber reinforced polymer. Frontiers in Materials. 2024;11 doi: 10.3389/fmats.2024.1484544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmats.2024.1484544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahra W., Shiddieqy M.I., Anisa R., Yani A., Purwanto B.P. The dynamics of nitrous oxide and methane emissions from various types of dairy manure at smallholder dairy farms as affected by storage periods. Waste Management. 2024;183:10&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1016/j.wasman.2024.04.039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wasman.2024.04.039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38704922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zbair M., Limousy L., Dran&#xe9; M., Richard C., Juge M., Aemig Q., Trably &#xc9;., Escudi&#xe9; R., Peyrelasse C., Bennici S. Integration of digestate-derived biochar into the anaerobic digestion process through circular economic and environmental approaches&#x2013;A review. Materials. 2024;17(14):3527. doi: 10.3390/ma17143527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17143527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11278828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39063819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z. Recovery and reuse of thermosetting carbon fibre reinforced composites. Applied and Computational Engineering. 2024 doi: 10.54254/2755-2721/60/20240859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.54254/2755-2721/60/20240859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, R., Sadhukhan, J., Zhang, D., Short, M., McKechnie, J., Liu, Y., Bywater, A., Murali, R., Dolat, M., Zhang, D., &amp; Zarei, M. (2024). Novel life cycle GHG formulations of anaerobic digestion systems aligned with policy. 10.2139/ssrn.4837715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.4837715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Liang Q., Yu Y., Jin S., Huang J., Xu Z., Liu E., Wang W., Zhang F., Liu F., Shi Y., Li F., Li Z., Jin S., Li M. MFMGP: An integrated machine learning fusion model for genomic prediction. Plant Biotechnology Journal. 2025 doi: 10.1111/pbi.14532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pbi.14532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11869184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39799387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Bao X., Shi X., Jin S., Meng Y., Li Z., Du Z., Yan X. In vitro evaluation of enzymatically transformed alfalfa saponins on methane reduction, rumen microbes and metabolomics in goats. Animals. 2025;15(11):1516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12153755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40508983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Tan J., Fang L., Jiang L. Harnessing meta-omics to unveil and mitigate methane emissions in ruminants: Integrative approaches and future directions. Science of the Total Environment. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.175732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.175732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39182764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao R., Sun J., Lin Y., Yan H., Zhang S., Huo W., Chen L., Liu Q., Wang C., Guo G. Effects of dietary tannic acid and tea polyphenol supplementation on rumen fermentation, methane emissions, milk protein synthesis and microbiota in cows. Microorganisms. 2025;13(8):1848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12388258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40871352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y., Chen A., Fu X., Li D. Photovoltaics and agriculture nexus: exploring the influence of agrivoltaics on food production and electricity generation. IEEE Journal of Photovoltaics. 2024:1&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1109/jphotov.2024.3421298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jphotov.2024.3421298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhengtian L., Chen L., Yuan H., Ayub J. Biosensors and nano-detection systems for monitoring animal health and environmental safety. Animal BioSphere. 2025;1(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong K., Chen X., Zhang J., Jiang X., Zhang J., Qu Y., Bi S., Ju C., Luo Y. Recent advances in oral vaccines for animals. Veterinary Sciences. 2024;11(8):353. doi: 10.3390/vetsci11080353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vetsci11080353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11360704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39195807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong P., Li Q., Zhang Y., Guo C., Abdelsattar M.M., Bi Y. Precision microbial regulation: Strategies for modulating GIT microbiota for host health. iMetaOmics. 2025 doi: 10.1002/imo2.54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/imo2.54</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12806292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41675700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L. Optimization of sewage treatment processes: Process control based on artificial intelligence. Applied and Computational Engineering. 2024;93(1):185&#x2013;190. doi: 10.54254/2755-2721/93/20240981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.54254/2755-2721/93/20240981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zin M.M.T., Hussain M., Kim D., Yang J.E., Choi Y.J., Park Y.K. Circular economy approach: Nutrient recovery and economical struvite production from wastewater sources by using modified biochars. Chemosphere. 2024;362 doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.142589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.142589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38866334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Z., Xing Y., Liu T., Zheng M., Lu X., Chen Y., Jiang G., Liang P., Huang X., Liu Y. Methane mitigation via the nitrite-DAMO process induced by nitrate dosing in sewers. Water Research. 2024;257 doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2024.121701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2024.121701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38733962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zysman J., Breznitz D., Zilberman D. Pathways for a green transition to a bio-economy. Social Science Research Network. 2024 doi: 10.2139/ssrn.4937526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.4937526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>