<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41845162</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fueling Women's Football: Evidence-Informed Practical Nutrition Strategies for Performance and Health.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-026-02413-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This paper synthesizes current research on women's football to develop comprehensive, evidence-informed nutritional strategies tailored to the specific demands of the sport. Four key themes are addressed: (1) energy requirements in women's football; (2) macronutrient and nutrient-timing applications around training and match play, including an illustrative case study; (3) supporting a player with inadequate energy intake, including an illustrative case study; and (4) nutritional considerations relating to fluctuations in female sex hormones. Rather than providing another descriptive narrative review, this synthesis translates research findings into practical strategies for implementation in real-world performance environments. Adequate energy availability is identified as a fundamental nutritional priority. Carbohydrate and protein intake are emphasized as essential for sustaining training quality, supporting recovery, and maximizing match performance. Nutrient timing is highlighted as a critical determinant of in-season performance and effective match preparation. Consideration is also given to the influence of hormonal fluctuations on thermoregulation and menstrual cycle-related symptoms, alongside nutritional strategies to mitigate these effects. This synthesis underscores the importance of individualized nutritional strategies to optimize health, performance, and return-to-play outcomes in women footballers.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith-Ryan</LastName><ForeName>Abbie E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise and Sport Science, Department of Nutrition, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, NC, 27713, USA. abbiesmith@unc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moore</LastName><ForeName>Sam R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise and Sport Science, Department of Nutrition, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, NC, 27713, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arent</LastName><ForeName>Michelle</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Athletics, University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cantu</LastName><ForeName>Elena</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise and Sport Science, Department of Nutrition, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, NC, 27713, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cornejo</LastName><ForeName>Lissette</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lissette Cornejo Nutrition, LLC, Orlando, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hackney</LastName><ForeName>Anthony C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise and Sport Science, Department of Nutrition, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, NC, 27713, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ihalainen</LastName><ForeName>Johanna K</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport and Health Sciences, University of Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Finnish Institute of High Performance Sport KIHU, Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mikkonen</LastName><ForeName>Ritva S</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Finnish Institute of High Performance Sport KIHU, Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bruinvels</LastName><ForeName>Georgie</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9352-7228</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Targeted Intervention, University College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Author Contributions: AESR conceptualized the manuscript, led the writing and revision process, and coordinated contributions from all authors. SRM contributed to manuscript development, figure creation, and writing. MA provided real-world case studies, contributed to writing, and assisted with revisions. EC supported manuscript writing, designed all figures, and participated in revisions. LC contributed practical insights for the dietary components and assisted with figure development, writing, and revisions. ACH, JKI, RSM, and GB contributed to writing and manuscript revisions. GB also provided expertise in practical translation and editing. All authors reviewed and approved the final manuscript. Conflict of interest/competing interests: ASR receives research funding through the university to complete research studies on dietary supplements and serves as a scientific advisor for Alzchem and Create Wellness. GB is a consultant with Orreco, who provide consultancy to women athletes and the free FitrWoman app. All other authors (SRM, MA, EC, LC, ACH, JKI, RSM) have no conflicts to declare</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41845162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-026-02413-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-026-02413-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Shirreffs SM. Nutrition and hydration concerns of the female football player. Br J Sports Med. 2007;41(Suppl 1):i60&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17646250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2465245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2007.036475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins J, Maughan RJ, Gleeson M, Bilsborough J, Jeukendrup A, Morton JP, et al. UEFA expert group statement on nutrition in elite football. Current evidence to inform practical recommendations and guide future research. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55(8):416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33097528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2019-101961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguinaga-Ontoso I, Guillen-Aguinaga S, Guillen-Aguinaga L, Alas-Brun R, Guillen-Grima F. Effects of nutrition interventions on athletic performance in soccer players: a systematic review. Life. 2023;13(6):1271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37374054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10301089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/life13061271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randell RK, Clifford T, Drust B, Moss SL, Unnithan VB, De Ste Croix MBA, et al. Physiological characteristics of female soccer players and health and performance considerations: a narrative review. Sports Med. 2021;51(7):1377&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33844195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8222040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01458-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtzman B, Ackerman KE. Recommendations and nutritional considerations for female athletes: health and performance. Sports Med. 2021;51(s1):43&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34515972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8566643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01508-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Sousa MV, Lundsgaard AM, Christensen PM, Christensen L, Randers MB, Mohr M, et al. Nutritional optimization for female elite football players&#x2014;topical review. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022;32(S1):81&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34865242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sims ST, Kerksick CM, Smith-Ryan AE, Janse De Jonge XAK, Hirsch KR, Arent SM, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: nutritional concerns of the female athlete. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2023;20(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harkness-Armstrong A, Till K, Datson N, Myhill N, Emmonds S. A systematic review of match-play characteristics in women&#x2019;s soccer. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(6):e0268334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35771861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9246157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0268334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panduro J, Ermidis G, R&#xf8;ddik L, Vigh-Larsen JF, Madsen EE, Larsen MN, et al. Physical performance and loading for six playing positions in elite female football: full-game, end-game, and peak periods. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022;32(S1):115&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33749045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Krustrup P, Andersson H, Kirkendall D, Bangsbo J. Match activities of elite women soccer players at different performance levels. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(2):341&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18550946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318165fef6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith-Ryan AE, Mock MG, Ryan ED, Gerstner GR, Trexler ET, Hirsch KR. Validity and reliability of a 4-compartment body composition model using dual energy x-ray absorptiometry-derived body volume. Clin Nutr. 2017;36(3):825&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27237796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2016.05.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes CJ, Racette SB. The utility of body composition assessment in nutrition and clinical practice: an overview of current methodology. Nutrients. 2021;13(8):2493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34444653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8399582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13082493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolte J, Kirmse M, De Mar&#xe9;es M, Platen P. Effects of short-term low energy availability on metabolism and performance-related parameters in physically active adults. Nutrients. 2025;17(2):278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39861408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11767613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu17020278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melin AK, Heikura IA, Tenforde A, Mountjoy M. Energy availability in athletics: health, performance, and physique. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2019;29(2):152&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30632422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2018-0201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathisen TF, Ackland T, Burke LM, Constantini N, Haudum J, Macnaughton LS, et al. Best practice recommendations for body composition considerations in sport to reduce health and performance risks: a critical review, original survey and expert opinion by a subgroup of the IOC consensus on Relative Energy Deficiency in Sport (REDs). Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(17):1148&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37752006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-106812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campo SS, Vaeyens R, Philippaerts RM, Redondo JC, de Benito AM, Cuadrado G. Effects of lower-limb plyometric training on body composition, explosive strength, and kicking speed in female soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(6):1714&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b3f537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todd M, Scott D, Chisnall P. Fitness characteristics of English female soccer players: an analysis by position and playing standard. Science and Football IV2002. p. 374&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark M, Reed DB, Crouse SF, Armstrong RB. Pre- and post-season dietary intake, body composition, and performance indices of NCAA Division I Female Soccer Plauers. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2003;13(3):303&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14669931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.13.3.303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira R, Francisco R, Fernandes R, Martins A, Nobari H, Clemente FM, et al. In-season body composition effects in professional women soccer players. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(22):12023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34831776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8624767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph182212023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roelofs E, Bockin A, Bosch T, Oliver J, Bach CW, Carbuhn A, et al. Body composition of national collegiate athletic association (NCAA) Division I female soccer athletes through competitive seasons. Int J Sports Med. 2020;41(11):766&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32650343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanforth PR, Crim BN, Stanforth D, Stults-Kolehmainen MA. Body composition changes among female NCAA Division I athletes across the competitive season over a multiyear time frame. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(2):300&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23860290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182a20f06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields JB, Merrigan JJ, White JB, Jones MT. Body composition variables by sport and sport-position in elite collegiate athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(11):3153&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30239454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukaski H, Raymond-Pope CJ. New frontiers of body composition in sport. Int J Sports Med. 2021;42(7):588&#x2013;601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33621995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8421000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1373-5881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gould LM, Cabre HE, Brewer GJ, Hirsch KR, Blue MNM, Smith-Ryan AE. Impact of follicular menstrual phase on body composition measures and resting metabolism. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53(11):2396&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34280938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicks CS, McLester CN, Esmat TA, McLester JR. A comparison of body composition across two phases of the menstrual cycle utilizing dual-energy X-Ray absorptiometry, air displacement plethysmography, and bioelectrical impedance analysis. Int J Exerc Sci. 2017;10(8):1235&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29399250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5786198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/HREA6128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prado CM, Gonzalez MC, Norman K, Barazzoni R, Cederholm T, Compher C, et al. Methodological standards for body composition-an expert-endorsed guide for research and clinical applications: levels, models, and terminology. Am J Clin Nutr. 2025;122(2):384&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40754386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12405783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajcnut.2025.05.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joniak KE, Moore SR, Ladan AN, Cant&#xfa; EI, Britton ME, Smith-Ryan AE. Custom regional segmental lower limb lean soft tissue analysis in male and female Division I athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2025;38(8):868&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong JN, Ducker KJ, Furzer BJ, Dymock M, Landers GJ. Measures of body composition via dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry, ultrasound and skinfolds are not impacted by the menstrual cycle in active eumenorrheic females. J Sci Med Sport. 2022;25(2):115&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34756512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2021.09.192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuikman MA, McKay AKA, Minahan C, Harris R, Elliott-Sale KJ, Stellingwerff T, et al. Effect of menstrual cycle phase and hormonal contraceptives on resting metabolic rate and body composition. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2024;34(4):207&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38653456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2023-0193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bongiovanni T, Lacome M, Rodriguez C, Tinsley GM. Tracking body composition over a competitive season in elite soccer players using laboratory- and field-based assessment methods. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38(3):e104&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38416450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blue MNM, Hirsch KR, Pihoker AA, Trexler ET, Smith-Ryan AE. Normative fat-free mass index values for a diverse sample of collegiate female athletes. J Sports Sci. 2019;37(15):1741&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30893018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2019.1591575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagim AR, Harty PS, Jones MT, Fields JB, Magee M, Smith-Ryan AE, et al. Fat-free mass index in sport: normative profiles and applications for collegiate athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38(9):1687&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39074219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burkhart TA, Schinkel-Ivy A, Andrews DM. Tissue mass ratios and the reporting of distal lower extremity injuries in varsity athletes at a Canadian university. J Sports Sci. 2013;31(6):684&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23215824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2012.747691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCaskie C, Sim M, Newton R, Heasman J, Rogalski B, Hart N. Preseason body composition is associated with in-season player availability in elite male Australian footballers. J Strength Cond Res. 2023;37(5):1089&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36730574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasa MS, Friborg O, Kristoffersen M, Pettersen G, Plasqui G, Sundgot-Borgen JK, et al. Energy expenditure, dietary intake and energy availability in female professional football players. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2023;9(1):e001553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36865769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9972418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2023-001553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez-Hixson K, Biagioni E, Brown ML. Significant differences in dietary intake of NCAA Division III soccer players compared to recommended levels. J Am Coll Health. 2020;70(1):150&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32101508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07448481.2020.1728279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinho DV, Field A, Naughton R, Ribeiro AS, Rebelo A, Gouveia &#xc9;R, et al. Nutritional perspectives in female soccer: a scoping review. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1080/15502783.2024.2366427 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2024.2366427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38961627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11225636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas D, Erdman K, Burke L. American College of Sports Medicine joint position statement. Nutrition and athletic performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(3):543&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26891166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagim AR, Camic CL, Kisiolek J, Luedke J, Erickson J, Jones MT, et al. Accuracy of resting metabolic rate prediction equation in athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(7):1875&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28682934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neill JER, Corish CA, Horner K. Accuracy of resting metabolic rate prediction equations in athletes: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53(12):2373&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37632665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10687135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01896-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loucks A. Energy balance and energy availability. The Encyclopaedia of sports medicine (An IOC Medical Commission Publication). 2013. p. 72&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mountjoy M, Ackerman KE, Bailey DM, Burke LM, Constantini N, Hackney AC, et al. 2023 International Olympic Committee&#x2019;s (IOC) consensus statement on Relative Energy Deficiency in Sport (REDs). Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(17):1073&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37752011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-106994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM, Lundy B, Fahrenholtz IL, Melin AK. Pitfalls of conducting and interpreting estimates of energy availability in free-living athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2018;28(4):350&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30029584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2018-0142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Sygo J, Morton JP. Fuelling the female athlete: carbohydrate and protein recommendations. Eur J Sport Sci. 2021;0(0):1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, &#xd8;rtenblad N, Nielsen J, Nybo L, Gunnarsson TP, Iaia FM, et al. Maximal voluntary contraction force, SR function and glycogen resynthesis during the first 72 h after a high-level competitive soccer game. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(12):2987&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21448723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-1919-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausswirth C, Le Meur Y. Physiological and nutritional aspects of post-exercise recovery. Sports Med. 2011;41(10):861&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21923203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11593180-000000000-00000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper Marosek SE, Antharam V, Dowlatshahi K. Quantitative analysis of the acetic acid content in substances used by athletes for the possible prevention and alleviation of exercise-associated muscle cramps. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(6):1539&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32459412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craven J, Desbrow B, Sabapathy S, Bellinger P, McCartney D, Irwin C. The effect of consuming carbohydrate with and without protein on the rate of muscle glycogen re-synthesis during short-term post-exercise recovery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med Open. 2021;7(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulios A, Fatouros IG, Mohr M, Draganidis D, Deli CK, Papanikolaou K, et al. Post-game high protein intake may improve recovery of football-specific performance during a congested game fixture: results from the PRO-FOOTBALL study. Nutrients. 2018;10(4):494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29659539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5946279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10040494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcantara JMA, Sanchez-Delgado G, Martinez-Tellez B, Labayen I, Ruiz JR. Impact of cow&#x2019;s milk intake on exercise performance and recovery of muscle function: a systematic review. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2019;16(1):22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31060583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6503439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-019-0288-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J. Pre-sleep casein protein ingestion: new paradigm in post-exercise recovery nutrition. Phys Act Nutr. 2020;24(2):6&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32698256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7451833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20463/pan.2020.0009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cintineo HP, Arent MA, Antonio J, Arent SM. Effects of protein supplementation on performance and recovery in resistance and endurance training. Front Nutr. 2018. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2018.00083 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2018.00083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30255023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6142015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranchordas MK, Rogerson D, Soltani H, Costello JT. Antioxidants for preventing and reducing muscle soreness after exercise: a Cochrane systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(2):74&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30054340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-099599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimble R, Jones K, Howatson G. The effect of dietary anthocyanins on biochemical, physiological, and subjective exercise recovery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. 2023;63(9):1262&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34402657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408398.2021.1963208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker LB. Sweating rate and sweat sodium concentration in athletes: a review of methodology and intra/interindividual variability. Sports Med. 2017;47(S1):111&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28332116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5371639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0691-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnowski CA, Rollo I, Carter JM, Lizarraga-Dallo MA, Oliva MP, Clifford T, et al. Fluid balance and carbohydrate intake of elite female soccer players during training and competition. Nutrients. 2022;14(15):3188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35956363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9370343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14153188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barley OR, Chapman DW, Abbiss CR. Reviewing the current methods of assessing hydration in athletes. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12970-020-00381-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-020-00381-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33126891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7602338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostelnik SB, Davy KP, Hedrick VE, Thomas DT, Davy BM. The validity of urine color as a hydration biomarker within the general adult population and athletes: a systematic review. J Am Coll Nutr. 2021;40(2):172&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32330109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07315724.2020.1750073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nattiv A, Loucks AB, Manore MM, Sanborn CF, Sundgot-Borgen J, Warren MP. The female athlete triad. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(10):1867&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17909417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0b013e318149f111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ihalainen JK, Mikkonen RS, Ackerman KE, Heikura IA, Mjosund K, Valtonen M, et al. Beyond menstrual dysfunction: does altered endocrine function caused by problematic low energy availability impair health and sports performance in female athletes? Sports Med. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-024-02065-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02065-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38995599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11393114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fensham NC, Heikura IA, McKay AKA, Tee N, Ackerman KE, Burke LM. Short-term carbohydrate restriction impairs bone formation at rest and during prolonged exercise to a greater degree than low energy availability. J Bone Miner Res. 2022;37(10):1915&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35869933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9804216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jbmr.4658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabre HE, Moore SR, Smith-Ryan AE, Hackney AC. Relative energy deficiency in sport (RED-S): scientific, clinical, and practical implications for the female athlete. Dtsch Z Sportmed. 2022;73(7):225&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36479178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9724109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5960/dzsm.2022.546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahrenholtz IL, Sj&#xf6;din A, Benardot D, Tornberg B, Skouby S, Faber J, et al. Within-day energy deficiency and reproductive function in female endurance athletes. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018;28(3):1139&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29205517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oosthuyse T, Strauss JA, Hackney AC. Understanding the female athlete: molecular mechanisms underpinning menstrual phase differences in exercise metabolism. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2023;123(3):423&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36402915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stachenfeld N, Silva C, Keefe DL. Estrogen modifies the temperature effects of progesterone. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88(5):1643&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10797125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2000.88.5.1643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giersch GEW, Morrissey MC, Katch RK, Colburn AT, Sims ST, Stachenfeld NS, et al. Menstrual cycle and thermoregulation during exercise in the heat: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2020;23(12):1134&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32499153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2020.05.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker FC, Siboza F, Fuller A. Temperature regulation in women: effects of the menstrual cycle. Temperature. 2020;7(3):226&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23328940.2020.1735927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanovich R, Ketko I, Charkoudian N. Sex differences in human thermoregulation: relevance for 2020 and beyond. Physiology (Bethesda). 2020;35(3):177&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32293229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirby NV, Lucas SJE, Cable TG, Armstrong OJ, Weaver SR, Lucas RAI. Sex differences in adaptation to intermittent post-exercise sauna bathing in trained middle-distance runners. Sports Med. 2021;7(1):51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mee JA, Gibson OR, Doust J, Maxwell NS. A comparison of males and females&#x2019; temporal patterning to short- and long-term heat acclimation. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25(Suppl 1):250&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25943676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charkoudian N, Stachenfeld N. Sex hormone effects on autonomic mechanisms of thermoregulation in humans. Auton Neurosci. 2016;196:75&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26674572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2015.11.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christison K. Menstrual cycle effects on thermoregulation while exercising in the heat. J Therm Biol. 2025;127:104036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39805177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtherbio.2024.104036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freemas J, Goss C, Ables R, Baker T, Bruinvels G, Mundel T, et al. Fluid balance during physical work in the heat is not modified by the menstrual cycle when fluids are freely available. J Appl Physiol. 2023;134(6):1376&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37055034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10202473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00580.2022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boisseau N, Isacco L. Substrate metabolism during exercise: sexual dimorphism and women&#x2019;s specificities. Eur J Sport Sci. 2021;22(5):672&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34134602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2021.1943713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oosthuyse T, Bosch A. The effect of gender and menstrual phase on serum creatine kinase activity and muscle soreness following downhill running. Antioxidants. 2017;6(1):16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28241459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5384179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox6010016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLay RT, Thomson CD, Williams SM, Rehrer NJ. Carbohydrate loading and female endurance athletes: effect of menstrual-cycle phase. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2007;17(2):189&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17507743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.17.2.189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicklas B, Hackney A, Sharp R. The menstrual cycle and exercise: performance, muscle glycogen, and substrate responses. Int J Sports Med. 1989;10(04):264&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2606593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-1024913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamadeh MJ, Devries MC, Tarnopolsky MA. Estrogen supplementation reduces whole body leucine and carbohydrate oxidation and increases lipid oxidation in men during endurance exercise. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2005;90(6):3592&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15755861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2004-1743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabre HE, Moore SR, Smith-Ryan AE. A survey evaluating the relationship between the perceived side effects of hormonal contraception and physical activity levels in adult U.S.A. women. Women Sport Phys Act J. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng J, Santiago KA, Abutalib Z, Temme KE, Hulme A, Goolsby MA, et al. Menstrual irregularity, hormonal contraceptive use, and bone stress injuries in collegiate female athletes in the United States. PM R. 2021;13(11):1207&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33340255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8262270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pmrj.12539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker LJ, Elliott-Sale KJ, Hannon MP, Morton JP, Close GL. An audit of hormonal contraceptive use in Women&#x2019;s Super League soccer players; implications on symptomology. Sci Med Football. 2021;6(2):153&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24733938.2021.1921248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitruk-Ware R, Nath A. Characteristics and metabolic effects of estrogen and progestins contained in oral contraceptive pills. Best Pract Res Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013;27(1):13&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23384742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.beem.2012.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekenros L, Von Rosen P, Solli GS, Sandbakk &#xd8;, Holmberg H-C, Hirschberg AL, et al. Perceived impact of the menstrual cycle and hormonal contraceptives on physical exercise and performance in 1,086 athletes from 57 sports. Front Physiol. 2022. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2022.954760 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.954760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36111164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9468598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oester C, Norris D, Scott D, Pedlar C, Bruinvels G, Lovell R. Inconsistencies in the perceived impact of the menstrual cycle on sport performance and in the prevalence of menstrual cycle symptoms: a scoping review of the literature. J Sci Med Sport. 2024;27(6):373&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38508888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2024.02.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilar-Aguilar E. Menstrual disorders: what we know about dietary-nutritional therapy. Nutrici&#xf3;n Hospitalaria. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradifili B, Ghiasvand R, Pourmasoumi M, Feizi A, Shahdadian F, Shahshahan Z. Dietary patterns are associated with premenstrual syndrome: evidence from a case-control study. Public Health Nutr. 2020;23(5):833&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31612836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1368980019002192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown N, Martin D, Waldron M, Bruinvels G, Farrant L, Fairchild R. Nutritional practices to manage menstrual cycle related symptoms: a systematic review. Nutr Res Rev. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1017/s0954422423000227 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/s0954422423000227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37746736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parazzini F, Di Martino M, Pellegrino P. Magnesium in the gynecological practice: a literature review. Magnes Res. 2017;30(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28392498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notbohm HL, Moser F, Goh J, Feuerbacher JF, Bloch W, Schumann M. The effects of menstrual cycle phases on immune function and inflammation at rest and after acute exercise: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Acta Physiol Oxf. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1111/apha.14013 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apha.14013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37309068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torkan B, Mousavi M, Dehghani S, Hajipour L, Sadeghi N, Ziaei Rad M, et al. The role of water intake in the severity of pain and menstrual distress among females suffering from primary dysmenorrhea: a semi-experimental study. BMC Womens Health. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12905-021-01184-w .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-021-01184-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33509179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7845092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorczyca AM, Sjaarda LA, Mitchell EM, Perkins NJ, Schliep KC, Wactawski-Wende J, et al. Changes in macronutrient, micronutrient, and food group intakes throughout the menstrual cycle in healthy, premenopausal women. Eur J Nutr. 2016;55(3):1181&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26043860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00394-015-0931-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wohlgemuth KJ, Arieta LR, Brewer GJ, Hoselton AL, Gould LM, Smith-Ryan AE. Sex differences and considerations for female specific nutritional strategies: a narrative review. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2021;18(1):1&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-021-00422-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavia M, Moreno A, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Trabanco B, Carrillo C, Alonso-Torre S. Anthropometric characteristics and somatotype of professional soccer players by position. J Sports Med Ther. 2019;4(4):073&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29328/journal.jsmt.1001047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-Munera M, Arcusa R, L&#xf3;pez-Rom&#xe1;n FJ, Victoria-Montesinos D, Garc&#xed;a-Mu&#xf1;oz AM, &#xc1;vila-Gand&#xed;a V, et al. Anthropometric and body composition changes during pre-season of Spanish professional female soccer players according to playing position. Nutrients. 2024;16(16):2799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39203934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11357517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu16162799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>