<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41889581</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2160-2026</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of burns and trauma</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Burns Trauma</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Radiographic and functional outcomes of dorsal-assisted volar plate fixation in comminuted intra-articular distal radius fractures: a prospective study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>25</StartPage><EndPage>32</EndPage><MedlinePgn>25-32</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.62347/GFNB2009</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Comminuted intra-articular distal radius fractures (DRFs) present significant treatment challenges due to their complex morphology and tendency for post-traumatic arthritis. Volar plating alone may be insufficient to achieve and maintain reduction in dorsally displaced fractures. This prospective study evaluated the radiological and functional outcomes of dorsal-assisted volar plate fixation in dorsally displaced comminuted intra-articular DRFs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 21 patients treated at a tertiary care trauma centre were enrolled. All underwent dorsal-assisted reduction followed by volar plating without dorsal instrumentation and were followed for a minimum of one year (mean follow-up: 19.6 &#xb1; 4.7 months). Radiological outcomes were assessed using radial height, radial inclination, volar tilt, and intra-articular step-off, while functional outcomes were measured using the QuickDASH and modified Mayo Wrist scores. The study was prospectively registered in the Department review board in department of Orthopaedic Surgery, PGIMER, under registration number DRB/Ortho/2023/49.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The mean patient age was 38 years, with a male predominance (17/21; 80.9%). Most fractures (15/21; 71.4%) were AO type 2R3C3. Postoperative evaluation demonstrated restoration of wrist alignment with a mean radial inclination of 23.35&#xb0;, radial height of 11.29 mm, and volar tilt of 6.70&#xb0;, closely approximating the uninjured wrist. Functional outcomes improved significantly from two months postoperatively to the final follow-up (P &lt; 0.001), achieving a mean QuickDASH score of 4.95 and a modified Mayo Wrist Score of 90. Only two patients experienced minor complications related to implant prominence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Dorsal-assisted volar plating is a safe and effective technique for managing dorsally displaced comminuted intra-articular distal radius fractures, providing excellent anatomical restoration and functional recovery with minimal complications. It offers a valuable surgical option where volar plating alone may be inadequate.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>IJBT Copyright &#xa9; 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shreegan</LastName><ForeName>Akshay A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research Sector 12, Chandigarh 160012, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Deepak</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research Sector 12, Chandigarh 160012, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kotteda</LastName><ForeName>Anil Kumar</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research Sector 12, Chandigarh 160012, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bansal</LastName><ForeName>Arjit</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research Sector 12, Chandigarh 160012, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aduri</LastName><ForeName>Tharun Teja</ForeName><Initials>TT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research Sector 12, Chandigarh 160012, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goni</LastName><ForeName>Vijay</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research Sector 12, Chandigarh 160012, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Burns Trauma</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101581623</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2160-2026</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Distal radius fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mayo Wrist Score</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">QuickDASH</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">comminuted fractures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dorsal-assisted volar plating</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional outcome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intra-articular fractures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">radiological outcome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41889581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13012884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62347/GFNB2009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nellans KW, Kowalski E, Chung KC. The epidemiology of distal radius fractures. Hand Clin. 2012;28:113&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3345129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22554654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoare CP, Dickson DR, Armstrong DJ, Nuttall D, Watts AC. Internal fixation for treating distal radius fractures in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;2017:CD011213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mader K, Pennig D. The treatment of severely comminuted intra-articular fractures of the distal radius. Strategies Trauma Limb Reconstr. 2006;1:2&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gogna P, Selhi HS, Singla R, Devgan A, Magu NK, Mahindra P, Yamin M. Dorsally comminuted fractures of the distal end of the radius: osteosynthesis with volar fixed angle locking plates. ISRN Orthop. 2013;2013:131757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4045357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24959352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayakumar P, Teunis T, Gim&#xe9;nez BB, Verstreken F, Di Mascio L, Jupiter JB. AO distal radius fracture classification: global perspective on observer agreement. J Wrist Surg. 2017;6:46&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5258123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28119795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner RG, Faber KJ, Athwal GS. Complications of distal radius fractures. Hand Clin. 2010;26:85&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20006247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutow AP. Avoidance and treatment of complications of distal radius fractures. Hand Clin. 2005;21:295&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16039441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karantana A, Downing ND, Forward DP, Hatton M, Taylor AM, Scammell BE, Moran CG, Davis TR. Surgical treatment of distal radial fractures with a volar locking plate versus conventional percutaneous methods: a randomized controlled trial. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2013;95:1737&#x2013;1744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24088965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson AN, Rizzo M. Locking plate technology and its applications in upper extremity fracture care. Hand Clin. 2007;23:269&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17548017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramo A, Kopylov P, Geijer M, T&#xe4;gil M. Open reduction and internal fixation compared to closed reduction and external fixation in distal radial fractures: a randomized study of 50 patients. Acta Orthop. 2009;80:478&#x2013;485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2823185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19857180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond I, Durand-Hill M, Jones N, O&#x2019;Hagan PJ, Edwards D. Systematic review: dorsal bridge plating in distal radius fractures. Musculoskelet Surg. 2024;108:359&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11371870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38967772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alter TH, Sandrowski K, Gallant G, Kwok M, Ilyas AM. Complications of volar plating of distal radius fractures: a systematic review. J Wrist Surg. 2019;8:255&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6546498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31192050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramasamy A. Advanced trauma life support 2025: a brief review of updates. Injury. 2026;57:113079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41671886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarmiento A, Pratt GW, Berry NC, Sinclair WF. Colles&#x2019; fractures. Functional bracing in supination. JBJS. 1975;57:311&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1123382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green DP, O&#x2019;Brien ET. Open reduction of carpal dislocations: indications and operative techniques. The Journal of Hand Surgery. 1978;3:250&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">350947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooney WP, Bussey R, Dobyns JH, Linscheid RL. Difficult wrist fractures perilunate fracture-dislocations of the wrist. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1987;214:136&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3791735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gummesson C, Ward MM, Atroshi I. The shortened disabilities of the arm, shoulder and hand questionnaire (quick dash): validity and reliability based on responses within the full-length dash. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2006;7:44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1513569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16709254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozental TD, Blazar PE. Functional outcome and complications after volar plating for dorsally displaced, unstable fractures of the distal radius. The Journal of Hand Surgery. 2006;31:359&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16516728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quadlbauer S, Pezzei C, Jurkowitsch J, Rosenauer R, Pichler A, Sch&#xe4;ttin S, Hausner T, Leixnering M. Functional and radiological outcome of distal radius fractures stabilized by volar-locking plate with a minimum follow-up of 1 year. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2020;140:843&#x2013;852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32221705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei J, Yang TB, Luo W, Qin JB, Kong FJ. Complications following dorsal versus volar plate fixation of distal radius fracture: a meta-analysis. J Int Med Res. 2013;41:265&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23569022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadzhinikolova M, Zderic I, Ciric D, Barcik JP, Enchev D, Baltov A, Rusimov L, Varga P, Stoffel K, Richards G, Gueorguiev B. Volar versus combined dorsal and volar plate fixation of complex intraarticular distal radius fractures with small dorsoulnar fragment-a biomechanical study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2022;23:35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8734044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34986819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc;di S, Kurz C, Deforth M, Ghafoor H, Haefeli M, Honigmann P. Radiological, clinical, and functional outcomes of combined dorsal and volar locking plate osteosynthesis for complex distal radius fractures. J Hand Surg Am. 2023;48:377&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35190216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundqvist E, Fischer P, Wretenberg P, Pettersson K, Lopez Personat A, Sagerfors M. Volar locking plate compared with combined plating of AO type C distal radius fractures: a randomized controlled study of 150 cases. J Hand Surg Am. 2022;47:813&#x2013;822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35842329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X, Lu WH, Ma WW, Lu HJ, Ao RG, Liu BL. Volar approach combined with small dorsal incision in the treatment of AO type C distal radius fracture: a retrospective cohort study. Medicine (Baltimore) 2025;104:e46624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12727260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41430984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal RN, Shapiro LM. Practical application of the 2020 distal radius fracture AAOS/ASSH clinical practice guideline: a clinical case. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2022;30:e714&#x2013;e720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9035062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35383613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ring D, Prommersberger K, Jupiter JB. Combined dorsal and volar plate fixation of complex fractures of the distal part of the radius. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2005;87(Suppl 1):195&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16140794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>