<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41918076</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2334</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC infectious diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The role of ivermectin in the prevention and treatment of SARS-CoV-2 infection: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12879-026-13195-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Ivermectin, as a potential drug for the treatment of Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection, remains controversial regarding its efficacy and safety. This study aims to systematically evaluate the therapeutic and preventive effect of ivermectin in patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A comprehensive literature search was conducted on October 11, 2025, to include randomized controlled trials (RCTs) assessing ivermectin for the treatment of SARS-CoV-2 infection. The primary outcome measures were mortality rate and adverse event rate for hospitalized patients and outpatient patients, while secondary outcomes included hospitalization time and recovery time. Given the anticipated clinical and methodological heterogeneity across the included RCTs (e.g., variations in ivermectin dosage, study population characteristics, trial implementation time and SARS-CoV-2 variants), a random-effects model was used for the meta-analysis to obtain a robust synthesis of heterogeneous study results and reliable estimation of pooled effect sizes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 40 RCTs involving 23,243 participants were included. Among them, 4 studies evaluated the preventive effect of ivermectin on SARS-CoV-2 infection, and the other 36 studies evaluated the therapeutic effect of ivermectin in patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection. For prevention, there was no statistically significant difference between the ivermectin group and control group in SARS-CoV-2 infection rate [risk ratio (RR) 0.37; 95% Confidence Interval (CI) 0.12 to 1.20]. For treatment, all-cause mortality for both hospitalized patients (RR 0.94; 95%CI 0.74 to 1.20) and outpatients (RR 0.88; 95%CI 0.55 to 1.42) showed no statistically significant difference. Adverse events for hospitalized patients (RR 1.02; 95%CI 0.76 to 1.37) and outpatients (RR 0.96; 95%CI 0.82 to 1.13) also showed no statistically significant difference.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This meta-analysis provides evidence that ivermectin does not statistically significantly reduce the risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection or improve clinical outcomes in patients with COVID-19. Further high-quality trials are needed to clarify the potential benefits of ivermectin.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL NUMBER" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Not applicable.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xuanyu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, 410008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xiangya School of Medicine, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, 410008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Jiahao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, 410008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Aging-Related Bone and Joint Diseases Prevention and Treatment, Xiangya Hospital, Ministry of Education, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yinghui</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central South University of Forestry and Technology, Changsha, Hunan, 410004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiang</LastName><ForeName>Yuqing</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, 410008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xiangya School of Medicine, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, 410008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Yumei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, 410008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Yilin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, 410008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Aging-Related Bone and Joint Diseases Prevention and Treatment, Xiangya Hospital, Ministry of Education, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Geriatric Diseases (Xiangya Hospital), Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Pan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, 410008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Shuguang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, 410008, China. gaoshuguang0341@csu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Aging-Related Bone and Joint Diseases Prevention and Treatment, Xiangya Hospital, Ministry of Education, Central South University, Changsha, China. gaoshuguang0341@csu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Geriatric Diseases (Xiangya Hospital), Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, China. gaoshuguang0341@csu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China. gaoshuguang0341@csu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2334</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ivermectin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41918076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-026-13195-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12879-026-13195-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Attaway AH, Scheraga RG, Bhimraj A, Biehl M, Hatipo&#x11f;lu U. Severe covid-19 pneumonia: pathogenesis and clinical management. BMJ (Clinical Res ed). 2021;372:n436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berlin DA, Gulick RM, Martinez FJ. Severe Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(25):2451&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozer M, Goksu SY, Conception R, Ulker E, Balderas RM, Mahdi M, Manning Z, To K, Effendi M, Anandakrishnan R, et al. Effectiveness and safety of Ivermectin in COVID-19 patients: A prospective study at a safety-net hospital. J Med Virol. 2022;94(4):1473&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartoletti M, Azap O, Barac A, Bussini L, Ergonul O, Krause R, Pa&#xf1;o-Pardo JR, Power NR, Sibani M, Szabo BG, et al. ESCMID COVID-19 living guidelines: drug treatment and clinical management. Clin Microbiol infection: official publication Eur Soc Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2022;28(2):222&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azeez TA, Lakoh S, Adeleke AA, Balogun OT, Olanipekun BJ, Olusola FI. Chemoprophylaxis against COVID-19 among health-care workers using Ivermectin in low- and middle-income countries: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Indian J Pharmacol. 2021;53(6):493&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dilli Babu A, Singh S, Goel S. META-ANALYSIS OF THE USE OF IVERMECTIN FOR MILD-MODERATE COVID-19. Chest. 2023;164(4):A3892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu GY, Liang CA, Lin PC, Lin CY. Ivermectin&#x2019;s Role in the Prevention of COVID-19: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Clin Pharmacol. 2023;63(3):288&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kow CS, Merchant HA, Mustafa ZU, Hasan SS. The association between the use of ivermectin and mortality in patients with COVID-19: a meta-analysis. Pharmacol Rep. 2021;73(5):1473&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddukuri RK, Desimalla ML, Banavathu R, Arepalli SPK. Ivermectin as a Treatment Modality in COVID-19 Patients: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Up-To-Date RCTs. Indian J community medicine: official publication Indian Association Prev Social Med. 2025;50(1):9&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zein A, Sulistiyana CS, Raffaelo WM, Pranata R. Ivermectin and mortality in patients with COVID-19: A systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression of randomized controlled trials. Diabetes metabolic syndrome. 2021;15(4):102186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sai Yengu N, Raheem A, Pons AG, Ho WL, Ali SMS, Haseeb A, Fadlalla Ahmad TK, Mustafa MS. The impact of ivermectin on COVID-19 outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Annals Med Surg (2012). 2025;87(2):809&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satyam SM, El-Tanani M, Patni MA, Rehman A, Wali AF, Rangraze IR, Babiker R, Rabbani SA, El-Tanani Y, Rizzo M. Repurposing Anthelmintic Drugs for COVID-19 Treatment: A Comprehensive Meta-Analysis of Randomized Clinical Trials on Ivermectin and Mebendazole. Antibiot (Basel Switzerland) 2025, 14(5).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Z, Shi S, Zhang Y. Ivermectin for treatment of COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Heliyon. 2024;10(6):e27647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. PLoS Med. 2009;6(7):e1000097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, J&#xfc;ni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, Savovic J, Schulz KF, Weeks L, Sterne JA. The Cochrane Collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ (Clinical Res ed). 2011;343:d5928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustafa RA, Santesso N, Brozek J, Akl EA, Walter SD, Norman G, Kulasegaram M, Christensen R, Guyatt GH, Falck-Ytter Y, et al. The GRADE approach is reproducible in assessing the quality of evidence of quantitative evidence syntheses. J Clin Epidemiol. 2013;66(7):736&#x2013;42. quiz 742.e731-735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh ML. Interrater reliability: the kappa statistic. Biochemia Med. 2012;22(3):276&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vetter TR. Fundamentals of Research Data and Variables: The Devil Is in the Details. Anesth Analg. 2017;125(4):1375&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Chandler J, Welch VA, Higgins JP, Thomas J. Updated guidance for trusted systematic reviews: a new edition of the Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;10(10):Ed000142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muka T, Glisic M, Milic J, Verhoog S, Bohlius J, Bramer W, Chowdhury R, Franco OH. A 24-step guide on how to design, conduct, and successfully publish a systematic review and meta-analysis in medical research. Eur J Epidemiol. 2020;35(1):49&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Tulder M, Furlan A, Bombardier C, Bouter L. Updated method guidelines for systematic reviews in the cochrane collaboration back review group. Spine. 2003;28(12):1290&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cele S, Jackson L, Khoury DS, Khan K, Moyo-Gwete T, Tegally H, San JE, Cromer D, Scheepers C, Amoako DG, et al. Omicron extensively but incompletely escapes Pfizer BNT162b2 neutralization. Nature. 2022;602(7898):654&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pather S, Madhi SA, Cowling BJ, Moss P, Kamil JP, Ciesek S, Muik A, T&#xfc;reci &#xd6;. SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variants: burden of disease, impact on vaccine effectiveness and need for variant-adapted vaccines. Front Immunol 2023. 2023;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angkasekwinai N, Rattanaumpawan P, Chayakulkeeree M, Phoompoung P, Koomanachai P, Chantarasut S, Wangchinda W, Srinonprasert V, Thamlikitkul V. Safety and Efficacy of Ivermectin for the Prevention and Treatment of COVID-19: A Double-Blinded Randomized Placebo-Controlled Study. Antibiot (Basel Switzerland) 2022;11(6).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chahla RE, Medina Ruiz L, Ortega ES, Morales Rn MF, Barreiro F, George A, Mancilla Rn C, S, Barrenechea DAR, Goroso G. Intensive Treatment With Ivermectin and Iota-Carrageenan as Pre-exposure Prophylaxis for COVID-19 in Health Care Workers From Tucuman, Argentina. Am J Ther. 2021;28(5):e601&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seet RCS, Quek AML, Ooi DSQ, Sengupta S, Lakshminarasappa SR, Koo CY, So JBY, Goh BC, Loh KS, Fisher D, et al. Positive impact of oral hydroxychloroquine and povidone-iodine throat spray for COVID-19 prophylaxis: An open-label randomized trial. Int J Infect diseases: IJID : official publication Int Soc Infect Dis. 2021;106:314&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shouman W, Hegazy A, Nafae R, Sileem A. Use of Ivermectin as a potential chemoprophylaxis for COVID-19 in Egypt: a Randomised clinical trial. J Clin Diagn Res. 2021;15(2):OC27&#x2013;OC32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Davey Smith G, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ (Clinical Res ed). 1997;315(7109):629&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson-Arbor K. Ivermectin: a mini-review. Clin Toxicol (Phila). 2022;60(5):571&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rendic SP. Metabolism and interactions of Ivermectin with human cytochrome P450 enzymes and drug transporters, possible adverse and toxic effects. Arch Toxicol. 2021;95(5):1535&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinesh Kumar N, Ter Ellen BM, Bouma EM, Troost B, van de Pol DPI, van der Ende-Metselaar HH, van Gosliga D, Apperloo L, Carpaij OA, van den Berge M, et al. Moxidectin and Ivermectin Inhibit SARS-CoV-2 Replication in Vero E6 Cells but Not in Human Primary Bronchial Epithelial Cells. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2022;66(1):e0154321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwabufo CK, Hoque MT, Yip L, Khara M, Mubareka S, Pollanen MS, Bendayan R. SARS-CoV-2 infection dysregulates the expression of clinically relevant drug metabolizing enzymes in Vero E6 cells and membrane transporters in human lung tissues. Front Pharmacol. 2023;14:1124693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eastman RT, Rusinova R, Herold KF, Huang XP, Voss T, White AD, Hemmings HC Jr., Andersen OS, Dahlin JL. Membrane Perturbations and Assay Interferences by Ivermectin Explain Its In Vitro SARS-CoV-2 Antiviral Activities and Lack of Translatability. J Med Chem. 2025;68(20):20979&#x2013;1002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popp M, Reis S, Schie&#xdf;er S, Hausinger RI, Stegemann M, Metzendorf MI, Kranke P, Meybohm P, Skoetz N, Weibel S. Ivermectin for preventing and treating COVID-19. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2022;6(6):Cd015017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou G, Verweij S, Bijlsma MJ, de Vos S, Oude Rengerink K, Pasmooij AMG, van Baarle D, Niesters HGM, Mol P, Vonk JM et al. Repurposed drug studies on the primary prevention of SARS-CoV-2 infection during the pandemic: systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ open respiratory Res 2023, 10(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryant A, Lawrie TA, Dowswell T, Fordham EJ, Mitchell S, Hill SR, Tham TC. Ivermectin for Prevention and Treatment of COVID-19 Infection: A Systematic Review, Meta-analysis, and Trial Sequential Analysis to Inform Clinical Guidelines. Am J Ther. 2021;28(4):e434&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarojvisut P, Apisarnthanarak A, Jantarathaneewat K, Sathitakorn O, Pienthong T, Mingmalairak C, Warren DK, Weber DJ. An Open Label Randomized Controlled Trial of Ivermectin Plus Favipiravir-Based Standard of Care versus Favipiravir-Based Standard of Care for Treatment of Moderate COVID-19 in Thailand. Infect Chemother. 2023;55(1):50&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malektojari A, Ghazizadeh S, Ersi M, Brahimi E, Hassanipour S, Fathalipour M, Hassaniazad M. Efficacy and safety of ivermectin in patients with mild and moderate COVID-19: a randomized controlled trial. Asian Pac J Trop Med. 2023;16(1):3&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayward G, Yu LM, Little P, Gbinigie O, Shanyinde M, Harris V, Dorward J, Saville BR, Berry N, Evans PH, et al. Ivermectin for COVID-19 in adults in the community (PRINCIPLE): An open, randomised, controlled, adaptive platform trial of short- and longer-term outcomes. J Infect. 2024;88(4):106130.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>