<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41930058</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intensive Care Management of Anti-Mi2-Positive Dermatomyositis: Lupus Overlap Syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e104509</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e104509</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e104509</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.104509</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We report the case of a 49-year-old woman diagnosed with an autoimmune overlap syndrome characterized by anti-Mi2-positive dermatomyositis and systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE), presenting with extreme hyper-creatine kinase (CK) levels (&gt;3000 U/L), progressive muscle weakness, and respiratory failure requiring intensive care management. Muscle biopsy revealed chronic inflammatory myopathy with perifascicular necrosis, and immunologic testing showed antinuclear antibody (ANA) 1:640, anti-double-stranded (ds)DNA, and anti-Mi2 positivity, confirming the diagnosis. During her clinical course, she developed hypoxemic respiratory failure, multiple endocrine dysfunctions (central hypopituitarism and autoimmune hypothyroidism), and nosocomial infections, all of which were successfully controlled. She received intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG) therapy followed by five sessions of therapeutic plasma exchange (PLEX) (1.5 plasma volumes replaced with albumin), achieving partial muscle strength recovery, a 60% reduction in CK levels, and hemodynamic stabilization. This case represents a rare and severe form of dermatomyositis-lupus overlap syndrome with critical evolution and favorable response to combined immunomodulatory therapy. It highlights the importance of early diagnosis, multidisciplinary management, and the timely use of therapeutic PLEX as a rescue treatment for refractory autoimmune diseases in critically ill patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Ruiz Barrera et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ruiz Barrera</LastName><ForeName>Maria Dioselina</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Hospital Regional de Alta Especialidad de Ixtapaluca, Ixtapaluca, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Galvan Merlos</LastName><ForeName>Maria Alaciel</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Critical Care Medicine, Hospital Regional de Alta Especialidad de Ixtapaluca, Ixtapaluca, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castro Meza</LastName><ForeName>Jorge Omar</ForeName><Initials>JO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Critical Care Medicine, Hospital Regional de Alta Especialidad de Ixtapaluca, Ixtapaluca, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayala Davila</LastName><ForeName>Dafne Thamara</ForeName><Initials>DT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Hospital Regional de Alta Especialidad de Ixtapaluca, Ixtapaluca, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gardu&#xf1;o Becerra</LastName><ForeName>Janeet</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Hospital Regional de Alta Especialidad de Ixtapaluca, Ixtapaluca, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adult-onset dermatomyositis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anti-mi-2a antibodies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">auto immune</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmune overlap syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">critical care and internal medicine education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hospital mexico</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">serum creatinine phosphokinase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sle and myositis overlap syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sytemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic plasmapheresis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41930058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13038630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.104509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Intravenous immunoglobulin in autoimmune neuromuscular diseases. Dalakas MC. JAMA. 2004;291:2367&#x2013;2375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15150209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnosis and classification of idiopathic inflammatory myopathies. Lundberg IE, Miller FW, Tj&#xe4;rnlund A, Bottai M. J Intern Med. 2016;280:39&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5021058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27320359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myositis-specific autoantibodies: an important tool to support diagnosis of myositis. Betteridge Z, McHugh N. J Intern Med. 2016;280:8&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26602539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The clinical phenotype of patients positive for antibodies to myositis and myositis-related disorders. Gofrit SG, Yonath H, Lidar M, Shoenfeld Y, Kivity S. Clin Rheumatol. 2018;37:1257&#x2013;1263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29453582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polymyositis/dermatomyositis is a potential risk factor for acute respiratory failure: a pulmonary heart disease. Syue SH, Chang YH, Shih PJ, Lin CL, Yeh JJ, Kao CH. Ann Transl Med. 2020;8:202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7154474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32309349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overlap of systemic lupus erythematosus and myositis is rare in anti-Ku antibody-positive patients. Ogawa-Momohara M, Muro Y, Akiyama M. Ann Rheum Dis. 2021;80:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31604706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term survival of patients with idiopathic inflammatory myopathies according to clinical features: a longitudinal study of 162 cases. Dank&#xf3; K, Ponyi A, Constantin T, Borgulya G, Szegedi G. Medicine (Baltimore) 2004;83:35&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14747766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>119th ENMC international workshop: trial design in adult idiopathic inflammatory myopathies, with the exception of inclusion body myositis, 10-12 October 2003, Naarden, The Netherlands. Hoogendijk JE, Amato AA, Lecky BR, et al. Neuromuscul Disord. 2004;14:337&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15099594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Role of autoantibodies in the diagnosis and prognosis of interstitial lung disease in autoimmune rheumatic disorders. Kuwana M, Gil-Vila A, Selva-O'Callaghan A. Ther Adv Musculoskelet Dis. 2021;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8320553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34377160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidelines on the use of therapeutic apheresis in clinical practice &#x2014; evidence-based approach from the Writing Committee of the American Society for Apheresis: the ninth special issue. Connelly-Smith L, Alquist CR, Aqui NA, et al. J Clin Apher. 2023;38:77&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37017433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidelines on the use of therapeutic apheresis in clinical practice &#x2014; evidence-based approach from the Writing Committee of the American Society for Apheresis: the seventh special issue. Schwartz J, Padmanabhan A, Aqui N, et al. J Clin Apher. 2016;31:149&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27322218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dermatomyositis: muscle pathology according to antibody subtypes. Tanboon J, Inoue M, Saito Y, et al. Neurology. 2022;98:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8865893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34873015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An overview of polymyositis and dermatomyositis. Findlay AR, Goyal NA, Mozaffar T. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51:638&#x2013;656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25641317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monocyte/macrophage differentiation in dermatomyositis and polymyositis. Rostasy KM, Piepkorn M, Goebel HH, Menck S, Hanefeld F, Schulz-Schaeffer WJ. Muscle Nerve. 2004;30:225&#x2013;230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15266639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dermatomyositis and polymyositis: clinical presentation, autoantibodies, and pathogenesis. Mammen AL. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2010;1184:134&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20146695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comprehensive overview on myositis-specific antibodies: new and old biomarkers in idiopathic inflammatory myopathy. Satoh M, Tanaka S, Ceribelli A, Calise SJ, Chan EK. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2017;52:1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5828023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26424665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A rare case of anti-Mi-2 antibody-positive dermatomyositis associated with gastrointestinal stromal tumor. Akpoigbe O, Anim-Koranteng C, Tasmin R, Sammut A. J Rheumatol. 2024;51:944&#x2013;945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38749561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idiopathic inflammatory myopathies. Lundberg IE, Fujimoto M, Vencovsky J, et al. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2021;7:87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10425161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34857780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inflammatory muscle diseases. Dalakas MC. N Engl J Med. 2015;372:1734&#x2013;1747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25923553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>