<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41779708</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tailored job coaching for people with severe mental illness living in supported housing settings: A realist approach.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0343044</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0343044</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0343044</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0343044</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">For people with severe mental illness (SMI) residing in supported housing settings, finding and maintaining paid or unpaid work is challenging. This study was initiated to examine how professionals tailor job coaching trajectories to effectively address the specific needs of clients. The aim was to unravel the complexity of these trajectories, providing a deeper understanding of how and under what circumstances people with SMI in supported housing can obtain and sustain meaningful daily activities, including paid or unpaid work, as part of their recovery journey.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Interviews were conducted with 24 clients with severe mental illness (SMI) and their job coaches (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;15) in dyads. Additionally, two mixed focus group discussions were held with job coaches (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;16) and their supervisors (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;2). A realist evaluation approach was used to determine what works for whom, how, and under which conditions. Self-Determination Theory (SDT) served as the analytical framework to explore the motivational factors that drive clients to seek and retain paid or unpaid work.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Our findings are structured in three sections, each focusing on context-intervention-mechanism-outcome (CIMO) configurations. These configurations illustrate how job coaches address clients' needs for relatedness, competence and autonomy. The findings provide a deeper understanding of the inner workings of job coaching trajectories, showing how job coaches foster autonomous motivation and thereby enable clients to obtain and retain both paid and unpaid work.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study highlights that there is no universal approach to job coaching. Job coaching requires a tailored approach with a strong emphasis on building personal-professional relationships and adapting interventions to individual circumstances.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Binkhorst et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Binkhorst</LastName><ForeName>Joep</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-1284-4759</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Group Decent Work, Research Centre for Social Innovation, University of Applied Sciences Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dikkers</LastName><ForeName>Josje</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Group Decent Work, Research Centre for Social Innovation, University of Applied Sciences Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blonk</LastName><ForeName>Roland</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department Tranzo, Scientific Center for Care and Wellbeing, Tilburg School of Social and Behavioral Sciences, Tilburg University, Tilburg, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Optentia, North West University, Vanderbijlpark, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Veldhoven</LastName><ForeName>Marc</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department Human Resource Studies, Tilburg School of Social and Behavioral Sciences, Tilburg University, Tilburg, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001523" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mental Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071252" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mentoring</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009042" MajorTopicYN="N">Motivation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017144" MajorTopicYN="N">Focus Groups</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41779708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12959649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0343044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-13591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Modini M, Joyce S, Mykletun A, Christensen H, Bryant RA, Mitchell PB, et al. The mental health benefits of employment: results of a systematic meta-review. Australas Psychiatry. 2016;24(4):331&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1177/1039856215618523</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1039856215618523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26773063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuring M. The role of health and health promotion in labour force participation [Doctoral Thesis]. Rotterdam: Erasmus University Rotterdam; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Corrales J, Huertas-Hoyas E, Garc&#xed;a-Bravo C, G&#xfc;eita-Rodr&#xed;guez J, Palacios-Ce&#xf1;a D. Volunteering as a meaningful occupation in the process of recovery from serious mental illness: a qualitative study. Am J Occup Ther. 2022;76(2):7602205090. doi: 10.5014/ajot.2022.045104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5014/ajot.2022.045104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35201298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn EC, Wewiorski NJ, Rogers ES. The meaning and importance of employment to people in recovery from serious mental illness: results of a qualitative study. Psychiatr Rehabil J. 2008;32(1):59&#x2013;62. doi: 10.2975/32.1.2008.59.62</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2975/32.1.2008.59.62</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18614451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delespaul P, van Weeghel J, EPA CG. Consensus over de definitie van mensen met een ernstige psychische aandoening (EPA) en hun aantal in Nederland. Tijdschrift voor Psychiatrie. 2013;2013(6):427&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23864410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patmisari E, Huang Y, Orr M, Govindasamy S, Hielscher E, McLaren H. Supported employment interventions with people who have severe mental illness: systematic mixed-methods umbrella review. PLoS One. 2024;19(6):e0304527. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0304527</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0304527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11152269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38838025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Winter L, Couwenbergh C, van Weeghel J, Sanches S, Michon H, Bond GR. Who benefits from individual placement and support? A meta-analysis. Epidemiol Psychiatr Sci. 2022;31:e50. doi: 10.1017/S2045796022000300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S2045796022000300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9281491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35815640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lange A, Michon HWC, Knispel A, Hulsbosch L, Twisk JWR, Kroon H. It is not only competitive employment that counts: findings from a longitudinal panel of people with severe mental illness. Psychiatr Rehabil J. 2022;45(3):266&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1037/prj0000524</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/prj0000524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35771516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knaeps J, DeSmet A, Van Audenhove C. The IPS fidelity scale as a guideline to implement Supported Employment. J Vocat Rehabil. 2012;37(1):13&#x2013;23. doi: 10.3233/jvr-2012-0596</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/jvr-2012-0596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michon H, van Weeghel J. Rehabilitatieonderzoek in Nederland. Overzicht van onderzoek en synthese van bevindingen in 2000-2008. Tijdschr Psychiatr. 2010;52(10):683&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20931482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beek L, van Geel S, Oortwijn W, Pickles A, Versteegh M. Zo gek nog niet, aan het werk met een psychische stoornis. Vooronderzoek: literatuurstudie. Rotterdam: Ecorys; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinchmann B, Widding-Havneraas T, Modini M, Rinaldi M, Moe CF, McDaid D, et al. A meta-regression of the impact of policy on the efficacy of individual placement and support. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2020;141(3):206&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1111/acps.13129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acps.13129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31733146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frederick DE, VanderWeele TJ. Supported employment: Meta-analysis and review of randomized controlled trials of individual placement and support. PLoS One. 2019;14(2):e0212208. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0212208</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0212208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6382127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30785954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metcalfe JD, Drake RE, Bond GR. Economic, labor, and regulatory moderators of the effect of individual placement and support among people with severe mental illness: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Schizophr Bull. 2018;44(1):22&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1093/schbul/sbx132</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/schbul/sbx132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5768052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29036727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luciano A, Bond GR, Drake RE. Does employment alter the course and outcome of schizophrenia and other severe mental illnesses? A systematic review of longitudinal research. Schizophr Res. 2014;159(2&#x2013;3):312&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.schres.2014.09.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.schres.2014.09.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25278105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthony WA, Cohen M, Farkas M, Gagne C. Psychiatric rehabilitation. 2nd ed. Boston, MA: Boston University, Center for Psychiatric Rehabilitation; 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weld-Blundell I, Shields M, Devine A, Dickinson H, Kavanagh A, Marck C. Vocational interventions to improve employment participation of people with psychosocial disability, autism and/or intellectual disability: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(22):12083. doi: 10.3390/ijerph182212083</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph182212083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8618542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34831840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michon H, van Busschbach JT, Stant AD, van Vugt MD, van Weeghel J, Kroon H. Effectiveness of individual placement and support for people with severe mental illness in The Netherlands: a 30-month randomized controlled trial. Psychiatr Rehabil J. 2014;37(2):129&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1037/prj0000061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/prj0000061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24912062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loef B, van Oostrom S, Proper K. De effectiviteit van &#x2018;Individuele plaatsing en steun&#x2019; (IPS) op gezondheid en participatie. RIVM brief rapport 2020-0182. Bilthoven: RIVM; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanches SA, Swildens WE, Schaefer B, Moerbeek M, Feenstra TL, van Asselt ADI, et al. Effectiveness of the Boston University approach to psychiatric rehabilitation in improving social participation in people with severe mental illnesses: a randomized controlled trial. Front Psychiatry. 2020;11:571640. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2020.571640</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2020.571640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7538503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33173519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boumans J, Knispel A, Kroon H, Michon H, Hulsbosch L, De Lange A. De ambivalentie van werk. <i>Participatie en Herstel</i> [2 &#x2013; 2020]. Amsterdam: SWP; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouwers EPM, Joosen MCW, van Zelst C, Van Weeghel J. To disclose or not to disclose: a multi-stakeholder focus group study on mental health issues in the work environment. J Occup Rehabil. 2020;30(1):84&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1007/s10926-019-09848-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10926-019-09848-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7031172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31410722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasalvia A, Zoppei S, Van Bortel T, Bonetto C, Cristofalo D, Wahlbeck K, et al. Global pattern of experienced and anticipated discrimination reported by people with major depressive disorder: a cross-sectional survey. Lancet. 2013;381(9860):55&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(12)61379-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(12)61379-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23083627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepherd G, Boardman J, Slade M. Making recovery a reality. Policy Paper. London: Sainsbury Centre for Mental Health; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwan A, Berinstein S, Morris J, Barbic S. Perspectives on implementing Individual Placement and Support (IPS) within primary health care settings for adults living in British Columbia, Canada. BMC Psychiatry. 2023;23(1):919. doi: 10.1186/s12888-023-05395-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-023-05395-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10704795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38062406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDowell C, Ennals P, Fossey E. Vocational service models and approaches to improve job tenure of people with severe and enduring mental illness: a narrative review. Front Psychiatry. 2021;12:668716. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2021.668716</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2021.668716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8298859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34305676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kordsmeyer A-C, Lengen JC, Kiepe N, Harth V, Mache S. Working conditions in social firms and health promotion interventions in relation to employees&#x2019; health and work-related outcomes-a scoping review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(11):3963. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17113963</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17113963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7312385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32503252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doroud N, Fossey E, Fortune T. Recovery as an occupational journey: a scoping review exploring the links between occupational engagement and recovery for people with enduring mental health issues. Aust Occup Ther J. 2015;62(6):378&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1111/1440-1630.12238</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1440-1630.12238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26555561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Held ML, Lee S. Relationship between volunteering and perceived general health of individuals with serious mental illness. Community Ment Health J. 2020;56(2):348&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1007/s10597-019-00475-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10597-019-00475-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31571087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Winter L, Couwenbergh C, van Weeghel J, Bergmans C, Bond GR. Fidelity and IPS: does quality of implementation predict vocational outcomes over time for organizations treating persons with severe mental illness in the Netherlands? Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2020;55(12):1607&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1007/s00127-020-01890-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00127-020-01890-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32468101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bitter N, Roeg D, van Assen M, van Nieuwenhuizen C, van Weeghel J. How effective is the comprehensive approach to rehabilitation (CARe) methodology? A cluster randomized controlled trial. BMC Psychiatry. 2017;17(1):396. doi: 10.1186/s12888-017-1565-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-017-1565-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5725818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29228919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Haaren M, de Jong S, Roeg DPK. The foundations of the working alliance in assertive community treatment teams. BMC Psychiatry. 2021;21(1):559. doi: 10.1186/s12888-021-03563-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-021-03563-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8582115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34758777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanches SA, van Busschbach JT, Michon HWC, van Weeghel J, Swildens WE. The role of working alliance in attainment of personal goals and improvement in quality of life during psychiatric rehabilitation. Psychiatr Serv. 2018;69(8):903&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1176/appi.ps.201700438</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ps.201700438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29734920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanches SA. Working towards social participation: helping individuals with severe mental illnesses reach their goals related to work, education, and meaningful daily activities through psychiatric rehabilitation. s.l.: Proefschriftmaken; 2021. 224 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vukadin M, Schaafsma FG, Vlaar SJ, van Busschbach JT, van de Ven PM, Michon HWC, et al. Work motivation and employment outcomes in people with severe mental illness. J Occup Rehabil. 2019;29(4):803&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1007/s10926-019-09839-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10926-019-09839-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6838012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31154594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medalia A, Saperstein A. The role of motivation for treatment success. Schizophr Bull. 2011;37 Suppl 2(Suppl 2):S122-8. doi: 10.1093/schbul/sbr063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/schbul/sbr063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3160119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21860041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundermann LM, Haunberger S, Gisler F, Kita Z. How do supported employment programs work? Answers from a systematic literature review. Int J Educ Vocat Guid. 2023;23(3):659&#x2013;79. doi: 10.1007/s10775-022-09533-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10775-022-09533-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10444632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37621963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackwood B, O&#x2019;Halloran P, Porter S. On the problems of mixing RCTs with qualitative research: the case of the MRC framework for the evaluation of complex healthcare interventions. J Res Nurs. 2010;15(6):511&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1177/1744987110373860</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1744987110373860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hees S, Carlier B, Joosen M, Blonk R, Oomens S. A workplace intervention to strengthen supervisor support for employees with common mental health problems: a mixed-methods realist evaluation. Scand J Work Organ Psychol. 2024;9(1):9. doi: 10.16993/sjwop.249</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16993/sjwop.249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagosh J. Realist synthesis for public health: building an ontologically deep understanding of how programs work, for whom, and in which contexts. Annu Rev Public Health. 2019;40:361&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1146/annurev-publhealth-031816-044451</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-publhealth-031816-044451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30633712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawson R. The science of evaluation: a realist manifesto. London: SAGE Publications Ltd; 2013. doi: 10.4135/9781473913820</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4135/9781473913820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawson R, Greenhalgh T, Harvey G, Walshe K. Realist review--a new method of systematic review designed for complex policy interventions. J Health Serv Res Policy. 2005;10 Suppl 1:21&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1258/1355819054308530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1258/1355819054308530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16053581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boevink WA. HEE! Over Herstel, Empowerment en Ervaringsdeskundigheid in de psychiatrie. Utrecht: Trimbos-instituut; 2017. doi: 10.26481/dis.20170413wb</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26481/dis.20170413wb</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake RE, Bond GR. Individual placement and support: history, current status, and future directions. PCN Rep. 2023;2(3):e122. doi: 10.1002/pcn5.122</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pcn5.122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11114326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38867819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajzen I. The theory of planned behavior. Organ Behav Hum Decis Process. 1991;50:179&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Social learning theory. Englewood Cliffs (NJ): Prentice Hall; 1977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan RM, Deci EL. Self-determination theory and the facilitation of intrinsic motivation, social development, and well-being. Am Psychol. 2000;55(1):68&#x2013;78. doi: 10.1037//0003-066x.55.1.68</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037//0003-066x.55.1.68</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11392867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook DA, Artino AR Jr. Motivation to learn: an overview of contemporary theories. Med Educ. 2016;50(10):997&#x2013;1014. doi: 10.1111/medu.13074</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/medu.13074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5113774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27628718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Bell L, Dikkers J. Organiseren van waardig werk voor mensen met een kwetsbare arbeidsmarktpositie. TvA. 2022;38(1):105&#x2013;16. doi: 10.5117/tva2022.1.009.bell</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5117/tva2022.1.009.bell</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulsebosch J, Wielers R. Ongelijkheid en verschillen in intrinsieke en extrinsieke arbeidsmotivatie. TvA. 2018;34(2):200&#x2013;20. doi: 10.5117/2018.034.002.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5117/2018.034.002.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancini AD. Self-determination theory: a framework for the recovery paradigm. Adv psychiatr treat. 2008;14(5):358&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1192/apt.bp.107.004036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/apt.bp.107.004036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SAMHSA. National consensus statement on mental health recovery. Rockville (MD): US Department of Health and Human Services, Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, Center for Mental Health Services; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong G, Westhorp G, Manzano A, Greenhalgh J, Jagosh J, Greenhalgh T. RAMESES II reporting standards for realist evaluations. BMC Med. 2016;14(1):96. doi: 10.1186/s12916-016-0643-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-016-0643-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4920991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27342217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalkin SM, Greenhalgh J, Jones D, Cunningham B, Lhussier M. What&#x2019;s in a mechanism? Development of a key concept in realist evaluation. Implement Sci. 2015;10:49. doi: 10.1186/s13012-015-0237-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-015-0237-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4408605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25885787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westhorp G. Realist impact evaluation: an introduction. London: Overseas Development Institute; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denyer D, Tranfield D, van Aken JE. Developing design propositions through research synthesis. Organ Stud. 2008;29(3):393&#x2013;413. doi: 10.1177/0170840607088020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0170840607088020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza DE. Elaborating the Context-Mechanism-Outcome configuration (CMOc) in realist evaluation: a critical realist perspective. Evaluation. 2013;19(2):141&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1177/1356389013485194</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1356389013485194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halminen O, Chen A, Tenhunen H, Lillrank P. Demonstrating the value of digital health: guidance on contextual evidence gathering for companies in different stages of maturity. Health Serv Manage Res. 2021;34(1):13&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1177/0951484820971447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0951484820971447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33291977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hees SGM, Carlier BE, Blonk RWB, Oomens S. Understanding work participation among employees with common mental disorders: what works, for whom, under what circumstances and how? A systematic realist review protocol. Work. 2021;69(3):827&#x2013;38. doi: 10.3233/WOR-213515</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/WOR-213515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8385521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34180455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emmel N, Greenhalgh J, Manzano A, Monaghan M, Dalkin S, editors. Doing realist research. London: SAGE Publications Ltd; 2018. Available from: doi: 10.4135/9781526451729</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4135/9781526451729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagosh J, Stott H, Halls S, Thomas R, Liddiard C, Cupples M, et al. Benefits of realist evaluation for rapidly changing health service delivery. BMJ Open. 2022;12(7):e060347. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2021-060347</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2021-060347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9335061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35896288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawson R, Greenhalgh T, Harvey G, Walshe K. Realist review--a new method of systematic review designed for complex policy interventions. J Health Serv Res Policy. 2005;10 Suppl 1:21&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1258/1355819054308530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1258/1355819054308530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16053581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa E, Soares AL, Pinho de Sousa J. Exploring the CIMO-logic in the design of collaborative networks mediated by digital platforms. In: Camarinha-Matos L, Afsarmanesh H, Rezgui Y, editors. IFIP advances in information and communication technology. Cham: Springer Nature; 2018. p. 266&#x2013;77. (IFIP Advances in Information and Communication Technology). doi: 10.1007/978-3-319-99127-6_23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-99127-6_23</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eastwood J, Barmaky S, Hansen S, Millere E, Ratcliff S, Fotheringham P, et al. Refining program theory for a place-based integrated care initiative in Sydney, Australia. Int J Integr Care. 2020;20(3):13. doi: 10.5334/ijic.5422</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5334/ijic.5422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7528678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33041730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagosh J, Pluye P, Macaulay AC, Salsberg J, Henderson J, Sirett E, et al. Assessing the outcomes of participatory research: protocol for identifying, selecting, appraising and synthesizing the literature for realist review. Implement Sci. 2011;6:24. doi: 10.1186/1748-5908-6-24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-6-24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3072934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21418604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeije HR, Bleijenbergh I. Analyseren in kwalitatief onderzoek: Denken en doen. Amsterdam: Boom; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukumbang FC, Marchal B, Van Belle S, van Wyk B. Using the realist interview approach to maintain theoretical awareness in realist studies. Qual Res. 2020;20(4):485&#x2013;515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzano A. The craft of interviewing in realist evaluation. Evaluation. 2016;22(3):342&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1177/1356389016638615</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1356389016638615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawson R. Theorizing the interview. Br J Sociol. 1996;47(2):295. doi: 10.2307/591728</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/591728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual Res Psychol. 2006;3(2):77&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guba EG, Lincoln YS. Fourth generation evaluation. Newbury Park (CA): SAGE; 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong A, Sainsbury P, Craig J. Consolidated criteria for reporting qualitative research (COREQ): a 32-item checklist for interviews and focus groups. Int J Qual Health Care. 2007;19(6):349&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1093/intqhc/mzm042</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intqhc/mzm042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priebe S, McCabe R, Bullenkamp J, Hansson L, Lauber C, Martinez-Leal R, et al. Structured patient-clinician communication and 1-year outcome in community mental healthcare: cluster randomised controlled trial. Br J Psychiatry. 2007;191:420&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1192/bjp.bp.107.036939</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.107.036939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17978322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilken JPL. Recovering care: a contribution to a theory and practice of good care. Amsterdam: SWP; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lean M, Fornells-Ambrojo M, Milton A, Lloyd-Evans B, Harrison-Stewart B, Yesufu-Udechuku A, et al. Self-management interventions for people with severe mental illness: systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Psychiatry. 2019;214(5):260&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1192/bjp.2019.54</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.2019.54</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6499726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30898177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herman JL. Trauma &amp; herstel: de gevolgen van geweld. Van mishandeling thuis tot politiek geweld. Amsterdam: Wereldbibliotheek; 2016. 202 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x200c;Korevaar EL, Dr&#xf6;es J, editors. Handboek rehabilitatie voor zorg en welzijn: ondersteuning van maatschappelijke participatie en herstel. 3rd ed. Bussum: Uitgeverij Coutinho; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Wel T, van Weeghel J. Vroege psychose vereist vroege rehabilitatie. In: Handboek Vroege Psychose Diagnostiek, behandeling, rehabilitatie en organisatie van zorg. Amsterdam: SWP; 2013. p. 142&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scanlan JN, Feder K, Ennals P, Hancock N. Outcomes of an individual placement and support programme incorporating principles of the collaborative recovery model. Aust Occup Ther J. 2019;66(4):519&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1111/1440-1630.12580</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1440-1630.12580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31134658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan DL, Eliot S, Lowe RA, Gorman P. Dyadic interviews as a tool for qualitative evaluation. Am J Eval. 2015;37(1):109&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1177/1098214015611244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1098214015611244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klevan T, Jonassen R, S&#xe6;l&#xf8;r KT, Borg M. Using dyadic interviews to explore recovery as collaborative practices: challenging the epistemic norm of the single person perspective. Int J Qual Methods. 2020;19:160940692096786. doi: 10.1177/1609406920967860</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1609406920967860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Pawson R, Wong G, et al. The realist interview. In: The RAMESES II project, 2017. Available from: https://www.ramesesproject.org/media/RAMESES_II_Realist_interviewing.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilmore B. Realist evaluations in low- and middle-income countries: reflections and recommendations from the experiences of a foreign researcher. BMJ Glob Health. 2019;4(5):e001638. doi: 10.1136/bmjgh-2019-001638</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2019-001638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6830045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31749993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen K, Randall R. Opening the black box: presenting a model for evaluating organizational-level interventions. Eur J Work Organ Psychol. 2013;22(5):601&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1080/1359432x.2012.690556</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1359432x.2012.690556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corrigan PW, Mueser KT, Bond GR, Drake RE, Solomon P. Principles and practices of psychiatric rehabilitation: an empirical approach. New York: Guilford Press; 2008.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>