<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41645885</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1553-5606</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of hospital medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hosp Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A randomized trial of I-SLEEP: A patient education and empowerment intervention on inpatient sleep duration and medical sleep disruptions.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jhm.70273</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Sleep is essential for recovery in hospitalized patients, yet frequent disruptions from medical care make rest difficult. Most prior efforts have focused on environmental modifications, often overlooking patients' role in advocating for their sleep.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study evaluated the effectiveness of the Inpatient Sleep Loss: Educating and Empowering Patients (I-SLEEP) intervention in improving sleep duration and reducing medical care disruptions among hospitalized patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this single-center randomized controlled trial (NCT04151251), general medicine patients at the University of Chicago were randomized to either I-SLEEP (sleep education, advocacy questions, and a sleep kit) or standard care (sleep kit alone) between July 2019 and March 2023. The primary outcome was patient-reported sleep duration. Secondary outcomes included actigraphy-measured sleep duration and continuity (efficiency and wake after sleep onset), as well as patient-reported sleep disruptions. Mixed effects models adjusted for covariates were used for analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 194 participants were enrolled. There were no significant differences in demographic characteristics between groups. Sleep duration and continuity did not differ significantly between groups. However, patients receiving I-SLEEP reported fewer disruptions from vital sign monitoring (63% vs. 75%, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.004), medication administration (49% vs. 61%, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.003), and laboratory draws (57% vs. 68%, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;.009). These findings remained significant after adjusting for covariates.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">I-SLEEP did not increase sleep duration or continuity but reduced medical care disruptions. These findings suggest that patient education and empowerment may be effective strategies for reducing preventable care-related sleep disruptions in hospitals. Further research should examine implementation at scale and potential long-term benefits.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Journal of Hospital Medicine published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Society of Hospital Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sunderrajan</LastName><ForeName>Aashna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3615-0118</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cursio</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2131-1767</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health Sciences, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mason</LastName><ForeName>Noah</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, University of Colorado, Boulder, Colorado, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Byron</LastName><ForeName>Maxx</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chicago School of Professional Psychology, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martinez</LastName><ForeName>Maylyn</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orlov</LastName><ForeName>Nicola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Knutson</LastName><ForeName>Kristen L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Circadian and Sleep Medicine, Northwestern University, Evanston, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mokhlesi</LastName><ForeName>Babak</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Rush University, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Press</LastName><ForeName>Valerie G</ForeName><Initials>VG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meltzer</LastName><ForeName>David O</ForeName><Initials>DO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arora</LastName><ForeName>Vineet M</ForeName><Initials>VM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K23 MD019072</GrantID><Acronym>MD</Acronym><Agency>NIMHD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K24HL136859-05</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Hosp Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101271025</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1553-5592</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41645885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jhm.70273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Stewart NH, Arora VM. Sleep in hospitalized patients. In: Badr MS, Martin JL, eds. Essentials of sleep medicine: a practical approach to patients with sleep complaints. 2nd ed. Humana; 2022: 453&#x2010;470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossman MN, Anderson SL, Worku A, et al. Awakenings? Patient and hospital staff perceptions of nighttime disruptions and their effect on patient sleep. J Clin Sleep Med. 2017;13(2):301&#x2010;306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friese RS, Diaz&#x2010;Arrastia R, McBride D, Frankel H, Gentilello LM. Quantity and quality of sleep in the surgical intensive care unit: are our patients sleeping? J Trauma. 2007;63(6):1210&#x2010;1214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoder JC, Staisiunas PG, Meltzer DO, Knutson KL, Arora VM. Noise and sleep among adult medical inpatients: far from a quiet night. Arch Intern Med. 2012;172(1):68&#x2010;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pamuk K, Turan N. The effect of light on sleep quality and physiological parameters in patients in the intensive care unit. Appl Nurs Res. 2022;66:151607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora VM, Machado N, Anderson SL, et al. Effectiveness of SIESTA on objective and subjective metrics of nighttime hospital sleep disruptors. J Hosp Med. 2019;14(1):38&#x2010;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa&#x2010;Ramos MI, Arroyo&#x2010;Novoa CM, Lee KA, Padilla G, Puntillo KA. Sleep and delirium in ICU patients: a review of mechanisms and manifestations. Intensive Care Med. 2009;35(5):781&#x2010;795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Innv&#xe6;r KS, Myklatun SH Sleep deprivation and its consequences on health&#x2013;with emphasis on metabolic and immunological functions. Bachelor's thesis, H&#xf8;gskulen p&#xe5; Vestlandet.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora VM, Chang KL, Fazal AZ, et al. Objective sleep duration and quality in hospitalized older adults: associations with blood pressure and mood. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2011;59(11):2185&#x2010;2186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knutson KL, Spiegel K, Penev P, Van Cauter E. The metabolic consequences of sleep deprivation. Sleep Med Rev. 2007;11(3):163&#x2010;178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews EE. Sleep disturbances and fatigue in critically ill patients. AACN Adv Crit Care. 2011;22(3):204&#x2010;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xdc;nsal A, Demir G. Evaluation of sleep quality and fatigue in hospitalized patients. Int J Caring Sci. 2012;Sep 5(3):311&#x2010;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willinger CM, Waddell KJ, Arora V, Patel MS, Ryan Greysen S. Patient&#x2010;reported sleep and physical function during and after hospitalization. Sleep health. 2024;10(2):249&#x2010;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler R, Knutson KL, Mokhlesi B, et al. Sleep and activity patterns in older patients discharged from the hospital. Sleep. 2019;42(11):zsz153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labrosciano C, Tavella R, Reynolds A, et al. The association between sleep duration and quality with readmissions: an exploratory pilot&#x2010;study among cardiology inpatients. Clocks Sleep. 2020;2(2):120&#x2010;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin JL, Fiorentino L, Jouldjian S, Mitchell M, Josephson KR, Alessi CA. Poor self&#x2010;reported sleep quality predicts mortality within one year of inpatient post&#x2010;acute rehabilitation among older adults. Sleep. 2011;34(12):1715&#x2010;1721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweity S, Finlay A, Lees C, Monk A, Sherpa T, Wade D. SleepSure: a pilot randomized&#x2010;controlled trial to assess the effects of eye masks and earplugs on the quality of sleep for patients in hospital. Clin Rehabil. 2019;33(2):253&#x2010;261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babaii A, Adib&#x2010;Hajbaghery M, Hajibagheri A. Effect of using eye mask on sleep quality in cardiac patients: a randomized controlled trial. Nurs Midwifery Stud. 2015;4(4):e28332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendon&#xe7;a SC, Martins DMS, Dur&#xe3;o C, Teixeira JMF, da Silva Rafael Henriques HM. Sleep&#x2010;enhancing nursing interventions in hospital wards: A systematic review. Int Nurs Rev. 2025; 72(1):e13062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDaniel LM, Seshadri N, Harkins EA, et al. Promoting a sleep&#x2010;friendly environment by minimizing overnight room entries. Pediatr Qual Saf. 2023;8(6):e668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bion V, Lowe AS, Puthucheary Z, Montgomery H. Reducing sound and light exposure to improve sleep on the adult intensive care unit: an inclusive narrative review. J Intensive Care Soc. 2018;19(2):138&#x2010;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahcecioglu Turan G, G&#xfc;rcan F, &#xd6;zer Z. The effects of eye masks and earplugs on sleep quality, anxiety, fear, and vital signs in patients in an intensive care unit: a randomised controlled study. J Sleep Res. 2024;33(2):e14044.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson A, Allsop M, Coghill E, Turnock C. Earplugs and eye masks: do they improve critical care patients' sleep? Nurs Crit Care. 2007;12(6):278&#x2010;286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demoule A, Carreira S, Lavault S, et al. Impact of earplugs and eye mask on sleep in critically ill patients: a prospective randomized study. Crit Care. 2017;21(1):284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu RF, Jiang XY, Hegadoren KM, Zhang YH. Effects of earplugs and eye masks combined with relaxing music on sleep, melatonin and cortisol levels in ICU patients: a randomized controlled trial. Crit Care. 2015;19(1):115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holleck ME, Tikkanen K, Holleck JL, et al. Reducing nighttime interruptions and improving sleep for hospitalized patients by restructuring nighttime clinical workflow. J Gen Intern Med. 2023;38(9):2091&#x2010;2097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beswick AD, Wylde V, Bertram W, Whale K. The effectiveness of non&#x2010;pharmacological sleep interventions for improving inpatient sleep in hospital: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sleep Med. 2023;107:243&#x2010;267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Affini MI, Arora VM, Gulati J, et al. Defining existing practices to support the sleep of hospitalized patients: A mixed&#x2010;methods study of top&#x2010;ranked hospitals. J Hosp Med. 2022;17(8):633&#x2010;638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hibbard JH, Greene J. What the evidence shows about patient activation: better health outcomes and care experiences; fewer data on costs. Health Aff. 2013;32(2):207&#x2010;214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alegr&#xed;a M, Polo A, Gao S, et al. Evaluation of a patient activation and empowerment intervention in mental health care. Med Care. 2008;46(3):247&#x2010;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietrich SK, Francis&#x2010;Jimenez CM, Knibbs MD, Umali IL, Truglio&#x2010;Londrigan M. Effectiveness of sleep education programs to improve sleep hygiene and/or sleep quality in college students: a systematic review. JBI Evid Synth. 2016;14(9):108&#x2010;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung KF, Lee CT, Yeung WF, Chan MS, Chung EWY, Lin WL. Sleep hygiene education as a treatment of insomnia: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Fam Pract. 2018;35(4):365&#x2010;375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hittle BM, Hils J, Fendinger SL, Wong IS. A scoping review of sleep education and training for nurses. Int J Nurs Stud. 2023;142:104468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi M, Staisiunas PG, Knutson KL, Beveridge C, Meltzer DO, Arora VM. Perceived control and sleep in hospitalized older adults: a sound hypothesis? J Hosp Med. 2013;8(4):184&#x2010;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason NR, Orlov NM, Anderson S, Byron M, Mozer C, Arora VM. Piloting I&#x2010;SLEEP: a patient&#x2010;centered education and empowerment intervention to improve patients' in&#x2010;hospital sleep. Pilot Feasibility Stud. 2021;7(1):161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHLBI sleep brochure [Internet] National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute; 2018. https://www.nhlbi.nih.gov/health-topics/all-publications-and-resources/sleep-brochure</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keklund G, &#xc5;kerstedt T. Objective components of individual differences in subjective sleep quality. J Sleep Res. 1997;6(4):217&#x2010;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh A, Hauri PJ, Kripke DF, Lavie P. The role of actigraphy in the evaluation of sleep disorders. Sleep. 1995; 18(4):288&#x2010;302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedman NS, Kotzer N, Schwab RJ. Patient perception of sleep quality and etiology of sleep disruption in the intensive care unit. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 1999;159(4):1155&#x2010;1162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Thielke R, Payne J, Gonzalez N, Conde JG. Research electronic data capture (REDCap)&#x2014;a metadata&#x2010;driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J Biomed Inf. 2009;42(2):377&#x2010;381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamrat R, Huynh&#x2010;Le MP, Goyal M. Non&#x2010;pharmacologic interventions to improve the sleep of hospitalized patients: a systematic review. J Gen Intern Med. 2014;29(5):788&#x2010;795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva GE, Goodwin JL, Sherrill DL, et al. Relationship between reported and measured sleep times: the sleep heart health study (SHHS). J Clin Sleep Med. 2007;03(6):622&#x2010;630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson CL, Patel SR, Jackson WB, Lutsey PL, Redline S. Agreement between self&#x2010;reported and objectively measured sleep duration among white, black, Hispanic, and Chinese adults in the United States: multi&#x2010;ethnic study of atherosclerosis. Sleep. 2018;41(6):zsy057.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>