<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41637591</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2328-5273</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>83</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Bulletin of the Hospital for Joint Disease (2013)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Bull Hosp Jt Dis (2013)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Winning the arms race: Optimizing upper extremity amputations and advancements in prosthetic technology.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>29</StartPage><EndPage>34</EndPage><MedlinePgn>29-34</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/bh9.0000000000000005</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Since the beginning of documented medical history, amputation procedures, limb loss, and the myriad creative solutions attempted to care for these individuals have been reported. With the coalescence of multiple World Wars resulting in an ever-increasing number of individuals with limb loss and advancing medical technology, a need to innovate in this field has always been present. The complexity of the hand and upper extremity in self-care, communication, vocation, and exercise results in more demands of prostheses to mimic or replace these functions as opposed to the lower extremity, which is focused mostly on weight bearing and ambulation. As such, this need has pushed technological advances past the simpler passive or body-powered prostheses alone, now with externally powered and hybrid devices revolutionizing the way these appliances were implemented in everyday life. Despite the ever-advancing field of prosthetic technology, upper and lower extremity amputees alike still battle common challenges of pain, phantom limb sensation, and lack of prosthetic control and sensation. Targeted muscle reinnervation and regenerative peripheral nerve interface offer new surgical solutions to some of these challenges and are proving invaluable. As technology and surgical options continue to advance at an ever-rapid pace, a more thoughtful and individualized approach to the care of upper extremity limb loss is available. In this study, we review the history and evolution of upper extremity prostheses and discuss considerations in making optimal surgical and prosthetic decisions for upper extremity amputees.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Alumni Association for the Hospital of Joint Diseases, published by Wolters Kluwer, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neal</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Hand Surgery, NYU Langone Health Department of Orthopedic Surgery, New York, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donnelly</LastName><ForeName>Megan R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayalon</LastName><ForeName>Omri B</ForeName><Initials>OB</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Bull Hosp Jt Dis (2013)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101614130</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2328-4633</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001186" MajorTopicYN="Y">Artificial Limbs</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000639" MajorTopicYN="N">trends</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000671" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amputation, Surgical</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D034941" MajorTopicYN="Y">Upper Extremity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000294" MajorTopicYN="N">innervation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011474" MajorTopicYN="N">Prosthesis Design</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000674" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amputees</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020127" MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery of Function</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010591" MajorTopicYN="N">Phantom Limb</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amputation reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amputation surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">limb loss</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prosthetic optimization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">upper extremity limb loss</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">upper extremity prosthesis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41637591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12742501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/bh9.0000000000000005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01745195-202512000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Thurston AJ. Par&#xe9; and prosthetics: the early history of artificial limbs. ANZ J Surg 2007;77:1114&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17973673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellerson TL. Historical development of upper extremity prosthetics. O&amp;P Libr Orthortics Prosthetics 1957;11:73&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo KJ, Olson JL. The evolution of functional hand replacement: from iron prostheses to hand transplantation. Plast Surg (Oakv) 2014;22:44&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4128433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25152647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prosthetics through the ages. NIH Medline Plus Magazine. 2023. Accessed November 19, 2024. https://guides.himmelfarb.gwu.edu/AMA/websites.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breath Powers Pediatric Prosthetic Hand. Mathworks News and Stories. 2023. Accessed November 19, 2024. https://www.mathworks.com/company/mathworks-stories/virtual-prototyping-produces-breath-powered-pediatric-prosthetic-hand.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowe M, Lara Peralta F, Letts L. The return home: disability experiences of second world war veterans with amputations. J Mil Veteran Fam Health 2024;10.58, 66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart CPU, Jain AS. An epidemiological study of war amputees and the cost to society. Prosthetics Orthotics Int 1999;23:102&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10493136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becoming Bespoke. When one size of prosthetic does not fit all. Natl WWI Mus Memorial Accessed November 19, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols PJR, Rogers EE, Clark MS, Stamp WG. The acceptance and rejection of prostheses by children with multiple congenital limb deformities. Artif Limbs 1968;12:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5743284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Childress DS. Historical aspects of powered limb prostheses. O&amp;P Libr Clin Prosthetics Orthotics 1985;9:2&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziegler-Graham K, MacKenzie EJ, Ephraim PL, Travison TG, Brookmeyer R. Estimating the prevalence of limb loss in the United States: 2005 to 2050. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2008;89:422&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18295618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan TKK, Chung KC. The mangled upper extremity-algorithm for salvage: my workhorse flaps. Clin Plast Surg 2024;51:495&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39216936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qureshi MK, Ghaffar A, Tak S, Khaled A. Limb salvage versus amputation: a review of the current evidence. Cureus 2020;12:e10092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7540187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33047072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and medicine; health and medicine division; board on health care services; committee on the use of selected assistive products and technologies in eliminating or reducing the effects of impairments; Flaubert JL, Spicer CM, Jette AM, editors. The Promise of Assistive Technology to Enhance Activity and Work Participation. Washington (DC): National Academies Press (US); 2017, Upper-Extremity Prostheses.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resnik L, Cancio J, Klinger S, Latlief G, Sasson N, Smurr-Walters L. Predictors of retention and attrition in a study of an advanced upper limb prosthesis: implications for adoption of the DEKA arm. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol 2018;13:206&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28375687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resnik L, Meucci MR, Lieberman-Klinger S, et al. Advanced upper limb prosthetic devices: implications for upper limb prosthetic rehabilitation. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2012;93:710&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22464092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFarland LV, Hubbard Winkler SL, Heinemann AW, Jones M, Esquenazi A. Unilateral upper-limb loss: satisfaction and prosthetic-device use in veterans and servicemembers from Vietnam and OIF/OEF conflicts. J Rehabil Res Dev 2010;47:299&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20803400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanley MA, Ehde DM, Jensen M, Czerniecki J, Smith DG, Robinson LR. Chronic pain associated with upper-limb loss. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 2009;88:742&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3079279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19692791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Soliman N, Gan Z, et al. A systematic review of the prevalence of postamputation and chronic neuropathic pain associated with combat injury in military personnel. Pain 2024;165:727&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10949216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38112578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanyu-Deutmeyer AA, Cascella M, Varacallo M. Phantom limb pain. In: StatPearls [Internet]. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28846343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modest JM, Raducha JE, Testa EJ, Eberson CP. Management of post-amputation pain. R Med J (2013) 2020;103:19&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32357588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinosa M, Nathan-Roberts D. Understanding prosthetic abandonment. Proc Hum Factors Ergon Soc Annu Meet 2019;63.1644&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto M, Chung KC, Sterbenz J, et al. Cross-sectional international multicenter study on quality of life and reasons for abandonment of upper limb prostheses. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open 2019;7:e2205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6571339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31333938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graczyk EL, Resnik L, Schiefer MA, et al. Home use of a neural-connected sensory prosthesis provides the functional and psychosocial experience of having a hand again. Sci Rep 2018;8:9866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6026118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29959334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan DJ, Ayalon O, Hacquebord J. Targeted muscle reinnervation (tmr) and other considerations in upper extremity amputation. Bull Hosp Joint Dis (2013) 2022;80:25&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35234583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gstoettner C, Laengle G, Harnoncourt L, Sassu P, Aszmann OC. Targeted muscle reinnervation in bionic upper limb reconstruction: current status and future directions. J Hand Surg Eur Vol 2024;49:783&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38366374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper RC, Cederna PS, Brown DL, et al. Regenerative peripheral nerve interfaces for the management of symptomatic hand and digital neuromas. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open 2020;8:e2792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7339232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32766027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>