<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41755924</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Narrative Review of Evolving Techniques in Nonsurgical Rhinoplasty: Risk Profile and Clinical Outcomes of Fillers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e102303</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e102303</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e102303</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.102303</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Nonsurgical rhinoplasty (NSR) is a minimally invasive alternative to surgical rhinoplasty that uses dermal fillers to enhance nasal aesthetics. When performed by trained injectors, NSR offers rapid correction with relatively low downtime.&#xa0;This narrative review explores the historical evolution, anatomical considerations, filler materials, patient selection, procedural techniques, risk mitigation strategies, and clinical outcomes associated with NSR. Hyaluronic acid (HA)-based fillers remain the gold standard due to their reversibility, biocompatibility, and favorable safety profile. Recent innovations, including ultrasound-guided injections, hybrid techniques combining HA with polydioxanone (PDO) threads, and AI-assisted facial mapping, have improved precision and patient satisfaction. Although most complications are transient, such as edema and erythema, rare but severe events like vascular occlusion, skin necrosis, and visual loss underline the importance of detailed anatomical knowledge and preventive techniques. The review also emphasizes individualized treatment approaches considering ethnic and anatomical variations. Overall, NSR demonstrates high efficacy, rapid recovery, and reversibility, with satisfaction rates exceeding 90% across multiple studies, reaffirming its position as a valuable aesthetic procedure when performed by trained professionals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Torres C&#xe9;spedes et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Torres C&#xe9;spedes</LastName><ForeName>Sergio Camilo</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Universidad Nacional de Colombia, Bogota, COL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagan</LastName><ForeName>Ahtziri</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, University of Medicine and Health Sciences, Basseterre, KNA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alotaibi</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Surgery, Al Adan Hospital, Ministry of Health, Al-Mubarak Al-Kabeer, KWT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>D Amico</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe Antonio</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Policlinico "G. Martino", Messina, ITA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almutiri</LastName><ForeName>Manar</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Otolaryngology, Zain Hospital, Kuwait, KWT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guillen</LastName><ForeName>Gustavo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Caja Costarricense de Seguro Social, San Jose, CRI.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imam</LastName><ForeName>Bashir</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics, University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, Coudersport, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shamsah</LastName><ForeName>Amar</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Surgery, Al Adan Hospital, Ministry of Health, Al-Mubarak Al-Kabeer, KWT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manjarrez</LastName><ForeName>Amaranta</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Westhill University, Mexico City, MEX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dermal fillers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyaluronic acid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-surgical rhinoplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient satisfaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultrasound guidance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vascular occlusion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41755924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12934192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.102303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Recommendations for treatment of soft-tissue filler complications. Van Wicklin SA. Plast Aesthet Nurs (Phila) 2022;42:7&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36450065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonsurgical rhinoplasty: a systematic review of technique, outcomes, and complications. Williams LC, Kidwai SM, Mehta K, Kamel G, Tepper OM, Rosenberg JD. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2020;146:41&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32590640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonsurgical rhinoplasty: an updated systematic review of technique, outcomes, complications, and its treatments. Song D, Wang X, Yu Z. Aesthetic Plast Surg. 2024;48:4902&#x2013;4915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38862661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyaluronan hydrogels for injection in superficial dermal layers: an in vitro characterization to compare performance and unravel the scientific basis of their indication. La Gatta A, Aschettino M, Stellavato A, et al. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8199639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34199374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Multicenter, randomized, parallel-group study of the safety and effectiveness of onabotulinumtoxinA and hyaluronic acid dermal fillers (24-mg/ml smooth, cohesive gel) alone and in combination for lower facial rejuvenation. Carruthers A, Carruthers J, Monheit GD, Davis PG, Tardie G. Dermatol Surg. 2010;36:2121&#x2013;2134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21134044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Complications secondary to nonsurgical rhinoplasty: a systematic review and meta-analysis. DeVictor S, Ong AA, Sherris DA. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2021;165:611&#x2013;616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33588622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The nonsurgical rhinoplasty: a retrospective review of 5000 treatments. Harb A, Brewster CT. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2020;145:661&#x2013;667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32097303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treatment of soft tissue filler complications: expert consensus recommendations. Urdiales-G&#xe1;lvez F, Delgado NE, Figueiredo V, et al. Aesthetic Plast Surg. 2018;42:498&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5840246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29305643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonsurgical rhinoplasty using injectable fillers: a safety review of 2488 procedures. Rivkin A. Facial Plast Surg Aesthet Med. 2021;23:6&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33270519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonsurgical rhinoplasty with polydioxanone threads and fillers. Kang SH, Moon SH, Kim HS. Dermatol Surg. 2020;46:664&#x2013;670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31517664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyaluronic acid fillers for midface augmentation: a systematic review. Trinh LN, Gupta A. Facial Plast Surg. 2021;37:576&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33634456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Current strategies for aesthetic soft tissue refinement in nasal reconstruction. Kim MJ, Lim H, Park DH. Arch Craniofac Surg. 2022;23:95&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9271655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35811340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arterial features of inner canthus region: confirming the safety for the flap design. Erdogmus S, Govsa F. J Craniofac Surg. 2006;17:864&#x2013;868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17003612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasal tip blood supply: an anatomic study validating the safety of the transcolumellar incision in rhinoplasty. Rohrich RJ, Gunter JP, Friedman RM. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7708862/ Plast Reconstr Surg. 1995;95:795&#x2013;799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7708862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vascular anatomy of the nose and the external rhinoplasty approach. Toriumi DM, Mueller RA, Grosch T, Bhattacharyya TK, Larrabee WF Jr. Arch Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 1996;122:24&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8554743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasal arterial vasculature: medical and surgical applications. Saban Y, Andretto Amodeo C, Bouaziz D, Polselli R. Arch Facial Plast Surg. 2012;14:429&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22710606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facial artery in the upper lip and nose: anatomy and a clinical application. Nakajima H, Imanishi N, Aiso S. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2002;109:855&#x2013;861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11884796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A practical guide to selecting facial fillers. Al-Ghanim K, Richards R, Cohen S. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2023;22:3232&#x2013;3236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37395390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Injectable fillers: current status, physicochemical properties, function mechanism, and perspectives. Guo J, Fang W, Wang F. RSC Adv. 2023;13:23841&#x2013;23858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10413051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37577103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Use of hyaluronic acid fillers for the treatment of the aging face. Gold MH. Clin Interv Aging. 2007;2:369&#x2013;376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2685277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18044187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raggio BS, Asaria J. Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls; 2025. Nonsurgical Rhinoplasty Using Fillers.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32119468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of calcium hydroxylapatite (Radiesse) as a regenerative aesthetic treatment: a narrative review. Aguilera SB, McCarthy A, Khalifian S, Lorenc ZP, Goldie K, Chernoff WG. Aesthet Surg J. 2023;43:1063&#x2013;1090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11025388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37635437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poly-L-lactic acid fillers improved dermal collagen synthesis by modulating M2 macrophage polarization in aged animal skin. Oh S, Lee JH, Kim HM, et al. Cells. 2023;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10177436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37174720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DelMauro Matthew A, Lorenc Z. Paul: Background/Basic Science of Polymethylmethacrylate Fillers. Background/basic science of polymethylmethacrylate fillers. 2021. https://www.rejuvenationresource.com/articles/background-science/background-basic-science-of-polymethylmethacrylate-fillers https://www.rejuvenationresource.com/articles/background-science/background-basic-science-of-polymethylmethacrylate-fillers</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Non-surgical minimally invasive rhinoplasty: tips and tricks from the perspective of a dermatologist. Sahan A, Tamer F. Acta Dermatovenerol Alp Pannonica Adriat. 2017;26:101&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29264900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tip up - Simplified technique for non-surgical rhinoplasty: a case series. Almeida C, Rogerio V, Giro G, Munoz-Lora V, Germani M. J Oral Biol Craniofac Res. 2025;15:355&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12039370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40303842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonsurgical rhinoplasty. Hall SS, Kontis TC. World J Otorhinolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2023;9:212&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10541163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37780677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonsurgical rhinoplasty: a graft-based technique. Segreto F, Marangi GF, Cerbone V, Alessandri-Bonetti M, Caldaria E, Persichetti P. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2019;7:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6635207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31624669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avoiding and treating blindness from fillers: a review of the world literature. Beleznay K, Carruthers JD, Humphrey S, Jones D. Dermatol Surg. 2015;41:1097&#x2013;1117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26356847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasal dorsum augmentation using soft tissue filler injection. Lee W, Kim JS, Oh W, Koh IS, Yang EJ. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2019;18:1254&#x2013;1260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31157508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A 10-point plan for avoiding hyaluronic acid dermal filler-related complications during facial aesthetic procedures and algorithms for management. Heydenrych I, Kapoor KM, De Boulle K, Goodman G, Swift A, Kumar N, Rahman E. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol. 2018;11:603&#x2013;611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6257077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30538521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vascular compromise from soft tissue augmentation: experience with 12 cases and recommendations for optimal outcomes. Beleznay K, Humphrey S, Carruthers JD, Carruthers A. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25276276/ J Clin Aesthet Dermatol. 2014;7:37&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4174919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25276276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ultrasound in aesthetics: filler and non-filler applications. Cavallieri FA, Balassiano LK, Munhoz G, Tembra MF, Wortsman X. Semin Ultrasound CT MR. 2024;45:251&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38072289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early ultrasound for diagnosis and treatment of vascular adverse events with hyaluronic acid fillers. Schelke LW, Velthuis P, Kadouch J, Swift A. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2023;88:79&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31325548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation and proportion in nasal filling with hyaluronic acid. Bravo BS, Bravo LG, Mariano Da Rocha C, De Souza SB, Lopes FL, Totti J. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29657670/ J Clin Aesthet Dermatol. 2018;11:36&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5891085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29657670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Non-surgical rhinoplasty and use of hyaluronic acid based dermal filler-user experience in few subjects. Baser B, Singh P, Shubha P, Roy PK, Chaubey P. Indian J Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2021;73:52&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7881997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33643885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethnicity and nonsurgical rhinoplasty. Ziade G, Mojallal A, Ho-Asjoe M, Arenas JC, Ascher B. Aesthet Surg J Open Forum. 2022;4:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9337225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35912364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonsurgical correction of surgical rhinoplasty complications with hyaluronic acid fillers: a retrospective review of 2088 cases. Harb A, Abdul-Razzak A. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2024;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11379477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39247575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonsurgical rhinoplasty: Long-term follow-up of high G&#x2019; HA nasal injections. Bertossi D, Magagnotto N, Chirumbolo S, D'Souza A, Nocini R. Facial Plast Surg. 2022;38:96&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35158387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spontaneous and induced degradation of dermal fillers: a review. Wollina U, Goldman A. J Cutan Aesthet Surg. 2024;17:273&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11619174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39649762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Application of hyaluronic acid linear stereoscopic stack volume enhancement injection technique in nasal reshaping. Dong R, Lei J, Liu Q. J Craniofac Surg. 2025;36:684&#x2013;687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11845067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39750737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonsurgical rhinoplasty using the hyaluronic acid filler VYC-25L: safety and patient satisfaction in a retrospective analysis of 492 patients. Jalali A. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2024;23:426&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37740484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Body dysmorphic disorder in aesthetic rhinoplasty candidates. Mr F, Tabrizi A G, Bafghi A F, Sa N, A M. Pak J Med Sci. 2013;29:197&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3809162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24353539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High prevalence of body dysmorphic disorder among rhinoplasty candidates: insights from a cross-sectional study in Saudi Arabia. Rammal A, Bukhari JS, Alsharif GN, Aseeri HS, Alkhamesi AA, Alharbi RF, Almohammadi WF. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11763559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39867022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of body dysmorphic disorder in rhinoplasty candidates: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nabavizadeh SS, Naseri R, Sadeghi E, Afshari A, Dehdari Ebrahimi N, Sadeghi A. Health Sci Rep. 2023;6:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10435832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37599660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyaluronic acid filler-induced vascular occlusion-three case reports and overview of prevention and treatment. Wang R, Li Y, Li Z, Yao H, Zhai Z. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2024;23:1217&#x2013;1223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38131127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Complications of nonsurgical rhinoplasty with hyaluronic acid injections: a narrative review. Caranti A, Thomas R, Facchini F, et al. Aesthetic Plast Surg. 2025;49:3016&#x2013;3025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39747417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ultrasound assisted hyaluronic acid vascular adverse event management based on the vascular anatomy. Mojallal A, Schelke L, Velthuis PJ, Boucher F, Henry G. Ann Chir Plast Esthet. 2024;69:674&#x2013;680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39542539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Update on blindness from filler: review of prognostic factors, management approaches, and a century of published cases. Doyon VC, Liu C, Fitzgerald R, Humphrey S, Jones D, Carruthers JD, Beleznay K. Aesthet Surg J. 2024;44:1091&#x2013;1104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38630871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasal reshaping using barbed threads combined with hyaluronic acid filler and botulinum toxin A. Ziade G, Saade R, Daou D, Karam D, Bendito A, Tsintsadze M. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2025;24:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11816005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39936459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enhancing facial projection: Efficacy and safety of a novel filler combining cross-linked sodium hyaluronate gel with poly-L-lactic acid-B-PEG microspheres for T-zone augmentation. Wang S, Qiu Y, Zhu M, et al. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2025;24:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11926505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40114452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhinomodelation with polycarpolactone-a safer and effective solution for the future. Qureshi KI, Vercesi F, Qureshi HF. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2025;24:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11804163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39918162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A critical review of complications in non-surgical rhinoplasty and their management. Babu SH, Rapaport BH. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2021;20:3391&#x2013;3397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34587355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Non-surgical rhinoplasty through minimal invasive nose thread procedures: Adverse effects and prevention methods. Park SY, Kim SB, Suwanchinda A, Yi KH. Skin Res Technol. 2024;30:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10818120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38279564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A new time-saving technique for ultrasound-guided filler injection: a 3-year retrospective study. Teixeira DA. Aesthet Surg J Open Forum. 2025;7:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12254949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40657559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vision-threatening complications of soft tissue fillers: a report by the American Academy of Ophthalmology. Foster J, Aakalu VK, Freitag SK, et al. Ophthalmology. 2025;132:935&#x2013;944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40167411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk factor analysis for vascular occlusions after dermal filler injections: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Chakhachiro A, Waseem M. Cureus. 2025;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12097758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40406769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Profiloplasty and facial contouring with injectables: A holistic, practical, and user-friendly approach. Farollch-Prats L, Braz A, Urdiales-G&#xe1;lvez F, de la Guardia C, Nazari A. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2024;23:3158&#x2013;3172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38769652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Best practices for the use of high-frequency ultrasound to guide aesthetic filler injections-part 2: middle third of the face, nose, and tear troughs. Vasconcelos-Berg R, Desyatnikova S, Bonavia P, Chammas MC, Navarini A, Sigrist R. Diagnostics (Basel) 2024;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11593187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39594210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA executive summary general issues panel meeting on dermal fillers prepared for the meeting of the general and plastic surgery Devices Advisory Panel. 2021. https://www.fda.gov/media/188185/download https://www.fda.gov/media/188185/download</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aesthetic surgical pathway in permanent facial filler removal. Pascali M, Chirico F, Rugge L, Rauso R. Facial Plast Surg. 2024;40:19&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36696919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resolution of vascular compromise from liquid rhinoplasty using Hirudo medicinalis therapy. Rivkin A, Chepka S. Aesthet Surg J Open Forum. 2024;6:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11483493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39421582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>New high dose pulsed hyaluronidase protocol for hyaluronic acid filler vascular adverse events. DeLorenzi C. Aesthet Surg J. 2017;37:814&#x2013;825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28333326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of impending necrosis associated with soft tissue filler injections. Dayan SH, Arkins JP, Mathison CC. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22052269/ J Drugs Dermatol. 2011;11:1007&#x2013;1012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22052269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of hyaluronidase on depth of necrosis in hyaluronic acid filling-related skin complications. Ors S. Aesthetic Plast Surg. 2020;44:1778&#x2013;1785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32424534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The rhinoplasty outcome evaluation (ROE) questionnaire in rhinoplasty: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Rot P, Krzywdzi&#x144;ska S, Grab P, Jurkiewicz D, Chloupek A, Sobol M. J Clin Med. 2024;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11355392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39200785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novel ultrasound-assisted nonsurgical rhinoplasty technique: injection guidelines from evidence to clinical practice based on 4400 procedures. Ortiz Middleton E, Guzman C. Aesthet Surg J Open Forum. 2025;7:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12548051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41141629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artificial intelligence in aesthetic medicine: applications, challenges, and future directions. Al-Dhubaibi MS, Mohammed GF, Atef LM, Bahaj SS, Al-Dhubaibi AM, Bukhari AM. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2025;24:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12159716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40501296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Customized precision facial assessment: an AI-assisted analysis of facial microexpressions for advanced aesthetic treatment. Li CW, Wang CC, Chou CY, Lin CS. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2020;8:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7253289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32537345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Injectable profiloplasty: forehead, nose, lips, and chin filler treatment. Bertossi D, Lanaro L, Dell'Acqua I, Albanese M, Malchiodi L, Nocini PF. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2019;18:976&#x2013;984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30444074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dermal fillers in aesthetics: an overview of adverse events and treatment approaches. Funt D, Pavicic T. Plast Surg Nurs. 2015;35:13&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25730536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>