<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41868683</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2160-8407</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of nuclear medicine and molecular imaging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Nucl Med Mol Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Scatter correction for self-collimating SPECT using a 3D U-Net framework.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>33</StartPage><EndPage>43</EndPage><MedlinePgn>33-43</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.62347/ZZHP6340</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Conventional single-photon emission computed tomography (SPECT) relies on mechanical collimators, which impose an inherent trade-off between spatial resolution and sensitivity. A novel cardiac SPECT system that employs a self-collimating design with interleaved mosaic scintillators has been proposed, which markedly enhances sensitivity without compromising resolution. However, the unique self-collimating and closely arranged detector geometry also introduces more complex scatter distribution and increased scatter fractions, making accurate scatter correction essential yet technically challenging. We employed a 3D U-Net framework to directly predict scatter-corrected images from uncorrected images. The network was trained using 36 distinct XCAT phantoms based on GATE simulations, with the true scatter-corrected images (true-SC) precisely obtained from the simulations serving as labels. Quantitative evaluation was performed using another two XCAT phantoms with different contrast levels: a high-contrast phantom (H-Phantom, 10 realizations) and a low-contrast phantom (L-Phantom, 5 realizations). The proposed U-Net approach were compared with two triple energy window (TEW) methods (trapezoidal and triangular). For both contrast levels, the U-Net-based approach achieved higher contrast recovery coefficients, myocardium-to-blood-pool ratios closer to the true-SC, higher contrast-to-noise ratios, and lower relative noise compared to the TEW methods. In addition, the U-Net-based method produced images with higher structural similarity and lower normalized mean square error relative to the true-SC reference, compared with the TEW-corrected images. In conclusion, the proposed 3D U-Net-based scatter correction method provides more accurate scatter estimation and superior quantitative performance for self-collimating SPECT systems than conventional TEW approaches.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>AJNMMI Copyright &#xa9; 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Yabo</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced Quantum Studies, School of Physics and Astronomy, Beijing Normal University Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Multiscale Spin Physics (Ministry of Education), Beijing Normal University Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Wenyang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced Quantum Studies, School of Physics and Astronomy, Beijing Normal University Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Multiscale Spin Physics (Ministry of Education), Beijing Normal University Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Hai</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced Quantum Studies, School of Physics and Astronomy, Beijing Normal University Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Multiscale Spin Physics (Ministry of Education), Beijing Normal University Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Liang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Engineering Physics, Tsinghua University Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Biomedical Imaging, Yale University New Haven, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lyu</LastName><ForeName>Zhenlei</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Engineering Physics, Tsinghua University Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Debin</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Engineering Physics, Tsinghua University Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, Beijing Chaoyang Hospital, Capital Medical University Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Peng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Institute of Spacecraft System Engineering Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Engineering Physics, Tsinghua University Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Tianyu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Engineering Physics, Tsinghua University Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced Quantum Studies, School of Physics and Astronomy, Beijing Normal University Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Multiscale Spin Physics (Ministry of Education), Beijing Normal University Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Nucl Med Mol Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101564121</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SPECT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">U-Net</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scatter correction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-collimation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41868683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13003232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62347/ZZHP6340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Niu X, Yang Y, Jin M, Wernick MN, King MA. Effects of motion, attenuation, and scatter corrections on gated cardiac SPECT reconstruction. Med Phys. 2011;38:6571&#x2013;6584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3247926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22149839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutton BF, Buvat I, Beekman FJ. Review and current status of SPECT scatter correction. Phys Med Biol. 2011;56:R85&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21701055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs F, Sundermann E, De Sutter B, Christiaens M, Lemahieu I. A fast algorithm to calculate the exact radiological path through a pixel or voxel space. J Comput Inf Technol. 1998;6:89&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berker Y, Li Y. Attenuation correction in emission tomography using the emission data--A review. Med Phys. 2016;43:807&#x2013;832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4715007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26843243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan P, Hutton BF, Holstensson M, Ljungberg M, Pretorius PH, Prasad R, Ma T, Liu Y, Wang S, Thorn SL, Stacy MR, Sinusas AJ, Liu C. Scatter and crosstalk corrections for (99m)Tc/(123)I dual-radionuclide imaging using a CZT SPECT system with pinhole collimators. Med Phys. 2015;42:6895&#x2013;6911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26632046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velo AF, Fan P, Xie H, Chen X, Boutagy N, Feher A, Sinusas AJ, Ljungberg M, Liu C. (99m)Tc/(123)I dual-radionuclide correction for self-scatter, down-scatter, and tailing effect for a CZT SPECT with varying tracer distributions. IEEE Trans Radiat Plasma Med Sci. 2023;7:839&#x2013;850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11090119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38745858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang JT, Yamamoto K, Sadato N, Tsuchida T, Takahashi N, Hayashi N, Yonekura Y, Ishii Y. Clinical value of triple-energy window scatter correction in simultaneous dual-isotope single-photon emission tomography with 123I-BMIPP and 201Tl. Eur J Nucl Med. 1997;24:1099&#x2013;1106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9283101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noori-Asl M, Sadremomtaz A, Bitarafan-Rajabi A. Evaluation of three scatter correction methods based on estimation of photopeak scatter spectrum in SPECT imaging: a simulation study. Phys Med. 2014;30:947&#x2013;953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24985135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michael K, Frangos S, Iakovou I, Lontos A, Demosthenous G, Parpottas Y. The impact of dual and triple energy window scatter correction on I-123 postsurgical thyroid SPECT/CT imaging using a phantom with small sizes of thyroid remnants. Life (Basel) 2024;14:113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10821084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38255728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson AP, Tipping J, Cullen DM, Hamilton D. The influence of triple energy window scatter correction on activity quantification for (177)Lu molecular radiotherapy. Phys Med Biol. 2016;61:5107&#x2013;5127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27351914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Wu J, Miller EJ, Liu C, Liu Y, Liu YH. Diagnostic accuracy of stress-only myocardial perfusion SPECT improved by deep learning. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2021;48:2793&#x2013;2800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33511425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Zhou B, Xie H, Shi L, Liu H, Holler W, Lin M, Liu YH, Miller EJ, Sinusas AJ, Liu C. Direct and indirect strategies of deep-learning-based attenuation correction for general purpose and dedicated cardiac SPECT. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2022;49:3046&#x2013;3060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9253078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35169887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Li Z, Son J, Fessler JA, Dewaraja YK, Chun SY. Physics-guided deep scatter estimation by weak supervision for quantitative SPECT. IEEE Trans Med Imaging. 2023;42:2961&#x2013;2973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10593395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37104110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronneberger O, Fischer P, Brox T. U-Net: convolutional networks for biomedical image segmentation. Medical Image Computing and Computer-Assisted Intervention - MICCAI. 2015;2015:234&#x2013;241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian S, Luo Z, Zhong Z, Lin X, Su S, Li S. Attention guided U-Net for accurate iris segmentation. J Visual Commun Image Represent. 2018;56:296&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W, Liu B, Peng S, Sun J, Qiao X. S3D-UNet: separable 3D U-Net for brain tumor segmentation. Brainlesion: Glioma, Multiple Sclerosis, Stroke and Traumatic Brain Injuries. 2019:358&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Wu J, Lu W, Onofrey JA, Liu YH, Liu C. Noise reduction with cross-tracer and cross-protocol deep transfer learning for low-dose PET. Phys Med Biol. 2020;65:185006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12434544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32924973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Yousefi H, Mirian N, Lin M, Menard D, Gregory M, Aboian M, Boustani A, Chen MK, Saperstein L, Pucar D, Kulon M, Liu C. PET image denoising using a deep-learning method for extremely obese patients. IEEE Trans Radiat Plasma Med Sci. 2022;6:766&#x2013;770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10241407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37284026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Zhang Y, Lyu Z, Cheng L, Gao L, Wu J, Liu Y. Investigation of a deep learning-based reconstruction approach utilizing dual-view projection for myocardial perfusion SPECT imaging. Am J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2025;15:15&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11929010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40124765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Park D, Gullberg GT, Seo Y. Joint correction of attenuation and scatter in image space using deep convolutional neural networks for dedicated brain (18)F-FDG PET. Phys Med Biol. 2019;64:075019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6449185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30743246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent B, Bousse A, Merlin T, Nekolla S, Visvikis D. PET scatter estimation using deep learning U-Net architecture. Phys Med Biol. 2023;68:065004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36240745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore SC, Kouris K, Cullum I. Collimator design for single photon emission tomography. Eur J Nucl Med. 1992;19:138&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1563442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Audenhaege K, Van Holen R, Vandenberghe S, Vanhove C, Metzler SD, Moore SC. Review of SPECT collimator selection, optimization, and fabrication for clinical and preclinical imaging. Med Phys. 2015;42:4796&#x2013;4813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5148182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26233207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Liu C. Recent advances in cardiac SPECT instrumentation and imaging methods. Phys Med Biol. 2019;64:06TR01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30726779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma T, Wei Q, Lyu Z, Zhang D, Zhang H, Wang R, Dong J, Liu Y, Yao R, He ZX. Self-collimating SPECT with multi-layer interspaced mosaic detectors. IEEE Trans Med Imaging. 2021;40:2152&#x2013;2169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12832190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33852384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Lyu Z, Liu Y, He ZX, Yao R, Ma T. Characterization and assessment of projection probability density function and enhanced sampling in self-collimation SPECT. IEEE Trans Med Imaging. 2023;42:2787&#x2013;2801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10597595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37037258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Cheng L, Hu Y, Lyu Z, Wang L, Fang W, Yao R, Ma T. Design optimization and simulated performance evaluation of a self-collimated cardiac SPECT with simultaneous high sensitivity and resolution. Med Phys. 2025;52:3823&#x2013;3839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12834042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40358854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R, Zhang D, Hu Y, Lyu Z, Ma T. High-sensitivity cardiac SPECT system design with collimator-less interspaced mosaic-patterned scintillators. Front Med (Lausanne) 2023;10:1145351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10336213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37448793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Guo L, Liu H, Lyu Z, Zhang D, Liu Y, Ma T, Wu J. Comparison of three triple-energy-window scatter correction approaches for self-collimating SPECT. J Nucl Med. 2024;65:241929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Liu H, Guo L, Jiang W, Lyu Z, Zhang D, Ma T, Wu J. Deep learning-based scatter correction for self-collimating SPECT. 2024 IEEE Nuclear Science Symposium (NSS), Medical Imaging Conference (MIC) and Room Temperature Semiconductor Detector Conference (RTSD); 2024. pp. 1&#x2013;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayal G, Chauvin M, Vergara-Gil A, Clayton N, Ferrer L, Moalosi T, Knoll P, Struelens L, Bardi&#xe8;s M. Generation of clinical 177Lu SPECT/CT images based on Monte Carlo simulation with GATE. Phys Med. 2021;85:24&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33957577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Guo L, Liu H, Lyu Z, Zhao Y, Zhang D, He ZX, Liu Y, Ma T. Accurate attenuation correction for self-collimating SPECT imaging. 2023 IEEE Nuclear Science Symposium, Medical Imaging Conference and International Symposium on Room-Temperature Semiconductor Detectors (NSS MIC RTSD); 2023. pp. 1&#x2013;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogawa K, Harata Y, Ichihara T, Kubo A, Hashimoto S. A practical method for position-dependent Compton-scatter correction in single photon emission CT. IEEE Trans Med Imaging. 1991;10:408&#x2013;412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18222843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buvat I, Rodriguez-Villafuerte M, Todd-Pokropek A, Benali H, Di Paola R. Comparative assessment of nine scatter correction methods based on spectral analysis using Monte Carlo simulations. J Nucl Med. 1995;36:1476&#x2013;1488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7629598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Liu H, Hashemi Zonouz T, Sandoval VM, Mohy-Ud-Din H, Lampert RJ, Sinusas AJ, Liu C, Liu YH. A blind deconvolution method incorporated with anatomical-based filtering for partial volume correction: validations with (123) I-mIBG cardiac SPECT/CT. Med Phys. 2017;44:6435&#x2013;6446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28994458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin J, Cheng L, Jiang N, Gao L, Huang S, Zhang D, Zhao R, Zhang J, Liu H, Liu Y, Wu J. Deconvolution-based partial volume correction for dynamic cardiac PET imaging of (18)F-FDG in rats using a time-variant point spread function. 2025 IEEE Nuclear Science Symposium (NSS), Medical Imaging Conference (MIC) and Room Temperature Semiconductor Detector Conference (RTSD); 2025. pp. 1&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>