<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41684979</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Multiligament Knee Injuries: A 15-Year Clinical and Epidemiological Analysis at a Tertiary Referral Center.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e101310</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e101310</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e101310</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.101310</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Multiligament knee injuries (MLKIs) represent a significant diagnostic and therapeutic challenge and are most often the result of high-energy trauma. The LaPrade technique has become a reproducible option for anatomical reconstruction of the posterolateral corner. This study presents the experience of a tertiary care center in the management of these complex injuries.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective descriptive study was conducted on 25 patients with MLKIs treated between 2010 and 2023 at our tertiary care hospital. Demographic and clinical variables, injury type (Schenck classification), mechanism of injury, treatment, and complications were analyzed. Prognostic outcomes were categorized as good or fair-poor based on direct patient-reported assessment at the one-year follow&#x2011;up regarding overall functional status, without the use of validated functional scales. Data analysis was performed using R&#x2011;Statistics version 3.5.2 (R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna, AUT).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Around 80% of patients were male, with a mean age of 42.1 &#xb1; 11.8 years and a mean BMI of 26.8 &#xb1; 3.9 kg/m&#xb2;. Traffic accidents were the most common mechanism (56%), followed by sports injuries and falls (20% each). Knee dislocation (KD) V was the most prevalent injury type (40%). Anatomical multiligament reconstruction, primarily following the LaPrade technique, was performed in 44% of cases. Complications occurred in 20% of patients, including joint stiffness, condylar necrosis, and ligament re&#x2011;rupture.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Anatomical multiligament reconstruction provides satisfactory functional outcomes with a complication rate comparable to the literature. A multidisciplinary approach and early rehabilitation are essential to optimize functional recovery in complex knee injuries.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Mayorga-Naranjo et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mayorga-Naranjo</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery and Traumatology, Hospital Universitari i Polit&#xe8;cnic La Fe, Valencia, ESP.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ortega-Yago</LastName><ForeName>Amparo</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery and Traumatology, Hospital Universitari i Polit&#xe8;cnic La Fe, Valencia, ESP.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pedraza-Corbi</LastName><ForeName>Aranza</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery and Traumatology, Hospital Universitari i Polit&#xe8;cnic La Fe, Valencia, ESP.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bonete-Lluch</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery and Traumatology, Hospital Universitari i Polit&#xe8;cnic La Fe, Valencia, ESP.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anatomical reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high energy trauma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">laprade technique</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mlki</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multiligament knee injuries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">orthopedic surgery</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41684979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12891746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.101310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Multiple-ligament knee injuries: a systematic review of the timing of operative intervention and postoperative rehabilitation. Mook WR, Miller MD, Diduch DR, Hertel J, Boachie-Adjei Y, Hart JM. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2009;91:2946&#x2013;2957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19952260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes of operative and nonoperative treatment of multiligament knee injuries: an evidence-based review. Peskun CJ, Whelan DB. Sports Med Arthrosc Rev. 2011;19:167&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21540715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decision making in the multiligament-injured knee: an evidence-based systematic review. Levy BA, Dajani KA, Whelan DB, et al. Arthroscopy. 2009;25:430&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19341932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High-energy knee dislocation. Wascher DC. Oper Tech Sports Med. 2003;11:235&#x2013;245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcome after knee dislocations: a 2-9 years follow-up of 85 consecutive patients. Engebretsen L, Risberg MA, Robertson B, Ludvigsen TC, Johansen S. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2009;17:1013&#x2013;1026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19609504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnostic and management strategies for Multiligament knee injuries: a critical analysis review. Burrus MT, Werner BC, Griffin JW, Gwathmey FW, Miller MD. JBJS Rev. 2016;4:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27490131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The epidemiology of knee dislocations. Brautigan B, Johnson DL. Clin Sports Med. 2000;19:387&#x2013;397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10918955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Multiligament knee injury (MLKI): an expert consensus statement on nomenclature, diagnosis, treatment and rehabilitation. Murray IR, Makaram NS, Geeslin AG, et al. Br J Sports Med. 2024;58:1385&#x2013;1400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39237264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Major concern in the multiligament-injured knee treatment: a systematic review. Vicenti G, Solarino G, Carrozzo M, De Giorgi S, Moretti L, De Crescenzo A, Moretti B. Injury. 2019;50:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30797544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Single-stage vs. multi-stage reconstruction in multi-ligament knee injuries: a systematic review and meta-analysis of outcomes and complications. Jaibaji M, Najim O, Alali H, Wood L, Van Niekerk L, Bonner T, Volpin A. J Clin Med. 2025;14:6897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12525300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41095975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An analysis of an anatomical posterolateral knee reconstruction: an in vitro biomechanical study and development of a surgical technique. LaPrade RF, Johansen S, Wentorf FA, Engebretsen L, Esterberg JL, Tso A. Am J Sports Med. 2004;32:1405&#x2013;1414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15310564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reconstruction of the posterolateral corner of the knee using Laprade and modified Larson technique: a prospective study. Sharma A, Saha P, Bandyopadhyay U. Indian J Orthop. 2022;56:125&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8748594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35070152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Classifications in brief: the Schenck classification of knee dislocations. Goebel CP, Domes C. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2020;478:1368&#x2013;1172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7319364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32106128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reconstruction of the posterolateral corner of the knee. Stannard JP, Brown SL, Robinson JT, McGwin G Jr, Volgas DA. Arthroscopy. 2005;21:1051&#x2013;1059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16171629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Repair versus reconstruction of the fibular collateral ligament and posterolateral corner in the multiligament-injured knee. Levy BA, Dajani KA, Morgan JA, Shah JP, Dahm DL, Stuart MJ. Am J Sports Med. 2010;38:804&#x2013;809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20118498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Posterolateral corner repair and reconstruction: overview of current techniques. Franciozi CE, Kubota MS, Abdalla RJ, Cohen M, Luzo MVM, LaPrade RF. Ann Joint. 2018;3:89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Posterolateral corner of the knee: current concepts. Chahla J, Moatshe G, Dean CS, LaPrade RF. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27200384/ Arch Bone Jt Surg. 2016;4:97&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4852053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27200384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes after multiligament knee injury worsen over time: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Klasan A, Maerz A, Putnis SE, Ernat JJ, Ollier E, Neri T. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:1281&#x2013;1298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11948183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39194423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthrofibrosis in acute anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. The effect of timing of reconstruction and rehabilitation. Shelbourne KD, Wilckens JH, Mollabashy A, DeCarlo M. Am J Sports Med. 1991;19:332&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1897645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incidence of intraoperative and postoperative complications after posterolateral corner reconstruction or repair: a systematic review of the current literature. Maheshwer B, Drager J, John NS, Williams BT, LaPrade RF, Chahla J. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49:3443&#x2013;3452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33502894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postoperative rehabilitation of multiligament knee reconstruction: a systematic review. Keeling LE, Powell SN, Purvis E, Willauer TJ, Postma WF. Sports Med Arthrosc Rev. 2021;29:94&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33972486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>