<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41902572</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1751-7893</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Early intervention in psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Early Interv Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Pilot Study of the Peer Supported Family Intervention, Psychosis Recovery by Enabling Adult Carers at Home (Psychosis-REACH) in an Early Psychosis Clinic.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70169</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70169</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/eip.70169</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Psychosis REACH (p-REACH) is a co-produced, bichronous (hybrid synchronous and asynchronous) Family Intervention for psychosis that leverages a direct-to-family delivery model to enhance access. We aimed to assess the effect, feasibility and acceptability of the p-REACH core training when combined with longitudinal, family peer-delivered support in an early psychosis setting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">After completing the p-REACH core training, caregiver participants (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;20) engaged in monthly peer and clinician co-led coaching groups for 6&#x2009;months to support skill development and met with a peer with lived experience of caring for a loved one with psychosis twice a month for the course of the intervention. We assessed depression, anxiety, expressed emotion, perceptions of carer burden and attitudes towards psychosis at baseline, immediately post-intervention and at 3 and 6&#x2009;months post-intervention, the latter of which coincided with the end of the coaching period.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The intervention, combined with ongoing peer facilitated group and individual family support, had a positive impact on all carers' outcomes, except depression which was subthreshold at baseline.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study demonstrates the feasibility and acceptability of the p-REACH intervention in an early psychosis clinic and demonstrates the positive impact of teaching CBTp-informed skills to caregivers on both carer and service user outcomes. Further randomised controlled studies are needed to fully assess the key components and impact of this intervention.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lean</LastName><ForeName>Melanie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3654-9914</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benitah</LastName><ForeName>Katie C</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, York University, Toronto, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wakeham</LastName><ForeName>Diane E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9893-372X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Lauren</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Virtheim</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Runestad</LastName><ForeName>Summer</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kopelovich</LastName><ForeName>Sarah L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, University of Washington School of Medicine, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hardy</LastName><ForeName>Kate V</ForeName><Initials>KV</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2019-5090</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Mental Research Institute (MRI)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>University of Washington</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Early Interv Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101320027</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1751-7885</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011618" MajorTopicYN="Y">Psychotic Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017028" MajorTopicYN="Y">Caregivers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010379" MajorTopicYN="Y">Peer Group</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005240" MajorTopicYN="N">Feasibility Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005196" MajorTopicYN="Y">Family Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive behavioural therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">family interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychosis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41902572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/eip.70169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Ajnakina, O., B. Stubbs, E. Francis, et&#xa0;al. 2021. &#x201c;Employment and Relationship Outcomes in First&#x2010;Episode Psychosis: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Longitudinal Studies.&#x201d; Schizophrenia Research 231: 122&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanthorn&#x2010;Hazell, S., A. Gracia, J. Roberts, A. Boldeanu, and D. Judge. 2018. &#x201c;A Survey of Caregiver Burden in Those Providing Informal Care for Patients With Schizophrenia or Bipolar Disorder With Agitation: Results From a European Study.&#x201d; Annals of General Psychiatry 17, no. 1: 8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloch, S., G. I. Szmukler, H. Herrman, A. Benson, and S. Colussa. 1995. &#x201c;Counseling Caregivers of Relatives With Schizophrenia: Themes, Interventions, and Caveats.&#x201d; Family Process 34, no. 4: 413&#x2013;425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brain, C., S. Kymes, D. B. DiBenedetti, T. Brevig, and D. I. Velligan. 2018. &#x201c;Experiences, Attitudes, and Perceptions of Caregivers of Individuals With Treatment&#x2010;Resistant Schizophrenia: A Qualitative Study.&#x201d; BMC Psychiatry 18, no. 1: 253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles, S., J. B. Kirkbride, J. Onwumere, et&#xa0;al. 2021. &#x201c;Carer Subjective Burden After First&#x2010;Episode Psychosis: Types and Predictors. A Multilevel Statistical Approach.&#x201d; International Journal of Social Psychiatry 67, no. 1: 73&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claxton, M., J. Onwumere, and M. Fornells&#x2010;Ambrojo. 2017. &#x201c;Do Family Interventions Improve Outcomes in Early Psychosis? A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis.&#x201d; Frontiers in Psychology 8: 1&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estrad&#xe9;, A., J. Onwumere, J. Venables, et&#xa0;al. 2023. &#x201c;The Lived Experiences of Family Members and Carers of People With Psychosis: A Bottom&#x2010;Up Review Co&#x2010;Written by Experts by Experience and Academics.&#x201d; Psychopathology 56, no. 5: 371&#x2013;382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fusar&#x2010;Poli, P., A. Estrad&#xe9;, G. Stanghellini, et&#xa0;al. 2022. &#x201c;The Lived Experience of Psychosis: A Bottom&#x2010;Up Review Co&#x2010;Written by Experts by Experience and Academics.&#x201d; World Psychiatry 21, no. 2: 168&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleeson, J. F. M., K. Ludwig, B. J. Stiles, et&#xa0;al. 2025. &#x201c;Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Family&#x2010;Based Interventions for Early Psychosis: Carer and Patient Outcomes.&#x201d; Schizophrenia Research 276: 57&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guy, W., and National Institute of Mental Health, Psychopharmacology Research Branch, and Early Clinical Drug Evaluation Program. 1976. ECDEU Assessment Manual for Psychopharmacology, Revised. U. S. Dept. of Health, Education, and Welfare, Public Health Service, Alcohol, Drug Abuse, and Mental Health Administration, National Institute of Mental Health, Psychopharmacology Research Branch, Division of Extramural Research Programs.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris, P. A., R. Taylor, B. L. Minor, et&#xa0;al. 2019. &#x201c;The REDCap Consortium: Building an International Community of Software Platform Partners.&#x201d; Journal of Biomedical Informatics 95: 103208. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbi.2019.103208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris, P. A., R. Taylor, R. Thielke, et&#xa0;al. 2009. &#x201c;Research Electronic Data Capture (REDCap)&#x2014;A Metadata&#x2010;Driven Methodology and Workflow Process For Providing Translational Research Informatics Support.&#x201d; Journal of Biomedical Informatics 42, no. 2: 377&#x2013;381. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbi.2008.08.010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes, L., G. Hawthorne, J. Farhall, B. O'Hanlon, and C. Harvey. 2015. &#x201c;Quality of Life and Social Isolation Among Caregivers of Adults With Schizophrenia: Policy and Outcomes.&#x201d; Community Mental Health Journal 51, no. 5: 591&#x2013;597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, J. P. T., D. G. Altman, P. C. Gotzsche, et&#xa0;al. 2011. &#x201c;The Cochrane Collaboration's Tool for Assessing Risk of Bias in Randomised Trials.&#x201d; BMJ 343: d5928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavanagh, D. J. 1992. &#x201c;Recent Developments in Expressed Emotion and Schizophrenia.&#x201d; British Journal of Psychiatry 160: 601&#x2013;620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavanagh, D. J., P. O'Halloran, V. Manicavasagar, et&#xa0;al. 1997. &#x201c;The Family Attitude Scale: Reliability and Validity of a New Scale for Measuring the Emotional Climate of Families.&#x201d; Psychiatry Research 70, no. 3: 185&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keepers, G. A., L. J. Fochtmann, J. M. Anzia, et&#xa0;al. 2020. &#x201c;The American Psychiatric Association Practice Guideline for the Treatment of Patients With Schizophrenia.&#x201d; American Journal of Psychiatry 177, no. 9: 868&#x2013;872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopelovich, S., J. Blank, A. Vaswani&#x2010;Bye, et&#xa0;al. 2025. Scaling Family Interventions for Psychosis Through Hybrid Digital Training: A Feasibility Study of Psychosis REACH. Rev.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopelovich, S., A. Vaswani&#x2010;Bye, M. Monroe&#x2010;DeVita, and H. T. Buckland. 2020. Psychosis REACH Family Ambassador Manual. Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, University of Washington.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopelovich, S. L., B. Stiles, K. A. Hallgren, V. Kreider, D. R. Hrouda, and H. J. Sivec. 2022. &#x201c;Measuring Practitioner Attitudes Toward Psychosis and Recovery: Exploratory Factor Analysis of the Psychosis Attitudes Scale.&#x201d; Psychiatric Rehabilitation Journal 45, no. 3: 273&#x2013;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopelovich, S. L., B. Stiles, M. Monroe&#x2010;DeVita, K. Hardy, K. Hallgren, and D. Turkington. 2021. &#x201c;Psychosis REACH: Effects of a Brief CBT&#x2010;Informed Training for Family and Caregivers of Individuals With Psychosis.&#x201d; Psychiatric Services 72, no. 11: 1254&#x2013;1260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavis, A., H. Lester, L. Everard, et&#xa0;al. 2015. &#x201c;Layers of Listening: Qualitative Analysis of the Impact of Early Intervention Services for First&#x2010;Episode Psychosis on Carers' Experiences.&#x201d; British Journal of Psychiatry 207, no. 2: 135&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lean, M., K. Benitah, D. Wakeham, D. Virtheim, S. L. Kopelovich, and K. Hardy. 2025. &#x201c;A Qualitative Study of Family Experiences of the Peer Supported Family Intervention, Psychosis Recovery by Enabling Adult Carers at Home (Psychosis REACH), in an Early Psychosis Clinic.&#x201d; Early Intervention in Psychiatry Submitted Nov 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobban, F., A. Postlethwaite, D. Glentworth, et&#xa0;al. 2013. &#x201c;A Systematic Review of Randomised Controlled Trials of Interventions Reporting Outcomes for Relatives of People With Psychosis.&#x201d; Clinical Psychology Review 33, no. 3: 372&#x2013;382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGrath, J., S. Saha, D. Chant, and J. Welham. 2008. &#x201c;Schizophrenia: A Concise Overview of Incidence, Prevalence, and Mortality.&#x201d; Epidemiologic Reviews 30, no. 1: 67&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miklowitz, D. J., M. J. Goldstein, J. A. Doane, et&#xa0;al. 1989. &#x201c;Is Expressed Emotion an Index of a Transactional Process? I. Parents' Affective Style.&#x201d; Family Process 28, no. 2: 153&#x2013;167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE). 2013. Psychosis and Schizophrenia in Children and Young People: Recognition and Management Clinical Guidelines CG155. NICE. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/cg155/ifp/chapter/treating&#x2010;a&#x2010;first&#x2010;episode&#x2010;of&#x2010;psychosis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Driscoll, C., S. Farrelly, P. Burgess, G. Szmukler, and M. Shaikh. 2018. &#x201c;The Development and Validation of the Brief Experience of Caregiving Inventory (BECI).&#x201d; Comprehensive Psychiatry 86: 54&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oluwoye, O., B. Stokes, K. S. Garcia, et&#xa0;al. 2025. &#x201c;Feasibility and Acceptability Study of an Engagement Intervention for Family Members in Early Intervention Programs for Psychosis.&#x201d; Schizophrenia 12, no. 1: 5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onwumere, J., D. Shiers, and C. Chew&#x2010;Graham. 2016. &#x201c;Understanding the Needs of Carers of People With Psychosis in Primary Care.&#x201d; British Journal of General Practice 66, no. 649: 400&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson, N., P. J. Naylor, M. C. Ashe, M. Fernandez, S. L. Yoong, and L. Wolfenden. 2020. &#x201c;Guidance for Conducting Feasibility and Pilot Studies for Implementation Trials.&#x201d; Pilot and Feasibility Studies 6, no. 1: 167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pharoah, F., J. Mari, J. Rathbone, and W. Wong. 2010. &#x201c;Family Intervention for Schizophrenia.&#x201d; Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 12: CD000088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlosser, D. A., J. L. Zinberg, R. L. Loewy, et&#xa0;al. 2010. &#x201c;Predicting the Longitudinal Effects of the Family Environment on Prodromal Symptoms and Functioning in Patients At&#x2010;Risk for Psychosis.&#x201d; Schizophrenia Research 118, no. 1&#x2013;3: 69&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sin, J., J. Elkes, R. Batchelor, et&#xa0;al. 2021. &#x201c;Mental Health and Caregiving Experiences of Family Carers Supporting People With Psychosis.&#x201d; Epidemiology and Psychiatric Sciences 30: e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivec, H. J., V. A. L. Kreider, C. Buzzelli, D. R. Hrouda, and M. M. Hricovec. 2020. &#x201c;Do Attitudes Matter? Evaluating the Influence of Training in CBT&#x2010;p&#x2010;Informed Strategies on Attitudes About Working With People Who Experience Psychosis.&#x201d; Community Mental Health Journal 56, no. 6: 1153&#x2013;1159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stiles, B. J., A. M. Kuczynski, V. Shepard, J. Blank, and S. L. Kopelovich. 2025. &#x201c;Evaluating Response to a Cognitive Behavioural Therapy for Psychosis&#x2010;Informed Family Intervention at Variable Duration of a Psychotic Illness.&#x201d; Early Intervention in Psychiatry 19, no. 2: e70003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stowkowy, J., D. Addington, L. Liu, B. Hollowell, and J. Addington. 2012. &#x201c;Predictors of Disengagement From Treatment in an Early Psychosis Program.&#x201d; Schizophrenia Research 136, no. 1&#x2013;3: 7&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Interdepartmental Serious Mental Illness Coordinating Committee (ISMICC). 2017. The Way Forward: Federal Action for a System That Works for All People Living With SMI and SED and Their Families and Caregivers. Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration. https://www.samhsa.gov/sites/default/files/programs_campaigns/ismicc_2017_report_to_congress.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turkington, D., L. Gega, L. Lebert, et&#xa0;al. 2018. &#x201c;A Training Model for Relatives and Friends in Cognitive Behaviour Therapy (CBT) Informed Care for Psychosis.&#x201d; Cogent Psychology 5, no. 1: 1497749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaswani&#x2010;Bye, A., C. McCain, J. Blank, M. Tennison, and S. Kopelovich. 2024. &#x201c;A Thematic Analysis Investigating the Inaugural Psychosis REACH Family Ambassador Peer Training Program.&#x201d; Neuropsychiatric Disease and Treatment 20: 233&#x2013;245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villena Jimena, A., J. M. Morales&#x2010;Asencio, C. Quemada, and M. M. Hurtado. 2024. &#x201c;&#x201c;Sustaining the Burden&#x201d;. A Qualitative Study on the Emotional Impact and Social Functioning of Family Caregivers of Patients With Psychosis.&#x201d; Archives of Psychiatric Nursing 51: 95&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wainwright, L. D., D. Glentworth, G. Haddock, R. Bentley, and F. Lobban. 2015. &#x201c;What Do Relatives Experience When Supporting Someone in Early Psychosis?&#x201d; Psychology and Psychotherapy: Theory, Research and Practice 88, no. 1: 105&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zigmond, A. S., and R. P. Snaith. 1983. &#x201c;The Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale.&#x201d; Acta Psychiatrica Scandinavica 67, no. 6: 361&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>