<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41802761</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1439-3964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Seasonal Physical Performance Changes in U12-U15 Male Youth Soccer Players.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/a-2830-3088</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The present study aimed to investigate the development of physical performance attributes across one competition year in male youth soccer players from different playing levels, while controlling for baseline performance, chronological age, and biological maturity. A total of 175 male Scottish youth soccer players from three distinct playing levels, such as grassroots, professional youth, and performance school, were recruited. Physical testing (linear sprint, change of direction, squat jump, and Yo-Yo Intermittent Recovery Test Level 1) was conducted for all players to establish baseline fitness and then repeated under matched conditions at the end of the same competition year. A Bayesian approach was used to estimate the size of any change in each physical test over the season, estimate the uncertainty around these changes, and estimate the probability of direction of these changes. In all cases, the players improved fitness testing metrics. The grassroot group made the greatest changes in physical performances but did not match absolute performance of the professional youth and performance school groups. Our results provide meaningful benchmark data for evaluating and interpreting isolated physical fitness metrics between distinct youth playing levels and may augment the ongoing critique of the discriminative ability of isolated physical fitness tests in youth soccer.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Thieme. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>King</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Cardiovascular &amp; Metabolic Health, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ball</LastName><ForeName>Derek</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Medical Sciences and Nutrition, University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gibson</LastName><ForeName>Neil V</ForeName><Initials>NV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Transformational Design, Blacktown City Council, Blacktown, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weston</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Sport, Physical Education and Health Science, Moray House School of Education and Sport, The University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sport, Manchester Metropolitan University, Manchester, United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gallagher</LastName><ForeName>Iain J</ForeName><Initials>IJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Applied Sciences, Edinburgh Napier University, Edinburgh, United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dugdale</LastName><ForeName>James H</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Applied Sciences, Edinburgh Napier University, Edinburgh, United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8008349</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0172-4622</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41802761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2830-3088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>