<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41786838</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integrated deep learning-driven multi-stage steam forecasting and scheduling optimization for converter energy systems.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-42104-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Converter steam is a valuable secondary energy in steelmaking, and improving its recovery and utilization is essential for reducing energy cost. However, converter steam data are inherently time-segmented: before steelmaking starts, only limited planning information is available, while during production, high-frequency process signals drive rapid steam fluctuations. Existing studies mainly rely on single-stage time series forecasting, and rarely combine planning forecasts with sequential production forecasts to support steam scheduling. To address this gap, this study proposes an integrated two-stage, multi-time-scale forecasting framework for converter steam. First, the planning-to-production nature of converter steam generation is explicitly formulated, and a time-segmented forecasting workflow is established to link long-horizon planning prediction with short-horizon rolling prediction. Then, in the planning stage (approximately 2 hours ahead), a hyperparameter-optimized SVM model (IBKA-SVM) is employed to generate interval steam output forecasts, providing a reliable baseline for upper-level scheduling tasks such as steam network target setting and buffer allocation. Finally, in the production stage, a DSC-Transformer model performs fine-grained rolling steam-flow prediction based on time-series production data, and its outputs are used to dynamically update and correct the planning-stage baseline for operational control. Experiments on industrial converter data demonstrate that the proposed models achieve strong predictive performance (IBKA-SVM: 92.3%, DSC-Transformer: 98.7%) and consistently outperform conventional baselines. The proposed framework provides practical, multi-time-scale predictive support for converter steam scheduling and energy-efficient operation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Chongqing University of Science and Technology, Chongqing, 401331, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Baoshan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Chongqing University of Science and Technology, Chongqing, 401331, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronics and Internet of Things, Chongqing Polytechnic University of Electronic Technology, Chongqing, 401331, China. gaochao@cqcet.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Runying</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Chongqing University of Science and Technology, Chongqing, 401331, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Xuming</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science and Engineering, Chongqing University of Science and Technology, Chongqing, 401331, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>KJZD-K202503105</GrantID><Agency>Chongqing Municipal Education Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41786838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-42104-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-42104-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li, L. Analysis of automatic control technology in converter steelmaking. Metall. Mater. 44, 84&#x2013;86 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H., Xu, A., Gu, M. &amp; Liu, X. Prediction model of converter oxygen supply based on segmented oxygen decarburization efficiency. China Metall. 33, 91&#x2013;99 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, W., Huang, Y., Li, Z. &amp; Wang, X. Steam pipeline flow prediction based on improved informer. J. Shanghai Univ. Electr. Power 39, 571&#x2013;577 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, L., Wu, S. &amp; Zhang, Q. Simulation modeling and production-consumption forecasting of the steam system in iron and steel enterprises. Metall. Energy 41, 7&#x2013;12 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X., Jin, F., Zhao, J., Liu, Y. &amp; Liu, Q. Input-delay-based LSTM-GRU dynamic modeling method for steam flow in steel industry. In: Proceeding China Automation Congress (CAC), 1069&#x2013;1074 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, G. Prediction model of main steam flow for turbines based on improved whale optimization algorithm. Electr. Eng. Technol. 26&#x2013;28 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, D. Industrial steam volume forecasting method based on machine learning. Petrochem. Des. 38, 35&#x2013;38 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, Z., Zhu, Y. &amp; Gao, F. Steam volume prediction for thermal power plants based on a BLS-Lasso combined model. Sci. Technol. Eng. 22, 11394&#x2013;11401 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, M. &amp; He, L. Steam flow forecasting model based on time-set partitioning. Softw. Guide 19, 88&#x2013;93 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, L., Hu, J., Chen, L., Ren, Y. &amp; Wu, M. Coke oven gas generation forecasting model based on multi-temporal-scale feature fusion. Control Theory Appl. 1&#x2013;11 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao, X. et al. Multi-step prediction comparison of blast furnace gas generation based on temporal models. Iron Steel 57, 166&#x2013;172 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai, H., Xiong, W., Li, F. &amp; Yang, J. Simulation of cold rolling gas consumption forecasting model based on EMD-LSTM. Mach. Tool Hydraul. 50, 141&#x2013;145 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X. &amp; Li, Z. Prediction of blast furnace gas generation based on EMD-LSSVM model. Netw. Secur. Technol. Appl. 58&#x2013;60 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, Y., Li, Z. &amp; Liu, H. Application of dynamic gas prediction method. Shanxi Metall. 43, 176&#x2013;177 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zha, W. et al. Forecasting monthly gas field production based on the CNN-LSTM model. Energy 260, 124889 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norvai&#x161;a, E., Galinis, A. &amp; Neni&#x161;kis, E. Incorporation of wind power probabilities into long-term energy system development analysis using bottom-up models. Energ. Strat. Rev. 38, 100770. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esr.2021.100770 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kova&#x10d;evi&#x107;, R. M. &amp; Paraschiv, F. Medium-term planning for thermal electricity production. OR Spectrum 36, 723&#x2013;759. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00291-013-0349-4 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neni&#x161;kis, E. &amp; Galinis, A. Representation of wind power generation in economic models for long-term energy planning. Energetika 64 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao, W. et al. Natural gas consumption forecasting using a novel two-stage model based on improved sparrow search algorithm. J. Pipeline Sci. Eng. 5, 100220 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laib, O., Khadir, M. T. &amp; Mihaylova, L. Toward efficient energy systems based on natural gas consumption prediction with LSTM recurrent neural networks. Energy 177, 530&#x2013;542 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. et al. Enhancing XRF sensor-based sorting of porphyritic copper ore using particle swarm optimization-support vector machine (PSO-SVM) algorithm. Int. J. Min. Sci. Technol. 34, 545&#x2013;556 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, C., Yin, K., Cao, Y. &amp; Ahmed, B. Application of time series analysis and PSO-SVM model in predicting the Bazimen landslide in the three gorges reservoir, China. Eng. Geol. 204, 108&#x2013;120 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Wang, W., Hu, X., Qiu, L. &amp; Zang, H. Black-winged kite algorithm: a nature-inspired meta-heuristic for solving benchmark functions and engineering problems. Artif. Intell. Rev. 57, 98 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J., Zhang, M. &amp; Wang, D. Enhanced gallinule optimization algorithm and its application. Mini-Micro Comput. Syst. 45, 2401&#x2013;2410 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y., Wang, W., Yang, Y. &amp; Zhou, H. Multi-strategy improved marine predators algorithm and its engineering application. Comput. Integr. Manuf. Syst. 1&#x2013;21 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, S. et al. Dimension decided Harris Hawks optimization with gaussian mutation: Balance analysis and diversity patterns. Knowl. Based Syst. 215, 106425 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Cao, J., Yuan, S. &amp; Cheng, M. Short-term forecasting of natural gas prices by using a novel hybrid method based on a combination of the ceemdan-se-and the pso-als-optimized gru network. Energy 233, 121082 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y., Sun, S. &amp; Cai, Z. Daily peak-valley electric-load forecasting based on an SSA-LSTM-RF algorithm. Energies 16, 7964 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi, Y., He, Y., Qi, X., Zhang, Y. &amp; Yang, G. Dynamic snake convolution based on topological geometric constraints for tubular structure segmentation. In: Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 6047&#x2013;6056 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu, Y. et al. Road crack detection by combining dynamic snake convolution and attention mechanism. Appl. Sci. 14, 8100 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaswani, A. et al. Attention is all you need (In Advances in neural information processing systems, 2017).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>