<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41796147</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of static oxidation characteristics and analysis of displacement efficiency during air injection in light oil reservoirs.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-40187-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Air injection oil displacement is a highly promising enhanced oil recovery technology due to its wide gas source availability, low cost and strong reservoir adaptability. To enhance the application effectiveness of air injection for low-temperature oxidation (LTO) flooding in a specific light oil reservoir in China's Xinjiang oilfield, this study systematically investigates the static oxidation characteristics of crude oil and their influence on oil displacement performance. High-pressure static oxidation experiments and long-core physical simulation tests were conducted to examine the effects of oxidation time, water saturation, oxygen concentration, medium oil components (C<sub>7</sub>-C<sub>17</sub>), and reservoir minerals on the LTO behavior of crude oil. The oil displacement efficiency under different permeability conditions during air flooding was also analyzed. The results indicate that the LTO process exhibits stage-wise characteristics: in the initial stage, oxygen consumption is rapid, light and medium components decrease while heavy components increase, leading to higher viscosity and density of the crude oil. Reservoir conditions significantly influence oxidation pathways-high water saturation, low oxygen concentration, and high medium components inhibit oxidation, whereas reservoir cuttings promote cracking reactions due to their catalytic effect, resulting in oil lightening. Long-core flooding experiments further reveal that air flooding is more suitable for formations with relatively high permeability, which helps delay gas channeling, improve sweep efficiency, and thus achieve higher oil recovery. This research clarifies the intrinsic relationship between oxidation reactions and oil displacement performance during air injection, providing a theoretical basis for the application of air injection technology in light oil reservoirs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Zhezhi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Petroleum and Natural Gas Engineering, Chongqing University of Science and Technology, Chongqing, 401331, China. liuzhezhi1@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Joint Engineering Research Center for Shale Gas Exploration and Development, Chongqing Institute of Geology and Mineral Resources, Chongqing, 401120, China. liuzhezhi1@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Coal Mine Disaster Dynamics and Control, Chongqing University, Chongqing, 400044, China. liuzhezhi1@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Bowen</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Petroleum and Natural Gas Engineering, Chongqing University of Science and Technology, Chongqing, 401331, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Suhan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Petroleum and Natural Gas Engineering, Chongqing University of Science and Technology, Chongqing, 401331, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Petroleum and Natural Gas Engineering, Chongqing University of Science and Technology, Chongqing, 401331, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>CSTB2024NSCQ-MSX1016</GrantID><Agency>The Natural Science Foundation of Chongqing</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>KJQN202301533</GrantID><Agency>The Scientific and Technological Research Program of Chongqing Municipal Education Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Air injection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Light oil reservoir</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Low-temperature oxidation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oil displacement efficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Static oxidation experiment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41796147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-40187-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-40187-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xu, C. et al. Exploration and development of deep oil and gas resources in onshore china: status and prospect. Nat. Gas Geosci. 28 (08), 1139&#x2013;1153 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Yi. Classification and evaluation of undeveloped reserves in low-permeability reservoirs based on development technologies. Petroleum Geol. Exp. 44 (02), 337&#x2013;341 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, S. et al. Oxidation characteristics and kinetics of shale oil using high-pressure differential scanning calorimetry. Energy Fuels. 35 (22), 18726&#x2013;18732 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. et al. Current status and prospect of enhanced oil recovery technology in low permeability reservoirs. Spec. Oil Gas Reserv. 30 (01), 1&#x2013;13 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. et al. Technical progress of enhanced oil recovery in low permeability reservoirs of Yanchang oilfield. Petroleum Geol. Recovery Effi. 29 (04), 69&#x2013;75. https://doi.org/10.13673/j.cnki.cn37-1359/te.202201005 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zafar, A. et al. Tight gas production model considering TPG as a function of pore pressure, permeability and water saturation. Pet. Sci. 17 (5), 1356&#x2013;1369 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, Y. L. et al. A new model for predicting irreducible water saturation in tight gas reservoirs. Pet. Sci. 17 (4), 1087&#x2013;1100 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahir, M. U. et al. Simulating the strategies of oil field development for enhanced oil recovery. Therm. Sci. 24 (Suppl. 1), 411&#x2013;422 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. et al. Combustion tube experiments on key factors controlling the combustion process of air injection with light oil reservoir. Geoenergy Sci. Eng. 224, 211611 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Z. et al. Study on transformation of waterflooding development method in low permeability reservoirs: a case study of Kongnan GD6X1 block in Dagang Oilfield. Petroleum Geol. Recovery Effi. 27 (05), 105&#x2013;111. https://doi.org/10.13673/j.cnki.cn37-1359/te.2020.05.012 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, S. et al. Technological progress and prospects of enhanced oil recovery by gas injection. Acta Petrol. Sin. 41 (12), 1623&#x2013;1632 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao, G. et al. Oxidation reaction characteristics of crude oil in air injection and corresponding development methods across the full temperature range. Pet. Explor. Dev. 47 (02), 334&#x2013;340 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua, D. et al. Research on the development mechanism of air thermal miscible flooding in the high water cut stage of medium to high permeability light oil reservoirs. Energies 18 (11), 2783 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. et al. New insights on low temperature oxidation characteristics and possibility of auto-ignition in light oil reservoir. Geoenergy Sci. Eng. 223, 211583 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C. et al. Capillary and viscous forces during CO2 flooding in tight reservoirs. Capillarity 5 (6), 105&#x2013;114 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, Z., Shen, H. &amp; Li, Y. Feasibility study on air injection for enhancing oil recovery in Xinjiang C oilfield. Sci. Technol. Eng. 22 (26), 11364&#x2013;11371 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, C. et al. Oxidation characteristics and oil displacement effect evaluation of air flooding in low permeability reservoirs. Special Oil Gas Reserv. 31 (04), 109&#x2013;117 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi, H. et al. Low-temperature oxidation characteristics of light crude oil during oxygen-reduced air flooding. Pet. Explor. Dev. 48 (06), 1210&#x2013;1217 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, J. et al. Study on low temperature oxidation characteristics of shale oil and its influencing factors. Appl. Chem. Ind. 51 (S2), 79&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.16581/j.cnki.issn1671-3206.2022.s2.056 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H. Study on oxidation characteristics of different heavy oil fractions during air injection development. J. Xi&#x2019;an Shiyou Univ. (Natural Sci. Edition). 36 (02), 76&#x2013;82 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, C. et al. Experiment of air injection for enhancing oil recovery in low-permeability reservoirs and characteristics of low-temperature oxidation reaction. Petroleum Geol. Oilfield Dev. Daqing. 41 (01), 97&#x2013;103. https://doi.org/10.19597/j.issn.1000-3754.202101025 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, P. et al. Investigation on the low temperature oxidation of light oil for safely enhancing oil recovery at high temperatures and pressures. Energy 200, 117546 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huan, Q. I. &amp; Yiqiang, L. I. Low-temperature oxidation of light crude oil in oxygen-reduced air flooding. Pet. Explor. Dev. 48 (6), 1393&#x2013;1402 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, S., Zhang, Y. &amp; Sheng, J. J. Experimental investigation of enhanced oil recovery mechanisms of air injection under a low-temperature oxidation process: thermal effect and residual oil recovery efficiency. Energy Fuels. 32 (6), 6774&#x2013;6781 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, T. et al. Catalytic mechanism of low-temperature oxidation and reservoir adaptability of catalytic air flooding technology. Acta Petrol. Sin. 44 (07), 1118&#x2013;1128 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Changfeng, X. I. et al. Oxidization characteristics and thermal miscible flooding of high pressure air injection in light oil reservoirs. Pet. Explor. Dev. 49 (4), 874&#x2013;885 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X. et al. Evaluation of low-temperature oxidation analysis and the development effect of high-pressure air injection in low-permeability reservoirs. Front. Earth Sci. 12, 1416824 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pu, W. et al. High pressure air injection in ultra-low permeability reservoirs: effects of physical and chemical reactions on oil recovery. Chem. Eng. Res. Des. 195, 323&#x2013;331 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, S. et al. Low-temperature oxidation characteristics and reaction pathways of crude oil within tight shale during air injection. Petroleum 11 (1), 84&#x2013;93 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, C. et al. Crude oil oxidation in an air injection based enhanced oil recovery process: chemical reaction mechanism and catalysis. Energy Fuels. 36 (10), 5209&#x2013;5227 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, S. et al. Low-temperature oxidation of heavy crude oil characterized by TG, DSC, GC-MS, and negative ion ESI FT-ICR MS. Energy 214, 119004 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L. et al. Thermo-oxidative behavior and kinetics analysis of light and heavy oils based on TG, DSC, and FTIR. Geoenergy Sci. Eng. 223, 211525 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, C. et al. Experimental study on the isothermal low-temperature oxidation behavior and kinetics of light oil using TG-FTIR. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 2025, 1&#x2013;8 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L. et al. Oxidation behaviors of Hongqian heavy crude oil characterized by TG-DSC-FTIR-MS within full temperature regions. Fuel 353, 129242 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, S. et al. Influence of water on thermo-oxidative behavior and kinetic triplets of shale oil during combustion. Fuel 318, 123690 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huan, Q. I. et al. Low-temperature oxidation of light crude oil in oxygen-reduced air flooding. Pet. Explor. Dev. 48 (6), 1393&#x2013;1402 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gui, B. et al. Study of the effects of low-temperature oxidation on the chemical composition of a light crude oil. Energy Fuels. 24 (2), 1139&#x2013;1145 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J. et al. A comprehensive analysis of the properties of light crude oil in oxidation experimental studies. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 117 (2), 979&#x2013;984 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Saffar, H. B. et al. Oxidation reactions of a light crude oil and its SARA fractions in consolidated cores. Energy Fuels. 15 (1), 182&#x2013;188 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X. et al. Catalytic capacity evolution of montmorillonite in in-situ combustion of heavy oil. Fuel 333, 126621 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, L. et al. A review on the research progress of zeolite catalysts for heavy oil cracking. Catalysts 15 (4), 401 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, C. et al. Catalytic role of various clay minerals during the thermal reaction process with oxidized and pyrolyzed oils. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 149 (15), 8681&#x2013;8691 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xi, C. et al. Oxidization characteristics and thermal miscible flooding of high pressure air injection in light oil reservoirs. Pet. Explor. Dev. 49 (4), 760&#x2013;769 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, K. et al. The characteristics of two-phase flow in porous media over wide range of Capillary, Viscous, and inertial force. J. Appl. Math. Comput. 9, 4 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue-wu, W. et al. Experimental and theoretical investigation of nonlinear flow in low permeability reservoir. Procedia Environ. Sci. 11, 1392&#x2013;1399 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zafar, A. et al. The numerical simulation of effects of porosity, permeability and fluid saturation on heat dissipation in an oil reservoir. In Conference of the Arabian Journal of Geosciences 425&#x2013;428 (Springer International Publishing, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W. et al. Investigation of plugging performance and enhanced oil recovery of multi-scale polymer microspheres in low-permeability reservoirs. Nat. Gas Ind. B 10 (3), 223&#x2013;232 (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>