<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41902575</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1941-0921</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Impact of Psychological and Social Factors on Recovery After ACL Reconstruction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>19417381261430758</StartPage><MedlinePgn>19417381261430758</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">19417381261430758</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/19417381261430758</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The purpose of this study was to investigate the impact of demographic, psychological, and social factors on self-reported recovery after anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction (ACLR).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="HYPOTHESIS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Psychological and social factors would be associated with lower patient-reported outcome scores (PROMS) after ACLR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Case series.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level 4.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Retrospective review was conducted of patients who underwent ACLR at a single institution. Recovery was measured by using the PROMIS 10 SF Global Health Physical score, Lysholm Knee score, International Knee Documentation Committee (IKDC) score, and Knee Outcome Survey (KOS) scores. Multivariable linear regression models were developed to predict 6-month PROMIS 10 SF Global Health Physical, Lysholm Knee, IKDC, and KOS scores. Sociodemographic, surgical, and preoperative PROMS with variance inflation factors &gt;5 were removed to minimize collinearity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 67 patients who underwent ACLR between December 2013 to August 2023 were included in this study, with a mean age of 31.1&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;10.3&#x2009;years. Smoking history was consistently associated with lower 6-month IKDC (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;-33.5 [-54.0, -13.0], <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002), KOS (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;-35.6 [-42.3, -18.4], <i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), and Lysholm (&#x3b2; = -27.6 [-45.1, -10.0], <i>P</i> = 0.004) scores. White race was associated with lower Lysholm scores (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;-8.0 [-13.1, -3.0], <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.003). Higher preoperative PROMIS mental health scores were associated with higher KOS (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.4 [0.1, 0.6], <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01). Patients with Medicaid reported higher KOS scores (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;7.2 [2.4, 12.0], <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.004).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Several psychosocial and demographic factors may influence recovery after ACL reconstruction. In our study, smoking predicted worse outcomes, while having Medicaid insurance was unexpectedly linked to better self-reported recovery. White race predicted worse outcomes. Mental health findings were contradictory, with high preoperative PROMIS mental health scores, representing current mental health, and a history of depression potentially associated with improved outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL RELEVANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Identifying psychological and social factors preoperatively can help clinicians better understand which patients may be at risk for lower self-reported outcomes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malempati</LastName><ForeName>Mahant</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2179-3997</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tulane University School of Medicine, New Orleans, Louisiana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siddiqui</LastName><ForeName>Raheyma N</ForeName><Initials>RN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-4003-8699</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Loyola Stritch School of Medicine, Maywood, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lo</LastName><ForeName>Jordan E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Loyola Stritch School of Medicine, Maywood, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varieur</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin M</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Loyola Stritch School of Medicine, Maywood, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rumps</LastName><ForeName>Mia V</ForeName><Initials>MV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Loyola Stritch School of Medicine, Maywood, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mulcahey</LastName><ForeName>Mary K</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6125-8169</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Loyola University Medical Center, Maywood, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518422</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1941-0921</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACL reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social determinants of health</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41902575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13033041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381261430758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ardebol J, Kili&#xe7; AI-, Pak T, Menendez ME, Denard PJ. Greater socioeconomic disadvantage as measured by the area deprivation index is associated with failure of healing following arthroscopic repair of massive rotator cuff tears but not with clinical outcomes. Arthroscopy. 2024;40(2):287-293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37774937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Taylor NF, Feller JA, Whitehead TS, Webster KE. Psychological responses matter in returning to preinjury level of sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41(7):1549-1558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23733635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Webster KE, Taylor NF, Feller JA. Return to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis of the state of play. Br J Sports Med. 2011;45(7):596-606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21398310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashton ML, Kraeutler MJ, Brown SM, Mulcahey MK. Psychological readiness to return to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. JBJS Rev. 2020;8(3):e0110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32149933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer M, Feeley BT, Wawrzyniak JR, Pinkowsky G, Gallo RA. Factors affecting return to play after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a review of the current literature. Phys Sportsmed. 2014;42(4):71-79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25419890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck PR, Nho SJ, Balin J, et al. Postoperative pain management after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Knee Surg. 2004;17(1):18-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14971669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buller LT, Best MJ, Baraga MG, Kaplan LD. Trends in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in the United States. Orthop J Sports Med. 2014;3(1):2325967114563664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4555588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26535368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christino MA, Fantry AJ, Vopat BG. Psychological aspects of recovery following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2015;23(8):501-509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26209145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cupal DD, Brewer BW. Effects of relaxation and guided imagery on knee strength, reinjury anxiety, and pain following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Rehabil Psychol. 2001;46(1):28-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dingenen B, Gokeler A. Optimization of the return-to-sport paradigm after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a critical step back to move forward. Sports Med. 2017;47(8):1487-1500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28078610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubin JA, Bains SS, Hameed D, et al. The utility of the area deprivation index in assessing complications after total joint arthroplasty. JB JS Open Access. 2024;9(2):e23.00115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10984656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38577548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glattke KE, Tummala SV, Chhabra A. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction recovery and rehabilitation: a systematic review. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2022;104(8):739-754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34932514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hays RD, Schalet BD, Spritzer KL, Cella D. Two-item PROMIS&#xae; global physical and mental health scales. J Patient Rep Outcomes. 2017;1(1):2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5934936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29757325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewett TE, Di Stasi SL, Myer GD. Current concepts for injury prevention in athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41(1):216-224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3592333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23041233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins LD, Taylor MK, Park D, et al. Reliability and validity of the International Knee Documentation Committee (IKDC) Subjective Knee Form. Joint Bone Spine. 2007;74(6):594-599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17888709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irrgang JJ, Anderson AF, Boland AL, et al. Development and validation of the international knee documentation committee subjective knee form. Am J Sports Med. 2001;29(5):600-613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11573919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayakumar P, Teunis T, Vranceanu AM, Lamb S, Ring D, Gwilym S. Early psychological and social factors explain the recovery trajectory after distal radial fracture. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2020;102(9):788-795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan H, Roderick P, Martin D. The Index of Multiple Deprivation 2000 and accessibility effects on health. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2004;58(3):250-257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1732697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14966241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellezi B, Coupland C, Morriss R, et al. The impact of psychological factors on recovery from injury: a multicentre cohort study. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2017;52(7):855-866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5504249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27803978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lysholm J, Gillquist J. Evaluation of knee ligament surgery results with special emphasis on use of a scoring scale. Am J Sports Med. 1982;10(3):150-154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6896798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mall NA, Chalmers PN, Moric M, et al. Incidence and trends of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in the United States. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42(10):2363-2370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25086064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musahl V, Karlsson J. Anterior cruciate ligament tear. New Engl J Med. 2019;380(24):2341-2348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31189037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novikov DA, Swensen SJ, Buza JA, III, Gidumal RH, Strauss EJ. The effect of smoking on ACL reconstruction: a systematic review. Phys Sportsmed. 2016;44(4):335-341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27456300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaffer JC, Kuhns B, Reuter J, et al. Clinically depressed patients having anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction show improved but inferior rate of achieving minimum clinically important difference for patient-reported outcomes measurement information system compared with situationally depressed or nondepressed patients. Arthroscopy. 2022;38(10):2863-2872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35550418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherzer CB, Brewer BW, Cornelius AE, et al. Psychological skills and adherence to rehabilitation after reconstruction of the anterior cruciate ligament. J Sport Rehabil. 2001;10(3):165-172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thome&#xe9; P, W&#xe4;hrborg P, B&#xf6;rjesson M, Thome&#xe9; R, Eriksson BI, Karlsson J. A new instrument for measuring self-efficacy in patients with an anterior cruciate ligament injury. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2006;16(3):181-187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16643196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thome&#xe9; P, W&#xe4;hrborg P, B&#xf6;rjesson M, Thome&#xe9; R, Eriksson BI, Karlsson J. Self-efficacy of knee function as a pre-operative predictor of outcome 1&#x2009;year after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2008;16(2):118-127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18034333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turk R, Shah S, Chilton M, et al. Return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction requires evaluation of &gt;2 functional tests, psychological readiness, quadriceps/hamstring strength, and time after surgery of 8 months. Arthroscopy. 2023;39(3):790-801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36216133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health. 2023. Area Deprivation Index Version 4.0. https://www.neighborhoodatlas.medicine.wisc.edu/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Feller JA. Psychological readiness to return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in the adolescent athlete. J Athl Train. 2022;57(9-10):955-960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9842114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36638341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, McPherson AL, Hewett TE, Feller JA. Factors associated with a return to preinjury level of sport performance after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Am J Sports Med. 2019;47(11):2557-2562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31381373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfensberger A, Vuistiner P, Konzelmann M, Plomb-Holmes C, L&#xe9;ger B, Luthi F. Clinician and patient-reported outcomes are associated with psychological factors in patients with chronic shoulder pain. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2016;474(9):2030-2039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4965376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27357692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>