<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41663661</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>ReFaceX: donor-driven reversible face anonymisation with detached recovery.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7882</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-39337-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Organisations must share facial imagery that remains useful for analysis while protecting identity. Many current methods fail to strike this balance: reconstruction-centred encoder-decoder designs tend to blur salient detail, whereas latent edits in pretrained generators often retain or drift identity cues, undermining privacy and utility. We present ReFaceX, a reversible anonymisation framework that separates what to protect from what to preserve. A donor identity code steers a U-Net anonymiser with Identity Feature Fusion to change identity while retaining non-identity content such as pose, background and expression. A learned steganographic channel carries a compact recovery payload, and reconstruction gradients are blocked at the stego image so the anonymiser is never rewarded for keeping identity. The threat model is stated explicitly and outcomes are audited with strong recognisers. On LFW and CelebA-HQ datasets at [Formula: see text], ReFaceX reduces identity similarity across FaceNet, ArcFace and AdaFace, and improves recovered-image quality (SSIM [Formula: see text], LPIPS [Formula: see text], PSNR [Formula: see text] dB), while operating in real time on a single RTX&#xa0;3090. Robustness to common JPEG re-encoding is also demonstrated. By turning the privacy-utility balance into an explicit and auditable operating choice, ReFaceX provides a practical template for responsible release of facial imagery and a foundation for extensions to video, higher resolutions and stronger recovery guarantees.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muhammad</LastName><ForeName>Dost</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Ireland Center of Research Training and Artificial Intelligence (CRT-AI), Galway, Ireland. d.muhammad1@universityofgalway.ie.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ADAPT Research Centre, School of Computer Science, University of Galway, Galway, Ireland. d.muhammad1@universityofgalway.ie.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salman</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Software Engineering, University of Malakand, Malakand, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Syed Muhammad Haider</ForeName><Initials>SMH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science, University of Galway, Galway, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bendechache</LastName><ForeName>Malika</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ADAPT Research Centre, School of Computer Science, University of Galway, Galway, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>GOIPG/2025/847</GrantID><Acronym>SFI_</Acronym><Agency>Science Foundation Ireland</Agency><Country>Ireland</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005145" MajorTopicYN="Y">Face</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068240" MajorTopicYN="Y">Data Anonymization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007091" MajorTopicYN="Y">Image Processing, Computer-Assisted</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018907" MajorTopicYN="N">Privacy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep learning in imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Detached recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Donor-driven identity transfer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Face recognition auditing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Identity feature fusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Image steganography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Open set re-identification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Privacy utility trade off</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ReFaceX</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reversible face anonymisation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41663661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12953573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-39337-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-39337-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Huang, G.&#xa0;B., Mattar, M., Berg, T. &amp; Learned-Miller, E. Labeled faces in the wild: A database for studying face recognition in unconstrained environments. In <i>Workshop on Faces in Real-Life Images</i> (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hukkel&#xe5;s, H., Mester, R. &amp; Lindseth, F. Deepprivacy: A generative adversarial network for face anonymization. In <i>ISVC</i> (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, J., Guo, J., Xue, N. &amp; Zafeiriou, S. Arcface: Additive angular margin loss for deep face recognition. In <i>CVPR</i> (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34106845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H. et al. Cosface: Large margin cosine loss for deep face recognition. In <i>CVPR</i> (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isola, P., Zhu, J.-Y., Zhou, T. &amp; Efros, A.&#xa0;A. Image-to-image translation with conditional adversarial networks. In <i>CVPR</i> (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledig, C. et al. Photo-realistic single image super-resolution using a generative adversarial network. In <i>CVPR</i> (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baluja, S. Hiding images in plain sight: Deep steganography. In <i>NeurIPS</i> (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Z., Han, S. &amp; Liu, X. A security analysis of generative steganography. <i>IEEE Access</i> (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes, J. &amp; Danezis, G. Generating steganographic images via adversarial training. In <i>NeurIPS Workshop on Machine Deception</i> (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, R., Isola, P., Efros, A.&#xa0;A., Shechtman, E. &amp; Wang, O. The unreasonable effectiveness of deep features as a perceptual metric. <i>CVPR</i> (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tov, O., Alaluf, Y., Nitzan, Y., Patashnik, O. &amp; Cohen-Or, D. Designing an encoder for stylegan image manipulation. In <i>SIGGRAPH</i> (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alaluf, Y., Patashnik, O. &amp; Cohen-Or, D. Restyle: A residual-based stylegan encoder via iterative refinement. In <i>ICCV</i> (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronneberger, O., Fischer, P. &amp; Brox, T. U-net: Convolutional networks for biomedical image segmentation. In <i>MICCAI</i> (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maximov, M., Elezi, I. &amp; Leal-Taix&#xe9;, L. Ciagan: Conditional identity anonymization with generative adversarial networks. In <i>CVPR Workshops</i> (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meden, B. et al. Privacy-enhancing face biometrics: A comprehensive survey. <i>IEEE Trans. Inf. Forensics Secur.</i><b>16</b>, 4147&#x2013;4183 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIFS.2021.3096024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barattin, S. et al. Attribute-preserving face dataset anonymization via latent code optimization. In <i>Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)</i> (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, D. &amp; et al. Riddle: Reversible and diversified de-identification with latent encryptor. arXiv:2303.05171 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, J., Kaplan, R., Johnson, J. &amp; Fei-Fei, L. Hidden: Hiding data with deep networks. In <i>ECCV</i> (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tancik, M. et al. Stegastamp: Invisible hyperlinks in physical photographs. In <i>CVPR</i> (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tancik, M., Mildenhall, B. &amp; Ng, R. Stegastamp: Invisible hyperlinks in physical photographs. In <i>Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF conference on computer vision and pattern recognition</i>, 2117&#x2013;2126 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingma, D.&#xa0;P. &amp; Ba, J. Adam: A method for stochastic optimisation. In <i>International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)</i>arXiv:1412.6980 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karras, T., Laine, S. &amp; Aila, T. A style-based generator architecture for generative adversarial networks. In <i>Proc. CVPR</i>, 4401&#x2013;4410 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32012000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, K., Zhang, Z., Li, Z. &amp; Qiao, Y. Joint face detection and alignment using multitask cascaded convolutional networks. In: <i>Proc. IEEE SPL</i><b>23</b>, 1499&#x2013;1503 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karras, T., Aila, T., Laine, S. &amp; Lehtinen, J. Progressive growing of GANs for improved quality, stability, and variation. In <i>Proc. ICLR</i> (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z., Luo, P., Wang, X. &amp; Tang, X. Deep learning face attributes in the wild. In <i>Proc. ICCV</i>, 3730&#x2013;3738 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, G.&#xa0;B., Ramesh, M., Berg, T. &amp; Learned-Miller, E. Labeled faces in the wild: A database for studying face recognition in unconstrained environments. In <i>Proc. Workshop on Faces in &#x2019;Real-Life&#x2019; Images</i> (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe4;rkk&#xe4;inen, K. &amp; Joo, J. Fairface: Face attribute dataset for balanced race, gender, and age. arXiv:1908.04913 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, X. et al. Password-conditioned anonymization and deanonymization with face identity transformers. In <i>European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), Proceedings of ECCV 2020</i> (Springer International Publishing, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rombach, R., Blattmann, A., Lorenz, D., Esser, P. &amp; Ommer, B. High-resolution image synthesis with latent diffusion models. In <i>Proc. CVPR</i>, 10684&#x2013;10695 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L. et al. Adding conditional control to text-to-image diffusion models. arXiv:2302.05543 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad, D. &amp; Bendechache, M. Can ai be faster, accurate, and explainable? spikenet makes it happen. In <i>Annual Conference on Medical Image Understanding and Analysis</i>, 43&#x2013;57 (Springer, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z., Zhang, Z., Zhou, H. &amp; Hu, N. Steganogan: High capacity image steganography with GANs. In <i>Proc. ICASSP</i>, 2087&#x2013;2091 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad, D., Keles, A. &amp; Bendechache, M. Towards explainable deep learning in oncology: Integrating efficientnet-b7 with xai techniques for acute lymphoblastic leukaemia. In <i>Proceedings of the 27th European Conference on Artificial Intelligence (ECAI) (Spain, 2024)</i> (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, M., Muhammad, D., Khalaf, O. I. &amp; Habib, R. Optimizing mobile cloud computing: A comparative analysis and innovative cost-efficient partitioning model. <i>SN Comput. Sci.</i><b>6</b>, 1&#x2013;25 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad, D., Salman, M. &amp; Bendechache, M. High cost, low trust? msa-pnet fixes both for medical imaging. In <i>Proceedings of the Second Workshop on Explainable Artificial Intelligence for the medical domain-25-30 October</i> (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad, D., Salman, M. &amp; Bendechache, M. Cracking the clinical code: A scoping review on mechanistic interpretability in medical report generation. <i>Comput. Struct. Biotechnol. Rep.</i> 100066 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z., Bovik, A. C., Sheikh, H. R. &amp; Simoncelli, E. P. Image quality assessment: From error visibility to structural similarity. <i>IEEE Trans. Image Process.</i><b>13</b>, 600&#x2013;612. 10.1109/TIP.2003.819861 (2004).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIP.2003.819861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15376593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hore, A. &amp; Ziou, D. Image quality metrics: Psnr vs. ssim. In <i>Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR)</i>, 2366&#x2013;2369, 10.1109/ICPR.2010.579 (IEEE, 2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke, W. et al. Improving the transferability of adversarial examples through neighborhood attribution. <i>Knowl.-Based Syst.</i><b>296</b>, 111909 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knosys.2024.111909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, D. et al. Enhancing the transferability of adversarial attacks via multi-feature attention. <i>IEEE Trans. Inf. Forensics Secur.</i> (2025).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>