<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41848720</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Menstrual Cycle Influence on Post-exercise Recovery: Comparing the Efficacy of Dry and Ice Massage in Female Combat Sports Athletes.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005367</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Trybulski, R, Smoter, M, Vovkanych, A, Svyshch, Y, and Clemente, FM. Menstrual cycle influence on post-exercise recovery: comparing the efficacy of dry and ice massage in female combat sports athletes. J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2025-This study investigated how menstrual cycle phases affect recovery in female athletes after intense exercise, comparing dry massage and ice massage. Thirty-three combat sports athletes (age: 25.3 &#xb1; 2.1) were divided into 3 groups: dry massage, ice massage, and control. Subjects underwent an intense plyometric session during both the early-follicular and mid-luteal phases of their menstrual cycle. Measurements of muscle stiffness (MS), pressure pain threshold (PPT), cutaneous microvascular blood flow (CMBF), reactive strength index (RSI), creatine kinase (CK), and total quality of recovery (TQR) were taken pre- and post-exercise, at 24 and 72 hours. Massage groups received treatment twice daily for 3 days per cycle. Both dry and ice massages significantly reduced CMBF and MS and increased PPT compared with control up to 24 hours posttreatment (p &lt; 0.001), though effects differed at 72 hours. In addition, recovery in these 3 measures was greater during the early-follicular phase compared with the mid-luteal phase (p &lt; 0.05), with significant effects observed on CMBF and PPT. Reactive strength index and total quality of recovery were significantly higher at 24 and 72 hours in both massage groups compared with the control (p &lt; 0.001). Meanwhile, CK levels were significantly superior in both experimental groups only at 72 hours post-session (p &lt; 0.001) when compared with the control. Menstrual cycle phase did not influence CK, while RSI and TQR showed slight differences. In conclusion, both dry and ice massage effectively enhance recovery following intense exercise, particularly in improving MS, PPT, and CMBF, with the early-follicular phase showing slightly better recovery outcomes than the mid-luteal phase.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trybulski</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Department Wojciech Korfanty, Upper Silesian Academy in Katowice, Katowice, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy and Ergotherapy, Ivan Boberkyj Lviv State University of Physical Culture, Lviv, Ukraine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smoter</LastName><ForeName>Ma&#x142;gorzata</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Basic Physiotherapy, Gdansk University of Physical Education and Sport, Gdansk, Poland; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vovkanych</LastName><ForeName>Andriy</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy and Ergotherapy, Ivan Boberkyj Lviv State University of Physical Culture, Lviv, Ukraine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Svyshch</LastName><ForeName>Yaroslav</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy and Ergotherapy, Ivan Boberkyj Lviv State University of Physical Culture, Lviv, Ukraine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clemente</LastName><ForeName>Filipe Manuel</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9813-2842</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomechanics and Sport Engineering, Gdansk University of Physical Education and Sport, Gdansk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle stiffness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">perceived recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical readiness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pressure pain threshold</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reactive strength index</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41848720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aboodarda S, Spence A, Button DC. Pain pressure threshold of a muscle tender spot increases following local and non-local rolling massage. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 16: 265, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamczyk JG, Krasowska I, Boguszewski D, Reaburn P. The use of thermal imaging to assess the effectiveness of ice massage and cold-water immersion as methods for supporting post-exercise recovery. J Therm Biol 60: 20&#x2013;25, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anaya-Terroba L, Arroyo-Morales M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-las-Pe&#xf1;as C, D&#xed;az-Rodr&#xed;guez L, Cleland JA. Effects of ice massage on pressure pain thresholds and electromyography activity postexercise: A randomized controlled crossover study. J Manipulative Physiol Ther 33: 212&#x2013;219, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arroyo-Morales M, Olea N, Ru&#xed;z C, et al. Massage after exercise-responses of immunologic and endocrine markers: A randomized single-blind placebo-controlled study. J Strength Cond Res 23: 638&#x2013;644, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayer ML, Hoegberget&#x2010;Kalisz M, Jensen MH, et al. Role of tissue perfusion, muscle strength recovery, and pain in rehabilitation after acute muscle strain injury: A randomized controlled trial comparing early and delayed rehabilitation. Scand J Med Sci Sports 28: 2579&#x2013;2591, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bezuglov E, Lazarev A, Khaitin V, et al. The prevalence of use of various post-exercise recovery methods after training among elite endurance athletes. Int J Environ Res Public Health 18: 11698, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coswig VS, Ramos SdP, Del Vecchio FB. Time-motion and biological responses in simulated mixed martial arts sparring matches. J Strength Cond Res 30: 2156&#x2013;2163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daki&#x107; M, Ili&#x107; V, Toski&#x107; L, et al. Acute effects of short-term massage procedures on neuromechanical contractile properties of rectus femoris muscle. Med (B Aires) 60: 125, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daki&#x107; M, Toski&#x107; L, Ili&#x107; V, &#x110;uri&#x107; S, Dopsaj M, &#x160;imenko J. The effects of massage therapy on sport and exercise performance: A systematic review. Sports 11: 110, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuy O, Douzi W, Theurot D, Bosquet L, Dugu&#xe9; B. An evidence-based approach for choosing post-exercise recovery techniques to reduce markers of muscle damage, soreness, fatigue, and inflammation: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Front Physiol 9: 403, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott-Sale KJ, Altini M, Doyle-Baker P, et al. Why we must stop assuming and estimating menstrual cycle phases in laboratory and field-based sport related research. Sports Med 55: 1339&#x2013;1351, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fessi MS, Nouira S, Dellal A, et al. Changes of the psychophysical state and feeling of wellness of professional soccer players during pre-season and in-season periods. Res Sports Med 24: 375&#x2013;386, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flanagan EP, Ebben WP, Jensen RL. Reliability of the reactive strength index and time to stabilization during depth jumps. J Strength Cond Res 22: 1677&#x2013;1682, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredriksson I, Larsson M. On the equivalence and differences between laser Doppler flowmetry and laser speckle contrast analysis. J Biomed Opt 21: 126018, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner CA, Webb RC. Cold-induced vasodilatation in isolated, perfused rat tail artery. Am J Physiol 251: H176&#x2013;H181, 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg EJ, Schmidt CA, Green TD, et al. Temporal association between ischemic muscle perfusion recovery and the restoration of muscle contractile function after hindlimb ischemia. Front Physiol 10: 804, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo J, Li L, Gong Y, et al. Massage alleviates delayed onset muscle soreness after strenuous exercise: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol 8: 747, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haroun D, Croker H, Viner RM, et al. Validation of BIA in obese children and adolescents and re&#x2010;evaluation in a longitudinal study. Obesity 17: 2245&#x2013;2250, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausswirth C, Le Meur Y. Physiological and nutritional aspects of post-exercise recovery: Specific recommendations for female athletes. Sports Med 41: 861&#x2013;882, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healy R, Kenny IC, Harrison AJ. Reactive strength index: A poor indicator of reactive strength? Int J Sports Physiol Perform 13: 802&#x2013;809, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotfiel T, Hoppe MW, Heiss R, et al. Quantifiable contrast-enhanced ultrasound explores the role of protection, rest, ice (cryotherapy), compression and elevation (PRICE) therapy on microvascular blood flow. Ultrasound Med Biol 47: 1269&#x2013;1278, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G, Gaze D, Van Someren KA. The efficacy of ice massage in the treatment of exercise&#x2010;induced muscle damage. Scand J Med Sci Sports 15: 416&#x2013;422, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ihsan M, Watson G, Abbiss CR. What are the physiological mechanisms for post-exercise cold water immersion in the recovery from prolonged endurance and intermittent exercise? Sports Med 46: 1095&#x2013;1109, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaleel G, Shaphe MA, Khan AR, et al. Effect of exercises on central and endocrine system for pain modulation in primary dysmenorrhea. J Lifestyle Med 12: 15&#x2013;25, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerautret Y, Di Rienzo F, Eyssautier C, Guillot A. Selective effects of manual massage and foam rolling on perceived recovery and performance: Current knowledge and future directions toward robotic massages. Front Physiol 11: 598898, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konecna L, Yan MS, Miller LE, Sch&#xf6;lmerich J, Falk W, Straub RH. Modulation of IL-6 production during the menstrual cycle in vivo and in vitro. Brain Behav Immun 14: 49&#x2013;61, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ku&#x17c;dza&#x142; A, Clemente FM, Klich S, Kawczy&#x144;ski A, Trybulski R. Combination of manual therapy and dry needling effectively improves acute neck pain and muscular tone and stiffness in combat sports athletes: A randomized controlled study. J Sports Sci Med 23: 852&#x2013;862, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lester A, Vickers GL, Macro L, et al. Exercise&#x2010;induced amplification of mitogen&#x2010;stimulated oxidative burst in whole blood is strongly influenced by neutrophil counts during and following exercise. Physiol Rep 9: e15010, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liana R, Chuda&#x144;ski M, Ponikowska I. Standarisation of laser Doppler flowmetry-own standards. Clin Diabetol 10: 58&#x2013;64, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markwick WJ, Bird SP, Tufano JJ, Seitz LB, Haff GG. The intraday reliability of the reactive strength index calculated from a drop jump in professional men's basketball. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 10: 482&#x2013;488, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: A participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 317&#x2013;331, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteiro Rodrigues L, Rocha C, Ferreira HT, Silva HN. Lower limb massage in humans increases local perfusion and impacts systemic hemodynamics. J Appl Physiol 128: 1217&#x2013;1226, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niering M, Wolf-Belala N, Seifert J, et al. The influence of menstrual cycle phases on maximal strength performance in healthy female adults: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports 12: 31, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Sakamoto K, Newton M, Sacco P. How long does the protective effect on eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage last? Med Sci Sports Exerc 33: 1490&#x2013;1495, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojeda-Aravena A, Herrera-Valenzuela T, Vald&#xe9;s-Badilla P, et al. A systematic review with meta-analysis on the effects of plyometric-jump training on the physical fitness of combat sport athletes. Sports 11: 33, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oleka CT. Use of the menstrual cycle to enhance female sports performance and decrease sports-related injury. J Pediatr Adolesc Gynecol 33: 110&#x2013;111, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oosthuyse T, Bosch A. The effect of gender and menstrual phase on serum creatine kinase activity and muscle soreness following downhill running. Antioxidants 6: 16, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park G, Kim CW, Park SB, Kim MJ, Jang SH. Reliability and usefulness of the pressure pain threshold measurement in patients with myofascial pain. Ann Rehabil Med 35: 412&#x2013;417, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts KA, van Gent T, Hopkins ND, et al. Reproducibility of four frequently used local heating protocols to assess cutaneous microvascular function. Microvasc Res 112: 65&#x2013;71, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts L. Effects of patterns of pressure application on resting electromyography during massage. Int J Therap Massage Bodywork 4: 4&#x2013;11, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues LM, Rocha C, Ferreira H, Silva H. Different lasers reveal different skin microcirculatory flowmotion&#x2014;Data from the wavelet transform analysis of human hindlimb perfusion. Sci Rep 9: 16951, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Parra N, Alfaro-Magallanes VM, Rael B, et al. Indirect markers of muscle damage throughout the menstrual cycle. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 16: 190&#x2013;198, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Parra N, Barba-Moreno L, Rael B, et al. Influence of the menstrual cycle on blood markers of muscle damage and inflammation following eccentric exercise. Int J Environ Res Public Health 17: 1618, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Parra N, Cupeiro R, Alfaro-Magallanes VM, et al. Menstrual cycle and menopause influence on creatine kinase response after exercise-induced muscle damage. Med Sci Sports Exerc 52: 187, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Parra N, Cupeiro R, Alfaro-Magallanes VM, et al. Exercise-induced muscle damage during the menstrual cycle: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 35: 549&#x2013;561, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawai A, Mitsuhashi R, Zaboronok A, Warashina Y, Mathis BJ. Serum creatine kinase increases after acute strength training in college athletes with menstrual irregularities. Women 1: 71&#x2013;79, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selim Kaplan A. Effect of sport massage on pressure pain threshold and tolerance in athletes under eccentric exercise. Int J Sci Cult Sport 2: 136, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheffield CW, Sessler DI, Hopf HW, et al. Centrally and locally mediated thermoregulatory responses alter subcutaneous oxygen tension. Wound Repair Regenerat 4: 339&#x2013;345, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stachenfeld NS, Keefe DL, Palter SF. Estrogen and progesterone effects on transcapillary fluid dynamics. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 281: R1319&#x2013;R1329, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szygu&#x142;a R, Wierzbicka M, Sondel G. Influence of 8-week aerobic training on the skin microcirculation in patients with ischaemic heart disease. J Aging Res 2020: 4602067&#x2013;4602068, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toussaint J-F, Kwong KK, M'Kparu F, et al. Interrelationship of oxidative metabolism and local perfusion demonstrated by NMR in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol 81: 2221&#x2013;2228, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trybulski R, Ku&#x17c;d&#x17c;a&#x142; A, Bichowska-Paw&#x119;ska M, et al. Immediate effect of cryo-compression therapy on biomechanical properties and perfusion of forearm muscles in mixed martial arts fighters. J Clin Med 13: 1177, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trybulski R, Ku&#x17c;d&#x17c;a&#x142; A, Stanula A, et al. Biomechanical profile after dry needling in mixed martial arts. Int J Sports Med 45: 968&#x2013;979, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trybulski R, Ku&#x17c;d&#x17c;a&#x142; A, Wilk M, et al. Reliability of MyotonPro in measuring the biomechanical properties of the quadriceps femoris muscle in people with different levels and types of motor preparation. Front Sports Act Living 6: 1453730, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trybulski R, &#x17b;ebrowska A, Bichowska-Paw&#x119;ska M, et al. The effects of combined contrast heat cold pressure therapy on post-exercise muscle recovery in MMA fighters: A randomized controlled trial. J Hum Kinet 94: 127&#x2013;146, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weerapong P, Hume PA, Kolt GS. The mechanisms of massage and effects on performance, muscle recovery and injury prevention. Sports Med 35: 235&#x2013;256, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams JS, Dunford EC, MacDonald MJ. Impact of the menstrual cycle on peripheral vascular function in premenopausal women: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 319: H1327&#x2013;H1337, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood SC, Gonzales R. Hypothermia in hypoxic animals: Mechanisms, mediators, and functional significance. Comp Biochem Physiol B Biochem Mol Biol 113: 37&#x2013;43, 1996.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>