<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41680733</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2482</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of laparoscopic manual suturing and laparoscopic stapler usage for gallbladder duodenal fistula stoma closure.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">206</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12893-026-03585-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Cholecystoduodenal fistula (CDF) is a rare complication of recurrent gallstone disease, characterized by chronic inflammation, localized ischemia, and tissue necrosis. In this study, the clinical outcomes associated with laparoscopic manual suturing and stapler-assisted closure were compared in the context of CDF repair with accompanying video presentations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Overall, 21 patients diagnosed with CDF who underwent treatment at Fujian Provincial Hospital between January 2010 and December 2024 were retrospectively analyzed. Participants were categorized into two groups: those who underwent stapler-assisted closure (stapler group, <i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;12) and those who underwent manual suturing (manual suture group, <i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;9). Intraoperative parameters, postoperative recovery markers, and complication rates were compared between groups. Statistical data were evaluated using SPSS version 26.0 (SPSS Inc., IL, USA) and <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 was considered as significant in all analyses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The patient characteristics and preoperative factors were similar in two groups (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). The stapler group had a significantly shorter operative time in comparison with the manual suture group (72.5&#xa0;min vs. 115.0&#xa0;min, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) and four patients (44.4%) in the manual suture group required conversion to open surgery (p:0.021). Subtotal cholecystectomy was performed in 5 patients (41.7%) in stapler group, and 3 patients (33.3%) in manual suture group. The sizes of the cholecystoduodenal fistulas were almost same between two groups (0.8&#xa0;cm vs. 0.7&#xa0;cm). Postoperative complications were mostly seen in manual suture group; 3 patients (33.3%) had duodenal fistula and 2 patients (22.2%) required reoperation. Postoperative recovery occurred more rapidly in the stapler group, with a shorter period to start to oral intake, for removal of nasogastric and drainage tubes; and a shorter duration of hospitalization time (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Laparoscopic stapler-assisted repair of CDF using the preserved gallbladder wall offers significant advantages over traditional manual suturing. It decreases the operative duration, lowers conversion rates, and reduces the odds of postoperative complications. Given these benefits, this technique is recommended for broader clinical adoption. However, in cases where the stapler use is inappropriate due to the technical issues; manual suturing can be the preferable method in selected cases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12893-026-03585-w.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Long</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shengli Clinical Medical College of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Medical University, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatobiliary Pancreatic Surgery, Fujian Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou University Affliated Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Jianlin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shengli Clinical Medical College of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Medical University, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatobiliary Pancreatic Surgery, Fujian Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou University Affliated Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Dihang</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shengli Clinical Medical College of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Medical University, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatobiliary Pancreatic Surgery, Fujian Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou University Affliated Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhan</LastName><ForeName>Xu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shengli Clinical Medical College of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Medical University, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatobiliary Pancreatic Surgery, Fujian Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou University Affliated Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou, 350001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Yifeng</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shengli Clinical Medical College of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Medical University, Fuzhou, 350001, China. tianyifeng@fjmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatobiliary Pancreatic Surgery, Fujian Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou University Affliated Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou, 350001, China. tianyifeng@fjmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Shi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shengli Clinical Medical College of Fujian Medical University, Fujian Medical University, Fuzhou, 350001, China. wawljwalj@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatobiliary Pancreatic Surgery, Fujian Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou University Affliated Provincial Hospital, Fuzhou, 350001, China. wawljwalj@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No.2021(60)</GrantID><Agency>Fujian Research and Training Grants for Young and Middle-aged Leaders in Healthcare</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968567</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2482</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cholecystoduodenal fistula</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cholecystolitiaisis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic cholecystitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gallbladder wall repair</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Laparoscopic approach</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Manual suturing technique</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stapler technique</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Ethics Committee of the Fujian Provincial Hospital (K2025-09-011) and study was conducted under the guidance of the Declaration of Helsinki. All participants signed a written informed consent form. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41680733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13005490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12893-026-03585-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12893-026-03585-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Turner A R, Kudaravalli P, Al-musawi J H et al. Bouveret syndrome (Bilioduodenal Fistula) [M]. StatPearls. Treasure Island (FL) ineligible companies. Disclosure: Pujitha Kudaravalli declares no relevant financial relationships with ineligible companies. Disclosure: Jasim Al-Musawi declares no relevant financial relationships with ineligible companies. Disclosure: Hira Ahmad declares no relevant financial relationships with ineligible companies.; StatPearls Publishing Copyright &#xa9; 2025, StatPearls Publishing LLC. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tantia O, Bandyopadhyay S K Senb, et al. Pericholecystic fistula: a study of 64 cases. Int Surg. 2002;87(2):90&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12222924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Urquijo M, Rodarte-Shade M, Lozano-Balderas G, et al. Cholecystoenteric fistula with and without gallstone ileus: A case series. Volume 19. Hepatobiliary &amp; pancreatic diseases international: HBPD INT; 2020. pp. 36&#x2013;40. 1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31919039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ignjatovic NS, Golubovic I D, Djordjevic M N, Bouveret&#x2019;s Syndrome as a Rare Life-Threatening Complication of Gallstone Disease-A Surgical Problem: Two Case Reports., Medicina et al. (Kaunas, Lithuania), 2024, 61(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11767053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39858987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker M A, Kragh N, Sandoval J, et al. Surgical management of gallstone ileus: Approach, Outcome, case Report, and literature review. Cureus. 2024;16(9):e69930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11495830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39439607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen D, Zhai Y. Li M. Bouveret syndrome treated with endoscopic lithotripsy and gallbladder access via Cholecysto-duodenal fistula. Clinical gastroenterology and hepatology: the official clinical practice journal of. the American Gastroenterological Association; 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39742985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thatipalli N, Gattani R, Nayak K, et al. Bouveret syndrome: Etiology, clinical Presentation, differential Diagnosis, Complications, and treatment options. Cureus. 2024;16(7):e64754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11329337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39156444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos G P, Chiang N E. Bouveret&#x2019;s syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(14):1335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMicm1711592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29617586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg J, Wiggins T, Sahloul M. Bouveret syndrome managed conservatively with the insertion of a double Pigtail stent between the stomach and the gallbladder. BMJ Case Rep, 2024, 17(12).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39675789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez De la Cruz J. Upper Gastrointestinal bleeding secondary to Choledochoduodenal fistula as a presentation of gallbladder adenocarcinoma. Revista espanola de enfermedades digestivas; 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39297603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C Y, Chiu S H, Chang W C, et al. Cholecystoenteric fistula in a patient with advanced gallbladder cancer: A case report and review of literature. World J Clin Cases. 2023;11(36):8519&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12998/wjcc.v11.i36.8519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10768506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38188217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanada T, Baba H, Ohba A, et al. [Gallbladder carcinoma, progressed along cholecystoduodenal fistula&#x2013;a case report]. Gan Kagaku Ryoho Cancer Chemother. 2010;37(12):2717&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21224690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stamou K M, Kekis P B Glynatsism. Gallbladder-duodenal fistula presenting with liver abscess and upper Gastrointestinal bleeding. HPB: Official J Int Hepato Pancreato Biliary Association. 2006;8(1):69&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13651820600574202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2131362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18333244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roa JC, Garc&#xed;a P. Gallbladder cancer [J]. Nat Reviews Disease Primers. 2022;8(1):69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41572-022-00398-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12314663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36302789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walia D J S, Singla A, Singh S, et al. A rare case of cholecystoduodenal and cholecystocolic fistula with gallstone ileus. Int J Appl Basic Med Res. 2023;13(2):121&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijabmr.ijabmr_598_22</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10443450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37614840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S F, Han Y H, Chen J et al. Surgical Management of Cholecystoenteric Fistula in Patients With and Without Gallstone Ileus: An Experience of 29 Cases. Frontiers in surgery, 2022, 9(950292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9304664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35874133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourgouin S, Lamblin G, Rose P, et al. Minimally invasive management of gallstone ileus with cholecystoduodenal fistula. ANZ J Surg. 2018;88(10):1081&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ans.13748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27599371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh B K P, Low T Y, Teo J Y, et al. Initial single institution experience with robotic biliary surgery and bilio-enteric anastomosis in Southeast Asia. ANZ J Surg. 2019;89(4):E142&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ans.15135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30887681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuexun S, Peizhong S, Wei Z. Clinical experience of laparoscopic cholecystoduodenal fistula closure using the gallbladder wall as a cover. J Laparosc Surg. 2023;28(12):906&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfonso A, McFarland K N, Savsani K, et al. Robotic management of primary cholecystoduodenal fistula: A case report and brief literature review. Int J Med Rob + Comput Assist Surgery: MRCAS. 2024;20(2):e2629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rcs.2629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38643388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furusawa N, Kobayashi A, Yokoyama T, et al. Surgical treatment of 144 cases of hilar cholangiocarcinoma without liver-related mortality. World J Surg. 2014;38(5):1164&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00268-013-2394-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24305942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C K, Ramcharan D N, Alaimo K L, et al. Cholecystoduodenal fistula evading imaging and endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography: A case report. Cureus. 2021;13(11):e20049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8717936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34987929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramrakhiani H, Simpson N, Strichartz SD, et al. Like a rolling gallstone: cholecystoduodenal fistula as evidence of gallstone ileus. Dig Dis Sci. 2020;65(9):2518&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10620-020-06088-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31989397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alnagar A, Elkomy H, Foula M, et al. Laparoscopic management of cholecysto-duodenal fistula after spontaneous resolution of intestinal obstruction component of gallstone ileus case report and literature review. Rozhledy V Chirurgii: Mesicnik Ceskoslovenske Chirurgicke Spolecnosti. 2022;101(1):42&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35148616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meena R, Srivastava V. Roy S, et al. Incidental cholecystojejunal fistula: a rare complication of gall stone disease. MOJ Surgery; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon O, Paik K Y. Laparoscopic adrenalectomy performed with the Endo GIA&#x2122; stapler as an easy and safe approach. Minerva Surg. 2025;80(1):15&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39356217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Q X, Yang F Y, Chen D, et al. [Application of Endo-GIA stapler in laparoscopic radicalcystectomy]. Zhonghua Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2020;100(24):1872&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32575930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raftopoulos Y, Rajkumar S. Prospective randomized comparison of linear endostaplers during laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy. Obes Surg. 2022;32(10):3472&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11695-022-06240-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35974292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toro A, Teodoro M, Khan M, et al. Subtotal cholecystectomy for difficult acute cholecystitis: how to finalize safely by laparoscopy-a systematic review. World J Emerg Surgery: WJES. 2021;16(1):45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13017-021-00392-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8424983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34496916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo SS, Krishnan R J, Ishikawa K et al. Subtotal vs total cholecystectomy for difficult gallbladders: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Surg, 2024, 229(145&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11529787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38168604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisano M, Allievi N, Gurusamy K, et al. 2020 world society of emergency surgery updated guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute calculus cholecystitis. World J Emerg Surgery: WJES. 2020;15(1):61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13017-020-00336-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7643471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33153472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tay W M, Toh Y J Shelatvg, et al. Subtotal cholecystectomy: early and long-term outcomes. Surg Endosc. 2020;34(10):4536&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-019-07242-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31701285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiawei J, Yang S, Jun H, et al. Clinical analysis of diagnosis and treatment in 21 cases of cholelithiasis complicated by cholecystoenteric fistula. Chin J Gen Surg. 2024;33(8):1251&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W K, Yeh C N. Jan Y Y. Successful laparoscopic management for cholecystoenteric fistula. World J Gastroenterol. 2006;12(5):772&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v12.i5.772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4066130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16521193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odabasi M, Muftuoglu M A Ozkane, et al. Use of stapling devices for safe cholecystectomy in acute cholecystitis. Int Surg. 2014;99(5):571&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9738/INTSURG-D-14-00035.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4253926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25216423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alyami R, Alotaibi A E, Alhoumaily B, et al. Safety and efficacy of using stapler device for wide cystic duct ligation in acute setting of laparoscopic cholecystectomy. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):25062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-75398-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11499593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39443523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X Y, Zhao X. Laparoscopic management of cholecystoenteric fistula: A single-center experience. J Int Med Res. 2017;45(3):1090&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0300060517699038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5536399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28417651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soto D J, Evan S J, Kavic M S. Laparoscopic management of gallstone ileus. JSLS: J Soc Laparoendoscopic Surg. 2001;5(3):279&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3015453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11548836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin E T, Kaye K S, Knott C, et al. Diabetes and risk of surgical site infection: A systematic review and Meta-analysis. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol. 2016;37(1):88&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/ice.2015.249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4914132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26503187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu P, He W, Chen HL. Diabetes mellitus as a risk factor for surgery-related pressure ulcers: a meta-analysis. Journal of wound, ostomy, and continence nursing: official publication of the wound. Ostomy Cont Nurses Soc. 2012;39(5):495&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WON.0b013e318265222a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22864191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romagnani P, Remuzzi G, Glassock R, et al. Chronic kidney disease. Nat Reviews Disease Primers. 2017;3:17088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrdp.2017.88</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29168475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KDIGO. 2022 Clinical Practice Guideline for Diabetes Management in Chronic Kidney Disease. Kidney international, 2022, 102(5s): S1-s127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36272764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>