<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41719203</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1421-9786</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cerebrovascular diseases (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cerebrovasc Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of Socioeconomic Status on Recovery in Hemorrhagic Stroke Patients: International Implications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>16</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-16</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1159/000551033</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Hemorrhagic stroke (HS), including intracerebral and subarachnoid hemorrhages, is a devastating neurological condition with high rates of mortality and long-term disability. Socioeconomic status (SES) has been identified as a critical determinant of outcomes, influencing not only the incidence of HS, but also survival, recovery trajectories, and quality of life. Lower SES is consistently linked to delays in presentation, limited access to specialized stroke units, reduced utilization of rehabilitation services, and greater barriers to long-term care, all of which compounded the risk of poor outcomes. Although global trends show improvements in stroke survival, the burden of HS and its consequences remain disproportionately concentrated in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This review evaluates current evidence regarding the influence of SES on HS recovery from both national and international perspectives. Within high-income countries (HICs), inequities persist despite advanced health systems, as uninsured or socioeconomically disadvantaged patients remain less likely to receive inpatient rehabilitation or benefit from new interventions. In LMICs, where over 80% of HS cases and nearly two-thirds of HS-related deaths occur, disparities are magnified by systemic limitations, including shortage of neurologists and neurosurgeons, lack of neurocritical care infrastructure, and prohibitive out-of-pocket costs. Rehabilitation is particularly underdeveloped in these regions, leaving many survivors with preventable disability. Innovative strategies such as telestroke networks, mobile stroke units, and digital or AI-driven rehabilitation platforms have begun to demonstrate the feasibility of bridging these gaps, particularly in Brazil, India, and certain parts of sub-Saharan Africa. Lessons from countries with universal healthcare systems have highlighted the importance of structured stroke services and coordinated rehabilitation. However, these models require targeted efforts to address the persistent impact of social determinants.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="KEY MESSAGES" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">SES has a profound impact on HS outcomes worldwide. Equitable recovery will require not only advances in acute interventions and rehabilitation, but also policies and community-based approaches that reduce barriers to care, enhance patient and caregiver education, and prioritize access to services across socioeconomic strata and global health systems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>S. Karger AG, Basel.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kunz</LastName><ForeName>Eric M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ciesla</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Foster</LastName><ForeName>Devon T</ForeName><Initials>DT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kioutchoukova</LastName><ForeName>Ivelina P</ForeName><Initials>IP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manhard</LastName><ForeName>Claire E</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gilham</LastName><ForeName>Wiley</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lucke-Wold</LastName><ForeName>Brandon</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Cerebrovasc Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9100851</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1015-9770</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41719203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000551033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">000551033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>