<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41736010</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2458</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long-term trends of influenza-like illness and severe acute respiratory infection across pandemic phases: an interrupted time-series study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1062</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12889-026-26616-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Influenza-like illness (ILI) and severe acute respiratory infection (SARI) remain significant public health burdens, particularly among older adults and in resource-limited settings. However, long-term epidemiologic trends across different pandemic phases remain poorly understood, especially for vulnerable populations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Surveillance and hospital records collected between 2017 and 2024 from two sentinel hospitals in Shanghai, China, were analyzed. Interrupted time-series (ITS) models were used to evaluate temporal changes in ILI and SARI incidence. Large-scale data processing techniques were applied to extract structured information from unstructured medical records, enabling comprehensive analysis of clinical characteristics and outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Both ILI and SARI cases declined sharply during the COVID-19 pandemic but rebounded thereafter. Older adults (&#x2265;60 years) experienced disproportionately greater increases in these cases, along with higher risks of ILI-to-SARI progression and ICU admission. Although clinical recovery rates improved in the post-pandemic period, the demand for oxygen therapy and hospital-based care remained elevated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">These findings highlight the long-term impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on respiratory infection dynamics and underscore the need for targeted interventions for older adults. Despite highest susceptibility and baseline risk for severe illness, older adults demonstrated improved post-pandemic clinical outcomes due to enhanced clinical prioritization. Strengthening vaccination programs, improving health education, and enhancing resource preparedness are crucial to reduce the post-pandemic disease burden, particularly in settings with limited healthcare capacity. These findings provide important evidence to strengthen post-pandemic respiratory surveillance and improve protection strategies for older adults in China.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12889-026-26616-w.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Infectious Disease and Biosecurity, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhongshan Hospital, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhongshan Hospital Wusong Branch, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Ning</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhongshan Hospital Wusong Branch, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Huimin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhongshan Hospital Wusong Branch, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Fangyi</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Nanchang University, Nanchang, Jiangxi Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qiao</LastName><ForeName>Wanyu</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Ye</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Infectious Disease and Biosecurity, Fudan University, Shanghai, China. yyao@fudan.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Weibing</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Infectious Disease and Biosecurity, Fudan University, Shanghai, China. wwb@fudan.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968562</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2458</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Influenza-like Illness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Severe Acute Respiratory Infection</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This retrospective real-world data analysis was approved by the Clinical Trials Ethics Committee of Wu Song Central Hospital, Baoshan District, Shanghai (Approval No. Ethical Review [2024] No. 18). Given the retrospective nature of the study and the use of de-identified electronic medical record (EMR) data (no personal identifiers such as names, ID numbers, or contact information), the above-mentioned ethics committee waived the requirement for individual informed consent, in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41736010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13037121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-026-26616-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12889-026-26616-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Huang QS, Wood T, Jelley L, Jennings T, Jefferies S, Daniells K, et al. Impact of the COVID-19 nonpharmaceutical interventions on influenza and other respiratory viral infections in New Zealand. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):1001. 10.1038/s41467-021-21157-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-21157-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7881137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33579926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CC, Shih TP, Ko WC, Tang HJ, Hsueh PR. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) and coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19): the epidemic and the challenges. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2020;55(3):105924. 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2020.105924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2020.105924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7127800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32081636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellizzi S, Panu Napodano CM, Pinto S, Pichierri G. COVID-19 and seasonal influenza: the potential 2021-22 &#x201c;twindemic.&#x201d; Vaccine. 2022;40(24):3286&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.vaccine.2022.04.074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2022.04.074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9069306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35527058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fricke LM, Gl&#xf6;ckner S, Dreier M, Lange B. Impact of nonpharmaceutical interventions targeted at the COVID-19 pandemic on influenza burden&#x2013;a systematic review. J Infect. 2021;82(1):1&#x2013;35. 10.1016/j.jinf.2020.11.039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2020.11.039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9183207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33278399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi Y, Shaman J, Pei S. Quantifying the impact of COVID-19 nonpharmaceutical interventions on influenza transmission in the United States. J Infect Dis. 2021;224(9):1500&#x2013;8. 10.1093/infdis/jiab485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiab485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8522386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34551108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doroshenko A, Lee N, MacDonald C, Zelyas N, Asadi L, Kanji JN. Decline of influenza and respiratory virus infections with COVID-19 public health measures: Alberta, Canada. Mayo Clin Proc. 2021;96(12):3042&#x2013;52. 10.1016/j.mayocp.2021.09.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mayocp.2021.09.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34863395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu P, Xu M, Cao L, Su L, Lu L, Dong N, et al. Impact of COVID-19 pandemic on the prevalence of respiratory viruses in children with lower respiratory tract infections in China. Virol J. 2021;18(1):159. 10.1186/s12985-021-01627-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12985-021-01627-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8329611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34344406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li ZJ, Yu LJ, Zhang HY, Shan CX, Lu QB, Zhang XA, et al. Broad impacts of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic on acute respiratory infections in China: an observational study. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;75(1):e1054&#x2013;62. 10.1093/cid/ciab942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8767888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34788811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potdar V, Gharpure R, Mamuti S, Munyua P, Njenga MK, Makayotto L, et al. Early warning and response systems for respiratory disease outbreaks: lessons learnt from cluster-associated cases of acute respiratory illnesses in Gilgil subcounty, Nakuru County, Kenya, 2021. BMJ Glob Health. 2025;10(2):e016418. 10.1136/bmjgh-2024-016418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2024-016418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11865744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40010777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu SS, Cowling BJ, Peiris JSM, Chan ELY, Wong WHS, Lee KP. Effects of nonpharmaceutical COVID-19 interventions on pediatric hospitalizations for other respiratory virus infections, Hong Kong. Emerg Infect Dis. 2022;28(1):62&#x2013;8. 10.3201/eid2801.211099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid2801.211099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8714236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34932446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen-Tran HT, Messacar K; PREMISE Study Group. Dynamics of endemic virus re-emergence in children in the USA following the COVID-19 pandemic (2022&#x2013;23): a prospective, multicentre, longitudinal, immunoepidemiological surveillance study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2025. 10.1016/S1473-3099(25)00349-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12458095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40782819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng L, Zang F, Song N, Li Z. Analysis of influenza trend and impact of COVID-19 in Kezhou, Xinjiang for 8 consecutive years. J Med Virol. 2022;94(7):3081&#x2013;6. 10.1002/jmv.27678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.27678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9088564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35218043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Peng Y, Chen Z, Jiang F, Ni F, Tang Z, et al. Impact of non-pharmaceutical interventions during COVID-19 on future influenza trends in mainland China. BMC Infect Dis. 2023;23(1):632. 10.1186/s12879-023-08594-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-023-08594-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10523625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37759271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauro MV, Greco S, Pellegrini M, Campagna T, Caprino F, Elia N, et al. Epidemiology and clinical impact of single and multi-viral respiratory infections in post-pandemic era. New Microbiol. 2024;47(1):28&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38700880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han JS, Jang SH, Jeon JS, Kim JK. Long-term trends in respiratory syncytial virus A infections (2007&#x2013;2024) in Korea. Diseases. 2025;13(5):147. 10.3390/diseases13050147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diseases13050147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12110253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40422579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanghai Municipal Health Bureau. Shanghai Influenza Surveillance Program (2011 Edition) [Report]. Hu Wei Ji Fu [2011] No. 054. 2011 September 5. https://wsjkw.sh.gov.cn/xxgk/xxgkml/ywgz/ylqx/jszl/201109/t20110905_123456.shtml.&#xa0;Accessed 1 Mar 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochrane D, Orcutt GH. Application of least squares regression to relationships containing auto-correlated error terms. J Am Stat Assoc. 1949;44:32&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngere P, Gharpure R, Mamuti S, Munyua P, Njenga MK, Makayotto L, et al. Early warning and response systems for respiratory disease outbreaks: lessons learnt from cluster-associated cases of acute respiratory illnesses in Gilgil subcounty, Nakuru County, Kenya, 2021. BMJ Glob Health. 2025;10(2):e016418. 10.1136/bmjgh-2024-016418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2024-016418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11865744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40010777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Zhang T, Miao Y, Li X, Li Y. Management cost of acute respiratory infections in older adults in China: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Glob Health. 2024;14:04165. 10.7189/jogh.14.04165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7189/jogh.14.04165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11466502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39388681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emborg HD, Valentiner-Branth P, Trebbien R, Bolt Botnen A, Grove Krause T, S&#xf8;borg B. Enhanced influenza vaccines impact effectiveness in individuals aged 65 years and older, Denmark, 2024/25 influenza season up to 4 March 2025. Euro Surveill. 2025;30(12):2500174. 10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2025.30.12.2500174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2025.30.12.2500174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11951413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40156348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>chM&#x2019;nemosyme N, Frumence E, Souply L, Heaugwane D, Traversier N, Mercier A, et al. Shifts in respiratory virus epidemiology on Reunion Island from 2017 to 2023: impact of COVID-19 pandemic and nonpharmaceutical interventions. Influenza Other Respir Viruses. 2025;19(3):e70075. 10.1111/irv.70075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/irv.70075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11880683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40040473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>