<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41828117</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Synergistic Enhancement of Electrochemical-Oxidative Chlorine-Free Bromine Extraction from Oil and Gas Field Water by Zero-Gap Electrolyzer and Carbon Cloth Electrode: A Study on Efficient, Selective Extraction and Resistance to Other Ions.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">850</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma19050850</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Bromine, as a strategic fundamental chemical raw material, is crucial for modern industry, but the traditional chlorine displacement method poses safety risks in oilfield brine development and faces challenges like resource depletion and inefficient utilization. Addressing the need for high-concentration bromine brine development in underground oilfields, this study developed an electrochemical oxidation-based chlorine-free bromine extraction technology. Leveraging the standard redox potential difference between Br<sup>-</sup> and Cl<sup>-</sup> (0.271 V), the effective potential window for selective Br<sup>-</sup> oxidation was determined as 1.0-1.52 V (vs. SHE) via linear sweep voltammetry (LSV). Within this window, efficient and preferential oxidation of Br<sup>-</sup> over Cl<sup>-</sup> and OH<sup>-</sup> was achieved. In simulated brine with high chloride and low bromide concentrations, a Br<sup>-</sup> conversion rate of 92.3% was attained with no Cl<sub>2</sub> generation. The self-designed zero-gap electrolyzer with carbon cloth as the anode reduced the reaction time by over 75% compared to a traditional H-type cell, oxidizing over 90% of Br<sup>-</sup> within 12 min. Kinetic studies revealed that the reaction follows first-order kinetics, with current intensity positively correlated with Br<sup>-</sup> concentration. Investigation of coexisting ions revealed that low concentrations of Cl<sup>-</sup> promote the reaction, while high concentrations exert inhibitory effects. CO<sub>3</sub><sup>2-</sup> exhibits a weak promoting effect, and Ca<sup>2+</sup>/Mg<sup>2+</sup> show negligible impact. Notably, organic matter (e.g., ethylene glycol) concentrations exceeding 80 mg/L substantially compromise bromine recovery efficiency. This technology provides a feasible solution for the safe and green development of high-concentration bromine resources and holds significant importance for the upgrading of the bromine chemical industry.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Shiyong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Key Laboratory of Mineral Resources Processing and Environment, Key Laboratory of Green Utilization of Critical Non-Metallic Mineral Resources, Ministry of Education, Wuhan University of Technology, 122 Luoshi Road, Wuhan 430070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ji</LastName><ForeName>Rong</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Metallurgy and Environment, Central South University, Changsha 410083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9919-9990</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Key Laboratory of Mineral Resources Processing and Environment, Key Laboratory of Green Utilization of Critical Non-Metallic Mineral Resources, Ministry of Education, Wuhan University of Technology, 122 Luoshi Road, Wuhan 430070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023DJC35</GrantID><Agency>Hubei Province Science and Technology Innovation Talent Plan</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carbon cloth electrode</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electrooxidative bromine extraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oil and gas field water</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">selective oxidation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">zero-gap electrolyzer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41828117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12985701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma19050850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma19050850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wu J., Mu P., Zhang X., Jiang G., Tan Z., Pan D. Efficient conversion process and mechanism of bromine in bromine-rich saline wastewater. J. Clean. Prod. 2024;470:143322. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.143322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.143322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choden Y., Askari M., Kabir M.M., Choo Y., Sabur G.M., Mamun M.F.K., Choi J.S., Woo Y.C., Kim Y., Hong S., et al. Recovery of bromide for bromine extraction: A review of technologies and circular economy implications. Desalination. 2025;613:118968. doi: 10.1016/j.desal.2025.118968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.desal.2025.118968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Zhen X., Liu L., Li Y., Zhen X., Liu L., Zhang J., Tang J. Species-specific and habitat-dependent bioaccumulation of halogenated flame retardants in marine organisms from estuary to coastal seas. J. Hazard. Mater. 2024;472:134529. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.134529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.134529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38723482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Luo Q., Gao F., Luo X., Ma Y., Huang X., Wang X. Confined-structured bismuth oxybromide&#x2013;based polyaniline composite film electrodes for highly efficient and selective bromine ion extraction from oilfield brine. Desalination. 2025;613:118966. doi: 10.1016/j.desal.2025.118966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.desal.2025.118966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Wang H., Zheng J., Liu Y., Zhu S., Yin J., Peng X., Sun G., Cui Y. A novel crosslinked chitosan material modified by quaternary ammonium group for efficient adsorption of bromide ions from wastewater. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2025;307:141926. doi: 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.141926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.141926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40068759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Song X., Ling L., Wang Z., Hao X., Guan G. Terminal-dependent ion recognition of BiOBr/PPy hybrid film with befitting absorption function for rapidly selective bromine ions removal. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;457:141213. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2022.141213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2022.141213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yal&#xe7;in H., Ko&#xe7; T., Pamuk V. Hydrogen and bromine production from concentrated sea-water. Int. J. Hydrog. Energy. 1997;22:967&#x2013;970. doi: 10.1016/S0360-3199(96)00214-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0360-3199(96)00214-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Zhang X., Li Y., Li W., Hang C., Sharma V.K. Phototransformation of halophenolic disinfection byproducts in receiving seawater: Kinetics, products, and toxicity. Water Res. 2019;150:68&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2018.11.059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2018.11.059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6390291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30508715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Zhan L., Xu Z. Debromination with bromine recovery from pyrolysis of waste printed circuit boards offers economic and environmental benefits. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2023;57:3496&#x2013;3504. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.2c06448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.2c06448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36794988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vachtman D., Laronne J.B. Remotely sensed estimation of water discharge into the rapidly dwindling Dead Sea. Hydrol. Sci. J. 2014;59:1593&#x2013;1605. doi: 10.1080/02626667.2013.852278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02626667.2013.852278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Zhan L., Xu Z. Enhancing debromination efficiency through introducing water vapor atmosphere to overcome limitations of conventional pyrolysis. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2023;57:20941&#x2013;20950. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.3c06640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.3c06640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38032848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allard S., Fouche L., Dick J., Heitz A., von Gunten U. Oxidation of manganese (II) during chlorination: Role of bromide. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2013;47:8716&#x2013;8723. doi: 10.1021/es401304r.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/es401304r</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23859083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin B., Lin M., Chen X., Xu Z., Fu Y., Hu J., Ruan J. A novel approach for determining the accurate debromination time in the ball-milling process of nonmetallic particles from waste printed circuit boards by computation. J. Hazard. Mater. 2021;410:124611. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2020.124611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2020.124611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33246811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C., Zhang Y., Xing X., Zhang T., Siyal A.A., Liu Y., Dai J., Qu J., Liu C., Yao B., et al. Comparative study of continuous and batch microwave-assisted pyrolysis of waste printed circuit boards: Product characteristic, bromine transformation, and energy efficiency assessment. J. Clean. Prod. 2023;421:138546. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.138546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.138546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun M., Lowry G.V., Gregory K.B. Selective oxidation of bromide in wastewater brines from hydraulic fracturing. Water Res. 2013;47:3723&#x2013;3731. doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2013.04.041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2013.04.041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23726709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S., Cheng G., Xiong Y., Ding Y., Luo X. Adsorption of low concentrations of bromide ions from water by cellulose-based beads modified with TEMPO-mediated oxidation and Fe (III) complexation. J. Hazard. Mater. 2020;384:121195. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2019.121195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2019.121195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31585281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo J.W., Lee J., Nam S.H., Kye H., Kim E., Kim H., Lee Y., Hwang T.M. Evaluation of the prediction of micropollutant elimination during bromide ion-containing industrial wastewater ozonation using the ROH, O3 value. Chemosphere. 2023;338:139450. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2023.139450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2023.139450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37451645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun M., Li X., Li Y., Bi J., Zhao Y., Ji Z.Y. Direct Conversion of Bromine-Rich Fluid into High-Value Calcium Bromide via Continuous Electrodialysis Metathesis. ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2025;13:596&#x2013;610. doi: 10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c08816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c08816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y., Tao L., Chi Y., Yan J. Conversion of bromine during thermal decomposition of printed circuit boards at high temperature. J. Hazard. Mater. 2011;186:707&#x2013;712. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2010.11.050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2010.11.050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21145653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shtangeeva I., Niemel&#xe4; M., Per&#xe4;m&#xe4;ki P., Ryumin A., Timofeev S., Chukov S., Kasatkina G. Phytoextration of bromine from contaminated soil. J. Geochem. Explor. 2017;174:21&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1016/j.gexplo.2016.03.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gexplo.2016.03.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Qian T., Yan C., He X., Xu Z., Li W., Xin Z., Zhang H., Qian X., Zai J. Efficient electrochemical bromine extraction from low-concentration brine via a flow electrolyzer. Chin. Chem. Lett. 2025:111439. doi: 10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cclet.2025.111439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Ham M.P.J.M., Creus J., Bitter J.H., Koper M.T.M., Pescarmona P.P. Electrochemical and non-electrochemical pathways in the electrocatalytic oxidation of monosaccharides and related sugar alcohols into valuable products. Chem. Rev. 2024;124:11915&#x2013;11961. doi: 10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11565578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39480753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T., Wang Y., Wu Y., Jiang W., Deng Y., Li Q., Lan C., Zhao Z., Zhu L., Yang D., et al. Continuous decoupled redox electrochemical CO2 capture. Nat. Commun. 2024;15:10920. doi: 10.1038/s41467-024-55334-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-55334-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11686173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39738075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavrikis S., G&#xf6;ltz M., Perry S.C., Bogdan F., Leung P.K., Rosiwal S., Wang L., Ponce de Le&#xf3;n C. Effective hydrogen peroxide production from electrochemical water oxidation. ACS Energy Lett. 2021;6:2369&#x2013;2377. doi: 10.1021/acsenergylett.1c00904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.1c00904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu B., Wang L., Li Z., Liang H., Zhao K., Guo Y., Deng T. Innovative electrooxidation-adsorption technology for efficient iodine recovery from ultrahigh Cl/I ratio underground brine. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;512:162356. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.162356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.162356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen I., Shapira B., Avraham E., Soffer A., Aurbach D. Bromide ions specific removal and recovery by electrochemical desalination. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2018;52:6275&#x2013;6281. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.8b00282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.8b00282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29749732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Ji Z.Y., Liu F., Zhao Y.Y., Liu J., Wang S.Z., Li F., Guo X.F., Wang J., Yuan J.S. Investigation of electrochemical oxidation technology for selective bromine extraction in comprehensive utilization of concentrated seawater. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2020;248:117108. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2020.117108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2020.117108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Li C., Ji J.Y., Niu Z., Gu H., Abrahams B.F., Lang J.P. Tailorable carbon cloth electrodes covered with heterostructured Co/CoO/CoN interfaces for scalable electrocatalytic overall water splitting. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;461:141937. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2023.141937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.141937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuqin S., Yi W., Peikang S. Thermodynamic and kinetic considerations for ethanol electrooxidation in direct ethanol fuel cells. Chin. J. Catal. 2007;28:752&#x2013;754. doi: 10.1016/s1872-2067(07)60063-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1872-2067(07)60063-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng B., Yu G., Zhao W., Long Y., Yang C., Du P., He X., Zhang Z., Huang K., Li X., et al. A self-circulating pathway for the oxygen evolution reaction. Energy Environ. Sci. 2023;16:5210&#x2013;5219. doi: 10.1039/D3EE02360E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3EE02360E</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones T.E., Teschner D., Piccinin S. Toward realistic models of the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction. Chem. Rev. 2024;124:9136&#x2013;9223. doi: 10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39038270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H.S., Shin H., Park S., Kim J., Jung E., Hwang W., Lee B.H., Yoo J.M., Hooch Antink W., Lee K., et al. Electrochemically generated electrophilic peroxo species accelerates alkaline oxygen evolution reaction. Joule. 2023;7:1902&#x2013;1919. doi: 10.1016/j.joule.2023.06.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2023.06.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian Q., Zhu Y., Ahmad N., Feng Y., Zhang H., Cheng M., Liu H., Xiao C., Zhang G., Xie Y. Recent advancements in electrochemical hydrogen production via hybrid water splitting. Adv. Mater. 2024;36:2306108. doi: 10.1002/adma.202306108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202306108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37815215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao L., Li J., Battaglia F., He Z. Investigation of multiphysics in tubular microbial fuel cells by coupled computational fluid dynamics with multi-order Butler&#x2013;Volmer reactions. Chem. Eng. J. 2016;296:377&#x2013;385. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2016.03.110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2016.03.110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Algurainy Y., Call D.F. Asymmetrical removal of sodium and chloride in flow-through capacitive deionization. Water Res. 2020;183:116044. doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2020.116044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2020.116044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32721704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y., Chen D., Liu H., Zhang X., Chen X., Jin H. Membrane deposition electrodialysis for cooling water treatment: Ion step removal and stable membrane regeneration. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;451:138908. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2022.138908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2022.138908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiang L., Vaddiraju S., Rusling J.F., Papadimitrakopoulos F. Highly sensitive and reusable Pt-black microfluidic electrodes for long-term electrochemical sensing. Biosens. Bioelectron. 2010;26:682&#x2013;688. doi: 10.1016/j.bios.2010.06.064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bios.2010.06.064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2995378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20655730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleh L., Remot M., Remaury Q.B., Pardon P., Labadi P., Budzinski H., Coutanceau C., Crou&#xe9; J.P. PFAS degradation by anodic electrooxidation: Influence of BDD electrode configuration and presence of dissolved organic matter. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;489:151355. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.151355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.151355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>