<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41776510</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2482</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Beyond traditional setons: multicenter outcomes of a hybrid approach for high transsphincteric fistulas.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12893-026-03616-6</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yildirak</LastName><ForeName>Muhammed Kadir</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, University of Health Sciences, Umraniye Training and Research Hospital, Istanbul, Turkey. kadiryildira@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, Tekirdag City Hospital, Tekirda&#x11f;, Turkey. kadiryildira@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kirkan</LastName><ForeName>Emre Furkan</ForeName><Initials>EF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, University of Health Sciences, Umraniye Training and Research Hospital, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, Yalova University, Yalova Training and Research Hospital, Yalova, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968567</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2482</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Complex Anal Fistula</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enhanced Recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fecal&#xa0;Incontinence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High Transsphincteric Fistula</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hybrid Seton Technique</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Tekirdag Namik Kemal University Non-Interventional Clinical Research Ethics Committee. The study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Due to the retrospective nature of the study and the use of anonymized clinical data, the requirement for informed consent to participate was waived by the ethics committee. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41776510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12893-026-03616-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12893-026-03616-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Awad PBA, Hassan BHA, Awad KBA, et al. A comparative study between high ligation of the inter-sphincteric fistula tract via lateral Approach Versus Fistulotomy and primary sphincteroplasty in High Trans-Sphincteric Fistula-in-Ano: a randomized clinical trial. BMC Surg. 2023;23(1):224. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12893-023-02117-0. PMID: 37559044; PMCID: PMC10413541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Onkelen RS, Gosselink MP, van Rosmalen J et al. Different characteristics of high and low transsphincteric fistulae. Colorectal Dis. 2014;16(6):471-5. https://doi.org/10.1111/codi.12578. PMID: 24471695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudukgian H, Abcarian H. Why do we have so much trouble treating anal fistula? World J Gastroenterol. 2011;17(28):3292&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.3748/wjg.v17.i28.3292. PMID: 21876616; PMCID: PMC3160532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Onkelen RS, Gosselink MP, Schouten WR. Is it possible to improve the outcome of transanal advancement flap repair for high transsphincteric fistulas by additional ligation of the intersphincteric fistula tract? Dis Colon Rectum. 2012;55(2):163&#x2013;6. . https://doi.org/10.1097/DCR.0b013e31823c0f74. PMID: 22228159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Bonnechose G, Lefevre JH, Aubert M, et al. Laser ablation of fistula tract (LAFT)and complex fistula-in-ano: the ideal indication is becoming clearer&#x2026;. Tech Coloproctol. 2020;24(7):695&#x2013;701. . https://doi.org/10.1007/s10151-020-02203-y. Epub 2020 Apr 24. PMID: 32333136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reza L, Gottgens K, Kleijnen J, et al. European Society of Coloproctology: Guidelines for diagnosis and treatment of cryptoglandular anal fistula. Colorectal Dis. 2024;26(1):145&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1111/codi.16741. Epub 2023 Dec 5. PMID: 38050857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaertner WB, Burgess PL, Davids JS, et al. The American Society of Colon and Rectal Surgeons Clinical Practice Guidelines for the Management of Anorectal Abscess, Fistula-in-Ano, and Rectovaginal Fistula. Dis Colon Rectum. 2022;65(8):964&#x2013;85. https://doi.org/10.1097/DCR.0000000000002473. Epub 2022 Jul 5. PMID: 35732009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ege B, Levento&#x11f;lu S, Mente&#x15f; BB, et al. Hybrid seton for the treatment of high anal fistulas: results of 128 consecutive patients. Tech Coloproctol. 2014;18(2):187&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10151-013-1021-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavanaugh M, Hyman N, Osler T. Fecal incontinence severity index after fistulotomy: a predictor of quality of life. Dis Colon Rectum. 2002;45(3):349&#x2013;53. . https://doi.org/10.1007/s10350-004-6181-5. PMID: 12068193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Koperen PJ, ten Kate FJ, Bemelman WA, et al. Histological identification of epithelium in perianal fistulae: a prospective study. Colorectal Dis. 2010;12(9):891&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1463-1318.2009.01880.x. Epub 2009 Apr 10. PMID: 19486085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinedo MG, Caselli MG, Urrejola SG, et al. Modified loose-seton technique for the treatment of complex anal fistulas. Colorectal Dis. 2010;12(10 Online):e310-3. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1463-1318.2010.02195.x. PMID: 20070336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pescatori M, Ayabaca SM, Cafaro D, et al. Marsupialization of fistulotomy and fistulectomy wounds improves healing and decreases bleeding: a randomized controlled trial. Colorectal Dis. 2006;8(1):11&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1463-1318.2005.00835.x. PMID: 16519632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghahramani L, Minaie MR, Arasteh P, et al. Antibiotic therapy for prevention of fistula in-ano after incision and drainage of simple perianal abscess: A randomized single blind clinical trial. Surgery. 2017;162(5):1017&#x2013;25. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surg.2017.07.001. Epub 2017 Aug 16. PMID: 28822559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;ltekin T, Ozer BK, Akin G, et al. Prevalence of overweight and obesity in Turkish adults. Anthropol Anz. 2009;67(2):205&#x2013;12. PMID: 19739469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr S, Velasco AL. Fistula-in-Ano. [Updated 2023 Jul 31]. In: StatPearls [Internet]. Treasure Island: StatPearls Publishing; 2025. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK557517/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng L, Shi Y, Zhi C, et al. Loose combined cutting seton for patients with high intersphincteric fistula: a retrospective study. Ann Transl Med. 2020;8(19):1236. https://doi.org/10.21037/atm-20-6123. PMID: 33178768; PMCID: PMC7607110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lykke A, Steendahl J, Wille-J&#xf8;rgensen PA. H&#xf8;je analfistler behandlet med langsomt skaerende seton [Treating high anal fistulae with slow cutting seton]. Ugeskr Laeger. 2010;172(7):516&#x2013;9. Danish. PMID: 20156398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokunaga Y, Sasaki H, Saito T. Clinical role of a modified seton technique for the treatment of trans-sphincteric and supra-sphincteric anal fistulas. Surg Today. 2013;43(3):245&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00595-012-0211-z. Epub 2012 Jun 4. PMID: 22661282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulen M, Sariyildiz GT, Pala MI, et al. The effect of hybrid seton on anal continence and quality of life in transsphincteric fistulas. Long-term follow-up. Ann Ital Chir. 2022;93:716&#x2013;9. PMID: 36617281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taskin AK, Akar M, Ozcetin B. Comparison of the Efficacy of Laser and Hybrid Seton Methods in the Treatment of Perianal Fistula. J Coll Physicians Surg Pak. 2024;34(9):1040&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.29271/jcpsp.2024.09.1040. PMID: 39262002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang J, Zhang Y, Ding X, et al. Efficacy and safety of an innovatively modified cutting seton technique for the treatment of high anal fistula: A protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Med (Baltim). 2021;100(5):e24442. https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000024442. PMID: 33592892; PMCID: PMC7870255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xi J, Li W, Li T, et al. Effects of loose combined cutting seton surgery on wound healing and pain in patients with high anal fistula: A meta-analysis. Int Wound J. 2024;21(3):e14675. https://doi.org/10.1111/iwj.14675. PMID: 38484699; PMCID: PMC10940002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhi C, Huang Z, Liu D, et al. Long-term follow-up study of loose combined cutting seton surgery for patients with high anal fistula. Ann Transl Med. 2021;9(14):1160. https://doi.org/10.21037/atm-21-3242. PMID: 34430601; PMCID: PMC8350621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mentes BB, Oktemer S, Tezcaner T, et al. Elastic one-stage cutting seton for the treatment of high anal fistulas: preliminary results. Tech Coloproctol. 2004;8(3):159&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10151-004-0080-6. PMID: 15654522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen DR, Kaiser AM. Definitive seton management for transsphincteric fistula-in-ano: harm or charm? Colorectal Dis. 2016;18(5):488&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.1111/codi.13120. PMID: 26382283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bordeianou LG, Thorsen AJ, Keller DS, et al. The American Society of Colon and Rectal Surgeons Clinical Practice Guidelines for the Management of Fecal Incontinence. Dis Colon Rectum. 2023;66(5):647&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.1097/DCR.0000000000002776. Epub 2023 Feb 14. PMID: 40324433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaveli Diaz C, Esquiroz Lizaur I, Marzo Virto J, et al. Fistulectomy and endorectal advancement flap repair for cryptoglandular anal fistula: recurrence and functional outcome over 10 years of follow-up. Int J Colorectal Dis. 2021;36(4):841&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00384-021-03867-0. Epub 2021 Feb 12. PMID: 33580275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emile SH. Recurrent anal fistulas: When, why, and how to manage? World J Clin Cases. 2020;8(9):1586&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.12998/wjcc.v8.i9.1586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browder LK, Sweet S, Kaiser AM. Modified Hanley procedure for management of complex horseshoe fistulae. Tech Coloproctol. 2009;13(4):301&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10151-009-0539-6. Epub 2009 Oct 8. PMID: 19813077.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subhas G, Singh Bhullar J, Al-Omari A, et al. Setons in the treatment of anal fistula: review of variations in materials and techniques. Dig Surg. 2012;29(4):292&#x2013;300. https://doi.org/10.1159/000342398. Epub 2012 Aug 31. PMID: 22948115.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>