<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41882746</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2050-2974</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of eating disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Eat Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Changes in agouti-related protein and symptom improvement in drug-na&#xef;ve Chinese female patients with anorexia nervosa: a 6-month real-world longitudinal study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40337-026-01582-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Agouti-related protein (AgRP) is an orexigenic neuropeptide that also plays a role in stereotypic behaviors and cognitive impairments. This study examined whether plasma AgRP levels are associated with eating disorder symptom severity and longitudinal symptom changes in anorexia nervosa (AN).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study included 53 drug-na&#xef;ve patients diagnosed with AN, comprising 41 with the restricting subtype (AN-R) and 12 with the binge/purging subtype (AN-BP), along with 43 healthy controls (HC). At baseline, all participants underwent fasting blood sampling for plasma AgRP measurement and completed the Eating Disorder Examination Questionnaire, Version 6 (EDE-Q). During the 6-month follow-up, patients received routine clinical treatment, and 32 patients underwent repeat AgRP measurement and clinical reassessment. Baseline variables were compared using Mann-Whitney U tests for two-group comparisons or Kruskal-Wallis tests for three-group comparisons, with Bonferroni correction applied for post-hoc analyses. Changes between baseline and follow-up were assessed using the Wilcoxon signed-rank test. Associations between AgRP levels and clinical measures were examined using Spearman correlation and linear regression analyses, with Bonferroni correction applied for multiple comparisons.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The study found elevated plasma AgRP concentrations in patients with AN, with post hoc analyses indicating higher levels in AN-R compared with HC, while no significant differences were observed between AN-R and AN-BP or between AN-BP and HC. During the 6-month follow-up, AgRP concentrations in patients with AN declined and approached levels observed in HC. Among the 32 patients with AN who completed follow-up, baseline AgRP levels were negatively correlated with follow-up EDE-Q total scores. Body mass index (BMI) was negatively correlated with AgRP levels in all participants. Partial correlation, controlling for baseline BMI, showed that changes in AgRP were positively correlated with improvements in EDE-Q total scores. This association remained significant in regression analysis after adjusting for BMI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">AgRP levels were elevated in patients with AN at baseline and decreased to levels comparable with HC during treatment, with the magnitude of reduction associated with improvements in EDE-Q total scores. These findings suggest that dynamic changes in AgRP may serve as a biological correlate of the metabolic and clinical recovery process in AN.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yanran</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, No. 600, South Wanping Road, Shanghai, 200030, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Qing</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, No. 600, South Wanping Road, Shanghai, 200030, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mental health center, West China Second University Hospital of Sichuan University, Sichuan University, No. 20, Section 3, South Renmin Road, Chengdu, 610041, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pang</LastName><ForeName>Sufang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, No. 600, South Wanping Road, Shanghai, 200030, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, No. 600, South Wanping Road, Shanghai, 200030, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, No. 600, South Wanping Road, Shanghai, 200030, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Han</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, No. 600, South Wanping Road, Shanghai, 200030, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, No. 600, South Wanping Road, Shanghai, 200030, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jue</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, No. 600, South Wanping Road, Shanghai, 200030, People's Republic of China. chenjue2088@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023-QH-01</GrantID><Agency>Hospital-level research projects of Shanghai Mental Health Center</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>GWVI-11.2-YQ39</GrantID><Agency>Shanghai three-year action plan to strengthen the construction of public health system-Outstanding young talents project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82471573</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SHDC12023122</GrantID><Agency>Clinical Science and Technology Innovation Project of Shanghai Hospital Development Center</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022KTM033</GrantID><Agency>Chinese Medicine Education Association</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Eat Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610672</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-2974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>People with anorexia nervosa (AN) often restrict food, leading to low weight, due to concerns about weight and body image. Research suggests that their difficulty in maintaining a healthy weight may also involve changes in how the body regulates energy and metabolism. A key system involved in hunger and energy balance is the Agouti-related protein (AgRP) system in the brain, which helps regulate appetite. To explore the relationship between AgRP and symptom changes in AN, this study measured plasma AgRP levels in 53 patients with AN and 43 healthy controls (HC). This study found that, compared with HC, patients with AN had higher AgRP levels, particularly those with the restricting subtype, while no significant difference was observed between AN-R and AN-BP. After six months of treatment, AgRP levels in AN decreased to levels similar to HC, reflecting normalization alongside clinical improvement. Higher starting AgRP levels were linked to fewer eating disorder symptoms later, and a greater reduction in AgRP was linked to more symptom improvement. These findings suggest that reductions in AgRP occur alongside recovery and may reflect improvements in nutritional and clinical status. Therefore, AgRP may serve as a potential biological indicator of disease improvement, and longitudinal tracking of AgRP may provide insights into the recovery process in AN.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Agouti-related protein (AgRP)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anorexia nervosa (AN)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Appetite</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eating Disorder Examination Questionnaire, Version 6 (EDE-Q)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eating disorders (ED)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval was obtained from the Ethics Committee of the Shanghai Mental Health Center (Ethical Approval No.2018&#x2013;28). The study was performed according to the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent for publication: All authors have approved the submission of this manuscript for publication. All participants were informed about the publication plan and provided their consent. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41882746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40337-026-01582-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40337-026-01582-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Attia E, Becker AE, Bryant-Waugh R, Hoek HW, Kreipe RE, Marcus MD, et al. Feeding and eating disorders in DSM-5. Am J Psychiatry. 2013;170(11):1237&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Call C, Walsh BT, Attia E. From DSM-IV to DSM-5: changes to eating disorder diagnoses. Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2013;26(6):532&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keating C. Theoretical perspective on anorexia nervosa: the conflict of reward. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2010;34(1):73&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson HJ, Yilmaz Z, Thornton LM, H&#xfc;bel C, Coleman JRI, Gaspar HA, et al. Genome-wide association study identifies eight risk loci and implicates metabo-psychiatric origins for anorexia nervosa. Nat Genet. 2019;51(8):1207&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;quinion M, Foldi CJ, Andrews ZB. The ghrelin-AgRP neuron nexus in anorexia nervosa: implications for metabolic and behavioral adaptations. Front Nutr. 2019;6:190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deem JD, Faber CL, Morton GJ. AgRP neurons: regulators of feeding, energy expenditure, and behavior. FEBS J. 2022;289(8):2362&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joly-Amado A, Cansell C, Denis RGP, Delbes A-S, Castel J, Martinez S, et al. The hypothalamic arcuate nucleus and the control of peripheral substrates. Best Pract Res Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2014;28(5):725&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah Bhavik KMJ, Koda P, Lowell Bradford S. Rapid versus delayed stimulation of feeding by the endogenously released AgRP neuron mediators GABA, NPY, and AgRP. Cell Metab. 2013;18(4):588&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SR, Chen H, Zhou JJ, Pradhan G, Sun Y, Pan HL, et al. Ghrelin receptors mediate ghrelin-induced excitation of agouti-related protein/neuropeptide Y but not pro-opiomelanocortin neurons. J Neurochem. 2017;142(4):512&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luquet S, Perez FA, Hnasko TS, Palmiter RD. NPY/AgRP neurons are essential for feeding in adult mice but can be ablated in neonates. Science. 2005;310(5748):683&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gropp E, Shanabrough M, Borok E, Xu AW, Janoschek R, Buch T, et al. Agouti-related peptide&#x2013;expressing neurons are mandatory for feeding. Nat Neurosci. 2005;8(10):1289&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Y, Xia G, Wu Q. Functional interrogation of the AgRP neural circuits in control of appetite, body weight, and behaviors. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2018;1090:1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnett CJ, Li C, Webber E, Tsaousidou E, Xue Stephen Y, Br&#xfc;ning Jens C, et al. Hunger-driven motivational state competition. Neuron. 2016;92(1):187&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietrich Marcelo O, Zimmer Marcelo R, Bober J, Horvath Tamas L. Hypothalamic agrp neurons drive stereotypic behaviors beyond feeding. Cell. 2015;160(6):1222&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spadini S, Ferro M, Lamanna J, Malgaroli A. Activity-based anorexia animal model: a review of the main neurobiological findings. J Eat Disord. 2021;9(1):123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miletta MC, Iyilikci O, Shanabrough M, &#x160;estan-Pe&#x161;a M, Cammisa A, Zeiss CJ, et al. AgRP neurons control compulsive exercise and survival in an activity-based anorexia model. Nat metabolism. 2020;2(11):1204&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietrich MO, Zimmer MR, Bober J, Horvath TL. Hypothalamic Agrp neurons drive stereotypic behaviors beyond feeding. Cell. 2015;160(6):1222&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarrar L, Ehrlich S, Merle JV, Pfeiffer E, Lehmkuhl U, Schneider N. Cognitive flexibility and agouti-related protein in adolescent patients with anorexia nervosa. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2011;36(9):1396&#x2013;406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rokot NT, Ataka K, Iwai H, Suzuki H, Tachibe H, Kairupan TS, et al. Antagonism for NPY signaling reverses cognitive behavior defects induced by activity-based anorexia in mice. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2021;126:105133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinulescu DM, Cone RD. Agouti and agouti-related protein: analogies and contrasts*. J Biol Chem. 2000;275(10):6695&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doghman M, Soltani Y, Rebuffet V, Naville D, B&#xe9;geot M. Role of Agouti-related protein in adrenal steroidogenesis. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2007;265&#x2013;266:108&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon HY, Bultman SJ, L&#xf6;ffler C, Chen WJ, Furdon PJ, Powell JG, et al. Molecular structure and chromosomal mapping of the human homolog of the agouti gene. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1994;91(21):9760&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson BD, Ollmann MM, Kang L, Stoffel M, Bell GI, Barsh GS. Structure and function of ASP, the human homolog of the mouse agouti gene. Hum Mol Genet. 1995;4(2):223&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz Z, Kaplan AS, Tiwari AK, Levitan RD, Piran S, Bergen AW, et al. The role of leptin, melanocortin, and neurotrophin system genes on body weight in anorexia nervosa and bulimia nervosa. J Psychiatr Res. 2014;55:77&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vink T, Hinney A, van Elburg AA, van Goozen SH, Sandkuijl LA, Sinke RJ, et al. Association between an agouti-related protein gene polymorphism and anorexia nervosa. Mol Psychiatry. 2001;6(3):325&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriya J, Takimoto Y, Yoshiuchi K, Shimosawa T, Akabayashi A. Plasma agouti-related protein levels in women with anorexia nervosa. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2006;31(9):1057&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merle JV, Haas V, Burghardt R, Dohler N, Schneider N, Lehmkuhl U, et al. Agouti-related protein in patients with acute and weight-restored anorexia nervosa. Psychol Med. 2011;41(10):2183&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page-Wilson G, Nguyen KT, Atalayer D, Meece K, Bainbridge HA, Korner J, et al. Evaluation of CSF and plasma biomarkers of brain melanocortin activity in response to caloric restriction in humans. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2017;312(1):E19&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu L, Zhou B, Peng S, Chen H, Kang Q, Chen J. Cross-cultural validation and application of the EDE-Q 6.0 for screening and assessment of eating disorders in Chinese females. Int J Eat Disord. 2025;58(7):1319&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Wang Y, Xin T. The psychometric properties of the Chinese version of the beck depression inventory-II with middle school teachers. Front Psychol. 2020;11:548965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Y, Wang L, Zhu J. Factor structure and psychometric properties of Chinese version of beck anxiety inventory in Chinese doctors. J Health Psychol. 2018;23(5):657&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tortorella A, Brambilla F, Fabrazzo M, Volpe U, Monteleone AM, Mastromo D, et al. Central and peripheral peptides regulating eating behaviour and energy homeostasis in anorexia nervosa and bulimia nervosa: a literature review. Eur Eat Disord Rev. 2014;22(5):307&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry FE, Sugino K, Tozer A, Branco T, Sternson SM. Cell type-specific transcriptomics of hypothalamic energy-sensing neuron responses to weight-loss. eLife. 2015;4:e09800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Lin YC, Kuo TW, Knight ZA. Sensory detection of food rapidly modulates arcuate feeding circuits. Cell. 2015;160(5):829&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Z, Alhadeff AL, Betley JN, Nutritive. Post-ingestive signals are the primary regulators of AgRP neuron activity. Cell Rep. 2017;21(10):2724&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beutler LR, Chen Y, Ahn JS, Lin YC, Essner RA, Knight ZA. Dynamics of gut-brain communication underlying hunger. Neuron. 2017;96(2):461&#x2013;. &#x2013;&#x2009;75.e5.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>