<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41845380</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2482</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development of machine learning-based predictive models for seroma formation after transabdominal preperitoneal inguinal hernia repair.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12893-026-03555-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Inguinal hernia repair, particularly transabdominal preperitoneal (TAPP) repair, is a common surgical procedure. However, seroma formation remains a frequent postoperative complication, impacting patient recovery and increasing healthcare burden. Accurate prediction of seroma formation is crucial for personalized patient management and improved outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to develop and validate machine learning (ML)-based predictive models for seroma formation following TAPP inguinal hernia repair.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective cohort of patients undergoing TAPP repair was analyzed. Demographic, clinical, laboratory, and surgical data were collected. Data preprocessing included handling missing values and encoding categorical variables. Feature selection was performed using LASSO regression and multivariate logistic regression. Five distinct machine learning algorithms-Logistic Regression (LR), Decision Tree (DT), eXtreme Gradient Boosting (XGBoost), Support Vector Machine (SVM), and K-Nearest Neighbors (KNN)-were developed and evaluated. Model performance was assessed using various metrics, including Accuracy, Sensitivity, Specificity, Precision, Recall, F1-score, Receiver Operating Characteristic (ROC) curves, Area Under the Curve (AUC), Precision-Recall (PR) curves, Calibration curves, and Decision Curve Analysis (DCA). SHapley Additive exPlanations (SHAP) were employed to interpret the models and identify key influential features.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 167 patients were included in the study, divided into training (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;133) and validation (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;34) sets. Multivariate analysis identified several independent risk factors for seroma formation, including Diabetes, Smoking, Age, Hemoglobin, and sac diameter. Among the developed ML models, XGBoost consistently demonstrated superior predictive performance with an AUC of 0.979 (0.961-0.997) on the training set and 0.746 (0.557-0.935) on the test set. SHAP analysis revealed that sac diameter, Hemoglobin, Age, Diabetes, and Smoking were the most significant features influencing seroma prediction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Machine learning models, particularly XGBoost, can accurately predict seroma formation after TAPP inguinal hernia repair. The identified risk factors and the developed predictive models have the potential to facilitate early risk stratification, guide clinical decision-making, and ultimately improve patient outcomes by enabling targeted preventive strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhai</LastName><ForeName>Yibo</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bengbu Medical University, Bengbu, Anhui, 233030, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastrointestinal Surgery, The Second Peoples'Hospital of Hefei, Hefei, Anhui, 230011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastrointestinal Surgery, The Second Peoples'Hospital of Hefei, Hefei, Anhui, 230011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Chang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastrointestinal Surgery, The Second Peoples'Hospital of Hefei, Hefei, Anhui, 230011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bao</LastName><ForeName>Wenzhong</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastrointestinal Surgery, The Second Peoples'Hospital of Hefei, Hefei, Anhui, 230011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Dawei</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bengbu Medical University, Bengbu, Anhui, 233030, China. tangdw21@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastrointestinal Surgery, The Second Peoples'Hospital of Hefei, Hefei, Anhui, 230011, China. tangdw21@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968567</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2482</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine Learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Seroma Formation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transabdominal Preperitioneal Repair</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">XGBoost</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This retrospective study was approved by the Institutional Review Board (IRB) of the Second People&#x2019;s Hospital of Hefei (Approval No.: 2024KYC025). The requirement for informed consent to participate was waived by the Institutional Review Board (IRB) of the Second People&#x2019;s Hospital of Hefei due to the retrospective design and the use of anonymized clinical data. All procedures were conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki (2013 revision). Consent for publication: Not Applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41845380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12893-026-03555-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12893-026-03555-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Peng XF, Yu M, Wang DC. Establishment of a Predictive Model for Seroma Formation After TAPP Repair for Unilateral Indirect Inguinal Hernia in Males. Am Surg. 2025;91(3):351&#x2013;360. https://doi.org/10.1177/00031348241300369. Epub 2024 Nov 11. PMID: 39527918IF: 0.9 Q3 B4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng X-F, Miao Yu, and, Deng-Chao, Wang. Establishment of a predictive model for seroma formation after TAPP repair for unilateral indirect inguinal hernia in males. Am Surgeon&#x2122;. 2025;91(3):351&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Supsamutchai C, Pongratanakul R, Jirasiritham J, Punmeechao P, Poprom N, Wilasrusmee J, Meakleartmongkol T, Plangsiri S, Wilasrusmee C. Differences in the rates of seroma complications between hernial sac transection and reduction after laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair: systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):10030. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-94683-x. PMID: 40122984IF: 3.9 Q1 B3; PMCID: PMC11930968IF: 3.9 Q1 B3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Ge Y, Liu J, Shen W, Gu H, Cheng G. Modified frailty index and albumin-fibrinogen ratio predicts postoperative seroma after laparoscopic TAPP. Clin Interv Aging. 2023;18:1397&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinhorn M, et al. Posterior mesh inguinal hernia repairs: a propensity score matched analysis of laparoscopic and robotic versus open approaches. Hernia. 2023;27(1):93&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filho M, Almeida AM, Barros EM, et al. Simulated training model in a low cost for laparoscopic inguinal hernioplasty. Acta Cir&#xfa;rgica Brasileira. 2021;36(1):e360108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taha A, et al. The development of artificial intelligence in hernia surgery: a scoping review. Front Surg. 2022;9:908014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Buono G, Romano G, Rodolico V, et al. Progrip versus proflor: two fixation-free devices for laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair&#x2014;the Pro/Pro study, a randomized clinical trial. Surg Endosc. 2025;39:3113&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baur J, Ramser M, Dietz UA. Management of hernial orifices in robotic inguinal hernia repair. Mini-Invasive Surg. 2021;5(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Hong-yang, et al. Risk factors and clinical impact of seroma formation following laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair: a retrospective study. BMC Surg. 2024;24(1):274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogel R, Bj&#xf6;rn, M&#xfc;ck. Artificial Intelligence&#x2014;What to expect from machine learning and deep learning in hernia surgery. J Abdom Wall Surg. 2024;3:13059.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hundal J, Ballambat N, Helen S, Namazi S, Dugan A. Predictors of receiving work accommodations among employed breast cancer survivors with adult and child dependents at home. J Clin Oncol. 2024;42(16_suppl):211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marte A, Caldamone AA. Aguiar. The history of the pediatric inguinal hernia repair. J Pediatr Urol. 2021;17(4):485&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Restrepo-Rodas G, et al. The role of AI in modern hernia surgery: A review and practical insights. Surg Innov. 2025;32(3):301&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuccaro G. 44th Annual Meeting of International Society for Pediatric Neurosurgery, Kobe, Japan, Oct 23&#x2013;27, 2016. Child&#x2019;s Nerv Syst. 2016;32(10):1957&#x2013;2040.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh ETH. CRP as a mediator of disease. Circulation. 2004;109(21 Suppl 1):II-11&#x2013;II-14. https://doi.org/10.1161/01.CIR.0000129507.12719.80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan W-H, et al. Risk factors for recurrence of common bile duct stones after surgical treatment and effect of ursodeoxycholic acid intervention. World J Gastrointest Surg. 2024;16(1):103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Ramahi M, et al. Risk factors for seroma formation after laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Hernia. 2023;27(3):675&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, et al. Machine learning in surgical outcomes prediction: A systematic review. Ann Surg. 2022;275(1):e1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson AEW, et al. Artificial intelligence in surgery: A review of current applications and future directions. J Am Coll Surg. 2021;232(4):585&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith J, et al. External validation of predictive models for postoperative complications: A methodological review. J Clin Epidemiol. 2023;153:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, et al. Clinical utility of machine learning models in surgical risk stratification: A decision curve analysis. Surgery. 2022;171(5):1300&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee P, et al. Impact of surgical technique on seroma formation after inguinal hernia repair: A comparative study. Surg Endosc. 2020;34(10):4500&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown A, et al. Genetic predispositions to postoperative complications: A review. Br J Surg. 2019;106(7):812&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis R, et al. Real-time intraoperative data for predictive analytics in surgery: A prospective study. JAMA Surg. 2024;159(1):70&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia M, et al. Advanced imaging techniques for early detection of postoperative complications. Radiology. 2023;306(2):e222001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White S, et al. Biomarkers for predicting surgical outcomes: A review of current evidence. Annals Translational Med. 2022;10(18):987&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kriplani AK, Shyam S, Pachisia, Ghosh D. Laparoscopic trans abdominal pre-peritoneal (TAPP) repair of inguinal hernia. In: Kriplani A, Bhatia P, Prasad A, et al., editors. Comprehensive Laparoscopic Surgery. New Delhi: Sagar Printers; 2007. p. 119&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>