<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41853763</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2589-5141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of hand surgery global online</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hand Surg Glob Online</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Likelihood of Dupuytren Contracture Recurrence After Limited Fasciectomy, Needle Aponeurotomy or Collagenase <i>Clostridium histolyticum</i>: Systematic Review of Prospective Data With 2- to 7-Year Follow-up.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100979</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100979</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100979</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jhsg.2026.100979</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Compare contracture recurrence after limited fasciectomy (LF), collagenase <i>Clostridium histolyticum</i> (CCH), and needle aponeurotomy (NA) for Dupuytren contracture (DC) using prospectively collected studies with &#x2265;2-year follow-up and assess recurrence by joint (metacarpophalangeal [MCP] vs proximal interphalangeal [PIP]).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Systematic review restricted to prospective cohort series or randomized controlled trials treating DC with LF, CCH, and/or NA. Eligibility required &#x2265;2-year, in-person clinical follow-up and explicit definition of contracture recurrence. Exclusions included non-English publications, telephone/questionnaire-only follow-up, no recurrence data at follow-up, and sample size &lt;15 patients. The primary end point was recurrence by treatment. Secondary analyses evaluated recurrence by joint treated and reintervention and complications when reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Ten studies met criteria, encompassing 1,411 patients and 1,698 treated joints with a mean follow-up of 3.8 years. Across studies, LF demonstrated a lower risk of recurrence than both CCH and NA, and CCH demonstrated a lower risk of recurrence than NA. Recurrence was less likely in the treatment of MCP versus PIP contractures across all treatments. For studies that reported subsequent procedures for recurrence, there was a lower likelihood of reinterventions after LF than after CCH or NA. Commonly reported complications included digital nerve injury, tendon injury, skin tears, swelling, pain, and bleeding.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In prospectively collected cohorts with a mean 3.8 years of follow-up, recurrence after DC treatment was common. LF demonstrated the lowest recurrence (16.5%), CCH had an intermediate recurrence (32.5%), and NA showed the highest recurrence (46.4%). PIP joint contractures were more likely to recur than MCP joint contractures, regardless of treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL RELEVANCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">LF offers greater durability and a lower likelihood of subsequent procedures than CCH or NA in the treatment of DC at intermediate term follow-up; however, the clinician must also weigh the length of recovery and potential complications between these three treatment options. Patients with PIP contractures should be counseled about a higher recurrence risk and potential need for closer follow-up.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nocek</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Colorado School of Medicine, Anschutz Medical Campus, Aurora, CO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wakefield</LastName><ForeName>Dorothy</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ONS Foundation for Clinical Research and Education, 6 Greenwich Office Park, 40 Valley Drive, Greenwich, CT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vitale</LastName><ForeName>Mark A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ONS Foundation for Clinical Research and Education, 6 Greenwich Office Park, 40 Valley Drive, Greenwich, CT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Greenwich Hospital, Yale-New Haven Health, 5 Perryridge Road, Greenwich, CT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Hand Surg Glob Online</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101759126</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2589-5141</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Collagenase Clostridium histolyticum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dupuytren contracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fasciectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Needle aponeurotomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recurrence</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Dr. Mark A. Vitale served on the advisory board for Endo Pharmaceuticals, Inc in 2022. The other authors have no relevant conflicts to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41853763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12992953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhsg.2026.100979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2589-5141(26)00034-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Salari N., Heydari M., Hassanabadi M., et al. The worldwide prevalence of the Dupuytren disease: a comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis. J Orthop Surg Res. 2020;15(1):495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7594412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33115483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townley W.A., Baker R., Sheppard N., Grobbelaar A.O. Dupuytren's contracture unfolded. Bmj. 2006;332(7538):397&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1370973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16484265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dibenedetti D.B., Nguyen D., Zografos L., Ziemiecki R., Zhou X. Prevalence, incidence, and treatments of Dupuytren's disease in the United States: results from a population-based study. Hand (N Y) 2011;6(2):149&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3092891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21776198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turesson C., Kvist J., Krevers B. Experiences of men living with Dupuytren's disease-consequences of the disease for hand function and daily activities. J Hand Ther. 2020;33(3):386&#x2013;393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31477329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilburn J., McKenna S.P., Perry-Hinsley D., Bayat A. The impact of Dupuytren disease on patient activity and quality of life. J Hand Surg Am. 2013;38(6):1209&#x2013;1214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23707018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues J.N., Becker G.W., Ball C., et al. Surgery for Dupuytren's contracture of the fingers. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;2015(12)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26648251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandya W.C.A., Bhatti D., Manley O. A longitudinal analysis of 281 cases of dermofasciectomy efficacy in advanced Dupuytren disease cases: a 20-year perspective. J Hand Surg Am. 2025;50(6):656&#x2013;662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40237682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias J., Tharmanathan P., Arundel C., et al. Collagenase injection versus limited fasciectomy for Dupuytren's contracture. N Engl J Med. 2024;391(16):1499&#x2013;1510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7616701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39383454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traynor K. Enzyme product approved for rare hand disorder. Am J Health Syst Pharm. 2010;67(6):416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20208044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilpin D., Coleman S., Hall S., Houston A., Karrasch J., Jones N. Injectable collagenase Clostridium histolyticum: a new nonsurgical treatment for Dupuytren's disease. J Hand Surg Am. 2010;35(12):2027&#x2013;2038.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21134613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst L.C., Badalamente M.A., Hentz V.R., et al. Injectable collagenase Clostridium histolyticum for Dupuytren's contracture. N Engl J Med. 2009;361(10):968&#x2013;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19726771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smeraglia F., Del Buono A., Maffulli N. Collagenase Clostridium histolyticum in Dupuytren's contracture: a systematic review. Br Med Bull. Jun 2016;118(1):149&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5127428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27151958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy A., Lalonde D.H., Eaton C., et al. Minimally invasive options in Dupuytren's contracture: aponeurotomy, enzymes, stretching, and fat grafting. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2014;134(5):822e&#x2013;829e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25347658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morhart M. Pearls and pitfalls of needle aponeurotomy in Dupuytren's disease. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2015;135(3):817&#x2013;825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25719700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias J.J., Singh H.P., Ullah A., Bhowal B., Thompson J.R. Patterns of recontracture after surgical correction of Dupuytren disease. J Hand Surg Am. 2013;38(10):1987&#x2013;1993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23910381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen M.S., Karjalainen V.L., Reddy A., Karjalainen T., Chung K.C. Effectiveness and safety of Dupuytren contracture treatments: a systematic review and meta-analysis using the GRADE approach. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2025;156(3):375e&#x2013;384e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39451139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soreide E., Murad M.H., Denbeigh J.M., et al. Treatment of Dupuytren's contracture: a systematic review. Bone Joint J. 2018;100-b(9):1138&#x2013;1145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30168768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cocci A., Russo G.I., Salamanca J.I.M., Ralph D., Palmieri A., Mondaini N. The end of an era: withdrawal of Xiapex (Clostridium histolyticum collagenase) from the European market. Eur Urol. 2020;77(5):660&#x2013;661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31810821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felici N., Marcoccio I., Giunta R., et al. Dupuytren contracture recurrence project: reaching consensus on a definition of recurrence. Handchir Mikrochir Plast Chir. 2014;46(6):350&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25412239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werker P.M.N., Pess G.M., van Rijssen A.L., Denkler K. Correction of contracture and recurrence rates of Dupuytren contracture following invasive treatment: the importance of clear definitions. J Hand Surg Am. 2012;37(10):2095&#x2013;2105.e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22938804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kan H.J., Verrijp F.W., Huisstede B.M.A., Hovius S.E.R., van Nieuwenhoven C.A., Selles R.W. The consequences of different definitions for recurrence of Dupuytren's disease. J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg. 2013;66(1):95&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23137947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kan H.J., Verrijp F.W., Hovius S.E.R., van Nieuwenhoven C.A., Dupuytren Delphi Group. Selles R.W. Recurrence of Dupuytren's contracture: a consensus-based definition. PLoS One. 2017;12(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5432164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28505187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page M.J., McKenzie J.E., Bossuyt P.M., et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Syst Rev. 2021;10(1):89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuinness L.A., Higgins J.P.T. Risk-of-bias VISualization (robvis): an R package and Shiny web app for visualizing risk-of-bias assessments. Res Synth Methods. 2021;12(1):55&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32336025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe Y. Comparison of treatment outcomes after collagenase injection and percutaneous needle fasciotomy for Dupuytren's contracture: objective and subjective comparisons with a 3-year follow-up. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2020;145(6):1464&#x2013;1474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32459776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vitis R., Passiatore M., Perna A., Careri S., Cilli V., Taccardo G. Seven-year clinical outcomes after collagenase injection in patients with Dupuytren's disease: a prospective study. J Orthop. 2020;21:218&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7132050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32273660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selles R.W., Zhou C., Kan H.J., Wouters R.M., van Nieuwenhoven C.A., Hovius S.E.R. Percutaneous aponeurotomy and lipofilling versus limited fasciectomy for Dupuytren's contracture: 5-year results from a randomized clinical trial. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2018;142(6):1523&#x2013;1531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30489526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf8;rgensen R.W., Jensen C.H., J&#xf8;rring S. Three- year recurrence of Dupuytren contracture after needle fasciotomy or collagenase injection: a randomized controlled trial. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2023;151(2):365&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36342689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skov S.T., Bisgaard T., S&#xf8;ndergaard P., Lange J. Injectable collagenase versus percutaneous needle fasciotomy for Dupuytren contracture in proximal interphalangeal joints: a randomized controlled trial. J Hand Surg Am. 2017;42(5):321&#x2013;328.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28473158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rijssen A.L., Ter Linden H., Werker P.M.N. Five-year results of a randomized clinical trial on treatment in Dupuytren's disease: percutaneous needle fasciotomy versus limited fasciectomy. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2012;129(2):469&#x2013;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21987045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peimer C.A., Blazar P., Coleman S., Kaplan F.T.D., Smith T., Lindau T. Dupuytren contracture recurrence following treatment with collagenase Clostridium histolyticum (CORDLESS [collagenase option for reduction of Dupuytren long-term evaluation of safety study]): 5- year data. J Hand Surg Am. 2015;40(8):1597&#x2013;1605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26096221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim&#xf3;n-P&#xe9;rez C., Al&#xed;a-Ortega J., Garc&#xed;a-Medrano B., et al. Factors influencing recurrence and progression of Dupuytren's disease treated by collagenase Clostridium histolitycum. Int Orthop. 2018;42(4):859&#x2013;866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29170879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Beeck A., Van den Broek M., Michielsen M., Didden K., Vuylsteke K., Verstreken F. Efficacy and safety of collagenase treatment for Dupuytren's disease: 2-year follow-up results. Hand Surg Rehabil. 2017;36(5):346&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28732844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xe4;is&#xe4;nen M.P., Lepp&#xe4;nen O.V., Soikkeli J., et al. Surgery, needle fasciotomy, or collagenase injection for Dupuytren contracture: a randomized controlled trial. Ann Intern Med. 2024;177(3):280&#x2013;290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38346307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess T., Wegener E., McClelland B., et al. Adverse events after adjuvant radiation therapy for Dupuytren's disease in the DEPART randomized trial. J Hand Surg Eur Vol. 2025;50(7):891&#x2013;897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40017303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanchahal J., Ball C., Rombach I., et al. Anti-tumour necrosis factor therapy for early-stage Dupuytren's disease (RIDD): a phase 2b, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Rheumatol. 2022;4(6):E407&#x2013;E416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7613263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35949922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker G.W., Davis T.R. The outcome of surgical treatments for primary Dupuytren's disease--a systematic review. J Hand Surg Eur Vol. 2010;35(8):623&#x2013;626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20621942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen N.C., Srinivasan R.C., Shauver M.J., Chung K.C. A systematic review of outcomes of fasciotomy, aponeurotomy, and collagenase treatments for Dupuytren's contracture. Hand (N Y) 2011;6(3):250&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3153627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22942847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D., Earp B.E., Blazar P. Collagenase treatment versus needle fasciotomy for single-digit Dupuytren contractures: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Hand Surg Am. 2023;48(12):1200&#x2013;1209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37725027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liechti R., Merky D.N., Sutter D., Ipaktchi R., V&#xf6;gelin E. Collagenase Clostridium histolyticum injection versus limited fasciectomy for the treatment of Dupuytren's disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis of comparative studies. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2024;144(1):527&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37665353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cevik J., Rajaram R., Pollock M., Seth I., M Rozen W. Collagenase clostridium histolyticum for Dupuytren's disease: a comprehensive systematic review and comparative analysis against percutaneous needle aponeurotomy and limited fasciectomy. J Plast Surg Hand Surg. 2025;60:27&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39945007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Berge B.A., Habibi H., Dijkstra P.U., et al. Outcomes of limited fasciectomy, needle fasciotomy and collagenase injection for Dupuytren's disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis of individual patient data. J Hand Surg Eur Vol. 2025;50(7):878&#x2013;890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12149465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40391547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordenskj&#xf6;ld J., Lauritzson A., &#xc5;kesson A., Atroshi I. Collagenase injections for Dupuytren disease: 3-year treatment outcomes and predictors of recurrence in 89 hands. Acta Orthop. 2019;90(6):517&#x2013;522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6844429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31500473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passiatore M., Cilli V., Cannella A., et al. Long-term assessment of collagenase treatment for Dupuytren's contracture: a 10-year follow-up study. World J Orthop. 2024;15(4):355&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11045466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38680672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riesmeijer S.A., Nolte I.M., Olde Loohuis L.M., et al. Polygenic risk associations with clinical characteristics and recurrence of Dupuytren disease. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2024;153(3):573e&#x2013;583e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10876167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37257093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulstrode N.W., Jemec B., Smith P.J. The complications of Dupuytren's contracture surgery. J Hand Surg Am. 2005;30(5):1021&#x2013;1025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16182062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hummer B., Sebastiani P., Leshchyk A., et al. Published online August 15, 2025. Identification of novel plasma proteomic biomarkers of Dupuytren Disease. bioRxiv.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2024.12.13.628406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>