<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41732234</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2325-9671</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Orthopaedic journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Orthop J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Surgical Volume of ACL Reconstruction, Knee Arthroscopy, and Rotator Cuff Repair Before and After the COVID-19 Pandemic: National Surgical Quality Improvement Program Data from 2015 to 2022.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23259671251403156</StartPage><MedlinePgn>23259671251403156</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23259671251403156</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/23259671251403156</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The COVID-19 pandemic significantly disrupted elective orthopaedic sports procedures, including anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstructions, meniscal surgeries, and rotator cuff repairs. These disruptions also extended into athletics, likely resulting in reduced injury rates in athletes leading to decreased surgical volumes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="HYPOTHESIS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">It was hypothesized that the COVID-19 pandemic led to an initial decline in ACL reconstructions, meniscal surgeries, and rotator cuff repairs, with a gradual recovery in surgical volumes during the later pandemic years.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Descriptive epidemiology study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A retrospective analysis of the American College of Surgeons' National Surgical Quality Improvement Program database was conducted from 2015 to 2022. Patients undergoing ACL reconstruction, knee meniscectomy or repair, knee foreign body removal, and rotator cuff repair were identified using Current Procedural Terminology codes. Surgical volumes and demographics from 2015 to 2019 served as a baseline for comparison with 2020 to 2022 data. Primary outcome was surgical volume change; secondary outcomes included patient demographics and operative-related factors. Chi-square tests were used for categorical variables and Student <i>t</i> tests for numerical variables, with nonparametric corrections and substitutions as needed. Significance was set at <i>P</i> &lt; .05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Overall, a total of 200,511 cases (N = 200,511 patients) were identified in our database search. From 2019 to 2020, surgical volume decreased by 25.48%, followed by a 10.32% rebound in 2021 and a 2.17% decrease in 2022. All 2022 volume remained below 2019 levels, except for knee meniscal repair. Postpandemic data showed a 5.66% increase in diabetic patients (<i>P</i> &lt; .001), 14.64% increase in total operative time (<i>P</i> &lt; .001), 71.43% increase in pneumonia incidence (<i>P</i> = .02), and 48.48% increase in inpatient surgeries (<i>P</i> &lt; .001). There was a 21.38% decrease in current smokers (<i>P</i> &lt; .001) and 5.12% decrease in patients with insulin-dependent diabetes (<i>P</i> &lt; .001). No change in hospital length of stay was observed (<i>P</i> = .52).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The study showed that orthopaedic sports surgery volumes declined in 2020 because of the COVID-19 pandemic and had not fully returned to prepandemic levels by 2022. Surgeries postpandemic were more commonly inpatient, required longer operative times, and involved patients with shifting demographic and comorbidity profiles. Understanding and reporting changes in surgical volume, setting, and patient profiles postpandemic may better prepare surgeons and health care institutions for future resource disruptions or impaired elective surgical capabilities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stone</LastName><ForeName>Dillon</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paul L. Foster School of Medicine, Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center El Paso, El Paso, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Cole</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and Rehabilitation, Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center El Paso, El Paso, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patrick</LastName><ForeName>Cole</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and Rehabilitation, Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center El Paso, El Paso, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajani</LastName><ForeName>Rajiv</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and Rehabilitation, Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center El Paso, El Paso, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Guowei</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center El Paso, El Paso, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aloman</LastName><ForeName>Catalina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paul L. Foster School of Medicine, Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center El Paso, El Paso, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Corning</LastName><ForeName>Evan</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and Rehabilitation, Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center El Paso, El Paso, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Orthop J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101620522</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2325-9671</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACL reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee meniscectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">orthopaedic outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rotator cuff repair</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgical volume</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>One or more of the authors has declared the following potential conflict of interest or source of funding: The American College of Surgeons National Surgical Quality Improvement Program and the hospitals participating in the ACS NSQIP are the source of the data used herein; they have not verified and are not responsible for the statistical validity of the data analysis or the conclusions derived by the authors. R.R. has received hospitality payments from Heraeus Medical LLC, KCI USA Inc, Linvatec Corporation, Onkos Surgical Inc, OsteoCentric Technolgies Inc, Stryker Corporation, Ultragenyx Pharmaceutical Inc, Bone Support Inc, Curasan Inc, Zimmer Biomet Holdings Inc, Bioventus LLC, DePuy Synthes Sales Inc, Orthalign Inc, Smith &amp; Nephew, and Integra LifeSciences Corporation; consulting fees from Bone Support Inc and Daiichi Sankyo Inc; and support for education from Zimmer Biomet Holdings Inc. E.C. is a consultant for CTM and has received hospitality payments from Arthrex Inc, Embody Inc, Linvatec Corporation, OsteoCentric Technologies Inc, Rattan and Associates, Stryker Corporation, Orthofix Medical Inc, SI-BONE Inc, Zimmer Biomet Holdings Inc, Sequoia Surgical Inc, Smith &amp; Nephew, Plyant Medical, Terumo BCT Inc, and Sequoia Surgical Inc; support for education from Rattan and Associates, Arthrex Inc, Medical Device Business Services Inc, Sequoia Surgical Inc, and Smith &amp; Nephew; and a grant from Arthrex Inc. AOSSM checks author disclosures against the Open Payments Database (OPD). AOSSM has not conducted an independent investigation on the OPD and disclaims any liability or responsibility relating thereto.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41732234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12925032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671251403156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_23259671251403156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agarwalla A, Gowd AK, Liu JN, et al. Effect of operative time on short-term adverse events after isolated anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Orthop J Sports Med. 2019;7(2):2325967118825453. doi: 10.1177/2325967118825453</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967118825453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6454657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31001565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Aspen Institute Project Play. State of Play 2023: Participation Trends. Accessed September 27, 2024. https://projectplay.org/state-of-play-2023/participation</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal S, Floyd ER, Kowalski MA, et al. Meniscal repair: the current state and recent advances in augmentation. J Orthop Res. 2021;39(7):1368-1382. doi: 10.1002/jor.25021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.25021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8249336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33751642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carolin K, Ertl M, Lenze U, et al. COVID-19-related cancellation of elective orthopaedic surgery caused increased pain and psychosocial distress levels. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2021;29(8):2379-2385. doi: 10.1007/s00167-021-06529-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-021-06529-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7952835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33710414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services. CMS Issues Recommendations to Re-Open Health Care Systems in Areas With Low Incidence of COVID-19 | CMS. CMS.gov. Accessed March 26, 2025. https://www.cms.gov/newsroom/press-releases/cms-issues-recommendations-re-open-health-care-systems-areas-low-incidence-covid-19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services. CMS Releases Recommendations on Adult Elective Surgeries, Non-Essential Medical, Surgical, and Dental Procedures During COVID-19 Response | CMS. CMS.gov. Accessed March 26, 2025. https://www.cms.gov/newsroom/press-releases/cms-releases-recommendations-adult-elective-surgeries-non-essential-medical-surgical-and-dental</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chughtai M, Gwam CU, Mohamed N, et al. The epidemiology and risk factors for postoperative pneumonia. J Clin Med Res. 2017;9(6):466-475. doi: 10.14740/jocmr3002w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14740/jocmr3002w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5412519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28496546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cushman DM, Teramoto M, Babu A, et al. Sports medicine physician decision making, practice changes, and mental health during the early phase of the SARS-COV-2 global pandemic. Clin J Sport Med. 2022;32(1):28-39. doi: 10.1097/JSM.0000000000000905</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8663923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33675623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datzmann T, D&#xf6;rfer L, Freude G, et al. Impact of COVID-19 pandemic-induced surgical restrictions on operational performance: a case study at the University Hospital of Ulm. Eur J Trauma Emerg Surg. 2024;50(5):2411-2420. doi: 10.1007/s00068-024-02558-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00068-024-02558-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11599351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38869511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day M, Westermann R, Duchman K, et al. Comparison of short-term complications after rotator cuff repair: open versus arthroscopic. Arthroscopy. 2018;34(4):1130-1136. doi: 10.1016/j.arthro.2017.10.027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2017.10.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29305290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doro MR, de Ara&#xfa;jo IP, Santana JO, et al. Has COVID-19 lowered physical activity practice while boosting online searches for professional exercise information? Eur J Transl Myol. 2023;33(2):11343. doi: 10.4081/ejtm.2023.11343</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/ejtm.2023.11343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10388599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37337783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dotson P. CPT&#xae; codes: what are they, why are they necessary, and how are they developed? Adv Wound Care (New Rochelle). 2013;2(10):583-587. doi: 10.1089/wound.2013.0483</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/wound.2013.0483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3865623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24761332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari D, Lopes TJA, Fran&#xe7;a PFA, Azevedo FM, Pappas E. Outpatient versus inpatient anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Knee. 2017;24(2):197-206. doi: 10.1016/j.knee.2017.01.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2017.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28117216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filbay SR, Grindem H. Evidence-based recommendations for the management of anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) rupture. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2019;33(1):33-47. doi: 10.1016/j.berh.2019.01.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.berh.2019.01.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6723618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31431274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghoshal S, Stovall N, King AH, Miller AS, Harris MB, Succi MD. Orthopedic surgery volume trends during the COVID-19 pandemic and postvaccination era: implications for healthcare planning. J Arthroplasty. 2024;39(8):1959-1966.e1. doi: 10.1016/j.arth.2024.03.028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arth.2024.03.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38513749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowd AK, Liu JN, Bohl DD, et al. Operative time as an independent and modifiable risk factor for short-term complications after knee arthroscopy. Arthroscopy. 2019;35(7):2089-2098. doi: 10.1016/j.arthro.2019.01.059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2019.01.059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31227396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanreich C, Boettner F, DeNegre S, Jungwirth-Weinberger A, Jerabek S. The impact of the COVID-19 associated shutdown on orthopedic patient care. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2022;143(6):2885-2892. doi: 10.1007/s00402-022-04466-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00402-022-04466-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9119384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35589981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horvath B, Kloesel B, Todd MM, Cole DJ, Prielipp RC. The evolution, current value, and future of the American Society of Anesthesiologists Physical Status classification system. Anesthesiology. 2021;135(5):904-919. doi: 10.1097/ALN.0000000000003947</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0000000000003947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34491303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khuri SF. The NSQIP: a new frontier in surgery. Surgery. 2005;138(5):837-843. doi: 10.1016/j.surg.2005.08.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surg.2005.08.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16291383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiani SN, Yellin JL, Houlihan NV, Talwar D, Shea KG, Ganley TJ. Trends in pediatric anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: the effect of COVID-19. J Athl Train. 2022;57(9-10):972-977. doi: 10.4085/1062-6050-0582.21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-0582.21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9842116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35271733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopka M, Fritz JA, Hiemstra LA, Kerslake S. Female and younger orthopaedic sport medicine patients are more negatively affected by COVID-19-related health care closures. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2021;3(5):e1329-e1335. doi: 10.1016/j.asmr.2021.06.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asmr.2021.06.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8264518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34254056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kranjac AW, Kranjac D. Explaining adult obesity, severe obesity, and BMI: five decades of change. Heliyon. 2023;9(5):e16210. doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e16210</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e16210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10213181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37251838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krywulak SA, Mohtadi NGH, Russell ML, Sasyniuk TM. Patient satisfaction with inpatient versus outpatient reconstruction of the anterior cruciate ligament: a randomized clinical trial. Can J Surg. 2005;48(3):201-206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3211553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16013623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunze KN, Fabricant PD, Marx RG, Nwachukwu BU. Perspectives on the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the sports medicine surgeon: implications for current and future care. Clin Sports Med. 2021;40(1):213-220. doi: 10.1016/j.csm.2020.08.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csm.2020.08.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7442913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33187611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mardinger C, Drover A, Hyndman E, et al. A novel computerized approach to scoping reviews using Synthesis software: the first 15 years of The American College of Surgeons National Surgical Quality Improvement Program. Can J Surg. 2023;66(2):e156-e161. doi: 10.1503/cjs.001722</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1503/cjs.001722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10069414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37001974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta A, Awuah WA, Ng JC, et al. Elective surgeries during and after the COVID-19 pandemic: case burden and physician shortage concerns. Ann Med Surg (Lond). 2022;81:104395. doi: 10.1016/j.amsu.2022.104395</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amsu.2022.104395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35999832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meza R, Cao P, Jeon J, Warner KE, Levy DT. Trends in US adult smoking prevalence, 2011 to 2022. JAMA Health Forum. 2023;4(12):e234213. doi: 10.1001/jamahealthforum.2023.4213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamahealthforum.2023.4213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10692849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38038988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moverman MA, Puzzitiello RN, Pagani NR, Barnes CL, Jawa A, Menendez ME. Public perceptions of resuming elective surgery during the COVID-19 pandemic. J Arthroplasty. 2021;36(2):397-402.e2. doi: 10.1016/j.arth.2020.07.037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arth.2020.07.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7369592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32807565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neupane S, Florkowski WJ, Dhakal C. Trends and disparities in diabetes prevalence in the United States from 2012 to 2022. Am J Prev Med. 2024;67(2):299-302. doi: 10.1016/j.amepre.2024.04.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2024.04.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38648908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peebles LA, Aman ZS, Kraeutler MJ, Mulcahey MK. Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on sports medicine patient care. Arthroscopy. 2023;39(2):161-165. doi: 10.1016/j.arthro.2022.11.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2022.11.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9636596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36347417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raval MV, Pawlik TM. Practical guide to surgical data sets: National Surgical Quality Improvement Program (NSQIP) and pediatric NSQIP. JAMA Surgery. 2018;153(8):764-765. doi: 10.1001/jamasurg.2018.0486</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamasurg.2018.0486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29617521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraswathula A, Shippey E, Sprankle LA, et al. Comparison of subspecialty major surgical volume in the United States during the COVID-19 pandemic. Laryngoscope. 2022;132(11):2139-2141. doi: 10.1002/lary.30066</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/lary.30066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9088461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35147217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiloach M, Frencher SK, Steeger JE, et al. Toward robust information: data quality and inter-rater reliability in the American College of Surgeons National Surgical Quality Improvement Program. J Am Coll Surg. 2010;210(1):6-16. doi: 10.1016/j.jamcollsurg.2009.09.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jamcollsurg.2009.09.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20123325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasan RC, Elhassan BT, Wright TW. Rotator cuff repair and reconstruction. J Hand Surg. 2021;46(6):493-500. doi: 10.1016/j.jhsa.2021.02.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhsa.2021.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsui GO, Kunac A, Oliver JB, Mehra S, Anjaria DJ. Did residents stop operating during COVID? Impact of COVID-19 across VA teaching hospitals on surgical resident education. Am Surg. 2024;90(5):1015-1022. doi: 10.1177/00031348231220598</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00031348231220598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38059816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasta S, Papalia R, Albo E, Maffulli N, Denaro V. Top orthopedic sports medicine procedures. J Orthop Surg Res. 2018;13(1):190. doi: 10.1186/s13018-018-0889-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-018-0889-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6069744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30064451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif JA, Farooq A, Krug I, et al. Training during the COVID-19 lockdown: knowledge, beliefs, and practices of 12,526 athletes from 142 countries and six continents. Sports Med. 2022;52(4):933-948. doi: 10.1007/s40279-021-01573-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01573-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8536915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34687439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Schwartz AM, Farley KX, Roberson JR, Bradbury TL, Guild GN. Quantifying the backlog of total hip and knee arthroplasty cases: predicting the impact of COVID-19. HSS J. 2020;16(suppl 1):85-91. doi: 10.1007/s11420-020-09806-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11420-020-09806-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7640577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33169071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>