<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41694952</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Carotid Endarterectomy With Stent Explantation for In-Stent Restenosis in Two Patients and Review of the Literature.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e101321</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e101321</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e101321</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.101321</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Carotid artery stenting (CAS) is a well-established alternative to carotid endarterectomy (CEA) for the treatment of carotid artery stenosis, particularly in patients at high surgical risk. However, in-stent restenosis (ISR) remains a notable long-term complication, occurring in up to 20% of patients within five years. The optimal management strategy for ISR&#xa0;remains unclear, as endovascular reintervention carries a significant risk of recurrence, and evidence supporting surgical explantation is limited. We present two patients who developed severe carotid ISR and were successfully treated with CEA and complete stent explantation followed by bovine pericardial patch angioplasty. The first patient, an 84-year-old woman with bilateral carotid disease and a history of left carotid stenting, developed 90% restenosis at surveillance and underwent staged bilateral carotid revascularization with durable patency at three-year follow-up. The second patient, a 70-year-old man, presented with acute visual loss and imaging demonstrating near-occlusive thrombosis within a previously placed carotid stent. He underwent urgent surgical stent removal and patch angioplasty, achieving full recovery and maintaining patency at one year. Neither patient experienced perioperative neurological or cardiovascular complications. These cases highlight the feasibility and safety of surgical stent explantation in the management of carotid ISR. Compared with repeat endovascular interventions, surgical removal directly addresses the underlying mechanical and neointimal causes of restenosis and may provide superior long-term durability in appropriately selected patients. CEA with stent explantation represents an effective treatment option for ISR, particularly when endovascular options are limited by calcification, thrombus, or mechanical failure. Larger prospective studies are needed to establish patient selection criteria and optimize management strategies for this challenging clinical scenario.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Alchaer et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alchaer</LastName><ForeName>Michael W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Surgery, HCA Healthcare/University of South Florida (USF) Morsani College of Medicine Graduate Medical Education (GME) HCA Florida Brandon Hospital, Brandon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gorran</LastName><ForeName>Harrison</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Surgery, HCA Healthcare/University of South Florida (USF) Morsani College of Medicine Graduate Medical Education (GME) HCA Florida Brandon Hospital, Brandon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alchaer</LastName><ForeName>Anthony W</ForeName><Initials>AW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, University of Kansas School of Medicine-Wichita, Wichita, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abbruzzese</LastName><ForeName>Thomas A</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Surgery, HCA Healthcare/University of South Florida (USF) Morsani College of Medicine Graduate Medical Education (GME) HCA Florida Brandon Hospital, Brandon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carotid artery stenosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carotid endarterectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">in-stent restenosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patch angioplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stent explantation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. HCA Healthcare Institutional Review Board issued approval N/A. This case report was reviewed in accordance with HCA Healthcare policy and determined to be exempt from Institutional Review Board oversight. The HCA Healthcare Institutional Review Board has confirmed that single-patient case reports do not meet the definition of human subjects research and therefore do not require IRB approval, provided all patient identifiers are removed. Written informed consent for publication of this case and accompanying images was obtained from the patient. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41694952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12894099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.101321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Restenosis after carotid artery stenting and endarterectomy: a secondary analysis of CREST, a randomised controlled trial. Lal BK, Beach KW, Roubin GS, et al. Lancet Neurol. 2012;11:755&#x2013;763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3912998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22857850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Restenosis is more frequent after carotid stenting than after endarterectomy: the EVA-3S study. Arquizan C, Trinquart L, Touboul PJ, et al. Stroke. 2011;42:1015&#x2013;1020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21311065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Restenosis and risk of stroke after stenting or endarterectomy for symptomatic carotid stenosis in the International Carotid Stenting Study (ICSS): secondary analysis of a randomised trial. Bonati LH, Gregson J, Dobson J, et al. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17:587&#x2013;596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6004555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29861139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treatment of the carotid in-stent restenosis: a systematic review. Huang H, Wu L, Guo Y, Zhang Y, Zhao J, Yu Z, Luo X. Front Neurol. 2021;12:748304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8521022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34671314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The management of carotid restenosis: a comprehensive review. Stilo F, Montelione N, Calandrelli R, Distefano M, Spinelli F, Di Lazzaro V, Pilato F. Ann Transl Med. 2020;8:1272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7607074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33178804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Editor's choice-European Society for Vascular Surgery (ESVS) 2023 clinical practice guidelines on the management of atherosclerotic carotid and vertebral artery disease. Naylor R, Rantner B, Ancetti S, et al. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2023;65:7&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35598721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenting versus endarterectomy for treatment of carotid-artery stenosis. Brott TG, Hobson RW 2nd, Howard G, et al. N Engl J Med. 2010;363:11&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2932446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20505173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Predictors of restenosis following carotid angioplasty and stenting. Zapata-Arriaza E, Moniche F, Gonz&#xe1;lez A, et al. Stroke. 2016;47:2144&#x2013;2147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27328701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In stent restenosis predictors after carotid artery stenting. Cosottini M, Michelassi MC, Bencivelli W, et al. Stroke Res Treat. 2010;2010:864724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2925310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20798894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carotid endarterectomy for treatment of in-stent restenosis after carotid angioplasty and stenting. Reichmann BL, van Laanen JH, de Vries JP, Hendriks JM, Verhagen HJ, Moll FL, de Borst GJ. J Vasc Surg. 2011;54:87&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21315546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carotid endarterectomy for acute carotid thrombosis after carotid artery stenting with CASPER Rx&#xae; stent: a case report. Segawa M, Inoue T, Tsunoda S, Kanamaru T, Okubo S. Surg Neurol Int. 2023;14:25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9990767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36895231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carotid endarterectomy with stent removal for recurring in-stent restenosis: a case report and literature review. Takahashi Y, Higashida T, Uchida T, Watanabe S, Kanazawa R. Surg Neurol Int. 2022;13:192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9168307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35673638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>