<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41646551</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An Unusual Cause of Buttock Pain in a Collegiate Football Player: A Septic Sacroiliac Joint.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e100835</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e100835</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e100835</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.100835</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Early recognition of sacroiliac (SI) joint infection can be challenging in young, otherwise healthy individuals presenting with nonspecific buttock or thigh pain. We present the case of a 21-year-old collegiate football player who developed progressive buttock and thigh pain after a minor fall during practice. Initial evaluation suggested sciatic nerve compression, and early MRI revealed only subtle soft tissue edema. Despite conservative treatment and a nerve block, his pain acutely worsened, and he developed fever and chills. Repeat MRI five days later demonstrated a fluid collection consistent with septic sacroiliitis and abscess formation, with additional findings of iliopsoas and gluteal myositis. Blood cultures and CT-guided aspiration confirmed methicillin-sensitive <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> (MSSA). The patient was treated with intravenous nafcillin for four weeks via peripherally inserted central catheter (PICC) line following a nine-day hospital admission. He made a full recovery and started a slow return to play back into collegiate football three months after admission. This case highlights the diagnostic challenge of septic sacroiliitis in young athletes, the importance of repeat MRI when symptoms progress, and the favorable prognosis when prompt, culture-directed antibiotic therapy is initiated.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Guin et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guin</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moran</LastName><ForeName>Ryan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Athletic Training, University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bentley</LastName><ForeName>Brett C</ForeName><Initials>BC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">college sports</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">football injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">primary care sports medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sacroiliac infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">septic sacroiliitis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41646551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12871442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.100835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Infectious sacroiliitis: MRI- and CT-based assessment of disease extent, complications, and anatomic correlation. Interligator S, Le Bozec A, Cluzel G, et al. Skeletal Radiol. 2024;53:2247&#x2013;2262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38110777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Septic arthritis of the sacroiliac joint. Woytala PJ, Sebastian A, B&#x142;ach K, Silicki J, Wiland P. Reumatologia. 2018;56:55&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5911659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29686444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Infectious sacroiliitis: a retrospective, multicentre study of 39 adults. Hermet M, Minichiello E, Flipo RM, et al. BMC Infect Dis. 2012;12:305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3519695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23153120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pregnancy-associated sacroiliitis following an uncomplicated pregnancy. Ahmadi M, Abiri F, Ahmadiani S, Jenabi E. Case Rep Med. 2022;2022:3596672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9095408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35573053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severe onset of acute infectious sacroiliitis masquerading as musculoskeletal dysfunction: a case report. Hannah MC, Dennis DL, Stephenson M. JOSPT Cases. 2022;2:112&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The utility of diffusion weighted MRI imaging in diagnosing a challenging case of de novo septic sacroiliitis. Joglekar SB, Reddy P, Reddy S, et al.  https://journalonsurgery-org.meddocsonline.org/articles/js-v3-1122.html J Surg. 2023;3:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of instability following pyogenic sacroiliitis: technical case report. Passaplan C, Simonin A, Maestretti G, Gautier E. Case Rep Orthop. 2020;2020:3409306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7066396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32181037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serratia sacroiliitis secondary to intravenous drug use: a case report. Delgadillo BE, Buchman ZJ, Webber K, Federico JR. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11419597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39314578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>