<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41749133</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2393</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC pregnancy and childbirth</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lived experiences of first-time mothers receiving postpartum social support at Banadir Hospital, Mogadishu, Somalia: a phenomenological qualitative study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">367</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12884-026-08875-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The postpartum period is crucial for maternal and newborn health but remains a high-risk phase in low-resource settings like Somalia, where psychosocial support is often lacking. Social support (including practical help), emotional care, and health education are essential for recovery and well-being. Despite Somalia&#x2019;s high maternal mortality, little research has focused on first-time mothers&#x2019; experiences. This study explored their experiences of postpartum support at Banadir Hospital in Mogadishu.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">An exploratory phenomenological design guided this study. Data was collected through 16 individual interviews, two focus group discussions (12 participants), and 10 key informant interviews with healthcare workers, totaling 38 participants. Purposive sampling ensured the selection of participants with relevant experiences, and data saturation determined the final sample size. Interviews were conducted in Somali, audio-recorded with consent, and transcribed verbatim. Inductive thematic content analysis was performed using NVivo 11. Methodological rigor was maintained through triangulation, member checking, reflexive journaling, peer debriefing, and a comprehensive audit trail.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Three major themes emerged that reflected the postpartum social support experiences of first-time mothers. They received initial physical support primarily from family members, including mothers, mothers-in-law, and spouses. However, this assistance was limited and diminished significantly after the first month due to financial constraints and competing responsibilities. Emotional support was insufficient and primarily provided by healthcare workers rather than family, reflecting limited awareness of postpartum mental health needs and signs of depression. Informational support was critically inadequate, with mothers reporting unmet needs for structured guidance on newborn care, infant danger signs, and maternal health; they relied predominantly on informal sources, including family and neighbors, who often provided conflicting or inaccurate information. Overall, although postpartum support mechanisms exist, they are fragmented, inconsistent, and insufficient to meet first-time mothers&#x2019; holistic physical, emotional, and informational needs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The study highlights the urgent need for policy action to enhance postpartum care systems. This includes workforce capacity building and structured follow-up in fragile settings like Somalia. Strengthening postpartum social support through trained health workers, family engagement, and peer programs can improve maternal and neonatal outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12884-026-08875-y.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ibrahim</LastName><ForeName>Abdullahi Abdiasis</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Clarke International University, P.O. BOX 7782, Kampala, Uganda. abdullahiabdiasis11@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Bosaso, Puntland, Somalia. abdullahiabdiasis11@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Githinji</LastName><ForeName>Florence</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quality Assurance Department, Clarke International University, P.O. BOX 7782, Kampala, Uganda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ndagire</LastName><ForeName>Regina</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Postgraduate Studies Research and Innovations, Clarke International University, P.O. BOX 7782, Kampala, Uganda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Namwanje</LastName><ForeName>Angela</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Business and Applied Technology, Clarke International University, P.O. BOX 7782, Kampala, Uganda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ssenyondo</LastName><ForeName>Aaron</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Postgraduate Studies Research and Innovations, Clarke International University, P.O. BOX 7782, Kampala, Uganda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agwang</LastName><ForeName>Agnes</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Clarke International University, P.O. BOX 7782, Kampala, Uganda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nampiima</LastName><ForeName>Chloe</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Postgraduate Studies Research and Innovations, Clarke International University, P.O. BOX 7782, Kampala, Uganda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Atim</LastName><ForeName>Fiona</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Clarke International University, P.O. BOX 7782, Kampala, Uganda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Postgraduate Studies Research and Innovations, Clarke International University, P.O. BOX 7782, Kampala, Uganda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967799</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2393</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Banadir Hospital</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">First-time mothers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postpartum care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Social support</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Somalia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical clearance was obtained from the Clarke International University Research and Ethics Committee (Reference: CIU-REC/025/2024) prior to data collection. This study complied with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Written informed consent was obtained from all 38 participants before they participated in interviews or focus-group discussions. Confidentiality was maintained through anonymization of transcripts using coded identifiers and secure storage of all data. Consent for publication: All participants provided explicit informed consent for the publication of anonymized quotations and findings derived from the study. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41749133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13040759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-026-08875-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12884-026-08875-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wojcieszek AM, Bonet M, Portela A, Althabe F, Bahl R, Chowdhary N, et al. WHO recommendations on maternal and newborn care for a positive postnatal experience: strengthening the maternal and newborn care continuum. BMJ Glob Health. 2023;8:e010992. 10.1136/bmjgh-2022-010992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2022-010992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9887708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36717156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos Alves DF, da Silva SO, Ullman A, de Maia F. Effectiveness of checklists in multidisciplinary rounds for improving patient safety in the pediatric intensive care unit: a systematic review protocol. JBI Evid Synth. 2022;20:1835&#x2013;41. 10.11124/JBIES-21-00180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11124/JBIES-21-00180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35689174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO, Maternal mortality. WHO. 2025. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/maternal-mortality. Accessed 06 Sep 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dol J, Hughes B, Bonet M, Dorey R, Dorling J, Grant A, et al. Timing of maternal mortality and severe morbidity during the postpartum period: a systematic review. JBI Evid Synth. 2022;20:2119&#x2013;94. 10.11124/JBIES-20-00578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11124/JBIES-20-00578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9594153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35916004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bianchi DW, Clayton JA, Zenk SN. Addressing the Public Health Crisis of Maternal Mortality. JAMA. 2023;330:1729. 10.1001/jama.2023.21294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2023.21294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11742278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37831443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nweke M, Ukwuoma M, Adiuku-Brown AC, Okemuo AJ, Ugwu PI, Nseka E. Burden of postpartum depression in sub-Saharan Africa: An updated systematic review. S Afr J Sci. 2024;120. 10.17159/sajs.2024/14197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nweke M, Ukwuoma M, Adiuku-Brown AC, Ugwu P, Nseka E. Characterization and stratification of the correlates of postpartum depression in sub-Saharan Africa: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Women&#x2019;s Health. 2022;18. 10.1177/17455057221118773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9434669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36039898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pope CJ, Mazmanian D. Breastfeeding and Postpartum Depression: An Overview and Methodological Recommendations for Future Research. Depress Res Treat. 2016;2016:1&#x2013;9. 10.1155/2016/4765310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/4765310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4842365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27148457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Sousa Machado T, Chur-Hansen A, Due C. First-time mothers&#x2019; perceptions of social support: Recommendations for best practice. Health Psychol Open. 2020;7. 10.1177/2055102919898611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7008558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32095254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White LK, Kornfield SL, Himes MM, Forkpa M, Waller R, Njoroge WFM, et al. The impact of postpartum social support on postpartum mental health outcomes during the COVID-19 pandemic. Arch Womens Ment Health. 2023;26:531&#x2013;41. 10.1007/s00737-023-01330-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00737-023-01330-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10238239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37268777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schobinger E, Vanetti M, Ramelet A-S, Horsch A. Social support needs of first-time parents in the early-postpartum period: A qualitative study. Front Psychiatry. 2022;13. 10.3389/fpsyt.2022.1043990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9794858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36590631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLeish J, Harvey M, Redshaw M, Alderdice F. A qualitative study of first time mothers&#x2019; experiences of postnatal social support from health professionals in England. Women Birth. 2021;34:e451&#x2013;60. 10.1016/j.wombi.2020.10.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wombi.2020.10.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8396053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33153952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcpherson L. First-time Parent Experiences of Social Support in the Early Postpartum Period: A Couple&#x2019;s Perspective. 2014. https://mspace.lib.umanitoba.ca/server/api/core/bitstreams/4dfd0bca-f02b-4003-873a-17a2c83f4071/content. Accessed 26 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogale B, Scambler S, Mohd Khairuddin AN, Gallagher JE. Health system strengthening in fragile and conflict-affected states: A review of systematic reviews. PLoS ONE. 2024;19:e0305234. 10.1371/journal.pone.0305234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0305234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11178226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38875266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truppa C, Yaacoub S, Valente M, Celentano G, Ragazzoni L, Saulnier D. Health systems resilience in fragile and conflict-affected settings: a systematic scoping review. Confl Health. 2024;18:2. 10.1186/s13031-023-00560-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13031-023-00560-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10763433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38172918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed AA, Ak&#x131;n A, Mihciokur S, &#xdc;ner S, Gele A. Level of completion of maternity continuum of care among ever-married women: An analysis of Somalia&#x2019;s health and demographic survey 2020. PLOS Global Public Health. 2025;5:e0004102. 10.1371/journal.pgph.0004102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0004102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11723541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39792806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson AJ, Buchan J, Duffield C, Homer CSE, Wijewardena K. Task shifting and sharing in maternal and reproductive health in low-income countries: a narrative synthesis of current evidence. Health Policy Plan. 2014;29:396&#x2013;408. 10.1093/heapol/czt026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapol/czt026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23656700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okoroafor SC, Christmals C, Dela. Task Shifting and Task Sharing Implementation in Africa: A Scoping Review on Rationale and Scope. Healthcare. 2023;11:1200. 10.3390/healthcare11081200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11081200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10138489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37108033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison J, Malik SMMR. Health equity in Somalia? An evaluation of the progress made from 2006 to 2019 in reducing inequities in maternal and newborn health. Int J Equity Health. 2024;23:46. 10.1186/s12939-023-02092-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12939-023-02092-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10916226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38443921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodgson JE, Phenomenology. Researching the lived experience. J Hum Lactation. 2023;39(3):385&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08903344231176453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37278304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naeem M, Ozuem W, Howell K, Ranfagni S. A step-by-step process of thematic analysis to develop a conceptual model in qualitative research. Int J qualitative methods. 2023;22:16094069231205789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/16094069231205789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swain J. A hybrid approach to thematic analysis in qualitative research: Using a practical example. Sage Res methods. 2018 Jan 12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ababneh AMT, Alrida N, Abu-Abbas M, Rayan A, Abu Sumaqa Y, Alhamory S, et al. The Lived Experience of Family Support Among Women During and After Childbirth in Jordan: A Phenomenological Study. SAGE Open Nurs. 2024;10. 10.1177/23779608241240137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10956139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38515526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali Abdulai M, Adhikary P, Baumann SG, Ejaz M, Priya JO, Spelke MB, et al. How maternal morbidities impact women&#x2019;s quality of life during pregnancy and postpartum in sub-Saharan Africa and South Asia: A qualitative study. PLOS Global Public Health. 2025;5:e0004229. 10.1371/journal.pgph.0004229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0004229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12425202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40934181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tessema M, Abera M, Birhanu Z. Improving postnatal social support using antenatal group-based psychoeducation: a cluster randomized controlled trial. Front Glob Womens Health 2025;6. 10.3389/fgwh.2025.1510725</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11986638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40225206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Place JMS, Renbarger K, Van De Griend K, Guinn M, Wheatley C, Holmes O. Barriers to help-seeking for postpartum depression mapped onto the socio-ecological model and recommendations to address barriers. Front Glob Womens Health 2024;5. 10.3389/fgwh.2024.1335437</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11157017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38855482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangdang A, Phahuwatanakorn W, Limruangrong P. Factors Influencing Maternal Health Literacy in Postpartum Women. Int J Womens Health 2025;Volume 17:1103&#x2013;14. 10.2147/IJWH.S511322</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12024475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40291153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Time to act-Making motherhood and childhood safer in Somalia Policy brief 2023. http://emro.who.int/images/stories/somalia/RMNCAH-Policy-Brief-August-2023.pdf. Accessed 26 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaup&#x161;ien&#x117; A, Vainauskait&#x117; A, Baglajeva J, Stukas R, Rama&#x161;auskait&#x117; D, Paliulyt&#x117; V, et al. Associations between maternal health literacy, neonatal health and breastfeeding outcomes in the early postpartum period. Eur J Midwifery. 2023;7:1&#x2013;6. 10.18332/ejm/170161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18332/ejm/170161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10546471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37794862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habte A, Tamene A, Tesfaye L. Towards a positive postnatal experience in Sub-Saharan African countries: the receipt of adequate services during the immediate postpartum period: a multilevel analysis. Front Public Health. 2023;11. 10.3389/fpubh.2023.1272888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10753759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38155886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien J, Gregg L, Wittkowski A. A systematic review of clinical psychological guidance for perinatal mental health. BMC Psychiatry. 2023;23:790. 10.1186/s12888-023-05173-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-023-05173-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10614401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37904101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oladeji BD, Ayinde OO, Bello T, Kola L, Faregh N, Abdulmalik J, et al. Cascade training for scaling up care for perinatal depression in primary care in Nigeria. Int J Ment Health Syst. 2023;17:41. 10.1186/s13033-023-00607-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13033-023-00607-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10658820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37986025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Song B, Zhang Q, Qi W, Xu Y. Hsa_circ_0022383 promote non-small cell lung cancer tumorigenesis through regulating the miR-495-3p/KPNA2 axis. Cancer Cell Int. 2023;23:282. 10.1186/s12935-023-03068-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12935-023-03068-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10658815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37981709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sebela A, Horakova A, Nemcova H, Kuklova M, Noskova E, Svancer P, et al. Mom Supporting Mom: Effective Peer Support Intervention for Women with Postpartum Psychological Distress. Psychosocial Intervention. 2025;34:151&#x2013;60. 10.5093/pi2025a12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5093/pi2025a12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12322603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40765646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Time to act-Making motherhood and childhood safer in Somalia Policy brief 2023. https://www.emro.who.int/images/stories/somalia/RMNCAH-Policy-Brief-August-2023.pdf. Accessed 06 Sep 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kay TL, Moulson MC, Vigod SN, Schoueri-Mychasiw N, Singla DR. The Role of Social Support in Perinatal Mental Health and Psychosocial Stimulation. Yale J Biol Med. 2024;97:3&#x2013;16. 10.59249/WMGE9032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.59249/WMGE9032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10964812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38559463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilavuz M, Topalo&#x11f;lu S. Psychosocial and maternal care needs of recently delivered women during the postpartum period. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2025;25:874. 10.1186/s12884-025-07982-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-025-07982-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12369193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40841625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdi YH, Abdullahi YB, Abdi MS, Bashir SG, Ahmed NI, Alin AO, et al. Antenatal Care Utilization in Somalia, 2020 Somalia Demographic Health Survey. J Epidemiol Glob Health. 2025;15:126. 10.1007/s44197-025-00475-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44197-025-00475-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12537624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41114755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLeish J, McCourt C, Ayers S. A realist change model for community-based perinatal mental health peer support from peer volunteers. J Reprod Infant Psychol 2024:1&#x2013;22. 10.1080/02646838.2024.2416448</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39450897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>