<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41645992</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2583-150X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Season>Jan-Feb</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The National medical journal of India</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Natl Med J India</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical spectrum and intermediate outcomes of community and hospital-acquired acute kidney injury: A single centre study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23</StartPage><EndPage>29</EndPage><MedlinePgn>23-29</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.25259/NMJI_295_2023</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10.25259/NMJI_295_2023</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background There is minimal literature on the spectrum and long-term outcomes of acute kidney injury (AKI) from tropical countries. Methods Patients with AKI without underlying chronic kidney disease (CKD), were recruited from March 2017 to December 2018 to assess their outcomes. Survivors were followed for a year post-discharge. A linear model with fixed effects was created to compare the estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) trajectories of patients with and without CKD at the end of follow-up. Results A total of 529 patients with AKI were recruited, of which 288 (54.4%) were hospital-acquired AKI. Infections and sepsis were the most common aetiologies for community-acquired AKI and hospital-acquired AKI. The overall mortality rate was 42.9% (n=227). The ICU stay (HR 1.78; 95% CI 1.08-2.93), mechanical ventilation (HR 1.98; 95% CI 1.09-3.54), and the requirement for inotropic support (HR 2.36; 95% CI 1.65-3.39) were independent risk factors of in-hospital mortality. Among 156 subjects with long-term follow-up, 70 (44.9%) developed CKD after a median follow-up of 12 months. Age (p&lt;0.001) and hospital-acquired AKI (p=0.014) were significant predictors, whereas ICU stay and comorbid conditions did not influence the GFR trajectories. CKD patients showed a lower eGFR from the first follow-up (p&lt;0.001). Conclusions AKI is associated with significant mortality. Even after an apparent recovery, around half the survivors progress to CKD at the end of 1 year.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mattewada</LastName><ForeName>Naveen Kumar</ForeName><Initials>NK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Jawaharlal Institute of Postgraduate Medical Education and Research (JIPMER), Puducherry 605006, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Puthiyottil</LastName><ForeName>Dhanin</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Jawaharlal Institute of Postgraduate Medical Education and Research (JIPMER), Puducherry 605006, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parameswaran</LastName><ForeName>Sreejith</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Jawaharlal Institute of Postgraduate Medical Education and Research (JIPMER), Puducherry 605006, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Priyamvada</LastName><ForeName>P S</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Jawaharlal Institute of Postgraduate Medical Education and Research (JIPMER), Puducherry 605006, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Natl Med J India</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8809315</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0970-258X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058186" MajorTopicYN="Y">Acute Kidney Injury</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017052" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospital Mortality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005919" MajorTopicYN="N">Glomerular Filtration Rate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051436" MajorTopicYN="Y">Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007902" MajorTopicYN="N">Length of Stay</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007362" MajorTopicYN="N">Intensive Care Units</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007194" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">India</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012121" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiration, Artificial</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018805" MajorTopicYN="N">Sepsis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41645992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25259/NMJI_295_2023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.25259/NMJI_295_2023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title/><Reference><Citation>Burdmann EA, Jha V,. Acute kidney injury due to tropical infectious diseases and animal venoms: A tale of two continents. Kidney Int. 2017; 91:1033-46</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerd&#xe1; J, Bagga A, Kher V, Chakravarthi RM,. The contrasting characteristics of acute kidney injury in developed and developing countries. Nat Clin Pract Nephrol. 2008; 4:138-53</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta RL, Cerd&#xe1; J, Burdmann EA, Tonelli M, Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a G, Jha V, et al. International Society of Nephrology's Oby25 initiative for acute kidney injury (zero preventable deaths by 2025): A human rights case for nephrology. Lancet. 2015; 385:2616-43</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoste EAJ, Kellum JA, Selby NM, Zarbock A, Palevsky PM, Bagshaw SM, et al. Global epidemiology and outcomes of acute kidney injury. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2018; 14:607-25</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakash J, Singh TB, Ghosh B, Malhotra V, Rathore SS, Vohra R, et al. Changing epidemiology of community-acquired acute kidney injury in developing countries: Analysis of 2405 cases in 26 years from eastern India. Clin Kidney J. 2013; 6: 150-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohli HS, Bhat A, Jairam A, Aravindan AN, Sud K, Jha V, et al. Predictors of mortality in acute renal failure in a developing country: A prospective study. Ren Fail. 2007; 29:463-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S, Raina S, Vikrant S, Patial RK,. Spectrum of acute kidney injury in the Himalayan region. Indian J Nephrol. 2012; 22:363-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anandh U, Renuka S, Somiah S, Vincent L,. Acute renal failure in the tropics: Emerging trends from a tertiary care hospital in South India. Clin Nephrol. 2003; 59: 341-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayakumar M, Prabahar MR, Fernando EM, Manorajan R, Venkatraman R, Balaraman V,. Epidemiologic trend changes in acute renal failure-a tertiary center experience from South India. Ren Fail. 2006; 28:405-10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikrant S, Gupta D, Singh M,. Epidemiology and outcome of acute kidney injury from a tertiary care hospital in India. Saudi J Kidney Dis Transpl. 2018; 29: 956-66</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer M, Deutschman CS, Seymour CW, Shankar-Hari M, Annane D, Bauer M, et al. The Third International Consensus Definitions for Sepsis and Septic Shock (Sepsis-3). JAMA. 2016; 315:801-10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raji YR, Ajayi SO, Ademola AF, Lawal TA, Ayandipo OO, Adigun T, et al. Acute kidney injury among adult patients undergoing major surgery in a tertiary hospital in Nigeria. Clin Kidney J. 2018; 11:443-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vairakkani R, Fernando M, Sujith S,. Acute kidney injury in a tertiary care center of South India. Indian J Nephrol. 2022; 32:206-15</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakash J, Ganiger VC,. Acute kidney injury in pregnancy-specific disorders. Indian J Nephrol. 2017; 27:258-70</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakash J, Prakash S, Ganiger VC,. Changing epidemiology of acute kidney injury in pregnancy: A journey of four decades from a developing country. Saudi J Kidney Dis Transpl. 2019; 30:1118-30</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goswami S, Raju BM, Purohit A, Pahwa N,. Clinical spectrum of community-acquired acute kidney injury: A prospective study from central India. Saudi J Kidney Dis Transpl. 2020; 31:224-34</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher EF, Silva Junior GB, Santos SQ, Bezerra CCR, Diniz EJB, Lima RSA, et al. Differences in community, hospital and intensive care unit-acquired acute kidney injury: Observational study in a nephrology service of a developing country. Clin Nephrol. 2012; 78:449-55</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priyamvada P, Jayasurya R, Shankar V, Parameswaran S,. Epidemiology and outcomes of acute kidney injury in critically ill: Experience from a tertiary care center. Indian J Nephrol. 2018; 28:413-19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eswarappa M, Gireesh MS, Ravi V, Kumar D, Dev G,. Spectrum of acute kidney injury in critically ill patients: A single center study from South India. Indian J Nephrol. 2014; 24:280-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandiraseharan V, Kalimuthu M, Prakash T, George T, Rajenesh A, Jayaseelan V, et al. Acute kidney injury is an independent predictor of in-hospital mortality in a general medical ward: A retrospective study from a tertiary care centre in South India. Indian J Med Res. 2020; 152:386-92</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Patel PS, Doley PK, Sharma SS, Iqbal M, Agarwal A, et al. Outcomes of hospital-acquired acute kidney injury in elderly patients: A single-centre study. Int Urol Nephrol. 2019; 51:875-83</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goswami S, Pahwa N, Vohra R, Raju BM,. Clinical spectrum of hospital acquired acute kidney injury: A prospective study from Central India. Saudi J Kidney Dis Transpl. 2018; 29:946-55</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wonnacott A, Meran S, Amphlett B, Talabani B, Phillips A,. Epidemiology and outcomes in community-acquired versus hospital-acquired AKI. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2014; 9:1007-14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schissler MM, Zaidi S, Kumar H, Deo D, Brier ME, McLeish KR,. Characteristics and outcomes in community-acquired versus hospital-acquired acute kidney injury. Nephrology (Carlton). 2013; 18:183-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Xue C, Kuai J, Ruan M, Yang B, Chen X, et al. Clinical characteristics and outcomes of community-acquired versus hospital-acquired acute kidney injury: A meta-analysis. Kidney Blood Press Res. 2019; 44:879-96</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue C, Zhou C, Xu J,. Differences in characteristics and outcomes between community-and hospital-acquired acute kidney injury: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Nephrol. 2017; 88:299-300</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duran PA, Concepcion LA,. Survival after acute kidney injury requiring dialysis: Long-term follow up. Hemodial Int. 2014; 18:(Suppl 1)S1-S6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver SA, Harel Z, McArthur E, Nash DM, Acedillo R, Kitchlu A, et al. Causes of death after a hospitalisation with AKI. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2018; 29:1001-10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher M, Cass A, Bellomo R, Finfer S, Gattas D, Lee J, et al. Long-term survival and dialysis dependency following acute kidney injury in intensive care: Extended follow-up of a randomised controlled trial. PLoS Med. 2014; 11:e1001601</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira MB, Zanetta DMT, Abdulkader RCRM,. The real importance of pre-existing comorbidities on long-term mortality after acute kidney injury. PLoS One. 2012; 7:e47746</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>See EJ, Jayasinghe K, Glassford N, Bailey M, Johnson DW, Polkinghorne KR, et al. Long-term risk of adverse outcomes after acute kidney injury: A systematic review and meta-analysis of cohort studies using consensus definitions of exposure. Kidney Int. 2019; 95:160-72</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coca SG, Singanamala S, Parikh CR,. Chronic kidney disease after acute kidney injury: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Kidney Int. 2012; 81:442-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priyamvada PS, Jaswanth C, Zachariah B, Haridasan S, Parameswaran S, Swaminathan RP,. Prognosis and long-term outcomes of acute kidney injury due to snake envenomation. Clin Kidney J. 2020; 13:564-70</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herath NJ, Kularatne SAM, Weerakoon KGAD, Wazil A, Subasinghe N, Ratnatunga NV,. Long term outcome of acute kidney injury due to leptospirosis: A longitudinal study in Sri Lanka. BMC Res Notes. 2014; 7:398</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffl H, Fischer R,. Clinical cause of presumed acute tubular necrosis requiring renal replacement therapy and outcome of critically ill patients: Post hoc analysis of a prospective 7-year cohort study. Int Urol Nephrol. 2012; 44:1779-89</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatraju PK, Zelnick LR, Chinchilli VM, Moledina DG, Coca SG, Parikh CR, et al. Association between early recovery of kidney function after acute kidney injury and long-term clinical outcomes. JAMA Netw Open. 2020; 3:e202682</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siew ED, Abdel-Kader K, Perkins AM, Greevy RA, Parr SK, Horner J, et al. Timing of recovery from moderate to severe AKI and the risk for future loss of kidney function. Am J Kidney Dis. 2020; 75:204-13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawhney S, Marks A, Fluck N, Levin A, McLernon D, Prescott G, et al. Post-discharge kidney function is associated with subsequent ten-year renal progression risk among survivors of acute kidney injury. Kidney Int. 2017; 92:440-52</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parr SK, Matheny ME, Abdel-Kader K, Greevy RA, Bian A, Fly J, et al. Acute kidney injury is a risk factor for subsequent proteinuria. Kidney Int. 2018; 93: 460-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu CY, Chinchilli VM, Coca S, Devarajan P, Ghahramani N, Go AS, et al. Post-acute kidney injury proteinuria and subsequent kidney disease progression: The Assessment, Serial Evaluation, and Subsequent Sequelae in Acute Kidney Injury (ASSESS-AKI) Study. JAMA Intern Med. 2020; 180:402-10</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>