<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41733074</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Knee surgery, sports traumatology, arthroscopy : official journal of the ESSKA</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hamstring muscle strength recovery remains incomplete at 2 years after harvest for ACL reconstruction and does not correlate with radiological tendon regeneration at 6 months: A prospective study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ksa.70346</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim was to assess the effect of the degree of hamstring tendon regeneration on isometric flexion strength of the knee at short-term (6 months) and long-term (2 years) follow-up.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A prospective cohort study was conducted from January 2021 to December 2023 at our tertiary care centre, including 48 patients (mean age 27.69&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;9.48 years) who underwent anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction using hamstring autografts. Hamstring strength was measured by digital spring balance at 90&#xb0; knee flexion at 6 months and 2 years. A magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) was done at 6-month postoperative follow-up to assess tendon regeneration. Patients were grouped based on regeneration status: none, partial, or complete. Functional scores (Visual Analogue Scale [VAS], International Knee Documentation Committee [IKDC], Knee Injury and Osteoarthritis Outcome Score [KOOS], Lysholm Tegner) were evaluated preoperatively and 6 months postoperatively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At 6 months, 50% patients showed complete tendon regeneration, while 29.2% had no regeneration. Mean strength recovery did not significantly differ among regeneration groups (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.783). Patients with semitendinosus (ST) grafts had slightly higher strength recovery than those with ST&#x2009;+&#x2009;gracilis (G) grafts, though not significant (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.145). Functional outcomes were similar across graft types and regeneration status. At 2 years, significant improvement in hamstring strength was observed compared to 6 months with mean strength of 83.5% (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Tendon regeneration was frequently observed on MRI at 6 months, but knee flexion strength deficits were similar across regeneration groups and graft types. Strength recovery improved by 2 years but did not reach that of the contralateral limb, highlighting the need for ongoing rehabilitation focussed on hamstring strengthening.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level II, prospective comparative study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 European Society of Sports Traumatology, Knee Surgery and Arthroscopy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choudhary</LastName><ForeName>Aakash</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4669-6563</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), Jodhpur, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gahlot</LastName><ForeName>Nitesh</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7352-5228</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), Jodhpur, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Banerjee</LastName><ForeName>Sumit</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5067-2230</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), Jodhpur, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elhence</LastName><ForeName>Abhay</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9655-5806</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), Jodhpur, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khera</LastName><ForeName>Pushpinder</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9714-5462</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic and Interventional Radiology, All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS), Jodhpur, Rajasthan, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saxena</LastName><ForeName>Suvinay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3511-9303</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Interventional Radiology, Chirayu Medical College and Hospital, Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9314730</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0942-2056</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional outcome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hamstring muscles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hamstring regeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41733074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.70346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>&#xc5;hl&#xe9;n M, Lid&#xe9;n M, Bovaller &#xc5;, Sernert N, Kartus J. Bilateral magnetic resonance imaging and functional assessment of the semitendinosus and gracilis tendons a minimum of 6 years after ipsilateral harvest for anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40:1735&#x2013;1741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boden BP, Sheehan FT, Torg JS, Hewett TE. Noncontact anterior cruciate ligament injuries: mechanisms and risk factors. Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2010;18:520&#x2013;527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Danelon F, La Rosa G, Nanni G, Stride M, Della Villa F. Recommendations for hamstring function recovery after ACL reconstruction. Sports Med. 2021;51:607&#x2013;624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi JY, Ha JK, Kim YW, Shim JC, Yang SJ, Kim JG. Relationships among tendon regeneration on MRI, flexor strength, and functional performance after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with hamstring autograft. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40:152&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross MJ, Roger G, Kujawa P, Anderson IF. Regeneration of the semitendinosus and gracilis tendons following their transection for repair of the anterior cruciate ligament. Am J Sports Med. 1992;20:221&#x2013;223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhillon MS, Rajnish RK, Dhillon S, Kumar P. Is there significant regeneration of the hamstring tendons after harvest for ACL reconstruction? A systematic review of literature. J Clin Orthop Trauma. 2021;16:208&#x2013;218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmlinger BS, Nyland JA, Tillett ED. Knee flexor function 2 years after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with semitendinosus&#x2010;gracilis autografts. Arthroscopy. 2006;22:650&#x2013;655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan L, Zhang L, Tang J, Xu Z, Fu W. Comparison of clinical outcomes between hamstring tendon autografts and hybrid grafts in ACL reconstruction: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Orthop Surg Res. 2024;19:809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farshad M, Gerber C, Meyer DC, Schwab A, Blank PR, Szucs T. Reconstruction versus conservative treatment after rupture of the anterior cruciate ligament: cost effectiveness analysis. BMC Health Serv Res. 2011;11:317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao B, Zheng N. Alterations in three&#x2010;dimensional joint kinematics of anterior cruciate ligament&#x2010;deficient and &#x2010;reconstructed knees during walking. Clin Biomech. 2010;25:222&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindem H, Snyder&#x2010;Mackler L, Moksnes H, Engebretsen L, Risberg MA. Simple decision rules can reduce reinjury risk by 84% after ACL reconstruction: the Delaware&#x2010;Oslo ACL cohort study. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:804&#x2013;808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbawi F, Lozano&#x2010;Lozano M, Lopez&#x2010;Garzon M, Postigo&#x2010;Martin P, Ortiz&#x2010;Comino L, Martin&#x2010;Alguacil JL, et al. A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of strength recovery measured by isokinetic dynamometer technology after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction using quadriceps tendon autografts vs. hamstring tendon autografts or patellar tendon autografts. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:6764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J, Qu J, Xu D, Zhou J, Lu H. Allograft versus autograft for anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: an up&#x2010;to&#x2010;date meta&#x2010;analysis of prospective studies. Int Orthop. 2013;37:311&#x2013;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen RPA, van der Velden MJF, Pasmans HLM, Sala HAGM. Regeneration of hamstring tendons after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2013;21:898&#x2013;905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim WK, Kim DK, Seo KM, Kang SH. Reliability and validity of isometric knee extensor strength test with hand&#x2010;held dynamometer depending on its fixation: a pilot study. Ann Rehabil Med. 2014;38:84&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrath JM, Vertullo CJ, Kennedy BA, Bush HS, Barrett RS, Lloyd DG. Morphologic characteristics and strength of the hamstring muscles remain altered at 2 years after use of a hamstring tendon graft in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44:2589&#x2013;2598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutras G, Bernard M, Terzidis IP, Papadopoulos P, Georgoulis A, Pappas E. Comparison of knee flexion isokinetic deficits between seated and prone positions after ACL reconstruction with hamstrings graft: implications for rehabilitation and return to sports decisions. J Sci Med Sport. 2016;19:559&#x2013;562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maletis GB, Inacio MCS, Desmond JL, Funahashi TT. Reconstruction of the anterior cruciate ligament: association of graft choice with increased risk of early revision. Bone Joint J. 2013;95&#x2013;B:623&#x2013;628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesnard G, Fournier G, Cance N, Magnussen RA, Lustig S, Servien E. Isokinetic testing after anterior cruciate ligament injury showed a greater hamstrings/quadriceps ratio at 240&#xb0;/s over 6 months from injury but no difference of limb symmetry index. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2025;7:101063. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asmr.2024.101063</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikose SS, Nikose D, Jain S, Kekatpure A, Saoji K, Chaudhary R, et al. Determinants of regeneration and strength of hamstrings after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction&#x2010;fate of hamstring tendon. Int Orthop. 2021;45:1751&#x2013;1760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogborn DI, Bellemare A, Bruinooge B, Brown H, McRae S, Leiter J. Comparison of common methodologies for the determination of knee flexor muscle strength. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2021;16:350&#x2013;359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmieri&#x2010;Smith RM, Lepley LK. Quadriceps strength asymmetry after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction alters knee joint biomechanics and functional performance at time of return to activity. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43:1662&#x2013;1669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romanini E, D'Angelo F, De Masi S, Adriani E, Magaletti M, Lacorte E, et al. Graft selection in arthroscopic anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Traumatol. 2010;11:211&#x2013;219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snyder&#x2010;Mackler L, Delitto A, Bailey SL, Stralka SW. Strength of the quadriceps femoris muscle and functional recovery after reconstruction of the anterior cruciate ligament. A prospective, randomized clinical trial of electrical stimulation. J Bone Joint Surg. 1995;77:1166&#x2013;1173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugaya H, Moriishi J, Dohi M, Kon Y, Tsuchiya A. Glenoid rim morphology in recurrent anterior glenohumeral instability. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2003;85:878&#x2013;884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suijkerbuijk MAM, Reijman M, Lodewijks SJM, Punt J, Meuffels DE. Hamstring tendon regeneration after harvesting: a systematic review. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43:2591&#x2013;2598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suijkerbuijk MAM, Reijman M, Oei EHG, van Meer BL, van Arkel ERA, Meuffels DE. Predictive factors of hamstring tendon regeneration and functional recovery after harvesting: a prospective follow&#x2010;up study. Am J Sports Med. 2018;46:1166&#x2013;1174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suydam SM, Cortes DH, Axe MJ, Snyder&#x2010;Mackler L, Buchanan TS. Semitendinosus tendon for ACL reconstruction: regrowth and mechanical property recovery. Orthop J Sports Med. 2017;5:2325967117712944. https://doi.org/10.1177/2325967117712944</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadokoro K, Matsui N, Yagi M, Kuroda R, Kurosaka M, Yoshiya S. Evaluation of hamstring strength and tendon regrowth after harvesting for anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2004;32:1644&#x2013;1650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda Y, Kashiwaguchi S, Matsuura T, Higashida T, Minato A. Hamstring muscle function after tendon harvest for anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: evaluation with T2 relaxation time of magnetic resonance imaging. Am J Sports Med. 2006;34:281&#x2013;288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorborg K, Bandholm T, H&#xf6;lmich P. Hip&#x2010; and knee&#x2010;strength assessments using a hand&#x2010;held dynamometer with external belt&#x2010;fixation are inter&#x2010;tester reliable. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2013;21:550&#x2013;555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Melick N, van Cingel REH, Brooijmans F, Neeter C, van Tienen T, Hullegie W, et al. Evidence&#x2010;based clinical practice update: practice guidelines for anterior cruciate ligament rehabilitation based on a systematic review and multidisciplinary consensus. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:1506&#x2013;1515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk KE, Arrigo CA, Davies GJ. Isokinetic testing: why it is more important today than ever. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2024;19:374&#x2013;380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerer A, L&#xf6;chel J, Schoon J, Janz V, Wassilew GI, Zimmerer A, et al. Author correction: defining the Gothic arch angle (GAA) as a radiographic diagnostic tool for instability in hip dysplasia. Sci Rep. 2021;11:19531. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-00095-y</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>