<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41917715</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3724</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical journal of sport medicine : official journal of the Canadian Academy of Sport Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin J Sport Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Role of Collagen Supplementation in Bone Metabolism and Structure: A Scoping Review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001442</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the current literature on the role of collagen peptide supplementation in bone health, focusing on changes in bone turnover markers (BTMs) and bone mineral density (BMD).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES" NlmCategory="METHODS">A search was conducted following PRISMA guidelines in the databases Academic Search Premier, APA PsychInfo, CINAHL Plus, GreenFILE, MEDLINE, and SPORTDiscus. Keywords included "collagen supplementation," "bone turnover," and "bone structure." Studies published between January 2000 and March 2024 were included if they involved human subjects, oral collagen supplementation, and skeletal-related outcomes (BTMs or BMD). Risk of bias was assessed using the modified Physiotherapy Evidence Database (PEDro) scale.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Fifteen studies met the inclusion criteria. Collagen supplementation was associated with improvements in BTMs such as procollagen type I N-terminal propeptide and C-terminal telopeptide of type I collagen, as well as increases in BMD at whole body, femoral neck, and lumbar spine sites, particularly in postmenopausal women. However, neutral findings and substantial heterogeneity in study design, population characteristics, and dosing protocols were also observed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Collagen supplementation shows promise for supporting bone health, particularly in postmenopausal women, but the evidence remains inconsistent. Future research should address these gaps by focusing on premenopausal populations, standardizing dosing protocols, and exploring broader orthopedic applications, such as reducing stress fractures and enhancing recovery from musculoskeletal injuries.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuhlman</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas M</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutritional Sciences, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jagim</LastName><ForeName>Andrew R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Medicine Department, Mayo Clinic Health System, La Crosse, Wisconsin.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Patriot Performance Laboratory, Frank Pettrone Center for Sports Performance, George Mason University, Fairfax, Virginia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blesso</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutritional Sciences, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Margaret T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Patriot Performance Laboratory, Frank Pettrone Center for Sports Performance, George Mason University, Fairfax, Virginia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport, Recreation, and Tourism Management, George Mason University, Fairfax, Virginia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chun</LastName><ForeName>Ock</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutritional Sciences, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Puglisi</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutritional Sciences, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fields</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer B</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-1453-3181</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutritional Sciences, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Patriot Performance Laboratory, Frank Pettrone Center for Sports Performance, George Mason University, Fairfax, Virginia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin J Sport Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9103300</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1050-642X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bone health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bone metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bone mineral density</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bone turnover markers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">collagen</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">musculoskeletal health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41917715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00042752-990000000-00396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Karaguzel G, Holick MF. Diagnosis and treatment of osteopenia. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2010;11:237&#x2013;251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnell O, Kanis JA. An estimate of the worldwide prevalence and disability associated with osteoporotic fractures. Osteoporos Int. 2006;17:1726&#x2013;1733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warden SJ, Davis IS, Fredericson M. Management and prevention of bone stress injuries in long-distance runners. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2014;44:749&#x2013;765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin RM. Bone health: preventing osteoporosis. Public Health Rep. 2010;125:368&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-Bautista E, Martin-Matillas M, Martin-Lagos JA, et al. A nutritional intervention study with hydrolyzed collagen in pre-pubertal Spanish children: influence on bone modeling biomarkers. J Pediatr Endocrinol Metab. 2011;24:147&#x2013;153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zdzieblik D, Oesser S, K&#xf6;nig D. Specific bioactive collagen peptides in osteopenia and osteoporosis: long-term observation in postmenopausal women. J Bone Metab. 2021;28:207&#x2013;213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tella SH, Gallagher JC. Prevention and treatment of postmenopausal osteoporosis. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2014;142:155&#x2013;170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elam ML, Johnson SA, Hooshmand S, et al. A calcium-collagen chelate dietary supplement attenuates bone loss in postmenopausal women with osteopenia: a randomized controlled trial. J Med Food. 2015;18:324&#x2013;331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tell-Lebanon O, Yaacobi E, Ohana N, et al. Osteoporosis treatment after osteoporotic fractures: data from a single medical center. Endocr Pract. 2022;28:1221&#x2013;1225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonnelli S, Cepollaro C, Pondrelli C, et al. Bone turnover and the response to alendronate treatment in postmenopausal osteoporosis. Calcif Tissue Int. 1999;65:359&#x2013;364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reginster JY, Deroisy R, Lecart MP, et al. A double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose-finding trial of intermittent nasal salmon calcitonin for prevention of postmenopausal lumbar spine bone loss. Am J Med. 1995;98:452&#x2013;458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storm T, Thamsborg G, Steiniche T, et al. Effect of intermittent cyclical etidronate therapy on bone mass and fracture rate in women with postmenopausal osteoporosis. N Engl J Med. 1990;322:1265&#x2013;1271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y K. Effects of collagen ingestion and their biological significance. J Nutr Food Sci. 2016;6:1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shigemura Y, Kubomura D, Sato Y, et al. Dose-dependent changes in the levels of free and peptide forms of hydroxyproline in human plasma after collagen hydrolysate ingestion. Food Chem. 2014;159:328&#x2013;332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walrand S, Chiotelli E, Noirt F, et al. Consumption of a functional fermented milk containing collagen hydrolysate improves the concentration of collagen-specific amino acids in plasma. J Agric Food Chem. 2008;56:7790&#x2013;7795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu K, Sato M, Zhang Y, et al. The bioavailable octapeptide Gly-Ala-Hyp-Gly-Leu-Hyp-Gly-Pro stimulates nitric oxide synthesis in vascular endothelial cells. J Agric Food Chem. 2010;58:6960&#x2013;6965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohara H, Matsumoto H, Ito K, et al. Comparison of quantity and structures of hydroxyproline-containing peptides in human blood after oral ingestion of gelatin hydrolysates from different sources. J Agric Food Chem. 2007;55:1532&#x2013;1535.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwai K, Hasegawa T, Taguchi Y, et al. Identification of food-derived collagen peptides in human blood after oral ingestion of gelatin hydrolysates. J Agric Food Chem. 2005;53:6531&#x2013;6536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey AJ, Sims TJ, Ebbesen EN, et al. Age-related changes in the biochemical properties of human cancellous bone collagen: relationship to bone strength. Calcif Tissue Int. 1999;65:203&#x2013;210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HK, Kim M-G, Leem K-H. Osteogenic activity of collagen peptide via ERK/MAPK pathway mediated boosting of collagen synthesis and its therapeutic efficacy in osteoporotic bone by back-scattered electron imaging and microarchitecture analysis. Molecules. 2013;18:15474&#x2013;15489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillerminet F, Beaupied H, Fabien-Soul&#xe9; V, et al. Hydrolyzed collagen improves bone metabolism and biomechanical parameters in ovariectomized mice: an in vitro and in vivo study. Bone. 2010;46:827&#x2013;834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillerminet F, Fabien-Soul&#xe9; V, Even PC, et al. Hydrolyzed collagen improves bone status and prevents bone loss in ovariectomized C3H/HeN mice. Osteoporos Int. 2012;23:1909&#x2013;1919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Almeida Jackix E, C&#xfa;neo F, Amaya-Farfan J, et al. A food supplement of hydrolyzed collagen improves compositional and biodynamic characteristics of vertebrae in ovariectomized rats. J Med Food. 2010;13:1385&#x2013;1390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lampropoulou-Adamidou K, Karlafti E, Argyrou C, et al. Effect of calcium and vitamin D supplementation with and without collagen peptides on volumetric and areal bone mineral density, bone geometry and bone turnover in postmenopausal women with osteopenia. J Clin Densitom. 2022;25:357&#x2013;372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;nig D, Oesser S, Scharla S, et al. Specific collagen peptides improve bone mineral density and bone markers in postmenopausal Women-A randomized controlled study. Nutrients. 2018;10:97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooshmand S, Elam ML, Brown J, et al. Evidence for bone reversal properties of a Calcium- collagen chelate, a novel dietary supplement. J Food Nutr Disor. 2013;2:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw G, Lee-Barthel A, Ross ML, et al. Vitamin C-enriched gelatin supplementation before intermittent activity augments collagen synthesis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2017;105:136&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bongers CCWG, Ten Haaf DSM, Catoire M, et al. Effectiveness of collagen supplementation on pain scores in healthy individuals with self-reported knee pain: a randomized controlled trial. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2020;45:793&#x2013;800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xfa;neo F, Costa-Paiva L, Pinto-Neto AM, et al. Effect of dietary supplementation with collagen hydrolysates on bone metabolism of postmenopausal women with low mineral density. Maturitas. 2010;65:253&#x2013;257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilkens L, Boerboom M, van Schijndel N, et al. Bone turnover following high-impact exercise is not modulated by collagen supplementation in young men: a randomized cross-over trial. Bone. 2023;170:116705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamseer L, Moher D, Clarke M, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015: elaboration and explanation. BMJ. 2015;350:g7647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilkens L, van Schijndel N, Weijer VCR, et al. Jumping exercise combined with collagen supplementation preserves bone mineral density in elite cyclists. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2024;34:38&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cashin AG, McAuley JH. Clinimetrics: physiotherapy evidence database (pedro) scale. J Physiother. 2020;66:59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez GZ, Moseley AM, Maher CG, et al. Methodologic quality and statistical reporting of physical therapy randomized controlled trials relevant to musculoskeletal conditions. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2018;99:129&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greer B, Mojock C, Arjmandi B, et al. Twelve week calcium collagen chelate or calcium plus vitamin D supplementation does not affect bone metabolism in trained cyclists. J Sci Cycling. 2022;11:49&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argyrou C, Karlafti E, Lampropoulou-Adamidou K, et al. Effect of calcium and vitamin D supplementation with and without collagen peptides on bone turnover in postmenopausal women with osteopenia. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2020;20:12&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clifford T, Ventress M, Allerton DM, et al. The effects of collagen peptides on muscle damage, inflammation and bone turnover following exercise: a randomized, controlled trial. Amino Acids. 2019;51:691&#x2013;704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elvira-Aranda C, De Castellar-Sans&#xf3; R, Gomis-Gomis MJ, et al. Effects of the hydrolyzed collagen supplement colnatur sport&#xae; on endurance training and performance of runners. JHSE. 2022;18:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasikaran S, Eastell R, Bruy&#xe8;re O, et al. Markers of bone turnover for the prediction of fracture risk and monitoring of osteoporosis treatment: a need for international reference standards. Osteoporos Int. 2011;22:391&#x2013;420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szulc P, Naylor K, Hoyle NR, et al. National bone health alliance bone turnover marker Project. Use of CTX-I and PINP as bone turnover markers: National bone health alliance recommendations to standardize sample handling and patient preparation to reduce pre-analytical variability. Osteoporos Int. 2017;28:2541&#x2013;2556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C-H, Chang Y-F, Chen C-H, et al. Consensus statement on the use of bone turnover markers for short-term monitoring of osteoporosis treatment in the Asia-Pacific region. J Clin Densitom. 2021;24:3&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty S, Kapoor N, Bondu JD, et al. Bone turnover markers: emerging tool in the management of osteoporosis. Indian J Endocrinol Metab. 2016;20:846&#x2013;852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo T-R, Chen C-H. Bone biomarker for the clinical assessment of osteoporosis: recent developments and future perspectives. Biomark Res. 2017;5:18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutson MJ, O'Donnell E, Brooke-Wavell K, et al. Effects of low energy availability on bone health in endurance athletes and high-impact exercise as A potential countermeasure: a narrative review. Sports Med. 2021;51:391&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrack MT, Gibbs JC, De Souza MJ, et al. Higher incidence of bone stress injuries with increasing female athlete triad-related risk factors: a prospective multisite study of exercising girls and women. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42:949&#x2013;958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredericson M, Roche M, Barrack MT, et al. Healthy runner project: a 7-year, multisite nutrition education intervention to reduce bone stress injury incidence in collegiate distance runners. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2023;9:e001545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale C, Elliott-Sale KJ. Nutrition and athlete bone health. Sports Med. 2019;49(suppl 2):139&#x2013;151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch KR, Kemper HCG, Turi-Lynch B, et al. Impact sports and bone fractures among adolescents. J Sports Sci. 2017;35:2421&#x2013;2426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Changstrom BG, Brou L, Khodaee M, et al. Epidemiology of stress fracture injuries among US high school athletes, 2005-2006 through 2012-2013. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43:26&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>