<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41634743</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1749-8090</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cardiothoracic surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cardiothorac Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Surgical management of ventricular septal rupture post device migration: a case report.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">117</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13019-026-03864-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Ventricular septal rupture (VSR) following myocardial infarction is a rare but life-threatening complication. While percutaneous closure offers a less invasive option, it remains technically challenging in posterior defects due to anatomical constraints. This case report emphasizes the limitations of device-based closure in such settings and reinforces the role of surgery as the definitive management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE PRESENTATION">: We report the case of a 58-year-old male who developed a posterior ventricular septal rupture following an acute inferior wall myocardial infarction. Initial management included percutaneous device closure of the VSR. However, the patient developed persistent residual shunting and device migration, which resulted in its entanglement with the tricuspid valve apparatus and worsening heart failure. The patient subsequently underwent successful surgical repair through device extraction, infarct exclusion technique along with tricuspid valve replacement. Postoperative recovery was uneventful, and follow-up echocardiography confirmed complete closure of the defect with preserved biventricular function.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This case underscores the limitations of percutaneous closure in posterior VSRs and supports surgical repair as the more reliable and definitive treatment. This case is unique due to extensive device migration into the tricuspid valve apparatus, necessitating combined device extraction, infarct exclusion repair, and tricuspid valve replacement&#x2014;an uncommon combination in posterior VSR. Medium-term follow-up demonstrated stable cardiac function and no residual shunting.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaswal</LastName><ForeName>Vivek</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiothoracic and Vascular surgery, Post Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Edem</LastName><ForeName>Sanketh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiothoracic and Vascular surgery, Post Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India. sanketh.edem@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mishra</LastName><ForeName>Anand Kumar</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiothoracic and Vascular surgery, Post Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kheni</LastName><ForeName>Akshay</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiothoracic and Vascular surgery, Post Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reddy</LastName><ForeName>Lasya</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiothoracic and Vascular surgery, Post Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Cardiothorac Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101265113</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1749-8090</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Device migration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infarct exclusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inferior wall myocardial infarction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Percutaneous closure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Posterior ventricular septal rupture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Residual shunt</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surgical repair</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tricuspid valve injury</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Approval was taken from Institutional Ethics Committee. Consent for publication: Informed consent was taken from the patient for participation and publication. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41634743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12955169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13019-026-03864-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13019-026-03864-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jones BM, Kapadia SR, Smedira NG, Robich MP, Tuzcu EM, Menon V, et al. Post-myocardial infarction ventricular septal rupture. Circulation. 2020;142(1):73&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaffery Z, Krishnaswamy A, Rajeswaran J, Kapadia SR. Percutaneous closure of post-MI VSR: benefits and pitfalls. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2019;12(4):345&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne RA, Rossello X, Coughlan J, Barbato E, Berry C, Chieffo A, et al. 2023 ESC guidelines for the management of acute coronary syndromes: developed by the task force on the management of acute coronary syndromes of the European society of cardiology (ESC). Eur Heart J Acute Cardiovasc Care. 2024;13(1):55&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37740496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Members WC, Lawton JS, Tamis-Holland JE, Bangalore S, Bates ER, Beckie TM, Bischoff JM, Bittl JA, Cohen MG, DiMaio JM, Don CW. 2021 ACC/AHA/SCAI guideline for coronary artery revascularization: a report of the American college of Cardiology/American heart association joint committee on clinical practice guidelines. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;79(2):e21&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2021.09.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34895950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiele H, Lurz P, De Waha S, Desch S, Eitel I, Borger MA, et al. Ventricular septal rupture: percutaneous or surgical treatment? Eur Heart J. 2019;40(3):199&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson WM, Horlick EM. Management of post-myocardial infarction ventricular septal rupture. EuroIntervention. 2016;12(Suppl X):X18&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4244/EIJV12SXA4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27174106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bapat V, Kim WK, Boone RH, Hilker L, Holzhey D, Thiele H, et al. Structural complications of device closure in VSR. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2021;162(5):1471&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlotter F, de Waha S, Eitel I, Fuernau G, Desch S, Thiele H. Ventricular septal rupture in acute myocardial infarction: a review. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76(6):1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RL, Wagener J, Bhatt DL, Gillinov AM, Kapadia SR. Surgical repair of post-MI VSR: timing and outcomes. Ann Thorac Surg. 2019;108(4):1163&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvert PA, Cockburn J, Wynne D, Ludman P, Rana BS, Northridge D, Mullen MJ, Malik I, Turner M, Khogali S, Veldtman GR. Percutaneous closure of postinfarction ventricular septal defect: in-hospital outcomes and long-term follow-up of UK experience. Circulation. 2014;129(23):2395&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.113.005839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24668286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premchand RK, Garipalli R, Padmanabhan TN, Manik G. Percutaneous closure of post-myocardial infarction ventricular septal rupture&#x2013;a single centre experience. Indian Heart J. 2017;69:S24-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ihj.2016.10.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5388014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28400035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assenza GE, McElhinney DB, Valente AM, Pearson DD, Volpe M, Martucci G, et al. Transcatheter closure of post-myocardial infarction ventricular septal rupture. Circ Cardiovasc Interv. 2013;6(1):59&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCINTERVENTIONS.112.972711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23339839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapadia SR, Ohman EM, Stewart WJ, Popovic ZB, Lauer MS, Thomas JD, et al. Device failure in ventricular septal rupture closure: A meta-analysis. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2016;9(10):1018&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvert PA, Northridge DB, Malik IS, Shapiro LM, Redwood SR. Bioprosthetic valve replacement for failed VSR closure. Heart. 2017;103(11):892&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>