<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41879218</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-7401</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Technology and health care : official journal of the European Society for Engineering and Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Technol Health Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of manual lymphatic drainage on post-HIIT oxidative stress and lactate dynamics assessed via wearable and point-of-care physiological monitoring.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9287329261419297</StartPage><MedlinePgn>9287329261419297</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/09287329261419297</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>BackgroundHigh-intensity interval training (HIIT) is a time-efficient approach that improves cardiovascular and metabolic health, but it can acutely increase oxidative stress and delay recovery. With the growing availability of wearable sensors and point-of-care biochemical testing, recovery interventions can be evaluated with objective physiological monitoring.ObjectiveTo investigate whether a single session of manual lymphatic drainage (MLD) modulates post-HIIT oxidative stress and lactate responses measured using wearable and point-of-care monitoring tools in healthy adults.MethodsThirty healthy adults were randomized to an MLD group (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;15) or a passive-rest control group (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;15). Exercise intensity was controlled using a wearable heart-rate monitor during a standardized HIIT protocol. Capillary blood lactate, reactive oxygen species (ROS), and antioxidant capacity were assessed at baseline, immediately after HIIT, after 35&#x2005;min of MLD or rest, and at 24&#x2005;h using portable analyzers and photometric assays. Two-way repeated-measures ANOVA and within-group one-way repeated-measures ANOVA were applied.ResultsTime effects were observed in oxidative stress and lactate markers. Within the MLD group, ROS and antioxidant capacity changed significantly over time (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05). Antioxidant capacity increased immediately after exercise and declined at 24&#x2005;h. Lactate increased after HIIT and decreased after MLD and at 24&#x2005;h (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05). Between-group differences were not significant.ConclusionMLD appears to support post-HIIT physiological recovery, and its effects can be quantified using wearable heart-rate monitoring and point-of-care oxidative stress and lactate testing. This monitoring-based framework strengthens the clinical engineering relevance of MLD as an adjunct recovery strategy in rehabilitation and health-management settings.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Sumin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-2380-0849</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Gangneung Yeongdong University, Gangneung-si, Gangwon State, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moon</LastName><ForeName>Ilyoung</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6457-8125</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Hallym Sacred Heart University, Chuncheon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Seongjung</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Kangwon National University, Samcheok, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Technol Health Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9314590</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0928-7329</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high-intensity interval training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">manual lymphatic drainage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxidative stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-exercise recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reactive oxygen species</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41879218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/09287329261419297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>