<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41734596</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-3072</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>101</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Tissue &amp; cell</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Tissue Cell</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biochemical markers of muscle damage and recovery: Insights from exercise physiology and molecular biology.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103406</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103406</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.tice.2026.103406</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0040-8166(26)00098-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Exercise-induced muscle damage (EIMD) is a multifactorial biological phenomenon arising from the coordinated effects of mechanical overload, metabolic perturbations, oxidative stress, inflammatory signaling, and molecular remodeling. Rather than constituting a purely deleterious consequence of exercise, EIMD represents a dynamic physiological stimulus that initiates repair, regeneration, and long-term skeletal muscle adaptation. This review synthesizes current evidence to provide an integrated framework linking structural disruption at the sarcomeric level with downstream biochemical responses, immune regulation, and growth factor-mediated remodeling processes. Classical biochemical markers, including creatine kinase, lactate dehydrogenase, and myoglobin, remain widely used indicators of sarcolemmal permeability and metabolic stress; however, their interpretative value is limited by indirectness and substantial inter-individual variability. Emerging structural biomarkers such as skeletal muscle troponins, titin fragments, and desmin offer enhanced mechanistic specificity by directly reflecting myofibrillar and cytoskeletal disruption, thereby improving the molecular resolution of EIMD assessment. Concurrently, tightly regulated inflammatory responses characterized by a temporal transition from pro-inflammatory to anti-inflammatory signaling play a dual role by mediating tissue clearance while promoting satellite cell activation and regenerative remodeling. Growth factors including insulin-like growth factor-1, fibroblast growth factor-2, vascular endothelial growth factor, and the inhibitory regulator myostatin are highlighted as central integrators of mechanical, metabolic, and immune-derived cues that coordinate myogenesis, angiogenesis, and hypertrophic adaptation. From a practical perspective, the review emphasizes that optimal management of EIMD should focus on modulation rather than suppression of damage-associated pathways through appropriate exercise prescription, nutritional support, and recovery strategies. Collectively, EIMD is conceptualized as a programmable biological process whose magnitude, timing, and resolution critically determine skeletal muscle resilience, performance, and long-term health.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xd6;zdemir</LastName><ForeName>K&#xfc;bra</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Atat&#xfc;rk University, Faculty of Sports Sciences, Physical Education and Sports Teaching Department, Erzurum 25030, T&#xfc;rkiye. Electronic address: kubra.ozdemir@atauni.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demir</LastName><ForeName>Yeliz</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ardahan University, Nihat Delibalta G&#xf6;le Vocational High School, Department of Pharmacy Services, Ardahan 75700, T&#xfc;rkiye; Atat&#xfc;rk University, Faculty of Science, Department of Chemistry, Erzurum 25240, T&#xfc;rkiye. Electronic address: yelizdemir@ardahan.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Scotland</Country><MedlineTA>Tissue Cell</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0214745</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0040-8166</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biochemical and structural biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise-induced muscle damage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Growth factor signaling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation and regeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Skeletal muscle remodeling</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41734596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tice.2026.103406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0040-8166(26)00098-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>