<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41836757</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-4185</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in bioengineering and biotechnology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Bioeng Biotechnol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Structural improvement towards the efficiency of biodigesters in the 21st century: a review of the different designs.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1721607</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1721607</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1721607</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fbioe.2026.1721607</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Anaerobic biodigesters play a crucial role in the sustainable development of rural areas, managing waste and generating renewable energy. This review evaluates the development and performance of the fixed dome, floating drum, and tubular biodigesters, viz, shows how design improvements and operational strategies impact their efficiency. The original design of these traditional models was found to be restricted by microbial instability caused by climate fluctuations and operational disturbances. In response, modern designs incorporated specific adaptations, such as thermal control and feedstock optimization. The fixed dome model demonstrated improved durability and performance with solar heating and self-mixing capabilities that increase methane production and volatile solids removal. In contrast, floating drum digesters, which are constantly limited by corrosion and inconsistent yields, have been developed to incorporate plastic protective layers, integrated mixing shafts, and <i>in-situ</i> purification to achieve better methane concentrations and improved system efficiency. Affordable and adaptable tubular digesters with modular expansion capabilities, incorporating trench burial and greenhouse enclosures, have been designed to enhance affordability and mitigate the effects of climate change. The modifications increase methane production, process stability, and energy recovery. Biodigester performance and efficiency are fundamentally driven by design. Accordingly, the future adoption of anaerobic biodigesters will depend on locally adaptable and affordable systems supported by practical maintenance frameworks, as well as community awareness and training. Overall, recent design innovations have enabled a shift from climate-sensitive traditional models toward more durable, efficient, and adaptable digesters capable of stabilizing methane yield under variable operating conditions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Nethavhanani, Nekhubvi, Mathomu and Maluta.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nethavhanani</LastName><ForeName>Takalani</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physics Department, University of Venda, Thohoyandou, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nekhubvi</LastName><ForeName>Vhutshilo</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physics Department, University of Venda, Thohoyandou, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mathomu</LastName><ForeName>Lutendo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biochemistry and Microbiology, University of Venda, Thohoyandou, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maluta</LastName><ForeName>Nnditshedzeni Eric</ForeName><Initials>NE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Green Technology Confucious Institute (GTCI), University of Venda, Thohoyandou, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Theoretical and Computational Sciences (NITheCS), Pretoria, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Bioeng Biotechnol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101632513</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-4185</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biodigesters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biogas production</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digester efficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digester operation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fixed dome digester</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">floating drum digesters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">structural design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tubular digester</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41836757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12982178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2026.1721607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1721607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abdoli M. A., Amiri L., Baghvand A., Nasiri J., Madadian E. (2014). Methane production from anaerobic co-digestion of maize and cow dung. Environ. Prog. Sustain. Energy 33 (2), 597&#x2013;601. 10.1002/ep.11783</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ep.11783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ai H., Wang Q., Fan X., Xie W., Shinohara R. (2005). Effect of hydraulic retention time on the efficiency of vertical tubular anaerobic sludge digester treating waste activated sludge. Environ. Technol. 26 (7), 725&#x2013;732. 10.1080/0959333260861851</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0959333260861851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16080328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amigun B., Von Blottnitz H. (2010). Capacity-cost and location-cost analyses for biogas plants in Africa. Resour. Conservation Recycl. 55 (1), 63&#x2013;73. 10.1016/j.resconrec.2010.07.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2010.07.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amo-Duodu G., Rathilal S., Chollom M. N., Kweinor Tetteh E. (2021). Application of metallic nanoparticles for biogas enhancement using the biomethane potential test. Sci. Afr. 12, e00728. 10.1016/j.sciaf.2021.e00728</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sciaf.2021.e00728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelidaki I., Treu L., Tsapekos P., Luo G., Campanaro S., Wenzel H., et al. (2018). Biogas upgrading and utilization: current status and perspectives. Biotechnol. Adv. 36 (2), 452&#x2013;466. 10.1016/j.biotechadv.2018.01.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biotechadv.2018.01.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29360505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baniamerian H., Isfahani P. G., Tsapekos P., Alvarado-Morales M., Shahrokhi M., Vossoughi M., et al. (2019). Application of nano-structured materials in anaerobic digestion: current status and perspectives. Chemosphere 229, 188&#x2013;199. 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2019.04.193</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2019.04.193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31078033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bond T., Templeton M. R. (2011). History and future of domestic biogas plants in the developing world. Energy Sustain. Dev. 15 (4), 347&#x2013;354. 10.1016/j.esd.2011.09.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.esd.2011.09.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouallagui H., Haouari O., Touhami Y., Ben Cheikh R., Marouani L., Hamdi M. (2004). Effect of temperature on the performance of an anaerobic tubular reactor treating fruit and vegetable waste. Process Biochem. 39 (12), 2143&#x2013;2148. 10.1016/j.procbio.2003.11.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procbio.2003.11.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casta&#xf1;o J. M., Martin J. F., Ciotola R. (2014). Performance of a small-scale, variable temperature fixed dome digester in a temperate climate. Energies 7 (9), 5701&#x2013;5716. 10.3390/en7095701</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en7095701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chojnacka K., Moustakas K. (2024). Anaerobic digestate management for carbon neutrality and fertilizer use: a review of current practices and future opportunities. Biomass Bioenergy 180, 106991. 10.1016/j.biombioe.2023.106991</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biombioe.2023.106991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Eze J. I., Agbo K. E. (2010). Studies on the microbial spectrum in anaerobic biomethannization of cow dung in 10 m<sup>3</sup> fixed dome biogas digester. Int. J. Phys. Sci.
5 (8), 1331&#x2013;1337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faisal S., Hafeez F. Y., Zafar Y., Majeed S., Leng X., Zhao S., et al. (2018). A review on nanoparticles as boon for biogas producers-Nano fuels and biosensing monitoring. Appl. Sci. 9 (1). 10.3390/app9010059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app9010059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fouedjio C. A., Djumyong Wafo G. V., Ayo A., Jeuke Ngougni I. U., Nounja Zuitchou M., Nana Ndangang J. J., et al. (2025). Assessment of operational efficiency of a low-cost tubular digester for pig manure in the urban areas of yaound&#xe9;. Waste Biomass Valorization 16, 5287&#x2013;5300. 10.1007/s12649-025-02923-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12649-025-02923-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaballah E. S., Yuan Q., Abdelkader T. K. (2024). Improving biogas production by integrated solar greenhouse technique: a pilot study using semi-buried tubular digester in cold climate regions. Waste Biomass Valorization 15 (3), 1355&#x2013;1367. 10.1007/s12649-023-02206-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12649-023-02206-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gangagni Rao A., Gandu B., Sandhya K., Kranti K., Ahuja S., Swamy Y. V. (2013). Decentralized application of anaerobic digesters in small poultry farms: performance analysis of high rate self mixed anaerobic digester and conventional fixed dome anaerobic digester. Bioresour. Technol. 144, 121&#x2013;127. 10.1016/j.biortech.2013.06.076</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2013.06.076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23867531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garf&#xed; M., Ferrer-Mart&#xed; L., Perez I., Flotats X., Ferrer I. (2011). Codigestion of cow and Guinea pig manure in low-cost tubular digesters at high altitude. Ecol. Eng. 37 (12), 2066&#x2013;2070. 10.1016/j.ecoleng.2011.08.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoleng.2011.08.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geddafa T., Melka Y., Sime G. (2023). Cost-benefit analysis and financial viability of household biogas plant investment in south Ethiopia. Sustain. Energy Res. 10 (20), 1&#x2013;16. 10.1186/s40807-023-00089-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40807-023-00089-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issahaku M., Derkyi N. S. A., Kemausuor F. (2024). A systematic review of the design considerations for the operation and maintenance of small-scale biogas digesters. Heliyon 10 (1), e24019. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e24019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e24019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10789629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38230247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyer N. S., Velmurugan B. (2024). Study on potential use of semi-solid potato peel waste in biomethanation and pelletization. Biomass Convers. Biorefinery 14 (4), 5005&#x2013;5017. 10.1007/s13399-022-02634-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13399-022-02634-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaimes-Est&#xe9;vez J., Zafra G., Mart&#xed;-Herrero J., Pelaz G., Mor&#xe1;n A., Puentes A., et al. (2021). Psychrophilic full scale tubular digester operating over eight years: complete performance evaluation and microbiological population. Energies 14 (1). 10.3390/en14010151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en14010151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Paute R., Hidalgo M., Guaya D., Mart&#xed;-Herrero J. (2025). Performance of a low-cost full-scale wastewater treatment system: tubular digesters combined with granular filtration for domestic wastewater in the Ecuadorian amazon. J. Water Process Eng. 69. 10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.106797</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.106797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabeyi M. J. B., Olanrewaju O. A. (2022). Sustainable energy transition for renewable and low carbon grid electricity generation and supply. Front. Energy Res. 9, 743114. 10.3389/fenrg.2021.743114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenrg.2021.743114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karne H. U., Bhatkhande D. (2024). Influence of nitrogen content in food waste on biogas production. Chem. Eng. Technol. 47(7), 994&#x2013;1002. 10.1002/ceat.202300417</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ceat.202300417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasinath A., Fudala-Ksiazek S., Szopinska M., Bylinski H., Artichowicz W., Remiszewska-Skwarek A., et al. (2021). Biomass in biogas production: pretreatment and codigestion. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 150. 111509. 10.1016/j.rser.2021.111509</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2021.111509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinyua M. N., Rowse L. E., Ergas S. J. (2016). Review of small-scale tubular anaerobic digesters treating livestock waste in the developing world. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 58, 896&#x2013;910. 10.1016/j.rser.2015.12.324</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2015.12.324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kluczek A., Gladysz B. (2022). Energy sustainability performance index of biodigester using energy LCA-based indicators. Front. Energy Res. 10, 848584. 10.3389/fenrg.2022.848584</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenrg.2022.848584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishania M., Vijay V. K., Chandra R. (2016). Performance evaluation of various bioreactors for methane fermentation of pretreated wheat straw with cattle manure. Green Process. Synthesis 5 (2), 113&#x2013;121. 10.1515/gps-2015-0067</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/gps-2015-0067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S. S., Ghosh P., Kataria N., Kumar D., Thakur S., Pathania D., et al. (2021). The role of conductive nanoparticles in anaerobic digestion: mechanism, current status, and future perspectives. Chemosphere 280, 130601. 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2021.130601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2021.130601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33945900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leigh R. (2022). Effects of solar heating and insulation on model biodigester temperature. Master&#x2019;s dissertation, Austin, TX: The University of Texas.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makamure F., Mukumba P., Makaka G. (2024). Biogas production from a solar-heated temperature-controlled biogas digester. Sustainability 16 (22), 9894. 10.3390/su16229894</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su16229894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;-Herrero J., Chipana M., Cuevas C., Paco G., Serrano V., Zymla B., et al. (2014). Low cost tubular digesters as appropriate technology for widespread application: results and lessons learned from Bolivia. Renew. Energy 71, 156&#x2013;165. 10.1016/j.renene.2014.05.036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2014.05.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meegoda J. N., Li B., Patel K., Wang L. B. (2018). A review of the processes, parameters, and optimization of anaerobic digestion. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 15 (10). 10.3390/ijerph15102224</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph15102224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6210450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30314318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mereu R. I. (2016). Standard design procedure for low-cost biodigester technologies: design, construction and monitoring of a tubular digester in puerto matilde. Italy: Politecnico di Milano. Master&#x2019;s dissertation.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed Zaki M. B. A., Shamsudin R., Mohd Yusoff M. Z. (2020). Portable biodigester system for household use: a review. Adv. Agric. Food Res. J. 2 (2). 10.36877/aafrj.a0000148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36877/aafrj.a0000148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Msibi S. S., Kornelius G. (2017). Potential for domestic biogas as household energy supply in South Africa. J. Energy South. Afr. 28 (2), 1&#x2013;13. 10.17159/2413-3051/2017/v28i2a1754</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17159/2413-3051/2017/v28i2a1754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mungwe J. N., Colombo E., Adani F., Schievano A. (2016). The fixed dome digester: an appropriate design for the context of sub-sahara Africa? Biomass Bioenerg 95, 35&#x2013;44. 10.1016/j.biombioe.2016.09.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biombioe.2016.09.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mungwe J. N., Asoh D. A., Mbinkar E. (2021). Design considerations of a flexible biogas digester system for use in rural communities of developing countries. J. Sustain. Bioenergy Syst. 11 (4), 260&#x2013;271. 10.4236/jsbs.2021.114016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/jsbs.2021.114016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutungwazi A., Mukumba P., Makaka G. (2018). Biogas digester types installed in South Africa: a review. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 81, 172&#x2013;180. 10.1016/j.rser.2017.07.051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2017.07.051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nape K. M., Magama P., Moeletsi M. E., Tongwane M. I., Nakana P. M., Mliswa V. K., et al. (2019). Introduction of household biogas digesters in rural farming households of the Maluti-a-Phofung municipality, South Africa. J. Energy South. Afr. 30 (2), 28&#x2013;37. 10.17159/2413-3051/2019/v30i2a5885</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17159/2413-3051/2019/v30i2a5885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie E., He P., Zhang H., Hao L., Shao L., L&#xfc; F. (2021). How does temperature regulate anaerobic digestion? Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 150, 111453. 10.1016/j.rser.2021.111453</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2021.111453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Njuguna Matheri A., Mbohwa C., Ntuli F., Belaid M., Seodigeng T., Catherine Ngila J., et al. (2018). Waste to energy bio-digester selection and design model for the organic fraction of municipal solid waste. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 82, 1113&#x2013;1121. 10.1016/j.rser.2017.09.051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2017.09.051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obileke K. C., Mamphweli S., Meyer E. L., Makaka G., Nwokolo N., Onyeaka H. (2020). Comparative study on the performance of aboveground and underground fixed-dome biogas digesters. Chem. Eng. Technol. 43 (1), 68&#x2013;74. 10.1002/ceat.201900378</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ceat.201900378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obileke K. C., Onyeaka H., Nwokolo N. (2021). Materials for the design and construction of household biogas digesters for biogas production: a review. Int. J. Energy Res. 45 (3), 3761&#x2013;3779. 10.1002/er.6120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/er.6120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojo O. I., Ojo O. M. (2023). Design modification, construction and performance testing of a floating drum anaerobic digester. J. Agric. Eng. Technol. 28 (2), 43&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otanocha O. B., Oyovwikefe R., Okwu M. O., Tartibu L. K. (2023). Modified biogas digester tank for production of gas from decomposable organic wastes. Biomass Convers. Biorefinery 13 (13), 2863&#x2013;2873. 10.1007/s13399-020-01195-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13399-020-01195-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal S., Bello A., Muratova E., Chekanov A. (2025). A review of the materials utilized in the design and fabrication of biogas digesters. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 211, 115167. 10.1016/j.rser.2024.115167</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2024.115167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilloni M., Abu Hamed T. (2021). Small-size biogas technology applications for rural areas in the context of developing countries. IntechOpen. 10.5772/intechopen.96857</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5772/intechopen.96857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quintero M., Alzate M., Pati&#xf1;o F., Arboleda A., Pinz&#xf3;n Y., Mantilla A., et al. (2019). Physicochemical and microbiological monitoring of anaerobic digestion at laboratory and low cost tubular digester. Bioresour. Technol. 274, 321&#x2013;328. 10.1016/j.biortech.2018.11.091</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2018.11.091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30529479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman M. M., Faizal H. M., Wahid M. A., Rahman M., Hasan M. F., Saat A., et al. (2017). Economics of biogas plants and solar home systems: for household energy applications. J. Adv. Res. Fluid Mech. Therm. Sci. 33 (1), 14&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajendran K., Aslanzadeh S., Taherzadeh M. J. (2012). Household biogas digesters: a review. Energies 5 (8), 2911&#x2013;2942. 10.3390/en5082911</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en5082911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehman M. L. U., Iqbal A., Chang C. C., Li W., Ju M. (2019). Anaerobic digestion. Water Environ. Res. 91 (10), 1253&#x2013;1271. 10.1002/wer.1219</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wer.1219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31529649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renwick M., Subedi P. S., Hutton G. (2007). A cost benefit analysis of national and regional integrated biogas and sanitation programs in Sub-Saharan Africa, 1-68. Arlington, VA: Winrock International.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahu O. (2013). Study of biodigester design for fuel and fertilizer. Int. J. Renew. Sustain. Energy 2 (4), 147. 10.11648/j.ijrse.20130204.13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11648/j.ijrse.20130204.13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satyanarayana K. G., Mariano A. B., Vargas J. V. C. (2011). A review on microalgae, a versatile source for sustainable energy and materials. Int. J. Energy Res. 35 (4), 291&#x2013;311. 10.1002/er.1695</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/er.1695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semelane M. S. (2019). Investigating a sustainable operational method for a micro-scale biodigester in South Africa. Johannesburg, South Africa: University of Witwatersrand. Master&#x2019;s dissertation.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A. K., Sahoo P. K., Mukherjee M., Patel A. (2022). Assessment of sustainable biogas production from Co-Digestion of jatropha De-Oiled cake and cattle dung using floating drum type digester under psychrophilic and mesophilic conditions. Clean. Technol. 4 (2), 529&#x2013;541. 10.3390/cleantechnol4020032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cleantechnol4020032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strubbe L., Dierickx A., Verbist B., Denayer A., Volcke E. I. P. (2024). Household-scale digesters in Rwanda: performance analysis and net-greenhouse gas effect. J. Clean. Prod. 457, 142492. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142492</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su X., Shao X., Geng Y., Tian S., Huang Y. (2022). Optimization of feedstock and insulating strategies to enhance biogas production of solar-assisted biodigester system. Renew. Energy 197, 59&#x2013;68. 10.1016/j.renene.2022.07.090</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2022.07.090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tolessa A. (2024). Current status and future prospects of small-scale household biodigesters in Sub-Saharan Africa. J. Energy 2024, 1&#x2013;19. 10.1155/2024/5596028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2024/5596028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trois C., Kalina M., Ogwang J., Reale G. (2021). Decentralised Micro-biodigester systems for rural South Africa decentralised Micro-biodigester systems for rural South Africa.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>