<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41835999</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2325-9671</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Orthopaedic journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Orthop J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Defining Minimal Clinically Important Difference Thresholds for Pediatric Knee Surgeries.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23259671251413264</StartPage><MedlinePgn>23259671251413264</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23259671251413264</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/23259671251413264</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The minimal clinically important difference (MCID) has been established for adult questionnaires administered after pediatric anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction (ACLR) and medial patellofemoral ligament reconstruction (MPFLR), but the MCID remains unquantified in pediatric-specific patient-reported outcome (PRO) instruments.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To establish MCIDs for the Hospital for Special Surgery Pediatric Functional Activity Brief Scale (HSS Pedi-FABS), Pediatric International Knee Documentation Committee (Pedi-IKDC), and pediatric and parent-proxy Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS) pain interference (PI), mobility, and physical activity scores in pediatric patients who underwent ACLR and MPFLR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Cohort study; Level of evidence, 3.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The medical records of patients &lt;18 years of age who underwent ACLR or MPFLR with 1 of 2 pediatric orthopaedic surgeons between 2016 and 2023 were retrospectively reviewed. Patient demographic and clinical factors were collected. Preoperative HSS Pedi-FABS, Pedi-IKDC, and pediatric and parent-proxy PROMIS pain interference (PI), physical activity, and mobility questionnaire scores were collected. The MCID was defined as one-half the standard deviation of preoperative scores. The MCIDs were calculated for patients undergoing ACLR and MPFLR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In the ACLR group (505 patients; mean age, 14.5 &#xb1; 2.0 years), the MCIDs were established for the HSS Pedi-FABS (-5.0); Pedi-IKDC (8.7); pediatric PROMIS PI (-5.2), mobility (2.2), and physical activity (5.6); and parent-proxy PROMIS PI (-4.3), mobility (4.3), and physical activity (5.0) questionnaires. In the MPFLR group (253 patients; mean age, 14.4 &#xb1; 2.1 years), the MCIDs were established for the HSS Pedi-FABS (-5.1); Pedi-IKDC (9.1); pediatric PROMIS PI (-5.7), mobility (4.9), and physical activity (5.6); and parent-proxy PROMIS PI (-4.3), mobility (4.5), and physical activity (5.9) questionnaires. Negative MCIDs were reported for activity and pain scores to indicate MCID thresholds for decreased postoperative pain (i.e., pain improvement) and activity levels (i.e., decreased activity levels compared to healthiest and most active condition, absence of full recovery).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study establishes novel MCIDs for the HSS Pedi-FABS, Pedi-IKDC, and pediatric and parent-proxy PROMIS PI, physical activity, and mobility questionnaires in pediatric patients undergoing ACLR and MPFLR.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Umesh</LastName><ForeName>Amith</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Orthopedic Surgery, Hospital for Special Surgery, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bram</LastName><ForeName>Joshua T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3913-2804</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Orthopedic Surgery, Hospital for Special Surgery, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nian</LastName><ForeName>Patrick P</ForeName><Initials>PP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Orthopedic Surgery, Hospital for Special Surgery, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Ruth H</ForeName><Initials>RH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-3097-0747</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Orthopedic Surgery, Hospital for Special Surgery, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simpson</LastName><ForeName>Shae K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Orthopedic Surgery, Hospital for Special Surgery, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Green</LastName><ForeName>Daniel W</ForeName><Initials>DW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7286-6864</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Orthopedic Surgery, Hospital for Special Surgery, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fabricant</LastName><ForeName>Peter D</ForeName><Initials>PD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8070-685X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Orthopedic Surgery, Hospital for Special Surgery, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Orthop J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101620522</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2325-9671</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MCID</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PRO</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric knee</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>One or more of the authors has declared the following potential conflict of interest or source of funding: P.D.F. has received consulting fees from BICMD and publishing royalties from Springer Nature; and holds stock or stock options in OssoVR. D.W.G. has received royalties from Orthopediatrics. AOSSM checks author disclosures against the Open Payments Database (OPD). AOSSM has not conducted an independent investigation on the OPD and disclaims any liability or responsibility relating thereto. Ethical approval for this study was obtained from Hospital for Special Surgery, New York, New York, USA.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41835999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12979866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671251413264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_23259671251413264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bag&#xf3; J, P&#xe9;rez-Grueso FJS, Les E, Hern&#xe1;ndez P, Pellis&#xe9; F. Minimal important differences of the SRS-22 Patient Questionnaire following surgical treatment of idiopathic scoliosis. Eur Spine J. 2009;18(12):1898-1904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2899428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19533179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beletsky A, Naami E, Lu Y, et al. The minimally clinically important difference and substantial clinical benefit in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a time-to-achievement analysis. Orthopedics. 2021;44(5):299-305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34590953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bram JT, Fabricant PD. CORR synthesis: the role of the LET/ALLR in pediatric and adolescent ACL reconstruction&#x2014;should all young athletes receive lateral augmentation? Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2026;484(1):33-47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40632078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cella D, Eton DT, Lai JS, Peterman AH, Merkel DE. Combining anchor and distribution-based methods to derive minimal clinically important differences on the Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy (FACT) anemia and fatigue scales. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2002;24(6):547-561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12551804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen RE, Papuga MO, Voloshin I, et al. Preoperative PROMIS scores predict postoperative outcomes after primary ACL reconstruction. Orthop J Sports Med. 2018;6(5):2325967118771286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5946616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29761114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crosby RD, Kolotkin RL, Williams GR. An integrated method to determine meaningful changes in health-related quality of life. J Clin Epidemiol. 2004;57(11):1153-1160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15567631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crosby RD, Kolotkin RL, Williams GR. Defining clinically meaningful change in health-related quality of life. J Clin Epidemiol. 2003;56(5):395-407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12812812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vet HCW, Ostelo RWJG, Terwee CB, et al. Minimally important change determined by a visual method integrating an anchor-based and a distribution-based approach. Qual Life Res. 2007;16(1):131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2778628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17033901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeWitt EM, Stucky BD, Thissen D, et al. Construction of the eight-item Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System pediatric physical function scales: built using item response theory. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64(7):794-804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3100387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21292444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodwell ER, LaMont LE, Green DW, Pan TJ, Marx RG, Lyman S. 20 years of pediatric anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in New York State. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42(3):675-680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24477820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elias T, Haneberg E, Phillips A, et al. Poster 306: establishing the minimum clinically important difference two years following medial patellofemoral ligament reconstruction. Orthop J Sports Med. 2024;12(7 suppl 2):2325967124S00273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eton DT, Cella D, Yost KJ, et al. A combination of distribution- and anchor-based approaches determined minimally important differences (MIDs) for four endpoints in a breast cancer scale. J Clin Epidemiol. 2004;57(9):898-910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15504633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evuarherhe A, Condron NB, Gilat R, et al. Defining clinically significant outcomes following superior capsular reconstruction with acellular dermal allograft. Arthroscopy. 2022;38(5):1444-1453.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34863902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabricant P, Borst E, Green S, Marx R, Fragomen A, Rozbruch SR. Validation of a modified Scoliosis Research Society instrument for patients with limb deformity: the limb deformity-Scoliosis Research Society (LD-SRS) score. J Limb Lengthen Reconstr. 2016;2(2):86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabricant PD, Robles A, Downey-Zayas T, et al. Development and validation of a Pediatric Sports Activity Rating Scale: the Hospital for Special Surgery Pediatric Functional Activity Brief Scale (HSS Pedi-FABS). Am J Sports Med. 2013;41(10):2421-2429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23893420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher DJ, Copas AJ, Tierney JF, Parmar MKB. A critical review of methods for the assessment of patient-level interactions in individual participant data meta-analysis of randomized trials, and guidance for practitioners. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64(9):949-967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21411280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin DE, Gross HE, Stucky BD, et al. Development of six PROMIS pediatrics proxy-report item banks. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2012;10(1):22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3312870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22357192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javeed S, Greenberg JK, Plog B, et al. Clinically meaningful improvement in Disabilities of Arm, Shoulder, and Hand (DASH) following cervical spine surgery. Spine J. 2023;23(6):832-840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36708927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Yi Q, He L, et al. Comparing nonoperative treatment, MPFL repair, and MPFL reconstruction for patients with patellar dislocation: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Orthop J Sports Med. 2021;9(9):23259671211026624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8485172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34604425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maheshwer B, Polce EM, Parvaresh KC, et al. Establishing clinically significant outcomes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in pediatric patients. J Pediatr Orthop. 2022;42(6):e641-e648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35297390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall AN, Root HJ, Valovich McLeod TC, Lam KC. Patient-reported outcome measures for pediatric patients with sport-related injuries: a systematic review. J Athl Train. 2022;57(4):371-384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9020602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34478555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Most J, Hoelen TCA, Spekenbrink-Spooren A, Schotanus MGM, Boonen B. Defining clinically meaningful thresholds for patient-reported outcomes in knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty. 2022;37(5):837-844.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35134515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine AY, Connell PL, Kalish LA, et al. The Pediatric International Knee Documentation Committee (Pedi-IKDC) Subjective Knee Evaluation Form: normative data. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45(3):527-534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27864185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman GR, Sloan JA, Wyrwich KW. Interpretation of changes in health-related quality of life: the remarkable universality of half a standard deviation. Med Care. 2003;41(5):582-592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12719681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman GR, Sloan JA, Wyrwich KW. The truly remarkable universality of half a standard deviation: confirmation through another look. Expert Rev Pharmacoecon Outcomes Res. 2004;4(5):581-585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19807551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwachukwu BU, Beck EC, Kunze KN, Chahla J, Rasio J, Nho SJ. Defining the clinically meaningful outcomes for arthroscopic treatment of femoroacetabular impingement syndrome at minimum 5-year follow-up. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48(4):901-907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32167843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwachukwu BU, Chang B, Rotter BZ, Kelly BT, Ranawat AS, Nawabi DH. Minimal clinically important difference and substantial clinical benefit after revision hip arthroscopy. Arthroscopy. 2018;34(6):1862-1868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29653791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwachukwu BU, Fields K, Chang B, Nawabi DH, Kelly BT, Ranawat AS. Preoperative outcome scores are predictive of achieving the minimal clinically important difference after arthroscopic treatment of femoroacetabular impingement. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45(3):612-619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27765733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwachukwu BU, Sullivan SW, Rauck RC, et al. Patient-reported outcomes and factors associated with achieving the minimal clinically important difference after ACL reconstruction: results at a mean 7.7-year follow-up. JBJS Open Access. 2021;6(4):e21.00056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8613365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34841188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oak SR, O&#x2019;Rourke C, Strnad G, et al. Statistical comparison of the pediatric versus adult IKDC Subjective Knee Evaluation Form in adolescents. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43(9):2216-2221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26093004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owens JS, Jimenez AE, Lee MS, George T, Maldonado DR, Domb BG. Determining clinically meaningful thresholds for the Hip Outcome Score Sport-Specific Subscale in athletes undergoing hip arthroscopy for femoroacetabular impingement syndrome. Am J Sports Med. 2022;50(11):3009-3018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35971944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascual-Leone N, Fabricant PD. Can return-to-sport rates be taken at face value in the pediatric and adolescent sports literature? HSS J. 2024;20(3):325-326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11299333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39108452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popkin CA, Wright ML, Pennock AT, et al. Trends in management and complications of anterior cruciate ligament injuries in pediatric patients: a survey of the PRiSM Society. J Pediatr Orthop. 2018;38(2):e61-e65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29189529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Previtali D, Milev SR, Pagliazzi G, Filardo G, Zaffagnini S, Candrian C. Recurrent patellar dislocations without untreated predisposing factors: medial patellofemoral ligament reconstruction versus other medial soft-tissue surgical techniques&#x2014;a meta-analysis. Arthroscopy. 2020;36(6):1725-1734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32001279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao Y, Wu C, Wu X, et al. The value of minimal clinically important difference, substantial clinical benefit, and Patient-Acceptable Symptomatic State for commonly used patient-reported outcomes in recurrent patellar instability patients after medial patellofemoral ligament reconstruction and tibial tubercle transfer. Arthroscopy. 2024;40(1):115-123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37419222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn H, Thissen D, Liu Y, et al. Using item response theory to enrich and expand the PROMIS&#xae; pediatric self report banks. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2014;12(1):160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4212129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25344155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swigris JJ, Brown KK, Behr J, et al. The SF-36 and SGRQ: validity and first look at minimum important differences in IPF. Respir Med. 2010;104(2):296-304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2856332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19815403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tepolt FA, Feldman L, Kocher MS. Trends in pediatric ACL reconstruction from the PHIS database. J Pediatr Orthop. 2018;38(9):e490-e494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29975296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker CA, Bevans KB, Teneralli RE, Smith AW, Bowles HR, Forrest CB. Self-reported pediatric measures of physical activity, sedentary behavior, and strength impact for PROMIS: item development. Pediatr Phys Ther. 2014;26(4):385-392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4176727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25251790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale MG, Levy DE, Johnson MG, et al. Assessment of quality of life in adolescent patients with orthopaedic problems: are adult measures appropriate? J Pediatr Orthop. 2001;21(5):622-628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11521031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh JM, Huddleston HP, Alzein MM, et al. The minimal clinically important difference, substantial clinical benefit, and Patient-Acceptable Symptomatic State after medial patellofemoral ligament reconstruction. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2022;4(2):e661-e678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9042905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35494257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waters TL, Miller EM, Beck EC, Rider DE, Waterman BR. Adding lateral retinacular release to medial patellofemoral ligament reconstruction fails to demonstrate clinical benefit compared with isolated medial patellofemoral ligament reconstruction. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2024;6(2):100890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10851212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38333569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyrwich KW. Minimal important difference thresholds and the standard error of measurement: is there a connection? J Biopharm Stat. 2004;14(1):97-110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15027502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>