<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41920259</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1993-0402</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Chinese journal of integrative medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Chin J Integr Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ginsenoside Rg2 Targeting PDHE1 &#x3b1; to Improve High Glucose-Induced Hippocampal Neuronal Damage Based on CETSA Experiment.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11655-026-3946-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To explore the effect of ginsenoside Rg2 (G-Rg2) targeting pyruvate dehydrogenase E1 component subunit alpha (PDHE1 &#x3b1;) on its downstream energy metabolism to repair damaged hippocampal neurons.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The binding affinity between G-Rg2 and PDHE1 &#x3b1; was obtained by molecular docking (MD) and surface plasmon resonance (SPR). The thermal stability of Rg2 binding to PDHE1 &#x3b1; protein was evaluated by cellular thermal shift assay (CETSA), and the binding of Rg2 to PDHE1 &#x3b1; protein was further confirmed by isothermal dose-response curve. The mouse hippocampal neuronal cell line (HT22) was divided into 2 main groups: a PDHE1 &#x3b1; transfection control group and a PDHE1 &#x3b1; silencing group. Each main group was further subdivided into 3 treatment groups: a normal group (untreated), a high-glucose injury model group, and a Rg2 adminis0tration group. The downstream molecules and metabolites of PDHE1 &#x3b1; such as adenosine triphosphate (ATP), reactive oxygen species (ROS), acetyl coenzyme A (acetyl-CoA), and the oxidized/reduced ratio of nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide (NAD<sup>+</sup>/NADH ratio) were measured. The energy metabolism patterns of each group were analyzed using the hippocampus bioenergy analyzer to further confirm the interaction between Rg2 and PDHE1 &#x3b1; and the biological effect of the interaction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">MD and SPR techniques found that G-Rg2 directly bound to the target protein PDHE1 &#x3b1; and significantly improved its thermal stability. Isothermal dose-response results were consistent with these findings. The high glucose-induced HT22 cell injury model showed abnormal phenotypes including decreased PDH enzyme activity, increased ROS, decreased ATP production, an imbalanced NAD<sup>+</sup>/NADH ratio, decreased acetyl-CoA production, and altered glucose metabolism. After G-Rg2 intervention, different degrees of metabolic recovery were observed (P&lt;0.05 or P&lt;0.01). When PDHE1 &#x3b1; was silenced, the silenced group showed a similar metabolic damage phenotype induced by high glucose, compared with the normal group. After PDHE1 &#x3b1; silencing, glucose modeling further aggravated the damage. In the injury model of PDHE1 &#x3b1; silencing with glucose induction, G-Rg2 showed different degrees of metabolic recovery after intervention (P&lt;0.05 or P&lt;0.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">PDHE1 &#x3b1; can be used as a direct cell target for G-Rg2 to treat high glucose-injured neurons, which can provide data support for the protein activity of PDHE1 &#x3b1; and the pharmacological activity of G-Rg2 in improving neurodegenerative diseases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Chinese Journal of Integrated Traditional and Western Medicine Press and Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Lian-Lian</ForeName><Initials>LL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ministry of Education for TCM Viscera-State Theory and Applications, Liaoning University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shenyang, 110847, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National and Local Joint Engineering Laboratory for Integrated Chinese and Western Medicine Prevention and Treatment Technology on Cardio-Brain Diseases, Liaoning University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shenyang, 110847, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Dan-Feng</ForeName><Initials>DF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Integrated Chinese and Western Medicine, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing, 210023, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Qi-Ge</ForeName><Initials>QG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ministry of Education for TCM Viscera-State Theory and Applications, Liaoning University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shenyang, 110847, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National and Local Joint Engineering Laboratory for Integrated Chinese and Western Medicine Prevention and Treatment Technology on Cardio-Brain Diseases, Liaoning University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shenyang, 110847, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Tong</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency Ward, The First Affiliated Hospital of Liaoning University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shenyang, 110032, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhan</LastName><ForeName>Li-Bin</ForeName><Initials>LB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ministry of Education for TCM Viscera-State Theory and Applications, Liaoning University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shenyang, 110847, China. zlblibin2021@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National and Local Joint Engineering Laboratory for Integrated Chinese and Western Medicine Prevention and Treatment Technology on Cardio-Brain Diseases, Liaoning University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shenyang, 110847, China. zlblibin2021@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China</Country><MedlineTA>Chin J Integr Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101181180</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1672-0415</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HT22 cell line</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cellular thermal shift assay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ginsenoside Rg2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hippocampal neuronal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pyruvate dehydrogenase E1 component subunit alpha</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest. The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41920259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11655-026-3946-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11655-026-3946-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Cecarini V, Cuccioloni M, Bonfili L, Gong C, Angeletti M, et al. Ginsenosides Rg1 and Rg2 activate autophagy and attenuate oxidative stress in neuroblastoma cells overexpressing A&#x3b2; (1&#x2013;42). Antioxidants (Basel) 2024;13:310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox13030310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38539843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10967604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L, Xu L, Huang Y, Xie C, Dou D, Xu J. Correlations between ecological factors and the chemical compositions of mountainous forest cultivated ginseng. J Food Compos Anal 2022;114:104867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfca.2022.104867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng B, Gao W, Wu X, Zheng M, Yu Y, Song C, et al. Ginsenoside Rg2 ameliorates high-fat diet-induced metabolic disease through SIRT1. J Agric Food Chem 2020;68:4215&#x2013;4226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jafc.0c00833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32181656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye X, Shao S, Wang Y, Su W. Ginsenoside Rg2 alleviates neurovascular damage in 3xTg-AD mice with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease through the MAPK-ERK pathway. J Chem Neuroanat 2023;133:102346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jchemneu.2023.102346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37805189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrnoosh F, Rezaei D, Pakmehr SA, Nataj PG, Sattar M, Shadi M, et al. The role of Panax ginseng in neurodegenerative disorders: mechanisms, benefits, and future directions. Metab Brain Dis 2025;40:183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11011-025-01610-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40232582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui J, Wang J, Zheng M, Gou D, Liu C, Zhou Y. Ginsenoside Rg2 protects PC12 cells against &#x3b2;-amyloid<sub>25&#x2013;35</sub>-induced apoptosis via the phosphoinositide 3-kinase/Akt pathway. Chem Biol Interact 2017;275:152&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cbi.2017.07.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28756148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan W, Fan L, Wang Z, Mei Y, Liu L, Li L, et al. Rare ginsenosides: a unique perspective of ginseng research. J Adv Res 2024;66:303&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jare.2024.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38195040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11674801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JJ, Chen KC, Zhou Y, Wei H, Qi MH, Wang Z, et al. Evaluating the effects of mitochondrial autophagy flux on ginsenoside Rg2 for delaying D-galactose induced brain aging in mice. Phytomedicine 2022;104:154341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phymed.2022.154341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35870376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Che L, Zhu C, Huang L, Xu H, Ma X, Luo X, et al. Ginsenoside Rg2 promotes the proliferation and stemness maintenance of porcine mesenchymal stem cells through autophagy induction. Foods 2023;12:1075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/foods12051075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36900592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10000966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Lu M, Lyu Q, Shi L, Zhou C, Li M, et al. Mitochondrial dynamics dysfunction: unraveling the hidden link to depression. Biomed Pharmacother 2024;175:116656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2024.116656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38678964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhold S, Zdanowicz R, Giese C, Glockshuber R. Dimerization of a 5-kDa domain defines the architecture of the 5-MDa gammaproteobacterial pyruvate dehydrogenase complex. Sci Adv 2024;10:eadj6358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.adj6358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38324697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10849603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou T, Zhong Y, Zhang Y, Zhou Y. Pyruvate dehydrogenase complex in neonatal hypoxic-ischemic brain injury. ACS Pharmacol Transl Sci 2023;7:42&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsptsci.3c00191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38230287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10789137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Xie Z, Lei X, Yang X, Huang S, Yuan W, et al. Recent advances in pyruvate dehydrogenase kinase inhibitors: structures, inhibitory mechanisms and biological activities. Bioorg Chem 2024;144:107160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bioorg.2024.107160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38301426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stacpoole PW, McCall CE. The pyruvate dehydrogenase complex: life&#x2019;s essential, vulnerable and druggable energy homeostat. Mitochondrion 2023;70:59&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mito.2023.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36863425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou W, Tang Z, Li Y, Lu L, Bi T, Zhan L. Hippocampal PDHA1 gene knockout inhibits the Warburg effect leading to cognitive dysfunction and attenuates the beneficial effects of Zibupiyin Recipe on cognition. J Ethnopharmacol 2025;337:118895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2024.118895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39374880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W, Sun X, Zhan L, Zhou W, Bi T. Conditional knockout of Pdha1 in mouse hippocampus impairs cognitive function: the possible involvement of lactate. Front Neurosci 2021;15:767560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2021.767560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34720870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8552971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu SY, Zhang XW, Gao G, Liu CX, Chen H, Fu ZX, et al. Pseudolaric acid B alleviates non-alcoholic fatty liver disease by targeting PPAR&#x3b1; to regulate lipid metabolism and promote mitochondrial biogenesis. Chin J Integr Med 2025;31:877&#x2013;888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11655-025-3832-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40515882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai L, Hu F, Fu W, Yu X, Zhong W, Liu F, et al. Ginsenoside Rg2 ameliorates brain injury after intracerebral hemorrhage in a rat model of preeclampsia. Reprod Sci 2021;28:3431&#x2013;3439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43032-021-00692-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34270001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Z, Chen P, Li C, Deng S, Yang H. Chip-DSF: a rapid screening strategy for drug protein targets. Pharmacol Res 2022;182:106346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2022.106346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35809766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friman T. Mass spectrometry-based cellular thermal shift assay (CETSA&#xae;) for target deconvolution in phenotypic drug discovery. Bioorg Med Chem 2020;28:115174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bmc.2019.115174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31767405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dienel GA. Brain glucose metabolism: integration of energetics with function. Physiol Rev 2019;99:949&#x2013;1045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00062.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30565508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zong WX, Rabinowitz JD, White E. Mitochondria and cancer. Mol Cell 2016;61:667&#x2013;676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molcel.2016.02.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26942671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4779192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng N, Zhang Z, Zheng H, Ma C, Li M, Wang Z, et al. Scutellarin rescued mitochondrial damage through ameliorating mitochondrial glucose oxidation via the PDK-PDC axis. Adv Sci (Weinh) 2023;10:e2303584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/advs.202303584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37750289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10646256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon JH, Thoudam T, Choi EJ, Kim MJ, Harris RA, Lee IK. Loss of metabolic flexibility as a result of overexpression of pyruvate dehydrogenase kinases in muscle, liver and the immune system: therapeutic targets in metabolic diseases. J Diabetes Investig 2021;12:21&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdi.13345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32628351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Yang H, Geerts C, Furtos A, Waters P, Cyr D, et al. The multiple facets of acetyl-CoA metabolism: energetics, biosynthesis, regulation, acylation and inborn errors. Mol Genet Metab 2023;138:106966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymgme.2022.106966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36528988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luengo A, Li Z, Gui DY, Sullivan LB, Zagorulya M, Do BT, et al. Increased demand for NAD<sup>+</sup> relative to ATP drives aerobic glycolysis. Mol Cell 2021;81:691&#x2013;707.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molcel.2020.12.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33382985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MJ, Lee H, Chanda D, Thoudam T, Kang HJ, Harris RA, et al. The role of pyruvate metabolism in mitochondrial quality control and inflammation. Mol Cells 2023;46:259&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14348/molcells.2023.2128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36756776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10183795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stacpoole PW. Therapeutic targeting of the pyruvate dehydrogenase complex/pyruvate dehydrogenase kinase (PDC/PDK) axis in cancer. J Natl Cancer Inst 2017;109:djx071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnci/djx071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Cooper DE, Cluntun AA, Warmoes MO, Zhao S, Reid MA, et al. Acetate production from glucose and coupling to mitochondrial metabolism in mammals. Cell 2018;175:502&#x2013;513.e13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2018.08.040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30245009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6173642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peoples JN, Saraf A, Ghazal N, Pham TT, Kwong JQ. Mitochondrial dysfunction and oxidative stress in heart disease. Exp Mol Med 2019;51:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s12276-019-0355-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31857574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6923355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lennicke C, Cochem&#xe9; HM. Redox metabolism: ROS as specific molecular regulators of cell signaling and function. Mol Cell 2021;81:3691&#x2013;3707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molcel.2021.08.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34547234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chornyi S, Costa CF, IJlst L, Fransen M, Wanders RJA, van Roermund CWT, et al. Human peroxisomal NAD<sup>+</sup>/NADH homeostasis is regulated by two independent NAD(H) shuttle systems. Free Radic Biol Med 2023;206:22&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2023.06.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37355054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rimal S, Tantray I, Li Y, Pal Khaket T, Li Y, Bhurtel S, et al. Reverse electron transfer is activated during aging and contributes to aging and age-related disease. EMBO Rep 2023;24:e55548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15252/embr.202255548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36794623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10074108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>