<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41676297</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1943-8141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of translational research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Transl Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Psychological intervention as an adjunct to sedation and analgesia: benefits for emotional state, resilience, and postoperative recovery among emergency multiple trauma patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>421</StartPage><EndPage>431</EndPage><MedlinePgn>421-431</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.62347/DMQZ9016</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to explore the impact of combining sedation and analgesia management with psychological intervention for the rehabilitation of emergency patients with multiple trauma.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This retrospective study included 211 multiple trauma patients with traumatic fracture who were admitted to the First Affiliated Hospital of Bengbu Medical University between January 2020 and October 2024. Based on the intervention strategy, patients were assigned to either the conventional intervention group (n=102) or the conventional + psychological intervention group (n=109). The conventional intervention group received conventional sedation, analgesia and rehabilitation training. The conventional + psychological intervention group got added psychological intervention carried out by professional psychologists. The two patient groups were compared in terms of negative emotion, post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), psychological resilience, incidence of postoperative adverse reactions, and quality of life.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">After the intervention, the Self-rating Anxiety Scale (SAS) score (42.80&#xb1;5.60), Self-rating Depression Scale (SDS) score (40.36&#xb1;6.23), and all dimension scores of the PTSD Checklist-Civilian Version (PCL-C) in the conventional + psychological intervention group were significantly lower than those of the conventional intervention group (all <i>P</i>&lt;0.05). In contrast, the conventional + psychological intervention group showed significantly higher scores for all dimensions of the Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale (CD-RISC) and World Health Organization Quality of Life-BREF (WHOQOL-BREF), as well as a significantly lower incidence of postoperative adverse reactions, compared to the conventional group (all <i>P</i>&lt;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The combination of sedation and analgesia management with psychological intervention in emergency multiple trauma patients improved negative emotional states, psychological resilience, and quality of life, and reduced PTSD and postoperative complications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>AJTR Copyright &#xa9; 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhai</LastName><ForeName>Xiaohui</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Bengbu Medical University Bengbu 233000, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ziyao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Bengbu Medical University Bengbu 233000, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhai</LastName><ForeName>Xiaomin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology Chemotherapy, First Affiliated Hospital of University of Science and Technology of China Hefei 230000, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Bingmei</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Bengbu Medical University Bengbu 233000, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Bengbu Medical University Bengbu 233000, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Transl Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101493030</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1943-8141</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychological intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">application effect</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multiple trauma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychological condition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation treatment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41676297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12886130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62347/DMQZ9016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lingitz MT, Wollner G, Bauer J, Kuehtreiber H, Mildner M, Copic D, Bormann D, Direder M, Krenn CG, Haider T, Negrin LL, Ankersmit HJ. Elevation of neutrophil-derived factors in patients after multiple trauma. J Cell Mol Med. 2023;27:1859&#x2013;1866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10315721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37328954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Breugel JMM, Niemeyer MJS, Houwert RM, Groenwold RHH, Leenen LPH, van Wessem KJP. Global changes in mortality rates in polytrauma patients admitted to the ICU-a systematic review. World J Emerg Surg. 2020;15:55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7526208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32998744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barabino E, Pittaluga G, Nivolli A, Ivaldi D, Arn&#xf2; M, Gazzo P. Endovascular management of iatrogenic arterial injuries after orthopedic surgery of the lower limb. J Vasc Interv Radiol. 2023;34:1054&#x2013;1061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36775015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papathanassoglou ED. Psychological support and outcomes for ICU patients. Nurs Crit Care. 2010;15:118&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20500650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mure&#x219;anu IA, Grad DA, Mure&#x219;anu DF, Dobran SA, Hapca E, Strilciuc &#x218;, Benedek I, Capri&#x219; D, Popescu BO, Perju-Dumbrav&#x103; L, Chereche&#x219; RM. Evaluation of post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) and related comorbidities in clinical studies. J Med Life. 2022;15:436&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9126456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35646173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu YY, Lu XM, Shao CY, Wang CC, Xu TT, Zhang BL. Empathetic nursing with mindful cognitive therapy for fatigue, depression, and negative emotions in leukemia patients undergoing long-term chemotherapy. World J Clin Cases. 2022;10:1826&#x2013;1833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8891779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35317141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent JL, Shehabi Y, Walsh TS, Pandharipande PP, Ball JA, Spronk P, Longrois D, Str&#xf8;m T, Conti G, Funk GC, Badenes R, Mantz J, Spies C, Takala J. Comfort and patient-centred care without excessive sedation: the eCASH concept. Intensive Care Med. 2016;42:962&#x2013;971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4846689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27075762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F, Yao K, Liu X. Analysis on effect of psychological nursing combined with extended care for improving negative emotions and self-care ability in patients with colorectal cancer and enterostomy: a retrospective study. Medicine (Baltimore) 2024;103:e38165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11124709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38788010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Xie X, Xu H, Li H. A psychological nursing intervention for patients with breast cancer on inflammatory factors, negative emotions and quality of life. Iran J Public Health. 2022;51:2041&#x2013;2047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9884377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36743364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, Xia Y, Fan X, Chen Y, Li C, Zhang J. Influence of psychological nursing procedure on negative emotion, stress state, quality of life and nursing satisfaction in patients with lung cancer radical operation. Front Surg. 2022;9:899033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9115546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35599803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zung WW. A rating instrument for anxiety disorders. Psychosomatics. 1971;12:371&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5172928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zung WW, Richards CB, Short MJ. Self-rating depression scale in an outpatient clinic. Further validation of the SDS. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 1965;13:508&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4378854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei C, Han J, Zhang Y, Hannak W, Liu Z. The characteristics of emotional response of post-traumatic stress disorder and post-traumatic growth among Chinese adults exposed to an explosion incident. Front Public Health. 2017;5:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5296354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28229068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L, Tan Y, Liu Y. Factor structure and psychometric evaluation of the connor-davidson resilience scale in a new employee population of China. BMC Psychiatry. 2017;17:49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5290619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28152997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skevington SM, Lotfy M, O&#x2019;Connell KA WHOQOL Group. The World Health Organization&#x2019;s WHOQOL-BREF quality of life assessment: psychometric properties and results of the international field trial. A report from the WHOQOL group. Qual Life Res. 2004;13:299&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15085902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee K, Schubl SD, Tominaga G, Cantrell S, Kim B, Haines KL, Kaups KL, Barraco R, Staudenmayer K, Knowlton LM, Shiroff AM, Bauman ZM, Brooks SE, Kaafarani H, Crandall M, Nirula R, Agarwal SK Jr, Como JJ, Haut ER, Kasotakis G. Non-surgical management and analgesia strategies for older adults with multiple rib fractures: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and joint practice management guideline from the Eastern association for the surgery of trauma and the chest wall injury society. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2023;94:398&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36730672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maercker A, Cloitre M, Bachem R, Schlumpf YR, Khoury B, Hitchcock C, Bohus M. Complex post-traumatic stress disorder. Lancet. 2022;400:60&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35780794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strayer RJ. Management of pain and agitation in trauma. Emerg Med Clin North Am. 2023;41:117&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36424036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leri J, Cisler JM, Dodd CG, Clark SL, Taylor L, Theodorou A, Belford A, Liberzon I, Rathouz PJ, Newport DJ, Devargas C, Wagner K, Nemeroff CB. The role of recurrent trauma on post-traumatic stress disorder symptoms and substance use among trauma exposed youth. Psychiatry Res. 2024;338:115980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11450678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38833935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoppen TH, Meiser-Stedman R, Kip A, Birkeland MS, Morina N. The efficacy of psychological interventions for adult post-traumatic stress disorder following exposure to single versus multiple traumatic events: a meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Lancet Psychiatry. 2024;11:112&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38219762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>She SJ, Xu YY. Effect of CICARE communication nursing model combined with motivational psychological intervention in patients with post-intensive care unit syndrome. World J Psychiatry. 2023;13:707&#x2013;713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10523197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37771643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anghele M, Marina V, Moscu CA, Anghele AD, Dragomir L. Psycho-somatic evolution of patients with multiple traumatic injuries. Clin Pract. 2024;14:2419&#x2013;2432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11587048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39585017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheeler S, Davis D, Basch J, James G, Lehman B, Acord-Vira A. Cognitive behavioral therapy interventions for adults with traumatic brain injury (2013-2020) Am J Occup Ther. 2022;76(Suppl 2):7613393160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36166576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Yang L, Lin G, Huang B, Sheng X, Wang L, Chen L, Qiu X, Wu X, Lin R. The efficacy of progressive muscle relaxation training on cancer-related fatigue and quality of life in patients with cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled studies. Int J Nurs Stud. 2024;152:104694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38281450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe4;hk&#xf6;nen O, Paukkonen L, V&#xe4;h&#xe4;nikkil&#xe4; H, Oikarinen A. Perceived social support among percutaneous coronary intervention patients over a long-term follow-up period. Nurs Open. 2024;11:e2087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10853492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38332498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernardes SF, Rei A, Carvalho H. Assessing family social support for functional autonomy and dependence in pain: a psychometric study. J Pain. 2023;24:582&#x2013;592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36372361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J, Jin Z, Wang J, Wu Z, Xu T, Tong G, Shen E, Fan J, Jiang C, Wang J, Li X, Cong W, Lin L. FGF21 ameliorates septic liver injury by restraining proinflammatory macrophages activation through the autophagy/HIF-1&#x3b1; axis. J Adv Res. 2025;64:477&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11954821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38599281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senda M, Terada S, Fujiwara M, Yamada N. Venous thromboembolism in eating disorders: a retrospective observational study. Acta Med Okayama. 2023;77:131&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37094950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Basu R, Bauder AR, Quatramoni JG, Glaser J, Kalapatapu V, Gaffey AC. Endovascular repair of traumatic axillosubclavian artery injuries. J Vasc Surg Cases Innov Tech. 2021;8:23&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8743185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35036668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv B, Wang H, Zhang Z, Li W, Han G, Liu X, Zhang C. Nomogram for predicting postoperative deep vein thrombosis in patients with spinal fractures caused by high-energy injuries. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2024;144:171&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37792059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner AW. Cognitive-behavioral therapy for posttraumatic stress disorder: applications to injured trauma survivors. Semin Clin Neuropsychiatry. 2003;8:175&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12874738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madeleine P, Szeto GPY, Heredia-Rizo AM. Effects of biofeedback and strength training interventions on neck-shoulder sensory-motor responses among visual display unit users. A narrative review. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2024;79:102936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39321540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf8;seth GE, Eikemo M, Tr&#xf8;stheim M, Meier IM, Bj&#xf8;rnstad H, Asratian A, Pazmandi C, Tangen VW, Heilig M, Leknes S. Stress recovery with social support: a dyadic stress and support task. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2022;146:105949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36240542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbourn E, Brassel S, Steel J, Togher L. Perceptions of communication recovery following traumatic brain injury: a qualitative investigation across 2 years. Int J Lang Commun Disord. 2024;59:463&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36239151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>