<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41924771</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-5905</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>333</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biomaterials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biomaterials</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Self-assembled mesoporous bioglass polyphenol nanozymes for repairing musculoskeletal trauma.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>124153</StartPage><MedlinePgn>124153</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.biomaterials.2026.124153</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0142-9612(26)00177-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Volumetric Musculoskeletal Trauma (VMST), which is characterized by volumetric muscle loss accompanied by bone injury, poses a significant challenge to regenerative medicine. While current therapies primarily focus on the individual regeneration of muscle or bone, there is no systematic and integrated treatment strategy. In this study, we developed a CuMBG-PA, a copper-doped nanozyme based on mesoporous bioactive glass (MBG) and procyanidin (PA), for integrated muscle and bone repair of VMST. CuMBG-PA self-assembles into a stable polyphenol network via Cu-PA coordination bonds, enhancing PA stability and reactive oxygen species-scavenging capacity. In vitro and in vivo experiments demonstrated that CuMBG-PA promoted osteogenesis and myogenesis while exhibiting high biocompatibility and antibacterial activity. Single-cell RNA-sequencing results revealed that CuMBG-PA synergistically induces stem cell differentiation and promotes tissue repair through multiple myoskeletal shared metabolic pathways. Mechanistically, CuMBG-PA exerts its beneficial effects by increasing the number of Proteoglycan 4 (Prg4)&#xa0;+ fibro/adipogenic progenitor cells (FAPs), which highly express fibronectin and insulin-like growth factor. In addition, PRG4 regulates immune cells, removes overactivated muscle satellite cells, reduces muscle fibrosis, and promotes functional recovery during regeneration. In summary, this work demonstrates that the novel self-assembled CuMBG-PA nanozyme represents a potential biomaterial-based strategy for integrated muscle and bone repair in VMST.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Shuao</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Traumatic Orthopaedics, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Changzhou, 213003, China; Orthopaedic Institute, Suzhou Medical College, Soochow University, Suzhou, 215000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Yesheng</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedic Institute, Suzhou Medical College, Soochow University, Suzhou, 215000, China; Department of Orthopaedics, The First Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Soochow University, Suzhou, 215000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jia</LastName><ForeName>Zhihao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cambridge-Suda Genomic Resource Center, Suzhou Medical College, Soochow University, Suzhou, 215000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Rongzhao</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Renji Hospital, School of Medicine, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, 200127, China; Key Laboratory of Anesthesiology (Shanghai Jiao Tong University), Ministry of Education, Shanghai, 200127, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Yanxia</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedic Institute, Suzhou Medical College, Soochow University, Suzhou, 215000, China; Department of Orthopaedics, The First Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Soochow University, Suzhou, 215000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yige</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Traumatic Orthopaedics, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Changzhou, 213003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Yiwen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Traumatic Orthopaedics, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Changzhou, 213003, China. Electronic address: zyw3362@suda.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Ke</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Burn and Plastic Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Soochow University, Suzhou, 215006, China. Electronic address: like1234@suda.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedic Institute, Suzhou Medical College, Soochow University, Suzhou, 215000, China; Department of Orthopaedics, The First Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Soochow University, Suzhou, 215000, China. Electronic address: yxu1615@suda.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Wenge</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Traumatic Orthopaedics, The Third Affiliated Hospital of Soochow University, Changzhou, 213003, China. Electronic address: flying_ding@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Biomaterials</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8100316</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0142-9612</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mesoporous bioactive glass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Musculoskeletal trauma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Polyphenol nanozymes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Proanthocyanidins</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-assembly</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41924771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biomaterials.2026.124153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0142-9612(26)00177-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>