<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41691220</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1472-6955</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Critical care nurses'knowledge, attitudes, and practices regarding thirst management and its affecting factors in mechanically ventilated patients: a cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">264</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12912-026-04432-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Thirst is a common and distressing complication among mechanically ventilated patients in intensive care units (ICUs), often leading to significant discomfort and adverse psychological consequences. ICU nurses play a pivotal role in the early identification and management of thirst; however, their knowledge, attitudes, and practices (KAP) regarding thirst management in mechanically ventilated patients remain insufficiently understood.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional survey was conducted between May 2023 and January 2024. An online questionnaire was distributed to ICU nurses from 14 secondary and tertiary general hospitals across seven prefecture-level regions in Hainan Province. The questionnaire assessed nurses' KAP related to thirst management in mechanically ventilated patients. Differences in KAP scores across participant characteristics were examined using t-tests and analysis of variance (ANOVA). Multivariate linear regression analysis was applied to identify independent influencing factors. Mediation analysis was performed to examine whether attitude mediated the association between knowledge and practice. The study was reported in accordance with the STROBE checklist.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 428 valid questionnaires were collected, yielding a response rate of 91.26%. The mean knowledge score was (13.33&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.90), the mean attitude score was (44.61&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;5.99), and the mean practice score was (32.97&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;8.03). Multivariate analyses indicated that age, hospital level, education level, participation in training, and exposure to relevant literature were significant influencing factors for nurses' KAP regarding thirst management (all P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Knowledge was associated with practice both directly and indirectly through the mediating role of attitude.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">ICU nurses demonstrated adequate knowledge and generally positive attitudes toward thirst management in mechanically ventilated patients; however, their clinical practices were relatively insufficient. Knowledge was associated with practice directly and indirectly via attitudes. Identifying gaps in knowledge and attitudes, clarifying influencing factors, and elucidating their interrelationships may inform the development of targeted, context-specific training programs to promote practice improvement, enhance patient comfort, and support recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL NUMBER" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Not applicable.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Zhaohao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of The Operation Room, Hainan General Hospital (Hainan Affiliated Hospital of Hainan Medical University), Haikou, Hainan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Liurong</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of The Operation Room, Hainan General Hospital (Hainan Affiliated Hospital of Hainan Medical University), Haikou, Hainan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Qiufang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Hainan General Hospital (Hainan Affiliated Hospital of Hainan Medical University), Haikou, Hainan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Weiyan</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, Hainan General Hospital (Hainan Affiliated Hospital of Hainan Medical University), Haikou, Hainan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Ting</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of The Operation Room, Hainan General Hospital (Hainan Affiliated Hospital of Hainan Medical University), Haikou, Hainan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jiaqi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of The Operation Room, Hainan General Hospital (Hainan Affiliated Hospital of Hainan Medical University), Haikou, Hainan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Shuai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, Hainan General Hospital (Hainan Affiliated Hospital of Hainan Medical University), Haikou, Hainan, China. hy303979@muhn.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Cailing</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Hainan Medical University, Haikou City, Hainan Province, China. 13876901387@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>WSJK2025QN019</GrantID><Agency>Joint Program on Health Science &amp; Technology Innovation of Hainan Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088683</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6955</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Attitude</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanical ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Practice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thirst</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The protocol of this study was approved by the Medical Ethics Committee of Hainan general Hospital(grant no:374;Aug/2022). All information regarding the objectives and procedure of the research was provided in writing to potential participants, in the form of an online form. At the end, written informed consent was requested in this same online form, before accessing the questionnaire. Data were collected anonymously, respecting the confidentiality of the data collected in this study. All procedures were performed in accordance with the ethical standards laid down in the 1964 Declaration of Helsinki and its later amendents. Consent for publication: All authors approved the final manuscript and the submission to the journal. Patient consent for publication not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41691220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13011743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-026-04432-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12912-026-04432-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Greenleaf JE. Problem: thirst, drinking behavior, and involuntary dehydration. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1992;24(6):645&#x2013;56. PMID: 1602937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-199206000-00007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1602937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negro A, Villa G, Greco M, Ciriolo E, Luraschi EL, Scaramuzzi J, Manara DF, Zangrillo A. Thirst in patients admitted to intensive care units: an observational study. Ir J Med Sci. 2022;191(5):2283&#x2013;9. 10.1007/s11845-021-02817-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11845-021-02817-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8526093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34668107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjeldsen CL, Hansen MS, Jensen K, Holm A, Haahr A, Dreyer P. Patients&#x2019; experience of thirst while being conscious and mechanically ventilated in the intensive care unit. Nurs Crit Care. 2018;23(2):75&#x2013;81. 10.1111/nicc.12277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nicc.12277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28124464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puntillo K, Nelson JE, Weissman D, Curtis R, Weiss S, Frontera J, Gabriel M, Hays R, Lustbader D, Mosenthal A, Mulkerin C, Ray D, Bassett R, Boss R, Brasel K, Campbell M. Palliative care in the ICU: relief of pain, dyspnea, and thirst&#x2013;a report from the IPAL-ICU advisory board. Intensive Care Med. 2014;40(2):235&#x2013;48. 10.1007/s00134-013-3153-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-013-3153-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5428539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24275901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang YN, Xie YB, Huang MC, et al. Analysis of thirst levels and influencing factors in patients undergoing noninvasive mechanical ventilation in the ICU [J]. J Nurs Sci. 2019;34(7):19&#x2013;21. doi:CNKI:SUN:HLXZ.0.2019-07-007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato K, Okajima M, Taniguchi T. Association of persistent intense thirst with delirium among critically ill patients: A Cross-sectional study. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2019;57(6):1114&#x2013;20. 10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2019.02.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2019.02.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30831240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin R, Li H, Chen L, He J. Prevalence of and risk factors for thirst in the intensive care unit: an observational study. J Clin Nurs. 2023;32(3&#x2013;4):465&#x2013;76. 10.1111/jocn.16257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.16257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10078651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35199411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins PR, Fonseca LF, Rossetto EG. Developing and validating the Perioperative Thirst Discomfort Scale. Rev Esc Enferm USP. 2017;51:e03240. English, Portuguese. 10.1590/S1980-220X2016029003240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28746560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>do Nascimento LA, Fonseca LF, Dos Santos CB. Inter-rater reliability testing of the safety protocol for thirst management. J Perianesth Nurs. 2018;33(4):527&#x2013;36. 10.1016/j.jopan.2016.07.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jopan.2016.07.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30077297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan Y, Luo Q, Zhong W, Zhao Y, Chen F, Zhang X, Chen J, Hu R. Efficacy and safety of different methods and doses for thirst management in orotracheally intubated and mechanically ventilated patients with &#x2018;nothing by mouth&#x2019;: A randomized, controlled three-arm trial. Intensive Crit Care Nurs. 2025;89(104012). 10.1016/j.iccn.2025.104012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40262406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Gu Q, Gu Y, Zhao Y, Zhu L. Symptom management to alleviate thirst and dry mouth in critically ill patients: A randomised controlled trial. Aust Crit Care. 2022;35(2):123&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.aucc.2021.04.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aucc.2021.04.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34119409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He ZH, Wang QF, Zheng GX, et al. Study on the efficacy of 4&#xb0;C Plum and licorice spray in alleviating thirst in mechanically ventilated ICU patients [J]. Gen Nurs. 2025;23(08):1452&#x2013;6. doi:CNKI:SUN:JTHS.0.2025-08-045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Mi J, Tang Y. A qualitative study of nurses&#x2019; perception on patients&#x2019; thirst in intensive care units. Intensive Crit Care Nurs. 2022;69:103184. 10.1016/j.iccn.2021.103184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.iccn.2021.103184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34893396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochbaum GM. Public participation in medical screening programs: A Socio-psychological Study. U.S. Department of Health, Education, and welfare. Tuberculosis Program: Public Health Service, Bureau of State Services, Division of Special Health Services; 1958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam J, El Nsouli D, Lee EL, Alqeisi T, Kane R, McGonagle I, Laparidou D, Nelson D, Armani K. Assessing the knowledge, attitudes and practices of healthcare staff and students regarding disposal of unwantead medications: a systematic review. BMJ Open. 2024;14(12):e093636. 10.1136/bmjopen-2024-093636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2024-093636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11667366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39719285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y, Lv J, Wang X, Yang F, Zhang W. Knowledge, attitude and practice regarding thirst management in surgical patients among intensive care unit nurses: A cross-sectional study. Nurs Crit Care. 2025;30(3):e13176. 10.1111/nicc.13176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nicc.13176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39382126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C, Tang H, Zhang X, Zhu C, Feng Y, Ye C. Knowledge, attitudes, and practices of the general population, herpes Zoster patients, and dermatologists toward herpes Zoster in china: A quantitative cross-sectional survey. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2024;20(1):2338980. 10.1080/21645515.2024.2338980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21645515.2024.2338980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11195449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38898574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, Pocock SJ, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Vandenbroucke JP, STROBE Initiative. The strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. J Clin Epidemiol. 2008;61(4):344&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2007.11.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2007.11.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18313558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F, Jiang ZX, Yang MJ, et al. Survey on ICU nurses&#x2019; recognition of thirst and intervention practices for mechanically ventilated patients in Guizhou Province [J]. Chin J Nurs. 2023;58(09):1104&#x2013;11. doi: CNKI:SUN:ZHHL.0.2023-09-012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei L, Xu J, Zhang C, Chen C, Chen J. Knowledge, attitude, and practice toward Azithromycin infusion reactions among pediatric nurses: a cross-sectional study. BMC Nurs. 2025;24(1):1005. 10.1186/s12912-025-03682-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-025-03682-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12317439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40751161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landstr&#xf6;m M, Rehn IM, Frisman GH. Perceptions of registered and enrolled nurses on thirst in mechanically ventilated adult patients in intensive care units-a phenomenographic study. Intensive Crit Care Nurs. 2009;25(3):133&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.iccn.2009.03.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.iccn.2009.03.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19394226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CL, Luo Q, Fu B, et al. Survey on thirst perception and analysis of influencing factors in patients undergoing endotracheal intubation and mechanical ventilation in critical care units [J]. Chin J Respiratory Crit Care Med. 2022;21(05):316&#x2013;21. doi: CNKI:SUN:ZGHW.0.2022-05-003.`.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho V, Goh G, Tang XR, See KC. Underrecognition and undertreatment of thirst among hospitalized patients with restricted oral feeding and drinking. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):13636. 10.1038/s41598-021-93048-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-93048-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8249500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34211006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Ning N, Chen JL, et al. Analysis of the current situation and research progress on thirst and discomfort in critically ill patients [J]. J Nurse Train. 2024;39(9):933&#x2013;8. 10.16821/j.cnki.hsjx.2024.09.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16821/j.cnki.hsjx.2024.09.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia LQ, Yang XY, Huang P, et al. Survey on ICU nurses&#x2019; knowledge and behavioral intentions regarding Xerostomia in critically ill patients [J]. Nurs Rehabilitation. 2020;19(2):78&#x2013;80. DOI:CNKI:SUN:HLKF.0.2020-02-027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allida SM, Inglis SC, Davidson PM, Hayward CS, Shehab S, Newton PJ. A survey of views and opinions of health professionals managing thirst in chronic heart failure. Contemp Nurse. 2016;52(2&#x2013;3):244&#x2013;52. 10.1080/10376178.2016.1190288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10376178.2016.1190288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27216416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bridges E, McNeill M, Munro N. Research in review: driving critical care practice change. Am J Crit Care. 2016;25(1):76&#x2013;84. 10.4037/ajcc2016564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4037/ajcc2016564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26724298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai S, Stotts N, Puntillo K. Thirst in critically ill patients: from physiology to sensation. Am J Crit Care. 2013;22(4):328&#x2013;35. 10.4037/ajcc2013533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4037/ajcc2013533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3718499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23817822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guttormson JL, Khan B, Brodsky MB, et al. Symptom assessment for mechanically ventilated patients: principles and priorities: an official American thoracic society workshop Report[J]. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2023;20(4):491&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1513/AnnalsATS.202301-023ST</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10112406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37000144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leemhuis A, Shichishima Y, Puntillo K. Palliation of thirst in intensive care unit patients: translating research into practice. Crit Care Nurse. 2019;39(5):21&#x2013;8. 10.4037/ccn2019544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4037/ccn2019544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31575591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutler CJ, Davis N. Improving oral care in patients receiving mechanical ventilation. Am J Crit Care. 2005;14(5):389&#x2013;94. PMID: 16120890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4037/ajcc2005.14.5.389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16120890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>