<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41711236</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1743-9159</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of surgery (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>All-suture soft anchors versus metal anchors in arthroscopic rotator cuff repair: a multicenter randomized clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JS9.0000000000004768</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The study investigates the safety and efficacy of all-suture soft anchors (ASSA) versus metal anchors (MA) in patients undergoing arthroscopic rotator cuff repair (ARCR) through a randomized controlled trial, assessing whether ASSA's advantages - reduced bone loss and simplified deployment - can achieve non-inferior clinical outcomes compared to conventional MA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a multicenter randomized controlled trial at five Chinese tertiary hospitals (Jan-Oct 2022), with final follow-up in December 2023. Eligible patients had small-to-medium full-thickness rotator cuff tears, Ellman III bursal-side tears, or Lafosse I-IV subscapularis tears. Participants were randomized 1:1 to ARCR with ASSA or MA, followed at 6&#xa0;weeks, 3, 6, and 12&#xa0;months. The outcome was included Constant-Murley Score (CMS), American shoulder and elbow surgeons (ASES) score, visual analog scale (VAS) pain, passive range of motion (PROM), and radiographic assessments (postoperative, 6/12&#xa0;months). All adverse events were recorded. Finally, 87 patients were randomized (ASSA&#xa0;=&#xa0;43, MA&#xa0;=&#xa0;44) and 85 received allocated treatment (42 vs 43).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">ASSA showed better midterm (6-month) functional recovery ( P =&#xa0;0.031) and pain reduction ( P =&#xa0;0.005). There was no difference in ASES, VAS, or adverse events (all P &gt; 0.05). After 12&#xa0;months, both groups showed improved CMS ( P &lt; 0.001), with no between-group difference ( P =&#xa0;0.900). No anchor dislocations observed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">ASSA showed comparable safety and efficacy to MA in ARCR after 12&#xa0;months of follow-up, with superior improvement in early functional recovery and pain alleviation in midterm (6-month) functional recovery and pain relief, supporting its use as an alternative suture anchor for ARCR.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Renhao</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Sports Medicine Center, Shanghai Institute of Traumatology and Orthopedics, Ruijin Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Qingsong</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Medicine, Wuhan Fourth Hospital, Puai Hospital Affiliated to Tongji Medical College of Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhuang</LastName><ForeName>Chengyu</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Sports Medicine Center, Shanghai Institute of Traumatology and Orthopedics, Ruijin Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Sports Medicine Center, Shanghai Institute of Traumatology and Orthopedics, Ruijin Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Luning</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Shanghai General Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Jiangsu Province Hospital of Chinese Medicine, Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Yao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Jiangsu Province Hospital of Chinese Medicine, Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Yushun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Medicine, Wuhan Fourth Hospital, Puai Hospital Affiliated to Tongji Medical College of Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Shaohua</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Medicine, Wuhan Fourth Hospital, Puai Hospital Affiliated to Tongji Medical College of Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yanan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Medicine, Wuhan Fourth Hospital, Puai Hospital Affiliated to Tongji Medical College of Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Yaohua</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Shanghai Sixth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Weilin</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Shanghai Sixth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Haiming</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Shanghai Sixth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Qingxiang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Shanghai Sixth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ge</LastName><ForeName>Hengan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Shanghai Tenth People's Hospital, Tongji University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Biao</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Tongji Hospital of Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1627-4618</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Sports Medicine Center, Shanghai Institute of Traumatology and Orthopedics, Ruijin Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Jiangsu Province Hospital of Chinese Medicine, Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101228232</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-9159</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">all-suture soft anchor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">arthroscopic rotator cuff repair</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metal anchor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">safety and efficacy outcomes</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41711236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JS9.0000000000004768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01279778-990000000-04672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bedi A, Bishop J, Keener J, et al. Rotator cuff tears. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2024;10:8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain NB, Ayers GD, Koudelkova H, et al. Operative vs nonoperative treatment for atraumatic rotator cuff tears: a trial protocol for the arthroscopic rotator cuff pragmatic randomized clinical trial. JAMA Network Open 2019;2:e199050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalla AA, and Pendegrass CJ. Biological approaches to the repair and regeneration of the rotator cuff tendon-bone enthesis: a literature review. Biomater Transl 2023;4:85&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visscher LE, Jeffery C, Gilmour T, et al. The history of suture anchors in orthopaedic surgery. Clin Biomech (Bristol) 2019;61:70&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milano G, Grasso A, Salvatore M, et al. Arthroscopic rotator cuff repair with metal and biodegradable suture anchors: a prospective randomized study. Arthroscopy 2010;26:S112&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma R, Chow R, Choi L, Diduch D. Arthroscopic rotator cuff repair: suture anchor properties, modes of failure and technical considerations. Expert Rev Med Devices 2011;8:377&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka M, Hayashida K, Kobayashi A, Kakiuchi M. Arthroscopic rotator cuff repair with absorbable sutures in the medial-row anchors. Arthroscopy 2015;31:2099&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrd JWT. Arthroscopic acetabular labral repair using the Q-FIX suture anchor. Arthrosc Tech 2019;8:e801&#x2013;e05.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suroto H, Anindita Satmoko B, Prajasari T, et al. Biodegradable vs nonbiodegradable suture anchors for rotator cuff repair: a systematic review and meta-analysis. EFORT Open Rev 2023;8:731&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaar TK, Schenck RC Jr, Wirth MA, Rockwood CA Jr. Complications of metallic suture anchors in shoulder surgery: a report of 8 cases. Arthroscopy 2001;17:31&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer JD, Robinson S, Hohn E, et al. Fixation methods and implants in shoulder stabilization: a historical perspective. J Orthop 2018;15:630&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang YS, Shih CA, Fang CJ, et al. Biomechanical comparison of different suture anchors used in rotator cuff repair surgery-all-suture anchors are equivalent to other suture anchors: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. J Exp Orthop 2023;10:45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du C, Chen W, Fang J, et al. Comparison of 3 different surgical techniques for rotator cuff repair in a rabbit model: direct suture, inlay suture, and Polyether Ether Ketone (PEEK) suture anchor. Am J Sports Med 2024;52:1428&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J-H, Park I, Hyun H-S, et al. Comparison of clinical outcomes and computed tomography analysis for tunnel diameter after arthroscopic bankart repair with the all-suture anchor and the biodegradable suture anchor. Arthroscopy 2019;35:1351&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ro K, Pancholi S, Son HS, Rhee YG. Perianchor cyst formation after arthroscopic rotator cuff repair using all-suture&#x2013;type, bioabsorbable-type, and PEEK-type anchors. Arthroscopy 2019;35:2284&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;l O, Okutan AE, Ayas MS. Arthroscopic glenoid labral lesion repair using all-suture anchor for traumatic anterior shoulder instability: short-term results. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2019;28:1991&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber FA, Lee Evanson JR. Editorial commentary: acetabular labral repair-is a knotless anchor better? Arthroscopy 2019;35:77&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan H, Zhao L, Wang J, et al. An all-suture anchor offers equivalent clinical performance to an established solid suture anchor in the arthroscopic repair of rotator cuff tears: a prospective, randomized, multicenter trial with 12-month follow-up. Arthroscopy 2024;40:265&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman TR, Lamplot JD, McClish SJ, et al. Three medial all suture anchors improves contact force compared to two hard body anchors in a biomechanical two-tendon rotator cuff tear model. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil 2022;4:e1601&#x2013;e07.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agha RA, Mathew G, Rashid R, et al. Transparency in the reporting of Artificial Intelligence&#x2013; the TITAN guideline. Prem J Sci 2025;10:100082&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz KF, Altman DG, Moher D, Group C. CONSORT 2010 statement: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. Bmj 2010;340:c332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blonna D, Scelsi M, Marini E, et al. Can we improve the reliability of the Constant-Murley score? J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2012;21:4&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugaya H, Maeda K, Matsuki K, Moriishi J. Repair integrity and functional outcome after arthroscopic double-row rotator cuff repair. A prospective outcome study. J Bone Joint Surg Am 2007;89:953&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lapner P, Li A, Pollock JW, et al. A multicenter randomized controlled trial comparing single-row with double-row fixation in arthroscopic rotator cuff repair: long-term follow-up. Am J Sports Med 2021;49:3021&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim KC, Lee WY, Shin HD, Han SC. Incomplete articular-side repair increase re-tear rate in full-thickness rotator cuff tears. J Orthop Surg (Hong Kong) 2018;26:2309499018760113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burks RT, Crim J, Brown N, et al. A prospective randomized clinical trial comparing arthroscopic single- and double-row rotator cuff repair: magnetic resonance imaging and early clinical evaluation. Am J Sports Med 2009;37:674&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kukkonen J, Kauko T, Vahlberg T, et al. Investigating minimal clinically important difference for Constant score in patients undergoing rotator cuff surgery. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2013;22:1650&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo UG, Petrillo S, Loppini M, et al. Metallic versus biodegradable suture anchors for rotator cuff repair: a case control study. BMC Musculoskeletal Disorders 2019;20:477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong JH, Shin SJ. Arthroscopic removal of proud metallic suture anchors after Bankart repair. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg 2009;129:1109&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver MD, Daigneault JP. Symptomatic interarticular migration of glenoid suture anchors. Arthroscopy 2000;16:102&#x2013;05.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozbaydar M, Elhassan B, Warner JJ. The use of anchors in shoulder surgery: a shift from metallic to bioabsorbable anchors. Arthroscopy 2007;23:1124&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micic I, Kholinne E, Kwak JM, et al. Osteolysis is observed around both bioabsorbable and nonabsorbable anchors on serial magnetic resonance images of patients undergoing arthroscopic rotator cuff repair. Acta Orthop Traumatol Turc 2019;53:414&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papalia R, Franceschi F, Diaz Balzani L, et al. The arthroscopic treatment of shoulder instability: bioabsorbable and standard metallic anchors produce equivalent clinical results. Arthroscopy 2014;30:1173&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain V, Gupta H, Mehta N, et al. Retrospective comparative analysis of clinical and functional outcome after arthroscopic bankart repair using all-suture anchor and metal anchor. Malays Orthop J 2024;18:11&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ntalos D, Huber G, Sellenschloh K, et al. All-suture anchor pullout results in decreased bone damage and depends on cortical thickness. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 2021;29:2212&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trofa DP, Bixby EC, Fleischli JE, Saltzman BM. All-suture anchors in orthopaedic surgery: design, rationale, biomechanical data, and clinical outcomes. J Am Acad Orthop Surg 2021;29:e950&#x2013;e60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minkus M, Aigner A, Wolke J, Scheibel M. All-suture anchor vs. knotless suture anchor for the treatment of anterior shoulder instability-a prospective cohort study. J Clin Med 2024;13:1381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglass NP, Behn AW, Safran MR. Cyclic and load to failure properties of all-suture anchors in synthetic acetabular and glenoid cancellous bone. Arthroscopy 2017;33:977&#x2013;85e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ergun S, Akgun U, Barber FA, Karahan M. The clinical and biomechanical performance of all-suture anchors: a systematic review. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil 2020;2:e263&#x2013;e75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber FA, Herbert MA. All-suture anchors: biomechanical analysis of pullout strength, displacement, and failure mode. Arthroscopy 2017;33:1113&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarantino U, Greggi C, Cariati I, et al. Reviewing bone marrow edema in athletes: a difficult diagnostic and clinical approach. Medicina 2021;57:1143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaibara T, Kondo E, Matsuoka M, et al. Progressive subchondral bone cyst formation following autologous chondrocyte implantation with all-suture anchors: a Case Report with histological evaluation. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2025;26:115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uluyard&#x131;mc&#x131; E, &#xd6;&#xe7;g&#xfc;der DA, Bozkurt &#x130;, et al. All-suture anchors versus metal suture anchors in the arthroscopic treatment of traumatic anterior shoulder instability: a comparison of mid-term outcomes. Jt Dis Relat Surg 2021;32:101&#x2013;07.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>