<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41815660</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2250-0685</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of orthopaedic case reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Orthop Case Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Day-Care Direct Anterior Total Hip Arthroplasty in Urban India: Patient Education, Apprehensions, and Outcomes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>307</StartPage><EndPage>314</EndPage><MedlinePgn>307-314</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.13107/jocr.2026.v16.i03.6978</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">While total hip arthroplasty (THA) has evolved toward outpatient care in many regions, its adoption in the Indian subcontinent remains limited due to cultural apprehensions, logistical barriers, and concerns regarding early discharge safety. This study evaluates the feasibility, safety, and functional outcomes of day-care direct anterior approach (DAA) THA in the urban Indian population using enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) protocols.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Data of 76 American society of anesthesiologist I/II patients, aged 22-50 years, with avascular necrosis of the femoral head who underwent DAA THA under a standardized ERAS protocol were retrospectively assessed. Pre-operative education, multimodal analgesia, and early mobilization were incorporated. Data on demographics, surgical metrics, length of stay (LOS), complications, and functional outcomes using Harris Hip score (HHS) and Western Ontario and McMaster Universities Osteoarthritis Index (WOMAC) scores were also analyzed postoperatively at 2- and 6-weeks, 6 months and 1 year.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The mean age was 35.1&#xb1;8.4 years (54 males, 22 females). The mean surgical time was 213.45&#xb1;22.13 min, with an average blood loss of 201.7&#xb1;20.72 mL. No intraoperative complications or transfusions were required. A total of 31 patients (40.8%) were discharged within 24 h, while 45 patients (59.2%) remained hospitalized beyond 24 h due to concerns about complications and post-operative symptoms. The longest stay was 3 days, due to post-operative nausea and vomiting. The average LOS was 1.8 days. At 1 year, the mean HHS increased from 44.6 (pre-operative) to 97.1, and the WOMAC score improved from 74.6 (pre-operative) to 10.2. No readmissions or major post-operative complications were observed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Day-care THA using DAA achieved high early functional outcomes through minimally invasive techniques, multimodal analgesia, and enhanced recovery protocols. Pre-operative counseling and structured discharge planning enabled a significant proportion of patients to opt for same-day discharge, though sociocultural apprehensions remained a barrier. Strengthening patient education, caregiver involvement, and post-operative support is essential to further improve acceptance of outpatient THA in the Indian population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; Indian Orthopaedic Research Group.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aneja</LastName><ForeName>Kunal</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgeon, Max Super Speciality Hospital, Shalimar Bagh, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Managing Director, Naveda Healthcare Centres, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bajwa</LastName><ForeName>Supreet</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgeon, Wockhardt Hospitals, Mumbai Central, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rudraraju</LastName><ForeName>Ravi Teja</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgeon, Apollo Hospitals, Hyderabad, Telangana, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic, SVS Medical College, Mahbubnagar, Telangana, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Machaiah</LastName><ForeName>Ponnanna Karineravanda</ForeName><Initials>PK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic surgeon, Sparsh Hospital, Yeshwanthpur, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Deep</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic, Wockhardt Hospitals, Mumbai Central, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Orthop Case Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101641392</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2250-0685</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Direct anterior approach</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">avascular necrosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">day care surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enhanced recovery after surgery protocols</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">total hip arthroplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urban Indian population</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest: Nil</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41815660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12973057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13107/jocr.2026.v16.i03.6978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JOCR-16-3-307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shapira J, Chen SL, Rosinsky PJ, Maldonado DR, Lall AC, Domb BG. Outcomes of outpatient total hip arthroplasty: A systematic review. Hip Int. 2021;31:4&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32157903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock M, Somerville L, Firth A, Lanting B. Outpatient total hip arthroplasty, total knee arthroplasty, and unicompartmental knee arthroplasty: A systematic review of the literature. JBJS Rev. 2016;4:e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28060788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Zhu H, Liao R. Enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) pathway for primary hip and knee arthroplasty: Study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2019;20:599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6805414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31640757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malek IA, Royce G, Bhatti SU, Whittaker JP, Phillips SP, Wilson IR, et al. A comparison between the direct anterior and posterior approaches for total hip arthroplasty: The role of an 'Enhanced Recovery'pathway. Bone Joint J. 2016;98-B:754&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27235516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu S, Qian W, Jiang C, Ye C, Chen X. Enhanced recovery after surgery for hip and knee arthroplasty: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Postgrad Med J. 2017;93:736&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5740550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28751437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galakatos GR. Direct anterior total hip arthroplasty. Mo Med. 2018;115:537&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6312152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30643349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamo-Espinosa JM, Mariscal G, G&#xf3;mez-&#xc1;lvarez J, Benlloch M, San-Juli&#xe1;n M. Causes and risk factors for same-day discharge failure after total hip and knee arthroplasty: A meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2024;14:12627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11144238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38824204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vehmeijer SB, Husted H, Kehlet H. Outpatient total hip and knee arthroplasty. Acta Orthop. 2018;89:141&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5901509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29202644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto T, Ridley RJ, Edmondston SJ, Visser M, Headford J, Yates PJ. Day-of-surgery mobilization reduces the length of stay after elective hip arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty. 2016;31:2227&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27209333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dash A, Senapati JN, Sahu MC. Evolvement of day care orthopaedic surgery in a tertiary care teaching institute. Int J Pharm Sci Rev Res. 2016;37:15&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padilla JA, Feng JE, Anoushiravani AA, Hozack WJ, Schwarzkopf R, Macaulay WB. Modifying patient expectations can enhance total hip arthroplasty postoperative satisfaction. J Arthroplasty. 2019;34:S209&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30795937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson JW, Wignadasan W, Ibrahim M, Beasley L, Konan S, Plastow R, et al. Day-case total hip arthroplasty: A literature review and development of a hospital pathway. Bone Jt Open. 2021;2:93&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7925215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33573396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sang W, Liu Y, Jiang Y, Xue S, Zhu L, Ma J. Direct anterior approach with enhanced recovery protocols in outpatient total hip replacement. Int J Clin Exp Med. 2020;13:3608&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berend KR, Lombardi AV, Jr, Berend ME, Adams JB, Morris MJ. The outpatient total hip arthroplasty: A paradigm change. Bone Joint J. 2018;100-B:31&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6424444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29292337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Yang Q, Lin J, Qian W, Jin J, Gao P, et al. Risk factors of postoperative nausea and vomiting after total hip arthroplasty or total knee arthroplasty: A retrospective study. Ann Transl Med. 2020;8:1088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7575972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33145307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal N, Chen AF, Padgett SE, Tan TL, Kheir MM, Hopper RH, Jr, et al. Otto aufranc award: A multicenter, randomized study of outpatient versus inpatient total hip arthroplasty. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2017;475:364&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5213925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27287858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kutzner KP, Meyer A, Bausch M, Schneider M, Rehbein P, Drees P, et al. Outcome of an &#x201c;Enhanced Recovery&#x201d; program in contemporary total hip arthroplasty in Germany. Z Orthop Unfall. 2020;158:214&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31525792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leiss F, G&#xf6;tz JS, Maderbacher G, Meyer M, Reinhard J, Zeman F, et al. Excellent functional outcome and quality of life after primary cementless total hip arthroplasty (THA) using an enhanced recovery setup. J Clin Med. 2021;10:621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7915727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33562021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly KP, Kamath AF. Direct anterior total hip arthroplasty: Comparative outcomes and contemporary results. World J Orthop. 2016;7:94&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4757663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26925380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Free MD, Owen DH, Agius PA, Pascoe EM, Harvie P. Direct anterior approach total hip arthroplasty: An adjunct to an enhanced recovery pathway: Outcomes and learning curve effects in surgeons transitioning from other surgical approaches. J Arthroplasty. 2018;33:3490&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30055885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Martino A, Keating C, Butsick MJ, Platano D, Berti L, Hunter LN, et al. Enhancing recovery: Surgical techniques and rehabilitation strategies after direct anterior hip arthroplasty. J Orthop Traumatol. 2024;25:45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11442739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39349698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen JR, Skovgaard B, Pryn&#xf8; T, Bendikas L, Mikkelsen LR, Laursen M, et al. Feasibility of day-case total hip arthroplasty: A single-centre observational study. Hip Int. 2017;27:60&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27791240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akutay S, Ceyhan &#xd6;. The relationship between fear of surgery and affecting factors in surgical patients. Perioper Med (Lond) 2023;12:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10251663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37296486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj V, Agarwal S, Kumar A, Bandil S. An analysis of socio-cultural barriers limiting timely discharge of patients after day care surgery: A prospective observational study. Int J Acad Med Pharm. 2024;6:156&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Londhe SB, Shah RV, Patwardhan M, Doshi AP, Londhe SS, Subhedar K. Understanding the apprehension and concern haunting patients before a total knee arthroplasty. Arthroplasty. 2021;3:14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8796401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35236475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker P, Andrews SN, Mathews K, Nishioka S, Nakasone CK. Stepping toward outpatient total hip arthroplasty with a rapid discharge protocol. J Orthop. 2021;27:153&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8498222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34650323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraser JF, Danoff JR, Manrique J, Reynolds MJ, Hozack WJ. Identifying reasons for failed same-day discharge following primary total hip arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty. 2018;33:3624&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30172415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moulton LS, Evans PA, Starks I, Smith T. Pre-operative education prior to elective hip arthroplasty surgery improves postoperative outcome. Int Orthop. 2015;39:1483&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25862634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muthu S, Jeyaraman M, Jeyaraman N, Ramasubramanian S. Optimizing outcomes: Implementing enhanced recovery after surgery in orthopedic surgery. World J Methodol. 2024;14:95558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11287533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39712558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>