<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41859583</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does Pronator Quadratus Repair Affect the Functional Outcome Following Volar Plate Fixation for Distal End Radius Fracture?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103695</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103695</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103695</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103695</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background and objective Distal radius fractures represent the most common upper extremity injury requiring surgical intervention. Volar plate fixation necessitates division of the pronator quadratus muscle, yet the necessity of systematic muscle repair remains controversial. While some studies suggest enhanced functional outcomes with repair, others demonstrate equivalent recovery patterns regardless of muscle reconstruction. This study aimed to analyze functional outcomes following volar plate fixation for distal radius fractures, comparing patients with and without pronator quadratus repair. Methodology&#xa0; A retrospective cohort study was conducted involving sixty patients with displaced distal radius fractures treated with volar plate fixation between September 2023 and October 2024. Patients were stratified into pronator quadratus repair (n=31) and non-repair (n=29) groups. Functional assessment utilized the validated Patient-Rated Wrist Evaluation questionnaire at eight weeks, three months, and six months postoperatively. Additional measurements included range of motion parameters, grip strength assessment using standardized dynamometry, and isokinetic forearm rotation strength evaluation. Statistical analysis employed independent t-tests, chi-square tests, repeated measures analysis of variance, and multivariate linear regression modeling. Results No significant differences existed in baseline demographics between groups. Patient-Rated Wrist Evaluation scores demonstrated equivalent functional recovery at six months, with scores of 105.65 &#xb1; 13.15 versus 107.07 &#xb1; 12.43 (p=0.663). While initial advantages occurred in pronation strength 58.55 &#xb1; 4.12 degrees versus 55.17 &#xb1; 4.12 degrees (p=0.002) and wrist extension 65.97 &#xb1; 5.23 degrees versus 60.17 &#xb1; 1.63 degrees (p&lt;0.001) in the repair group, grip strength showed no significant differences 6.16 &#xb1; 0.90 versus 6.07 &#xb1; 0.96 (p=0.695). Satisfactory isokinetic rotation strength was achieved in 71% versus 69% of patients, respectively (p=0.863). Multivariate regression confirmed that pronator quadratus repair was not a significant predictor of functional outcomes. Conclusion Pronator quadratus repair following volar plate fixation does not significantly improve long-term functional outcomes despite initial mild biomechanical advantages. These findings support surgical decision-making frameworks that prioritize operative efficiency without compromising patient care standards, while acknowledging potential protective benefits for soft tissue coverage.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Ravishankar et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ravishankar</LastName><ForeName>Kashyap</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Sri Devaraj Urs Medical College, Kolar, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar K</LastName><ForeName>Vinod</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Sri Devaraj Urs Medical College, Kolar, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumaar</LastName><ForeName>Arun</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Sri Devaraj Urs Medical College, Kolar, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shanthappa</LastName><ForeName>Arun H</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Sri Devaraj Urs Medical College, Kolar, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bone plates</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">distal radius fractures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pronator quadratus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery of function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wrist joint</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Central Ethics Committee (CEC), Sri Devaraj Urs Academy of Higher Education and Research (SDUAHER) issued approval SDUAHER/RND/CEC/SDUMC-PG/121/NF/-2025-26. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41859583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12997136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Functional outcome and complications after volar plating for dorsally displaced, unstable fractures of the distal radius. Rozental TD, Blazar PE. https://www.jhandsurg.org/article/S0363-5023(05)00806-3/abstract. J Hand Surg Am. 2006;31:359&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16516728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Threaded pin and volar plate fixation of distal radius fractures: early functional recovery. Vaida J, Luchini PM, Glener JE, Kessler MW, McCabe LA, Taras JS. https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2589514121000499. J Hand Surg Glob Online. 2021;3:245&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8991605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35415575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The importance of pronator quadratus repair in the treatment of distal radius fractures with volar plating. Ahsan ZS, Yao J. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23997732/ Hand (N Y) 2012;7:276&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3418361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23997732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effects of pronator quadratus repair on outcomes after volar plating of distal radius fractures. Hershman SH, Immerman I, Bechtel C, Lekic N, Paksima N, Egol KA. https://journals.lww.com/jorthotrauma/FullText/2013/03000/The_Effects_of_Pronator_Quadratus_Repair_on.3.aspx. J Orthop Trauma. 2013;27:130&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22664580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A systematic review and meta-analysis of the pronator quadratus repair following volar plating of distal radius fractures. Lu CK, Liu WC, Chang CC, Shih CL, Fu YC, Jupiter JB. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32938491/ J Orthop Surg Res. 2020;15:419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7493143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32938491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Is pronator quadratus repair necessary to improve outcomes after volar plate fixation of distal radius fractures? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Shi F, Ren L. https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1877056820301912. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2020;106:1627&#x2013;1635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33189664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pronator quadratus repair after volar plate fixation in distal radial fractures: evaluation of the clinical and functional outcome and of the protective role on the flexor tendons-a randomized controlled study. Goorens CK, De Keyzer PB, Van Royen K, Provyn S, Goubau JF. https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00590-020-02804-1. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol. 2021;31:541&#x2013;548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33047176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prospective evaluation of pronator quadratus repair following volar plate fixation of distal radius fractures. Tosti R, Ilyas AM. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23916193/ J Hand Surg Am. 2013;38:1678&#x2013;1684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23916193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biomechanical comparison of pronator quadratus repair techniques in the modified henry approach for distal radius fracture. Marmen A, Lepine J, Leblanc E, Balg F. https://journals.lww.com/techortho/_layouts/15/oaks.journals/downloadpdf.aspx?an=00013611-202012000-00015 Tech Orthop. 2020;35:300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Do we really need to repair the pronator quadratus after distal radius plating? Pathak S, Anjum R, Gautam RK, Maheshwari P, Aggarwal J, Sharma A, Pruthi V. https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1008127519303268. Chin J Traumatol. 2019;22:345&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6921198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31753761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Does access through the pronator quadratus influence pronation strength in palmar plate fixation of distal radius fractures in elderly patients? Falk SS, Maksimow A, Mittlmeier T, Gradl G. https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00402-023-04847-5. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2023;143:5445&#x2013;5454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10374697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36973374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consistency of AO fracture classification for the distal radius. Kreder HJ, Hanel DP, McKee M, Jupiter J, McGillivary G, Swiontkowski MF. https://boneandjoint.org.uk/article/10.1302/0301-620X.78B5.0780726. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 1996;78:726&#x2013;731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8836058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>No effect on functional outcome after repair of pronator quadratus in volar plating of distal radial fractures: a randomized clinical trial. Sonntag J, Woythal L, Rasmussen P, et al. Bone Joint J. 2019;101-B:1498&#x2013;1505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31787001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patient rating of wrist pain and disability: a reliable and valid measurement tool. MacDermid JC, Turgeon T, Richards RS, Beadle M, Roth JH. https://journals.lww.com/jorthotrauma/abstract/1998/11000/patient_rating_of_wrist_pain_and_disability__a.9.aspx. J Orthop Trauma. 1998;12:577&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9840793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Development of a scale for patient rating of wrist pain and disability. MacDermid JC. J Hand Ther. 1996;9:178&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8784681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDermid J, Solomon G, Valdes K. American Society of Hand Therapists. American Society of Hand Therapists: American Society of Hand Therapists; 2015. Clinical Assessment Recommendations, 3rd Edition.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of pronator quadratus repair on outcome after volar plating of distal radius fracture. Maharjan R, Shrestha BP, Chaudhary P, Rijal R. https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Rajiv-Maharjan/publication/345016946_The_effect_of_pronator_quadratus_repair_on_outcome_after_volar_plating_of_distal_radius_fracture/links/609e98ea299bf1476999da6c/The-effect-of-pronator-quadratus-repair-on-outcome-after-volar-plating-of-distal-radius-fracture.pdf Int J Orthop Sci. 2020;6:801&#x2013;807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pronator quadratus repair does not affect reoperation rates following volar locking plate fixation of distal radius fractures. Meyer MA, Benavent KA, Janssen SJ, Chruscielski CM, Blazar PE, Earp BE. https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/15589447211017239 Hand (N Y) 2022;17:31&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9793612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34105394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volar plating: functional recovery of the pronator quadratus. Porter P, MacInnes A, Drew T, Wang W, Abboud R, Nicol G. https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00590-021-03133-7. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol. 2022;32:1535&#x2013;1541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9587960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34595550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of pronator quadratus muscle tear in distal radius fractures on patient outcomes: analyses of 55 patients in a volar locking plate arm of a randomized clinical trial. Eikrem M, Lian T, Madsen JE, Figved W. https://cureus.com/articles/247584-impact-of-pronator-quadratus-muscle-tear-in-distal-radius-fractures-on-patient-outcomes-analyses-of-55-patients-in-a-volar-locking-plate-arm-of-a-randomized-clinical-trial Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11102579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38765412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Repair of the pronator quadratus after volar plate fixation in distal radius fractures: a systematic review. Mulders MA, Walenkamp MM, Bos FJ, Schep NW, Goslings JC. https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11751-017-0288-4. Strategies Trauma Limb Reconstr. 2017;12:181&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5653597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28512698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>