<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41933020</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A novel intelligent framework for harnessing underground thermal energy through the optimization of grout and backfill thermophysical properties.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-46104-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Borehole heat exchanger-assisted underground thermal energy storage systems are increasingly employed to enhance the reliability of renewable and geothermal energy supply, yet their operational effectiveness is constrained by complex and nonlinear interactions between subsurface formations and engineered filling materials. This study presents an intelligent, integrated framework for the prediction, optimization, and prioritization of UTES configurations. The proposed approach couples machine-learning surrogate models with evolutionary multi-objective optimization and decision-analysis techniques to address the computational limitations of conventional simulation-based design. A numerical database derived from a finite-element representation of a single U-tube borehole embedded in a geological medium is used to train the models. Five governing parameters (rock thermal conductivity, heat capacity, and density, along with grout thermal conductivity and heat capacity) are selected as inputs, while supplied and recovered thermal energies are adopted as competing performance metrics. Multilayer perceptron neural networks optimized using genetic and cheetah-based algorithms demonstrate excellent predictive capability (R &#x2248; 0.99). These surrogates are embedded within a multi-objective artificial vultures optimization algorithm to construct a smooth and physically consistent Pareto front spanning supplied energies of approximately 1.27-2.29 GJ and recovered energies of 0.43-0.74 GJ. The results highlight the dominant influence of thermal conductivity, particularly that of grout, on energy recovery, with diminishing performance gains observed at extreme parameter values. Finally, the COPRAS method is employed to extract seven representative design alternatives reflecting different operational priorities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zandy Ilghani</LastName><ForeName>Nastaran</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Earth Sciences Engineering, Arak University of Technology, Arak, Iran. Nastaran_zandy@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maleki</LastName><ForeName>Hamid</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Isfahan University of Technology, Isfahan, 84156-83111, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Decision-making</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Geothermal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multi-objective optimization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multilayer perceptron neural networks</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renewable energy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Underground thermal energy storage</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41933020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-46104-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-46104-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fry, N., Adebayo, P., Tian, R., Shor, R. &amp; Mwesigye, A. A review of district energy technology with subsurface thermal storage integration. Geotherm. Energy 12(1), 29 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah, M., Prajapati, M., Yadav, K. &amp; Sircar, A. A comprehensive review of geothermal energy storage: Methods and applications. J. Energy Storage 98, 113019 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolo, I. et al. A comprehensive review of deep borehole heat exchangers (DBHEs): Subsurface modelling studies and applications. Geotherm. Energy 12(1), 19 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei, P., Sun, J., Liu, Y., Ran, R. &amp; Wang, Y. Properties of borehole heat exchangers in shallow bedrock: Insights and perspectives based on project data and rock mass characteristics. J. Energy Storage 130, 117463 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, C. et al. Assessing the technical potential for underground thermal energy storage in the UK. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 199, 114545 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albers, A. et al. In-situ thermal properties of grouting materials in borehole heat exchangers. Geotherm. Energy 13(1), 23 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud, M. et al. A review of grout materials in geothermal energy applications. Int. J. Thermofluids 10, 100070 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, A. A., Assadi, M., Kalantar, A., Sliwa, T. &amp; Sapi&#x144;ska-&#x15a;liwa, A. A critical review on the use of shallow geothermal energy systems for heating and cooling purposes. Energies 15(12), 4281 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eswiasi, A. &amp; Mukhopadhyaya, P. Critical review on efficiency of ground heat exchangers in heat pump systems. Clean Technol. 2(2), 204&#x2013;224 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heim, E. et al. Comparison of simulation tools for optimizing borehole heat exchanger field operation. Geothermal Energy 12(1), 24 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C., Sun, W., Fu, Q., Lu, Y. &amp; Zhang, P. Semi-analytical and numerical modeling of U-bend deep borehole heat exchanger. Renew. Energy 222, 119959 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, B., Lei, F. &amp; Shen, Z. A comprehensive simplified algorithm for heat transfer modeling of medium-deep borehole heat exchangers considering soil stratification and geothermal gradient. Energies 18(14), 3716 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delazar, A., Hu, E., Kotousov, A. &amp; Sofyan, S. E. A novel three-dimensional implicit numerical model of a borehole field heat exchanger that accounts for seasonal fluctuations of the soil temperature. Geothermics 97, 102236 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, C. S., Cassidy, N. J., Egan, S. S. &amp; Griffiths, D. Numerical modelling of deep coaxial borehole heat exchangers in the Cheshire Basin, UK. Comput. Geosci. 152, 104752 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, S. et al. Numerical modeling and thermal performance analysis of deep borehole heat exchangers considering groundwater seepage. Appl. Therm. Eng. 250, 123508 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, J. et al. Numerical research on the heat transfer model and performance of deep borehole heat exchangers combined with geothermal wells. Appl. Therm. Eng. 214, 118728 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia, Z. et al. Multi-factor optimization of thermo-economic performance of coaxial borehole heat exchanger geothermal system based on Levelized Cost of Energy analysis. Renew. Energy 219, 119513 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiru, W., Guohui, F., Weidong, L. &amp; Qiaoyu, L. Experimental and numerical study on heat storage and extraction characteristics of single and double U-tube borehole heat exchangers for thermal energy storage. Renewable Energy 257, 124792 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerme, E. D. &amp; Fung, A. S. Transient heat transfer simulation, analysis and thermal performance study of double U-tube borehole heat exchanger based on numerical heat transfer model. Appl. Therm. Eng. 173, 115189 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan, R. et al. A numerical study of damage evolution and crack propagation in backfill bodies of high-temperature thermal energy storage cavities in mines. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 171, 107362 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, G. et al. Thermomechanical behavior and damage mechanism of the lining backfill body of high-temperature thermal energy storage reservoirs in mines. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 171, 107409 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, H. et al. Automatic picking method for the first arrival time of microseismic signals based on fractal theory and feature fusion. Fractal Fract. 9(11), 679 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, W., Chen, C., Deng, J., Zeng, C. &amp; Zhang, W. Recent progress and advanced technologies in geothermal energy utilization for building heating and cooling. Front. Built Environ. 11, 1691631 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, N., Assadi, M., Ahmed, A. A. &amp; Banihabib, R. Optimal design, operational controls, and data-driven machine learning in sustainable borehole heat exchanger coupled heat pumps: Key implementation challenges and advancement opportunities. Energy Sustain. Dev. 74, 231&#x2013;257 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoaei, M., Noorollahi, Y., Hajinezhad, A. &amp; Moosavian, S. F. A review of the applications of artificial intelligence in renewable energy systems: An approach-based study. Energy Convers. Manag. 306, 118207 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Q., Li, Y. &amp; Li, R. Integrating artificial intelligence in energy transition: A comprehensive review. Energy Strategy Rev. 57, 101600 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, F. et al. Heat exchange capacity prediction of borehole heat exchanger (BHE) from infrastructure based on machine learning (ML) methods. IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst. 23(11), 22409&#x2013;22420 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, N., Assadi, M., Zhang, Q. &amp; &#x15a;liwa, T. Data-driven insights for improved heating and cooling predictions: Impact of input parameters on multivariate deep learning algorithms using geothermal borehole field data. Appl. Therm. Eng. 245, 122870 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Q. et al. A surrogate-based computational framework for optimizing thermal strategies in large multi-subsystem borehole heat exchanger sites. Energy 322, 135705 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, B. et al. Research on the heat extraction performance optimization of spiral fin coaxial borehole heat exchanger based on GA&#x2013;BPNN&#x2013;QLMPA. Processes 11(10), 2989 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King, M. &amp; Yune, C.-Y. Advanced machine learning techniques: Forecasting thermal resistance in borehole heat exchanger system through RSM and hybrid DFNN-GA approaches. Geothermics 120, 103004 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, S., Ullah, H., Abbasi, A. F., Ha, W. &amp; Lee, S. AI-driven prediction of borehole thermal resistance in coil-type energy piles considering 3D thermal interference. Case Stud. Therm. Eng. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.csite.2025.107211 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brettschneider, A. L. &amp; Perkovi&#x107;, L. Theoretical analysis of using multiple borehole heat exchangers for production of heating and cooling energy in shallow geothermal reservoirs with underground water flow. Appl. Therm. Eng. 254, 123914 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter, S. et al. Global sensitivity analysis and uncertainty quantification for design parameters of shallow geothermal systems. Geotherm. Energy 12(1), 8 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C. et al. A multi-parameter estimation of layered rock-soil thermal properties of borehole heat exchanger in a stratified subsurface. Renew. Energy 232, 121074 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wo&#x142;oszyn, J. &amp; Go&#x142;a&#x15b;, A. Sensitivity analysis of efficiency thermal energy storage on selected rock mass and grout parameters using design of experiment method. Energy Convers. Manag. 87, 1297&#x2013;1304 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schober, P., Boer, C. &amp; Schwarte, L. A. Correlation coefficients: Appropriate use and interpretation. Anesth. Analg. 126(5), 1763&#x2013;1768 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qamar, R. &amp; Zardari, B. A. Artificial neural networks: An overview. Mesopotam. J. Comput. Sci. 2023, 124&#x2013;133 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruse, R., Mostaghim, S., Borgelt, C., Braune, C., and Steinbrecher, M. Multi-layer perceptrons, in Computational intelligence: a methodological introduction: Springer, pp. 53&#x2013;124 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadhim, Z. S., Abdullah, H. S. &amp; Ghathwan, K. I. Artificial neural network hyperparameters optimization: A survey. Int. J. Online Biomed. Eng. 18(15), 59&#x2013;87 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang, Y. et al. Artificial neural network hyperparameters optimization for predicting the thermal conductivity of MXene/graphene nanofluids. J. Taiwan Inst. Chem. Eng. 164, 105673 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajab, H. et al. Enhancing solar energy conversion efficiency: Thermophysical property predicting of MXene/graphene hybrid nanofluids via Bayesian-optimized artificial neural networks. Results Eng. 24, 102858 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhijawi, B. &amp; Awajan, A. Genetic algorithms: Theory, genetic operators, solutions, and applications. Evol. Intell. 17(3), 1245&#x2013;1256 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basem, A. et al. Integrating artificial Intelligence-Based metaheuristic optimization with Machine learning to enhance Nanomaterial-Containing latent heat thermal energy storage systems. Energy Conv. Manage.: X 25, 100835 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsehli, M. et al. Insights into water-lubricated transport of heavy and extra-heavy oils: Application of CFD, RSM, and metaheuristic optimized machine learning models. Fuel 374, 132431 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hai, T. et al. Optimizing Gaussian process regression (GPR) hyperparameters with three metaheuristic algorithms for viscosity prediction of suspensions containing microencapsulated PCMs. Sci. Rep. 14(1), 20271 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbari, M. A., Zare, M., Azizipanah-Abarghooee, R., Mirjalili, S. &amp; Deriche, M. The cheetah optimizer: A nature-inspired metaheuristic algorithm for large-scale optimization problems. Sci. Rep. 12(1), 10953 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maleki, H., Ashrafi, M., Ilghani, N. Z., Goodarzi, M. &amp; Muhammad, T. Pareto optimal design of a finned latent heat thermal energy storage unit using a novel hybrid technique. J. Energy Storage 44, 103310 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. et al. Optimized ANFIS models based on grid partitioning, subtractive clustering, and fuzzy C-means to precise prediction of thermophysical properties of hybrid nanofluids. Chem. Eng. J. 471, 144362 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, T. et al. Optimization of thermophysical properties of nanofluids using a hybrid procedure based on machine learning, multi-objective optimization, and multi-criteria decision-making. Chem. Eng. J. 485, 150059 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdollahzadeh, B., Gharehchopogh, F. S. &amp; Mirjalili, S. African vultures optimization algorithm: A new nature-inspired metaheuristic algorithm for global optimization problems. Comput. Ind. Eng. 158, 107408 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodadadi, N., Soleimanian Gharehchopogh, F. &amp; Mirjalili, S. MOAVOA: a new multi-objective artificial vultures optimization algorithm,. Neural Comput. Appl. 34(23), 20791&#x2013;20829 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alinezhad, A., and Khalili, A., COPRAS method, in New methods and applications in multiple attribute decision making (Madm): Springer, pp. 87&#x2013;91. (2019)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefano, N. M., Casarotto Filho, N., Vergara, L. G. L. &amp; da Rocha, R. U. G. COPRAS (Complex Proportional Assessment): State of the art research and its applications. IEEE Latin America Trans. 13(12), 3899&#x2013;3906 (2015).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>