<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41840401</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1744-411X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical and experimental neuropsychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Exp Neuropsychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Symptom clusters and cognitive changes: predictors of recovery timelines following concussion in college athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>12</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-12</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/13803395.2026.2644925</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Further research is warranted to identify factors that may place an individual at greater risk for prolonged recovery, especially those present 24-48&#x2009;hours post-concussion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Using data available through FITBIR and the CARE Consortium, this study included 786 athletes. All athletes had available return-to-play (RTP) data which was examined continuously and categorically (&gt;28&#x2009;days vs&#x2009;&#x2264;28&#x2009;days). Reliable change index methods were used to examine reliable changes in cognitive performance (ImPACT) and total symptom severity (PCSS) from baseline to post-concussion. We also examined five symptom cluster scores from SCAT-3 as predictors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Linear regression revealed that, when examining cognitive performance, reliable decreases in performance on ImPACT Verbal Memory and Visual Memory composites were associated with longer RTP. When evaluating symptomatology, reliable increase in total PCSS score and higher SCAT-3 Physical Symptom cluster scores were associated with longer RTP. Combining cognitive performance and symptomatology, only the SCAT-3 Physical Symptom Cluster predicted longer RTP. Logistic regression results showed that, when examining cognitive performance, a reliable decrease in ImPACT Visual Memory performance was associated with 62% increased risk for prolonged recovery. When examining symptomatology, increases in SCAT-3 Physical Symptom Cluster scores and a reliable increase in PCSS Total Symptoms resulted in an increased risk for prolonged recovery by 33% and 76%, respectively. When examining cognitive performance and symptomatology, only the SCAT-3 Physical Symptom Cluster was associated with increased risk for prolonged recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Overall, these results demonstrate the unique effects of individual factors on recovery from concussion, particularly physical symptomatology. Further, these findings provide support for targeted, multidomain treatments for concussion based on presenting symptomatology. Future work should continue to explore the effectiveness of early intervention based on symptom profiles.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thomas</LastName><ForeName>Garrett A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UPMC Sports Medicine Concussion Program, Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arnett</LastName><ForeName>Peter A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, The Pennsylvania State University, University Park, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Exp Neuropsychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8502170</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1380-3395</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Concussion, mild</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuropsychology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-concussion symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">return to play</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports injuries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports medicine</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41840401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13803395.2026.2644925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>