<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41736918</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2296-9144</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in robotics and AI</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Robot AI</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Calibration-free per-finger force-feedback slip control for grasping by anthropomorphic hand with tri-axial tactile sensors.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1735467</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1735467</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1735467</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/frobt.2026.1735467</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This paper addresses the challenge of detecting and recovering from slip during robotic grasping of unknown objects, with the objective of establishing a robust no on-site or per-object calibration slip-recovery controller for an anthropomorphic hand. This hand is equipped with tri-axial piezoresistive tactile force sensors on each finger, and the proposed approach is validated through experimental analysis. The proposed methodology eliminates the need for object- or pose-specific calibration, explicit friction modelling, dense tactile arrays, line-of-sight vision, and a data-hungry learning process, enabling real-time implementation with minimal computation and integration effort. Using a commonly acquired online baseline from initial readings, slip is detected from relative changes between consecutive samples of the baseline-subtracted resultant tangential force, and object engagement is determined when the normal force reading deviates from a no-slip baseline beyond a preset threshold. Upon detecting slip, each finger increases its gripping force in closed-loop control until the slip stops, while enforcing motor-current protection in finger control to prevent actuator overload and object damage. Experiments were conducted on objects with different rigidity, weight, and surface textures, including an aluminium tube, a plastic water bottle, and a sponge. Additionally, the response time and variations in gripping force were evaluated. The results demonstrate rapid slip response via localized per-finger correction, good object conformability, and effective re-stabilization under different lifting speeds and sudden external disturbances. The per-finger design utilizes the minimum necessary correction at the offending finger, reducing unnecessary force increases on other fingers and improving grasp efficiency. This approach represents a practical solution for warehouse picking, human-robot collaboration, and <i>in situ</i> manipulation where task-specific calibrations, visual access, or training datasets are impractical.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wong and Zhu.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Dickson Chiu Yu</ForeName><Initials>DCY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, York University, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Zheng H</ForeName><Initials>ZH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, York University, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Robot AI</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101749350</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-9144</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anthropomorphic hand</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">calibration-free</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">robotic grasping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">slip detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tactile sensors</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41736918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12926654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frobt.2026.1735467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1735467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aceituno-Cabezas B., Ballester J., Rodriguez A. (2023). Certified grasping. Int. J. Robotics Res. 42, 249&#x2013;262. 10.1177/02783649231155952</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/02783649231155952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billard A., Kragic D. (2019). Trends and challenges in robot manipulation. Science 364, eaat8414. 10.1126/science.aat8414</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aat8414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31221831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S., Bai C., Zhang C., Geng D., Liu R., Xie Y., et al. (2021). Flexible piezoresistive three-dimensional force sensor based on interlocked structures. Sensors Actuators A Phys. 330, 112857. 10.1016/j.sna.2021.112857</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sna.2021.112857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R., Zhang H., Zhou S., Xu X., Yuan Z., Wang H., et al. (2024). A rigid-flexible-soft coupled dexterous hand with sliding tactile perception and feedback. IEEE Robotics Automation Lett. 9, 11682&#x2013;11689. 10.1109/LRA.2024.3497721</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LRA.2024.3497721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Wang L., Luo Y., Li X., Li S. (2025). Learning-based slip detection and fine control using the tactile sensor for robot stable grasping. IEEE Robotics Automation Lett. 10, 11156&#x2013;11163. 10.1109/LRA.2025.3604723</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LRA.2025.3604723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng H., Zhong G., Li X., Nie W. (2017). Slippage and deformation preventive control of bionic prosthetic hands. IEEE/ASME Trans. Mechatronics 22, 888&#x2013;897. 10.1109/TMECH.2016.2639553</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMECH.2016.2639553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efendi A., Shao Y.-H., Huang C.-Y. (2025). Technological development and optimization of pushing and grasping functions in robot arms: a review. Measurement 242, 115729. 10.1016/j.measurement.2024.115729</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2024.115729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong Y., Cheng X., Wu Z., Liu Y., Yu P., Hu X. (2021). A flexible tactile sensor array for dynamic triaxial force measurement based on aligned piezoresistive nanofibers. IEEE Sensors J. 21, 21989&#x2013;21998. 10.1109/JSEN.2021.3103781</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2021.3103781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammond F. L., Kramer R. K., Wan Q., Howe R. D., Wood R. J. (2014). Soft tactile sensor arrays for force feedback in micromanipulation. IEEE Sensors J. 14, 1443&#x2013;1452. 10.1109/JSEN.2013.2297380</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2013.2297380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howe R., Cutkosky M. (1989). Sensing skin acceleration for slip and texture perception. Proc. 1989 Int. Conf. Robotics Automation 1, 145&#x2013;150. 10.1109/ROBOT.1989.99981</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ROBOT.1989.99981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Z., Lin L., Lin W., Xu Y., Xia X., Peng Z., et al. (2023). Machine learning for tactile perception: advancements, challenges, and opportunities. Adv. Intell. Syst. 5, 2200371. 10.1002/aisy.202200371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aisy.202200371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahanshahi H., Zhu Z. H. (2024). Review of machine learning in robotic grasping control in space application. Acta Astronaut. 220, 37&#x2013;61. 10.1016/j.actaastro.2024.04.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actaastro.2024.04.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jassim H. S., Akhter Y., Aalwahab D. Z., Neamah H. A. (2025). Recent advances in tactile sensing technologies for human-robot interaction: current trends and future perspectives. Biosens. Bioelectron. X 26, 100669. 10.1016/j.biosx.2025.100669</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biosx.2025.100669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M., Yang J., Kim D., Yun D. (2022). Soft tactile sensor to detect the slip of a robotic hand. Measurement 200, 111615. 10.1016/j.measurement.2022.111615</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2022.111615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komeno N., Matsubara T. (2024). Incipient slip detection by vibration injection into soft sensor. IEEE Robotics Automation Lett. 9, 3251&#x2013;3258. 10.1109/LRA.2024.3366014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LRA.2024.3366014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lathers S., Mousa M., La Belle J. (2017). Additive manufacturing fused filament fabrication three-dimensional printed pressure sensor for prosthetics with low elastic modulus and high filler ratio filament composites. 3D Print. Addit. Manuf. 4, 30&#x2013;40. 10.1089/3dp.2016.0051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/3dp.2016.0051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z., Howe R. D. (2023). Beyond coulomb: stochastic friction models for practical grasping and manipulation. IEEE Robotics Automation Lett. 8, 5140&#x2013;5147. 10.1109/LRA.2023.3292580</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LRA.2023.3292580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Huh T. M., Chen S. X., Lu L., Kopsaftopoulos F., Cutkosky M. R., et al. (2023a). Design of active sensing smart skin for incipient slip detection in robotics applications. IEEE/ASME Trans. Mechatronics 28, 1766&#x2013;1777. 10.1109/TMECH.2022.3224119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMECH.2022.3224119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Hou J., Li C., Wang X. (2023b). Intelligent soft robotic grippers for agricultural and food product handling: a brief review with a focus on design and control. Adv. Intell. Syst. 5, 2300233. 10.1002/aisy.202300233</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aisy.202300233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Man J., Jin Z., Chen J. (2024). Magnetic tactile sensor with bionic hair array for sliding sensing and object recognition. Adv. Sci. 11, 2306832. 10.1002/advs.202306832</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/advs.202306832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10966537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38236170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng J., Buzzatto J., Liu Y., Liarokapis M. (2022). On aerial robots with grasping and perching capabilities: a comprehensive review. Front. Robotics AI 8, 8&#x2013;2021. 10.3389/frobt.2021.739173</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frobt.2021.739173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8989736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35399745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo Y., Han H., Liu Y., Wang X., Hu D., Zhang J., et al. (2022). A tactile sensor based on piezoresistive effect and electromagnetic induction. Sensors Actuators A Phys. 344, 113716. 10.1016/j.sna.2022.113716</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sna.2022.113716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mun H., Diaz Cortes D. S., Youn J.-H., Kyung K.-U. (2024). Multi-degree-of-freedom force sensor incorporated into soft robotic gripper for improved grasping stability. Soft Robot. 11, 628&#x2013;638. 10.1089/soro.2023.0068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/soro.2023.0068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38557239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortenzi V., Cosgun A., Pardi T., Chan W. P., Croft E., Kuli&#x107; D. (2021). Object handovers: a review for robotics. IEEE Trans. Robotics 37, 1855&#x2013;1873. 10.1109/TRO.2021.3075365</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TRO.2021.3075365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei Z., Zhang Q., Yang K., Yuan Z., Zhang W., Sang S. (2021). A fully 3d-printed wearable piezoresistive strain and tactile sensing array for robot hand. Adv. Mater. Technol. 6, 2100038. 10.1002/admt.202100038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/admt.202100038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennestr&#xec; E., Rossi V., Salvini P., Valentini P. P. (2016). Review and comparison of dry friction force models. Nonlinear Dynamics 83, 1785&#x2013;1801. 10.1007/s11071-015-2485-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11071-015-2485-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu J., Mao B., Li Z., Xu Y., Zhou K., Cao X., et al. (2023). Recent progress in advanced tactile sensing technologies for soft grippers. Adv. Funct. Mater. 33, 2306249. 10.1002/adfm.202306249</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202306249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romeo R. A., Zollo L. (2020). Methods and sensors for slip detection in robotics: a survey. IEEE Access 8, 73027&#x2013;73050. 10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2987849</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2987849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stachowsky M., Hummel T., Moussa M., Abdullah H. A. (2016). A slip detection and correction strategy for precision robot grasping. IEEE/ASME Trans. Mechatronics 21, 2214&#x2013;2226. 10.1109/TMECH.2016.2551557</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMECH.2016.2551557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sui R., Zhang L., Huang Q., Li T., Jiang Y. (2024). A novel incipient slip degree evaluation method and its application in adaptive control of grasping force. IEEE Trans. Automation Sci. Eng. 21, 2454&#x2013;2468. 10.1109/TASE.2023.3261403</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TASE.2023.3261403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Wyk K., Falco J. (2018). &#x201c;Calibration and analysis of tactile sensors as slip detectors,&#x201d; in 2018 IEEE international conference on robotics and automation (ICRA), 2744&#x2013;2751. 10.1109/ICRA.2018.8461117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ICRA.2018.8461117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Wu X., Mei D., Zhu L., Chen J. (2019). Flexible tactile sensor array for distributed tactile sensing and slip detection in robotic hand grasping. Sensors Actuators A Phys. 297, 111512. 10.1016/j.sna.2019.07.036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sna.2019.07.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Huang J., Ru H., Fu Z., Lei H., Wu D., et al. (2025a). Grasping state analysis of soft manipulator based on flexible tactile sensor and high-dimensional fuzzy system. IEEE/ASME Trans. Mechatronics 30, 2165&#x2013;2176. 10.1109/TMECH.2024.3445504</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMECH.2024.3445504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Wang Q., Tu Y., Xu W., Zhang J., Knoll A., Zhou M., et al.  (2025b). Towards damage-less robotic fragile fruit grasping: a systematic review on system design, end effector, and visual and tactile feedback. 
<i>J. of Field Robotics</i> N/a
42, 4521&#x2013;4543. 10.1002/rob.70021
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rob.70021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y., Liu Y., Zhou Y., Man Q., Hu C., Asghar W., et al. (2018). A skin-inspired tactile sensor for smart prosthetics. Sci. Robotics 3, eaat0429. 10.1126/scirobotics.aat0429</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scirobotics.aat0429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33141753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong S., Chapman J., Aw K. (2022). Soft and flexible large-strain piezoresistive sensors: on implementing proprioception, object classification and curvature estimation systems in adaptive, human-like robot hands. Sensors Actuators A Phys. 341, 113609. 10.1016/j.sna.2022.113609</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sna.2022.113609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J., Yao S., Li X., Ghaffar A., Yao Z. (2024). Design of a 3-d tactile sensing array for incipient slip detection in robotic dexterous manipulation. IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas. 73, 1&#x2013;14. 10.1109/TIM.2024.3436064</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2024.3436064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T., Jiang L., Wu X., Feng W., Zhou D., Liu H. (2015). Fingertip three-axis tactile sensor for multifingered grasping. IEEE/ASME Trans. Mechatronics 20, 1875&#x2013;1885. 10.1109/TMECH.2014.2357793</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMECH.2014.2357793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Zhao H., Chen K., Fei G., Li X., Wang Y., et al. (2025a). Dexterous hand towards intelligent manufacturing: a review of technologies, trends, and potential applications. Robotics Computer-Integrated Manuf. 95, 103021. 10.1016/j.rcim.2025.103021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rcim.2025.103021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S., Li H., Mao B., Zhao F., Chen W., Gao G., et al. (2025b). Mambaslip: a novel multimodal large language model for real-time robotic slip detection. IEEE Robotics Automation Lett. 10, 6592&#x2013;6599. 10.1109/LRA.2025.3568612</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LRA.2025.3568612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao C., Yu Y., Ye Z., Tian Z., Zhang Y., Zeng L.-L. (2025). Universal slip detection of robotic hand with tactile sensing. Front. Neurorobotics 19, 19&#x2013;2025. 10.3389/fnbot.2025.1478758</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnbot.2025.1478758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11843555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39991554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>