<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41934533</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1654-7209</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Ambio</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ambio</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Health impacts of the Aral Sea disaster: Current state, research gaps, and mitigation perspectives in the North Aral Sea region.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13280-026-02385-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The North Aral Sea (Kazakhstan) has been the focus of restoration efforts to counter the desiccation of one of the world's largest lakes. As restoration ultimately aims to improve human well-being, monitoring population health is essential. This review synthesizes health issues reported in the region in 2015-2025. Findings indicate multifactorial adverse outcomes, including cardiovascular, endocrine, reproductive, and nutritional disturbances linked to historical contamination, dietary deficiencies, psychosocial stress, and limited healthcare access. Although partial restoration has reduced some environmental hazards, residual risks persist, particularly in southern desiccated zones. Integrated preventive actions are recommended, including environmental management, strengthened healthcare, improved nutrition, education, and infrastructure. Any future industrial expansion, including resource extraction, must be paired with sustainable community engagement. The North Aral case provides broader lessons for environmentally stressed dryland basins, highlighting how coupled ecological and social disruptions can compound health risks across generations and underscoring the need for equity-focused recovery strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rzymski</LastName><ForeName>Piotr</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4713-0801</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Medicine, Poznan University of Medical Sciences, Pozna&#x144;, Poland. rzymskipiotr@ump.edu.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Polish Limnological Society, Torun, Poland. rzymskipiotr@ump.edu.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marszelewski</LastName><ForeName>W&#x142;odzimierz</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hydrology and Water Management, Nicolaus Copernicus University, Torun, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Polish Limnological Society, Torun, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rybak</LastName><ForeName>Micha&#x142;</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Water Protection, Adam Mickiewicz University, Pozna&#x144;, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Polish Limnological Society, Torun, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klimaszyk</LastName><ForeName>Piotr</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Water Protection, Adam Mickiewicz University, Pozna&#x144;, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Polish Limnological Society, Torun, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>IDUB-UAM 173/02/UAM/0037</GrantID><Agency>Excellence Initiative - Research University ID-UB</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Sweden</Country><MedlineTA>Ambio</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0364220</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0044-7447</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ecological disaster</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kazakhstan</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Public health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Syr-Darya</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41934533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13280-026-02385-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13280-026-02385-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>AAD. 2025. Akimat of the Aral District. https://www.gov.kz/memleket/entities/kyzylorda-aral .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adilov, B., K. Shomurodov, T. Rakhimova, A. Sultamuratov, F. Polvonov, G. Begjanova, Z. Jabbarov, L. Wang, et al. 2025. Vegetation colonization and biodiversity dynamics on the exposed Aral Sea bed: A 35 years investigation. Ecological Indicators 177: 113789. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecolind.2025.113789 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2025.113789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, N., Y. Bibi, Saboon, I. Raza, K. Zahara, S. Idrees, N. Khalid, T. Bashir, et al. 2015. Traditional uses and pharmacological properties of Alhagi maurorum: A review. Asian Pacific Journal of Tropical Disease 5: 856&#x2013;861. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2222-1808(15)60945-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2222-1808(15)60945-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhmedullin, R., T. Aimyshev, G. Zhakhina, S. Yerdessov, A. Beyembetova, A. Ablayeva, A. Biniyazova, T. Seyil, et al. 2024. In-depth analysis and trends of cancer mortality in Kazakhstan: A joinpoint analysis of nationwide healthcare data 2014&#x2013;2022. BMC Cancer 24: 1340. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12885-024-13128-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-024-13128-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aladin, N.V., and W.T.W. Potts. 1992. Changes in the Aral Sea ecosystems during the period 1960&#x2013;1990. Hydrobiologia 237: 67&#x2013;79. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00016032 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00016032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aladin, N.V., V.I. Gontar, L.V. Zhakova, I.S. Plotnikov, A.O. Smurov, P. Rzymski, and P. Klimaszyk. 2019. The zoocenosis of the Aral Sea: Six decades of fast-paced change. Environmental Science and Pollution Research 26: 2228&#x2013;2237. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-018-3807-z .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-018-3807-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amirgaliyev, N., C. Opp, M. Askarova, L. Ismukhanova, A. Madibekov, and A. Zhadi. 2023. Long-term dynamics of persistent organic pollutants in water bodies of the Aral Sea-Syrdarya basin. Applied Sciences 13: 11453. https://doi.org/10.3390/app132011453 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app132011453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrulionis, N.Y., A.S. Izhitskiy, A.S. Savvichev, and P.O. Zavialov. 2025. Recent changes in physical and biogeochemical state in residual basins of the Aral Sea. Aquatic Geochemistry 31: 1. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10498-024-09436-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10498-024-09436-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ataniyazova, O., S. Adrian, Z. Mazhitova, H. Moshammer, G. Prindull, and R. Zetterstr&#xf6;m. 2001. Continuing progressive deterioration of the environment in the Aral Sea Region: Disastrous effects on mother and child health. Acta Paediatrica 90: 589&#x2013;591. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1651-2227.2001.tb00806.x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1651-2227.2001.tb00806.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atshabarova, S. 2016. Comparative analysis of feeding habits the Aral sea region. Occupational Hygiene and Medical Ecology 3: 40&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balaj, M., C.A. Henson, A. Aronsson, A. Aravkin, K. Beck, C. Degail, L. Donadello, K. Eikemo, et al. 2024. Effects of education on adult mortality: A global systematic review and meta-analysis. The Lancet Public Health 9: e155&#x2013;e165. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2468-2667(23)00306-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-2667(23)00306-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banks, J.R., B. Heinold, and K. Schepanski. 2022. Impacts of the desiccation of the Aral Sea on the central Asian dust life-cycle. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres. https://doi.org/10.1029/2022JD036618 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2022JD036618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartram, J., and S. Cairncross. 2010. Hygiene, sanitation, and water: Forgotten foundations of health. PLoS Medicine 7: e1000367. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1000367 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1000367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennion, P., R. Hubbard, S. O&#x2019;Hara, G. Wiggs, J. Wegerdt, S. Lewis, I. Small, J. van der Meer, et al. 2007. The impact of airborne dust on respiratory health in children living in the Aral Sea region. International Journal of Epidemiology 36: 1103&#x2013;1110. https://doi.org/10.1093/ije/dym195 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/dym195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berdiakhmetkyzy, S., S.Z. Assylbekova, A.M. Abdybekova, and T.T. Barakbaev. 2021. Current state of populations of the main commercial fish species of the small Aral Sea. Experimental Biology. https://doi.org/10.26577/eb.2021.v88.i3.12 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26577/eb.2021.v88.i3.12</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berdimbetov, T., B. Pushpawela, N. Murzintcev, S. Nietullaeva, K. Gafforov, A. Tureniyazova, and D. Madetov. 2024. Unraveling the intricate links between the dwindling Aral Sea and climate variability during 2002&#x2013;2017. Climate 12: 105. https://doi.org/10.3390/cli12070105 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cli12070105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo&#x10d;kova, S., R. Bohovic, M. Hrn&#x10d;iar, M. Muro&#x148;, J. Chytr&#xfd;, M. Skalsk&#xfd;, M. &#x10c;ernochov&#xe1;, and D. Kalmykov. 2023. Air pollution in Kazakhstan as seen from space: Fundamental analysis, focus on the Karaganda Region, and notes on Kazakhstan&#x2019;s broader impact on climate change. Prague-Karaganda: Arnika. ISBN 9788088508168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosch, K., L. Erdinger, F. Ingel, S. Khussainova, E. Utegenova, N. Bresgen, and P. Eckl. 2007. Evaluation of the toxicological properties of ground- and surface-water samples from the Aral Sea Basin. Science of the Total Environment 374: 43&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2006.11.048 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2006.11.048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosch, K., L. Erdinger, F. Ingel, S. Khussainova, E. Utegenova, N. Bresgen, and P.M. Eckl. 2012. Aralkum - a Man-Made Desert. Ecological Studies. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-21117-1 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Z., X. Gao, and J. Lei. 2022. Dust emission and transport in the Aral Sea region. Geoderma 428: 116177. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geoderma.2022.116177 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoderma.2022.116177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crighton, E.J., L. Barwin, I. Small, and R. Upshur. 2011. What have we learned? A review of the literature on children&#x2019;s health and the environment in the Aral Sea area. International Journal of Public Health 56: 125&#x2013;138. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00038-010-0201-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00038-010-0201-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edelstein, M.R. 2018. Contaminated communities. New York: Routledge. https://doi.org/10.4324/9780429501395 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4324/9780429501395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdinger, L., P. Eckl, F. Ingel, S. Khussainova, E. Utegenova, V. Mann, and T. Gabrio. 2004. The Aral Sea disaster &#x2013; human biomonitoring of Hg, As, HCB, DDE, and PCBs in children living in Aralsk and Akchi, Kazakhstan. International Journal of Hygiene and Environmental Health 207: 541&#x2013;547. https://doi.org/10.1078/1438-4639-00325 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1078/1438-4639-00325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ermakhanov, Z.K., I.S. Plotnikov, N.V. Aladin, and P. Micklin. 2012. Changes in the Aral Sea ichthyofauna and fishery during the period of ecological crisis. Lakes &amp; Reservoirs: Science, Policy and Management for Sustainable Use 17: 3&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1440-1770.2012.00492.x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-1770.2012.00492.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ESMF. 2020. Environmental and social management framework.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glantz, M.H. 2009. Creeping environmental problems and sustainable development in the Aral Sea basin. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gwenzi, W., J. Marumure, Z. Makuvara, T.T. Simbanegavi, E.L. Njomou-Ngounou, E.L. Nya, K. Kaetzl, C. Noubactep, et al. 2023. The pit latrine paradox in low-income settings: A sanitation technology of choice or a pollution hotspot? Science of the Total Environment 879: 163179. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.163179 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.163179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issanova, G., J. Abuduwaili, A. Kaldybayev, O. Semenov, and T. Dedova. 2015. Dust storms in Kazakhstan: Frequency and division. Journal of the Geological Society of India 85: 348&#x2013;358. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12594-015-0224-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12594-015-0224-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izhitskiy, A.S., P.O. Zavialov, P.V. Sapozhnikov, G.B. Kirillin, H.P. Grossart, O.Y. Kalinina, A.K. Zalota, I.V. Goncharenko, et al. 2016. Present state of the Aral Sea: Diverging physical and biological characteristics of the residual basins. Scientific Reports 6: 23906. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep23906 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep23906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jangildinova, S., S. Ivassenko, A. Kelmyalene, B. Yessilbayeva, B. Dyussenbekova, and M. Kinayatov. 2019. Determination of the product of DNA oxidation in the blood of women living in the sub-Aral Area. Open Access Macedonian Journal of Medical Sciences 7: 1672&#x2013;1674. https://doi.org/10.3889/oamjms.2019.333 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3889/oamjms.2019.333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen, S., Z. Mazhitova, and R. Zetterstrom. 1997. Environmental pollution and child health in the Aral Sea region in Kazakhstan. Science of the Total Environment 206: 187&#x2013;193. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0048-9697(97)80009-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0048-9697(97)80009-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaibullina, Z., A. Amantaikyzy, D. Ariphanova, R. Temirbayeva, A. Mitusov, and Z. Zhurumbetova. 2022. Socio-economic and public health impacts of climate change and water availability in Aral District, Kyzylorda Region, Kazakhstan. Central Asian Journal of Water Research 8: 177&#x2013;204. https://doi.org/10.29258/CAJWR/2022-R1.v8-1/177-204.eng .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29258/CAJWR/2022-R1.v8-1/177-204.eng</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khatiwada, S., B. Gelal, N. Baral, and M. Lamsal. 2016. Association between iron status and thyroid function in Nepalese children. Thyroid Research 9: 2. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13044-016-0031-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13044-016-0031-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirillin, G.B., T. Shatwell, and A.S. Izhitskiy. 2025. Consequences of the Aral Sea restoration for its present physical state: Temperature, mixing, and oxygen regime. Hydrology and Earth System Sciences 29: 3569&#x2013;3588. https://doi.org/10.5194/hess-29-3569-2025 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/hess-29-3569-2025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klimaszyk, P., N. Kuczy&#x144;ska-Kippen, E. Szel&#x105;g-Wasielewska, W. Marszelewski, D. Borowiak, P. Niedzielski, K. Nowi&#x144;ski, R. Kurmanbayev, et al. 2022. Spatial heterogeneity of chemistry of the small aral sea and the syr darya river and its impact on plankton communities. Chemosphere 307: 135788. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.135788 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.135788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krivonogov, S.K., G.S. Burr, Y.V. Kuzmin, S.A. Gusskov, R.K. Kurmanbaev, T.I. Kenshinbay, and D.A. Voyakin. 2014. The fluctuating Aral Sea: A multidisciplinary-based history of the last two thousand years. Gondwana Research 26: 284&#x2013;300. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gr.2014.02.004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gr.2014.02.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulikov, Y., N. Sambayev, A. Pavlenko, K. Isbekov, and T. Barakbayev. 2024. Ways of optimizing the fishery in the Small Aral Sea, taking into account the biotopic distribution of fish fauna. Aquaculture, Aquarium, Conservation and Legislation 17: 1749&#x2013;1761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kultanov, B.Z., R.S. Dosmagambetova, S.A. Ivasenko, Y.S. Tatina, A.A. Kelmyalene, and L.H. Assenova. 2015. The study of cellular and molecular physiological characteristics of sperm in men living in the Aral Sea region. Open Access Macedonian Journal of Medical Sciences 4: 5&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.3889/oamjms.2016.007 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3889/oamjms.2016.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurbanova, N., A. Zhanbossinova, G. Kurumbaeva, Z. Khassenova, C. Karasartova, A. Bekboeva, and A. Balykova. 2024. Aral Sea: Environmental disaster and its consequences. E3S Web of Conferences 539: 01003. https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202453901003 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J., J. Ding, B. Liu, S. Wu, and Z. Han. 2025. Characteristics of salt dust aerosols and their transport implications in the Aral Sea. Scientific Reports 15: 3002. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-86880-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-86880-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamyrbayev, A., T. Djarkenov, A. Dosbayev, N. Dusembayeva, A. Shpakov, G. Umarova, Y. Drobchenko, T. Kunurkulzhayev, et al. 2016. The incidence of malignant tumors in environmentally disadvantaged regions of Kazakhstan. Asian Pacific Journal of Cancer Prevention: APJCP 17: 5203&#x2013;5209. https://doi.org/10.22034/APJCP.2016.17.12.5203 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22034/APJCP.2016.17.12.5203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massakbayeva, A., J. Abuduwaili, G.T. Issanova, S. Bissenbayeva, and B. Issina. 2019. Temperature and precipitation trend in the Aral Sea and Aral Sea region during 1960&#x2013;2016. Scientific Journal of Pedagogy and Economics 3: 6&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.32014/2019.2518-1467.63 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32014/2019.2518-1467.63</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micklin, P. 2016. The future Aral Sea: Hope and despair. Environmental Earth Sciences 75: 844. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12665-016-5614-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-016-5614-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micklin, P. 2014a. Aral Sea basin water resources and the changing Aral water balance. In The Aral Sea. Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-02356-9_5 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micklin, P. 2014b. Efforts to revive the Aral Sea. In The Aral Sea. Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-02356-9_15 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neria, Y., A. Nandi, and S. Galea. 2008. Post-traumatic stress disorder following disasters: A systematic review. Psychological Medicine 38: 467&#x2013;480. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291707001353 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291707001353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Hara, S.L., G.F. Wiggs, B. Mamedov, G. Davidson, and R.B. Hubbard. 2000. Exposure to airborne dust contaminated with pesticide in the Aral Sea region. The Lancet 355: 627&#x2013;628. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(99)04753-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(99)04753-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obeng, P.A., E.A. Donkor, E. Awere, P.A. Obeng, S. Oduro-Kwarteng, and E. Awuah. 2023. The ventilated improved pit latrine: A theoretical evaluation of conventional design guidelines, user adaptations and prospects for improvement. Journal of the Ghana Institution of Engineering (JGhIE) 23: 50&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.56049/jghie.v23i1.48 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.56049/jghie.v23i1.48</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opp, C., M. Groll, I. Aslanov, T. Lotz, and N. Vereshagina. 2017. Aeolian dust deposition in the southern Aral Sea region (Uzbekistan): Ground-based monitoring results from the LUCA project. Quaternary International 429: 86&#x2013;99. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.quaint.2015.12.103 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.quaint.2015.12.103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opp, C., M. Groll, H. Abbasi, and M.A. Foroushani. 2021. Causes and effects of sand and dust storms: What has past research taught us? A Survey. Journal of Risk and Financial Management 14: 326. https://doi.org/10.3390/jrfm14070326 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jrfm14070326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opp, C., M. Groll, O. Semenov, L. Shardakova, Y. Kovalevskaya, R. Kulmatov, I. Normatov, and I. Aslanov. 2024. Water household changes, climate change, and human impact: Reasons for the dusty side of the Aral Sea Syndrome. E3S Web of Conferences 575: 04001. https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202457504001 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otarbaeva, M.A., S.B. Battakova, A.U. Amanbekova, O.V. Grebeneva, and S.M. Gazalieva. 2020. Assessment of the risk of circulatory system disease development at the population of the Aral sea region. Ateroscleroz 16: 28&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.15372/ATER20200105 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15372/ATER20200105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plotnikov, I.S., N.V. Aladin, L.V. Zhakova, J. Mossin, and J.T. H&#xf8;eg. 2023. Past, present and future of the Aral Sea -A review of its fauna and flora before and during the regression crisis. Zoological Studies. https://doi.org/10.6620/ZS.2023.62-19 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6620/ZS.2023.62-19</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pr&#xfc;ss-Ust&#xfc;n, A., J. Wolf, J. Bartram, T. Clasen, O. Cumming, M.C. Freeman, B. Gordon, P.R. Hunter, et al. 2019. Burden of disease from inadequate water, sanitation and hygiene for selected adverse health outcomes: An updated analysis with a focus on low- and middle-income countries. International Journal of Hygiene and Environmental Health 222: 765&#x2013;777. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheh.2019.05.004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijheh.2019.05.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghupathi, V., and W. Raghupathi. 2020. The influence of education on health: An empirical assessment of OECD countries for the period 1995&#x2013;2015. Archives of Public Health 78: 20. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13690-020-00402-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13690-020-00402-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rzymski, P., P. Klimaszyk, P. Niedzielski, W. Marszelewski, D. Borowiak, K. Nowi&#x144;ski, A. Baikenzheyeva, R. Kurmanbayev, et al. 2019. Pollution with trace elements and rare-earth metals in the lower course of Syr Darya River and Small Aral Sea, Kazakhstan. Chemosphere 234: 81&#x2013;88. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2019.06.036 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2019.06.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabirov, Z.B., A.B. Eshmagambetova, G.K. Turlybekova, N.M. Duzbayeva, M.A. Mukasheva, and I.A. Onoshko. 2020. Biochemical parameters of blood plasma of the male population living on the territory of the Aral Sea. Bulletin of the Karaganda University &#x201c;Biology Medicine Geography Series&#x201d; 100: 100&#x2013;105. https://doi.org/10.31489/2020bmg4/100-105 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31489/2020bmg4/100-105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salmukhanbetova, Z., A.A. Imanalinova, L.A. Dimeyeva, and N.E. Zverev. 2020. State of Saxaul Plantations in Kazakhstan&#x2019;s Section of the Aral Sea Region. Central Asian Journal of Water Research 7: 128&#x2013;157. https://doi.org/10.29258/CAJWR/2020-R1.v7-1/128-157.eng .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29258/CAJWR/2020-R1.v7-1/128-157.eng</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satybaldiyev, B., B. Ismailov, N. Nurpeisov, K. Kenges, D.D. Snow, A. Malakar, O. Taukebayev, and B. Uralbekov. 2023. Downstream hydrochemistry and irrigation water quality of the Syr Darya, Aral Sea Basin, South Kazakhstan. Water Supply 23: 2119&#x2013;2134. https://doi.org/10.2166/ws.2023.114 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/ws.2023.114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serikbayeva, A., Z. Tauesheva, B. Kultanov, A.A. Turmukhambetova, R.S. Dosmagambetova, L.V. Shcherbakova, and O.D. Rymar. 2020. Indicators of thyroid functionof women of reproductive age, living on the ecologically unfavorable territories of Aral Sea region of Kazakhstan. Clinical and Experimental Thyroidology 16: 28&#x2013;37. https://doi.org/10.14341/ket11222 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14341/ket11222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;ikoparija, B. 2020. Desert dust has a notable impact on aerobiological measurements in Europe. Aeolian Research 47: 100636. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aeolia.2020.100636 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aeolia.2020.100636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, A., A. Behrangi, J.B. Fisher, and J.T. Reager. 2018. On the desiccation of the south Aral Sea observed from spaceborne missions. Remote Sensing 10: 793. https://doi.org/10.3390/rs10050793 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs10050793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spoor, M. 1998. The Aral Sea Basin crisis: Transition and environment in former Soviet central Asia. Development and Change 29: 409&#x2013;435. https://doi.org/10.1111/1467-7660.00084 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1467-7660.00084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stawkowski, M.E. 2016. &#x201c;I am a radioactive mutant&#x201d;: Emergent biological subjectivities at Kazakhstan&#x2019;s Semipalatinsk Nuclear Test Site. American Ethnologist 43: 144&#x2013;157. https://doi.org/10.1111/amet.12269 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/amet.12269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xf6;rnqvist, R., J. Jarsj&#xf6;, and B. Karimov. 2011. Health risks from large-scale water pollution: Trends in Central Asia. Environment International 37: 435&#x2013;442. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envint.2010.11.006 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envint.2010.11.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turdybekova, Y.G., R.S. Dosmagambetova, S.U. Zhanabayeva, G.V. Bublik, A.B. Kubayev, Z.G. Ibraibekov, I.L. Kopobayeva, and B.Z. Kultanov. 2015. The health status of the reproductive system in women living in the Aral Sea region. Open Access Macedonian Journal of Medical Sciences 3: 474&#x2013;477. https://doi.org/10.3889/oamjms.2015.078 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3889/oamjms.2015.078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ualikhanova, A. 2024. Kazakhstan to plant more saxaul trees in Aral basin. Astana: The Astana Times.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Der Meer, J.B.W., I.B. Small, E.J. Crighton, and N. Ford. 2002. Perceived health and psychosocial well-being in the Aral Sea area. In Toxic Turmoil.. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4615-0623-2_9 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voln&#xe1;, V., Z. Bla&#x17e;ek, and B. Krej&#x10d;&#xed;. 2021. Assessment of air pollution by PM10 suspended particles in the urban agglomeration of Central Europe in the period from 2001 to 2018. Urban Climate 39: 100959. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.uclim.2021.100959 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.uclim.2021.100959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, F., C. Li, S. Li, L. Cui, J. Zhao, and L. Liao. 2023. Selenium and thyroid diseases. Frontiers in Endocrinology. https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2023.1133000 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2023.1133000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. 2021. WHO global air quality guidelines: particulate matter (PM2.5 and PM10), ozone, nitrogen dioxide, sulfur dioxide and carbon monoxide.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiggs, G.F.S., S.L. O&#x2019;hara, J. Wegerdt, J. Van Der Meer, I. Small, and R. Hubbard. 2003. The dynamics and characteristics of aeolian dust in dryland Central Asia: Possible impacts on human exposure and respiratory health in the Aral Sea basin. The Geographical Journal 169: 142&#x2013;157. https://doi.org/10.1111/1475-4959.04976 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1475-4959.04976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf, J., R. Johnston, P.R. Hunter, B. Gordon, K. Medlicott, and A. Pr&#xfc;ss-Ust&#xfc;n. 2019. A Faecal Contamination Index for interpreting heterogeneous diarrhoea impacts of water, sanitation and hygiene interventions and overall, regional and country estimates of community sanitation coverage with a focus on low- and middle-income countries. International Journal of Hygiene and Environmental Health 222: 270&#x2013;282. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheh.2018.11.005 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijheh.2018.11.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xi, X., J. Wang, Z. Lu, A.M. Sayer, J. Lee, R.C. Levy, Y. Wang, A. Lyapustin, et al. 2025. Analysis of a saline dust storm from the Aralkum Desert &#x2013; Part 1: Consistency between multisensor satellite aerosol products. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics 25: 7403&#x2013;7429. https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-25-7403-2025 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/acp-25-7403-2025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zetterstr&#xf6;m, R. 1999. Child health and environmental pollution in the Aral Sea region in Kazakhstan. Acta Paediatrica 88: 49&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1651-2227.1999.tb01290.x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1651-2227.1999.tb01290.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann, M.B., and K. Boelaert. 2015. Iodine deficiency and thyroid disorders. The Lancet Diabetes &amp; Endocrinology 3: 286&#x2013;295. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213-8587(14)70225-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(14)70225-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>