<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41837055</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2210-2612</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>138</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of surgery case reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Surg Case Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Col II-CS-HA cartilage biomimetic matrix gel provides a new treatment option for huge cartilage defects - a case report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>400</StartPage><EndPage>405</EndPage><MedlinePgn>400-405</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/RC9.0000000000000103</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Articular cartilage injuries constitute a predominant musculoskeletal disease in athletic populations. These lesions frequently precipitate the progressive degeneration, culminating in premature career termination and increased functional impairment. However, current treatment methods for cartilage injury are not entirely satisfactory, especially for large full-thickness cartilage defects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PRESENTATION OF CASE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A 13-year-old male adolescent with documented high-intensity athletic engagement (training &gt;15&#xa0;hours/week) presented a huge exercise-induced full-thickness cartilage defect (6 cm<sup>2</sup>) over the sulcus of the trochlea. The patient underwent arthroscopic implantation of our laboratory-engineered type II collagen-chondroitin sulfate-hyaluronic acid (Col II-CS-HA) biomimetic matrix gel, a tri-component hydrogel designed to mimic native cartilage extracellular matrix composition. Serial evaluations over 12&#xa0;months postoperatively demonstrated significant improvement in both structural regeneration (7&#xa0;T MRI T2-mapping showing &gt;95% defect filling with hyaline-like tissue) and functional recovery (IKDC score increased from 31 to 100), with no adverse events reported. Notably, the patient resumed pre-injury sports activities at 9-month follow-up.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Current treatment strategies for cartilage defects, including microfracture and autologous chondrocyte implantation, demonstrate limited long-term efficacy for large full-thickness cartilage defects (&gt;2 cm<sup>2</sup>). The avascular nature of articular cartilage limits its inherent regenerative capacity. Tissue engineering approaches have emerged as promising solutions by providing biomimetic scaffolds and recruiting endogenous chondroprogenitor cells for hyaline-like cartilage regeneration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The case we present demonstrates the effectiveness of this Col II-CS-HA cartilage biomimetic matrix gel, which is expected to become a new effective solution for huge cartilage defects in future clinical practice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ni</LastName><ForeName>Qian-Kun</ForeName><Initials>QK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1211-6364</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Medicine Center, The First Affiliated Hospital of Army Medical University, Sha Ping Ba District, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lyu</LastName><ForeName>Jing-Tong</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Medicine Center, The First Affiliated Hospital of Army Medical University, Sha Ping Ba District, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Fu-You</ForeName><Initials>FY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Medicine Department, Jiang Bei Branch Hospital of The First Affiliated Hospital of Army Medical University (The 958th Army Hospital of the Chinese People's Liberation Army), Jiang Bei District, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Medicine Center, The First Affiliated Hospital of Army Medical University, Sha Ping Ba District, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Surg Case Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101529872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2210-2612</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomimetic matrix gel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cartilage defect</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cartilage regeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tissue engineering</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Sponsorships or competing interests that may be relevant to content are disclosed at the end of this article. The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41837055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12981881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RC9.0000000000000103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IJSCASEREPORTS-D-25-01510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Oussedik S, Tsitskaris K, Parker D. Treatment of articular cartilage lesions of the knee by microfracture or autologous chondrocyte implantation: a systematic review. Arthroscopy 2015;31:732&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25660008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimozono Y, Seow D, Yasui Y, et al. Knee-to-Talus Donor-Site Morbidity Following Autologous Osteochondral Transplantation: A Meta-Analysis with Best-case and Worst-case Analysis. Clin Orthop Relat Res 2019;477:1915&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7000024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31135553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Familiari F, Cinque ME, Chahla J, et al. Clinical Outcomes and Failure Rates of Osteochondral Allograft Transplantation in the Knee: A Systematic Review. Am J Sports Med 2018;46:3541&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29039969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraeutler MJ, Belk JW, Purcell JM, et al. Microfracture Versus Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation for Articular Cartilage Lesions in the Knee: A Systematic Review of 5-Year Outcomes. Am J Sports Med 2018;46:995&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28423287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gou G-H, Tseng F-J, Wang S-H, et al. Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation Versus Microfracture in the Knee: A Meta-analysis and Systematic Review. Arthroscopy 2020;36:289&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31708355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uysal O, Erybeh H, Canbek M, et al. Stem Cell-Based or Cell-Free Gene Therapy in Chondrocyte Regeneration: Synovial Fluid-Derived Mesenchymal Stem Cell Exosomes. Curr Mol Med 2024;24:906&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11327740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37859306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerwan A, Al-Jabir A, Mathew G, et al. Revised Surgical CAse REport (SCARE) guideline: An update for the age of Artificial Intelligence. Prem J Sci 2025;10:100079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiner MM, Raudner M, Marlovits S, et al. The MOCART (Magnetic Resonance Observation of Cartilage Repair Tissue) 2.0 Knee Score and Atlas. Cartilage 2021;13:571S&#x2013;87S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8725373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31422674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collaborators GO. Global, regional, and national burden of osteoarthritis, 1990-2020 and projections to 2050: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. Lancet Rheumatol 2023;5:e508&#x2013;e22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10477960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37675071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhillon J, Decilveo AP, Kraeutler MJ, et al. Third-Generation Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation (Cells Cultured Within Collagen Membrane) Is Superior to Microfracture for Focal Chondral Defects of the Knee Joint: Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Arthroscopy 2022;38:2579&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35283221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraamyan T, Johnson AJ, Wiedrick J, et al. Marrow Stimulation Has Relatively Inferior Patient-Reported Outcomes in Cartilage Restoration Surgery of the Knee: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials. Am J Sports Med 2022;50:858&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33890799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibarra C, Villalobos E, Madrazo-Ibarra A, et al. Arthroscopic Matrix-Assisted Autologous Chondrocyte Transplantation Versus Microfracture: A 6-Year Follow-up of a Prospective Randomized Trial. Am J Sports Med 2021;49:2165&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34048286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Tan H, Chen G, et al. One-step strategy for chondral defect repair. Front Biosci (Landmark Ed) 2019;24:628&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30844703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boffa A, Andriolo L, Angelelli L, et al. Matrix-Assisted Autologous Chondrocyte Transplantation for the Treatment of Patellofemoral Chondral Lesions: Long-term Results at a Minimum 15-Year Follow-up. Am J Sports Med 2024;52:2222&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11308357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39101726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert JR, Klinken S, Fallon M, et al. Clinical and Radiological Outcomes at &#x2265;10-Year Follow-up After Matrix-induced Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation in the Patellofemoral Joint. Am J Sports Med 2024;52:2532&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11344959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39101611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ao Y, Tang W, Tan H, et al. Hydrogel composed of type II collagen, chondroitin sulfate and hyaluronic acid for cartilage tissue engineering. Biomed Mater Eng 2022;33:515&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35754257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Fan H, Gong X, et al. Scaffold With Natural Calcified Cartilage Zone for Osteochondral Defect Repair in Minipigs. Am J Sports Med 2021;49:1883&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33961510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>