<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41783080</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2325-9671</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Orthopaedic journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Orthop J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Poor Adherence to Minimum Information for Studies Evaluating Biologics in Orthopaedics Guidelines: Platelet-Rich Plasma-Augmented ACL Reconstruction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23259671261416525</StartPage><MedlinePgn>23259671261416525</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23259671261416525</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/23259671261416525</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Platelet-rich plasma (PRP) has gained widespread use an adjunct to orthopaedic procedures, yet clinical studies have reported conflicting efficacy. The Minimum Information for Studies Evaluating Biologics in Orthopaedics (MIBO) guidelines were published in 2017 to standardize reporting of PRP preparation, characterization, and delivery, which may explain the heterogeneity of clinical outcomes in studies evaluating PRP for anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction (ACLR).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To evaluate adherence to MIBO guidelines in studies evaluating PRP-augmented ACLR and to assess whether reporting adherence improved after the publication of the 2017 guidelines.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Systematic review; Level of evidence, 3.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A systematic literature search was conducted using the PubMed/MEDLINE, Embase, and Web of Science databases in March 2025 to identify studies evaluating PRP-augmented ACLR. Included studies were randomized controlled trials (RCTs), prospective and retrospective cohort studies, and case-control studies published in the English language. Two independent reviewers extracted data on study characteristics and assessed adherence to all 23 MIBO checklist items.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 26 studies (14 RCTs, 12 observational studies) involving 1319 patients were included. The mean MIBO adherence was 40.1% (9.2/23 items) for pre-MIBO studies and 50.1% (11.5/23 items) for post-MIBO studies, with no statistically significant improvement (<i>P</i> = .115). The range of adherence was 17.4% to 82.6%. The most poorly reported items included CONSORT (Consolidated Standards of Reporting Trials)/STROBE (Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology) compliance, anti-inflammatory medication use, platelet recovery rate, PRP storage conditions, and final PRP analysis. No significant differences in MIBO adherence were found between RCTs and observational studies (<i>P</i> = .578). Half of the included studies reported positive outcomes with PRP augmentation, while half reported neutral outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Adherence to the 2017 MIBO guidelines in studies evaluating PRP-augmented ACLR remains poor, with no significant improvement after guideline publication. Critical information regarding PRP preparation, characterization, and platelet recovery rate continues to be inadequately reported, limiting study reproducibility and the ability to determine true PRP efficacy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>MacElroy</LastName><ForeName>Donald</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-5790-1461</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, New York Medical College, Valhalla, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Whitford</LastName><ForeName>Tobias</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, New York Medical College, Valhalla, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiss</LastName><ForeName>Matthew B</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6127-7626</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, New York Medical College, Valhalla, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4644-2571</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, New York Medical College, Valhalla, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eliasberg</LastName><ForeName>Claire D</ForeName><Initials>CD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4298-5755</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Hospital for Special Surgery, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bennett</LastName><ForeName>Dylan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Hospital for Special Surgery, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Orthop J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101620522</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2325-9671</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACLR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MIBO guidelines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PRP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">orthobiologics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">platelet-rich plasma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reporting standards</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>One or more of the authors has declared the following potential conflict of interest or source of funding: C.E. has received support for education from Smith &amp; Nephew and hospitality payments from Arthrex; has ownership interest in JEASO; and has received research funding support from AANA, OREF, and the Weill Cornell Medicine CTSC Pilot Award (UL1TR002384), none of which are directly relevant to this work. AOSSM checks author disclosures against the Open Payments Database (OPD). AOSSM has not conducted an independent investigation on the OPD and disclaims any liability or responsibility relating thereto.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41783080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12953987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671261416525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_23259671261416525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alves AFF, de Arruda Miranda JR, de Souza SAS, et al. Texture analysis to differentiate anterior cruciate ligament in patients after surgery with platelet-rich plasma. J Orthop Surg Res. 2021;16(1):283. doi: 10.1186/s13018-021-02437-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-021-02437-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8080342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33910605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amable PR, Carias RBV, Teixeira MVT, et al. Platelet-rich plasma preparation for regenerative medicine: optimization and quantification of cytokines and growth factors. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2013;4(3):67. doi: 10.1186/scrt218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/scrt218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3706762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23759113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andriolo L, Di Matteo B, Kon E, Filardo G, Venieri G, Marcacci M. PRP Augmentation for ACL reconstruction. Biomed Res Int. 2015;2015:371746. doi: 10.1155/2015/371746</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2015/371746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4430629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26064903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey L, Weldon M, Kleihege J, et al. Platelet-rich plasma augmentation of meniscal repair in the setting of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(12):3287-3292. doi: 10.1177/03635465211036471</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465211036471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34477016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berdis AS, Veale K, Fleissner PR. Outcomes of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction using biologic augmentation in patients 21&#x2009;years of age and younger. Arthroscopy. 2019;35(11):3107-3113. doi: 10.1016/j.arthro.2019.05.047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2019.05.047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31439458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brophy RH, Lowry KJ. American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons clinical practice guideline summary: management of anterior cruciate ligament injuries. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2023;31(11):531-537. doi: 10.5435/JAAOS-D-22-01020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5435/JAAOS-D-22-01020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10168113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36727995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Y, Wan YD. Effectiveness of platelet-rich plasma in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Orthop Surg. 2022;14(10):2406-2417. doi: 10.1111/os.13279</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/os.13279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9531067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36056588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chahla J, Cinque ME, Piuzzi NS, et al. A call for standardization in platelet-rich plasma preparation protocols and composition reporting: a systematic review of the clinical orthopaedic literature. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2017;99(20):1769-1779. doi: 10.2106/JBJS.16.01374</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.16.01374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29040132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen RJ, Zhu HZ, Gu XY, Xiang XX. Effects of platelet-rich plasma on tendon-bone healing after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Orthop Surg. 2022;14(1):88-95. doi: 10.1111/os.13175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/os.13175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8755887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34870370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corsini A, Perticarini L, Palermi S, Bettinsoli P, Marchini A. Re-evaluating platelet-rich plasma dosing strategies in sports medicine: the role of the &#x201c;10 billion platelet dose&#x201d; in optimizing therapeutic outcomes&#x2014;a narrative review. J Clin Med. 2025;14(8):2714. doi: 10.3390/jcm14082714</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm14082714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12027823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40283544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeClercq MG, Fiorentino AM, Lengel HA, et al. Systematic review of platelet-rich plasma for rotator cuff repair: are we adhering to the Minimum Information for Studies Evaluating Biologics in Orthopaedics? Orthop J Sports Med. 2021;9(12):23259671211041971. doi: 10.1177/23259671211041971</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671211041971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallouh L, Nakagawa K, Sasho T, et al. Effects of autologous platelet-rich plasma on cell viability and collagen synthesis in injured human anterior cruciate ligament. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2010;92(18):2909-2916. doi: 10.2106/JBJS.I.01158</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.I.01158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21159991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa D, Melean P, Calvo R, et al. Magnetic resonance imaging evaluation of the integration and maturation of semitendinosus-gracilis graft in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction using autologous platelet concentrate. Arthroscopy. 2010;26(10):1318-1325. doi: 10.1016/j.arthro.2010.02.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2010.02.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20800986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong H, Huang B, Zheng Z, Fu L, Chen L. Clinical use of platelet-rich plasma to promote tendon-bone healing and graft maturation in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction&#x2014;a randomized controlled study. Indian J Orthop. 2022;56(5):805-811. doi: 10.1007/s43465-021-00533-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43465-021-00533-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8791669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35103026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedbany D, Lezak BA, Butler J, Mercer NP, Krebsbach S, Kennedy JG. Adherence rates to the minimum information for studies evaluating biologics in orthopedics guidelines for clinical studies on platelet-rich plasma for the treatment of lateral epicondylitis: a systematic review. Clin Shoulder Elb. Published online May 23, 2025. doi: 10.5397/cise.2024.01060</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5397/cise.2024.01060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopewell S, Chan AW, Collins GS, et al. CONSORT 2025 statement: updated guideline for reporting randomised trials. BMJ. 2025;389:e081123. doi: 10.1136/bmj-2024-081123</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2024-081123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Kushwaha NS, Kumar D, Singh A, Gupta V, Kumar S. Prospective comparison of functional and radiological outcomes of arthroscopic anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction by hamstring graft alone and platelet-rich plasma added to the hamstring graft. Cureus. 2022;14(3):e23017. doi: 10.7759/cureus.23017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.23017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim JJ, Belk JW, Wharton BR, et al. Most orthopaedic platelet-rich plasma investigations don't report protocols and composition: an updated systematic review. Arthroscopy. 2025;41(3):821-834. doi: 10.1016/j.arthro.2024.03.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2024.03.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38522650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YC, Chen YJ, Fan TY, Chou PH, Lu CC. Effect of bone marrow aspiration concentrate and platelet-rich plasma combination in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a randomized, prospective, double-blinded study. J Orthop Surg Res. 2024;19(1):4. doi: 10.1186/s13018-023-04512-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-023-04512-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10763110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38169406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnussen RA, Flanigan DC, Pedroza AD, Heinlein KA, Kaeding CC. Platelet rich plasma use in allograft ACL reconstructions: two-year clinical results of a MOON cohort study. Knee. 2013;20(4):277-280. doi: 10.1016/j.knee.2012.12.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2012.12.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4170685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23270598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malinowski K, Ebisz M, LaPrade RF, Mostowy M. Platelet-rich plasma in anterior cruciate ligament quadriceps tendon bone reconstruction&#x2014;impact of PRP administration on pain, range of motion restoration, knee stability, tibial tunnel widening and functional results. Appl Sci. 2021;11(9):3993. doi: 10.3390/app11093993</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app11093993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millan SM, Thorn D, Ford E. A novel approach to augmenting allograft hamstring anterior cruciate ligament reconstructions utilizing a resorbable type I collagen matrix with platelet rich plasma. Case Rep Orthop. 2021;2021:5574676. doi: 10.1155/2021/5574676</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/5574676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzatolooei F, Alamdari MT, Khalkhali HR. The impact of platelet-rich plasma on the prevention of tunnel widening in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction using quadrupled autologous hamstring tendon: a randomised clinical trial. Bone Joint J. 2013;95-B(1):65-69. doi: 10.1302/0301-620X.95B1.30487</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/0301-620X.95B1.30487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23307675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munde K, Banerjee S, Gahlot N, Elhence A, Mandal S, Yadav T. Effect of platelet-rich plasma on healing of autologous graft after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a randomized control trial. Regen Med. 2023;18(8):601-610. doi: 10.2217/rme-2023-0108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/rme-2023-0108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37491949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray IR, Geeslin AG, Goudie EB, Petrigliano FA, LaPrade RF. Minimum Information for Studies Evaluating Biologics in Orthopaedics (MIBO): platelet-rich plasma and mesenchymal stem cells. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2017;99(10):809-819. doi: 10.2106/JBJS.16.00793</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.16.00793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28509821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa HF, Kim J, Rinaldi J, et al. Systematic review of randomized controlled trials evaluating the use of platelet-rich plasma for knee osteoarthritis: adherence to Minimum Information for Studies Evaluating Biologics in Orthopaedics. Am J Sports Med. 2025;53(5):1241-1253. doi: 10.1177/03635465241249996</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465241249996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39754417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orrego M, Larrain C, Rosales J, et al. Effects of platelet concentrate and a bone plug on the healing of hamstring tendons in a bone tunnel. Arthroscopy. 2008;24(12):1373-1380. doi: 10.1016/j.arthro.2008.07.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2008.07.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19038708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n71</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radice F, Y&#xe1;nez R, Guti&#xe9;rrez V, Rosales J, Pinedo M, Coda S. Comparison of magnetic resonance imaging findings in anterior cruciate ligament grafts with and without autologous platelet-derived growth factors. Arthroscopy. 2010;26(1):50-57. doi: 10.1016/j.arthro.2009.06.030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2009.06.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20117627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rousseau R, Labruyere C, Kajetanek C, Deschamps O, Makridis KG, Djian P. Complications after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction and their relation to the type of graft: a prospective study of 958 cases. Am J Sports Med. 2019;47(11):2543-2549. doi: 10.1177/0363546519867913</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546519867913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31403824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rupreht M, Vogrin M, Hussein M. MRI evaluation of tibial tunnel wall cortical bone formation after platelet-rich plasma applied during anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Radiol Oncol. 2013;47(2):119-124. doi: 10.2478/raon-2013-0009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/raon-2013-0009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3691087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23801907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez M, Yarza I, Jorquera C, et al. Genetics, sex and the use of platelet-rich plasma influence the development of arthrofibrosis after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Exp Orthop. 2025;12(1):e70156. doi: 10.1002/jeo2.70156</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jeo2.70156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders TL, Maradit Kremers H, Bryan AJ, et al. Incidence of anterior cruciate ligament tears and reconstruction: a 21-year population-based study. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44(6):1502-1507. doi: 10.1177/0363546516629944</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546516629944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26920430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkis-Onofre R, Poletto-Neto V, Cenci MS, Moher D, Pereira-Cenci T. CONSORT endorsement improves the quality of reports of randomized clinical trials in dentistry. J Clin Epidemiol. 2020;122:20-26. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2020.01.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2020.01.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32068103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seijas R, Ares O, Catala J, Alvarez-Diaz P, Cusco X, Cugat R. Magnetic resonance imaging evaluation of patellar tendon graft remodelling after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with or without platelet-rich plasma. J Orthop Surg (Hong Kong). 2013;21(1):10-14. doi: 10.1177/230949901302100105</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/230949901302100105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23629979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serag I, Abouzid M, Hikal H, et al. Platelet-rich plasma in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: an updated systematic review and quantitative meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Chin J Traumatol. Published online July 23, 2025. doi: 10.1016/j.cjtee.2025.02.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cjtee.2025.02.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheean AJ, Anz AW, Bradley JP. Platelet-rich plasma: fundamentals and clinical applications. Arthroscopy. 2021;37(9):2732-2734. doi: 10.1016/j.arthro.2021.07.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2021.07.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34481615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva A, Sampaio R. Anatomic ACL reconstruction: does the platelet-rich plasma accelerate tendon healing? Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2009;17(6):676-682. doi: 10.1007/s00167-009-0762-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-009-0762-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19288080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sofu H, Camurcu Y, Issin A, Ucpunar H, Ozcan S, Duman S. Should orthopedic surgeons consider reducing the negative effects of Outerbridge grade 2 patellofemoral chondral lesion on early postoperative recovery during anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol. 2019;29(2):471-478. doi: 10.1007/s00590-018-2303-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00590-018-2303-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30219996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorensen AA, Wojahn RD, Manske MC, Calfee RP. Using the Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) Statement to assess reporting of observational trials in hand surgery. J Hand Surg Am. 2013;38(8):1584-1589.e2. doi: 10.1016/j.jhsa.2013.05.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhsa.2013.05.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3989883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23845586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf6;zkesen S, Karahan HG, Kurtulmus A, Kayali C, Altay T. PRP on prevention of tunnel enlargement in ACL reconstruct&#x131;on. Ortop Traumatol Rehabil. 2018;20(4):285-291. doi: 10.5604/01.3001.0012.6462</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5604/01.3001.0012.6462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30648657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speich B, Mann E, Sch&#xf6;nenberger CM, et al. Reminding peer reviewers of reporting guideline items to improve completeness in published articles: primary results of 2 randomized trials. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6(6):e2317651. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.17651</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.17651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sporsheim AN, Gifstad T, Lundemo TO, et al. Autologous BPTB ACL reconstruction results in lower failure rates than ACL repair with and without synthetic augmentation at 30 years of follow-up: a prospective randomized study. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2019;101(23):2074-2081. doi: 10.2106/JBJS.19.00098</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.19.00098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31800420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starantzis KA, Mastrokalos D, Koulalis D, Papakonstantinou O, Soucacos PN, Papagelopoulos PJ. The potentially positive role of PRPs in preventing femoral tunnel widening in ACL reconstruction surgery using hamstrings: a clinical study in 51 patients. J Sports Med (Hindawi Publ Corp). 2014;2014:789317. doi: 10.1155/2014/789317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2014/789317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4590903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26464895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner L, Shamseer L, Altman DG, et al. Consolidated Standards of Reporting Trials (CONSORT) and the completeness of reporting of randomised controlled trials (RCTs) published in medical journals. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012;11(11):MR000030. doi: 10.1002/14651858.MR000030.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.MR000030.pub2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vadal&#xe0; A, Iorio R, De Carli A, et al. Platelet-rich plasma: does it help reduce tunnel widening after ACL reconstruction? Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2013;21(4):824-829. doi: 10.1007/s00167-012-1980-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-012-1980-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22488012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valent&#xed; Azc&#xe1;rate A, Lamo-Espinosa J, Aquerreta Beola JD, Hernandez Gonzalez M, Mora Gasque G, Valent&#xed; Nin., JR. Comparison between two different platelet-rich plasma preparations and control applied during anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Is there any evidence to support their use? Injury. 2014;45(suppl 4):S36-S41. doi: 10.1016/S0020-1383(14)70008-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0020-1383(14)70008-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogrin M, Rupreht M, Dinevski D, et al. Effects of a platelet gel on early graft revascularization after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a prospective, randomized, double-blind, clinical trial. Eur Surg Res. 2010;45(2):77-85. doi: 10.1159/000318597</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000318597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20814217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, et al. The Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. Ann Intern Med. 2007;147(8):573-577. doi: 10.7326/0003-4819-147-8-200710160-00010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-147-8-200710160-00010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17938396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiehn E, Ricci C, Alvarez-Perea A, et al. Adherence to the Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) checklist in articles published in EAACI Journals: a bibliographic study. Allergy. 2021;76(12):3581-3588. doi: 10.1111/all.14951</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/all.14951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34022062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie X, Zhao S, Wu H, et al. Platelet-rich plasma enhances autograft revascularization and reinnervation in a dog model of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Surg Res. 2013;183(1):214-222. doi: 10.1016/j.jss.2013.01.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jss.2013.01.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23472861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Z, Chen H, Qiao Y, et al. Intra-articular platelet-rich plasma injection after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2024;7(5):e2410134. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.10134</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.10134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu T, Zhou J, Hwang J, Xu X. Effects of platelet-rich plasma on clinical outcomes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Orthop J Sports Med. 2022;10(1):23259671211061535. doi: 10.1177/23259671211061535</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671211061535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>