<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41832926</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2212-5469</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Tissue engineering and regenerative medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Tissue Eng Regen Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biomimetic Constructs for Achilles Tendon Regeneration and their Translation to Human Medicine.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13770-026-00799-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Achilles tendon injuries are among the most common lower-body tendon injuries, often resulting fromoveruse and repetitive motion. Current treatments, ranging from conservative therapies to biological grafts, have drawbacks, including limited regenerative capacity and the risk of graft rejection. To overcome these challenges, tissue engineering shows growing promise for Achilles tendon regeneration, with ongoing research focused on developing biomimetic constructs that utilize various materials and biologics. Since every tendon has unique biomechanical and physiological characteristics, it is crucial to conduct individualized evaluations through detailed research and to address key considerations for clinical translation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This review focuses explicitly on advances in Achilles tendon tissue engineering for human medicine, assessing constructs made from natural, synthetic, and composite materials with/without biologics and discussing their clinical translation. Studies were searched in the PubMed database and Google Scholar, using the most relevant keywords, such as "Achilles tissue engineering", "Achilles biomimetic constructs", "Biomaterials for Achilles tendon", and "Clinical translation".</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Biomimetic constructs developed from various polymers and their combinations, when integrated with stem cells, demonstrate promising potential to reconstruct tissue microenvironments in vitro and to facilitate tissue repair and biomechanical functions in vivo. Carefully developing each element, including appropriate material structures, is essential for optimizing cell responses, biomechanical properties, and tissue repair in the Achilles tendon. Although the in vitro and in vivo advances reviewed in the paper contribute to clinical research, further studies with reproducible, long-term outcomes are needed to make the constructs clinically applicable in human medicine.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Achilles tissue engineering continues to progress, driven by a deeper understanding of the injuries and the integration of regenerative tools. Furthermore, clinical considerations, such as long-term in vivo follow-up to assess biocompatibility and functional recovery, will be critical to achieving clinical outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ozmen</LastName><ForeName>Emine Berfu</ForeName><Initials>EB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3751-9271</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Regenerative Medicine and Tissue Engineering, Department of Large Animal Clinical Sciences, College of Veterinary Medicine, University of Tennessee, Knoxville, TN, 37996, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Genome Science and Technology, The Bredesen Center for Interdisciplinary Research and Graduate Education, University of Tennessee Knoxville, Knoxville, TN, 37996, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anderson</LastName><ForeName>David E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0745-7591</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ward</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3068-6563</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, University of Tennessee Knoxville, Knoxville, TN, 37996, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Surgical Oncology, Department of Surgery, University of Tennessee Medical Center, Knoxville, TN, 37920, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dhar</LastName><ForeName>Madhu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0610-5351</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Regenerative Medicine and Tissue Engineering, Department of Large Animal Clinical Sciences, College of Veterinary Medicine, University of Tennessee, Knoxville, TN, 37996, USA. mdhar@utk.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Tissue Eng Regen Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101699923</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1738-2696</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Achilles tissue engineering</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomimetic constructs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical translation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41832926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13770-026-00799-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13770-026-00799-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hopkins C, Fu SC, Chua E, Hu X, Rolf C, Mattila VM, et al. Critical review on the socio-economic impact of tendinopathy. Asia-Pac J Sports Med, Arthrosc, Rehabilit Technol. 2016;4:9&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz-Alonso S, Lafuente-Merchan M, Ciriza J, Saenz-Del-Burgo L, Pedraz JL. Tendon tissue engineering: cells, growth factors, scaffolds and production techniques. J Control Release. 2021;333:448&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33811983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2021.03.040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q, Zhu Y, Zhu W, Zhang G, Yang YP, Zhao C. The role of MicroRNAs in tendon injury, repair, and related tissue engineering. Biomaterials. 2021;277:121083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34488121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9235073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biomaterials.2021.121083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JB, Wu YF, Cao Y, Chen CH, Zhou YL, Avanessian B, et al. Basic FGF or VEGF gene therapy corrects insufficiency in the intrinsic healing capacity of tendons. Sci Rep. 2016;6:20643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26865366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4749961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep20643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning C, Li P, Gao C, Fu L, Liao Z, Tian G, et al. Recent advances in tendon tissue engineering strategy. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2023;11:1115312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36890920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9986339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2023.1115312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler DL, Juncosa N, Dressler MR. Functional efficacy of tendon repair processes. Annu Rev Biomed Eng. 2004;6:303&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15255772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.bioeng.6.040803.140240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger AC, Berkowitz MJ. Achilles tendon injuries. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2017;10:72&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28194638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5344857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12178-017-9386-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinmann S, Pfeifer CG, Brochhausen C, Docheva D. Spectrum of tendon pathologies: triggers, trails and end-state. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:844..</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peers KH, Brys PP, Lysens RJ. Correlation between power Doppler ultrasonography and clinical severity in Achilles tendinopathy. Int Orthop. 2003;27:180&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12799763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3458440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00264-002-0426-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan JJ, Chen KK, Sarker S, Hasija R, Huang H-H, Guzman JZ, et al. Epidemiology of Achilles tendon injuries in collegiate level athletes in the United States. Int Orthop. 2020;44:585&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31907586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00264-019-04471-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Xu J, Wang A, Zheng M. Scaffolds for tendon and ligament repair: review of the efficacy of commercial products. Expert Rev Med Devices. 2009;6:61&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19105781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1586/17434440.6.1.61</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng S, Sun Z, Zhang C, Chen G, Li J. Surgical treatment versus conservative management for acute Achilles tendon rupture: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Foot Ankle Surg. 2017;56:1236&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29079238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.jfas.2017.05.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winnicki K, Ochala-Klos A, Rutowicz B, Pekala PA, Tomaszewski KA. Functional anatomy, histology and biomechanics of the human Achilles tendon - a comprehensive review. Ann Anat. 2020;229:151461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31978571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aanat.2020.151461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslan H, Kimelman-Bleich N, Pelled G, Gazit D. Molecular targets for tendon neoformation. J Clin Invest. 2008;118:439&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18246194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2214706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI33944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Towler DA, Gelberman RH. The alchemy of tendon repair: a primer for the (S)mad scientist. J Clin Invest. 2006;116(4):863&#x2013;6. .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16585955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1421371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI28320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenwick SA, Hazleman BL, Riley GP. The vasculature and its role in the damaged and healing tendon. Arthritis Res Ther. 2002;4:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjaer M. Role of extracellular matrix in adaptation of tendon and skeletal muscle to mechanical loading. Physiol Rev. 2004;84:649&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15044685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00031.2003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doral MN, Alam M, Bozkurt M, Turhan E, Atay OA, D&#xf6;nmez G, et al. Functional anatomy of the Achilles tendon. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2010;18:638&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20182867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-010-1083-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nickisch F. Anatomy of the Achilles tendon. The Achilles tendon: treatment and rehabilitation. 2009:2&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawe EJ, Davis J. (vi) Anatomy and biomechanics of the foot and ankle. Orthop Trauma. 2011;25:279&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mporth.2011.02.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maganaris CN, Narici MV, Maffulli N. Biomechanics of the Achilles tendon. Disabil Rehabil. 2008;30:1542&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18720120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638280701785494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, Zhang P, Shi G, Wang L, Sun C, Xiang W. Tendon extracellular-matrix-derived tissue engineering micro-tissue for Achilles tendon injury regeneration in rats. J Orthop Surg Res. 2024;19:377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38926735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11210118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-024-04863-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulze-Tanzil GG, Delgado C&#xe1;ceres M, Stange R, Wildemann B, Docheva D. Tendon healing: a concise review on cellular and molecular mechanisms with a particular focus on the Achilles tendon. Bone &amp; Joint Res. 2022;11:561&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/2046-3758.118.BJR-2021-0576.R1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomopoulos S, Parks WC, Rifkin DB, Derwin KA. Mechanisms of tendon injury and repair. J Orthop Res. 2015;33:832&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.22806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25641114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4418182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millar NL, Silbernagel KG, Thorborg K, Kirwan PD, Galatz LM, Abrams GD, et al. Tendinopathy. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2021;7:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33414454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41572-020-00234-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millar NL, Akbar M, Campbell AL, Reilly JH, Kerr SC, McLean M, et al. IL-17A mediates inflammatory and tissue remodelling events in early human tendinopathy. Sci Rep. 2016;6:27149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27263531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4893609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep27149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abate M, Gravare Silbernagel K, Siljeholm C, Di Iorio A, De Amicis D, Salini V, et al. Pathogenesis of tendinopathies: inflammation or degeneration? Arthritis Res Ther. 2009;11:235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19591655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2714139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/ar2723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paredes JJ, Andarawis-Puri N. Therapeutics for tendon regeneration: a multidisciplinary review of tendon research for improved healing. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2016;1383:125&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27768813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5560267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nyas.13228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger AC, Berkowitz MJ. Achilles tendon injuries. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2017;10:72&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28194638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5344857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12178-017-9386-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knobloch K, Grasemann R, Spies M, Vogt PM. Midportion achilles tendon microcirculation after intermittent combined cryotherapy and compression compared with cryotherapy alone: a randomized trial. Am J Sports Med. 2008;36:2128&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18641371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546508319313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vulpiani MC, Trischitta D, Trovato P, Vetrano M, Ferretti A. Extracorporeal shockwave therapy (ESWT) in Achilles tendinopathy. A long-term follow-up observational study. J Sports Med Phys Fit, The. 2009;49:171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chester R, Costa ML, Shepstone L, Cooper A, Donell ST. Eccentric calf muscle training compared with therapeutic ultrasound for chronic Achilles tendon pain&#x2014;a pilot study. Man Ther. 2008;13:484&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17662639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.math.2007.05.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der P, Molsberger A, Drabik A, Karst M, Merk H. Percutaneous bioelectric current stimulation in the treatment of chronic Achilles tendinopathy: protocol for a double-blind, placebo-controlled randomized multicenter trial. JMIR Res Protoc. 2022;11:e40894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36325808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9700236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/40894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Morales C, Mart&#xed;n-Llantino PJ, Calvo-Lobo C, Beltran-Alacreu H, L&#xf3;pez-L&#xf3;pez D, S&#xe1;nchez-G&#xf3;mez R, et al. Effectiveness of eccentric exercise and a vibration or cryotherapy program in enhancing rectus abdominis muscle thickness and inter-rectus distance in patients with chronic mid-portion achilles tendinopathy: A randomized clinical trial. Int J Med Sci. 2018;15:1764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30588201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6299416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/ijms.28656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skjong CC, Meininger AK, Ho SS. Tendinopathy treatment: where is the evidence? Clin Sports Med. 2012;31:329&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22341021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csm.2011.11.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kartus J, Movin T, Karlsson J. Donor-site morbidity and anterior knee problems after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction using autografts. Arthros: The J Arthros Relat Surg. 2001;17:971&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/jars.2001.28979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grove JR. Autograft, allograft and xenograft options in the treatment of neglected Achilles tendon ruptures: a historical review with illustration of surgical repair. Surgeon. 2008;15:47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarzaeem MM, Lemraski MM, Safdari F. Chronic Achilles tendon rupture reconstruction using a free semitendinosus tendon graft transfer. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2012;20:1386&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues MT, Reis RL, Gomes ME. Engineering tendon and ligament tissues: present developments towards successful clinical products. J Tissue Eng Regen Med. 2013;7:673&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22499564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/term.1459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones MP, Khan RJ, Carey Smith RL. Surgical interventions for treating acute achilles tendon rupture: key findings from a recent cochrane review. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2012;94:e88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo UG, Mazzola A, De Salvatore S, Denaro V. Biologic Strategies of Tendon Injuries. Orthopaedic Sports Medicine: An Encyclopedic Review of Diagnosis, Prevention, and Management. Springer; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez M, Anitua E, Azofra J, And&#xed;a I, Padilla S, Mujika I. Comparison of surgically repaired Achilles tendon tears using platelet-rich fibrin matrices. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35:245&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17099241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546506294078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou J, Mo X, Shi Z, Li T, Xue J, Mei G, et al. A prospective study of platelet-rich plasma as biological augmentation for acute Achilles tendon rupture repair. Biomed Res Int. 2016;2016:9364170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28116306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5225328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/9364170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boesen AP, Boesen MI, Hansen R, Barfod KW, Lenskjold A, Malliaras P, et al. Effect of platelet-rich plasma on nonsurgically treated acute Achilles tendon ruptures: a randomized, double-blinded prospective study. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48:2268&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32485112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546520922541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang X, Leng Q, Tang Y, Wang L, Huang J, Zhang Y, et al. Ultrasound-targeted microbubble destruction delivery of insulin-like growth factor 1 cDNA and transforming growth factor beta short hairpin RNA enhances tendon regeneration and inhibits scar formation in vivo. Hum Gene Ther Clin Dev. 2018;29:198&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30359117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/humc.2018.121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelled G, Snedeker JG, Ben-Arav A, Rigozzi S, Zilberman Y, Kimelman-Bleich N, et al. Smad8/BMP2-engineered mesenchymal stem cells induce accelerated recovery of the biomechanical properties of the Achilles tendon. J Orthop Res. 2012;30:1932&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22696396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3479351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.22167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Yu R, Wang M, Wang S, Ouyang X, Yan Z, et al. Insulin-like growth factor binding protein 4 loaded electrospun membrane ameliorating tendon injury by promoting retention of IGF-1. J Control Release. 2023;356:162&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36868516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2023.02.039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo D, Li H, Liu Y, Yu X, Zhang X, Chu W, et al. Fibroblast growth factor-2 promotes the function of tendon-derived stem cells in Achilles tendon restoration in an Achilles tendon injury rat model. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2020;521:91&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31629466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2019.10.082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgerald MJ, Mustapich T, Liang H, Larsen CG, Nellans KW, Grande DA. Tendon transection healing can be improved with adipose-derived stem cells cultured with growth differentiation factor 5 and platelet-derived growth factor. HAND. 2023;18:436&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34340572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15589447211028929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Liu H, Stile F, Lei M-P, Pang Y, Oswald TM, et al. Effect of vascular endothelial growth factor on rat Achilles tendon healing. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2003;112:1613&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14578792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.PRS.0000086772.72535.A4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin M, Li W, Ni X, Sui Y, Li H, Chen X, et al. Growth factors in the treatment of Achilles tendon injury. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2023;11:1250533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Yu Q, Wu B, Lin Z, Pavlos NJ, Xu J, et al. Autologous tenocyte therapy for experimental Achilles tendinopathy in a rabbit model. Tissue Eng Part A. 2011;17:2037&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21495863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/ten.tea.2010.0492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J, Zhang D, Lan Q, Zhong G, Liu Y, Holwell N, et al. Tendon decellularized matrix modified fibrous scaffolds with porous and crimped microstructure for tendon regeneration. ACS Appl Bio Mater. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng D, Wang W, Wang B, Zhang P, Zhou G, Zhang WJ, et al. Repair of Achilles tendon defect with autologous ASCs engineered tendon in a rabbit model. Biomaterials. 2014;35:8801&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25069604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biomaterials.2014.06.058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie S, Zhou Y, Tang Y, Chen C, Li S, Zhao C, et al. Book&#x2010;shaped decellularized tendon matrix scaffold combined with bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells&#x2010;sheets for repair of achilles tendon defect in rabbit. J Orthop Res. 2019;37:887&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30816590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.24255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chailakhyan RK, Kon E, Shekhter AB, Ivannikov SV, Telpukhov VI, Grosheva AG, et al. Autologous bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells provide complete regeneration in a rabbit model of the Achilles tendon bundle rupture. Int Orthop. 2021;45:3263&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34510279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00264-021-05168-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakajima T, Nakahata A, Yamada N, Yoshizawa K, Kato TM, Iwasaki M, et al. Grafting of iPS cell-derived tenocytes promotes motor function recovery after Achilles tendon rupture. Nat Commun. 2021;12:5012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34408142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8373964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-25328-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelakanti RV, Kooreman NG, Wu JC. Teratoma formation: a tool for monitoring pluripotency in stem cell research. Curr Protoc Stem Cell Biol. 2015;32:4A 8 1-4A 8 17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25640819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4402211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnabel LV, Koch DW. Use of mesenchymal stem cells for tendon healing in veterinary and human medicine: getting to the &#x201c;core&#x201d; of the problem through a one health approach. J Am Vet Med Assoc. 2023;261:1435&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37643722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11027114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2460/javma.23.07.0388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossuyt FM, Leonard TR, Scott WM, Taylor WR, Herzog W. In-vivo and in-vitro environments affect the storage and release of energy in tendons. Front Physiol. 2024;15:1443675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39148742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11324601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2024.1443675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bianchi E, Ruggeri M, Rossi S, Vigani B, Miele D, Bonferoni MC, et al. Innovative strategies in tendon tissue engineering. Pharmaceutics. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maghdouri-White Y, Sori N, Petrova S, Wriggers H, Kemper N, Dasgupta A, et al. Biomanufacturing organized collagen-based microfibers as a tissue ENgineered Device (TEND) for tendon regeneration. Biomed Mater. 2021;16:025025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32927444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-605X/abb875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Jin S, Luo D, He D, Shi C, Zhu L, et al. Functional regeneration and repair of tendons using biomimetic scaffolds loaded with recombinant periostin. Nat Commun. 2021;12:1293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33637721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7910464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-21545-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang L, Yang Y, Li Y, Yang G, Luo T, Xue Y, et al. Knitted silk mesh-like scaffold incorporated with sponge-like regenerated silk fibroin/collagen I and seeded with mesenchymal stem cells for repairing Achilles tendon in rabbits. Acta Bioeng Biomech. 2018;20:77&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30520436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S, Shi X, Li X, Wang J, Wang Y, Luo Y. Oriented collagen fiber membranes formed through counter-rotating extrusion and their application in tendon regeneration. Biomaterials. 2019;207:61&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30954886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biomaterials.2019.03.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen E, Yang L, Ye C, Zhang W, Ran J, Xue D, et al. An asymmetric chitosan scaffold for tendon tissue engineering: in vitro and in vivo evaluation with rat tendon stem/progenitor cells. Acta Biomater. 2018;73:377&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29678676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actbio.2018.04.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Z, Peng R, Zhang Y, Shan Y, Ding W, Liu Y, et al. Tendon repair and regeneration using bioinspired fibrillation engineering that mimicked the structure and mechanics of natural tissue. ACS Nano. 2023;17:17858&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37656882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.3c03428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koohi-Hosseinabadi O, Shahriarirad R, Dehghanian A, Amini L, Barzegar S, Daneshparvar A, et al. In-vitro and in-vivo assessment of biocompatibility and efficacy of ostrich eggshell membrane combined with platelet-rich plasma in Achilles tendon regeneration. Sci Rep. 2025;15:841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39755875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11700202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-85131-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang R, Chen L, Sefat F, Li X, Liu S, Yuan X, et al. A natural hydrogel with prohealing properties enhances tendon regeneration. Small. 2022;18:e2105255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35304821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202105255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Ma L. Therapeutic effects of chitosan/&#x3b2;-glycerophosphate/collagen hydrogel combined with MSCs on chronic achilles tendon injury via the Akt/GSK-3&#x3b2; pathway. J Orthop Surg Res. 2025;20:204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40012050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11866608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-025-05607-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai W, Xu Q, Li Q, Wang X, Zhang W, Zhou G, et al. Piezoelectric nanofilms fabricated by coaxial electrospun polycaprolactone/Barium titanate promote Achilles tendon regeneration by reducing IL-17A/NF-&#x3ba;B-mediated inflammation. Bioact Mater. 2025;49:1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40110584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11914770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge Z, Qiao Y, Zhu W, Xu Y, Fang Q, Wang D, et al. Highly stretchable polyester-based piezoelectric elastomer for simultaneously realization of accelerated regeneration and motion monitoring for Achilles tendon rupture. Nano Energy. 2023;115:108751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2023.108751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Lin X, Tu T, Guo Z, Song Z, Jiang Y, et al. Mechanical loading on cell-free polymer composite scaffold enhances in situ regeneration of fully functional Achilles tendon in a rabbit model. Biomater Adv. 2024;163:213950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38972278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bioadv.2024.213950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Sun Y, Chen Y, Lu J, Jiang G, Yu K, et al. Sandwich biomimetic scaffold based tendon stem/progenitor cell alignment in a 3D microenvironment for functional tendon regeneration. ACS Appl Mater Interfaces. 2023;15:4652&#x2013;67. https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.2c16584 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.2c16584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36698266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meimandi-Parizi A, Oryan A, Moshiri A. Tendon tissue engineering and its role on healing of the experimentally induced large tendon defect model in rabbits: a comprehensive in vivo study. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e73016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24039851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3764104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0073016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin Z, Sun L, Shi L, Nie H, Dai J, Zhang C. Bioinspired bimodal micro-nanofibrous scaffolds promote the tenogenic differentiation of tendon stem/progenitor cells for achilles tendon regeneration. Biomater Sci. 2022;10:753&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34985056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D1BM01287H</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Z, Lin B, Huang C, Duan A, Zhang C, Qiang G, et al. Biocompatible and stretchable chitosan piezoelectric gel with antibacterial capability and motion monitoring function for Achilles tendon rupture treatment. Carbohyd Polym. 2025;352:123149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2024.123149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Yuan H, Liu H, Chen X, Lu P, Zhu T, et al. Well-aligned chitosan-based ultrafine fibers committed teno-lineage differentiation of human induced pluripotent stem cells for Achilles tendon regeneration. Biomaterials. 2015;53:716&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25890767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biomaterials.2015.02.051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu T, Shen Y, Wang X, Zhang W, Zhou G, Zhang Y, et al. Tendon ECM modified bioactive electrospun fibers promote MSC tenogenic differentiation and tendon regeneration. Appl Mater Today. 2020;18:100495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmt.2019.100495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning C, Gao C, Li P, Fu L, Chen W, Liao Z, et al. Dual-phase aligned composite scaffolds loaded with tendon-derived stem cells for achilles tendon repair. Adv Ther. 2022;5:2200081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adtp.202200081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Yang Y, Zhang K, Li Y, Fang G. Weft-knitted silk-poly (lactide-co-glycolide) mesh scaffold combined with collagen matrix and seeded with mesenchymal stem cells for rabbit Achilles tendon repair. Connect Tissue Res. 2015;56:25&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25333819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/03008207.2014.976309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chailakhyan RK, Kon E, Shekhter AB, Ivannikov SV, Telpukhov VI, Grosheva AG, et al. Autologous bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells provide complete regeneration in a rabbit model of the Achilles tendon bundle rupture. Int Orthop. 2021;45:3263&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00264-021-05168-1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00264-021-05168-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34510279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert TW, Sellaro TL, Badylak SF. Decellularization of tissues and organs. Biomaterials. 2006;27:3675&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16519932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biomaterials.2006.02.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottagisio M, D&#x2019;Arrigo D, Tal&#xf2; G, Bongio M, Ferroni M, Boschetti F, et al. Achilles tendon repair by decellularized and engineered xenografts in a rabbit model. Stem Cells Int. 2019;2019:5267479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31558905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6735180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/5267479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Yu MZ, Peng H, Liu RT, Lim T, Zhang CQ, et al. Decellularized tilapia fish skin: a novel candidate for tendon tissue engineering. Mater Today Bio. 2022;17:100488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtbio.2022.100488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36388457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9647638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostadi Y, Khanali J, Tehrani FA, Yazdanpanah G, Bahrami S, Niazi F, et al. Decellularized extracellular matrix scaffolds for soft tissue augmentation: from Host-Scaffold interactions to bottlenecks in clinical translation. Biomater Res. 2024;28:0071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39247652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11378302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34133/bmr.0071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youngstrom DW, Barrett JG. Engineering tendon: scaffolds, bioreactors, and models of regeneration. Stem Cells Int. 2016;2016:3919030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26839559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/3919030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song H, Yin Z, Wu T, Li Y, Luo X, Xu M, et al. Enhanced effect of tendon stem/progenitor cells combined with tendon-derived decellularized extracellular matrix on tendon regeneration. Cell Transplant. 2018;27:1634&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30298746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6299202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0963689718805383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang X, Wu S, Kuss M, Kong Y, Shi W, Streubel PN, et al. 3D printing of multilayered scaffolds for rotator cuff tendon regeneration. Bioact Mater. 2020;5:636&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32405578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7212184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter JE, Hankenson KD. Animal models of tendon and ligament injuries for tissue engineering applications. Biomaterials. 2004;25:1715&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14697872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0142-9612(03)00507-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscat S, Nichols AE. Leveraging in vivo animal models of tendon loading to inform tissue engineering approaches. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2024;12:1449372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39434716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11491380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2024.1449372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aykora D, Ta&#x15f;&#xe7;&#x131; B, &#x15e;ahin MZ, Tekeo&#x11f;lu I, Uzun M, Sarafian V, et al. Tendon regeneration deserves better: focused review on in vivo models, artificial intelligence and 3D bioprinting approaches. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2025;13:1580490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40352349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12062838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2025.1580490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa ML, Achten J, Marian IR, Dutton SJ, Lamb SE, Ollivere B, et al. Plaster cast versus functional brace for non-surgical treatment of Achilles tendon rupture (UKSTAR): a multicentre randomised controlled trial and economic evaluation. The Lancet. 2020;395(10222):441&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)32942-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi JY, Choo SK, Kim BH, Suh JS. Conservative treatment outcome for Achilles tendon re-rupture occurring in the subacute phase after primary repair. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2024;144:1055&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38114740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00402-023-05161-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatz M, Driessen A, Eschweiler J, Tingart M, Migliorini F. Open versus minimally-invasive surgery for Achilles tendon rupture: a meta-analysis study. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2021;141:383&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32266518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00402-020-03437-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng H, Cheng X, Yang Y, Fang F, He J, Tian Y, et al. Rerupture outcome of conservative versus open repair versus minimally invasive repair of acute Achilles tendon ruptures: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2023;18:e0285046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37130120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10153690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0285046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King CM, Vartivarian M. Achilles tendon rupture repair: simple to complex. Clin Podiatr Med Surg. 2023;40:75&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36368849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpm.2022.07.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis RE, Towery EA, Bhat SG, Ward AJ, Heidel RE, Bielak KM, et al. Human acellular dermal matrix is a viable alternative to autologous skin graft in patients with cutaneous malignancy. The American Surgeon&#x2122;. 2019;85:1056&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31638524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/000313481908500953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajalik RE, Linares I, Alenchery RG, Zhang VZ, Wright TW, Miller BL, et al. Human tendon-on-a-chip for modeling the myofibroblast microenvironment in peritendinous fibrosis. Adv Healthc Mater. 2025;14:e2403116. https://doi.org/10.1002/adhm.202403116 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adhm.202403116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39544139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakht SM, Pardo A, Gomez-Florit M, Caballero D, Kundu SC, Reis RL, et al. Human tendon-on-chip: unveiling the effect of core compartment-T cell spatiotemporal crosstalk at the onset of tendon inflammation. Adv Sci. 2024;11:e2401170. https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202401170 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/advs.202401170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>