<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41737509</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1689-832X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of contemporary brachytherapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Contemp Brachytherapy</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Isoflurane as a cost-effective alternative to sevoflurane for short-duration gynaecological brachytherapy: a randomised non-inferiority trial of emergence.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>382</StartPage><EndPage>389</EndPage><MedlinePgn>382-389</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/jcb.2025.158427</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The optimal anaesthetic choice for gynaecological brachytherapy remains uncertain. While sevoflurane offers rapid recovery due to favourable pharmacokinetics, its higher cost limits affordability in resource-constrained settings. Isoflurane, a less expensive volatile agent, may be a cost-effective alternative if recovery profiles are comparable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIAL AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We conducted a prospective, randomised, non-inferiority trial including 100 women with American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) physical status I-III undergoing ambulatory intracavitary brachytherapy. Participants were randomly allocated to maintenance anaesthesia with either isoflurane (<i>n</i> = 50) or sevoflurane (<i>n</i> = 50), with anaesthetic depth titrated to maintain a bi-spectral index (BIS) between 40 and 60. The primary outcome was emergence time, defined as the interval from discontinuation of anaesthesia to eye opening after verbal command. Secondary outcomes included time to supraglottic airway removal, haemodynamic stability, postoperative cognitive function, post-anaesthesia care unit (PACU) stay, adverse events, and anaesthetic agent cost. Non-inferiority was prespecified with a margin of 3.2 minutes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Emergence times were similar between isoflurane and sevoflurane groups (7.13 &#xb1;1.60 min vs. 7.24 &#xb1;1.70 min; mean difference 0.12 min; 97.5% CI: 0.86 to -0.63), confirming non-inferiority of isoflurane. Secondary outcomes, including airway removal time, haemodynamics, cognitive scores, PACU stay and adverse events, showed no significant differences. Isoflurane administration cost was 61.6% lower compared to sevoflurane (22.2 &#xb1;2.77 INR vs. 57.8 &#xb1;9.35 INR; <i>p</i> = 0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Isoflurane is non-inferior to sevoflurane for emergence time in short-duration gynaecological brachytherapy, with comparable recovery profiles. Its substantial cost advantage supports its use as an economical anaesthetic option in high-volume, resource-limited oncology settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Termedia.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramya</LastName><ForeName>Ramachandiran</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia and Intensive Care, Post-Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ganesh</LastName><ForeName>Venkata</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia and Intensive Care, Post-Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naveen</LastName><ForeName>Naik B</ForeName><Initials>NB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia and Intensive Care, Post-Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Srinivasa</LastName><ForeName>G Y</ForeName><Initials>GY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiotherapy and Oncology, Post-Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Ajay</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia and Intensive Care, Post-Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Samra</LastName><ForeName>Tanvir</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia and Intensive Care, Post-Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhukal</LastName><ForeName>Ishwar</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia and Intensive Care, Post-Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Contemp Brachytherapy</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101506276</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2081-2841</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anaesthesia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brachytherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">costs and cost analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">isoflurane</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sevoflurane</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41737509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12928139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/jcb.2025.158427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">57407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lee JH. Anesthesia for ambulatory surgery. Korean J Anesthesiol 2017; 70: 398-406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5548941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28794834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awad IT, Chung F. Factors affecting recovery and discharge following ambulatory surgery. Can J Anaesth J Can Anesth 2006; 53: 858-872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16960263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellizzon ACA. Pain relief procedures before high-dose-rate brachytherapy for non-surgical treatment of cervix cancer. J Contemp Brachytherapy 2018; 10: 567-569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6335560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30662480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen AA, Liyanage TA, Leiserowitz GSet al. Optimal perioperative anesthesia management for gynecologic interstitial brachytherapy. J Contemp Brachytherapy 2017; 9: 216-223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5509989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28725244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan PW, Koh VY, Tang JI. Outpatient combined intracavitary and interstitial cervical brachytherapy: barriers and solutions to implementation of a successful programme&#x2013;a single institutional experience. J Contemp Brachytherapy 2015; 7: 259-263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4499522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26207117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Stierer T, Zuckerman Ret al. Comparison of recovery profile after ambulatory anesthesia with propofol, isoflurane, sevoflurane and desflurane: a systematic review. Anesth Analg 2004; 98: 632-641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14980911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakai EM, Connolly LA, Klauck JA. Inhalation anesthesiology and volatile liquid anesthetics: focus on isoflurane, desflurane, and sevoflurane. Pharmacotherapy 2005; 25: 1773-1788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16305297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado-Herrera L, Ostroff RD, Rogers SA. Sevoflurance: approaching the ideal inhalational anesthetic. a pharmacologic, pharmacoeconomic, and clinical review. CNS Drug Rev 2001; 7: 48-120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6741648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11420572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner BK, O&#x2019;Hara DA. Pharmacoeconomic analysis of sevoflurane versus isoflurane anesthesia in elective ambulatory surgery. Pharmacotherapy 1997; 17: 1006-1010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9324189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maheshwari K, Ahuja S, Mascha EJet al. Effect of sevoflurane versus isoflurane on emergence time and postanesthesia care unit length of stay: an alternating intervention trial. Anesth Analg 2020; 130: 360-366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30882520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golembiewski J. Economic considerations in the use of inhaled anesthetic agents. Am J Health-Syst Pharm 2010; 67 (8 Suppl 4): S9-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20360573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moody AE, Beutler BD, Moody CE. Predicting cost of inhalational anesthesia at low fresh gas flows: impact of a new generation carbon dioxide absorbent. Med Gas Res 2020; 10: 64-66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7885709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32541130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinberg L, Story D, Nam Jet al. Pharmacoeconomics of volatile inhalational anaesthetic agents: an 11-year retrospective analysis. Anaesth Intensive Care 2010; 38: 849-854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20865868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu CL, Chan YK, Ong GSet al. A comparison of the maintenance and recovery characteristic of sevoflurane-nitrous oxide against isoflurane-nitrous oxide anaesthesia. Singapore Med J 2000; 41: 530-533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11284610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda N, Lockhart SH, Eger EIet al. Comparison of kinetics of sevoflurane and isoflurane in humans. Anesth Analg 1991; 72: 316-324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1994760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda N, Targ AG, Eger EI. Solubility of I-653, sevoflurane, isoflurane, and halothane in human tissues. Anesth Analg 1989; 69: 370-373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2774233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendrix JM, Garmon EH. American Society of Anesthesiologists Physical Status Classification System. In: StatPearls [Internet]. StatPearls Publishing, Treasure Island (FL)
2025.  (cited 2025 Dec 9). Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK441940/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28722969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahantshetty U, Gudi S, Singh Ret al. Indian Brachytherapy Society Guidelines for radiotherapeutic management of cervical cancer with special emphasis on high-dose-rate brachytherapy. J Contemp Brachytherapy 2019; 11: 293-306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6737572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31523229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biro P, Kneschke O, Theusinger OM. Reliability of the volatile agent consumption display in the Draeger PrimusTM anesthesia machine. J Clin Monit Comput 2015; 29: 601-604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25388511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahajan VA, Ni Chonghaile M, Bokhari SAet al. Recovery of older patients undergoing ambulatory anaesthesia with isoflurane or sevoflurane. Eur J Anaesthesiol 2007; 24: 505-510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17202009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin JM, Park JS, Park BSet al. The comparison of recovery characteristics following anesthesia with propofol, sevoflurane or isoflurane in adults undergoing outpatient surgery. Korean J Anesthesiol 46: 213-217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson BJ, Uhrich TD, Ebert TJ. A review of recovery from sevoflurane anaesthesia: comparisons with isoflurane and propofol including meta-analysis. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand 1999; 43: 185-190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10027026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier A, Girard F, Boudreault Det al. Sevoflurane provides faster recovery and postoperative neurological assessment than isoflurane in long-duration neurosurgical cases. Anesth Analg 2002; 95: 1384-1388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12401630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell C, Andreen M, Battito MFet al. A phase III, multicenter, open-label, randomized, comparative study evaluating the effect of sevoflurane versus isoflurane on the maintenance of anesthesia in adult ASA class I, II, and III inpatients. J Clin Anesth 1996; 8: 557-563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8910177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scholz J, Bischoff P, Szafarczyk Wet al. Comparison of sevoflurane and isoflurane in ambulatory surgery. Results of a multicenter study. Anaesthesist 1996; 45 Suppl 1: S63-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8775106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert TJ, Robinson BJ, Uhrich TDet al. Recovery from sevoflurane anesthesia: a comparison to isoflurane and propofol anesthesia. Anesthesiology 1998; 89: 1524-1531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9856729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitsonen ERJ, Yli-Hankala AM, Korttila KT. Similar recovery from bispectral index-titrated isoflurane and sevoflurane anesthesia after outpatient gynecological surgery. J Clin Anesth 2006; 18: 272-279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16797429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ries CR, Azmud&#xe9;h A, Franciosi LGet al. Cost comparison of sevoflurane with isoflurane anesthesia in arthroscopic menisectomy surgery. Can J Anaesth J Can Anesth 1999; 46: 1008-1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10566918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutyala S, Smith G, Ansinelli Het al. Feasibility of outpatient hybrid brachytherapy for cervical cancer with minimal sedation: Results from a single-institutional protocol. J Contemp Brachytherapy 2023; 15: 43-47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10034729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36970442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fionda B, Placidi E, Lancellotta Vet al. COMIRI&#x2013;COMplexity Index of interventional Radiotherapy (brachytherapy) Implants: assessment of procedures based on type, equipment, and team. J Contemp Brachytherapy 2024; 16: 306-309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11609858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39628818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>