<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41739927</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2375-2548</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Science advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Inflamed vessel-anchored release of H<sub>2</sub> across the blood-brain barrier for ischemic stroke neuroprotection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>eaea3355</StartPage><MedlinePgn>eaea3355</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">eaea3355</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1126/sciadv.aea3355</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ischemic stroke followed by reperfusion urgently requires safe and efficient cytoprotective strategies, a need still unmet by current pharmacotherapies. Nanotechnology holds promise for improved drug delivery to the brain, yet the efficacy of nanomaterials crossing the blood-brain barrier (BBB) is quite limited, and long-term intracranial retention of nanomaterials may provoke neurotoxicity. Leveraging the anti-inflammatory, BBB-crossing, and biosafe properties of hydrogen (H<sub>2</sub>), we develop an inflamed vessel-targeted/anchored H<sub>2</sub>-producing system by modifying ZrSi<sub>2</sub> nanoparticles with a P-selectin-binding peptide (ZSNP), mimicking P-selectin/P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-mediated innate immune recruitment. Rather than relying on nanoparticle penetration into the brain parenchyma, this design enables ZSNP to anchor at the BBB vasculature, where it locally and continuously generates H<sub>2</sub> via hydrolysis. The released H<sub>2</sub> traverses the BBB, exerting cytoprotection through antioxidant and immunomodulatory mechanisms that coordinate multicellular recovery processes. Furthermore, ZSNP promotes microglia-mediated angiogenesis and neurogenesis, guides axonal projections along neovascular trajectories, and facilitates microglia-neuron interaction via the noncanonical Wnt/Ca<sup>2+</sup> pathway. This reconstruction of the neurovascular network supports the reintegration of functional neural circuits, leading to structural and functional recovery that surpasses the effects of edaravone. By enabling sustained H<sub>2</sub> release at the BBB interface without requiring nanoparticle intracranial accumulation, this strategy represents a promising and low-burden neuroprotective approach for ischemic stroke.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Yuanman</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0030-7881</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The State Key Laboratory of Bioreactor Engineering, Key Laboratory for Ultrafine Materials of Ministry of Education, Frontiers Science Center for Materiobiology and Dynamic Chemistry, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Mingjian</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Human-Machine-Intelligence Synergic System, Research Center for Neural Engineering, Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shenzhen, Guangdong 518055, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Gaoyi</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Human-Machine-Intelligence Synergic System, Research Center for Neural Engineering, Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shenzhen, Guangdong 518055, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yongcheng</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-6570-6445</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Human-Machine-Intelligence Synergic System, Research Center for Neural Engineering, Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shenzhen, Guangdong 518055, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xia</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2886-6415</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Laboratory of Hydrogen Science &amp; Center of Hydrogen Science, School of Materials Science and Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai 200240, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shenzhen Research Institute, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shenzhen 518057, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Wenjiang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Laboratory of Hydrogen Science &amp; Center of Hydrogen Science, School of Materials Science and Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai 200240, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Guanglin</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9016-2617</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Human-Machine-Intelligence Synergic System, Research Center for Neural Engineering, Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shenzhen, Guangdong 518055, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Qianjun</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0689-8838</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Laboratory of Hydrogen Science &amp; Center of Hydrogen Science, School of Materials Science and Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai 200240, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shenzhen Research Institute, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shenzhen 518057, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3524-7110</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Human-Machine-Intelligence Synergic System, Research Center for Neural Engineering, Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shenzhen, Guangdong 518055, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Changsheng</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0509-7334</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The State Key Laboratory of Bioreactor Engineering, Key Laboratory for Ultrafine Materials of Ministry of Education, Frontiers Science Center for Materiobiology and Dynamic Chemistry, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101653440</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2375-2548</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>The other authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41739927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12935045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.aea3355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Campbell B. C. V., De Silva D. A., Macleod M. R., Coutts S. B., Schwamm L. H., Davis S. M., Donnan G. A., Ischaemic stroke. Nat. Rev. Dis. Prim. 5, 70 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31601801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher M., Savitz S. I., Pharmacological brain cytoprotection in acute ischaemic stroke&#x2014;Renewed hope in the reperfusion era. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 18, 193&#x2013;202 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8788909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35079135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamorro &#xc1;., Dirnagl U., Urra X., Planas A. M., Neuroprotection in acute stroke: Targeting excitotoxicity, oxidative and nitrosative stress, and inflammation. Lancet Neurol. 15, 869&#x2013;881 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27180033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J., Wang A., Meng X., Yalkun G., Xu A., Gao Z., Chen H., Ji Y., Xu J., Geng D., Zhu R., Liu B., Dong A., Mu H., Lu Z., Li S., Zheng H., Chen X., Wang Y., Zhao X., Wang Y., Edaravone dexborneol versus edaravone alone for the treatment of acute ischemic stroke: A phase III, randomized, double-blind, comparative trial. Stroke 52, 772&#x2013;780 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33588596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He L., Huang G., Liu H., Sang C., Liu X., Chen T., Highly bioactive zeolitic imidazolate framework-8-capped nanotherapeutics for efficient reversal of reperfusion-induced injury in ischemic stroke. Sci. Adv. 6, 29&#x2013;31 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7080448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32206718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He W., Zhang Z., Sha X., Nanoparticles-mediated emerging approaches for effective treatment of ischemic stroke. Biomaterials 277, 121111 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34488117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco E., Shen H., Ferrari M., Principles of nanoparticle design for overcoming biological barriers to drug delivery. Nat. Biotechnol. 33, 941&#x2013;951 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4978509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26348965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J., Xia Z., Gunasekar S., Jiang C., Karp J. M., Joshi N., Precision drug delivery to the central nervous system using engineered nanoparticles. Nat. Rev. Mater. 9, 567&#x2013;588 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker S. J., Thayer M. B., Kim C., Tatarakis D., Simon M. J., Dial R., Nilewski L., Wells R. C., Zhou Y., Afetian M., Akkapeddi P., Chappell A., Chew K. S., Chow J., Clemens A., Discenza C. B., Dugas J. C., Dwyer C., Earr T., Ha C., Ho Y. S., Huynh D., Lozano E. I., Jayaraman S., Kwan W., Mahon C., Pizzo M., Robles-Colmenares Y., Roche E., Sanders L., Stergioulis A., Tong R., Tran H., Yu Zuchero Y. J., Estrada A. A., Gadkar K., Koth C. M. M., Sanchez P. E., Thorne R. G., Watts R. J., Sandmann T., Kane L. A., Rigo F., Dennis M. S., Lewcock J. W., DeVos S. L., Targeting the transferrin receptor to transport antisense oligonucleotides across the mammalian blood-brain barrier. Sci. Transl. Med. 17, eadi2245 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39141703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furtado D., Bj&#xf6;rnmalm M., Ayton S., Bush A. I., Kempe K., Caruso F., Overcoming the blood&#x2013;brain barrier: The role of nanomaterials in treating neurological diseases. Adv. Mater. 30, 1801362 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30066406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H., Jiang X., Li Y., Zhou Y., Zhang T., Zhi P., Gao J., Engineering stem cell derived biomimetic vesicles for versatility and effective targeted delivery. Adv. Funct. Mater. 30, 2006169 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan D., Zhao Y., Banks W. A., Bullock K. M., Haney M., Batrakova E., Kabanov A. V., Macrophage exosomes as natural nanocarriers for protein delivery to inflamed brain. Biomaterials 142, 1&#x2013;12 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5603188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28715655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang H. J., Underwood T. C., Bell J. G., Ranjan S., Sasselov D., Whitesides G. M., Focused ultrasound&#x2013;mediated brain genome editing. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 120, e2302910120 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10450663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37579143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezai A. R., D&#x2019;Haese P.-F., Finomore V., Carpenter J., Ranjan M., Wilhelmsen K., Mehta R. I., Wang P., Najib U., Teixeira C. V. L., Arsiwala T., Tarabishy A., Tirumalai P., Claassen D. O., Hodder S., Haut M. W., Ultrasound blood&#x2013;brain barrier opening and aducanumab in alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. N. Engl. J. Med. 390, 55&#x2013;62 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38169490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolak D. J., Thorne R. G., Diffusion of macromolecules in the brain: Implications for drug delivery. Mol. Pharm. 10, 1492&#x2013;1504 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3646902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23298378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barua S., Mitragotri S., Challenges associated with penetration of nanoparticles across cell and tissue barriers: A review of current status and future prospects. Nano Today 9, 223&#x2013;243 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4129396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25132862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J., Song Q., Gu X., Jiang G., Huang J., Tang Y., Yu R., Wang A., Huang Y., Zheng G., Chen H., Gao X., Intracerebral fate of organic and inorganic nanoparticles is dependent on microglial extracellular vesicle function. Nat. Nanotechnol. 19, 376&#x2013;386 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38158436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohsawa I., Ishikawa M., Takahashi K., Watanabe M., Nishimaki K., Yamagata K., Katsura K. I., Katayama Y., Asoh S., Ohta S., Hydrogen acts as a therapeutic antioxidant by selectively reducing cytotoxic oxygen radicals. Nat. Med. 13, 688&#x2013;694 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17486089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong W., Jiang L., Zhu Y., Jiang M., Chen D., Jin Z., Qin S., Yu Z., He Q., An Activity-based ratiometric fluorescent probe for in vivo real-time imaging of hydrogen molecules. Angew. Chemie Int. Ed. 61, e202114594 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34921480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S., Yu Y., Xie S., Liang D., Shi W., Chen S., Li G., Tang W., Liu C., He Q., 
Local H<sub>2</sub> release remodels senescence microenvironment for improved repair of injured bone. Nat. Commun.
14, 
7783 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10682449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38012166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo H. C., Den Chen K., Li P. C., Molecular hydrogen: Emerging treatment for stroke management. Chem. Res. Toxicol. 36, 1864&#x2013;1871 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37988743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamura T., Suzuki M., Homma K., Sano M., Iizuka R., Narimiya H., Tsuruta R., Kaneda K., Fujita M., Sasaki J., Akasaka O., Sawai K., Nozaki M., Imai H., Ishikura K., Ikejiri K., Kakihana Y., Niiyama S., Futatsuki T., Honda M., Ikeda Y., Oka H., Yoshihara H., Onishi H., Yamashita S., Shimizu K., Sakurai T., Yamada S., Fukami H., Shime N., Suzuki K., Kuroda Y., Kawakita K., Kimura A., Uemura T., Takuma K., Kanao K., Yanagawa Y., Takeuchi I., Efficacy of inhaled hydrogen on neurological outcome following brain ischaemia during post-cardiac arrest care (HYBRID II): A multi-centre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. eClinicalMedicine 58, 101907 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10030910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36969346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barancik M., Kura B., Lebaron T. W., Bolli R., Buday J., Slezak J., Molecular and cellular mechanisms associated with effects of molecular hydrogen in cardiovascular and central nervous systems. Antioxidants 9, 1281 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7765453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33333951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Liu K., Zhou Q., Xu C., Gao J., Wang Z., Wang F., Chen B., Ye Y., Ou J., Jiang J., Wilson D. A., Liu S., Peng F., Tu Y., Hydrogen-powered microswimmers for precise and active hydrogen therapy towards acute ischemic stroke. Adv. Funct. Mater. 31, 2009475 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolaczkowska E., Kubes P., Neutrophil recruitment and function in health and inflammation. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 13, 159&#x2013;175 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23435331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe9;meth T., Sperandio M., M&#xf3;csai A., Neutrophils as emerging therapeutic targets. Nat. Rev. Drug Discov. 19, 253&#x2013;275 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31969717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyu Z., Park J., Kim K. M., Jin H. J., Wu H., Rajadas J., Kim D. H., Steinberg G. K., Lee W., A neurovascular-unit-on-a-chip for the evaluation of the restorative potential of stem cell therapies for ischaemic stroke. Nat. Biomed. Eng. 5, 847&#x2013;863 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8524779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34385693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shichita T., Ooboshi H., Yoshimura A., Neuroimmune mechanisms and therapies mediating post-ischaemic brain injury and repair. Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 24, 299&#x2013;312 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36973481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ono H., Nishijima Y., Ohta S., Sakamoto M., Kinone K., Horikosi T., Tamaki M., Takeshita H., Futatuki T., Ohishi W., Ishiguro T., Okamoto S., Ishii S., Takanami H., Hydrogen gas inhalation treatment in acute cerebral infarction: A randomized controlled clinical study on safety and neuroprotection. J. Stroke Cerebrovasc. Dis. 26, 2587&#x2013;2594 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28669654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi L., Sun Z., Su W., Xu F., Xie D., Zhang Q., Dai X., Iyer K., Hitchens T. K., Foley L. M., Li S., Stolz D. B., Chen K., Ding Y., Thomson A. W., Leak R. K., Chen J., Hu X., Treg cell-derived osteopontin promotes microglia-mediated white matter repair after ischemic stroke. Immunity 54, 1527&#x2013;1542 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8282725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34015256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wynn T. A., Vannella K. M., Macrophages in tissue repair, regeneration, and fibrosis. Immunity 44, 450&#x2013;462 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4794754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26982353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W., Mandeville E. T., Dur&#xe1;n-Laforet V., Fukuda N., Yu Z., Zheng Y., Held A., Park J. H., Nakano T., Tanaka M., Shi J., Esposito E., Niu W., Xing C., Hayakawa K., Lizasoain I., van Leyen K., Ji X., Wainger B. J., Moro M. A., Lo E. H., Endothelial cells regulate astrocyte to neural progenitor cell trans-differentiation in a mouse model of stroke. Nat. Commun. 13, 7812 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9763251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36535938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan L., Wang B., Zhuge Q., Jin K., Coupling of neurogenesis and angiogenesis after ischemic stroke. Brain Res. 1623, 166&#x2013;173 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4552615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25736182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang H., Zhao H., Gleichman A., Machnicki M., Telang S., Tang S., Rshtouni M., Ruddell J., Thomas Carmichael S., Region-specific and activity-dependent regulation of SVZ neurogenesis and recovery after stroke. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 116, 13621&#x2013;13630 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6612913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31196958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang H., Li Y., Tang W., Zhu J., Parker G. C., Zhang J. H., Endogenous neural stem cell&#x2013;induced neurogenesis after ischemic stroke: Processes for brain repair and perspectives. Transl. Stroke Res. 14, 297&#x2013;303 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36057034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath S., Mart&#xed;nez Santamar&#xed;a J. C., Chu Y. H., Choi J. S., Conforti P., Di Lin J., Sankowski R., Amann L., Galanis C., Wu K., Deshpande S. S., Vlachos A., Prinz M., Lee J. K., Schachtrup C., Interaction between subventricular zone microglia and neural stem cells impacts the neurogenic response in a mouse model of cortical ischemic stroke. Nat. Commun. 15, 9095 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11502905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39448558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nih L. R., Gojgini S., Carmichael S. T., Segura T., Dual-function injectable angiogenic biomaterial for the repair of brain tissue following stroke. Nat. Mater. 17, 642&#x2013;651 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6019573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29784996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith K. S., Bucci D. J., Luikart B. W., Mahler S. V., Dreadds: Use and application in behavioral neuroscience. Behav. Neurosci. 135, 89&#x2013;107 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34060867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman G. E., Smith M. S., Verbalis J. G., c-Fos and related immediate early gene products as markers of activity in neuroendocrine systems. Front. Neuroendocrinol. 14, 173&#x2013;213 (1993).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8349003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Yang C., Zhang C., Wu J., Zhang X., Gao J., Wang X., Chan L. T., Zhou Y., Chen Y., Tam S. S. T., Chen S., Ma Y., Yung W. H., Duan L., Jiang L., Wang Y., Liu K., Functional optic tract rewiring via subtype- and target-specific axonal regeneration and presynaptic activity enhancement. Nat. Commun. 16, 2174 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11880380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40038284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phan N. V., Rathbun E. M., Ouyang Y., Carmichael S. T., Segura T., Biology-driven material design for ischaemic stroke repair. Nat. Rev. Bioeng. 2, 44&#x2013;63 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obermeier B., Daneman R., Ransohoff R. M., Development, maintenance and disruption of the blood-brain barrier. Nat. Med. 19, 1584&#x2013;1596 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4080800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24309662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown G. C., Neher J. J., Microglial phagocytosis of live neurons. Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 15, 209&#x2013;216 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24646669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastorakos P., Mihelson N., Luby M., Burks S. R., Johnson K., Hsia A. W., Witko J., Frank J. A., Latour L., McGavern D. B., Temporally distinct myeloid cell responses mediate damage and repair after cerebrovascular injury. Nat. Neurosci. 24, 245&#x2013;258 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7854523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33462481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao B., Zeng L., Chen D., Xie S., Jin Z., Li G., NIR-photocatalytic regulation of arthritic synovial microenvironment. Sci. Adv. 8, eabq0959 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9534508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36197972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H., Luo Y., Yang P., Liu J., Hydrogen as a complementary therapy against ischemic stroke: A review of the evidence. J. Neurol. Sci. 396, 240&#x2013;246 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30529801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ono H., Nishijima Y., Adachi N., Sakamoto M., Kudo Y., Kaneko K., Nakao A., Imaoka T., 
A basic study on molecular hydrogen (H<sub>2</sub>) inhalation in acute cerebral ischemia patients for safety check with physiological parameters and measurement of blood H<sub>2</sub> level. Med. Gas Res.
2, 
21 (2012).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3457852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22916706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadareishvili Z., Simpkins A. N., Hitomi E., Reyes D., Leigh R., Post-stroke blood-brain barrier disruption and poor functional outcome in patients receiving thrombolytic therapy. Cerebrovasc. Dis. 47, 135&#x2013;142 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6610790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30970357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman M. H., Bajgai J., Sharma S., Jeong E. S., Goh S. H., Jang Y. G., Kim C. S., Lee K. J., Effects of hydrogen gas inhalation on community-dwelling adults of various ages: A single-arm, open-label, prospective clinical trial. Antioxidants 12, 1241 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10295751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37371971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beuker C., Strecker J. K., Rawal R., Schmidt-Pogoda A., Ruck T., Wiendl H., Klotz L., Sch&#xe4;bitz W. R., Sommer C. J., Minnerup H., Meuth S. G., Minnerup J., Immune cell infiltration into the brain after ischemic stroke in humans compared to mice and rats: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Transl. Stroke Res. 12, 976&#x2013;990 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8557159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33496918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharp F. R., Jickling G. C., Modeling immunity and inflammation in stroke: Differences between rodents and humans? Stroke. 45, e179&#x2013;e180 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4215953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25061082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iadecola C., Anrather J., The immunology of stroke: From mechanisms to translation. Nat. Med. 17, 796&#x2013;808 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3137275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21738161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R. L., Balami J. S., Esiri M. M., Chen L. K., Buchan A. M., Ischemic stroke in the elderly: An overview of evidence. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 6, 256&#x2013;265 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20368741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamashiro T. T., Dalgard C. L., Byrnes K. R., Primary microglia isolation from mixed glial cell cultures of neonatal rat brain tissue. J. Vis. Exp. 66, e3814 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3486750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22929966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Z. X., Tan X., Fang H., Lau P. M., Wang X., Cheng H., Bi G. Q., Dendritic mitoflash as a putative signal for stabilizing long-term synaptic plasticity. Nat. Commun. 8, 31 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5484698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28652625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C., Liu H. J., Qi L., Tao C. L., Wang Y. J., Shen Z., Tian C. L., Lau P. M., Bi G. Q., Structure and plasticity of silent synapses in developing hippocampal neurons visualized by super-resolution imaging. Cell Discov. 6, 8 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7039918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32133151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang T., Messing R. O., Chou W. H., Mouse model of middle cerebral artery occlusion. J. Vis. Exp. 48, e2761 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3197421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21372780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarruk J. G., Garc&#xed;a-Y&#xe9;benes I., Romera V. G., Ballesteros I., Moraga A., Cuartero M. I., Hurtado O., Sobrado M., Pradillo J. M., Fern&#xe1;ndez-L&#xf3;pez D., Serena J., Castillo-Mel&#xe9;ndez M., Moro M. A., Lizasoain I., Neurological tests for functional outcome assessment in rodent models of ischaemic stroke. Rev. Neurol. 53, 607&#x2013;618 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22052176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson A. N., Huang B. S., MacIsaac S. E., Mody I., Carmichael S. T., Reducing excessive GABA-mediated tonic inhibition promotes functional recovery after stroke. Nature 468, 305&#x2013;309 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3058798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21048709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramson J., Adler J., Dunger J., Evans R., Green T., Pritzel A., Ronneberger O., Willmore L., Ballard A. J., Bambrick J., Bodenstein S. W., Evans D. A., Hung C. C., O&#x2019;Neill M., Reiman D., Tunyasuvunakool K., Wu Z., &#x17d;emgulyt&#x117; A., Arvaniti E., Beattie C., Bertolli O., Bridgland A., Cherepanov A., Congreve M., Cowen-Rivers A. I., Cowie A., Figurnov M., Fuchs F. B., Gladman H., Jain R., Khan Y. A., Low C. M. R., Perlin K., Potapenko A., Savy P., Singh S., Stecula A., Thillaisundaram A., Tong C., Yakneen S., Zhong E. D., Zielinski M., &#x17d;&#xed;dek A., Bapst V., Kohli P., Jaderberg M., Hassabis D., Jumper J. M., Accurate structure prediction of biomolecular interactions with AlphaFold 3. Nature 630, 493&#x2013;500 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11168924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38718835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allouche A., Software news and updates gabedit&#x2014;A graphical user interface for computational chemistry softwares. J. Comput. Chem. 32, 174&#x2013;182 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20607691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogan S. C., Roth B. L., Remote control of neuronal signaling. Pharmacol. Rev. 63, 291&#x2013;315 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3082452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21415127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>