<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41723485</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1477-3155</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of nanobiotechnology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Nanobiotechnology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A stimuli-responsive mitochondria-targeted nanoplatform for glioblastoma therapy: modulating the blood-brain barrier and delivering precise chemotherapy.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12951-026-04206-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The blood brain barrier (BBB) is crucial for maintaining homeostasis within the central nervous system (CNS). Its impairment under pathological conditions significantly compromises the efficacy of chemotherapy for glioblastoma (GBM). Therefore, strategies to promote BBB functional recovery could provide a valuable adjunct to GBM chemotherapy. Mitochondria, the primary cellular "powerhouses", are key organelles regulating apoptosis. Mitochondrial dysfunction in either BBB or GBM cells is closely associated with barrier disruption and enhanced tumor cell apoptosis, respectively. This positions mitochondria as a promising dual target for modulating BBB integrity and enabling targeted chemotherapy. Celastrol (Cela), a natural pentacyclic triterpenoid isolated from the traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) Tripterygium wilfordii, has been shown to exhibit many pharmacological activities, including anti-tumor, anti-fibrosis, anti-inflammatory, immunomodulation, antioxidant, and neuroprotective effects. In addition, Cela has been widely used as a mitochondrial protector in CNS disorders, and it also safeguards endothelial cells from apoptosis, which helps maintain the structural and functional integrity of the BBB. However, the applications of Cels are still limited due to its poor water stability, non-specific distribution, low bioavailability, and high systemic toxicity. In this study, we developed a stimuli-responsive mitochondria-targeted nanoplatform encapsulating Cela, termed Cela@Lip-IRH, for the precise treatment of GBM. The incorporation of IR780 facilitated cellular uptake and promoted mitochondrial co-localization of Cela@Lip-IRH in both BBB and GBM cells in vitro. Furthermore, the nanoplatform exhibited enhanced BBB penetration and achieved specific accumulation in GBM tumors in vivo. We systematically investigated the anti-tumor efficacy and underlying mechanisms of Cela@Lip-IRH, focusing on mitochondrial function-dependent BBB restoration and the induction of tumor cell apoptosis. Collectively, this work provided novel therapeutic strategies and mechanistic insights for targeted GBM therapy, positioning Cela@Lip-IRH as a promising nanoplatform for modulating mitochondrial activity. Moreover, the combined strategy of BBB repair and chemotherapy may have broader implications for treating a range of neurological disorders.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Weihong</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Province Key Laboratory of Pharmacology of Traditional Chinese Medicine, School of Pharmacy, Gannan Medical University, University Park in Rongjiang New District, Ganzhou, 341000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Fengtian</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>First Affiliated Hospital &amp; Clinical Medical College, Gannan Medical University, Jinling East Avenue, Zhanggong District, Ganzhou, 341001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Kai</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Zhejiang University, 866 Yuhangtang Road, Hangzhou, 310058, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Jiabin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Province Key Laboratory of Pharmacology of Traditional Chinese Medicine, School of Pharmacy, Gannan Medical University, University Park in Rongjiang New District, Ganzhou, 341000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Weiliang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Province Key Laboratory of Pharmacology of Traditional Chinese Medicine, School of Pharmacy, Gannan Medical University, University Park in Rongjiang New District, Ganzhou, 341000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Min</LastName><ForeName>Zhongjie</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Province Key Laboratory of Pharmacology of Traditional Chinese Medicine, School of Pharmacy, Gannan Medical University, University Park in Rongjiang New District, Ganzhou, 341000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Province Key Laboratory of Pharmacology of Traditional Chinese Medicine, School of Pharmacy, Gannan Medical University, University Park in Rongjiang New District, Ganzhou, 341000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Tian</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Province Key Laboratory of Pharmacology of Traditional Chinese Medicine, School of Pharmacy, Gannan Medical University, University Park in Rongjiang New District, Ganzhou, 341000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Zhenzhe</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>First Affiliated Hospital &amp; Clinical Medical College, Gannan Medical University, Jinling East Avenue, Zhanggong District, Ganzhou, 341001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wen</LastName><ForeName>Lijuan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Province Key Laboratory of Pharmacology of Traditional Chinese Medicine, School of Pharmacy, Gannan Medical University, University Park in Rongjiang New District, Ganzhou, 341000, China. nklijuanwen@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>20242BAB20419</GrantID><Agency>Jiangxi Provincial Natural Science Foundation, China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>20232BAB206177</GrantID><Agency>Jiangxi Provincial Natural Science Foundation, China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>GZ2024YLJ127</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Plan Special Project of Ganzhou City</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>GJJ2401301</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Research Project of Jiangxi Provincial Department of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>QD202413</GrantID><Agency>Ph.D. Start-up Fund of First Affiliated Hospital &amp; Clinical Medical College of Gannan Medical University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82460613</GrantID><Agency>the National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2025XDCE0023</GrantID><Agency>Ganzhou City Science and Technology Plan Project on University-Government Cooperation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Nanobiotechnology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101152208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1477-3155</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cell apoptosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glioblastoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mitochondria-targeted</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pathological blood brain barrier</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Restoration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stimuli-responsive</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41723485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12951-026-04206-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12951-026-04206-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Berger TR, Wen PY, Lang-Orsini M, Chukwueke UV. World health organization 2021 classification of central nervous system tumors and implications for therapy for adult-type gliomas: a review. JAMA Oncol. 2022;8:1493&#x2013;501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan AC, Ashley DM, L&#xf3;pez GY, Malinzak M, Friedman HS, Khasraw M. Management of glioblastoma: state of the art and future directions. CA Cancer J Clin. 2020;70:299&#x2013;312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishna S, Choudhury A, Keough MB, Seo K, Ni L, Kakaizada S, et al. Glioblastoma remodelling of human neural circuits decreases survival. Nature. 2023;617:599&#x2013;607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horowitz MA, Ghadiyaram A, Mehkri Y, Chakravarti S, Liu J, Fox K, et al. Surgical resection of glioblastoma in the very elderly: an analysis of survival outcomes using the surveillance, epidemiology, and end results database. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2024;245:108469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minniti G, Niyazi M, Alongi F, Navarria P, Belka C. Current status and recent advances in reirradiation of glioblastoma. Radiat Oncol. 2021;16:36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Yang J, Jiang S, Tian Y, Zhang Y, Xu L, et al. Targeted reprogramming of tumor-associated macrophages for overcoming glioblastoma resistance to chemotherapy and immunotherapy. Biomaterials. 2024;311:122708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Pan J, Liu S, Zhang Y, Sha S, Guo H, et al. Fruit-derived extracellular-vesicle-engineered structural droplet drugs for enhanced glioblastoma chemotherapy. Adv Mater. 2023;35:e2304187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadry H, Noorani B, Cucullo L. A blood-brain barrier overview on structure, function, impairment, and biomarkers of integrity. Fluids Barriers CNS. 2020;17:69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacoste B, Prat A, Freitas-Andrade M, Gu C. The blood-brain barrier: composition, properties, and roles in brain health. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol. 2025;17:a041422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X, Hussain B, Chang J. Peripheral inflammation and blood-brain barrier disruption: effects and mechanisms. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2021;27:36&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu F, Nakamori M. Blood-brain barrier disruption in neuroimmunological disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25:10625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segura-Collar B, Mata-Mart&#xed;nez P, Hern&#xe1;ndez-La&#xed;n A, S&#xe1;nchez-G&#xf3;mez P, Gargini R. Blood-brain barrier disruption: a common driver of central nervous system diseases. Neuroscientist. 2022;28:222&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Jung UJ, Kim SR. The crucial role of the blood-brain barrier in neurodegenerative diseases: mechanisms of disruption and therapeutic implications. J Clin Med. 2025;14:386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K, Zhang FT, Wen CL, Huang ZH, Hu ZH, Zhang YW, et al. Regulation of pathological blood-brain barrier for intracranial enhanced drug delivery and anti-glioblastoma therapeutics. Oncol Res. 2021;29:351&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeney MD, Sagare AP, Zlokovic BV. Blood-brain barrier breakdown in Alzheimer disease and other neurodegenerative disorders. Nat Rev Neurol. 2018;14:133&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang FT, Wen LJ, Wang K, Huang ZH, Jin XY, Xiong RW, et al. Effect of axitinib regulating the pathological blood-brain barrier functional recovery for glioblastoma therapeutics. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2022;28:411&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langen UH, Ayloo S, Gu C. Development and cell biology of the blood-brain barrier. Annu Rev Cell Dev Biol. 2019;35:591&#x2013;613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haileselassie B, Joshi AU, Minhas PS, Mukherjee R, Andreasson KI, Mochly-Rosen D. Mitochondrial dysfunction mediated through dynamin-related protein 1 (Drp1) propagates impairment in blood brain barrier in septic encephalopathy. J Neuroinflammation. 2020;17:36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou W, Lv Y, Li L, Zhang S, Liang J, Wu C, et al. FOXQ1 regulates brain endothelial mitochondrial function by orchestrating calcium signaling and Cristae morphology. Adv Sci (Weinh). 2025;30:e03082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abate M, Festa A, Falco M, Lombardi A, Luce A, Grimaldi A, et al. Mitochondria as playmakers of apoptosis, autophagy and senescence. Semin Cell Dev Biol. 2020;98:139&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen TT, Wei S, Nguyen TH, Jo Y, Zhang Y, Park W, et al. Mitochondria-associated programmed cell death as a therapeutic target for age-related disease. Exp Mol Med. 2023;55:1595&#x2013;619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y, Ma J, Lu W. The significance of mitochondrial dysfunction in cancer. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:5598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J, He GN, Dai L. A comprehensive review on celastrol, triptolide and triptonide: insights on their pharmacological activity, toxicity, combination therapy, new dosage form and novel drug delivery routes. Biomed Pharmacother. 2023;162:114705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei H, Ruan Y, Ding R, Li H, Zhang X, Ji X, et al. The role of celastrol in inflammation and diseases. Inflamm Res. 2025;74:23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Li W, Liu XL, Liang J, Wang LY, Liu GX, et al. Celastrol as a neuroprotective drug: current status and challenges. Int Immunopharmacol. 2026;168:115846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Sr, Liu W, Jiang GN, Lian JR, Zhong Y, Zhou JL, et al. Celastrol ameliorates neuronal mitochondrial dysfunction induced by intracerebral hemorrhage via targeting cAMP-activated exchange protein-1. Adv Sci (Weinh). 2024;11:e2307556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin MW, Lin CC, Chen YH, Yang HB, Huang SY. Celastrol inhibits dopaminergic neuronal death of parkinson&#x2019;s disease through activating mitophagy. Antioxid (Basel). 2019;9:37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao FF, Zhang P, Zheng ZL, Wang P, Wang Y, Shi Q, et al. Celastrol treatment attenuates the inflammatory response in alzheimer&#x2019;s disease model mice. Neurol Res. 2025;5:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai WY, Wang XG, Teng HL, Li C, Wang B, Wang J. Celastrol inhibits microglial pyroptosis and attenuates inflammatory reaction in acute spinal cord injury rats. Int Immunopharmacol. 2019;66:215&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu HZ, Cai Y, Yu MY, Sun J, Cai J, Li JB, et al. Celastrol protects against early brain injury after subarachnoid hemorrhage in rats through alleviating blood-brain barrier disruption and blocking necroptosis. Aging (Albany NY). 2021;13:16816&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng XM, Gao J, Ding Y, Lu Y, Wei QC, Cui DZ, et al. Multi-functional liposome: a powerful theranostic nano-platform enhancing photodynamic therapy. Adv Sci. 2021;8:e2100876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He P, Sun J, Tan J, Shi YN, Zhang CJ, Zhu N, et al. From physicochemical constraints to clinical prospects of Celastrol: challenges and nano delivery strategies. Int J Nanomedicine. 2025;20:10907&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper E, Woolf Z, Swanson MEV, Correia J, Schweder P, Mee E, et al. Single-cell image analysis reveals over-expression of organic anion transporting polypeptides (OATPs) in human glioblastoma tissue. Neuro-Oncol Adv. 2022;4:vdac166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao B, Vavricka SR, Meier PJ, Stieger B. Differential cellular expression of organic anion transporting peptides OATP1A2 and OATP2B1 in the human retina and brain: implications for carrier-mediated transport of neuropeptides and neurosteriods in the CNS. Pflugers Arch. 2015;467:1481&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen LJ, Peng Y, Wang K, Huang ZH, He SY, Xiong RW, et al. Regulation of pathological BBB restoration via nanostructured ROS-responsive glycolipid-like copolymer entrapping SiVEGF for glioblastoma targeted therapeutics. Nano Res. 2022;15:1455&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen LJ, Wang K, Zhang FT, Tan YN, Shang XW, Zhu Y et al. AKT activation by SC79 to transiently re-open pathological blood brain barrier for improved functionalized nanoparticles therapy of glioblastoma. Biomaterials 2020:237:119793&#x2013;807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang FT, Wen CL, Peng Y, Hu ZH, Zheng SK, Chen WL, et al. Biomimetic lipid nanoparticles for homologous-targeting and enhanced photodynamic therapy against glioma. Eur J Pharm Sci. 2023;190:106574&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernardi P, Gerle C, Halestrap AP, Jonas EA, Karch J, Mnatsakanyan N, et al. Identity, structure, and function of the mitochondrial permeability transition pore: controversies, consensus, recent advances, and future directions. Cell Death Differ. 2023;30:1869&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchi S, Patergnani S, Missiroli S, Morciano G, Rimessi A, Wieckowski MR, et al. Mitochondrial and Endoplasmic reticulum calcium homeostasis and cell death. Cell Calcium. 2018;69:62&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah A, Dobrovolskaia MA. Detection of nanoparticle-mediated change in mitochondrial membrane potential in T cells using JC-1 dye. Methods Mol Biol. 2024;2789:153&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giusti I, Poppa G, D&#x2019;Ascenzo S, Esposito L, Vitale AR, Calvisi G, et al. Cancer three-dimensional spheroids mimic in vivo tumor features, displaying inner extracellular vesicles and vasculogenic mimicry. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:11782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Niu C. IR780-based nanomaterials for cancer imaging and therapy. J Mater Chem B. 2021;9:4079&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;squez X, S&#xe1;nchez-G&#xf3;mez P, Palma V. Netrin-1 in glioblastoma neovascularization: the new partner in crime? Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:8248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pscheid R, Drent E, Wienke J, Strijker JGM, Throsby M, Molenaar JJ. Three-dimensional modeling of solid tumors and their microenvironment to evaluate T cell therapy efficacy in vitro. J Immunol. 2023;211:229&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habanjar O, Diab-Assaf M, Caldefie-Chezet F, Delort L. 3D cell culture systems: tumor application, advantages, and disadvantages. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:12200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flores-Romero H, Dadsena S, Garc&#xed;a-S&#xe1;ez AJ. Mitochondrial pores at the crossroad between cell death and inflammatory signaling. Mol Cell. 2023;83:843&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonora M, Giorgi C, Pinton P. Molecular mechanisms and consequences of mitochondrial permeability transition. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2023;23:266&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lonobile C, Di Nubila A, Simone R, Hushi M, Barbieri SS. The mitochondrial permeability transition pore in platelets: mechanisms, physiological roles, and therapeutic perspectives. Antioxidants (Basel). 2025;14(8):923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrageta DF, Freire-Brito L, Oliveira PF, Alves MG. Evaluation of human spermatozoa mitochondrial membrane potential using the JC-1 dye. Curr Protoc. 2022;2:e531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivandzade F, Bhalerao A, Cucullo L. Analysis of the mitochondrial membrane potential using the cationic JC-1 dye as a sensitive fluorescent probe. Bio Protoc. 2019;9:e3128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia GC, Gupta K, Bartol TM, Sejnowski TJ, Rangamani P. Mitochondrial morphology governs ATP production rate. J Gen Physiol. 2023;155:e202213263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giulivi C, Kotz R. Earthing effects on mitochondrial function: ATP production and ROS generation. FEBS Open Bio. 2025;15:1459&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu YY, Zhao XR, Zhang N, Yang Y, Yi Y, Shao QH, et al. Mitochondrial dysfunction as a therapeutic strategy for neurodegenerative diseases: current insights and future directions. Ageing Res Rev. 2024;102:102577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dithmer S, Blasig IE, Fraser PA, Qin Z, Haseloff RF. The basic requirement of tight junction proteins in blood-brain barrier function and their role in pathologies. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25:5601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam MT. Oxidative stress and mitochondrial dysfunction-linked neurodegenerative disorders. Neurol Res. 2017;39:73&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begum HM, Shen K. Intracellular and microenvironmental regulation of mitochondrial membrane potential in cancer cells. WIREs Mechanisms of Disease. 2023;15:e1595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryu KW, Fung TS, Baker DC, Saoi M, Park J, Febres-Aldana CA, et al. Cellular ATP demand creates metabolically distinct subpopulations of mitochondria. Nature. 2024;635:746&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xe1;bara LC, Segawa M, Prudent J. Molecular mechanisms of mitochondrial dynamics. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2025;26:123&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yapa NMB, Lisnyak V, Reljic B, Ryan MT. Mitochondrial dynamics in health and disease. FEBS Lett. 2021;595:1184&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>