<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41731569</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1743-0003</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neuroengineering and rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neuroeng Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Guided corticomuscular neuroplasticity for restoration of wrist-hand function post-stroke.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">105</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12984-026-01915-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">After stroke, maladaptive neuroplasticity often presents as excessive recruitment of contralesional motor areas and the adoption of proximal compensatory movement patterns, both of which hinder the recovery of fine wrist&#x2013;hand control. To address these limitations, this study introduces a guided corticomuscular neuroplasticity training strategy aimed at selectively enhancing ipsilesional cortical control during targeted muscle activations, thereby facilitating precise wrist&#x2013;hand motor restoration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A corticomuscular coherence (CMC)- and electromyography (EMG)-driven control algorithm was embedded within a neuromuscular electrical stimulation (NMES)-robot system. This system provided task-specific assistance for wrist&#x2013;hand flexion and extension only when ipsilesional cortical dominance was detected. Twenty-six individuals with chronic stroke were randomly assigned to either a guided group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;13) or a control group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;13) and completed 20 sessions of NMES-robot&#x2013;assisted training. In the control group, assistance was delivered regardless of cortical dominance. Rehabilitation outcomes were assessed using standardized clinical scales and neurophysiological measures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Both groups demonstrated significant improvements in Fugl-Meyer Assessment and Action Research Arm Test scores (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), which were maintained at the three-month follow-up. The guided group exhibited a slower learning trajectory but showed a progressive ipsilesional shift in the laterality index during training (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) and in the 40% maximum voluntary contraction flexion task after training (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). In contrast, the control group displayed a faster initial learning pattern but no significant ipsilesional shift during or after training (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). Their CMC remained bilaterally distributed and spatially inconsistent, suggesting reinforcement of maladaptive contralesional recruitment, where task success depended on pre-existing compensatory pathways. Although the guided group required more time to achieve task proficiency, they developed targeted ipsilesional reorganization characterized by enhanced corticomuscular coupling and more efficient neuromuscular coordination indicative of genuine restoration of functional motor control.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The guided corticomuscular neuroplasticity strategy effectively promotes ipsilesional cortical reorganization and coordinated neuromuscular control, demonstrating its potential as a targeted rehabilitation approach for individuals with chronic stroke. Trial registration: Clinical Trials Registry Identifier: NCT02117089.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Fangning</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4391-1854</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Research Institute for Smart Aging (RISA), The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Hong Kong, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Qing</LastName><ForeName>Wanyi</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1497-4204</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Research Institute for Smart Aging (RISA), The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Hong Kong, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ip</LastName><ForeName>Wing-Chun</ForeName><Initials>WC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-1618-8007</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Research Institute for Smart Aging (RISA), The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Hong Kong, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Ziqi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8103-6501</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Research Institute for Smart Aging (RISA), The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Hong Kong, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zengyong</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Key Laboratory of Rehabilitation Technical Aids for Old-Age Disability, National Research Center for Rehabilitation Technical Aids, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Shaomin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Qiushi Academy for Advanced Studies, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoling</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3188-3005</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Research Institute for Smart Aging (RISA), The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Hong Kong, Hong Kong SAR, China. xiaoling.hu@polyu.edu.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Joint Research Centre for Biosensing and Precision Theranostics, Research Institute for Sports Science and Technology, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Hong Kong, Hong Kong SAR, China. xiaoling.hu@polyu.edu.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Research Facility in Behavioral and Systems Neuroscience (UBSN), The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Hong Kong, Hong Kong SAR, China. xiaoling.hu@polyu.edu.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>15218324</GrantID><Agency>University Grants Committee</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ITS/011/23 &amp; ITT/012/23GP</GrantID><Agency>Innovation and Technology Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Neuroeng Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101232233</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-0003</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain&#x2013;computer interface</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Corticomuscular coherence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ipsilesional reorganization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wrist&#x2013;hand extension/flexion rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This randomized controlled trial was approved by the Human Subjects Ethics Subcommittee of The Hong Kong Polytechnic University (HSEARS20170502002; HSEARS20190119001). The study was also registered at ClinicalTrials.gov (Identifier: NCT02117089). Written informed consent was obtained from all participants before enrollment. Consent for publication: Consent for publication was obtained from participants prior to enrollment in the study. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41731569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13036954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12984-026-01915-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12984-026-01915-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li L, Scott CA, Rothwell PM. Trends in stroke incidence in high-income countries in the 21st century. Stroke. 2020. 10.1161/strokeaha.119.028484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/strokeaha.119.028484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7185053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32208842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodd KC, Nair VA, Prabhakaran V. Role of the contralesional vs. ipsilesional hemisphere in stroke recovery. Front Hum Neurosci. 2017;11:469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2017.00469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5613154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28983244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stinear CM, Byblow WD. Predicting and accelerating motor recovery after stroke. Curr Opin Neurol. 2014;27:624&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25364953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossini P, Altamura C, Ferreri F, Melgari J, Tecchio F, Tombini M, et al. Neuroimaging experimental studies on brain plasticity in recovery from stroke. Eur Med Phys. 2007;43:241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17589415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okabe N, Himi N, Maruyama-Nakamura E, Hayashi N, Narita K, Miyamoto O. Rehabilitative skilled forelimb training enhances axonal remodeling in the corticospinal pathway but not the brainstem-spinal pathways after photothrombotic stroke in the primary motor cortex. PLoS One. 2017;12:e0187413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0187413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5667818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29095902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones TA. Motor compensation and its effects on neural reorganization after stroke. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2017;18:267&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrn.2017.26</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6289262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28331232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimm F, Walter A, Sp&#xfc;ler M, Naros G, Rosenstiel W, Gharabaghi A. Hybrid neuroprosthesis for the upper limb: combining brain-controlled neuromuscular stimulation with a multi-joint arm exoskeleton. Front Neurosci. 2016;10: 367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4977295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27555805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi K, Domen K, Sakamoto T, Toshima M, Otaka Y, Seto M, Irie K, Haga B, Takebayashi T, Hachisuka K. Efficacy of upper extremity robotic therapy in subacute poststroke hemiplegia: an exploratory randomized trial. Stroke. 2016;47:1385&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.115.012520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27006452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu XL, Tong RK, Ho NS, Xue JJ, Rong W, Li LS. Wrist rehabilitation assisted by an electromyography-driven neuromuscular electrical stimulation robot after stroke. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2015;29:767&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1545968314565510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25549656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chae J, Kilgore K, Triolo R, Yu D. Neuromuscular stimulation for motor neuroprosthesis in hemiplegia. Crit Rev Phys Rehabil Med. 2000. 10.1615/CritRevPhysRehabilMed.v12.i1.10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1615/CritRevPhysRehabilMed.v12.i1.10</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jovanovic LI, Kapadia N, Zivanovic V, Rademeyer HJ, Alavinia M, McGillivray C, et al. Brain&#x2013;computer interface-triggered functional electrical stimulation therapy for rehabilitation of reaching and grasping after spinal cord injury: a feasibility study. Spinal Cord Series and Cases. 2021;7:24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41394-020-00380-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7979732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33741900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soekadar SR, Birbaumer N, Slutzky MW, Cohen LG. Brain&#x2013;machine interfaces in neurorehabilitation of stroke. Neurobiol Dis. 2015;83:172&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nbd.2014.11.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25489973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansour S, Giles J, Ang KK, Nair KP, Phua KS, Arvaneh M. Exploring the ability of stroke survivors in using the contralesional hemisphere to control a brain&#x2013;computer interface. Sci Rep. 2022;12:16223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-20345-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9519575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36171400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krebs HI, Volpe BT. Robotics: a rehabilitation modality. Curr Phys Med Rehabil Rep. 2015;3:243&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40141-015-0101-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4778734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26955506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Li Y, Chen X, Li G, Rymer WZ, Zhou P. The effect of involuntary motor activity on myoelectric pattern recognition: a case study with chronic stroke patients. J Neural Eng. 2013;10:046015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1741-2560/10/4/046015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3810411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23860192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown P, Salenius S, Rothwell JC, Hari R. Cortical correlate of the Piper rhythm in humans. J Neurophysiol. 1998;80:2911&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jn.1998.80.6.2911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9862895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Z, Qian Q, Wong K, Zhu H, Huang Y, Hu X, et al. Altered corticomuscular coherence (CMCoh) pattern in the upper limb during finger movements after stroke. Front Neurol. 2020;11:410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2020.00410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7240065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32477257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Z, Zhou S, Ji K, Zhuang Y, Song J, Nam C, Hu X, Zheng Y. Corticomuscular integrated representation of voluntary motor effort in robotic control for wrist-hand rehabilitation after stroke. J Neural Eng. 2022;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35193124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouse AG, Williams JJ, Wheeler JJ, Moran DW. Cortical adaptation to a chronic micro-electrocorticographic brain computer interface. J Neurosci. 2013;33:1326&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0271-12.2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3711409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23345208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouse A, Williams J, Wheeler J, Moran D. Spatial co-adaptation of cortical control columns in a micro-ECoG brain&#x2013;computer interface. J Neural Eng. 2016;13:056018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1741-2560/13/5/056018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27651034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fodor MA, Cant&#xfc;rk A, Heisenberg G, Volosyak I. Streamlining cVEP paradigms: effects of a minimized electrode montage on brain&#x2013;computer interface performance. Brain Sci. 2025;15:549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci15060549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12190882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40563723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong K-H, Chua KS, Lee J. Recovery of upper limb dexterity in patients more than 1 year after stroke: frequency, clinical correlates and predictors. Neurorehabil. 2011;28:105&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/NRE-2011-0639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21447911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folstein MF, Folstein SE, McHugh PR. Mini-mental state: a practical method for grading the cognitive state of patients for the clinician. J Psychiatr Res. 1975;12:189&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-3956(75)90026-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1202204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fugl-Meyer AR, J&#xe4;&#xe4;sk&#xf6; L, Leyman I, Olsson S, Steglind S. A method for evaluation of physical performance. Scand J Rehabil Med. 1975;7:13&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/1650197771331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1135616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandyan AD, Johnson G, Price C, Curless R, Barnes M, Rodgers H. A review of the properties and limitations of the Ashworth and modified Ashworth scales as measures of spasticity. Clin Rehabil. 1999;13:373&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/026921599677595404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S, Guo Z, Wong K, Zhu H, Huang Y, Hu X, et al. Pathway-specific cortico-muscular coherence in proximal-to-distal compensation during fine motor control of finger extension after stroke. J Neural Eng. 2021;18:056034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1741-2552/ac20bc</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34428752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Z, Zhou S, Ji K, Zhuang Y, Song J, Nam C, et al. Corticomuscular integrated representation of voluntary motor effort in robotic control for wrist-hand rehabilitation after stroke. J Neural Eng. 2022;19:026004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1741-2552/ac5757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35193124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rong W, Li W, Pang M, Hu J, Wei X, Yang B, et al. A neuromuscular electrical stimulation (NMES) and robot hybrid system for multi-joint coordinated upper limb rehabilitation after stroke. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2017;14:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12984-017-0245-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5406922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28446181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yozbatiran N, Der-Yeghiaian L, Cramer SC. A standardized approach to performing the action research arm test. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2008;22:78&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1545968307305353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17704352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seghier ML. Laterality index in functional MRI: methodological issues. Magn Reson Imaging. 2008;26:594&#x2013;601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mri.2007.10.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2726301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18158224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guadagnoli MA, Lee TD. Challenge point: a framework for conceptualizing the effects of various practice conditions in motor learning. J Mot Behav. 2004;36:212&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3200/JMBR.36.2.212-224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15130871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee TD, Schmidt RA. Motor learning and performance: from principles to application. Human Kinetics; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith MA, Ghazizadeh A, Shadmehr R. Interacting adaptive processes with different timescales underlie short-term motor learning. PLoS Biol. 2006;4:e179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pbio.0040179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1463025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16700627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehme AK, Grefkes C. Cerebral network disorders after stroke: evidence from imaging-based connectivity analyses of active and resting brain states in humans. J Physiol. 2013;591:17&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2012.243469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3630767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23090951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward NS. Restoring brain function after stroke&#x2014;bridging the gap between animals and humans. Nat Rev Neurol. 2017;13:244&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrneurol.2017.34</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28303914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaechter JD. Motor rehabilitation and brain plasticity after hemiparetic stroke. Prog Neurobiol. 2004;73:61&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pneurobio.2004.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15193779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croft RJ, Barry RJ. Removal of ocular artifact from the EEG: a review. Neurophysiol Clin. 2000;30:5&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0987-7053(00)00055-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10740792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popp WL, Richner L, Lambercy O, Shirota C, Barry A, Gassert R, Kamper DG. Effects of wrist posture and stabilization on precision grip force production and muscle activation patterns. J Neurophysiol. 2023;130:596&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jn.00420.2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37529845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleim JA, Jones TA. Principles of experience-dependent neural plasticity: implications for rehabilitation after brain damage. 2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18230848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo C-L, Hu G-C. Post-stroke spasticity: a review of epidemiology, pathophysiology, and treatments. Int J Gerontol. 2018;12:280&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijge.2018.05.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez MA, Lundbye-Jensen J, Nielsen JB. Changes in corticospinal drive to spinal motoneurones following visuo&#x2010;motor skill learning in humans. J Physiol. 2006;573:843&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2006.105361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1779755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16581867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diedrichsen J, Kornysheva K. Motor skill learning between selection and execution. Trends Cogn Sci. 2015;19:227&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tics.2015.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5617110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25746123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao K, He C, Xiang W, Zhou Y, Zhang Z, Li J, et al. Evidence of synergy coordination patterns of upper-limb motor control in stroke patients with mild and moderate impairment. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1214995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2023.1214995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10518409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37753453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anwar G, Moustafa IM, Khowailed I, Raghunathan MRK, Al Abdi R, Harrison DE. Comparison of corticomuscular coherence under different balance paradigms in individuals with and without forward head posture. Sci Rep. 2025;15:22985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-06603-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12215537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40594912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>