<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41870105</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-9617</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>66</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International ophthalmology clinics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int Ophthalmol Clin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Updates in Amblyopia Treatment Outcomes Through the Lens of Health Disparities.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>165</StartPage><EndPage>170</EndPage><MedlinePgn>165-170</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/IIO.0000000000000606</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amblyopia, the leading cause of monocular vision impairment in children, is a treatable condition when identified early. Despite advancements in nonsurgical therapies-including patching, atropine penalization, and emerging digital tools-significant disparities persist in who receives timely diagnosis and effective treatment. This commentary explores the intersection of amblyopia treatment and health disparities, synthesizing current evidence on how race, socioeconomic status, insurance coverage, age of diagnosis, and geography influence diagnosis, treatment, and outcomes. A keyword-based search across PubMed and Embase revealed a stark underrepresentation of disparities-focused research within the broader amblyopia literature. While recent studies suggest growing awareness, disparities persist in early detection, access to specialists, and treatment efficacy-particularly among children with public insurance, racial and ethnic minorities, and those in underserved regions. This review highlights key themes: early diagnosis is a strong predictor of successful treatment, access to screening alone does not ensure equitable care, and equity must be central to research and innovation as the field embraces digital and adult-targeted therapies. To ensure emerging treatments benefit all patients, future research must prioritize representative populations and use frameworks rooted in health equity. Deliberate efforts to address systemic barriers are essential to achieving equitable amblyopia care across the lifespan.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Medina</LastName><ForeName>Candice</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Continuing Education, Harvard University, Cambridge, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oke</LastName><ForeName>Isdin</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Boston Children's Hospital, Boston, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gaier</LastName><ForeName>Eric D</ForeName><Initials>ED</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Boston Children's Hospital, Boston, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Picower Institute for Learning and Memory, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int Ophthalmol Clin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0374731</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0020-8167</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000550" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amblyopia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054625" MajorTopicYN="Y">Healthcare Disparities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006297" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Services Accessibility</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014792" MajorTopicYN="N">Visual Acuity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amblyopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health disparity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health insurance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">race</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">socioeconomic position</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic inequity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">visual recovery</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>E.D.G.: Luminopia Inc (advisor, equity, patent/royalties), Stoke Therapeutics Inc (consultant), Neurofieldz Inc (consultant). The remaining authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41870105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/IIO.0000000000000606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004397-202606620-00010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wallace DK, Repka MX, Lee KA, et al. Amblyopia preferred practice pattern&#xae;. Ophthalmology. 2018;125:P105&#x2013;P142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeSantis D. Amblyopia. Pediatr Clin North Am. 2014;61:505&#x2013;518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeritsyan A, Surve AV, Ayinde B, et al. Efficacy of amblyopia treatments in children up to seven years old: a systematic review. Cureus. 2024;16:e56705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen DML, Han S, Summers A, et al. Interventions for improving adherence to amblyopia treatments in children. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2025;2025:CD015820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsunaga K, Rajagopalan A, Nallasamy S, et al. Disparities in amblyopia treatment outcomes. Ophthalmology. 2025;132:335&#x2013;342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes JM, Levi DM. Treatment of amblyopia as a function of age. Vis Neurosci. 2018;35:E015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul ME, Frempong T. Treatment rate of strabismus and amblyopia is associated with the location of pediatric ophthalmologists in the United States. J AAPOS. 2024;28:103868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajesh AE, Davidson O, Lacy M, et al. Race, ethnicity, insurance, and population density associations with pediatric strabismus and strabismic amblyopia in the IRIS&#xae; Registry. Ophthalmology. 2023;130:1090&#x2013;1098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stults CD, Liang S-Y, Wilcox J, et al. Amblyopia care trends following widespread photoscreener adoption. JAMA Ophthalmol. 2024;142:188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinert MC. Photoscreeners for amblyopia&#x2014;access does not equate to equity. JAMA Ophthalmol. 2024;142:197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trinidad S, Kotagal M. Socioeconomic factors and pediatric injury. Curr Trauma Rep. 2023;9:47&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (US). 2023 National healthcare quality and disparities report. Rockville, MD: AHRQ; 2023. &#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Repka MX, Li C, Lum F. Multivariable analyses of amblyopia treatment outcomes from a clinical data registry. Ophthalmology. 2023;130:164&#x2013;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R, Jeon J, Ness S. Socioeconomic associations of amblyopia in the All of Us Research Program. J AAPOS. 2025;29:104160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaier ED, Hunter DG. Advances in Amblyopia Treatment: Paradigm Shifts and Future Directions. Int Ophthalmol Clin. 2017;57:117&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falcone MM, Hunter DG, Gaier ED. Emerging therapies for amblyopia. Semin Ophthalmol. 2021;36:282&#x2013;288. doi:10.1080/08820538.2021.1893765</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08820538.2021.1893765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Chen Y, Han X, et al. Comparative effectiveness of gamified binocular treatment versus conventional patching for amblyopia: a randomized clinical trial. Front Med. 2025;12:1560203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirota M, Okumura Y, Nagino K, et al. Safety evaluation in healthy adults of motion-based virtual reality dichoptic training for pediatric patients with amblyopia: prospective intervention study. JMIR Form Res. 2025;9:e69801&#x2013;e69801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Ross JS, Patel NA, et al. Studies of prescription digital therapeutics often lack rigor and inclusivity. Health Aff (Millwood). 2023;42:1559&#x2013;1567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oke I, Repka MX, Gaier ED. Digital therapeutic user behaviors associated with amblyopia recovery. Poster presented at: The 49th Annual Meeting of the American Association for Pediatric Ophthalmology and Strabismus, Austin, Texas, JAAPOS. 2024;28:103972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koc I, Bagheri S, Chau RK, et al. Cost-effectiveness analysis of digital therapeutics for amblyopia. Ophthalmology. 2025;132:654&#x2013;660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Echavarri-Leet MP, Resnick HH, Bowen DA, et al. Spontaneous recovery from amblyopia following fellow eye vision loss: a systematic review and narrative synthesis. J AAPOS. 2024;28:103971.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C, Gaier ED, Nihalani BR, et al. Durable recovery from amblyopia with donepezil. Sci Rep. 2023;13:10161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y, Cai K. Transcranial magnetic stimulation-based neuroplasticity in the treatment of amblyopia. J Neurosci Methods. 2025;419:110464.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>