<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41633064</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-1983</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>58</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical nutrition (Edinburgh, Scotland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A holistic perspective on malnutrition in older adults: Towards an integrated clinical nutrition research guiding framework.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>106583</StartPage><MedlinePgn>106583</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.clnu.2026.106583</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0261-5614(26)00010-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Malnutrition is a multifactorial and complex condition with significant consequences for recovery, functional outcomes, and healthcare systems. Research in malnutrition is often limited by single-component interventions, heterogeneous study designs, and variable outcome measures. This perspective paper introduces a practical guiding framework for clinical nutrition research, emphasizing interdisciplinary, multifactorial approaches, co-designed interventions, and pragmatic, adaptive study designs. Evidence from several trials demonstrates that individualized nutritional support delivered by multidisciplinary teams improves clinical outcomes, yet challenges remain in recruitment, adherence, and balancing intervention intensity with patient burden. The framework provides a structured approach to intervention development, outcome selection, and implementation, while remaining flexible to accommodate innovation, context-specific adaptation, and emerging outcome measures. By integrating lessons from prior trials, globally, and promoting systematic reporting and feasibility assessment, this framework aims to enhance the design, comparability, and translational impact of future research in clinical nutrition in older and other clinically vulnerable populations. Adoption of such a framework can guide research prioritization, optimize intervention delivery, and ultimately improve patient recovery and quality of life.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Dronkelaar</LastName><ForeName>Carliene</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Amsterdam UMC, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, 1081 HV Amsterdam, the Netherlands; Center of Expertise Urban Vitality, Faculty of Sports and Nutrition, Amsterdam University of Applied Sciences, 1067 SM Amsterdam, the Netherlands; Amsterdam Public Health, Aging &amp; Later Life, 1081 HV Amsterdam, the Netherlands; Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Amsterdam UMC, Universiteit van Amsterdam, 1105 AZ, Amsterdam, the Netherlands; Medical University Department, Division of General Internal Medicine, Kantonsspital Aarau, Aarau, Switzerland. Electronic address: d.c.vandronkelaar@amsterdamumc.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soeters</LastName><ForeName>Maarten R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolism, Amsterdam UMC, Universiteit van Amsterdam, 1105 AZ, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schuetz</LastName><ForeName>Philipp</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical University Department, Division of General Internal Medicine, Kantonsspital Aarau, Aarau, Switzerland; Medical Faculty, University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prado</LastName><ForeName>Carla M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agricultural, Food, and Nutritional Science, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiss</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition, School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Geelong, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tieland</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Expertise Urban Vitality, Faculty of Sports and Nutrition, Amsterdam University of Applied Sciences, 1067 SM Amsterdam, the Netherlands; Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition, School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Geelong, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kruizenga</LastName><ForeName>Hinke</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Amsterdam UMC, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, 1081 HV Amsterdam, the Netherlands; Amsterdam Public Health, Aging &amp; Later Life, 1081 HV Amsterdam, the Netherlands; Amsterdam Movement Sciences, Ageing &amp; Vitality, 1081 HZ Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8309603</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0261-5614</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044342" MajorTopicYN="Y">Malnutrition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012107" MajorTopicYN="N">Research Design</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006694" MajorTopicYN="Y">Holistic Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018529" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Support</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D035843" MajorTopicYN="Y">Biomedical Research</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009752" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Status</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Co-design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Core set outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Guiding framework</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Study design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Undernutrition</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interests We have the following interests to declare: The Institution of P. Schuetz has previously received unrestricted grant money unrelated to this project from Neste Health Science and Abbott Nutrition. C Prado has previously received honoraria and/or paid consultancy from Abbott Nutrition, Nutricia, Nestl&#xe9; Health Science, and Novo Nordisk. Dr. Prado serves as an Associate Editor for Clinical Nutrition. M. Tieland received honoraria from Fonterra and grant money from Hort Innovation unrelated to this project. N. Kiss has received honoraria and/or paid consultancy from Nutricia and Abbott Australia. All other authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41633064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2026.106583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0261-5614(26)00010-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>