<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41773115</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lumbar Stabilization and Gluteal Strengthening Exercises Versus Health Education for Chronic Low Back Pain: A Retrospective Observational Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e102555</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e102555</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e102555</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.102555</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background and aim Chronic low back pain represents a substantial global health burden with escalating prevalence rates and significant disability implications. Contemporary clinical practice guidelines emphasize exercise-based interventions as first-line conservative management strategies. However, optimal exercise prescription protocols remain under investigation. This study aimed to compare functional disability outcomes between patients receiving combined gluteus muscle strengthening with lumbar stabilization exercises versus those receiving spine-neutral health education alone for chronic low back pain management, utilizing the Oswestry Disability Index (ODI) as the primary outcome measure. Methodology This retrospective, observational, comparative study was conducted at a tertiary care teaching hospital, analyzing treatment outcomes in 50 participants aged 18-45 years with chronic low back pain and ODI scores of 5 or higher who received physiotherapy management between August 2023 and February 2024. Patients were stratified into group A (n = 25), who received spine-neutral health training, or group B (n = 25), who received combined gluteus muscle strengthening and lumbar stabilization exercises plus health education, based on initial clinical assessment and therapeutic protocol assignment during routine clinical practice. Treatment protocols were implemented over four weeks with alternate-day exercise sessions for group B participants. Baseline and post-intervention assessments included demographic characterization, occupational classification, educational attainment, and ODI scoring. Statistical analysis employed independent samples t-tests, paired-samples t-tests, and chi-square tests with significance established at an alpha level of 0.05. Results Baseline demographic characteristics demonstrated homogeneity between groups, with mean ages of 28.48 years in group A and 27.80 years in group B without statistically significant differences. Both intervention modalities achieved significant within-group ODI reductions, with group A demonstrating a mean decrease from 12.28 to 6.60, representing a reduction of 5.68 points, and group B showing a mean decrease from 13.68 to 4.76, representing a reduction of 8.92 points, both achieving statistical significance with probability values below 0.0001. Between-group comparison revealed statistically significant superiority of the combined exercise protocol, with post-intervention ODI scores of 6.60 in group A compared to 4.76 in group B, with a probability value of 0.0433. Clinical success rates, defined as 50% or greater disability reduction, were achieved by 12 participants (48.00%) in group A compared to 20 participants (80.00%) in group B, with statistical significance. Complete functional recovery was attained by seven participants (28.00%) in group A compared to 12 participants (48.00%) in group B. Severe disability classification was completely eliminated across both intervention groups. Conclusion Combined gluteus muscle strengthening and lumbar stabilization exercises demonstrated superior therapeutic efficacy compared to spine-neutral health education alone, achieving significantly greater functional disability reduction and clinical success rates. Both interventions produced clinically meaningful improvements, supporting conservative management approaches as first-line treatment strategies for chronic low back pain rehabilitation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Rekha et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rekha</LastName><ForeName>Akshyaa T</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Community Medicine, Dhanalakshmi Srinivasan Medical College and Hospital, Siruvachur, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kulothungan</LastName><ForeName>Karthikeyan</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Community Medicine, Dhanalakshmi Srinivasan Medical College and Hospital, Siruvachur, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kanagamuthu</LastName><ForeName>Rekha</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiology, Srinivasan Medical College and Hospital, Dhanalakshmi Srinivasan University, Samayapuram, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malaiyandi</LastName><ForeName>Praveen</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics, Srinivasan Medical College and Hospital, Dhanalakshmi Srinivasan University, Samayapuram, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muniyapillai</LastName><ForeName>Tamilarasan</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Community Medicine, Dhanalakshmi Srinivasan Medical College and Hospital, Siruvachur, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vaishnavi S</LastName><ForeName>Bala</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Community Medicine, Dhanalakshmi Srinivasan Medical College and Hospital, Siruvachur, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elango</LastName><ForeName>Akalya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Community Medicine, Dhanalakshmi Srinivasan Medical College and Hospital, Siruvachur, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disability evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low back pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strengthening</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical therapy modalities</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Institutional Ethics Committee of Dhanalakshmi Srinivasan Medical College and Hospital issued approval #IECHS/IRCHS.No.416. This study was conducted in compliance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki and the Good Clinical Practice guidelines. The ethical approval encompassed a comprehensive review of the retrospective study protocol, waiver of informed consent for retrospective data analysis, patient confidentiality protection measures, data anonymization procedures, and secure data storage protocols. All treatment protocols analyzed were part of routine clinical care, and patients provided standard clinical consent for treatment and for the anonymized use of data for quality improvement and research purposes at the time of initial clinical consultation, ensuring adherence to principles of patient autonomy and confidentiality throughout the retrospective data analysis process. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41773115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12949845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.102555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Global low back pain prevalence and years lived with disability from 1990 to 2017: estimates from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017. Wu A, March L, Zheng X, et al. Ann Transl Med. 2020;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7186678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32355743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global, regional, and national burden of low back pain, 1990-2020, its attributable risk factors, and projections to 2050: a systematic analysis of the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. Ferreira ML, de Luca K, Haile LM, et al. Lancet Rheumatol. 2023;5:316&#x2013;329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10234592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37273833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recent clinical practice guidelines for the management of low back pain: a global comparison. Zhou T, Salman D, McGregor AH. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2024;25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11061926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38693474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chronic low back pain: a narrative review of recent international guidelines for diagnosis and conservative treatment. Nicol V, Verdaguer C, Daste C, et al. J Clin Med. 2023;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9964474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36836220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of lumbar stabilization exercise on functional disability and lumbar lordosis angle in patients with chronic low back pain. Cho I, Jeon C, Lee S, Lee D, Hwangbo G. J Phys Ther Sci. 2015;27:1983&#x2013;1985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4500026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26180363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lumbar stabilization: a review of core concepts and current literature, part 2. Barr KP, Griggs M, Cadby T. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2007;86:72&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17304690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stabilization exercise compared to general exercises or manual therapy for the management of low back pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Gomes-Neto M, Lopes JM, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o CS, et al. Phys Ther Sport. 2017;23:136&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27707631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dose-response-relationship of stabilisation exercises in patients with chronic non-specific low back pain: a systematic review with meta-regression. Mueller J, Niederer D. Sci Rep. 2020;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7547082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33037280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effects of an 8-week stabilization exercise program on lumbar movement sense in patients with low back pain. Boucher JA, Preuss R, Henry SM, Dumas JP, Larivi&#xe8;re C. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2016;17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4712498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26762185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effects of gluteus muscle strengthening exercise and lumbar stabilization exercise on lumbar muscle strength and balance in chronic low back pain patients. Jeong UC, Sim JH, Kim CY, Hwang-Bo G, Nam CW. J Phys Ther Sci. 2015;27:3813&#x2013;3816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4713798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26834359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessing and treating gluteus maximus weakness - a clinical commentary. Buckthorpe M, Stride M, Villa FD. https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC6670060/pdf/ijspt-14-655.pdf. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2019;14:655&#x2013;669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6670060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31440415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of hip muscle strengthening exercises on pain and disability in patients with non-specific low back pain - a systematic review. Santamar&#xed;a G, Rodr&#xed;guez I, Rodr&#xed;guez-P&#xe9;rez V, Cobreros-Mielgo R, Lantar&#xf3;n-Caeiro E, Seco-Casares M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-L&#xe1;zaro D. Sports (Basel) 2023;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10536491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37755844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of gluteal muscle strengthening exercise-based core stabilization training on pain and quality of life in patients with chronic low back pain. Ahn SE, Lee MY, Lee BH. Medicina (Kaunas) 2024;60</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11205821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38929466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Does adding hip strengthening exercises to manual therapy and segmental stabilization improve outcomes in patients with nonspecific low back pain? A randomized controlled trial. Fukuda TY, Aquino LM, Pereira P, Ayres I, Feio AF, de Jesus FL, Neto MG. Braz J Phys Ther. 2021;25:900&#x2013;907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8721074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34824001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of core stabilization exercise and strengthening exercise on proprioception, balance, muscle thickness and pain related outcomes in patients with subacute nonspecific low back pain: a randomized controlled trial. Hlaing SS, Puntumetakul R, Khine EE, Boucaut R. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2021;22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8630919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34847915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oswestry Disability Index scoring made easy. Mehra A, Baker D, Disney S, Pynsent PB. Ann R Coll Surg Engl. 2008;90:497&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2647244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18598595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Oswestry low back pain disability questionnaire. Fairbank JC, Couper J, Davies JB, O'Brien JP. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6450426/ Physiotherapy. 1980;66:271&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6450426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparative effectiveness of lumbar stabilization, dynamic strengthening, and Pilates on chronic low back pain: randomized clinical trial. Bhadauria EA, Gurudut P. J Exerc Rehabil. 2017;13:477&#x2013;485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5667628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29114516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of lumbar stabilization and walking exercises on chronic low back pain: a randomized controlled trial. Suh JH, Kim H, Jung GP, Ko JY, Ryu JS. Medicine (Baltimore) 2019;98</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6616307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31261549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of lumbar stabilization and dynamic lumbar strengthening exercises in patients with chronic low back pain. Moon HJ, Choi KH, Kim DH, et al. Ann Rehabil Med. 2013;37:110&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3604220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23525973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patient experiences of self-management for chronic low back pain: a qualitative study. Bourke MJ, Ferguson D, Cooke M. Phys Ther. 2022;102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35358311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>What do we mean by 'self-management' for chronic low back pain? A narrative review. Zhou T, Salman D, McGregor AH. Eur Spine J. 2023;32:4377&#x2013;4389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37640886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of lumbar stabilization exercises and thoracic mobilization and exercises on chronic low back pain patients. Heo MY, Kim K, Hur BY, Nam CW. J Phys Ther Sci. 2015;27:3843&#x2013;3846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4713804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26834365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of 6-week lumbar stabilization exercise performed on stable versus unstable surfaces in automobile assembly workers with mechanical chronic low back pain. Kang TW, Lee JH, Park DH, Cynn HS. Work. 2018;60:445&#x2013;454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30040774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Disability reduction following a lumbar stabilization exercise program for low back pain: large vs. small improvement subgroup analyses of physical and psychological variables. Larivi&#xe8;re C, Preuss R, Coutu MF, Sullivan MJ, Roy N, Henry SM. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2024;25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11069239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38704535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise as a treatment for chronic low back pain. Rainville J, Hartigan C, Martinez E, Limke J, Jouve C, Finno M. Spine J. 2004;4:106&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14749199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>