<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41725083</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3724</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical journal of sport medicine : official journal of the Canadian Academy of Sport Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin J Sport Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Licorice Toxicity in an Ultramarathon Trail Runner.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001430</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>For centuries, licorice has been used for its medicinal and sweetening properties. Today, it is widely used globally in the herbal medicine, food, tobacco, and cosmetic industries. However, excessive consumption of licorice's bioactive metabolite, glycyrrhizic acid, has led to numerous reports of life-threatening complications. We present the case of a 51-year-old ultramarathon trail runner who initially experienced menopausal symptoms, and then extreme fatigue, edema, weight gain, paresis, systolic hypertension, and lose stool from chronic consumption of herbal teas and a supplement containing licorice. After 10 months, she was diagnosed with licorice-induced pseudohyperaldosteronism, a condition that suppresses the renin-angiotensin system. Approximately 2 months after cessation of all licorice products, she made a full recovery. This case highlights the importance of taking a thorough patient history, including knowledge of foods, fluids, supplements, herbal remedies, and cosmetics used. Increased public awareness of the potentially life-threatening hazards of licorice consumption is necessary.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goodman</LastName><ForeName>Ashley</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Athletic Training Program, Gross Human Anatomy Laboratory, Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, Appalachian State University, Boone, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Howard</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Athletic Training Program, Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, Appalachian State University, Boone, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin J Sport Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9103300</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1050-642X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athlete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">herbal remedies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">menopause</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pseudohyperaldosteronism</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41725083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00042752-990000000-00384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Car&#xe9; W, Grenet G, Schmitt C, et al. Adverse effects of licorice consumed as food: an update. Article in French. Rev Med Interne. 2023;44:487&#x2013;494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabbadin C, Graziani A, Bavaresco A, et al. Pseudohyperaldosteronism due to licorice: a practice-based learning from a case series. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25:7454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omar HR, Komarova I, El-Ghonemi M, et al. Licorice abuse: time to send a warning message. Ther Adv Endocrinol Metab. 2012;3:125&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deutch MR, Grimm D, Wehland M, et al. Bioactive candy: effects of licorice on the cardiovascular system. Foods. 2019;8:495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merschel M. Black licorice is a candy that should inspire caution. Am Heart Assoc. 2022. Available at: https://www.heart.org/en/news/2022/10/28/black-licorice-is-a-candy-that-should-inspire-caution. Accessed November 14, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceccuzzi G, Rapino A, Perna B, et al. Liquorice toxicity: a comprehensive narrative review. Nutrients. 2023;15:3866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshino T, Shimada S, Homma M, et al. Clinical risk factors of licorice-induced pseudoaldosteronism based on glycyrrhizin-metabolite concentrations: a narrative review. Front Nutr. 2021;8:719197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conn JW, Rovner DR, Cohen EL. Licorice induced pseudoaldosteronism. JAMA. 1968;205:492&#x2013;496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penninkilampi R, Eslick EM. The association between consistent licorice ingestion, hypertension and hypokalemia: a systematic review. J Hum Hypertens. 2017;3:699&#x2013;707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallon KE, Lovell G. Pseudohyperaldosteronism in an elite triathlete. Clin J Sport Med. 2007;17:328&#x2013;329.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>