<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41764874</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-491X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>178</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of nursing studies</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Nurs Stud</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reimagining intensive care unit recovery: The Critical Illness Survivorship Programme for humanising post-intensive care unit care - A discussion paper.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>105386</StartPage><MedlinePgn>105386</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2026.105386</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0020-7489(26)00058-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Survivorship after critical illness is often characterised by fragmented recovery and lingering cognitive, psychological, and physical impairments collectively described as post-intensive care syndrome. Current recovery frameworks and follow-up models remain inconsistently delivered, poorly standardised, and rarely address survivors' and families' need to make sense of the intensive care unit (ICU) experience in a transparent, inclusive, and sensitive way. The Critical Illness Survivorship Programme is proposed to humanise post-intensive care by integrating generative artificial intelligence technologies with co-designed, person-centred recovery strategies. This discussion paper provides the theoretical foundation for the proposed Critical Illness Survivorship Programme, which intends to humanise post-intensive care recovery through ethically governed, artificial intelligence-enabled narrative approaches.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The Critical Illness Survivorship Programme redefines recovery as both a biological and narrative process. Drawing from interpretive nursing inquiry, narrative medicine, cognitive rehabilitation, and responsible artificial intelligence design, the Critical Illness Survivorship Programme is designed to generate personalised intensive care unit journey summaries that translate complex health-record data into accessible, emotionally attuned stories, visualisations, and audio outputs. These narratives aim to support sense-making, memory integration, and emotional recovery while promoting transparency, inclusivity, and cultural sensitivity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The proposed Critical Illness Survivorship Programme will offer a conceptual pathway for developing ethically governed, artificial intelligence-enabled tools that bridge digital innovation and human connection in survivorship care. It emphasises interdisciplinary collaboration, trauma-informed communication, and co-design as essential safeguards for compassionate technology integration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="IMPLICATIONS FOR PRACTICE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Future research should examine the feasibility, ethical oversight, and educational implications of the Critical Illness Survivorship Programme within clinical pathways. By reframing technology as a partner in empathy and understanding, the Critical Illness Survivorship Programme proposes a potential model of recovery - one that restores coherence, dignity, and meaning in life after critical illness.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Gideon U</ForeName><Initials>GU</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Florence Nightingale Faculty of Nursing, Midwifery &amp; Palliative Care, King's College London, London, United Kingdom. Electronic address: gideon.johnson@nhs.net.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robert</LastName><ForeName>Glenn</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Florence Nightingale Faculty of Nursing, Midwifery &amp; Palliative Care, King's College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Christopher S</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Connell School of Nursing, Boston College, Chestnut Hill, MA, United States; Department of Emergency Medical Service, Faculty of Nursing and Midwifery, Wroclaw Medical University, Wroclaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boehm</LastName><ForeName>Leanne</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vanderbilt University School of Nursing, Nashville, TN, United States; Critical Illness, Brain Dysfunction, and Survivorship (CIBS) Center, Nashville, TN, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pandharipande</LastName><ForeName>Pratik P</ForeName><Initials>PP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Critical Illness, Brain Dysfunction, and Survivorship (CIBS) Center, Nashville, TN, United States; Division of Anesthesiology and Critical Care Medicine, Nashville, TN, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ely</LastName><ForeName>E Wesley</ForeName><Initials>EW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Allergy, Pulmonary, and Critical Care Medicine, Nashville, TN, United States; Critical Illness, Brain Dysfunction, and Survivorship (CIBS) Center, Nashville, TN, United States; Veteran's Affairs Geriatric Research Education Clinical Center (GRECC), Nashville, TN, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Nurs Stud</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0400675</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0020-7489</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Critical care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Human-centred design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Narrative medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-intensive care syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Survivorship</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Given their role as associate editor, Professor Christopher S. Lee had no involvement in the peer-review of this article and has no access to information regarding its peer-review. Full responsibility for the editorial process for this article was delegated to another journal editor. If there are other authors, they declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41764874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2026.105386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0020-7489(26)00058-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>