<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41816699</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1520-6149</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2025</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Proceedings of the ... IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing. ICASSP (Conference)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Proc IEEE Int Conf Acoust Speech Signal Process</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>MAP Image Recovery with Guarantees using Locally Convex Multi-Scale Energy (LC-MUSE) Model.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1109/ICASSP49660.2025.10889960</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We propose a multi-scale deep energy model that is strongly convex in the local neighbourhood around the data manifold to represent its probability density, with application in inverse problems. In particular, we represent the negative log-prior as a multi-scale energy model parameterized by a Convolutional Neural Network (CNN). We restrict the gradient of the CNN to be locally monotone, which constrains the model as a Locally Convex Multi-Scale Energy (LC-MuSE). We use the learned energy model in image-based inverse problems, where the formulation offers several desirable properties: i) uniqueness of the solution, ii) convergence guarantees to a minimum of the inverse problem, and iii) robustness to input perturbations. In the context of parallel Magnetic Resonance (MR) image reconstruction, we show that the proposed method performs better than the state-of-the-art convex regularizers, while the performance is comparable to plug-and-play regularizers and end-to-end trained methods.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chand</LastName><ForeName>Jyothi Rikhab</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Iowa, IA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Virginia, VA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jacob</LastName><ForeName>Mathews</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Virginia, VA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG067078</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG087159</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 EB019961</GrantID><Acronym>EB</Acronym><Agency>NIBIB NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Proc IEEE Int Conf Acoust Speech Signal Process</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101182171</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1520-6149</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Locally convex regularizer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parallel MR image reconstruction</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41816699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2087655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12974777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ICASSP49660.2025.10889960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tikhonov AN and Arsenin VI, Solutions of Ill-posed Problems: Tikhonov Andrey N. and Arsenin Vasiliy Y.. Translation Editor Fritz John. Wiley, 1977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatakrishnan SV, Bouman CA, and Wohlberg B, &#x201c;Plug-and-play priors for model based reconstruction,&#x201d; in 2013 IEEE Global Conference on Signal and Information Processing, 2013, pp. 945&#x2013;948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buzzard GT, Chan SH, Sreehari S, and Bouman CA, &#x201c;Plug- and-play unplugged: Optimization-free reconstruction using consensus equilibrium,&#x201d; SIAM Journal on Imaging Sciences, vol. 11, no. 3, pp. 2001&#x2013;2020, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad R, Bouman CA, Buzzard GT, Chan S, Liu S, Reehorst ET, and Schniter P, &#x201c;Plug-and-play methods for magnetic resonance imaging: Using denoisers for image recovery,&#x201d; IEEE signal processing magazine, vol. 37, no. 1, pp. 105&#x2013;116, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8096200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33953526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pramanik A, Zimmerman MB, and Jacob M, &#x201c;Memory-efficient model-based deep learning with convergence and robustness guarantees,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Computational Imaging, vol. 9, pp. 260&#x2013;275, 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10121192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37090026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryu E, Liu J, Wang S, Chen X, Wang Z, and Yin W, &#x201c;Plug-and-play methods provably converge with properly trained denoisers,&#x201d; in International Conference on Machine Learning. PMLR, 2019, pp. 5546&#x2013;5557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chand JR and Jacob M, &#x201c;Multi-scale energy (muse) framework for inverse problems in imaging,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Computational Imaging, pp. 1&#x2013;16, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J, Li H, Xu Z et al. , &#x201c;Deep admm-net for compressive sensing mri,&#x201d; Advances in neural information processing systems, vol. 29, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammernik K, Klatzer T, Kobler E, Recht MP, Sodickson DK, Pock T, and Knoll F, &#x201c;Learning a variational network for reconstruction of accelerated mri data,&#x201d; Magnetic resonance in medicine, vol. 79, no. 6, pp. 3055&#x2013;3071, 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5902683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29115689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal HK, Mani MP, and Jacob M, &#x201c;Modl: Model-based deep learning architecture for inverse problems,&#x201d; IEEE transactions on medical imaging, vol. 38, no. 2, pp. 394&#x2013;405, 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6760673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30106719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;stner T, Fuin N, Hammernik K, Bustin A, Qi H, Hajhosseiny R, Masci PG, Neji R, Rueckert D, Botnar RM et al. , &#x201c;Cinenet: deep learning-based 3d cardiac cine mri reconstruction with multi-coil complex-valued 4d spatio-temporal convolutions,&#x201d; Scientific reports, vol. 10, no. 1, p. 13710, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7426830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32792507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen R, Blau Y, Freedman D, and Rivlin E, &#x201c;It has potential: Gradient-driven denoisers for convergent solutions to inverse problems,&#x201d; Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, vol. 34, pp. 18152&#x2013;18 164, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurault S, Leclaire A, and Papadakis N, &#x201c;Gradient step denoiser for convergent plug-and-play,&#x201d; arXiv preprint arXiv:2110.03220, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee S, Dittmer S, Shumaylov Z, Lunz S, &#xd6;ktem O, and Sch&#xf6;nlieb C-B, &#x201c;Learned convex regularizers for inverse problems,&#x201d; arXiv preprint arXiv:2008.02839, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goujon A, Neumayer S, Bohra P, Ducotterd S, and Unser M, &#x201c;A neural-network-based convex regularizer for inverse problems,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Computational Imaging, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goujon A, Neumayer S, and Unser M, &#x201c;Learning weakly convex regularizers for convergent image-reconstruction algorithms,&#x201d; SIAM Journal on Imaging Sciences, vol. 17, no. 1, pp. 91&#x2013;115, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shumaylov Z, Budd J, Mukherjee S, and Sch&#xf6;nlieb C-B, &#x201c;Weakly convex regularisers for inverse problems: Convergence of critical points and primal-dual optimisation,&#x201d; arXiv preprint arXiv:2402.01052, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent P, &#x201c;A connection between score matching and denoising autoencoders,&#x201d; Neural computation, vol. 23, no. 7, pp. 1661&#x2013;1674, 2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21492012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryu EK and Yin W, Large-scale convex optimization: algorithms &amp; analyses via monotone operators. Cambridge University Press, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyato T, Kataoka T, Koyama M, and Yoshida Y, &#x201c;Spectral normalization for generative adversarial networks,&#x201d; arXiv preprint arXiv:1802.05957, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bungert L, Raab R, Roith T, Schwinn L, and Tenbrinck D, &#x201c;Clip: Cheap lipschitz training of neural networks,&#x201d; in International Conference on Scale Space and Variational Methods in Computer Vision. Springer, 2021, pp. 307&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uecker M, Lai P, Murphy MJ, Virtue P, Elad M, Pauly JM, Vasanawala SS, and Lustig M, &#x201c;Espirit&#x2014;an eigenvalue approach to autocalibrating parallel mri: where sense meets grappa,&#x201d; Magnetic resonance in medicine, vol. 71, no. 3, pp. 990&#x2013;1001, 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4142121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23649942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zbontar J, Knoll F, Sriram A, Murrell T, Huang Z, Muckley MJ, Defazio A, Stern R, Johnson P, Bruno M et al. , &#x201c;fastmri: An open dataset and benchmarks for accelerated mri,&#x201d; arXiv preprint arXiv:1811.08839, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pruessmann KP, Weiger M, Scheidegger MB, and Boesiger P, &#x201c;Sense: sensitivity encoding for fast mri,&#x201d; Magnetic Resonance in Medicine: An Official Journal of the International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine, vol. 42, no. 5, pp. 952&#x2013;962, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai S, Kolter JZ, and Koltun V, &#x201c;Deep equilibrium models,&#x201d; Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, vol. 32, 2019.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>