<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41742095</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2393</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC pregnancy and childbirth</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute fatty liver of pregnancy in the context of normal-dose acetaminophen exposure: a case report.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">365</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12884-026-08844-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Acute fatty liver of pregnancy (AFLP) is a rare but serious complication in the third trimester, characterized by microvesicular hepatic steatosis and risk of rapid progression to liver failure and multi-organ dysfunction. Despite improved care, maternal and perinatal mortality remain significant. Acetaminophen is commonly used during pregnancy with a good safety profile, but hepatotoxicity can occur. This report highlights the successful treatment of AFLP during therapeutic acetaminophen use, emphasizing the need for timely, multidisciplinary management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE PRESENTATION">We report the case of a 37-year-old primigravida at 36&#x2009;+&#x2009;3 weeks&#x2019; gestation who presented with nausea, vomiting, abdominal pain, jaundice, and clinical signs of fetal growth restriction. Notably, she had been intermittently taking therapeutic doses of acetaminophen specifically for dental pain. Laboratory investigations revealed marked hepatic dysfunction, coagulopathy, and acute kidney injury. As her clinical condition deteriorated rapidly, an emergency cesarean section was performed, resulting in the birth of a healthy female neonate at 36 weeks of gestation, weighing 2220&#xa0;g, corresponding to the 7.6th percentile for gestational age according to locally derived reference standards. Postoperatively, her liver failure worsened, requiring plasma exchange, artificial liver support, and intensive care. Multidisciplinary management led to her full recovery, and she was discharged in stable condition. Both the mother and the infant remained in good health during the one&#x2011;year follow&#x2011;up period.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">AFLP is a rare but potentially life threatening complication of late gestation that can rapidly progress to acute hepatic dysfunction with coagulopathy and multiorgan involvement. This case highlights the diagnostic complexity of AFLP in late gestation, particularly when recent therapeutic acetaminophen use may confound clinical assessment despite the absence of overdose. In pregnant patients with acetaminophen exposure, careful differentiation between AFLP and drug induced liver injury is critical. Further studies are warranted to clarify whether therapeutic dose acetaminophen use contributes to AFLP risk in metabolically susceptible patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12884-026-08844-5.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Xing</LastName><ForeName>Aoshuang</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, West China Second University Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, Sichuan, 610041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Obstetric &amp; Gynecologic and Pediatric Diseases and Birth Defects of Ministry of Education, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Qu</LastName><ForeName>Zhen</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, West China Second University Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, Sichuan, 610041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Obstetric &amp; Gynecologic and Pediatric Diseases and Birth Defects of Ministry of Education, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, West China Second University Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, Sichuan, 610041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Obstetric &amp; Gynecologic and Pediatric Diseases and Birth Defects of Ministry of Education, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jia</LastName><ForeName>Jin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, West China Second University Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, Sichuan, 610041, China. jiajin@scu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Obstetric &amp; Gynecologic and Pediatric Diseases and Birth Defects of Ministry of Education, Chengdu, China. jiajin@scu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967799</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2393</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AFLP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acetaminophen</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drug-induced liver injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hepatic dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multidisciplinary management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Therapeutic dose</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Approval was waived, and written consent was obtained. Consent for publication: Written informed consent was obtained from our participant for the publication of their personal and clinical details, as well as any identifying images included in this manuscript. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41742095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13041479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-026-08844-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12884-026-08844-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ma K, Berger D, Reau N. Liver diseases during pregnancy. Clin Liver Dis. 2019;23(2):345&#x2013;61. 10.1016/j.cld.2018.12.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30947881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman TM, Wendon J. Severe hepatic dysfunction in pregnancy. QJM. 2002;95(6):343&#x2013;57. 10.1093/qjmed/95.6.343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12037242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knox TA, Olans LB. Liver disease in pregnancy. N Engl J Med. 1996;335(8):569&#x2013;76. 10.1056/NEJM199608223350807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8678935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang HY, Jiang Q, Shi H. Effect of caesarean section on maternal and foetal outcomes in acute fatty liver of pregnancy: a systematic review and meta-analysis[J]. Sci Rep. 2016,6:28826. 10.1038/srep28826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4937371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27387594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight M, Nelson-Piercy C, Kurinczuk JJ, Spark P, Brocklehurst P, UK Obstetric Surveillance System. A prospective national study of acute fatty liver of pregnancy in the UK. Gut. 2008;57(7):951&#x2013;6. 10.1136/gut.2008.148676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18332072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellouli MM, Amara FB, Maghrebi H, Bouchnack M, Khaled N, Reziga H. Acute fatty liver of pregnancy over a 10-year period at a Tunisian tertiary care center. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2012;117(1):88&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.ijgo.2011.11.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22257770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau HH, Chen YY, Huang JP, Chen CY, Su TH, Chen CP. Acute fatty liver of pregnancy in a Taiwanese tertiary care center: a retrospective review. Taiwan J Obstet Gynecol. 2010;;49(2):156&#x2013;9. 10.1016/S1028-4559(10)60033-2. :.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20708520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werler MM, Mitchell AA, Hernandez-Diaz S, Honein MA. Use of over-the-counter medications during pregnancy. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2005;193(3 Pt 1):771&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.ajog.2005.02.100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16150273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClure CK, Katz KD, Patrick TE, Kelsey SF, Weiss HB. The epidemiology of acute poisonings in women of reproductive age and during pregnancy, California, 2000&#x2013;2004. Matern Child Health J. 2011;15(7):964&#x2013;73. 10.1007/s10995-010-0571-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20169404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James LP, Mayeux PR, Hinson JA. Acetaminophen-induced hepatotoxicity. Drug Metab Dispos. 2003;31(12):1499&#x2013;506. 10.1124/dmd.31.12.1499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14625346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Association for the Study of the Liver. EASL Clinical Practice Guidelines on the management of liver diseases in pregnancy. J Hepatol. 2023;79(3):768&#x2013;828. 10.1016/j.jhep.2023.03.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37394016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey M, Reema K. Acute fatty liver of pregnancy[J]. N Am J Med Sci. 2012;4(11):611&#x2013;2. 10.4103/1947-2714.103339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3503387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23181240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramanathan R, Ibdah JA. Mitochondrial Dysfunction and Acute Fatty Liver of Pregnancy. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(7):3595. 10.3390/ijms23073595. Published 2022 Mar 25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8999031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35408956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Ghaziani TT, Wolf JL. Acute fatty liver disease of pregnancy: updates in pathogenesis, diagnosis, and management[J]. Am J Gastroenterol. 2017;112(6):838&#x2013;46. 10.1038/ajg.2017.54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28291236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joueidi Y, Peoc&#x2019;h K. Maternal and neonatal outcomes and prognostic factors in acute fatty liver of pregnancy. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2020;252:198&#x2013;205. 10.1016/j.ejogrb.2020.06.052. :LeLousM.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32622104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigil-de Gracia P, Montufar-Rueda C. Acute fatty liver of pregnancy: diagnosis, treatment, and outcome based on 35 consecutive cases. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med. 2011;24(9):1143&#x2013;6. 10.3109/14767058.2010.531325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21668324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moldenhauer JS, O&#x2019;brien JM, Barton JR, Sibai B. Acute fatty liver of pregnancy associated with pancreatitis: a life-threatening complication. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2004;190(2):502&#x2013;5. 10.1016/j.ajog.2003.09.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14981397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel A, Ramakrishna B, Zachariah U. How accurate are the Swansea criteria to diagnose acute fatty liver of pregnancy in predicting hepatic microvesicular steatosis? Gut. 2011;60(1):138&#x2013;40. 10.1136/gut.2009.198465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20938054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minakami H, Morikawa M, Yamada T, Yamada T, Akaishi R, Nishida R. Differentiation of acute fatty liver of pregnancy from syndrome of hemolysis, elevated liver enzymes and low platelet counts. J Obstet Gynaecol Res. 2014;40(3):641&#x2013;9. 10.1111/jog.12282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24428400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan J, Hou F, Xiong H, Pu L, Xiang P, Li C. Swansea criteria score in acute fatty liver of pregnancy. Chin Med J (Engl). 2022;135(7):860&#x2013;2. 10.1097/CM9.0000000000001821. Published 2022 Apr 5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9276417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35671185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton A, Laurie J. Physiological changes of pregnancy and the Swansea criteria in diagnosing acute fatty liver of pregnancy. Obstet Med. 2018;11(3):126&#x2013;31. 10.1177/1753495X18759353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6134352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30214478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson DB, Byrne JJ, Cunningham FG. Acute Fatty Liver of Pregnancy. Obstet Gynecol. 2021;137(3):535&#x2013;46. 10.1097/AOG.0000000000004289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33543900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siwatch S, De A, Kaur B., et al. Safety and efficacy of plasmapheresis in treatment of acute fatty liver of pregnancy-a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Med (Lausanne). 2024;11:1433324. Published 2024 Oct 18. doi:10.3389/fmed.2024.1433324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11527697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39493711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z, Huang P, Gong Y, Wan J, Zou W. Treating acute fatty liver of pregnancy with artificial liver support therapy: Systematic review. Med (Baltimore). 2018;97(38):e12473. 10.1097/MD.0000000000012473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6160087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30235743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liver Failure and Artificial Liver Group, Chinese Society of Infectious Diseases, Chinese Medical Association; Severe Liver Disease and Artificial Liver Group,. Chinese Society of Hepatology, Chinese Medical Association. Zhonghua Gan Zang Bing Za Zhi. 2025;33(1):18&#x2013;33. 10.3760/cma.j.cn501113-20241206-00614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glavind J, Boie S, Glavind E, Fuglsang J. Risk of recurrent acute fatty liver of pregnancy: survey from a social media group. Am J Obstet Gynecol MFM. 2020;2(2):100085. 10.1016/j.ajogmf.2020.100085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33345956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton A, Phillips L, Nisbet J, He JW. The risk of recurrence of acute fatty liver of pregnancy - a review of the current literature. Obstet Med Published online Febr. 2025; 2. 18(4):210-213. 10.1177/1753495X251317259</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11789041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39906898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira SP, O&#x2019;Donohue J, Wendon J, Williams R. Maternal and perinatal outcome in severe pregnancy-related liver disease. Hepatology. 1997;26(5):1258&#x2013;62. 10.1002/hep.510260525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9362370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne JJ, Seasely A, Nelson DB, Mcintire DD, Cunningham FG. Comparing acute fatty liver of pregnancy from hemolysis, elevated liver enzymes, and low platelets syndrome. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med. 2022;35(7):1352&#x2013;62. 10.1080/14767058.2020.1754790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32308076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zafeiri A, Mitchell RT, Hay DC, Fowler PA. Over-the-counter analgesics during pregnancy: a comprehensive review of global prevalence and offspring safety. Hum Reprod Update. 2021;27(1):67&#x2013;95. 10.1093/humupd/dmaa042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33118024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandoli G, Palmsten K, Chambers C. Acetaminophen use in pregnancy: Examining prevalence, timing, and indication of use in a prospective birth cohort. Paediatr Perinat Epidemiol. 2020;34(3):237&#x2013;46. 10.1111/ppe.12595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7192766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31696962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killion JA, Chambers C, Smith CJF, Bandoli G. Prenatal acetaminophen use in women with autoimmune disorders and adverse pregnancy and birth outcomes. Rheumatol (Oxford). 2022;;61(4):1630&#x2013;8. 10.1093/rheumatology/keab623. :.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8996782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34343244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro CT, Gama RS, Pereira M. Effect of Acetaminophen use during pregnancy on adverse pregnancy outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Expert Opin Drug Saf. 2022;21(2):241&#x2013;51. 10.1080/14740338.2022.2020246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34964403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smarr MM, Bible J, Gerlanc N, Buck Louis GM, Bever A, Grantz KL. Comparison of fetal growth by maternal prenatal acetaminophen use. Pediatr Res. 2019;86(2):261&#x2013;8. 10.1038/s41390-019-0379-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6658344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30911064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chidiac AS, Buckley NA, Noghrehchi F, Cairns R. Paracetamol (acetaminophen) overdose and hepatotoxicity: mechanism, treatment, prevention measures, and estimates of burden of disease. Expert Opin Drug Metab Toxicol. 2023;19(5):297&#x2013;317. 10.1080/17425255.2023.2223959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37436926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinese Society of Hepatology, Chinese Medical Association. Zhonghua Gan Zang Bing Za Zhi. 2022;30(11):1144&#x2013;50. 10.3760/cma.j.cn501113-20221027-00523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12769359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36891688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufman CS, Cretcher MR. Transjugular liver biopsy. Tech Vasc Interv Radiol. 2021;24(4):100795. 10.1016/j.tvir.2021.100795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34895709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkes JM, Clark LE, Herrera JL. Acetaminophen overdose in pregnancy. South Med J. 2005;98(11):1118&#x2013;22. 10.1097/01.smj.0000184792.15407.51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16351032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton SL, Minns AB. Unintentional chronic acetaminophen poisoning during pregnancy resulting in liver transplantation. J Med Toxicol. 2012;8(2):176&#x2013;8. 10.1007/s13181-012-0218-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3550237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22415886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiew AL, Reith D, Pomerleau A, et al. Updated guidelines for the management of paracetamol poisoning in Australia and New Zealand. Med J Aust. 2020;212(4):175&#x2013;83. 10.5694/mja2.50428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5694/mja2.50428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31786822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiew AL, Buckley NA. Acetaminophen poisoning. Crit Care Clin. 2021;37(3):543&#x2013;61. 10.1016/j.ccc.2021.03.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccc.2021.03.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34053705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>