<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41675732</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2049-0801</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>88</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of medicine and surgery (2012)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Med Surg (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An update on tibial tubercle avulsion fractures: a narrative review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1567</StartPage><EndPage>1573</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1567-1573</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MS9.0000000000004619</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Adolescent tibial tubercle avulsion fracture (TTAF) is a rare knee injury resulting from the combination of anatomical fragility and mechanical stress. This narrative review provides an updated synthesis of current evidence on the epidemiology, imaging-based classification, management strategies, and outcomes of TTAF. In this update, we highlight the role of advanced imaging modalities, such as computed tomography (CT) and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), in improving visualization of fracture morphology and associated soft tissue injuries; review emerging evidence supporting early range of motion (ROM) protocols to enhance postoperative recovery; and summarize recent data on compartment syndrome, emphasizing early recognition and prevention. We correlate fracture morphology, imaging characteristics, and fixation strategies with soft tissue involvement to further refine clinical decision-making. Nonoperative management remains appropriate for Ogden type IA fractures, whereas significantly displaced or complex fracture types require individualized surgical planning and careful selection of fixation devices. This review integrates the latest evidence and clinical practice to provide a concise, evidence-based framework for guiding personalized management of adolescent TTAF and improving patient outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Zhiyao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, The Second Hospital of Jilin University, Changchun, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Hairui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, The Second Hospital of Jilin University, Changchun, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Fangzheng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, The Second Hospital of Jilin University, Changchun, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yaohui</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, The Second Hospital of Jilin University, Changchun, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoning</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, The Second Hospital of Jilin University, Changchun, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Med Surg (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101616869</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2049-0801</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adolescent fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior knee pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">proximal tibia fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tibial tubercle avulsion fracture</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>All the authors declare to have no conflicts of interest relevant to this study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41675732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12889561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MS9.0000000000004619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">AMSU-D-25-01741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agha RA, Mathew G, Rashid R, et al. , TITAN Group. Transparency In The reporting of Artificial INtelligence &#x2013; the TITAN guideline. Prem J Sci 2025;10:100082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Englert EG, Waheed M, Saleh E. A tibial tubercle fracture masquerading as an inferior pole of the patella fracture. J Am Acad Orthop Surg Glob Res Rev 2023;7:e22.00029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes CD, Wu W, Pandya NK. Adolescent tibial tubercle fracture: review of outcomes and complications. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med 2023;16:392&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10427568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37436650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima AS, Cabral J, Boavida J, et al. Tibial tubercle avulsion fractures in adolescents: impact on function and quality of life. J Pediatr Orthop -Part B 2022;31:E135&#x2013;E40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton SW, Gibson PH. Simultaneous bilateral avulsion fractures of the tibial tuberosity in adolescence: a case report and review of over 50 years of literature. Knee 2006;13:404&#x2013;07.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16730992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole WW, Brown SM, Vopat B, et al. Epidemiology, diagnosis, and management of tibial tubercle avulsion fractures in adolescents. JBJS Rev 2020;8:e0186&#x2013;e0186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32304501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zrig M, Annabi H, Ammari T, et al. Acute tibial tubercle avulsion fractures in the sporting adolescent. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg 2008;128:1437&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18408944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKoy BE, Stanitski CL. Acute tibial tubercle avulsion fractures. Orthop Clin North Am 2003;34:397&#x2013;+.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12974489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez FF, Eberhardt O, Schr&#xf6;ter S, et al. Bilateral tibial tubercle avulsion fractures in children clinical results of a rare fracture. Z Orthop Unfall 2020;158:466&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31537040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields MW, Kaushal NK, Patel NM, et al. Variability in evaluation and treatment of tibial tubercle fractures among pediatric orthopedic surgeons. J Pediatr Orthop -Part B 2022;31:E141&#x2013;E6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Checa Betegon P, Arvinius C, Cabadas Gonzalez MI, et al. Management of pediatric tibial tubercle fractures: is surgical treatment really necessary? Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol: Orthop Traumatol 2019;29:1073&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogden JA, Hempton RF, Southwick WO. Development of the tibial tuberosity. Anat Record 1975;182:431&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1170775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretell-Mazzini J, Kelly DM, Sawyer JR, et al. Outcomes and complications of tibial tubercle fractures in pediatric patients: a systematic review of the literature. J Pediatr Orthop 2016;36:440&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25887827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergen MA, Vutescu ES, McKinnon S, et al. Risk of acute compartment syndrome in pediatric patients with tibial tubercle avulsion fractures: a retrospective review. J Pediatr Orthop 2024;44:555&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38853742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao ZY, Zhang HR, Zhou FZ, et al. Tibial tubercle avulsion fracture following preexisting Osgood-Schlatter disease in an adolescent: a case report. J Int Med Res 2024;52:3000605241247683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carius BM, and Long B. Osgood-schlatter disease as a possible cause of tibial tuberosity avulsion. Cureus J Med Sci 2021;13:e13256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard ED, Ramamurti P, Stake S, et al. Posterior tibial slope is increased in patients with tibial tubercle fractures and osgood-schlatter disease. J Pediatr Orthop 2021;41:E411&#x2013;E6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giffin JR, Vogrin TM, Zantop T, et al. Effects of increasing tibial slope on the biomechanics of the knee. Am J Sports Med 2004;32:376&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14977661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kralj R, Grzan IS, Vukovic A, et al. Is excessive body weight related to energy level of injury in tibial tubercle fractures in adolescents? J Pediatr Orthop -Part B 2025;34:33&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YW, Huang P, Fan MJ, et al. Risk factor analysis for tibial tubercle avulsion fractures in children. Int Orthop 2023;47:2347&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37432419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farr JN, Dimitri P. The impact of fat and obesity on bone microarchitecture and strength in children. Calcif Tissue Int 2017;100:500&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5395331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28013362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen PC, Williams BA, Edobor-Osula OF, et al. What is the utilization and impact of advanced imaging for tibial tubercle fractures? an analysis of 598 patients from the Tibial Tubercle Study (TITUS) Group. J Pediatr Orthop 2024;44:e876&#x2013;e82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38979941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XW, Zhang L, Hui TT, et al. MRI manifestations and associated injuries in adolescent tibial tuberosity fractures: a retrospective study. Injury Int J Care Inj 2025;56:112765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaya-Quezada C, Fanney L, Patel V, et al. Imaging of the pediatric knee. Semin Musculoskelet Radiol 2024;28:462&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39074728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kothari V, Park C, Sobti A, et al. Classification and management of tibial tubercle avulsion fractures in children. Br J Hosp Med 2024;85:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandya NK, Edmonds EW, Roocroft JH, et al. Tibial tubercle fractures: complications, classification, and the need for intra-articular assessment. J Pediatr Orthop 2012;32:749&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23147615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson-Jones R. The classic: &#x201c;Fractures and Joint Injuries&#x201d; by Sir Reginald Watson-Jones, taken from &#x201c;Fractures and Joint Injuries,&#x201d; by R. Watson-Jones, Vol. II, 4th ed., Baltimore, Williams and Wilkins Company. Clin Orthop Relat Res 1955;1974:4&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogden JA, Tross RB, Murphy MJ. Fractures of the tibial tuberosity in adolescents. J Bone Joint Surg Am 1980;62:205&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7358751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryu RK, Debenham JO. An unusual avulsion fracture of the proximal tibial epiphysis. Case report and proposed addition to the Watson-Jones classification. Clin Orthop Relat Res 1985;194:181&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankl U, Wasilewski SA, Healy WL. Avulsion fracture of the tibial tubercle with avulsion of the patellar ligament. Report of two cases. J Bone Joint Surg Am 1990;72:1411&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2229123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley T, Crowe M, Mayassi H, et al. Reliability of a modified watson-jones classification for tibial tubercle fractures in children. J Pediatr Orthop 2024;44:476&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38956967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang DN, Kell D, Syed A, et al. Does skeletal maturity predict the pattern of tibial tubercle avulsion fracture? J Pediatr Orthop 2023;43:E561&#x2013;E6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37205835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalifis G, Fermin TM, Seil R, et al. Tibial tubercle fractures are sports injuries in male adolescents with a considerable risk of complications and reoperations: a systematic review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 2023;31:2624&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36702926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shabshin N, Schweitzer ME, Morrison WB, et al. MRI criteria for patella alta and baja. Skeletal Radiol 2004;33:445&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15221214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luppi V, Mazzi M, Micaglio A, et al. Neglected patellar tendon rupture in tibial tubercle avulsion fracture in an adolescent: a case report. La Pediatria Medica E Chirurgica: Med Surg Pediatr 2022;44:10.4081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truong P, Bowen RE. Proximal tibia fractures. Sports Med Arthrosc Rev 2024;32:189&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39655825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franz P, Luderowski E, Tuca M. Tibial tubercle avulsion fractures in children. Curr Opin Pediatr 2020;32:86&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31895159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown C, Kelly BA, Brouillet K, et al. Ogden Type I to III tibial tubercle fractures in skeletally immature patients: is routine anterior compartment fasciotomy of the leg indicated? J Child Orthop 2021;15:515&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34987660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sessions WC, Herring M, Truong WH. Extensor mechanism injury in the pediatric population-A clinical review. J Knee Surg 2018;31:490&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29409066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickert KD, Hedequist D, Bomar JD. Screw fixation of pediatric tibial tubercle fractures. JBJS Essent Surg Tech 2021;11:e19.00062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dure A, Nowell JA, Antar RM, et al. Does screw size or configuration affect hardware removal rate in surgically treated tibial tubercle fracture. J Pediatr Orthop 2025;45:e513&#x2013;e9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40025639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maxwell BE, Edobor-Osula OF, Blanco JS, et al. Who is at risk for implant irritation after fixation of a tibial tubercle fracture? a multicenter study. J Pediatr Orthop 2025;45:e520&#x2013;e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39981943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menapace B, Shannon BA, Neal K, et al. Off with the head: decreasing complications with headless compression screws for tibial tubercle fracture fixation. J Pediatr Orthop 2025;46:42&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arkader A, Schur M, Refakis C, et al. Unicortical fixation is sufficient for surgical treatment of tibial tubercle avulsion fractures in children. J Pediatr Orthop 2019;39:E18&#x2013;E22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30376496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brnjos K, Edobor-Osula OF, Blanco JS, et al. Risk factors for stiffness after fixation of tibial tubercle fractures: a multicenter study from the TITUS Group. JB &amp; JS Open Access 2025;10:e25.00142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang K, Houlihan N, Arkader A, et al. Early knee range of motion following operative treatment for tibial tubercle avulsion fractures is safe. J Pediatr Orthop 2022;42:516&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35968996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Formiconi F, D&#x2019;Amato RD, Voto A, et al. Outcomes of surgical treatment of the tibial tuberosity fractures in skeletally immature patients: an update. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol 2020;30:789&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31989257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang AA, Erdman M, Kwok E, et al. Outcomes of displaced tibial tubercle fractures in adolescents. J Knee Surg 2023;36:1105&#x2013;08.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35798348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T, Wen YW, Zhu DJ, et al. Comparison of bioabsorbable screw versus metallic screw fixation for tibial tubercle fractures in adolescents: a retrospective cohort study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2025;26:38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haber DB, Tepolt FA, McClincy MP, et al. Tibial tubercle fractures in children and adolescents: a large retrospective case series. J Pediatr Orthop -Part B 2021;30:13&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez VH, Pluta N, Tadlock JC, et al. The prevalence of acute compartment syndrome in pediatric tibial tubercle fractures. J Pediatr Orthop 2024;44:e883&#x2013;e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39021084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed N, Kuo YH. Factors associated with compartment syndrome after a tibial fracture in children. Trauma Surg Acute Care Open 2023;8:e001158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10626752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37936901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>