<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41834035</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2050-2974</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of eating disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Eat Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring social support for eating disorders in Indigenous contexts.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40337-026-01574-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Eating disorders can affect anyone, regardless of cultural and ethnic background. However, culturally situated understandings of eating disorders are important for optimizing care. Moreover, social support is widely recognized as a key component in the recovery of eating disorders. Established Euro-Western treatment models generally conceptualize social support as the role family and close friends play in providing emotional and practical support during a loved one's recovery. Indigenous perspectives of social support, which may include connection to ancestors, community, non-human relatives, and the land, are largely absent from such models, which limits understanding of the culturally relevant social networks that can help support Indigenous peoples with eating disorders. The present research addresses this gap exploring social support through Indigenous worldviews.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This qualitative project was completed with an Indigenous research approach. Two Indigenous therapists participated in a semi-structured sharing circle (focus group) and one Indigenous therapist participated in a semi-structured individual conversation (interview). Both the sharing circle and the interview were facilitated by the lead author, who is an Indigenous researcher. The data were analysed using qualitative description.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Qualitative analysis produced two main themes that reflect interrelated conceptualizations of social support from Indigenous perspectives, relevant to working with Indigenous peoples struggling with eating disorders. The interrelated themes were Wahkotowin (relationships between all things), and 2) land as support and (re)connection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This research presents novel insights into Indigenous perspectives on social support as relevant to eating disorder treatment. It expands the understanding of social support beyond immediate family networks to include relationships between all things, including ancestors, community, all living things, and the importance of land-based healing. The study addresses the need for Indigenous perspectives in the field of eating disorders research and treatment as well as the need to understand and incorporate culturally specific forms of social support.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Plante</LastName><ForeName>Maureen</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education, Department of Educational Psychology, University of Alberta, 11405-87 Ave, Edmonton, AB, T6G 2C5, Canada. msplante@ualberta.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Austin</LastName><ForeName>Amelia</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mathison Centre for Mental Health Research &amp; Education, Cumming School of Medicine, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Damag</LastName><ForeName>Suha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Lethbridge, Lethbridge, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tremblay</LastName><ForeName>Melissa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education, Department of Educational Psychology, University of Alberta, 11405-87 Ave, Edmonton, AB, T6G 2C5, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Eat Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610672</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-2974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>This article reflects a collaborative research approach that explores the concept of social support from Indigenous therapists&#x2019; worldviews, relevant to working with Indigenous people who are struggling with eating disorders. The findings articulate key features of culturally relevant care pertaining to social support; namely Wahkotowin (Cree word for relationships between all things), and land. According to Indigenous therapists, these culturally situated social supports help a person with an eating disorder feel less isolated and allow for exploration of symptoms. Social support can draw on a number of connections specific to an individual and is complementary to conventional therapy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eating disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Indigenous mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Indigenous worldviews</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Social support</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This research project was approved by the University of Calgary&#x2019;s Human Research Ethics Board. All participants consented to be part of this study. Consent for publication: The authors consent to publish. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41834035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40337-026-01574-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40337-026-01574-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Treasure J, Duarte TA, Schmidt U. Eating disorders. Lancet. 2020;395(10227):899&#x2013;911. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-673(20)30059-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sil&#xe9;n Y, Keski-Rahkonen A. Worldwide prevalence of DSM-5 eating disorders among young people. Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2022;35(6):362&#x2013;71. https://doi.org/10.1097/YCO.0000000000000818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchison D, Broderstad AR, Burt A, Kval&#xf8;y K. Eating disorders in Indigenous peoples. In: Eating Disorders: An International Comprehensive View. 2023. p. 1&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-46096-8_19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams-Ridgway A, McGowan R, McNeil S, Tuomainen H. Eating disorders in minority ethnic populations in Australia, Canada, Aotearoa New Zealand and the UK: a scoping review. J Eat Disord. 2025;13(1):8. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40337-024-01173-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonneville KR, Lipson SK. Disparities in eating disorder diagnosis and treatment according to weight status, race/ethnicity, socioeconomic background, and sex among college students. Int J Eat Disord. 2018;51(6):518&#x2013;26. https://doi.org/10.1002/eat.22846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solmi M, Monaco F, H&#xf8;jlund M, Monteleone AM, Trott M, Firth J, et al. Outcomes in people with eating disorders: a transdiagnostic and disorder&#x2010;specific systematic review, meta&#x2010;analysis and multivariable meta&#x2010;regression analysis. World Psychiatry. 2024;23(1):124&#x2013;38. https://doi.org/10.1002/wps.21182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt UH, Claudino A, Fern&#xe1;ndez&#x2010;Aranda F, Giel KE, Griffiths J, Hay PJ, et al. The current clinical approach to feeding and eating disorders aimed to increase personalization of management. World Psychiatry. 2025;24(1):4&#x2013;3. https://doi.org/10.1002/wps.21263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverman JA. Anorexia nervosa: historical perspective on treatment. In: Garner DM, Garfinkel PE, editors. Handbook of treatment for eating disorders. New York: Guilford Press; 1997. p. 3&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loeb KL, le Grange D. Family-Based Treatment for Adolescent Eating Disorders: current status, new applications and future directions. Int J Child Adolesc Health. 2009;2(2):243&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisler I, Wallis A, Dodge E. What&#x2019;s new is old and what&#x2019;s old is new: The origins and evolution of eating disorders family therapy. In: Loeb KL, Le Grange D, Lock J, editors. Family therapy for adolescent eating and weight disorders: New applications. New York: Routledge/Taylor &amp; Francis Group; 2015. p. 6&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannah L, Cross M, Baily H, Grimwade K, Clarke T, Allan SM. A systematic review of the impact of carer interventions on outcomes for patients with eating disorders. Eat Weight Disord. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40519-021-01338-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potterton R, Brown G, Schmidt U. &#x201c;I thought if my parents got involved, then they&#x2019;d make me get better&#x201d;: Emerging adults&#x2019; experiences of support from family and friends during anorexia nervosa. J Eat Disord. 2025;13(1):1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40337-025-01260-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treasure J, Henghan A, Livanou M. The role of social and family support in the management of eating disorders. Cutting Edge Psychiatry Pract. 2024;1:171&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodge E, Baudinet J, Austin A, Eisler I, Le Grange D, Dimitropoulos G. Family therapy for emerging adults with anorexia nervosa: expert opinion on evidence, practice considerations, and future directions. Eur Eat Disord Rev. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1002/erv.3129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisler I, Simic M, Blessitt E, Dodge L, MCCAEDS Team. Maudsley service model for the management of child and adolescent eating disorders. Child and Adolescent Eating Disorders Service, South London &amp; Maudsley NHS Foundation Trust. 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lock J, Le Grange D. Treatment manual for anorexia nervosa: A family-based approach. New York: Guilford Press; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt U, Treasure J, Allen K. The Maudsley model of anorexia nervosa treatment for adults (MANTRA). In: Robinson P, Wade T, Herpertz-Dahlmann B, Fernandez-Aranda F, Treasure J, Wonderlich S, editors. Eating disorders. Cham: Springer; 2023. p. 1&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-97416-9_61-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treasure J, Smith G, Crane A. Skills-based caring for a loved one with an eating disorder: The new Maudsley method. New York: Routledge; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaMarre A, Couturier J, Dimitropoulos G, Jones S, Kumar S, Obeid N, et al. Peer support for eating disorders in Canada: program user perspectives. J Eat Disord. 2024Sep 4;12(1):133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alani-Verjee T, Braunberger P, Bobinski T, Mushquash C. First Nations elders in Northwestern Ontario&#x2019;s perspectives of health, body image and eating disorders. J Indigenous Wellbeing Te Mauri-Pimatisiwin. 2017;2(1):76&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams M, Kingston Miller A, Lafrance A. Ayahuasca ceremony leaders&#x2019; perspectives on special considerations for eating disorders. Eat Disord. 2024;32(2):120&#x2013;39. https://doi.org/10.1080/10640266.2023.2271201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark MTR, Manuel J, Lacey C, Pitama S, Cunningham R, Jordan J. &#x2018;E koekoe te T&#x16b;&#x12b;, e ketekete te K&#x101;k&#x101;, e kuku te Kerer&#x16b;, The T&#x16b;&#x12b; chatters, the K&#x101;k&#x101; cackles, and the Kerer&#x16b; coos&#x2019;: insights into explanatory factors, treatment experiences and recovery for M&#x101;ori with eating disorders&#x2013;a qualitative study. Aust N Z J Psychiatry. 2024;58(4):365&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1177/00048674231207583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraser G, Clark MTR, Rose BM, Martin K, Beavis B, Pettie M, et al. Ng&#x101; M&#x101;uiui Kai: creating indigenous M&#x101;ori terms for eating disorders in Aotearoa New Zealand. J Eat Disord. 2024;12(1):205. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40337-024-01179-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couturier J, Isserlin L, Norris M, Spettigue W, Brouwers M, Kimber M, et al. Canadian practice guidelines for the treatment of children and adolescents with eating disorders. J Eat Disord. 2020Feb 1;8(1):4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canadian Eating Disorders Alliance. Canadian Eating Disorders Strategy: 2019&#x2013;2029. Toronto (ON): National Eating Disorders Information Centre. 2019. Accessed 26 Oct 2025.&#xa0;https://nedic.ca/media/uploaded/Canadian_Eating_Disorders_Strategy_2019-2029_-_dps_-_ENG.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>First Nations Health Authority. First Nations Perspective on Health and Wellness. 2020. https://www.fnha.ca/wellness/wellness-for-first-nations/first-nations-perspective-on-health-and-wellness.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gone JP. Alternative knowledges and the future of community psychology: provocations from an American Indian healing tradition. Am J Community Psychol. 2016;58(3&#x2013;4):314&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajcp.12046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell T, Auger M, Gomes T, Brown FL, Young Leon A. Sharing our wisdom: a holistic aboriginal health initiative. Int J Indigenous Health. 2016;11(1):111&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.18357/ijih111201616015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panofsky S, Buchanan MJ, Wilat T, Madeek D, Neekupdeh D, Smogelgem D, et al. The Wet&#x2019;suwet&#x2019;en Nation&#x2019;s mobilization of Indigenous Focusing Oriented Therapy: an exploratory study. Counsel Psychol. 2023;51(3):333&#x2013;67. https://doi.org/10.1177/00110000221146571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gone JP, Calf Looking PE. American Indian culture as substance abuse treatment: pursuing evidence for a local intervention. J Psychoact Drugs. 2011;43(4):291&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1080/02791072.2011.628915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardinal de Ubiera R. Saddle Lake Cree Nation. Treaty 6. Lives in Edmonton. Oral teaching. Personal communication. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plante M. Stepping away from the campfire: decolonizing the concept of eating disorders through an Indigenous focusing oriented therapy lens. master&#x2019;s thesis. University of Calgary; 2022. 0.11575/PRISM/40692</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danto D, Walsh R, Sommerfeld J. Learning from those who do: land-based healing in a Mushkegowuk community. Int J Ment Health Addict. 2021;19(6):2131&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11469-020-00306-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redvers N, Nadeau M, Prince D. Urban land-based healing: a northern intervention strategy. Int J Indig Health. 2021;16(2):322&#x2013;37. https://doi.org/10.32799/ijih.v16i2.33177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toombs E, Lund J, Mushquash AR, Mushquash CJ. Predictors of land-based activity participation in a national representative sample of Indigenous individuals living off-reserve. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(13):8029. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19138029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turcotte S, Schiffer JJ. Aboriginal focusing-oriented therapy. In: Madison G, editor. Emerging practice in focusing-oriented psychotherapy: Innovative theory and applications. London: Jessica Kingsley Publishers; 2014. p. 48&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gendlin ET. Focusing-oriented psychotherapy: A manual of the experiential method. New York: Guilford Press; 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook-Cottone, C. P. 2020. Embodiment and the treatment of eating disorders&#x202f;: the body as a resource in recovery (1st ed.). W.W. Norton &amp; Company.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piran, N. 2017. Journeys of embodiment at the intersection of body and culture: The developmental theory of embodiment. Academic Press</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piran, N. &amp; Teall, T. 2012. The developmental theory of embodiment. In. McVey, G. Preventing Eating-Related and Weight-Related Disorders: Collaborative Research, Advocacy, and Policy Change. Wilfrid Laurier University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBride, H.L. &amp; Kwee, J.L. 2019. Intergenerational journeys: Mothers raising embodied daughters. In. McBride, H. L., &amp; Kwee, J. L. (Eds.). Embodiment and eating disorders&#x202f;: theory, research, prevention, and treatment. Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBride, H.L. 2019. Embodiment and body image: Relating and exploring constructs. In. McBride, H. L., &amp; Kwee, J. L. (Eds.). Embodiment and eating disorders&#x202f;: theory, research, prevention, and treatment. Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renelli M, Fletcher J, Tupper KW, Files N, Loizaga-Velder A, Lafrance A. An exploratory study of experiences with conventional eating disorder treatment and ceremonial ayahuasca for the healing of eating disorders. Eat Weight Disord-Stud Anorex Bulim Obes. 2020;25(2):437&#x2013;44. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40519-018-0619-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lafrance A, Loizaga-Velder A, Fletcher J, Renelli M, Files N, Tupper KW. Nourishing the spirit: exploratory research on ayahuasca experiences along the continuum of recovery from eating disorders. J Psychoactive Drugs. 2017(5). https://doi.org/10.1080/02791072.2017.1361559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh T-L, Coppola AM, Sabiston CM. &#x201c;I&#x2019;m thankful for being Native and my body is part of that&#x201d;: the body pride experiences of young Aboriginal women in Canada. Body Image. 2014;46(3):318&#x2013;27. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bodyim.2014.05.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall S, Liebenberg L. Qualitative description as an introductory method to qualitative research for master&#x2019;s-level students and research trainees. Int J Qual Methods. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1177/16094069241242264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colorafi KJ, Evans B. Qualitative descriptive methods in health science research. HERD. 2016;9(4):16&#x2013;25. https://doi.org/10.1177/1937586715614171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson S. Research Is Ceremony: Indigenous Research Ceremony.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor GW, Ussher JM. Making sense of S&amp;M: a discourse analytic account. Sexualities. 2001;4(3):293&#x2013;314. https://doi.org/10.1177/136346001004003002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panel on Research Ethics. Chapter 9: research involving the first nations, inuit and m&#xe9;tis peoples of canada. In: Tri-council policy statement: ethical conduct for research involving humans &#x2013; TCPS 2. Government of Canada; 2022. https://ethics.gc.ca/eng/tcps2-eptc2_2022_chapter9-chapitre9.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovach M. Indigenous methodologies: Characteristics, conversations, and contexts. Toronto: University of Toronto Press; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnette CE, Clark CB, Rodning CB. Living off the land": how subsistence promotes well-being and resilience among Indigenous Peoples of the Southeastern United States. Soc Serv Rev. 2018;92(3):369&#x2013;400. https://doi.org/10.1086/699287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gall A, Anderson K, Howard K, Diaz A, King A, Willing E, et al. Wellbeing of Indigenous Peoples in Canada, Aotearoa (New Zealand) and the United States: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;54(11):5832. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18115832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrasek MacDonald J, Cunsolo Willox A, Ford JD, Shiwak I, Wood M. Protective factors for mental health and well-being in a changing climate: perspectives from Inuit youth in Nunatsiavut, Labrador. Soc Sci Med. 2015;141:133&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2015.07.017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosby I. Administering Colonial Science: nutrition research and human biomedical experimentation in Aboriginal Communities and Residential Schools, 1942&#x2013;1952. Hist Soc. 2013;46(1):145&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1353/his.2013.0015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heywood L, Conti J, Hay P. Paper 1: a systematic synthesis of narrative therapy treatment components for the treatment of eating disorders. J Eat Disord. 2022;10(1):137. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40337-022-00635-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conti J, Heywood L, Hay P, Shrestha RM, Perich T. Paper 2: a systematic review of narrative therapy treatment outcomes for eating disorders&#x2014;bridging the divide between practice-based evidence and evidence-based practice. J Eat Disord. 2022;10(1):138. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40337-022-00636-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White M. Maps of narrative practice. New York: Norton; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buys ME. Exploring the evidence for Internal Family Systems therapy: a scoping review of current research, gaps, and future directions. Clin Psychol. 2025;29(3):241&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1080/13284207.2025.2533127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz RC. Working with &#x201c;internal and external&#x201d; families in treatment of bulimia. Fam Relat. 1987;36(3):242&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.2307/583534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCabe J. Resisting alienation: the social construction of Internet communities supporting eating disorders. Commun Stud. 2009;60(1):1&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1080/10510970802623542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lock A, Epston D, Maisel R, Faria N. Resisting anorexia/bulimia: foucauldian perspectives in narrative therapy. Br J Guid Couns. 2005;33(3):315&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.1080/03069880500179459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young A, Turcotte S, Gomes T, Lacombe B, Tipple SD. Indigenous tools for living: decolonizing genocide-informed health education. AlterNative. 2025;21(4):655&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.1177/11771801251356067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plante, M., Forest, K., Betker, L., Villebrun, G., &amp; Tremblay, M. (2025). First Nations and M&#xe9;tis Employees&#x2019; Experiences: Exploring Successes in Non-First Nations and M&#xe9;tis Organizations Through a Community-Based Project. International Journal of Indigenous Health, 21(1). https://doi.org/10.32799/ijih.v21i1.44399</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter N, Bryant-Lukosius D, DiCenso A, Blythe J, Neville AJ. The use of triangulation in qualitative research. Oncol Nurs Forum. 2014;41(5):545&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1188/14.ONF.545-547.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>