<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41913242</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1477-3155</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of nanobiotechnology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Nanobiotechnology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Recent advances in machine learning-enhanced extracellular vesicle omics for oncology.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12951-026-04342-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are nanoscale, membrane-bound particles that carry nucleic acids, proteins, metabolites, and lipids. Their omics profiles can reflect tumor and microenvironmental states, making EVs a promising source of liquid biopsy biomarkers. Machine learning (ML) is well suited to EV omics because it can learn predictive signatures from high-dimensional, correlated, and sparse features and integrate complementary modalities. However, clinical translation is often hindered by EV-specific issues-including heterogeneous vesicle populations, isolation-dependent recovery of subtypes, and co-isolated particles. Few reviews comprehensively synthesize ML studies across EV transcriptomics, proteomics, metabolomics, and lipidomics in oncology. This review introduces EV fundamentals and provides a structured, in-depth evaluation of recent advances in ML-enhanced EV omics for early cancer detection, molecular subtyping, prognosis, and treatment response prediction. Key challenges-including data quality, model generalizability, algorithmic interpretability, ethical considerations, and standardization issues-are critically examined and distilled into practical recommendations for study design, validation, and reporting. Emerging directions include single-vesicle omics, higher-resolution EV profiling, interpretable multimodal fusion, and end-to-end pipelines that integrate EV multi-omics with ML. Together, these advances could help translate EV-based liquid biopsy into clinically useful tools for precision oncology.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zesheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, School of Clinical Medicine, Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, 999077, Hong Kong.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Innovation Institute for Life Sciences and Energy (MILES), HKU-SIRI, Shenzhen, 518000, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Weiling</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, School of Clinical Medicine, Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, 999077, Hong Kong.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Innovation Institute for Life Sciences and Energy (MILES), HKU-SIRI, Shenzhen, 518000, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Zhenjun</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cancer Center, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Chongqing Medical University, Chongqing, 404100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Haoran</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Innovation Institute for Life Sciences and Energy (MILES), HKU-SIRI, Shenzhen, 518000, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Zhiwei</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Innovation Institute for Life Sciences and Energy (MILES), HKU-SIRI, Shenzhen, 518000, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Shihui</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatopancreatobiliary Surgery, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Harbin Medical University, Harbin, 150001, Heilongjiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhiyu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatopancreatobiliary Surgery, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Harbin Medical University, Harbin, 150001, Heilongjiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Ziyue</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Liver Surgery, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences and Peking Union Medical College (CAMS &amp; PUMC), Beijing, 100730, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoke</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medical Oncology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Harbin Medical University, Harbin, 150086, Heilongjiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, School of Clinical Medicine, Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, 999077, Hong Kong. xuyihrb@pathology.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Innovation Institute for Life Sciences and Energy (MILES), HKU-SIRI, Shenzhen, 518000, Guangdong, China. xuyihrb@pathology.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatopancreatobiliary Surgery, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Harbin Medical University, Harbin, 150001, Heilongjiang, China. xuyihrb@pathology.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Oncology in South China, Cancer Center of Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou, 510000, Guangdong, China. xuyihrb@pathology.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Laboratory of Cancer Systems Regulation and Clinical Translation, Jiading District Central Hospital, Jiading District Central Hospital Affiliated Shanghai University of Medicine &amp; Health Science, Shanghai, 201800, China. xuyihrb@pathology.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Early Prevention and Treatment for Regional High Frequency Tumor (Guangxi Medical University), Ministry of Education/Guangxi Key Laboratory of Early Prevention and Treatment for Regional High Frequency Tumor, Nanning, 530000, Guangxi, China. xuyihrb@pathology.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Clinical Laboratory Medicine of Guangxi Department of Education, Nanning, 530000, Guangxi, China. xuyihrb@pathology.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Clinical Laboratory Technology for Precision Medicine (Fujian Medical University), Fujian Province University, Fuzhou, 350000, Fujian, China. xuyihrb@pathology.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Provincial Key Laboratory of Tumor Evolution and Intelligent Diagnosis and Treatment, Bengbu, 233000, Anhui, China. xuyihrb@pathology.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Gastrointestinal Cancer (Fujian Medical University), Ministry of Education, School of Basic Medical Sciences, Fujian Medical University, Fuzhou, 350122, Fujian, China. xuyihrb@pathology.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yam</LastName><ForeName>Judy Wai Ping</ForeName><Initials>JWP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, School of Clinical Medicine, Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, 999077, Hong Kong. judyyam@pathology.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Liver Research (The University of Hong Kong), Hong Kong, 999077, Hong Kong. judyyam@pathology.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Innovation Institute for Life Sciences and Energy (MILES), HKU-SIRI, Shenzhen, 518000, Guangdong, China. judyyam@pathology.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatopancreatobiliary Surgery, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Harbin Medical University, Harbin, 150001, Heilongjiang, China. judyyam@pathology.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>82573164; 82472743; 82300921</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>AD25069077</GrantID><Agency>Guangxi Science and Technology Program</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>LH2023H043</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Heilongjiang Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>HN2025-02</GrantID><Agency>Open Funds of State Key Laboratory of Oncology in South China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>GXGXLCJYZDX2025001</GrantID><Agency>Shanghai Key Laboratory of Cancer Systems Regulation and Clinical Translation; Open Research Project from Key Laboratory of Clinical Laboratory Medicine of Guangxi Department of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CSRCT-KF0002</GrantID><Agency>Open Funds of the Shanghai Key Laboratory of Cancer Systems Regulation and Clinical Translation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>FMUGIC-202501</GrantID><Agency>Open Research Fund of the Key Laboratory of Gastrointestinal Cancer (Fujian Medical University), Ministry of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>FKLCLT-202504</GrantID><Agency>Open Funds of the Key Laboratory of Clinical Laboratory Technology for Precision Medicine</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>NcRNA202508</GrantID><Agency>Open Research Fund of the Anhui Province Key Laboratory of Non-coding RNA Basic and Clinical Transformation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>KFKT-202505</GrantID><Agency>Open Project of the Anhui Provincial Key Laboratory of Tumor Evolution and Intelligent Diagnosis and Treatment</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SKLLR/TRSS/2025/08</GrantID><Agency>Thematic Research Support Scheme of State Key Laboratory of Liver Research, The University of Hong Kong</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Project No. T12-716/22-R</GrantID><Agency>Research Grants Council Theme-Based Research Scheme</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Nanobiotechnology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101152208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1477-3155</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Extracellular vesicles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Liquid biopsy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multi-omics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Precision oncology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41913242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12951-026-04342-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12951-026-04342-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>a) M, AlDoughaim N, AlSuhebany M, AlZahrani T, AlQahtani S, AlGhamdi H, Badreldin H, Al Alshaykh. 2024, 18, 11795549241298541; b) D. Crosby, S. Bhatia, K. M. Brindle, L. M. Coussens, C. Dive, M. Emberton, S. Esener, R. C. Fitzgerald, S. S. Gambhir, P. Kuhn, T. R. Rebbeck, S. Balasubramanian, Science 2022, 375, eaay9040; c) A. H. Partridge, L. A. Carey, Clinical Cancer Research 2017, 23, 2611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Z, Liu J, Chen Y, Ren S, Liu Y, Ba A, Zuo P, Luo Q, Cheng H, Xu X, Han, Yu B, Wang Q, Liu X, Hu S, Zhou L, Xu Q, Sun Y, Hu X, Luo Z, Zhang X. 2024, 9, 270; b) N. I. Barrena Medel, J. D. Wright, T. J. Herzog, Journal of Oncology 2010, 2010, 314326; c) B. Yu, Q. Wang, X. Liu, S. Hu, L. Zhou, Q. Xu, Y. Sun, X. Hu, Z. Luo, X. Zhang Front Oncol 2022, 12, 723140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S, Zhang C, Gao Y, Wang L, Chen S, Gao JGO, Hanif H, Ali MJ, Susheela AT, Khan IW, Luna-Cuadros MA, Khan MM, Lau DT, Fan Z, Zhang Y. World J Gastroenterol 2022, 28, 216; c) T. Lee, T. Z. J. Teng, V. G. Shelat, World J Gastrointest Surg 2020, 12, 468; d) J. Zong, Z. Fan, Y. Zhang J Hepatocell Carcinoma 2020, 7, 413; e) C. Pang, Y. Ma, W. Shi, M. Zi, J. Chen, C. Liang, X. Li, Z. Liu, Y. Du, Journal of Gastrointestinal Surgery 2024, 28, 694.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S, Pandey P, Yadav, Watanabe K, Nakamura Y, Low S-K. 2025, 43, e00446; b) M. Ignatiadis, G. W. Sledge, S. S. Jeffrey, Nature Reviews Clinical Oncology 2021, 18, 297; c) K. Watanabe, Y. Nakamura, S.-K. Low Journal of Human Genetics 2021, 66, 909; d) K. K. Adhit, A. Wanjari, S. Menon, S. K, Cureus 2023, 15, e50176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) L, Ma H, Guo Y, Zhao Z, Liu C, Wang J, Bu T, Sun J, Wei, Velculescu V, Anagnostou. 2024, 9, 336; b) H. Wang, Y. Zhang, H. Zhang, H. Cao, J. Mao, X. Chen, L. Wang, N. Zhang, P. Luo, J. Xue, X. Qi, X. Dong, G. Liu, Q. Cheng, MedComm (2020) 2024, 5, e564; c) B. V. Landon, A. V. Annapragada, N. Niknafs, V. E. Velculescu, V., Anagnostou Nat Med 2025, 31, 4006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) M, Manno A, Bongiovanni L, Margolis P, Bergese P, Arosio, Tassoni S, Bergese P, Radeghieri A. 2024, 3, 68; b) D. Wang, Y. Shen, H. Qian, J. Jiang, W. Xu, Theranostics 2024, 14, 7309; c) S. Tassoni, P. Bergese, A. Radeghieri Nanomedicine (Lond) 2025, 20, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) R, Kalluri KM, McAndrews, Hallal S, Tuzesi A, Grau GE, Buckland ME, Alexander KL. 2023, 186, 1610; b) A. Moller, R. J. Lobb, Nat Rev Cancer 2020, 20, 697; c) S. Hallal, A. Tuzesi, G. E. Grau, M. E. Buckland, K. L. Alexander J Extracell Vesicles 2022, 11, e12260; d) C. L. S. Yeung, J. W. P. Yam, Seminars in Cancer Biology 2022, 86, 1088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) D, Fochtman L, Marczak M, Pietrowska A, Wojakowska JEV, Silva TF, Hutchins E, Zhao W, Ciani Y, Kim M, Ko E, Mariscal J, Qiu Z, Bedier F, Kittel A, Zhou B, Wang Y, Hall M, Galasso F, Reiman R, Freeman MR, Parker S, Van Eyk J, Yang W, Posadas E, Guarnerio J, Nolan J, Thery C, Zijlstra A, Stott S et al. Cell Rep Med 2025, 6, 102161; c) X. Lu, Y. Li, Y. Li, X. Zhang, J. Shi, H. Feng, Y. Gao, Z. Yu, Front Mol Biosci 2023, 10, 1114594; d) M. Manfredi, E. Williams, W. C. Cho, M. Falasca, Front Mol Biosci 2021, 8, 784436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) N, Zarovni D, Mladenovic D, Brambilla F, Panico M, Chiari. 2025, 14, e70034; b) V. Rondelli, S. Helmy, G. Passignani, P. Parisse, D. Di Silvestre, ACS Omega 2022, 7, 19058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) JA, L&#xf3;pez-Guerrero M, Val&#xe9;s-G&#xf3;mez FE, Borr&#xe1;s JM, Falc&#xf3;n-P&#xe9;rez MJ, Vicent M, Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-M&#xf3;, Herrmann-Sim F, Wilkesmann L, Helm D, Schneider M, Campione G, Pl&#xfc;gge K, Greiner G, Lazaro Garc&#xed;a L, Berker J, Richter K, Zielske L, Hofmann W-K, Clemm K. von Hohenberg, Scientific Reports 2025, 15, 24292; c) K. W. Witwer, E. I. Buz&#xe1;s, L. T. Bemis, A. Bora, C. L&#xe4;sser, J. L&#xf6;tvall, E. N. Nolte-&#x2018;t Hoen, M. G. Piper, S. Sivaraman, J. Skog, C. Th&#xe9;ry, M. H. Wauben, F. Hochberg, Journal of Extracellular Vesicles 2013, 2, 20360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) D, Feldner-Busztin P, Firbas Nisantzis SJ, Edmunds G, Boza F, Racimo S, Gopalakrishnan MT, Limborg L, Lahti GG, de Polavieja, Reel PS, Reel S, Pearson E, Trucco E, Jefferson E. 2023, 39; b) M. Lin, J. Guo, Z. Gu, W. Tang, H. Tao, S. You, D. Jia, Y. Sun, P. Jia, Journal of Translational Medicine 2025, 23, 388; c) P. S. Reel, S. Reel, E. Pearson, E. Trucco, E. Jefferson Biotechnology Advances 2021, 49, 107739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Q, Wang X, Zhou J, Wu W, Miao B, Shen R, Shi FO, Lotter W, Hassett MJ, Schultz N, Kehl KL, Van Allen EM, Cerami E, Hagen J, Hornung L, Barham W, Mukhopadhyay S, Bess A, Contrera K, Basu D, Sandulache V, Spielmann G, S., Kansara. Cancer Discov 2024, 14, 711; c) K. Kourou, K. P. Exarchos, C. Papaloukas, P. Sakaloglou, T. Exarchos, D. I. Fotiadis, Comput Struct Biotechnol J 2021, 19, 5546; d) J. Hagen, L. Hornung, W. Barham, S. Mukhopadhyay, A. Bess, K. Contrera, D. Basu, V. Sandulache, G. Spielmann, S. Kansara Cancers (Basel) 2025, 17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Li J, Gong W. Comput Struct Biotechnol J. 2025;27:2460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J, Amann A, Blasimme E, Vayena D, Frey VI, Madai Qc, Precise. 2020, 20, 310; b) K. Sel, A. Hawkins-Daarud, A. Chaudhuri, D. Osman, A. Bahai, D. Paydarfar, K. Willcox, C. Chung, R. Jafari, NPJ Digit Med 2025, 8, 40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) SB, Arya SP, Collie CA, Parent TCB, Wang Z, Zhou X, Kong Q, He H, Sun J, Qiu W, Zhang L, Yang M. Adv Sci (Weinh) 2024, 11, e2401069; c) N. M. Ahmed, K. Beatson, J. Patel, M. M. R. Eddama, L. H. Clapp, T. Abdel-Aziz, J Mol Med (Berl) 2025, DOI: 10.1007/s00109-025-02594-1IF: 4.2 Q1 B3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) ZF, Greenberg KS, Graim M, He ADDR, Garcia-Barberan V, Gomez Del Pulgar ME, Guaman HM, Benito-Martin A, Picchio V, Pontecorvi V, Dhori X, Bordin A, Floris E, Cozzolino C, Frati G, Pagano F, Chimenti I, De Falco E. Extracell Vesicles Circ Nucl Acids 2025, 6, 128; c) Q. Zhang, T. Ren, K. Cao, Z. Xu, Biosens Bioelectron 2024, 251, 116076; d) V. Picchio, V. Pontecorvi, X. Dhori, A. Bordin, E. Floris, C. Cozzolino, G. Frati, F. Pagano, I. Chimenti, E. De Falco Life Sci 2025, 375, 123752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S, Foser K, Maiese SR, Digumarthy JA, Puig-Butille C, Rebhan, Liu L, Chen X, Petinrin OO, Zhang W, Rahaman S, Tang ZR, Wong KC. 2024, 70, 27; b) O. Ginghina, A. Hudita, M. Zamfir, A. Spanu, M. Mardare, I. Bondoc, L. Buburuzan, S. E. Georgescu, M. Costache, C. Negrei, C. Nitipir, B. Galateanu, Front Oncol 2022, 12, 856575; c) L. Liu, X. Chen, O. O. Petinrin, W. Zhang, S. Rahaman, Z. R. Tang, K. C. Wong Life (Basel) 2021, 11; d) G. Di Sario, V. Rossella, E. S. Famulari, A. Maurizio, D. Lazarevic, F. Giannese, C. Felici, Front Genet 2023, 14, 1152470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welsh JA, Goberdhan DCI, O&#x2019;Driscoll L, Buzas EI, Blenkiron C, Bussolati B, Cai H, Di Vizio D, Driedonks TAP, Erdbrugger U, Falcon-Perez JM, Fu QL, Hill AF, Lenassi M, Lim SK, Mahoney MG, Mohanty S, Moller A, Nieuwland R, Ochiya T, Sahoo S, Torrecilhas AC, Zheng L, Zijlstra A, Abuelreich S, et al. J Extracell Vesicles. 2024;13:e12404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) A, Becker BK, Thakur JM, Weiss HS, Kim H, Peinado D, Lyden, Wang Z, Xie X, Zhou Y, He H, Guo Z, Zhou Z, Liu B, Sun J, Li W, Nie Q, Dai J, Yi W, Zhou X, Yan J, Yang M. 2016, 30, 836; b) Y. J. Liu, C. Wang, Cell Commun Signal 2023, 21, 77; c) Z. Wang, X. Xie, Y. Zhou, H. He, Z. Guo, Z. Zhou, B. Liu, J. Sun, W. Li, Q. Nie, J. Dai, W. Yi, X. Zhou, J. Yan, M. Yang J Extracell Vesicles 2025, 14, e70165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu D, Li Y, Wang M, Gu J, Xu W, Cai H, Fang X, Zhang X. Mol Cancer. 2022;21:56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J, Rak L, Strzadala. 2023, 71, 5; b) S. I. van de Wakker, F. M. Meijers, J. P. G. Sluijter, P. Vader, Pharmacol Rev 2023, 75, 1043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalluri R, LeBleu VS. Science 2020, 367,eaau6977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathieu M, Martin-Jaular L, Lavieu G, Thery C. Nat Cell Biol. 2019;21:9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) IA, Batista JC, Machado SA, Melo. 2024, 10, 947; b) N. C. H. Lau, J. W. P. Yam, Cancers 2023, 15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeppesen DK, Fenix AM, Franklin JL, Higginbotham JN, Zhang Q, Zimmerman LJ, Liebler DC, Ping J, Liu Q, Evans R, Fissell WH, Patton JG, Rome LH, Burnette DT, Coffey RJ. Cell. 2019;177:428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei R, Zhao L, Kong G, Liu X, Zhu S, Zhang S, Min L. Biol Proced Online. 2020;22:12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Jeppesen DK, Higginbotham JN, Franklin JL, Coffey RJ. Nat Protoc. 2023;18:1462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gyorgy B, Paloczi K, Balbisi M, Turiak L, Drahos L, Visnovitz T, Koltai E, Radak Z. Curr Issues Mol Biol. 2024;46:4337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He L, Zhu D, Wang J, Wu X. Int J Mol Med. 2019;43:83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandrasekera D, Shah R, van Hout I, De Jonge W, Bunton R, Parry D, Davis P, Katare R. Nanotheranostics 2023, 7, 345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filipovic L, Spasojevic M, Prodanovic R, Korac A, Matijasevic S, Brajuskovic G, de Marco A, Popovic M. N Biotechnol. 2022;69:36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai J, Wei X, Zhang X, Wu C, Wang Z, Chen M, Wang J. TRAC Trends Anal Chem 2023, 158, 116834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko M, Kim HJ, Park J, Lee H, Lee KN, Kim K, Lee J, Yoon SJ, Kim T, Jeong S, Heo K, Lee YK, Do YR. ACS Appl Mater Interfaces. 2023;15:26069.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Z, Hutchins Z, Li Z, Zhong W. Anal Chem. 2022;94:14083.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch LF, Best T, Wustenhagen E, Adrian K, Rammo O, Saul MJ. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2023;11:1298892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) KS, Visan LY, Wu S, Voss A, Wuethrich A, M&#xf6;ller. Semin. Cancer Biol. 2023, 88, 157; b) A. Hendrix, L. Lippens, C. Pinheiro, C. Th&#xe9;ry, L. Martin-Jaular, J. L&#xf6;tvall, C. L&#xe4;sser, A. F. Hill, K. W. Witwer, Nature Reviews Methods Primers 2023, 3, 56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma V, Nikolajeff F, Kumar S. Transl Neurodegener. 2023;12:7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascucci L, Scattini G. Biochim Biophys Acta Gen Subj. 2021;1865:129648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstrom K, Crescitelli R, Petursson HI, Johansson J, Lasser C, Olofsson R, Bagge. BMC Cancer. 2022;22:50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iha K, Tsurusawa N, Tsai HY, Lin MW, Sonoda H, Watabe S, Yoshimura T, Ito E. Anal Biochem. 2022;654:114831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalaludin I, Lubman DM, Kim J. Mass Spectrom Rev. 2023;42:844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng W, Sun D, Lu W, Yin S, Ye B, Wang X, Ren Y, Hong Z, Zhu W, Yu P, Xi JJ, Yao B. Anal Chem. 2023;95:10625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) L, Chitoiu A, Dobranici M, Gherghiceanu S, Dinescu M, Costache IJM, Wang T, Ng CY, Ng BZJ, Toh WS, Hui JHP, Ding T, Diao Y, Fu R, Gong C, He Q, He W, Zhang L, Yang X, Zeng X, Yu L, Liu J, Shi W, Zhang K, Hao X. 2020, 21; b) P. P. Dakup, I. D. Ludovico, Y. You, C. Rao, J. Flores, L. M. Bramer, M. Rewers, B. M. Webb-Robertson, T. O. Metz, R. G. Mirmira, E. K. Sims, E. S. Nakayasu, Proteomics 2025. https://doi.org/10.1002/pmic.70036e70036; c) T. Wang, C. Y. Ng, B. Z. J. Ng, W. S. Toh, J. H. P. Hui, Burns Trauma 2025, 13, tkaf023; d) F. A. San Lucas, K. Allenson, V. Bernard, J. Castillo, D. U. Kim, K. Ellis, E. A. Ehli, G. E. Davies, J. L. Petersen, D. Li, R. Wolff, M. Katz, G. Varadhachary, I. Wistuba, A. Maitra, H. Alvarez, Ann Oncol 2016, 27, 635; e) T. Ding, Y. Diao, R. Fu, C. Gong, Q. He, W. He, L. Zhang, X. Yang, X. Zeng, L. Yu, J. Liu, W. Shi, K. Zhang, X. Hao J Adv Res 2025, DOI: 10.1016/j.jare.2025.09.056IF: 13.0 Q1 B1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chitti SV, Gummadi S, Kang T, Shahi S, Marzan AL, Nedeva C, Sanwlani R, Bramich K, Stewart S, Petrovska M, Sen B, Ozkan A, Akinfenwa M, Fonseka P, Mathivanan S. Nucleic Acids Res. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkad1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keerthikumar S, Chisanga D, Ariyaratne D, Al Saffar H, Anand S, Zhao K, Samuel M, Pathan M, Jois M, Chilamkurti N, Gangoda L, Mathivanan S. J Mol Biol. 2016;428:688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) T, Liu Q, Zhang J, Zhang C, Li YR, Miao Q, Lei Q, Li AY, Guo. 2019, 47, D89; b) G.-Y. Xie, D. Song, T. Luo, Y. Liao, A.-Y. Guo, Q. Lei, Nucleic Acids Research 2025. https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkaf1054</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai H, Li Y, Zhang H, Hu J, Liao J, Su Y, Li Q, Chen B, Li C, Wang Z, Li Y, Wang J, Meng Z, Huang Z, Huang S. Nucleic Acids Res. 2022;50:D118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DK, Lee J, Kim SR, Choi DS, Yoon YJ, Kim JH, Go G, Nhung D, Hong K, Jang SC, Kim SH, Park KS, Kim OY, Park HT, Seo JH, Aikawa E, Baj-Krzyworzeka M, van Balkom BW, Belting M, Blanc L, Bond V, Bongiovanni A et al. F. E. Borras, L. Buee, E. I. Buzas,., Bioinformatics 2015, 31, 933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) EB, Gencer YK, Lor F, Abomaray S, El Andaloussi M, Pernemalm N, Sharma DW, Hagey A, Gorgens MO, Gustafsson K, Le Blanc M, Asad Toonsi L, Walther-Jallow C, Gotherstrom, Li J, Yu S, Rao M, Cheng B. 2024, 15, 77; b) T. Lokumcu, M. Iskar, M. Schneider, D. Helm, G. Klinke, L. Schlicker, F. Bethke, G. Muller, K. Richter, G. Poschet, E. Phillips, V. Goidts, ACS Nano 2024, 18, 2500; c) J. Li, S. Yu, M. Rao, B. Cheng Front Immunol 2025, 16, 1548535.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) M, Bayat JS, Nahand MC, Kuang L, Wu L, Li Y, Tan Y, Luo X, Lv W, Hu W, Zhao C, Xiong M, Yi Y, Wang D, Wang Y, Wang H, Wu Y, Zhang Q. Mol Cancer 2025, 24, 45; c) S. Rahmati, A. Moeinafshar, N. Rezaei, J Transl Med 2024, 22, 452; d) Y. Tan, X. Luo, W. Lv, W. Hu, C. Zhao, M. Xiong, Y. Yi, D. Wang, Y. Wang, H. Wang, Y. Wu, Q. Zhang Cell Death Dis 2021, 12, 547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Q, Zhu Y, Huang Q, Yang F, Liu, Shi X, Zhao X, Xue J, Jia E. 2021, 171; b) L. A. Ovchinnikova, Y. A. Lomakin, Acta Naturae 2025, 17, 28; c) X. Shi, X. Zhao, J. Xue, E. Jia BMC Cancer 2024, 24, 623; d) V. De Giorgis, E. Barberis, M. Manfredi, Seminars in Cancer Biology 2024, 104&#x2013;105, 18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) E, Lazaro-Ibanez C, Lasser GV, Shelke R, Crescitelli SC, Jang A, Cvjetkovic A, Garcia-Rodriguez J, Lotvall JEV, Lin B, Jiao Z, Dong S, Yan W, Jiang J, Du Y, Weng X, Wang H, Hu Z, Liu Y, Zhou X. Nat Commun 2025, 16, 8084; c) T. Tsering, A. Nadeau, T. Wu, K. Dickinson, J. V. Burnier, Cell Death Dis 2024, 15, 668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giancaterino S, Boi C. Biotechnol Adv. 2023;63:108092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) RC, Pink EM, Beaman P, Samuel SA, Brooks DRF, Carter. 2022, 126, 323; b) J. Li, A. Wang, H. Guo, W. Zheng, R. Chen, C. Miao, D. Zheng, J. Peng, J. Wang, Z. Chen, Theranostics 2025, 15, 5277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) E, Youssef D, Palmer B, Fletcher R, Vaughn, Fusco C, De Rosa G, Spatocco I, Vitiello E, Procaccini C, Frige C, Pellegrini V, La Grotta R, Furlan R, Matarese G, Prattichizzo F, de Candia P. 2025, 17; b) H. S. Ilamathi, G. Rinaldo, O. P. Wiklander, Cancer Lett 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.canlet.2025.217976217976; c) C. Fusco, G. De Rosa, I. Spatocco, E. Vitiello, C. Procaccini, C. Frige, V. Pellegrini, R. La Grotta, R. Furlan, G. Matarese, F. Prattichizzo, P. de Candia J Extracell Vesicles 2024, 13, e12433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S, Ayala-Mar J, Donoso-Quezada J, Gonzalez-Valdez JIR, Ma F, Liu X, Zhang Y, Tao Y, Zhao L, Abusalamah H, Huffman C, Harbison RA, Puram SV, Wang Y, Peng G. Sci Transl Med 2025, 17, eadm7269; c) N. Schone, M. Kemper, K. Menck, G. Evers, C. Krekeler, A. B. Schulze, G. Lenz, E. Wardelmann, C. Binder, A. Bleckmann, J Extracell Vesicles 2024, 13, e12418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) HI, Kim J, Park Y, Zhu X, Wang Y, Han D, Zhang, Ma Y, Wei W, Yang Z, Zhou Y, Dong T, Wang T, Xia X, Ma Y, Zhou M, Gao Y, Yu B, Wang C, Ruan L, Hong K, Gu C. 2024, 56, 836; b) G. Xu, J. Jin, Z. Fu, G. Wang, X. Lei, J. Xu, J. Wang, Signal Transduct Target Ther 2025, 10, 255; c) Y. Ma, W. Wei, Z. Yang, Y. Zhou, T. Dong, T. Wang, X. Xia, Y. Ma, M. Zhou, Y. Gao, B. Yu, C. Wang, L. Ruan, K. Hong, C. Gu Mol Ther 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ymthe.2025.11.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) R, Kar R, Dhar S, Mukherjee S, Nag S, Gorai N, Mukerjee D, Mukherjee R, Vatsa M, Chandrakanth Jadhav A, Ghosh A, Devi A, Krishnan ND, Thorat. 2023, 9, 577; b) J. Li, Y. Zhang, P. Y. Dong, G. M. Yang, S. Gurunathan, Biomed Pharmacother 2023, 165, 115087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) M, Ahn JG, Mun Y, Han JH, Seo FI, Mir R, Baba SK, Elfaki I, Algehainy N, Alanazi MA, Altemani FH, Tayeb FJ, Barnawi J, Husain E, Bedaiwi RI, Albalawi IA, Alhujaily M, Mir MM, Almotairi R, Alatwi HE, Albalawi AD, Kumar SK, Baba HQ, Sadida SA, Marzooqi J, Jerobin FH, Altemani N, Algehainy MA, Alanazi AB, Abou-Samra R, Kumar AS, Al-Shabeeb Akil. J Cancer 2024, 15, 6383; c) F. Xie, X. Zhou, M. Fang, H. Li, P. Su, Y. Tu, L. Zhang, F. Zhou, Adv Sci (Weinh) 2019, 6, 1901779; d) M. A. Kumar, S. K., Baba, H. Q., Sadida, S. A., Marzooqi, J., Jerobin, F. H., Altemani, N., Algehainy, M. A., Alanazi, A. B., Abou-Samra, R., Kumar, A. S., Al-Shabeeb Akil M. A. Macha, R. Mir, A. A. Bhat, Signal Transduct Target Ther 2024, 9, 27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He G, Liu J, Yu Y, Wei S, Peng X, Yang L, Li H. Cancer Lett. 2024;593:216960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S, Chakraborty G, Sharma S, Karmakar S, Banerjee, Heo YJ, Hwa C, Lee GH, Park JM. 2024, 1870, 167120; b) O. Menyhart, B. Gyorffy, Comput Struct Biotechnol J 2021, 19, 949; c) Y. J. Heo, C. Hwa, G. H. Lee, J. M. Park J. Y. An, Mol Cells 2021, 44, 433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) M, Catalano A, D&#x2019;Angelo F, De Logu R, Nassini D, Generali G, Roviello. 2025, 19, 1; b) S. Li, Y. Peng, M. Chen, Y. Zhao, Y. Xiong, J. Li, P. Luo, H. Wang, F. Zhao, Q. Zhao, Y. Cui, S. Chen, J. G. Zhou, S. Wang, Commun Biol 2024, 7, 1200; c) R. Vitorino, Proteomes 2024, 12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) AR, Baiao Z, Cai RC, Poulos PJ, Robinson RR, Reddel Q, Zhong S, Vinga E, Goncalves, Rahnenfuhrer J, De Bin R, Benner A, Ambrogi F, Lusa L, Boulesteix AL, Migliavacca E, Binder H, Michiels S, Sauerbrei W, McShane L. 2025, 26; b) E. Hernandez-Lemus, S. Ochoa, Front Genet 2024, 15, 1425456; c) J. Rahnenfuhrer, R. De Bin, A. Benner, F. Ambrogi, L. Lusa, A. L. Boulesteix, E. Migliavacca, H. Binder, S. Michiels, W. Sauerbrei, L. McShane S. i. for topic group High-dimensional data of the, BMC Med 2023, 21, 182; d) Y. Yu, Y. Mai, Y. Zheng, L. Shi, Genome Biol 2024, 25, 254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) D, Acharya A, Mukhopadhyay BFG, Wei L, Niraula D, Gates EDH, Fu J, Luo Y, Nyflot MJ, Bowen SR, El Naqa IM, Cui S. Br J Radiol 2023, 96, 20230211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J, Jovel R, Greiner. 2021, 8, 771607; b) J. Zhang, Y. Che, R. Liu, Z. Wang, W. Liu, Brief Bioinform 2025, 26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) G, Obaido ID, Mienye OF, Egbelowo ID, Emmanuel A, Ogunleye B, Ogbuokiri P, Mienye K, Aruleba. 2024, 17; b) T. Jiang, J. L. Gradus, A. J. Rosellini, Behav Ther 2020, 51, 675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) VB, Gladshiya S, Eckhardt CM, Madjarova SJ, Williams RJ, Ollivier M, Karlsson J, Pareek A, Nwachukwu BU. in Reshaping Intelligent Business and Industry, https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119905202.ch6 2024, p. 97; b) D. Valkenborg, A. J. Rousseau, M. Geubbelmans, T. Burzykowski, Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop 2023, 163, 877; c) C. M. Eckhardt, S. J. Madjarova, R. J. Williams, M. Ollivier, J. Karlsson, A. Pareek, B. U. Nwachukwu Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 2023, 31, 376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) M, Sheikh Hassani JR, Green HG, Bashiri FS, Caskey JR, Mayampurath A, Dussault N, Dumanian J, Bhavani SV, Carey KA, Gilbert ER, Winslow CJ, Shah NS, Edelson DP, Afshar M, Churpek MM. J Am Med Inform Assoc 2022, 29, 1696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) MLLLP, Kaelbling AW, Moore. 1996, 4, 237; b) J. Kober, J. A. Bagnell, J. Peters, 2013, 32, 1238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) SL, Cessie JCV, Houwelingen. 1992, 41, 191; b) J. Lu, X. Lu, Y. Wang, H. Zhang, L. Han, B. Zhu, B. Wang, Sci Rep 2025, 15, 15361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) A, Kirpich EA, Ainsworth JM, Wedow JRB, Newman G, Michailidis LM, McIntyre, Gonzales GB, De Saeger S. 2018, 13, e0197910; b) J. Ranstam, J. A. Cook, British Journal of Surgery 2018, 105, 1348; c) G. B. Gonzales, S. De Saeger Sci Rep 2018, 8, 3659; d) D. H. Kadir, N. H. Mahmood, Cihan University-Erbil Scientific Journal 2025, 9, 14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) A, Acharjee J, Larkman Y, Xu VR, Cardoso GV, Gkoutos BMCMG, Paul A, Mukherjee DP, Das P, Gangopadhyay A, Chintha AR, Kundu S, Chen L, Yuan X, Yang J, Xu Y, Shen L, Huang Y, Wang B, Yu F. IEEE Trans Image Process 2018, 27, 4012; c) T. Inoue, D. Ichikawa, T. Ueno, M. Cheong, T. Inoue, W. D. Whetstone, T. Endo, K. Nizuma, T. Tominaga, Neurotrauma Rep 2020, 1, 8; d) J. Shi, L. Chen, X. Yuan, J. Yang, Y. Xu, L. Shen, Y. Huang, B. Wang, F. Yu Front Immunol 2025, 16, 1574003; e) R. Rivera-Lopez, J. Canul-Reich, E. Mezura-Montes, M. A. Cruz-Ch&#xe1;vez, Swarm and Evolutionary Computation 2022, 69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) D, Bzdok M, Krzywinski N, Altman. 2018, 15, 5; b) S. Huang, N. Cai, P. P. Pacheco, S. Narrandes, Y. Wang, W. Xu, Cancer Genomics Proteomics 2018, 15, 41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) X, Wang C, Su. 2025, 17, 2089; b) M. Zubair, A. H. Khan, S. F. Bilal, J. Li, Brief Bioinform 2025, 26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S, Steyaert YL, Qiu Y, Zheng P, Mukherjee H, Vogel O, Gevaert. 2023, 3, 44; b) H. Yang, M. Yang, J. Chen, G. Yao, Q. Zou, L. Jia, Brief Bioinform 2024, 26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Z, Yang R, Kotoge X, Piao Z, Chen L, Zhu P, Gao Y, Matsubara Y, Sakurai J, Sun, Pudjihartono N, Fadason T, Kempa-Liehr AW, J. M. O&#x2019;, Sullivan. 2025, 12, 913; b) Y. Perez-Riverol, M. Kuhn, J. A. Vizcaino, M. P. Hitz, E. Audain, PLoS One 2017, 12, e0189875; c) N. Pudjihartono, T. Fadason, A. W. Kempa-Liehr, J. M. O&#x2019;Sullivan Front Bioinform 2022, 2, 927312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S, Arun M, Grosheva M, Kosenko JL, Robertus O, Blyuss R, Gabe D, Munblit J, Offman, Sammut SJ, Crispin-Ortuzar M, Chin SF, Provenzano E, Bardwell HA, Ma W, Cope W, Dariush A, Dawson SJ, Abraham JE, Dunn J, Hiller L, Thomas J, Cameron DA, Bartlett JMS, Hayward L, Pharoah PD, Markowetz F, Rueda OM, H. M. Earl, Caldas C. NPJ Precis Oncol 2025, 9, 166; b) L. Marconi, F. Cabitza, Int J Med Inform 2025, 202, 105970; c) S. J. Sammut, M. Crispin-Ortuzar, S. F. Chin, E. Provenzano, H. A. Bardwell, W. Ma, W. Cope, A. Dariush, S. J. Dawson, J. E. Abraham, J. Dunn, L. Hiller, J. Thomas, D. A. Cameron, J. M. S. Bartlett, L. Hayward, P. D. Pharoah, F. Markowetz, O. M. Rueda, H. M. Earl, C. Caldas Nature 2022, 601, 623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S-AN, Alexandropoulos SB, Kotsiantis MN, Vrahatis, Reich C, Ostropolets A, Ryan P, Rijnbeek P, Schuemie M, Davydov A, Dymshyts D, Hripcsak G. 2019, 34, e1; b) V. &#xc7;etin, O. Y&#x131;ld&#x131;z, Pamukkale University Journal of Engineering Sciences 2022, 28, 299; c) C. Reich, A. Ostropolets, P. Ryan, P. Rijnbeek, M. Schuemie, A. Davydov, D. Dymshyts, G. Hripcsak J Am Med Inform Assoc 2024, 31, 583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) HWH, Hui W, Kong WWB, Goh. 2024, 25; b) H. Voss, S. Schlumbohm, P. Barwikowski, M. Wurlitzer, M. Dottermusch, P. Neumann, H. Schluter, J. E. Neumann, C. Krisp, Nat Commun 2022, 13, 3523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) A, Demircioglu II, Tasci E, Zhuge Y, Camphausen K, Krauze AV, Salmi M, Atif D, Oliva D, Abraham A, Ventura S. Cancers (Basel) 2022, 14; c) A. Moscovich, S. Rosset, Journal of the Royal Statistical Society Series B: Statistical Methodology 2022, 84, 1474; d) M. Salmi, D. Atif, D. Oliva, A. Abraham, S. Ventura Artificial Intelligence Review 2024, 57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeys Y, Inza I, Larranaga P. Bioinformatics 2007, 23, 2507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remeseiro B, Bolon-Canedo V. Comput Biol Med. 2019;112:103375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Y, Li U, Mansmann S, Du R, Hornung. 2022, 23, 412; b) M. Piles, R. Bergsma, D. Gianola, H. Gilbert, L. Tusell, Front Genet 2021, 12, 611506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) C, Meng OA, Zeleznik GG, Thallinger B, Kuster AM, Gholami AC, Culhane. 2016, 17, 628; b) D. Paul, S. Chakraborty, S. Das, IEEE Trans Neural Netw Learn Syst 2024, 35, 16788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) A, Elguoshy H, Zedan S, Saito. 2025, 15; b) Y. Yang, H. Sun, Y. Zhang, T. Zhang, J. Gong, Y. Wei, Y. G. Duan, M. Shu, Y. Yang, D. Wu, D. Yu, Cell Rep 2021, 36, 109442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) TJ, Bradshaw Z, Huemann J, Hu A, Rahmim, Walsh. 2023, 5, e220232; b) D. Lilek, D. Zimmermann, L. Steininger, M. Musso, Bodo D. Wilts, S. Gamsjaeger, D. R. Hermann, C. Wiesner, A. Gr&#xfc;nfelder, B. Herbinger, K. Prohaska, Journal of Raman Spectroscopy 2025, 56, 867; c) D. Wilimitis, C. G. Walsh JMIR AI 2023, 2, e49023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyerberg EW, Vickers AJ, Cook NR, Gerds T, Gonen M, Obuchowski N, Pencina MJ, Kattan MW. Epidemiology 2010, 21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) CM, Ardila AM, Vivares-Builes E, Pineda-V&#xe9;lez OD, Thelagathoti RK, Chandel DS, Tom WA, Jiang C, Krzyzanowski G, Olou A, Fernando MR, Ogutu S, Mohammed M, Mwambi H. Bioengineering (Basel) 2025, 12; c) S. A. Hicks, I. Strumke, V. Thambawita, M. Hammou, M. A. Riegler, P. Halvorsen, S. Parasa, Sci Rep 2022, 12, 5979; d) S. Ogutu, M. Mohammed, H. Mwambi Discover Artificial Intelligence 2025, 5; e) S. Parvandeh, H. W. Yeh, M. P. Paulus, B. A. McKinney, Bioinformatics 2020, 36, 3093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) LEM, Tideman LG, Migas KV, Djambazova NH, Patterson RM, Caprioli JM, Spraggins R, Van de Plas. 2021, 1177, 338522; b) Y. Song, D. Zhang, Q. Wang, Y. Liu, K. Chen, J. Sun, L. Shi, B. Li, X. Yang, W. Mi, J. Cao, Transl Psychiatry 2024, 14, 57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Z, Cai RC, Poulos J, Liu Q, Zhong. 2022, 25, 103798; b) G. Nicora, F. Vitali, A. Dagliati, N. Geifman, R. Bellazzi, Front Oncol 2020, 10, 1030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S, Hormaty AN, Seiwan BH, Rasheed H, Parvaz A, Gharahzadeh H, Ghaznavi. Cancer Med 2025, 14, e71224; b) S. Kareem, Asia-Pacific Journal of Oncology 2025. https://doi.org/10.32948/ajo.2025.05.25</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) F, Shang M, Huang Y, Ji S, Zhang C, Fan K, Zhang Y, Fang X, Li L, Gu Z, Guan J, Jiang ASO, Glaab E, Rauschenberger A, Banzi R, Gerardi C, Garcia P, Demotes J. BMJ Open 2021, 11, e053674; c) X. Shao, S. Gao, P. Bai, Q. Yang, Y. Lin, M. Pang, W. Wu, L. Wang, Y. Li, S. Zhou, H. Liu, P. Yu, Clin Transl Med 2025, 15, e70133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) P, Forouzannezhad D, Maes DS, Hippe P, Thammasorn R, Iranzad J, Han C, Duan X, Liu S, Wang WA, Chaovalitwongse J, Zeng SR, Bowen, Bodalal Z, van den Broek D, Haanen JBAG, Beets-Tan RGH, Trebeschi S. 2022, 14; b) C. Jin, H. Yu, J. Ke, P. Ding, Y. Yi, X. Jiang, X. Duan, J. Tang, D. T. Chang, X. Wu, F. Gao, R. Li, Nat Commun 2021, 12, 1851; c) M. Yeghaian, Z. Bodalal, D. van den Broek, J. B. A. G. Haanen, R. G. H. Beets-Tan, S. Trebeschi M. A. J. van Gerven, Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association 2025, 32, 1267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) A, Ahmad R, Nabi D, Shehwar, Lobato-Delgado B, Priego-Torres B, Sanchez-Morillo D. 2025, 57, 2723; b) E. Fountzilas, T. Pearce, M. A. Baysal, A. Chakraborty, A. M. Tsimberidou, NPJ Digit Med 2025, 8, 75; c) B. Lobato-Delgado, B. Priego-Torres, D. Sanchez-Morillo Cancers (Basel) 2022, 14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagh B, Verma N, Setia A, Rani K, Randhave NV, Kumar V, Vaishali AK, Malik MS, Muthu. J Drug Deliv Sci Technol 2025, 113,107340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J, Hedou I, Maric G, Bellan J, Einhaus DK, Gaudilliere FX, Ladant F, Verdonk IA, Stelzer D, Feyaerts AS, Tsai EA, Ganio M, Sabayev J, Gillard J, Amar A, Cambriel TT, Oskotsky A, Roldan JL, Golob M, Sirota TA, Bonham M, Sato M, Diop X, Durand MS, Angst DK, Stevenson et al. Nat Biotechnol 2024, 42, 1581; b) J. Labory, E. Njomgue-Fotso, S. Bottini, Comput Struct Biotechnol J 2024, 23, 1274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) M, Aldea L, Friboulet S, Apcher F, Jaulin F, Mosele T, Sourisseau JC, Soria S, Nikolaev F, Andre. 2023, 8, 101642; b) M. Lin, J. Guo, Z. Gu, W. Tang, H. Tao, S. You, D. Jia, Y. Sun, P. Jia, J Transl Med 2025, 23, 388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) A, Morabito G, De Simone R, Pastorelli L, Brunelli M, Ferrario J, Flores DM, Claborne ZD, Weller BM, Webb-Robertson KM, Waters LM, Bramer. Transl Med 2025, 23, 425; b) A. Tiwari, Widodo, D. I. Krisnawati, K. Y. Tzou, T. R. Kuo, J Nanobiotechnology 2026, DOI: 10.1186/s12951-025-03952-4;IF: 12.6 Q1 B1 c) J. E. Flores, D. M., Claborne, Z. D., Weller, B. M., Webb-Robertson, K. M., Waters, L. M., Bramer 2023, 6, 1098308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) R, Tibshirani. 1996, 58, 267; b) H. Zou, T. Hastie, Journal of the Royal Statistical Society Series B: Statistical Methodology 2005, 67, 301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breiman a)L. 2001, 45, 5; b) T. Chen, C. Guestrin, in Proceedings of the 22nd ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining, https://doi.org/10.1145/2939672.2939785, 2016, 785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes C, Vapnik V. Mach Learn. 1995;20:273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe9;o EO, Grinsztajn, Ga&#xeb;l, Varoquaux. arXiv 2022, 2207.08815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) C, Strobl AL, Boulesteix T, Kneib T, Augustin A, Zeileis. 2008, 9, 307; b) C. Strobl, A. L. Boulesteix, A. Zeileis, T. Hothorn, BMC Bioinformatics 2007, 8, 25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) JG, Lijmer BW, Mol S, Heisterkamp GJ, Bonsel MH, Prins JHP, van der Meulen PMM, Bossuyt. JAMA 1999, 282, 1061; b) F. Ransohoff David, R. Feinstein Alvan, New England Journal of Medicine 1978, 299, 926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins GS, Moons KGM, Dhiman P, Riley RD, Beam AL, Van Calster B, Ghassemi M, Liu X, Reitsma JB, van Smeden M, Boulesteix AL, Camaradou JC, Celi LA, Denaxas S, Denniston AK, Glocker B, Golub RM, Harvey H, Heinze G, Hoffman MM, Kengne AP, Lam E, Lee N et al. E. W. Loder, L. Maier-Hein,., BMJ 2024, 385, e078378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rappoport N, Shamir R. Nucleic Acids Res. 2018;46:10546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) I, Casanova-Salas D, Aguilar S, Cordoba-Terreros L, Agundez J, Brandariz N, Herranz A, Mas M, Gonzalez R, Morales-Barrera A, Sierra M, Soriano-Navarro P, Cresta G, Mir S, Simonetti G, Rodrigues S, Arce-Gallego L, Delgado-Serrano I, Agusti E, Castellano-Sanz R, Mast M, de Albert A, Celma A, Santamaria L, Gonzalez N, Castro, Yin S, Chen A, Ding Y, Song J, Chen R, Zhang P, Yang C. Cancer Cell 2024, 42, 1301; b) Y. Ciani, C. Nardella, F. Demichelis, Cancer Cell 2024, 42, 1160; c) S. Yin, A. Chen, Y. Ding, J. Song, R. Chen, P. Zhang, C. Yang TrAC, Trends Anal. Chem. 2023, 158; d) Y. Li, S. Sui, A. Goel, Semin Cancer Biol 2024, 99, 5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding T, Diao Y, Fu R, Gong C, He Q, He W, Zhang L, Yang X, Zeng X, Yu L, Liu J, Shi W, Zhang K, Hao X. Journal of Advanced Research 2025, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jare.2025.09.056</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura K, Zhu Z, Roy S, Jun E, Han H, Munoz RM, Nishiwada S, Sharma G, Cridebring D, Zenhausern F, Kim S, Roe DJ, Darabi S, Han IW, Evans DB, Yamada S, Demeure MJ, Becerra C, Celinski SA, Borazanci E, Tsai S, Kodera Y, Park JO, Bolton JS, Wang X et al. Gastroenterology 2022, 163, 1252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu S, Li Y, Liao Z, Wang Z, Wang Z, Li Y, Qian L, Zhao J, Zong H, Kang B, Zou WB, Chen K, He X, Meng Z, Chen Z, Huang S, Wang P. Gut 2020, 69, 540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko J, Bhagwat N, Black T, Yee SS, Na YJ, Fisher S, Kim J, Carpenter EL, Stanger BZ, Issadore D. Cancer Res. 2018;78:3688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu SC, Zhang H. World J Gastrointest Oncol. 2025;17:111670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai ZR, Zheng YQ, Hu Y, Ma MY, Wu YJ, Liu J, Yang LP, Zheng JB, Tian T, Hu PS, Liu ZX, Zhang L, Xu RH, Ju HQ. Gut 2025, 74, 884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo B, Kim YI, Lee M, Lim SB, Shin Y. J Extracell Vesicles. 2025;14:e70088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Liu X, Peng C, Du R, Hong X, Xu J, Chen J, Li X, Tang Y, Li Y, Liu Y, Xu C, Liu D. ACS Nano. 2025;19:10013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostanci E, Kocak E, Unal M, Guzel MS, Acici K, Asuroglu T. Sens (Basel) 2023, 23(6), 3080.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo T, Tang XH, Gao XY, Zhou Y, Jin B, Deng ZQ, Hu Y, Xing XF, Li ZY, Ji JF. Mol Cancer. 2022;21:216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Zhang J, Zhang W, Wang Y, Zhai Y, Li Y, Li W, Chang J, Zhao X, Huang M, Geng Q, Yang Y, Gong Z, Yu N, Shen W, Li Q, Huang S, Guo W. Mol Cancer. 2023;22:199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K, Lin Y, Zhou Y, Xiong X, Wang L, Li J, Zhou F, Guo Y, Chen S, Chen Y, Tang H, Qiu X, Cai S, Zhang D, Bremer E, Jim SC, Yeung H, Zhang. Gastroenterology 2023, 165, 932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez-Martin C, Drees EEE, van Eijndhoven MAJ, Groenewegen NJ, Wang S, Verkuijlen S, van Weering JRT, Aparicio-Puerta E, Bosch L, Frerichs KA, Verkleij CPM, Kersten MJ, Zijlstra JM, de Jong D, Groothuis-Oudshoorn CGM, Hackenberg M, de Rooij JR, N. van de Donk, D. M., Pegtel. Cell Rep Med 2025, 6, 102358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J, Li Q, Hu J, Yu H, Shen Y, Lai H, Li Q, Zhang H, Li Y, Fang Z, Huang S. Genome Med. 2024;16:126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Sun B, Yu Y, Lu J, Lou Y, Qian F, Chen T, Zhang L, Yang J, Zhong H, Wu L, Han B. NPJ Precis Oncol. 2024;8:50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar SK, Kanaparthi N, Annes SB, Bendre RV, Balakrishna N, Kumar S, Hakeem AH, Sasidhar MV. Sci Rep. 2025;15:38310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Wang C, Chen S, Wei C, Ji J, Liu Y, Liang L, Chen Y, Li X, Zhao L, Shi X, Fang Y, Lu W, Li T, Liu Z, Lu W, Li T, Hu X, Li M, Liu F, He X, Wen J, Wang Z, Zhou W, Chen Z, et al. Mol Cancer. 2025;24:60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang L, Pang D, Wang C, Lin J, Chen S, Wu J, Cui J. Front Immunol. 2025;16:1630794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Y, Zhang W, Lu W, Feng Y, Wu X, Zhuo Z, Zhang D, Zhang Y. Front Immunol. 2024;15:1228235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yap JYY, Goh LSH, Lim AJW, Chong SS, Lim LJ, Lee CG. Cancers (Basel) 2023, 15(14), 3749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi K, Zhang Z, Chen P, Xi X, Zhao X, Rong Y, Long F, Zhang Q, Zhang Y, Gao M, Liu W, Liu BF, Zhu Z, Wang F. Biosens Bioelectron. 2025;276:117228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y, Wang S, Xi X, Zhang M, Liu X, Tang W, Cai P, Xing S, Bao P, Jin Y, Zhao W, Chen Y, Zhao H, Jia X, Lu S, Lu Y, Chen L, Yin J, Lu ZJ. Theranostics 2021, 11, 181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Li B, Lin H, Yang C, Guo J, Cui B, Pan W, Feng J, Luo T, Chu F, Xu X, Zheng L, Yao S. Biosens Bioelectron. 2021;194:113615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G, Wang H, Zhong J, Bai Y, Chen W, Jiang K, Huang J, Shao Y, Liu J, Gong Y, Zhang J, Sun R, Wei T, Gong R, Zhu J, Lu Z, Li Z, Lei J. Br J Cancer. 2024;130:925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang XW, Qi GX, Liu MX, Yang YF, Wang JH, Yu YL, Chen S. ACS Sens. 2024;9:1555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) JG, Lijmer BW, Mol S, Heisterkamp GJ, Bonsel MH, Prins JH, van der Meulen PM, Bossuyt, Singh S, Gupta S. 1999, 282, 1061; b) G. Putcha, A. Gutierrez, S. Skates, JCO Precis Oncol 2021, 5, 574; c) S. Singh, S. Gupta Gastroenterology 2022, 163, 1155; d) J. A. Usher-Smith, S. J. Sharp, S. J. Griffin, BMJ 2016, 353, i3139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Q, Su H, Li J, Lyon C, Tang W, Wan M, Hu TY. Precis Clin Med. 2020;3:54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan Y, Kao WC, Boppart M, Sweedler JV. J Proteome Res. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jproteome.5c00316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh M, Tiwari PK, Kashyap V, Kumar S. Proteomes 2025, 13(1), 12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoshino A, Kim HS, Bojmar L, Gyan KE, Cioffi M, Hernandez J, Zambirinis CP, Rodrigues G, Molina H, Heissel S, Mark MT, Steiner L, Benito-Martin A, Lucotti S, Di Giannatale A, Offer K, Nakajima M, Williams C, Nogues L, Pelissier Vatter FA, Hashimoto A, Davies AE, Freitas D, Kenific CM, Ararso Y et al. Cell 2020, 182, 1044.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai C, Xie F, Xu J, Yang Y, Zheng W, Hu H, Ding X, Yu H. J Extracell Vesicles. 2023;12:e12391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bingrui FGK, Li. Raghu Kalluri, eLife 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lapitz A, Azkargorta M, Milkiewicz P, Olaizola P, Zhuravleva E, Grimsrud MM, Schramm C, Arbelaiz A, O&#x2019;Rourke CJ, La Casta A, Milkiewicz M, Pastor T, Vesterhus M, Jimenez-Aguero R, Dill MT, Lamarca A, Valle JW, Macias RIR, Izquierdo-Sanchez L, Perez Castano Y, Caballero-Camino FJ, Riano I, Krawczyk M, Ibarra C et al. J. Bustamante,., J Hepatol 2023, 79, 93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin H, Xie J, Xing S, Lu X, Yu Y, Ren Y, Tao J, He G, Zhang L, Yuan X, Yang Z, Huang Z. Cell Rep Med. 2024;5:101689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Z, Deng C, Ma C, He G, Tao J, Zhang L, Hu X, Mo Y, Qiu L, Zhang N, Luo C, Xing S, Xie J, Yin H. Int J Surg. 2024;110:4672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Gu CZ, Wang PX, Xian JR, Wang H, Shang AQ, Zhong YC, Zheng WJ, Cheng JW, Yang WJ, Zhou J, Fan J, Guo W, Yang XR, Lu HJ. Cell Rep Med. 2025;6:102090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Jia Y, Li Z, Zhang Y, Wang C, Liang Y, Qiu J, Sun M, Chen X, Huang M, Zhang Y, Wang J, Liu H, Mao C, Han L. Adv Sci (Weinh). 2025. https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202506167e06167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinik Y, Ortega FG, Mills GB, Lu Y, Jurkowicz M, Halperin S, Aharoni M, Gutman M, Lev S. Sci Adv 2020, 6, eaba5714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyon JY, Kim MW, Hyun KA, Yang Y, Ha S, Kim JY, Kim Y, Park S, Gawk H, Lee H, Lee S, Moon S, Han EH, Kim JY, Yang JY, Jung HI, Kim SI, Chung YH. J Extracell Vesicles. 2025;14:e70089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu G, Huang R, Wumaier R, Lyu J, Huang M, Zhang Y, Chen Q, Liu W, Tao M, Li J, Tao Z, Yu B, Xu E, Wang L, Yu G, Gires O, Zhou L, Zhu W, Ding C, Wang H. Cancer Res. 2024;84:3267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han L, Song Y, Tong L, Sun J, Zhang X, Chen S, Li Y, Wang Z, Gao L, Zhu Q, Chao Y, Wang X, Zhang G, Zhu W, He L, Liu J, Wang Q, Wu Z, Ji Y, Bai C, Lv X, Zhou J. J Extracell Vesicles. 2025;14:e70129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan Y, Jiang H, Xue R, Feng XJ, Liu BF, Li L, Peng B, Ren CS, Li SM, Li N, Li M, Wang DB, Zhang XE. J Extracell Vesicles. 2025;14:e70078.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Y, Bu A, Han S, Ding Y, Zhang H, Sun J, Deng Y, Ma J, Wang S, Gu Y, Chang W, Gu Z, Xie Z, Hu L, Zhang Y. Angew Chem Int Ed Engl. 2025;64:e202509399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng W, Zhang Y, Wang X, Wang S, Lin T, Su T, Jin Y, Yuan Y, Luo M, Zhong Y, Li L, Zhang D, Gong M, Cheng J, Liu J, Liu S, Wang W, Yang L, Yang H. ACS Nano. 2025;19:15896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan YP, Zhang YT, Zhang G, Ma L, Lv Y, Li J, Luan Y, Zhang YX, Chen YT, Ren HY, Liu W, Li MH, Wu YX, Chen S, Han B, Tang QY, Chen LH, Wesselius A, Su WC, Zeegers MP, Gu Y, Qin QR, Hao H, Xia J, Zhang H, et al. Anal Chem. 2025;97:17368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang L, Sun F, Wang H, Hu Z. Pharmacol Ther. 2021;224:107827.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Y, Zhang F, Liang D, Zhang S, Qi Y, Liu. 2023, 157, 114046; b) P. Espiau-Romera, A. Gordo-Ortiz, I. Ortiz-de-Solorzano, P. Sancho, Extracell Vesicles Circ Nucl Acids 2024, 5, 455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngan H-L, Lam K-Y, Li Z, Zhang J, Cai Z. TRAC Trends Anal Chem 2023, 168, 117333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Huang C, Wu Y, Sun N, Deng C. ACS Nano. 2022;16:12952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yagin FH, Alkhateeb A, Colak C, Azzeh M, Yagin B, Rueda L. Metabolites 2023, 13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DJ, Yang J, Seo H, Lee WH, Lee DH, Kym S, Park YS, Kim JG, Jang IJ, Kim YK. J Y Cho Sci Rep. 2020;10:2860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Q, Huang L, Yang Q, Ao Z, Yang R, Krzesniak J, Lou D, Hu L, Dai X, Guo F, Liu F. Nanoscale. 2021;13:16457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Chen H, Deng C, Sun N. Anal Chem. 2024;96:2774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Y, Peng Z, Wang Y, Yang S, Xu X, Liu W, Bao Q, Jiang C, Qian K, Fan X. Small 2025, 21, e2411871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bollard SM, Howard J, Casalou C, Kelly BS, O&#x2019;Donnell K, Fenn G, O&#x2019;Reilly J, Milling R, Shields M, Wilson M, Ajaykumar A, Triana K, Wynne K, Tobin DJ, Kelly PA, McCann A, Potter SM. Transl Oncol. 2024;50:102152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Wu P, Li B, Huang X, Shi Q, Qiao L, Liu B, Chen X, Fang X. Anal Chem. 2024;96:17679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin F, Yang P, Xu R, Zhang S, Li L, Yang L, Bu X, Gao S, Han Y, Ma C, Chen P, Li Z, Zhan S, Liang G, Zhu X, Zhou S, Li X, Li Y, Yang Z, Li X, Wei X, Wang Y. Cell Rep. 2025;44:116259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moons KGM, Wolff RF, Riley RD, Whiting PF, Westwood M, Collins GS, Reitsma JB, Kleijnen J, Mallett S. Ann Intern Med. 2019;170:W1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) VE, Staartjes JM, Kernbach SJ, Vabalas A, Gowen E, Poliakoff E, Casson AJ. PLoS One 2019, 14, e0224365; c) K. Zantvoort, B. Nacke, D. Gorlich, S. Hornstein, C. Jacobi, B. Funk, NPJ Digit Med 2024, 7, 361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) C, Ambroise GJ, McLachlan. 2002, 99, 6562; b) S. Varma, R. Simon, BMC Bioinformatics 2006, 7, 91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) B, Van Calster DJ, McLernon M, van Smeden L, Wynants EW Steyerberg, t. Topic Group &#x2018;Evaluating diagnostic, S. i. prediction models&#x2019; of the,. 2019, 17, 230; b) A. J. Vickers, E. B. Elkin, Medical Decision Making 2006, 26, 565.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) G, Kemunto S, Ghadami K, Dellinger. 2025, DOI: 10.1002/pmic.700661; b) W. Yan, B. Ding, B. Yu, H. Jin, X. Zhang, G. Zhang, Y. Zhang, H. Liu, Y. Lu, Y. Zheng, C. Zhang, X. Ding, Q. Dai, X. Li, H. Zhang, S. Wang, 2025, 24, 4754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizenko RR, Feaver M, Bozkurt BT, Lowe N, Nguyen B, Huang KW, Wang A, Carney RP. J Extracell Vesicles. 2024;13:e12510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) R, Tutrone B, Lowentritt B, Neuman MJ, Donovan E, Hallmark TJ, Cole Y, Yao C, Biesecker S, Kumar V, Verma GR, Sant J, Alter J, Skog, Kretschmer A, Kajau H, Margolis E, Tutrone R, Grimm T, Trottmann M, Stief C, Stoll G, Fischer CA, Flinspach C, Albrecht A, Meyer L, Priewasser T, Enderle D, Muller R, Torkler P, J. Alter, J. Skog, M., Noerholm. 2023, 26, 596; b) E. Margolis, G. Brown, A. Partin, B. Carter, J. McKiernan, R. Tutrone, P. Torkler, C. Fischer, V. Tadigotla, M. Noerholm, M. J. Donovan, J. Skog, Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis 2022, 25, 296; c) A. Kretschmer, H. Kajau, E. Margolis, R. Tutrone, T. Grimm, M. Trottmann, C. Stief, G. Stoll, C. A. Fischer, C. Flinspach, A. Albrecht, L. Meyer, T. Priewasser, D. Enderle, R. Muller, P. Torkler, J. Alter, J. Skog, M. Noerholm Sci Rep 2022, 12, 4777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bio M. EvoLiver&#x2122; Receives FDA Breakthrough Device Designation for Early Detection of HCC, https://mursla.com/mursla-fda-receives-breakthrough-device-designation-for-evoliver/, accessed: 2025.11.24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P, Bai Y, Shan B, Zhang W, Liu Z, Zhu Y, Xu X, Chen Q, Sheng X, Deng X, Guo Z, Zhang D, Wang H, Zhang Y, Hu Y. Front Oncol. 2021;11:707658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) F, Emmert-Streib M, Dehmer. Machine Learning and Knowledge Extraction 2018, 1, 235; b) F. Emmert-Streib, Front Mol Med 2021, 1, 734659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) F, Royo C, Thery JM, Falcon-Perez R, Nieuwland KW, Witwer. 2020, 9; b) K. W. Witwer, D. C. Goberdhan, L. O&#x2019;Driscoll, C. Thery, J. A. Welsh, C. Blenkiron, E. I. Buzas, D. Di Vizio, U. Erdbrugger, J. M. Falcon-Perez, Q. L. Fu, A. F. Hill, M. Lenassi, J. Lotvall, R. Nieuwland, T. Ochiya, S. Rome, S. Sahoo, L. Zheng, J Extracell Vesicles 2021, 10, e12182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, Zhang N, Mai Y, Ren L, Chen Q, Cao Z, Chen Q, Liu Y, Hou W, Yang J, Hong H, Xu J, Tong W, Dong L, Shi L, Fang X, Zheng Y. Genome Biol. 2023;24:201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) L, Xu FN, Faruqu R, Liam-Or O, Abu Abed D, Li K, Venner RJ, Errington H, Summers JT, Wang KT, Al-Jamal, Penev TR, Buchanan MM, Ruppert M, Liu R, Shekouhi Z, Guan J, Balch T, Ozrazgat-Baslanti B, Shickel TJ, Loftus A, Bihorac. 2020, 9, 1779458; b) E. H. Castellanos, B. K. Wittmershaus, S. Chandwani, JCO Clin Cancer Inform 2024, 8, e2300046; c) Y. P. Penev, T. R., Buchanan, M. M., Ruppert, M., Liu, R., Shekouhi, Z., Guan, J., Balch, T., Ozrazgat-Baslanti, B., Shickel, T. J., Loftus, A., Bihorac JMIR Med Inform 2024, 12, e58130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) D, Fernandes Prabhu V, Gurupur A, Stone E, Trader. 2025, 13; b) N. Rieke, J. Hancox, W. Li, F. Milletari, H. R. Roth, S. Albarqouni, S. Bakas, M. N. Galtier, B. A. Landman, K. Maier-Hein, S. Ourselin, M. Sheller, R. M. Summers, A. Trask, D. Xu, M. Baust, M. J. Cardoso, NPJ Digit Med 2020, 3, 119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) X, Liu D, Lacombe S, Lejeune, Shabani M, Marelli L. 2025, 14, 54; b) D. Peloquin, M. DiMaio, B. Bierer, M. Barnes, Eur J Hum Genet 2020, 28, 697; c) M. Shabani, L. Marelli EMBO Rep 2019, 20; d) C. Dupras, E. M. Bunnik, The American Journal of Bioethics 2021, 21, 46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) X, Escriba-Montagut Y, Marcon A, Anguita-Ruiz D, Avraam J, Urquiza AS, Morgan RC, Wilson P, Burton JR, Gonzalez, Rahnasto J. 2024, 20, e1012626; b) P. E. Geyer, S. P. Mann, P. V. Treit, M. Mann, Mol Cell Proteomics 2021, 20, 100035; c) J. Rahnasto J Law Biosci 2023, 10, lsad029; d) M. A. Rujano, J. W. Boiten, C. Ohmann, S. Canham, S. Contrino, R. David, J. Ewbank, C. Filippone, C. Connellan, I. Custers, R. van Nuland, M. T. Mayrhofer, P. Holub, E. G. Alvarez, E. Bacry, N. Hughes, M. A. Freeberg, B. Schaffhauser, H. Wagener, A. Sanchez-Pla, G. Bertolini, M. Panagiotopoulou, Brief Bioinform 2024, 25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consortium E-T, Van Deun J, Mestdagh P, Agostinis P, Akay O, Anand S, Anckaert J, Martinez ZA, Baetens T, Beghein E, Bertier L, Berx G, Boere J, Boukouris S, Bremer M, Buschmann D, Byrd JB, Casert C, Cheng L, Cmoch A, Daveloose D, De Smedt E, Demirsoy S, Depoorter V, Dhondt B, et al. Nat Methods. 2017;14:228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) A, Niehues C, de Visser FA, Hagenbeek P, Kulkarni R, Pool N, Karu ASD, Kindt G, Singh R, Vermeiren DI, Boomsma J, van Dongen PAC, t Hoen AJ, van Gool. 2024, 13; b) W. A. M. Vierdag, S. K. Saka, Front Bioinform 2024, 4, 1336257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EPPerMed a), European Partnership for Personalised, Medicine B, Yadav N, Pandey S, Gupta A, Dudani P, Gupta S, Rangarajan K. Indian Dermatol Online J 2023, 14, 788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Z, Boys EL, Noor Z, Aref AT, Xavier D, Lucas N, Williams SG, Koh JMS, Poulos RC, Wu Y, Dausmann M, MacKenzie KL, Aguilar-Mahecha A, Armengol C, Barranco MM, Basik M, Bowman ED, Clifton-Bligh R, Connolly EA, Cooper WA, Dalal B, DeFazio A, Filipits M, Flynn PJ, J. D., Graham et al. Cancer Discov 2025, 15, 1803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins GS, Chester-Jones M, Gerry S, Ma J, Matos J, Sehjal J, Tsegaye B, Dhiman P. BMJ Oncol. 2025;4:e000914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsegaye B, Snell KIE, Archer L, Kirtley S, Riley RD, Sperrin M, Van Calster B, Collins GS, Dhiman P. J Clin Epidemiol. 2025;180:111675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) P, Dhiman J, Ma CL, Andaur Navarro B, Speich G, Bullock JAA, Damen L, Hooft S, Kirtley RD, Riley B, Van Calster KGM, Moons GS, Collins, Dhiman P, Ma J, Navarro CA, Speich B, Bullock G, Damen JA, Kirtley S, Hooft L, Riley RD, Van Calster B, K. G. M. Moons, G. S., Collins. 2022, 6, 13; b) P. Dhiman, J. Ma, C. L. Andaur Navarro, B. Speich, G. Bullock, J. A. A. Damen, L. Hooft, S. Kirtley, R. D. Riley, B. Van Calster, K. G. M. Moons, G. S. Collins, J Clin Epidemiol 2023, 157, 120; c) P. Dhiman, J. Ma, C. A. Navarro, B. Speich, G. Bullock, J. A. Damen, S. Kirtley, L. Hooft, R. D. Riley, B. Van Calster, K. G. M. Moons, G. S. Collins J Clin Epidemiol 2021, 138, 60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos CS, Amorim-Lopes M. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2025;25:45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghassemi M, Gusev A. Nat Rev Cancer. 2024;24:823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obermeyer Z, Powers B, Vogeli C, Mullainathan S. 2019, 366, 447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J, Eidlisz E, Ajmal BE, Awan. 2025, 190, 109846; b) R. Singh, M. Bapna, A. R. Diab, E. S. Ruiz, W. Lotter, NPJ Digit Med 2025, 8, 388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moulaei K, Akhlaghpour S, Fatehi F. Int J Med Inf. 2025;198:105872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahn SD, Terry SF. Sci Data. 2024;11:156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) T, Pham RSOS. 2025, 12, 241873; b) H. C. U.S. Food and Drug Administration, Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA), Good Machine Learning Practice for Medical Device Development: Guiding Principles. https://www.fda.gov/medical-devices/software-medical-device-samd/good-machine-learning-practice-medical-device-development-guiding-principles, accessed: 2026.03.10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S, Gerke T, Minssen G, Cohen. in Artificial Intelligence in Healthcare, https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-12-818438-7.00012-5 2020, p. 295; b) C. Mennella, U. Maniscalco, G. De Pietro, M. Esposito, Heliyon 2024, 10, e26297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S. a. C. O. United Nations Educational, Recommendation on the Ethics of Artificial Intelligence. , accessed: 2026.03.10; b) W. H. Organization, Ethics and governance of artificial intelligence for health. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240029200, accessed: 2026.03.10. https://www.unesco.org/en/articles/recommendation-ethics-artificial-intelligence</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) B, Arjmand SK, Hamidpour A, Tayanloo-Beik P, Goodarzi HR, Aghayan H, Adibi B, Larijani, Tjoa E, Guan C. 2022, 13, 824451; b) E. Shaba, L. Vantaggiato, L. Governini, A. Haxhiu, G. Sebastiani, D. Fignani, G. E. Grieco, L. Bergantini, L. Bini, C. Landi, Proteomes 2022, 10; c) E. Tjoa, C. Guan IEEE Trans Neural Netw Learn Syst 2021, 32, 4793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S, Cao J, Liu Y, Li FR, Liu Y, Li Y, Zeng T. Front Bioinform 2023, 3, 1117271; c) A. Yetgin, Quantitative Biology 2025, 13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J, Blackman R, Veerapen. 2025, 25, 111; b) J. Caterson, A. Lewin, E. Williamson, Digit Health 2024, 10, 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J, Zhang ZM, Zhang BMC. Med Inform Decis Mak 2023, 23, 7; b) A. M. Stroud, S. A. Minteer, X. Zhu, J. L. Ridgeway, J. E. Miller, B. A. Barry, PLOS Digit Health 2025, 4, e0000826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J, Fehr B, Citro R, Malpani C, Lippert VI, Madai. 2024, 6, 1267290; b) J. Fehr, G. Jaramillo-Gutierrez, L. Oala, M. I. Groschel, M. Bierwirth, P. Balachandran, A. Werneck-Leite, C. Lippert, Healthcare (Basel) 2022, 10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) RL, Pierce W, Van Biesen D, Van Cauwenberge J, Decruyenaere S, Sterckx. 2022, 13, 903600; b) H. Smith, Ai &amp; Society 2020, 36, 535.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duran JM, Jongsma KR. J Med Ethics. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1136/medethics-2020-106820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) H, Xu KMJ, Shuttleworth IM, Mienye ID, Obaido G, Jere N, Mienye E, Aruleba K, Emmanuel ID, Ogbuokiri B. Informatics in Medicine Unlocked 2024, 51; c) M. D. McCradden, S. Joshi, J. A. Anderson, M. Mazwi, A. Goldenberg, R. Zlotnik Shaul, J Am Med Inform Assoc 2020, 27, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Band SS, Yarahmadi A, Hsu C-C, Biyari M, Sookhak M, Ameri R, Dehzangi I, Chronopoulos AT, Liang H-W. Inf Med Unlocked 2023, 40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) SM, Lundberg S-I. Lee, in Proceedings of the 31st International Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems, Curran Associates Inc., Long Beach, California, 2017, 4768; b) M. T. Ribeiro, S. Singh, C. Guestrin, in Proceedings of the 22nd ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining, https://doi.org/10.1145/2939672.2939778, 2016, 1135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salih AM, Raisi-Estabragh Z, Galazzo IB, Radeva P, Petersen SE, Lekadir K, Menegaz G. Adv Intell Syst 2024, 7, 2400304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Y, Li X, He Q, Li H, Lai H, Zhang Z, Hu Y, Li S, Huang. 2020, 18, 2851; b) R. S. Varghese, X. Zhang, S. Giridharan, M. S. Sajid, M. M. Rashid, A. Kroemer, H. W. Ressom, Metabolites 2025, 15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) R, Kalluri VS, LeBleu. 2020, 367, eaau6977; b) G. van Niel, G. D&#x2019;Angelo, G. Raposo, Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol 2018, 19, 213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulcahy LA, Pink RC, Carter DR. J Extracell Vesicles 2014, 3, 24641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoshino A, Costa-Silva B, Shen TL, Rodrigues G, Hashimoto A, Tesic Mark M, Molina H, Kohsaka S, Di Giannatale A, Ceder S, Singh S, Williams C, Soplop N, Uryu K, Pharmer L, King T, Bojmar L, Davies AE, Ararso Y, Zhang T, Zhang H, Hernandez J, Weiss JM, Dumont-Cole VD, Kramer K, et al. Nature. 2015;527:329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) N, Nishida-Aoki N, Tominaga N, Kosaka T, Ochiya. 2020, 9, 1713527; b) F. Royo, U. Cossio, A. Ruiz de Angulo, J. Llop, J. M. Falcon-Perez, Nanoscale 2019, 11, 1531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Midekessa G, Godakumara K, Ord J, Viil J, Lattekivi F, Dissanayake K, Kopanchuk S, Rinken A, Andronowska A, Bhattacharjee S, Rinken T, Fazeli A. ACS Omega. 2020;5:16701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) NL, Patel-Murray M, Adam N, Huynh BT, Wassie P, Milani E, Fraenkel. 2020, 10, 954; b) Y. T. Zhang, H. Zhang, W. Su, W. Liu, Y. T. Chen, H. Y. Ren, M. He, Y. X. Zhang, Y. P. Fan, W. Liu, M. H. Li, Y. X. Shi, Q. Y. Tang, Y. Liu, S. H. Zong, A. Wesselius, M. P. Zeegers, Y. Xu, C. X. Ma, Y. Zhang, E. Yi-Wen Yu, Cell Rep Med 2025, 6, 102432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) P, Rajpurkar E, Chen O, Banerjee EJ, Topol. 2022, 28, 31; b) C. Kim, S. U. Gadgil, S.-I. Lee, Nature Reviews Bioengineering 2025. https://doi.org/10.1038/s44222-025-00363-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) A, Kiseleva D, Kotzinos P, De Hert. 2022, 5, 879603; b) G. S. Collins, P. Dhiman, C. L. Andaur Navarro, J. Ma, L. Hooft, J. B. Reitsma, P. Logullo, A. L. Beam, L. Peng, B. Van Calster, M. van Smeden, R. D. Riley, K. G. Moons, BMJ Open 2021, 11, e048008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan B. Med Health Care Philos. 2023;26:285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) CR, Aaron Fisher F, Dominici, Altmann A, Tolosi L, Sander O, Lengauer T, Subramanian A, Tamayo P, Mootha VK, Mukherjee S, Ebert BL, Gillette MA, Paulovich A, Pomeroy SL, Golub TR. 2019, 20, 1; b) K. Aas, M. Jullum, A. L&#xf8;land, Artificial Intelligence 2021, 298; c) A. Altmann, L. Tolosi, O. Sander, T. Lengauer, Bioinformatics 2010, 26, 1340; d) S.-I. L. Scott Lundberg, arXiv 2017, DOI: https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.1705.07874; e) A. Subramanian, P. Tamayo, V. K. Mootha, S. Mukherjee, B. L. Ebert, M. A. Gillette, A. Paulovich, S. L. Pomeroy, T. R. Golub E. S. Lander, J. P. Mesirov, 2005, 102, 15545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniel JZ, Apley W. 2016, DOI: arXiv:1612.08468IF: NA NA NA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) SM, Lundberg G, Erion H, Chen A, DeGrave JM, Prutkin B, Nair R, Katz J, Himmelfarb N, Bansal SI, Lee. Nat Mach Intell 2020, 2, 56; b) SM, Lundberg GG, Erion SI, Lee. arXiv 2018, arXiv:1802.03888IF: NA NA NA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) R, Browaeys W, Saelens Y, Saeys. 2020, 17, 159; b) S. Jin, C. F. Guerrero-Juarez, L. Zhang, I. Chang, R. Ramos, C. H. Kuan, P. Myung, M. V. Plikus, Q. Nie, Nat Commun 2021, 12, 1088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) CL, Andaur Navarro JAA, Damen T, Takada SWJ, Nijman P, Dhiman J, Ma GS, Collins R, Bajpai RD, Riley KGM, Moons L, Hooft, Norgeot B, Quer G, Beaulieu-Jones BK, Torkamani A, Dias R, Gianfrancesco M, Arnaout R, Kohane IS, Saria S, Topol E, Z. Obermeyer, B. Yu, A. J., Butte. 2023, 158, 99; b) C. L. Andaur Navarro, J. A. A. Damen, T. Takada, S. W. J. Nijman, P. Dhiman, J. Ma, G. S. Collins, R. Bajpai, R. D. Riley, K. G. M. Moons, L. Hooft, BMC Med Res Methodol 2022, 22, 12; c) B. Norgeot, G. Quer, B. K. Beaulieu-Jones, A. Torkamani, R. Dias, M. Gianfrancesco, R. Arnaout, I. S. Kohane, S. Saria, E. Topol, Z. Obermeyer, B. Yu, A. J. Butte Nature Medicine 2020, 26, 1320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) CL, Andaur Navarro JAA, Damen M, van Smeden T, Takada SWJ, Nijman P, Dhiman J, Ma GS, Collins R, Bajpai RD, Riley KGM, Moons L, Hooft, Damen JAA, Takada T, Nijman SWJ, Dhiman P, Ma J, Collins GS, Bajpai R, Riley RD, K. G. M. Moons, Hooft L. 2023, 154, 8; b) F. R. Kolbinger, G. P. Veldhuizen, J. Zhu, D. Truhn, J. N. Kather, Commun Med (Lond) 2024, 4, 71; c) C. L. Andaur Navarro, J. A. A. Damen, T. Takada, S. W. J. Nijman, P. Dhiman, J. Ma, G. S. Collins, R. Bajpai, R. D. Riley, K. G. M. Moons, L. Hooft BMJ 2021, 375, n2281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) R, Baek EK, Sondergaard K, Varming MM, Jorgensen JIM, Jamaly S, Ramberg C, Olsen R, Latysheva N, Webster P, Sovershaev T, Braekkan SK, Hansen JB. Sci Rep 2018, 8, 17216; c) J. Rios de Los Rios Resendiz, F. Herrmann-Sim, L. Wilkesmann, D. Helm, M. Schneider, G. Campione, K. Plugge, G. Greiner, L. Lazaro Garcia, J. Berker, K. Richter, L. Zielske, W. K. Hofmann, K. Clemm von Hohenberg, Sci Rep 2025, 15, 24292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelibter S, Marostica G, Mandelli A, Siciliani S, Podini P, Finardi A, Furlan R. J Extracell Vesicles. 2022;11:e12162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thery C, Witwer KW, Aikawa E, Alcaraz MJ, Anderson JD, Andriantsitohaina R, Antoniou A, Arab T, Archer F, Atkin-Smith GK, Ayre DC, Bach JM, Bachurski D, Baharvand H, Balaj L, Baldacchino S, Bauer NN, Baxter AA, Bebawy M, Beckham C, Bedina Zavec A, Benmoussa A, Berardi AC, Bergese P, Bielska E, et al. J Extracell Vesicles. 2018;7:1535750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poupardin R, Wolf M, Strunk D. Adv Drug Deliv Rev. 2021;176:113872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J, Van Deun P, Mestdagh R, Sormunen V, Cocquyt K, Vermaelen J, Vandesompele M, Bracke O, De Wever A, Hendrix, Askeland A, Borup A, Ostergaard O, Olsen JV, Lund SM, Christiansen G, Kristensen SR, N. H. H. Heegaard, Pedersen S. 2014, 3; b) S. Deville, P. Berckmans, R. Van Hoof, I. Lambrichts, A. Salvati, I. Nelissen, PLoS One 2021, 16, e0245835; c) A. Askeland, A. Borup, O. Ostergaard, J. V. Olsen, S. M. Lund, G. Christiansen, S. R. Kristensen, N. H. H. Heegaard, S. Pedersen Biomedicines 2020, 8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) K, Brennan K, Martin SP, FitzGerald J, O&#x2019;Sullivan Y, Wu A, Blanco C, Richardson MM, Mc Gee, Yellon SM, Davidson. 2020, 10, 1039; b) M. Wu, C. Chen, Z. Wang, H. Bachman, Y. Ouyang, P. H. Huang, Y. Sadovsky, T. J. Huang, Lab Chip 2019, 19, 1174; c) K. Takov, D. M. Yellon, S. M., Davidson J Extracell Vesicles 2019, 8, 1560809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuana Y, Levels J, Grootemaat A, Sturk A, Nieuwland R. J Extracell Vesicles 2014, 3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Z, Zhao Y, Yang Y, Zeng M, He. 2016, 16, 489; b) M. He, J. Crow, M. Roth, Y. Zeng, A. K. Godwin, Lab Chip 2014, 14, 3773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Z, Andreu E, Rivas A, Sanguino-Pascual A, Lamana M, Marazuela I, Gonzalez-Alvaro F, Sanchez-Madrid H, de la Fuente M, Yanez-Mo. 2016, 5, 31655; b) K. Rekker, M. Saare, A. M. Roost, A.-L. Kubo, N. Zarovni, A. Chiesi, A. Salumets, M. Peters, Clinical Biochemistry 2014, 47, 135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leek JT, Scharpf RB, Bravo HC, Simcha D, Langmead B, Johnson WE, Geman D, Baggerly K, Irizarry RA. Nat Rev Genet. 2010;11:733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S, Gandham X, Su J, Wood AL, Nocera SC, Alli L, Milane A, Zimmerman M, Amiji AR, Ivanov. 2020, 38, 1066; b) G. L. Liguori, A. Kisslinger, Front Bioeng Biotechnol 2022, 10, 826252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) GS, Collins P, Dhiman J, Ma MM, Schlussel L, Archer B, Van Calster FE, Harrell GP Jr., Martin KGM, Moons M, van Smeden M, Sperrin GS, Bullock RD, Riley. 2024, 384, e074819; b) C. Soneson, S. Gerster, M. Delorenzi, PLoS One 2014, 9, e100335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) A, Yekula K, Muralidharan KM, Kang L, Wang L, Balaj BS, Carter, Jiang C, Fu Y, Liu G, Shu B, Davis J, Tofaris GK. 2020, 177, 58; b) Y. Liang, B. M. Lehrich, S. Zheng, M. Lu, J Extracell Vesicles 2021, 10, e12090; c) C. Jiang, Y. Fu, G. Liu, B. Shu, J. Davis, G. K. Tofaris Nanomicro Lett 2021, 14, 3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) BJ, Benedikter FG, Bouwman T, Vajen ACA, Heinzmann G, Grauls EC, Mariman EFM, Wouters PH, Savelkoul C, Lopez-Iglesias RR, Koenen GGU, Rohde FRM, Stassen. 2017, 7, 15297; b) R. E. Veerman, L. Teeuwen, P. Czarnewski, G. Gucluler Akpinar, A. Sandberg, X. Cao, M. Pernemalm, L. M. Orre, S. Gabrielsson, M. Eldh, J Extracell Vesicles 2021, 10, e12128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) N, Karimi A, Cvjetkovic SC, Jang R, Crescitelli MA, Hosseinpour Feizi R, Nieuwland J, Lotvall C, Lasser. 2018, 75, 2873; b) T. S. Martins, M. Vaz, A. G. Henriques, Anal Bioanal Chem 2023, 415, 1239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) H, Contreras P, Alarc&#xf3;n-Zapata E, Nova-Lamperti V, Ormazabal M, Varas-Godoy C, Salomon FA, Zuniga. 2023, 5; b) T. Baranyai, K. Herczeg, Z. Onodi, I. Voszka, K. Modos, N. Marton, G. Nagy, I. Mager, M. J. Wood, S. El Andaloussi, Z. Palinkas, V. Kumar, P. Nagy, A. Kittel, E. I. Buzas, P. Ferdinandy, Z. Giricz, PLoS One 2015, 10, e0145686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams S, Fernandez-Rhodes M, Law A, Peacock B, Lewis MP, Davies OG. J Tissue Eng. 2023;14:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visan KS, Lobb RJ, Ham S, Lima LG, Palma C, Edna CPZ, Wu LY, Gowda H, Datta KK, Hartel G, Salomon C, Moller A. J Extracell Vesicles. 2022;11:e12266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor DD, Shah S. Methods 2015, 87, 3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Liu X, Zhang C, Xia H, Qin X, Guo Y, Chen C-H, Hu F, Guo X, Zhang D, Wei X. Biomedical Instrum 2025, 1, 100007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieuwland R, Falcon-Perez JM, Thery C, Witwer KW. J Extracell Vesicles. 2020;10:e12037.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu W, Hurley J, Roberts D, Chakrabortty SK, Enderle D, Noerholm M, Breakefield XO, Skog JK. Ann Oncol. 2021;32:466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) FDA, Proposed Regulatory Framework for Modifications to Artificial Intelligence, Cruz S, Rivera X, Liu AW, Chan AK, Denniston MJ, Calvert AI, Spirit C-AW, Group AI, Spirit C-AS, Group AI, Spirit C-AC, Group. 2020, 26, 1351; c) X. Liu, S. Cruz Rivera, D. Moher, M. J. Calvert, A. K. Denniston, A. I. Spirit, C.-A. W. Group, Nat Med 2020, 26, 1364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Y, Hasin M, Seldin A, Lusis. 2017, 18, 83; b) J. Lipkova, R. J. Chen, B. Chen, M. Y. Lu, M. Barbieri, D. Shao, A. J. Vaidya, C. Chen, L. Zhuang, D. F. K. Williamson, M. Shaban, T. Y. Chen, F. Mahmood, Cancer Cell 2022, 40, 1095.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carney RP, Mizenko RR, Bozkurt BT, Lowe N, Henson T, Arizzi A, Wang A, Tan C, George SC. Nat Nanotechnol. 2025;20:14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) DE, Reynolds G, Galanis Y, Wang J, Ko, Song Y, Zhang Q, Lin J, Wang J, Lin JM. 2023, 2689, 211; b) Y. Jiao, L. Gao, T. Zhang, Z. He, S. Y. Zheng, W. Liu, Anal Chem 2024, 96, 1293; c) Y. Song, Q. Zhang, J. Lin, J. Wang, J. M. Lin Anal Chem 2025, 97, 18689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) R, Lees R, Tempest A, Law D, Aubert OG, Davies S, Williams N, Peake B, Peacock J, von Lersner AK, Fernandes F, Ozawa PMM, Jackson M, Masureel M, Ho H, Lima SM, Vagner T, Sung BH, Wehbe M, Franze K, Pua H, Wilson JT, Irish JM, Weaver AM, D. Di Vizio, Zijlstra A. Vis Exp 2022, DOI: 10.3791/64020;IF: 1.0 Q3 B4 b) H. Liu, Y. Tian, C. Xue, Q. Niu, C. Chen, X. Yan, 2022, 11, e12206; c) A. K. von Lersner, F. Fernandes, P. M. M. Ozawa, M. Jackson, M. Masureel, H. Ho, S. M. Lima, T. Vagner, B. H. Sung, M. Wehbe, K. Franze, H. Pua, J. T. Wilson, J. M. Irish, A. M. Weaver, D. Di Vizio, A. Zijlstra ACS Nano 2024, 18, 10464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saftics A, Abuelreich S, Romano E, Ghaeli I, Jiang N, Spanos M, Lennon KM, Singh G, Das S, Van Keuren-Jensen K, Jovanovic-Talisman T. J Extracell Vesicles. 2023;12:e12346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Ng M, Srivastava S, Li T, Liu J, Phu TA, Mateescu B, Wang YT, Tsai CF, Liu T, Raffai RL, Xie YH. PLoS ONE. 2024;19:e0305418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) AA, Brock S, Duraivel J, Jiang J, Fischer ZF, Greenberg M, He TE, Angelini TD, Schmittgen, Luo T, Chen S-Y, Qiu Z-X, Miao Y-R, Ding Y, Pan X-Y, Li Y, Q. Lei, A.-Y., Guo. 2025, 17, 53110; b) N. Li, T. T. Tang, M. Gu, Y. Q. Fu, W. W. Qian, N. N. Ma, A. R. Shen, T. Zhu, R. B. Huo, T. Zhang, J. F. Xie, L. Zhang, B. C. Liu, L. L. Lv, Nat Commun 2025, 16, 6960; c) T. Luo, S.-Y. Chen, Z.-X. Qiu, Y.-R. Miao, Y. Ding, X.-Y. Pan, Y. Li, Q. Lei, A.-Y. Guo 2022, 6, 2200881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J, Cho MH, Cho H, Song Y, Lee SW, Nam HC, Yoon TH, Shin JC, Hong JS, Kim Y, Ekanayake E, Jeon J, You DG, Im SG, Choi GS, Park JS, Carter BC, Balaj L, Seo AN, Miller MA, Park SY, Kang T, Castro CM, Lee H. Nat Biotechnol. 2024;43:1485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J, Zhou Z, Wu J, Hu D, Yang X, Chen Q, Wang J, Liu M, Dou W, Peng Y, Wu W, Wang C, Xie M, Wang Y, Song H, Zeng C, Bai. 2020, 6, eabc1204; b) S. Ferguson, K. S. Yang, P. Zelga, A. S. Liss, J. C. T. Carlson, C. F. Del Castillo, R. Weissleder, Sci Adv 2022, 8, eabm3453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalali M, Real Mata CD, Montermini L, Jeanne O, I IH, Gu Z, Spinelli C, Lu Y, Tawil N, Guiot MC, He Z, Wachsmann-Hogiu S, Zhou R, Petrecca K, Reisner WW, Rak J, Mahshid S. ACS Nano. 2023;17:12052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) HJ, Lim GW, Kim GH, Heo U, Jeong MJ, Kim D, Jeong Y, Hyun D, Kim. 2024, 263, 116629; b) K. S. Kapoor, S. Kong, H. Sugimoto, W. Guo, V. Boominathan, Y. L. Chen, S. L. Biswal, T. Terlier, K. M. McAndrews, R. Kalluri, ACS Nano 2024, 18, 11717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Z, Zhou N, Jing M, Cai Y, Zhang Y, Wang X, Wang L, Wu D, Xue F, Hou Q. Nucleic Acids Res. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkaf1189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baek S, Song K, Lee I. Exp Mol Med. 2025;57:2169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) CV, Theodoris L, Xiao A, Chopra MD, Chaffin ZR, Al Sayed MC, Hill H, Mantineo EM, Brydon Z, Zeng XS, Liu PT, Ellinor. 2023, 618, 616; b) H. Cui, C. Wang, H. Maan, K. Pang, F. Luo, N. Duan, B. Wang, Nat Methods 2024, 21, 1470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) R, Lopez J, Regier MB, Cole MI, Jordan N, Yosef NM, Gayoso A, Steier Z, Lopez R, Regier J, Nazor KL, Streets A, Yosef N, Lotfollahi M, Naghipourfar M, Luecken MD, Khajavi M, Buttner M, Wagenstetter M, Avsec Z, Gayoso A, Yosef N, Interlandi M, Rybakov S, A. V. Misharin, F. J., Theis. Nat Methods 2021, 18, 272; c) T. Ashuach, M. I. Gabitto, R. V. Koodli, G. A. Saldi, M. I. Jordan, N. Yosef, Nat Methods 2023, 20, 1222; d) M. Lotfollahi, M. Naghipourfar, M. D. Luecken, M. Khajavi, M. Buttner, M. Wagenstetter, Z. Avsec, A. Gayoso, N. Yosef, M. Interlandi, S. Rybakov, A. V. Misharin, F. J. Theis Nat Biotechnol 2022, 40, 121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Shaham U, Stanton KP, Yao Y, Montgomery RR, Kluger Y. Bioinformatics. 2017;33:3423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C, Lopez R, Mehlman E, Regier J, Jordan MI, Yosef N. Mol Syst Biol. 2021;17:e9620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He R, Zhu J, Ji P, Zhao F. Nat Methods. 2024;21:259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Zhang D, Liu T, Wang A, Wang G, Zhao Y. Brief Bioinform 2025, 26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) A, Brankovic D, Cook J, Rahman A, Delaforce J, Li F, Magrabi F, Cabitza E, Coiera D, Bradford. 2025, 8, 364; b) Z. Sadeghi, R. Alizadehsani, M. A. Cifci, S. Kausar, R. Rehman, P. Mahanta, P. K. Bora, A. Almasri, R. S. Alkhawaldeh, S. Hussain, B. Alatas, A. Shoeibi, H. Moosaei, M. Hlad&#xed;k, S. Nahavandi, P. M. Pardalos, Computers and Electrical Engineering 2024, 118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu D, Zhang S, Liu Q, Zhu X, Liu B. J Med Internet Res. 2025;27:e65547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) A, Singhal N, Neveditsin H, Tanveer V, Mago. JMIR Med Inform 2024, 12, e50048; b) M. Ennab, H. McHeick, Front Robot AI 2024, 11, 1444763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S, Wang J, Xu Z, Wang S, Brauer D, Welton L, Cogan J, Chung YH, Tian L, Zhan Z, Hou Y, Lin M, Melton GB, Zhang R. NPJ Digit Med. 2025;8:690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S, Liao H, Long Q, Zhu S, Li L, Li S, Lu N, Tang Y, Liang M, Dong BMCG, Miao J, Li J, Xin J, Tu J, Ge M, Qi J, Zhou X, Zhu Y, Yang C, Lin Z. Nat Commun 2025, 16, 9403; c) W. Lan, H. Liao, Q. Chen, L. Zhu, Y. Pan, Y. P. Chen, Brief Bioinform 2024, 25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Tao Y, Cai Z, Bao P, Ma H, Li K, Li M, Zhu Y, Lu ZJ. Bioinformatics 2024, 40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) N, Koutsoubis A, Waqas Y, Yilmaz RP, Ramachandran MB, Schabath G, Rasool, Haripriya R, Khare N, Pandey M. Sci Rep 2025, 15, 12482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) RS, Gupta CE, Wood T, Engstrom JD, Pole S, Shrapnel, Marchisio M, Bennai M, Shafique. 2025, 8, 237; b) A. Thakur, P. C. Santos Bezerra, Abhishek, S. Zeng, K. Zhang, W. Treptow, A. Luna, U. Dougherty, A. Kwesi, I. R. Huang, C. Bestvina, M. C. Garassino, F. Duan, Y. Gokhale, B. Duan, Y. Chen, Q. Lian, M. Bissonnette, J. Huang, H. J. Chen, Bioact Mater 2025, 51, 414; c) N. Innan, A. Marchisio, M., Bennai, M., Shafique in Quantum Computational AI, https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-44-330259-6.00010-4 2026, p. 25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S, Kumari C, Lausted K, Scherler AHC, Ng Y, Lu I, Lee L, Hood K, Wang, Pink RC, Beaman E-M, Samuel P, Brooks SA. 2024, 14; b) J. P. Nolan, D. T. Chiu, J. A. Welsh, Extracell Vesicles Circ Nucl Acids 2022, 3, 244; c) R. C. Pink, E.-M. Beaman, P. Samuel, S. A. Brooks D. R. F. Carter, British Journal of Cancer 2022, 126, 323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) M, Palviainen M, Saraswat Z, Varga D, Kitka M, Neuvonen M, Puhka S, Joenvaara R, Renkonen R, Nieuwland M, Takatalo PRM, Siljander. 2020, 15, e0236439; b) B. Weber, A. Ritter, J. Han, I. Schaible, R. Sturm, B. Relja, M. Huber-Lang, F. Hildebrand, C. Pallas, M. Widera, D. Henrich, I. Marzi, L. Leppik, Int J Mol Sci 2024, 25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Zhou T, Han M, Wang H, Bao P, Tao Y, Chen X, Wu G, Liu T, Wang X, Lu Q, Zhu Y, Lu ZJ. Nucleic Acids Res. 2024;52:D607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) &#xc1;, Gonz&#xe1;lez S, L&#xf3;pez-Borrego A, Sand&#xfa;a M, Vales-Gomez E, Alegre. 2024, 61, 435; b) A. H. van der Vegt, I. A. Scott, K. Dermawan, R. J. Schnetler, V. R. Kalke, P. J. Lane, J Am Med Inform Assoc 2023, 30, 1503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) H, Shi L, Liu X, Deng X, Xing Y, Zhang Y, Djouda Rebecca L, Han, Wang H, Zhu J, Zou D, Rao Q, Han L, Lu H, Wang J, Liu L, Ma L, Sun L, Yi L, Feng W, Zhang Y, Du Y, Yang M, Feng Y, Zhang D, Lin Z, Zhou Q. 2024, 17, 4; b) R. Tutrone, M. J. Donovan, P. Torkler, V. Tadigotla, T. McLain, M. Noerholm, J. Skog, J. McKiernan, Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis 2020, 23, 607; c) H. Wang, J. Zhu, D. Zou, Q. Rao, L. Han, H. Lu, J. Wang, L. Liu, L. Ma, L. Sun, L. Yi, W. Feng, Y. Zhang, Y. Du, M. Yang, Y. Feng, D. Zhang, Z. Lin, Q. Zhou Gynecol Oncol 2025, 193, 58.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>