<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41774374</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1708-0428</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Obesity surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Obes Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Bariatric Surgery Versus Pelvic Floor Muscle Training: Which is Superior for Managing Urinary Incontinence?</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11695-026-08527-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Severe obesity substantially aggravates stress urinary incontinence (SUI) in older women. While both bariatric surgery and pelvic floor muscle exercise (PFME) are used to alleviate symptoms, their comparative effectiveness in elderly populations remains unclear. This retrospective study aimed to compare the continence outcomes of laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy (SG) and structured PFME in women aged&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;60 years with obesity-related SUI and to explore the impact of early postoperative gastrointestinal symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a retrospective propensity score-matched cohort study including women aged&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;60 years with SUI treated with SG, PFME, or no continence-directed intervention. Surgical patients were matched 1:2 to PFME participants and untreated controls based on age, body mass index, baseline International Consultation on Incontinence Questionnaire-Short Form (ICIQ-SF) score, incontinence subtype, parity, and menopausal duration. The primary outcome was continence improvement at 12 months, defined as an ICIQ-SF score&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;7. Secondary outcomes included absolute change in ICIQ-SF score, complete continence recovery, sleep quality, and postoperative gastrointestinal symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At 12 months, both SG and PFME were associated with significant improvements in urinary incontinence compared with no treatment (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). PFME achieved the highest rate of symptom remission (ICIQ-SF&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;7) at one year (56.5%), exceeding that observed after SG (34.8%) and in untreated controls (8.7%). Among patients undergoing SG, most improvements occurred within the moderate symptom range (ICIQ-SF 7-14). Multivariable analysis identified early postoperative diarrhea as an independent factor associated with reduced continence improvement after SG (adjusted OR 1.65, 95% CI 1.21-1.95).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In older women with obesity-related SUI, both sleeve gastrectomy and structured PFME improve continence outcomes, with PFME demonstrating superior effectiveness as a standalone intervention at one year. Early postoperative diarrhea significantly attenuates the continence benefits of bariatric surgery and represents a potentially modifiable factor.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Xian</LastName><ForeName>Yunxian</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou, China. ratm_jacz@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou, China. zhangjie@jnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>C2022089</GrantID><Agency>Guangdong Medical Science and Technology Research Fund</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>C2022089</GrantID><Agency>Guangdong Medical Science and Technology Research Fund</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>C2022089</GrantID><Agency>Guangdong Medical Science and Technology Research Fund</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Obes Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9106714</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0960-8923</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Geriatric obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolic surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic floor rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postoperative gastrointestinal symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleeve gastrectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stress urinary incontinence</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing Interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41774374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11695-026-08527-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11695-026-08527-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lukacz ES, Santiago-Lastra Y, Albo ME, Brubaker L. Urinary incontinence in women: a review. JAMA. 2017;318(16):1592&#x2013;604. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2017.12137 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2017.12137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29067433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Integrated care for older people (ICOPE) guidelines on community-level interventions to manage declines in intrinsic capacity evidence profile: urinary incontinence. World Health Organization. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilgic D, Beji NK, Ozbas A, Cavdar &#x130;, Yalcin O. Approaches to Cope with stress and depression in individuals with urinary incontinence. Gynecol Obstet Invest. 2017;82(2):181&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1159/000446955 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000446955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27299306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roe B, Flanagan L, Jack B, Barrett J, Chung A, Shaw C, et al. Systematic review of the management of incontinence and promotion of continence in older people in care homes: descriptive studies with urinary incontinence as primary focus. J Adv Nurs. 2011;67(2):228&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2648.2010.05481.x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2648.2010.05481.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21105895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silay K, Akinci S, Ulas A, Yalcin A, Silay Y, Akinci M, et al. Occult urinary incontinence in elderly women and its association with geriatric condition. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2016;20(3):447&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26914118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenzelius K, Molander U, Odeberg J, Hammarstr&#xf6;m M, Franzen K, Midl&#xf6;v P, et al. The effect of Conservative treatment of urinary incontinence among older and frail older people: a systematic review. Age Ageing. 2015;44(5):736&#x2013;44. https://doi.org/10.1093/ageing/afv070 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afv070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26112402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moudi E, Samadi F, Hosseini S, Bijani A, Ghadimi R. Urinary incontinency in elderly women and the potential risk factors: a cohort study among the elderly women of Amirkola. J Babol Univ Med Sci. 2017;19(2):14&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y, Zou P, Wang K, Li X, Wang J. Prevalence and risk factors of urinary incontinence among elderly adults in rural china: A Cross-Sectional survey. J Wound Ostomy Cont Nurs. 2022;49(1):78&#x2013;86. https://doi.org/10.1097/WON.0000000000000829</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WON.0000000000000829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y, Wang K, Zou P, Li X, He J, Wang J. Prevalence and associated factors of fecal incontinence and double incontinence among rural elderly in North China. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(23):9105. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17239105 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17239105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33291250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7730966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang XY, Chai YM, Huang WH, Zhang Y. Prostate artery embolization on lower urinary tract symptoms related to benign prostatic hyperplasia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. World J Clin Cases. 2022;10(32):11812&#x2013;26. https://doi.org/10.12998/wjcc.v10.i32.11812 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12998/wjcc.v10.i32.11812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36405270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9669846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aly WW, Sweed HS, Mossad NA, Tolba MF. Prevalence and risk factors of urinary incontinence in frail elderly females. J Aging Res. 2020;2020:1&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1155/2020/2425945 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/2425945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moudi E, Samadi F, Hosseini SR, Bijani A, Ghadimi R. Urinary incontinency in elderly women and the potential risk factors: a cohort study among the elderly women of Amirkola. J Babol Univ Med Sci. 2017;19(2):14&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashidi F, Hajian S, Darvish S, Alavi MH. Prevalence of urinary incontinence in Iranian women: systematic review and meta-analysis. Iran J Obstetr Gynecol Infertility. 2019;21(12):94&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuselier A, Hanberry J, Margaret Lovin J, Gomelsky A. Obesity and stress urinary incontinence: impact on pathophysiology and treatment. Curr Urol Rep. 2018;19(1):10. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11934-018-0762-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11934-018-0762-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29468457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilaka C, Toozs-Hobson P, Chilaka V. Pelvic floor dysfunction and obesity. Best Pract Res Clin Obstet Gynaecol. 2023;90:102389. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bpobgyn.2023.102389 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpobgyn.2023.102389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37541114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitcomb EL, Lukacz ES, Lawrence JM, Nager CW, Luber KM. Prevalence and degree of bother from pelvic floor disorders in obese women. Int Urogynecol J Pelvic Floor Dysfunct. 2009;20(3):289&#x2013;94. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00192-008-0765-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-008-0765-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19002365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber Pedersen L, Lose G, H&#xf8;ybye MT, Elsner S, Waldmann A, Rudnicki M. Prevalence of urinary incontinence among women and analysis of potential risk factors in Germany and Denmark. Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2017;96(8):939&#x2013;48. https://doi.org/10.1111/aogs.13149 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aogs.13149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28401541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wing RR, Creasman JM, West DS, Richter HE, Myers D, Burgio KL, Franklin F, Gorin AA, Vittinghoff E, Macer J, Kusek JW, Subak LL. Program to reduce incontinence by diet and exercise (PRIDE). Improving urinary incontinence in overweight and obese women through modest weight loss. Obstet Gynecol. 2010;116(2 Pt 1):284&#x2013;92. https://doi.org/10.1097/AOG.0b013e3181e8fb60 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0b013e3181e8fb60</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20664387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3038422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe BM, Kvach E, Eckel RH. Treatment of obesity: weight loss and bariatric surgery. Circ Res. 2016;118(11):1844&#x2013;55. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.116.307591 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.116.307591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27230645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4888907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Boyle CJ, O&#x2019;Sullivan OE, Shabana H, Boyce M, O&#x2019;Reilly BA. The effect of bariatric surgery on urinary incontinence in women. Obes Surg. 2016;26(7):1471&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11695-015-1969-z .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11695-015-1969-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26620218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitcomb EL, Subak LL. Effect of weight loss on urinary incontinence in women. Open Access J Urol. 2011;3:123&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.2147/OAJU.S21091 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/OAJU.S21091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24198645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3818946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ait Said K, Leroux Y, Menahem B, Doerfler A, Alves A, Tillou X. Effect of bariatric surgery on urinary and fecal incontinence: retrospective analysis with 1-year follow-up. Surg Obes Relat Dis. 2017;13(2):305&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.soard.2016.08.019 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soard.2016.08.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27639987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott KM, Bruffaerts R, Simon GE, Alonso J, Angermeyer M, de Girolamo G, Demyttenaere K, Gasquet I, Haro JM, Karam E, Kessler RC, Levinson D, Medina Mora ME, Oakley Browne MA, Ormel J, Villa JP, Uda H, Von Korff M. Obesity and mental disorders in the general population: results from the world mental health surveys. Int J Obes (Lond). 2008;32(1):192&#x2013;200. https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.ijo.0803701 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0803701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17712309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramezanzadeh K, Sharifzadeh G, Saljughi M, Moodi M, Ibrahimzadeh A. An epidemiological study of the infectious diseases of older adults hospitalized in hospitals affiliated to Birjand university of medical Sciences, in 2016. Iran J Ageing. 2019;14(3):298&#x2013;309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suhr R, Lahmann NA. Urinary incontinence in home care: a representative multicenter study on prevalence, severity, impact on quality of life, and risk factors. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2018;30(6):589&#x2013;94. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40520-017-0816-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40520-017-0816-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28836236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imamura M, Williams K, Wells M, McGrother C. Lifestyle interventions for the treatment of urinary incontinence in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;2015(12):CD003505. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD003505.pub5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD003505.pub5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26630349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8612696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barajas-Gamboa JS, Serra FE, Romero-Velez G, Dang JT, Del Gobbo GD, Abdallah M, Abril C, Raza J, Guerron AD, Corcelles R, Kroh M, Rodriguez J, Pantoja JP. Bariatric surgical outcomes in the elderly: A comparison study between primary and revisional procedures in the united Arab Emirates. Obes Surg. 2024;34(7):2515&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11695-024-07304-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11695-024-07304-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38819724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihalsky KP, Tran R, Moreno-Garcia F, Stenberg C, Mier Giraud F, Hare A, Quiroz LH, Fischer LE. Urinary incontinence in women who have undergone bariatric surgery. Surg Endosc. 2023;37(11):8791&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00464-023-10299-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-023-10299-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37587240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>