<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41816235</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-861X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Awareness and best practices in using ketogenic therapy to treat serious mental illness: a modified Delphi consensus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1749406</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1749406</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1749406</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fnut.2026.1749406</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Metabolic dysfunction is emerging as an important contributor to the pathophysiology of major depressive disorder, bipolar disorder, and schizophrenia, fueling interest in ketogenic metabolic therapy (KMT) as a potentially beneficial intervention for serious mental illness. KMT has been used successfully for decades in treating epilepsy, but evidence for treating mental illness has yet to mature.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study aimed to produce expert-informed guidance for the implementation of KMT in adults with serious mood and psychotic disorders.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A modified Delphi methodology was used to examine the opinions of KMT-experienced mental health experts. A steering group of eight such experts convened to develop an online survey comprising 33 statements regarding 1) the definition of KMT in the context of serious mood and psychotic illness; 2) identification of eligible candidates; 3) monitoring and measurement standards; and 4) best practices in employing KMT. This survey was distributed to clinician peers to examine opinions. The threshold for consensus agreement was set <i>a priori</i> at 75%.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Consensus was reached for all 33 statements (100%); therefore, the steering group approved the complete series of recommendations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This consensus provides expert-informed guidance to support the use of KMT in adults with major depressive disorder, bipolar disorder, and schizophrenia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Ede, Bernstein, Calabrese, Campbell, Laurent, Palmer, Sethi and Zupec-Kania.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ede</LastName><ForeName>Georgia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Georgia Ede MD PLLC, Newburyport, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bernstein</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Director, Ellenhorn LLC and Accord Mental Health LLC, Arlington, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Calabrese</LastName><ForeName>Lori</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Touchpoints180, South Windsor, CT, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campbell</LastName><ForeName>Iain H</ForeName><Initials>IH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Psychiatry, Center for Clinical Brain Sciences, University of Edinburgh, Kennedy Tower, Royal Edinburgh Hospital, Edinburgh, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laurent</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Licensed Mental Health Counselor, Family Renewal Inc, Vancouver, WA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palmer</LastName><ForeName>Chris M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, McLean Hospital, Belmont, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sethi</LastName><ForeName>Shebani</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zupec-Kania</LastName><ForeName>Beth</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ketogenic Therapies LLC, Elm Grove, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101642264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-861X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bipolar disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ketogenic diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">major depressive disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">schizophrenia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">serious mental illness</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>MB was the Chief Medical Officer at Ellenhorn LLC which provides comprehensive psychosocial recovery services for those with complex mental health struggles. He was the Chief Executive Officer and Chief Medical Officer at Accord Mental Health LLC, which provides immersive metabolic treatments, including ketogenic diets, for those with physical and mental health disorders. He served on the scientific and clinical advisory boards for the non-profit organizations Metabolic Mind, The Metabolic Revolution, and The Coalition for Metabolic Health and sat on the scientific advisory boards for Meru Health and MetabolicWise. LC was the Founder and Medical Director of Touchpoints180, a physician-led organization providing educational, consultative, and programmatic services supporting metabolic brain and body health, metabolic health consultations and ketogenic services, and free metabolic-forward community events. She served on the Clinician Advisory Committee for Baszucki Group and as a Clinical Advisor to the non-profits Metabolic Mind and Coalition for Metabolic Health. IC received research funding from Baszucki Group, UKRI Medical Research Council and The Wellcome Trust. He received speaker honoraria from the Society of Biological Psychiatry, Metabolic Health Summit, The Nutritional Medicine Institute and the Psychiatry Redefined Conference. He received consulting fees from the Mayo Clinic, Abbott Lingo, and Baszucki Group. He served on lived experience advisory panels for the UKRI MRC Mental Health Platform, Baszucki Group and Metabolic Mind, and the scientific advisory panel for Abbott Lingo, Metabolic Collective and Keto Live. GE served on the scientific and clinical advisory boards for Metabolic Mind, Metabolic Revolution, the Coalition for Metabolic Health, Children's Mental Health Resource Center, Owna Health, Meru Health, Accord, and the Healing Depression Project. She earned tuition fees from her CME training program Ketogenic Diets for Mental Health, received honoraria for speaking about metabolic psychiatry at medical conferences, and received royalties from her book Change Your Diet, Change Your Mind. NL was employed by and owns Family Renewal, Inc. She had a financial relationship with Ellenhorn through an honorarium for serving on the clinical advisory board of the Accord Program. She offered professional trainings through PESI and serves on clinical advisory boards for the nonprofit organizations Metabolic Mind, Metabolic Collective, Keto Live Project e.V., Institute for Personalized Therapeutic Nutrition (IPTN), and the Brain Inflammation Collaborative. CP was the founder and owner of MH2, a medical practice that provides comprehensive mental health care that may include metabolic and ketogenic therapies. He received honoraria for speaking at conferences on ketogenic therapies and received royalties from his book Brain Energy. He served on scientific and advisory boards for the nonprofit organizations Metabolic Mind, Metabolic Revolution, Countdown for a Cure, and the Coalition for Metabolic Health. SS was a cofounder of Metabolic Psychiatry Labs and has served as a scientific advisor for Found Health and Metabolic Mind. BZ-K was a private practice consultant and sole owner/employee of Ketogenic Therapies, LLC and was a paid consultant to the following non-profits: The Charlie Foundation for Ketogenic Therapies. Children's Mental Health Resource Center, and Metabolic Mind. She received an honorarium to speak at the 2025 Food and Nutrition Conference and Expo, and is a volunteer consultant to Accord Mental Health, Glut1 Deficiency Foundation, and Anorexit.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41816235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12971900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2026.1749406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2022). Mental disorders. Available online at: https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/mental-disorders (Accessed 1 August 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omori NE, Malys MK, Woo G, Mansor L. Exploring the role of ketone bodies in the diagnosis and treatment of psychiatric disorders. Front Psychiatry. (2023) 14:1142682. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2023.1142682</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2023.1142682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10149735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37139329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howes OD, Thase ME, Pillinger T. Treatment resistance in psychiatry: state of the art and new directions. Mol Psychiatry. (2022) 27:58&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1038/s41380-021-01200-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-021-01200-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8960394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34257409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CK, Hayes RD, Perera G, Broadbent MT, Fernandes AC, Lee WE, et al. Life expectancy at birth for people with serious mental illness and other major disorders from a secondary mental health care case register in London. PLoS ONE. (2011) 6:e19590. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0019590</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0019590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3097201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21611123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahlbeck K, Westman J, Nordentoft M, Gissler M, Laursen TM. Outcomes of Nordic mental health systems: life expectancy of patients with mental disorders. Br J Psychiatry. (2011) 199:453&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1192/bjp.bp.110.085100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.110.085100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21593516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caraci F, Leggio GM, Salomone S, Drago F. New drugs in psychiatry: focus on new pharmacological targets. F1000Res. (2017) 6:397. doi: 10.12688/f1000research.10233.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/f1000research.10233.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5373420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28408985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millan MJ, Goodwin GM, Meyer-Lindenberg A, Ove &#xd6;gren S. Learning from the past and looking to the future: emerging perspectives for improving the treatment of psychiatric disorders. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. (2015) 25:599&#x2013;656. doi: 10.1016/j.euroneuro.2015.01.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euroneuro.2015.01.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25836356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potkin SG, Kane JM, Correll CU, Lindenmayer JP, Agid O, Marder SR, et al. The neurobiology of treatment-resistant schizophrenia: paths to antipsychotic resistance and a roadmap for future research. Focus. (2020) 18:456&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1176/appi.focus.18309</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.focus.18309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7725153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33343259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz AP, Fernandes BS, Quevedo J, Sanches M, Soares JC. Treatment-resistant bipolar depression: concepts and challenges for novel interventions. Braz J Psychiatry. (2022) 44:178&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1590/1516-4446-2020-1627</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1516-4446-2020-1627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9041963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34037084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIntyre RS, Alsuwaidan M, Baune BT, Berk M, Demyttenaere K, Goldberg JF, et al. Treatment-resistant depression: definition, prevalence, detection, management, and investigational interventions. World Psychiatry. (2023) 22:394&#x2013;412. doi: 10.1002/wps.21120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.21120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10503923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37713549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kov&#xe1;cs Z, D'Agostino DP, Diamond D, Kindy MS, Rogers C, Ari C. Therapeutic potential of exogenous ketone supplement induced ketosis in the treatment of psychiatric disorders: review of current literature. Front Psychiatry. (2019) 10:363. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00363</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6543248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31178772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norwitz NG, Sethi S, Palmer CM. Ketogenic diet as a metabolic treatment for mental illness. Curr Opin Endocrinol Diabetes Obes. (2020) 27:269&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1097/MED.0000000000000564</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MED.0000000000000564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32773571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Chang Z, Kuja-Halkola R, D'Onofrio BM, Larsson H, Andell P, et al. Associations between general and specific mental health conditions in young adulthood and cardiometabolic complications in middle adulthood: a 40-year longitudinal familial coaggregation study of 672,823 Swedish individuals. Am J Psychiatry. (2024) 181:651&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.20220951</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.20220951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38263878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moorehead NR, Goodie JL, Krantz DS. Prospective bidirectional relations between depression and metabolic health: 30-year follow-up from the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI) coronary artery disease in young adults (CARDIA) study. Health Psychol. (2024) 43:259&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1037/hea0001339</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/hea0001339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10939906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38095973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson KT, Simard JF, Henderson VW, Nutkiewicz L, Lamers F, Nasca C, et al. Incident major depressive disorder predicted by three measures of insulin resistance: a Dutch cohort study. Am J Psychiatry. (2021) 178:914&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.2021.20101479</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2021.20101479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34551583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coello K, Vinberg M, Knop FK, Pedersen BK, McIntyre RS, Kessing LV, et al. Metabolic profile in patients with newly diagnosed bipolar disorder and their unaffected first-degree relatives. Int J Bipolar Disord. (2019) 7:8. doi: 10.1186/s40345-019-0142-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40345-019-0142-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6443746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30937579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasik J, Lago SG, V&#xe1;zquez-Bourgon J, Papiol S, Su&#xe1;rez-Pinilla P, Crespo-Facorro B, et al. Association of insulin resistance with schizophrenia polygenic risk score and response to antipsychotic treatment. JAMA Psychiatry. (2019) 76:864&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2019.0304</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2019.0304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6583823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30942838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Bianco A, Moro T, Mota JF, Coelho-Ravagnani CF. The effects of ketogenic diet on insulin sensitivity and weight loss, which came first: the chicken or the egg? Nutrients. (2023) 15:3120. doi: 10.3390/nu15143120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15143120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10385501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37513538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bl&#xe1;zquez E, Hurtado-Carneiro V, LeBaut-Ayuso Y, Vel&#xe1;zquez E, Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a L, G&#xf3;mez-Oliver F, et al. Significance of brain glucose hypometabolism, altered insulin signal transduction, and insulin resistance in several neurological diseases. Front Endocrinol. (2022) 13:873301. doi: 10.3389/fendo.2022.873301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2022.873301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9125423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35615716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calkin CV, Chengappa KNR, Cairns K, Cookey J, Gannon J, Alda M, et al. Treating insulin resistance with metformin as a strategy to improve clinical outcomes in treatment-resistant bipolar depression (the TRIO-BD study): a randomized, quadruple-masked, placebo-controlled clinical trial. J Clin Psychiatry. (2022) 83:21m14022. doi: 10.4088/JCP.21m14022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.21m14022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35120288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Napole&#xe3;o A, Fernandes L, Miranda C, Marum AP. Effects of calorie restriction on health span and insulin resistance: classic calorie restriction diet vs. ketosis-inducing diet Nutrients. (2021) 13:1302. doi: 10.3390/nu13041302</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13041302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8071299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33920973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels TE, Olsen EM, Tyrka AR. Stress and psychiatric disorders: the role of mitochondria. Annu Rev Clin Psychol. (2020) 16:165&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-082719-104030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-082719-104030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8007172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32092280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henkel ND, Wu X, O'Donovan SM, Devine EA, Jiron JM, Rowland LM, et al. Schizophrenia: a disorder of broken brain bioenergetics. Mol Psychiatry. (2022) 27:2393&#x2013;404. doi: 10.1038/s41380-022-01494-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-022-01494-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35264726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell I, Campbell H. Mechanisms of insulin resistance, mitochondrial dysfunction and the action of the ketogenic diet in bipolar disorder. Focus on the PI3K/AKT/HIF1-a pathway. Med Hypotheses. (2020) 145:110299. doi: 10.1016/j.mehy.2020.110299</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mehy.2020.110299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33091780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan LA, Naviaux JC, Wang L, Li K, Monk JM, Lingampelly SS, et al. Metabolic features of treatment-refractory major depressive disorder with suicidal ideation. Transl Psychiatry. (2023) 13:393. doi: 10.1038/s41398-023-02696-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-023-02696-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10721812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38097555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller VJ, Villamena FA, Volek JS. Nutritional ketosis and mitohormesis: potential implications for mitochondrial function and human health. J Nutr Metab. (2018) 2018:5157645. doi: 10.1155/2018/5157645</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/5157645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5828461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29607218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haridas B, Kossoff EH. Dietary treatments for epilepsy. Neurol Clin. (2022) 40:785&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1016/j.ncl.2022.03.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ncl.2022.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36270691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sethi S, Wakeham D, Ketter T, Hooshmand F, Bjornstad J, Richards B, et al. Ketogenic diet intervention on metabolic and psychiatric health in bipolar and schizophrenia: a pilot trial. Psychiatry Res. (2024) 335:115866. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2024.115866</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2024.115866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38547601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danan A, Westman EC, Saslow LR Ede G. The ketogenic diet for refractory mental illness: a retrospective analysis of 31 inpatients. Front Psychiatry. (2022) 13:951376. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2022.951376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2022.951376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9299263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35873236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang Z. Use of Delphi in health sciences research: a narrative review. Medicine. (2023) 102:e32829. doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000032829</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000032829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9936053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36800594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett D, Heale R. What are Delphi studies? Evid Based Nurs. (2020) 23:68&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1136/ebnurs-2020-103303</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ebnurs-2020-103303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32430290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diamond IR, Grant RC, Feldman BM, Pencharz PB, Ling SC, Moore AM, et al. Defining consensus: a systematic review recommends methodologic criteria for reporting of Delphi studies. J Clin Epidemiol. (2014) 67:401&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2013.12.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2013.12.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24581294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Yancy WS Jr, Gower BA, Phinney SD, Slavin J, Koutnik AP, et al. Expert consensus on nutrition and lower-carbohydrate diets: an evidence- and equity-based approach to dietary guidance. Front Nutr. (2024) 11:1376098. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2024.1376098</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2024.1376098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10937533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38487629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkpatrick CF, Bolick JP, Kris-Etherton PM, Sikand G, Aspry KE, Soffer DE, et al. Review of current evidence and clinical recommendations on the effects of low-carbohydrate and very-low-carbohydrate (including ketogenic) diets for the management of body weight and other cardiometabolic risk factors: a scientific statement from the National Lipid Association Nutrition and Lifestyle Task Force. J Clin Lipidol. (2019) 13:689&#x2013;711.e1. doi: 10.1016/j.jacl.2019.08.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacl.2019.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31611148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervenka MC, Wood S, Bagary M, Balabanov A, Bercovici E, Brown MG, et al. International recommendations for the management of adults treated with ketogenic diet therapies. Neurol Clin Pract. (2021) 11:385&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1212/CPJ.0000000000001007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/CPJ.0000000000001007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8610544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34840865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe M, Tuccinardi D, Ernesti I, Basciani S, Mariani S, Genco A, et al. Scientific evidence underlying contraindications to the ketogenic diet: an update. Obes Rev. (2020) 21:e13053. doi: 10.1111/obr.13053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7539910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32648647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diamond DM, Mason P, Bikman BT. Opinion: are mental health benefits of the ketogenic diet accompanied by an increased risk of cardiovascular disease? Front Nutr. (2024) 11:1394610. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2024.1394610</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2024.1394610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11095042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38751739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houttu V, Grefhorst A, Cohn DM, Levels JHM, Roeters van Lennep J, Stroes ESG, et al. Severe dyslipidemia mimicking familial hypercholesterolemia induced by high-fat, low-carbohydrate diets: a critical review. Nutrients. (2023) 15:962. doi: 10.3390/nu15040962</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15040962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9964047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36839320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dy&#x144;ka D, Kowalcze K, Charuta A, Paziewska A. The ketogenic diet and cardiovascular diseases. Nutrients. (2023) 15:3368. doi: 10.3390/nu15153368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15153368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10609625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37892389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soto-Mota A, Norwitz NG, Manubolu VS, Kinninger A, Wood TR, Earls J, et al. Longitudinal data from the KETO-CTA study: plaque predicts plaque, ApoB does not. JACC Adv. (2025) 4:101686. doi: 10.1016/j.jacadv.2025.101686</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacadv.2025.101686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12418260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40192608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Amorim ALB, Rodrigues EF, Sussi EL, Neri LCL. Carbohydrate restriction during lactation: a systematic review. Nutr Res. (2024) 125:91&#x2013;100. doi: 10.1016/j.nutres.2024.02.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nutres.2024.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38565002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firman CH, Mellor DD, Unwin D, Brown A. Does a ketogenic diet have a place within diabetes clinical practice? review of current evidence and controversie. Diabetes Ther. (2024) 15:77&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1007/s13300-023-01492-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13300-023-01492-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10786817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37966583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabrese L, Scolnick B, Zupec-Kania B, Beckwith C, Costello K, Frank GKW. Ketogenic diet and ketamine infusion treatment to target chronic persistent eating disorder psychopathology in anorexia nervosa: a pilot study. Eat Weight Disord. (2022) 27:3751&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1007/s40519-022-01455-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40519-022-01455-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9803738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35997954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea EM, Banks WA, Raber J. Insulin resistance in peripheral tissues and the brain: a tale of two sites. Biomedicines. (2022) 10:1582. doi: 10.3390/biomedicines10071582</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines10071582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9312939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35884888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrzak D, Kasperek K, Rekawek P, Piatkowska-Chmiel I. The therapeutic role of ketogenic diet in neurological disorders. Nutrients. (2022) 14:1952. doi: 10.3390/nu14091952</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14091952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9102882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35565918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu DY, Ravelli MN, Faltersack KM, Woods AL, Almane D, Li Z, et al. Hypocarnitinemia and its effect on seizure control in adult patients with intractable epilepsy on the modified Atkins diet. Front Nutr. (2024) 10:1304209. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2023.1304209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2023.1304209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10796679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38249600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flanagan JL, Simmons PA, Vehige J, Willcox MD, Garrett Q. Role of carnitine in disease. Nutr Metab. (2010) 7:30. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-7-30</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-7-30</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2861661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20398344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda M, Kawabe M, Takehara M, Iwano S, Kuwabara K, Kikuchi C, et al. Carnitine deficiency: risk factors and incidence in children with epilepsy. Brain Dev. (2015) 37:790&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.braindev.2014.12.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.braindev.2014.12.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25547040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman DM, Warbeck CB, Barbaro R, Khambatta C, Nagra M. Assessing the roles of retinol, vitamin K2, carnitine, and creatine in plant-based diets: a narrative review of nutritional adequacy and health implications. Nutrients. (2025) 17:525. doi: 10.3390/nu17030525</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu17030525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11820685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39940383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson JC, Mattar SG, Greenway FL, Lindquist RJ. Measuring ketone bodies for the monitoring of pathologic and therapeutic ketosis. Obes Sci Pract. (2021) 7:646&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1002/osp4.516</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/osp4.516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8488448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34631141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent N. From theory to practice: challenges and rewards of implementing ketogenic metabolic therapy in mental health. Front Nutr. (2024) 11:1331181. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2024.1331181</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2024.1331181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10881829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38389794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sondhi V, Agarwala A, Pandey RM, Chakrabarty B, Jauhari P, Lodha R, et al. Efficacy of ketogenic diet, modified Atkins diet, and low glycemic index therapy diet among children with drug-resistant epilepsy: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Pediatr. (2020) 174:944&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1001/jamapediatrics.2020.2282</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2020.2282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7400196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32761191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoeler NE, Whiteley VJ, Guglielmetti M, Neri LCL, Blackford R, Tan-Smith C, et al. Classical and modified ketogenic diets for children and young people with drug-resistant epilepsy: a reflection of international dietetic practice and best practice recommendations for dietitians. J Hum Nutr Diet. (2025) 38:e70129. doi: 10.1111/jhn.70129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jhn.70129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12516026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41077678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tayutivutikul N, Wanleenuwat P, Panapongvasin T, Klajing R, Iwanowski P. Dietary effects on antiseizure drug metabolism and management of epilepsy. Seizure. (2022) 102:14&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.seizure.2022.09.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2022.09.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36156390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinescu SCN, Apetroaei MM, Nedea MII, Arsene AL, Velescu B&#x15e;, H&#xee;ncu S, et al. Dietary influence on drug efficacy: a comprehensive review of ketogenic diet-pharmacotherapy interactions. Nutrients. (2024) 16:1213. doi: 10.3390/nu16081213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu16081213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11054576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38674903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cucuzzella M, Riley K, Isaacs D. Adapting medication for type 2 diabetes to a low carbohydrate diet. Front Nutr. (2021) 8:688540. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2021.688540</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2021.688540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8380766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34434951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armeno ML, Kossoff EH. Let food be thy medicine. The interaction between ketogenic diet therapy and anti-seizure medications: a systematic review. Epileptic Disord. (2023) 25:18&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1002/epd2.20055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/epd2.20055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36987562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skartun O, Smith CR, Laupsa-Borge J, Dankel SN. Symptoms during initiation of a ketogenic diet: a scoping review of occurrence rates, mechanisms and relief strategies. Front Nutr. (2025) 12:1538266. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2025.1538266</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2025.1538266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11978633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40206956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>