<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41635338</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Syphilitic Uveitis-Associated Chiasmal Optic Neuritis Presenting As Bitemporal Hemianopia-Like Visual Field Defects.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e100656</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e100656</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e100656</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.100656</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Syphilis is a systemic infectious disease that can involve both ocular tissues and the central nervous system,&#xa0;with syphilitic uveitis representing one of its ocular manifestations.&#xa0;We report a rare case of syphilitic uveitis occurring in conjunction with chiasmal optic neuritis. A 48-year-old man presented with blurred vision in the right eye and was found to have bilateral acute syphilitic posterior placoid chorioretinitis with vitreous opacity in the left eye. Visual field testing demonstrated bitemporal hemianopia-like defects, and magnetic resonance imaging revealed enhancement of the optic chiasm. Serologic testing confirmed syphilis. Oral amoxicillin therapy resulted in complete resolution of the inflammation and recovery of vision. This case highlights that bitemporal hemianopia in patients with syphilitic uveitis may reflect concurrent chiasmal involvement rather than uveitic pathology alone, underscoring the importance of early diagnosis and appropriate treatment are crucial for achieving favorable visual outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Ishibe et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishibe</LastName><ForeName>Tomoya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Oita University, Oita, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Otsuka</LastName><ForeName>Mami</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Oita University, Oita, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Itotani</LastName><ForeName>Maho</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Oita University, Oita, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takeda</LastName><ForeName>Atsunobu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Oita University, Oita, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acute syphilitic posterior placoid chorioretinitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bitemporal hemianopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chiasmal optic neuritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral amoxicillin hydrate therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">syphilitic uveitis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. The Ethics Committee of the Oita University Hospital issued approval 2085. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: Atsunobu Takeda declare(s) a grant from AMO Japan Inc. Atsunobu Takeda declare(s) a grant from Santen Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd. Atsunobu Takeda declare(s) a grant from HOYA Corportion. Atsunobu Takeda declare(s) a grant from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd. Atsunobu Takeda declare(s) a grant from the Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS), the Ministry of Education, Science, Sports, and Culture of Japan. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41635338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12862410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.100656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Spectral domain optical coherence tomography findings in patients with acute syphilitic posterior placoid chorioretinopathy. Pichi F, Ciardella AP, Cunningham ET Jr, et al. Retina. 2014;34:373&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23860561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology of syphilis in Tokyo from 2019 to 2022: a descriptive epidemiological study. Murata Y, Yoshida A, Suzuki E, et al. Jpn J Infect Dis. 2024;77:274&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38825456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demystifying ocular syphilis - a major review. Chauhan K, Fonollosa A, Giralt L, et al. Ocul Immunol Inflamm. 2023;31:1425&#x2013;1439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37307579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The great imitator on the rise: ocular and optic nerve manifestations in patients with newly diagnosed syphilis. Klein A, Fischer N, Goldstein M, Shulman S, Habot-Wilner Z. Acta Ophthalmol. 2019;97:0&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30328249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute syphilitic posterior placoid chorioretinitis. Gass JD, Braunstein RA, Chenoweth RG. Ophthalmology. 1990;97:1288&#x2013;1297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2243679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choriocapillaris involvement in acute syphilis posterior placoid chorioretinitis is responsible for functional impairment and points towards an immunologic mechanism: a comprehensive clinicopathological approach. Herbort CP Jr, Papasavvas I, Mantovani A. J Curr Ophthalmol. 2020;32:381&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7861097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33553841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiasmal arachnoiditis as a manifestation of generalized arachnoiditis in systemic vascular disease. Clinico-pathological report of two cases. Oliver M, Beller AJ, Behar A. Br J Ophthalmol. 1968;52:227&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC506560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4384625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurosyphilis with visual disturbances as the first symptom. Chen Z, Zhu J, Yin X. Neurol India. 2024;72:416&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38691489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical features associated with lesions other than pituitary adenoma in patients with an optic chiasmal syndrome. Mejico LJ, Miller NR, Dong LM. Am J Ophthalmol. 2004;137:908&#x2013;913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15126157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idiopathic chiasmal neuritis: clinical features and prognosis. Kawasaki A, Purvin VA. Arch Ophthalmol. 2009;127:76&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19139343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radiological differentiation of optic neuritis with myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein antibodies, aquaporin-4 antibodies, and multiple sclerosis. Ramanathan S, Prelog K, Barnes EH, et al. Mult Scler. 2016;22:470&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26163068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spectral domain optical coherence tomography findings in acute syphilitic posterior placoid chorioretinitis. Burkholder BM, Leung TG, Ostheimer TA, Butler NJ, Thorne JE, Dunn JP. J Ophthalmic Inflamm Infect. 2014;4:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3917537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24468306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ocular vs neurosyphilis. Are they the same? A guide to investigation and management. Reid GA, Halmagyi GM, Whyte C, McCluskey PJ. Eye (Lond) 2024;38:2337&#x2013;2349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11306553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38914721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical manifestations and outcome of syphilitic uveitis. Bollemeijer JG, Wieringa WG, Missotten TO, Meenken I, ten Dam-van Loon NH, Rothova A, Los LI. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2016;57:404&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26848879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluating optic system compression in sellar tumors: a novel application of quantitative pupillometry. Lenga P, Grutza M, K&#xfc;hlwein D, Walter J, Krieg SM, Beynon C. Acta Neurochir (Wien) 2024;166:510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11682009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39731604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diseases TJSoST: sexually transmitted diseases diagnosis and treatment guidelines. Syphilis section. 2020. http://chrome-extension://efaidnbmnnnibpcajpcglclefindmkaj/https://jssti.jp/pdf/syphilis-medical_guide_v2.pdf http://chrome-extension://efaidnbmnnnibpcajpcglclefindmkaj/https://jssti.jp/pdf/syphilis-medical_guide_v2.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurosyphilis cerebrospinal fluid findings in patients with ocular syphilis. Bazewicz M, Lhoir S, Makhoul D, Libois A, Van den Wijngaert S, Caspers L, Willermain F. Ocul Immunol Inflamm. 2021;29:95&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31647700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>