<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41753434</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Characterization of High-Temperature, Low-Temperature and Fatigue Performance of Phosphogypsum Warm-Mix Asphalt.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">713</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma19040713</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To explore the potential of phosphogypsum for resource utilization in asphalt pavements, this study evaluated its feasibility as a warm-mix asphalt (WMA) additive and investigated its influence on the rheological properties of asphalt binder. Phosphogypsum warm-mix asphalt was prepared by incorporating varying dosages of phosphogypsum warm-mix additive (PGWA) into both base asphalt and styrene-butadiene-styrene (SBS)-modified asphalt. The high-, medium-, and low-temperature performance of phosphogypsum warm-mix asphalt was evaluated using rheological tests. The results revealed that the complex modulus of PGWA-added base asphalt was higher than that of the base asphalt, with only minor changes in phase angle. The incorporation of the SBS modifier significantly enhanced the stiffness and elasticity of the asphalt binder. Compared with the control asphalt, PGWA-added asphalt exhibited lower creep strain and accumulated strain, higher creep recovery rates, and smaller non-recoverable compliance under the same stress level, indicating an improved resistance to high-temperature permanent deformation. PGWA increased the cumulative damage capacity and extended the fatigue life of the asphalt binder. Although the PGWA slightly reduced the low-temperature performance, the SBS modifier effectively compensated for this drawback. The Burgers model accurately captured the low-temperature rheological behavior of PGWA-added asphalt. Overall, PGWA-added asphalt demonstrated excellent rheological performance and high application potential, offering a promising pathway for the resource utilization of phosphogypsum and the development of sustainable, eco-friendly pavement materials.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jia</LastName><ForeName>Xiaodong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Urban Construction Engineering, Chongqing Open University, Chongqing 400052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ou</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Urban Construction Engineering, Chongqing Open University, Chongqing 400052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Hongzhou</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Chongqing Jiaotong University, Chongqing 400074, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National &amp; Local Joint Engineering Research Center of Transportation and Civil Engineering Materials, Chongqing 400074, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>BSH2024-02</GrantID><Agency>Postdoctoral Research Project of Chongqing Technology and Business Institute</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>KJQN202504007</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Research Program of Chongqing Municipal Education Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phosphogypsum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rheology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">solid waste recycling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">warm-mix asphalt</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41753434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12942067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma19040713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma19040713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Martins Z. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Riga Technical University; Riga, Latvia: 2010. Warm Mix Asphalt Investigation.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Khateeb G., Sukkari A., Ezzat H., Nasr E., Zeiada W. Rheology of crumb rubber-modified warm mix asphalt (WMA) Polymers. 2024;16:906. doi: 10.3390/polym16070906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym16070906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11013656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38611164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caputo P., Abe A.A., Loise V., Loise M., Loise P., Angelico R., Oliviero Rossi C. The role of additives in warm mix asphalt technology: An insight into their mechanisms of improving an emerging technology. Nanomaterials. 2020;10:1202. doi: 10.3390/nano10061202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nano10061202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7353127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32575602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kheradmand B., Muniandy R., Hua L.T., Yunus R.B., Solouki A. An overview of the emerging warm mix asphalt technology. Int. J. Pavement Eng. 2014;15:79&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1080/10298436.2013.839791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10298436.2013.839791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakar M.R., Hamzah M.O., Akhtar M.N., Woodward D. Surface free energy and moisture susceptibility evaluation of asphalt binders modified with surfactant-based chemical additive. J. Clean. Prod. 2016;112:2342&#x2013;2353. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2015.10.101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2015.10.101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng H.Y., Wu W.X., Li N.X., Wang X.B., Danilov R.G. Construction and validation of a model for asphalt foaming behavior. Phys. Fluids. 2025;37:013335. doi: 10.1063/5.0244111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0244111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuadri A.A., P&#xe9;rez-Moreno S., Altamar C.L., Navarro F.J., Bol&#xed;var J.P. Phosphogypsum as additive for foamed bitumen manufacturing used in asphalt paving. J. Clean. Prod. 2021;283:124661. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.124661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.124661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang N., Deng Z.X., Dai J.G., Yang K.K., Chen C.Y., Wang Q. Geopolymer as an additive of warm mix asphalt: Preparation and properties. J. Clean. Prod. 2018;192:906&#x2013;915. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.04.276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.04.276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang N., Nie N., Du W.J., Sun Y.H., Li R.X., Zhang R.F. Coal gangue based geopolymer as an additive of warm mix asphalt: Preparation and properties. Mater. Res. Express. 2024;11:115503. doi: 10.1088/2053-1591/ad8ff9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2053-1591/ad8ff9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou F., Xu X., Chen R., Lan J., Li G., Tan Z., Leng Z. A novel foaming additive derived from waste polyethylene terephthalate (PET) for low-carbon warm mix asphalt. Resour. Conserv. Recycl. 2024;202:107377. doi: 10.1016/j.resconrec.2023.107377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2023.107377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan P., Han Y., Cao W., Lei T., Liu Z., Min Z., Zeng S. Catalytic cracking of waste polyethylene into wax-based warm-mix agent for optimizing rheological and mechanical properties of asphalt composites. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;370:130732. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.130732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.130732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J., Jiang X., Chu Y., Xu S., Xu X. Mechanochemical Upcycling of Waste Polypropylene into Warm-Mix Modifier for Asphalt Pavement Incorporating Recycled Concrete Aggregates. Polymers. 2024;16:2494. doi: 10.3390/polym16172494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym16172494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11398089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39274127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;se H., &#xc7;elik O.N., Arslan D. A novel approach to warm mix asphalt additive production from polypropylene waste plastic via pyrolysis. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;411:134151. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou F., Leng Z., Cao R., Li G., Zhang Y., Sreeram A. Performance of zeolite synthesized from sewage sludge ash as a warm mix asphalt additive. Resour. Conserv. Recycl. 2022;181:106254. doi: 10.1016/j.resconrec.2022.106254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2022.106254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Chen M., Wu S., Zhu Y., Zhou X., Yang C., Chen D. Feasibility assessment of palmitamide derived from waste edible oil as a warm mix asphalt additive. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;401:132972. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razali R., Hainin M.R., Hassan N.A., Satar M.K.I.M., Abdulrahman S., Kamarudin S.N.N. Sustainable asphalt innovation: Harnessing treated waste cooking oil for enhanced warm mix rubberized pavement. Innov. Infrastruct. Solut. 2025;10:445. doi: 10.1007/s41062-025-02253-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41062-025-02253-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Liu Q., Fu C., Wang H., Wang T., Cheng Y., Zhou D. Laboratory investigation on the properties of warm mixing-recycled asphalt containing waste oil and plastics. Int. J. Pavement Eng. 2024;25:2301455. doi: 10.1080/10298436.2023.2301455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10298436.2023.2301455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xe1;novas C.R., Mac&#xed;as F., P&#xe9;rez-L&#xf3;pez R., Basallote M.D., Mill&#xe1;n-Becerro R. Valorization of wastes from the fertilizer industry: Current status and future trends. J. Clean. Prod. 2018;174:678&#x2013;690. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2017.10.293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2017.10.293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbonell-Barrachina A., DeLaune R.D., Jugsujinda A. Phosphogypsum chemistry under highly anoxic conditions. Waste Manag. 2002;22:657&#x2013;665. doi: 10.1016/S0956-053X(01)00044-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0956-053X(01)00044-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12214977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashad A.M. Potential use of phosphogypsum in alkali-activated fly ash under the effects of elevated temperatures and thermal shock cycles. J. Clean. Prod. 2015;87:717&#x2013;725. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2014.09.080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2014.09.080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan Q.J., Wang Z., Zhou F.J., Yu W.J., Yin Z.G., Zhang Z.Y., Chi R.A., Zhou J.C. The impurity removal and comprehensive utilization of phosphogypsum: A review. Materials. 2024;17:27. doi: 10.3390/ma17092067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17092067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11084927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38730874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaudry A., Zeroual S., Gaie-Levrel F., Moskura M., Boujrhal F.Z., Moursli R.C., Guessous A., Mouradi A., Givernaud T., Delmas R. Heavy metals pollution of the Atlantic marine environment by the Moroccan phosphate industry, as observed through their bioaccumulation in Ulva lactuca. Water Air. Soil Pollut. 2007;178:267&#x2013;285. doi: 10.1007/s11270-006-9196-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11270-006-9196-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou L., Zhang X., Zhu H., Shan B., Chen R., Yang S., Yang X. Phosphogypsum as a warm mix asphalt additive: Preparation and performance. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;490:142326. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.142326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.142326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Methods of Asphalt and Asphalt Mixture for Highway Engineering. China Communication Press; Beijing, China: 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morshed M.T. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Arkansas State University; Jonesboro, AR, USA: 2019. Laboratory Evaluation of Nanoclay Modified Asphalt Binders.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarrete C., Coelho L.M., dos Santos W.W., Monteiro S.N., Guimaraes A.C.R. Mechanical evaluation of the fine aggregate matrix in complete asphalt mixtures incorporating boiler ash. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2025;37:1850&#x2013;1861. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2025.06.071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2025.06.071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Method of Test for Estimating Damage Tolerance of Asphalt Binders Using the Linear Amplitude Sweep. AASHTO; Washington, DC, USA: 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson L.S., Isacsson U. Effect of filler on low temperature physical hardening of bitumen. Constr. Build. Mater. 1998;12:463&#x2013;470. doi: 10.1016/S0950-0618(98)00028-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0950-0618(98)00028-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheikhmotevali A.H., Ameri M. Application of bitumen rheological parameters to predict thermal cracking behavior of polymer modified asphalt mixture. Constr. Build. Mater. 2014;66:259&#x2013;267. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.05.070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.05.070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pszczola M., Jaczewski M., Rys D., Jaskula P., Szydlowski C. Evaluation of asphalt mixture low-temperature performance in bending beam creep test. Materials. 2018;11:100. doi: 10.3390/ma11010100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma11010100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5793598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29320443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsantilis L., Baglieri O., Santagata E. Low-temperature properties of bituminous nanocomposites for road applications. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;171:397&#x2013;403. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.03.154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.03.154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L., Cao Z., Alae M., Li X., Xiao F. Chemical component and low-temperature characteristics of modified asphalt composite with styrene&#x2013;butadiene rubber and liquid nitrile rubber. Int. J. Pavement Eng. 2024;25:2362874. doi: 10.1080/10298436.2024.2362874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10298436.2024.2362874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou L., Zhu H., Xu Y., Chen R., Yang X. Gray correlation entropy analysis of zero shear viscosity and high-temperature rheological parameters of phosphogypsum-modified asphalt. Case. Stud. Constr. Mat. 2022;17:17. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi Y., Wei R., Li R., Zhang J., Pei J. Evaluation of rheological master curves of asphalt mastics and asphalt-filler interaction indices. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;265:12. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A., Gupta A. Revisiting MSCR test parameters for LDPE-modified asphalt binders. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;494:143353. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.143353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.143353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashish P.K., Singh D., Bohm S. Evaluation of rutting, fatigue and moisture damage performance of nanoclay modified asphalt binder. Constr. Build. Mater. 2016;113:341&#x2013;350. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.03.057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.03.057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue L., Xie W., Wang Y., Wang C. Characterizing fatigue failure behavior of modified asphalt binders from linear amplitude sweep test; Proceedings of the 2017 International Conference on Transportation Infrastructure and Materials (ICTIM 2017); Qingdao, China. 9&#x2013;12 June 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Y., Dai M., Deng H., Deng D., Cheng P., Ma C. Incorporating hollow glass microsphere to cool asphalt pavement: Preliminary evaluation of asphalt mastic. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;244:118380. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S., Wu H., Song W., Zhan Y. Investigation of the aging behaviors of reclaimed asphalt. J. Clean. Prod. 2022;356:131837. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.131837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.131837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oner J., Sengoz B. Utilization of recycled asphalt concrete with warm mix asphalt and cost-benefit analysis. PLoS ONE. 2015;10:e116180. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0116180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0116180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4289063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25574851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J., Zhang S., Fan Z., Chen Z., Leng Z., Wang D. Interfacial interaction behavior between asphalt and solid waste fillers: Atomic-scale debonding mechanism and experimental investigation. Constr. Build. Mater. 2026;510:17. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2026.145174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2026.145174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>