<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41739949</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2329-9185</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JBJS reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JBJS Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Surgeon Experience and Patient Outcomes in Spine Surgery: A Narrative Review of Tenure, Volume, and Performance.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">e25.00250</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>&#xbb; Surgeon experience is a well-recognized determinant of patient outcomes, with greater experience associated with lower complication rates, improved efficiency, and better patient recovery.&#xbb; Experience has variable definitions across studies, including total or annual case volume, years in practice, surgeon age, and fellowship completion.&#xbb; Surgeon case volume reflects procedural repetition, and tenure encompasses judgment and decision-making that develops over time. Both independently contribute to patient outcomes.&#xbb; It is unclear whether surgeon subspecialty or age has an impact on objective outcomes, suggesting that experience and case volume are more reliable indicators of performance.&#xbb; Significant gaps remain in the literature, including inconsistent definitions, limited longitudinal data, a lack of statistically significant preliminary results, and an overrepresentation of complex academic cases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by The Journal of Bone and Joint Surgery, Incorporated.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Movva</LastName><ForeName>Arun K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-1364-2918</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Feinberg School of Medicine, Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jain</LastName><ForeName>Rishi</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4459-5504</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Feinberg School of Medicine, Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Govind</LastName><ForeName>Rohan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-7647-9740</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Louisville School of Medicine, Louisville, Kentucky.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patel</LastName><ForeName>Ashym A C</ForeName><Initials>AAC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-8619-7579</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Feinberg School of Medicine, Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Joaquin</LastName><ForeName>Theodore A</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-2474-7857</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsu</LastName><ForeName>Wellington K</ForeName><Initials>WK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patel</LastName><ForeName>Alpesh A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2193-4294</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Divi</LastName><ForeName>Srikanth N</ForeName><Initials>SN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5776-2044</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JBJS Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101674872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2329-9185</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002983" MajorTopicYN="Y">Clinical Competence</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066231" MajorTopicYN="Y">Surgeons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013131" MajorTopicYN="Y">Spine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Disclosure: The Disclosure of Potential Conflicts of Interest forms are provided with the online version of the article (http://links.lww.com/JBJSREV/B314).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41739949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.RVW.25.00250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01874474-202602000-00008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Maruthappu M, Gilbert BJ, El-Harasis MA, Nagendran M, McCulloch P, Duclos A, Carty MJ. The influence of volume and experience on individual surgical performance: a systematic review. Ann Surg. 2015;261(4):642-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weininger G, Mori M, Brooks C II, Shang M, Faggion Vinholo T, Zhang Y, Assi R, Geirsson A, Vallabhajosyula P. Association between cardiac surgeons' number of years in practice and surgical outcomes in New York cardiac centers. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3(11):e2023671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evers S, Jansen MC, Slijper HP, de Haas N, Smit X, Porsius JT, Hovius SER, Amadio PC, Selles RW. Hand surgeons performing more open carpal tunnel releases do not show better patient outcomes. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2018;141(6):1439-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Neill L, Lanska DJ, Hartz A. Surgeon characteristics associated with mortality and morbidity following carotid endarterectomy. Neurology. 2000;55(6):773-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhry NK, Fletcher RH, Soumerai SB. Systematic review: the relationship between clinical experience and quality of health care. Ann Intern Med. 2005;142(4):260-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartz AJ, Kuhn EM, Pulido J. Prestige of training programs and experience of bypass surgeons as factors in adjusted patient mortality rates. Med Care. 1999;37(1):93-103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chai CY, Chen CH, Lin HW, Lin HC. Association of increasing surgeon age with decreasing in-hospital mortality after coronary artery bypass graft surgery. World J Surg. 2010;34(1):3-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasio AT, Baumann AN, Callaghan ME, Walley KC, Gong DC, Talaski GM, Conry KT, Shafer C, Hoffmann JC. The impact of surgeon experience on surgical parameters and complication rates for the surgical management of adult spinal deformities: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Prosthesis. 2024;6(3):582-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schupper AJ, Neifert SN, Martini ML, Gal JS, Yuk FJ, Caridi JM. Surgeon experience influences patient characteristics and outcomes in spine deformity surgery. Spine Deform. 2021;9(2):341-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cahill PJ, Pahys JM, Asghar J, Yaszay B, Marks MC, Bastrom TP, Lonner BS, Shah SA, Shufflebarger HL, Newton PO, Betz RR, Samdani AF. The effect of surgeon experience on outcomes of surgery for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2014;96(16):1333-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson DP, Stevens MT, Stewart SA, Oxner WM, Dunning CE, Glennie RA. Describing the spine surgery learning curve during the first two years of independent practice. Medicine (Baltimore). 2021;100(41):e27515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng F, Chen X, Liu Z, Han Y, Chen H, Li Q, Lao L, Shen H. Learning curve of junior surgeons in robot-assisted pedicle screw placement: a comparative cohort study. Eur Spine J. 2024;33(1):314-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty KD, Chen PG, Brara HS, Anand N, Skaggs DL, Calsavara VF, Qureshi NS, Weir R, McKelvey K, Nuckols TK. Variations in surgical practice and short-term outcomes for degenerative lumbar scoliosis and spondylolisthesis: do surgeon training and experience matter? Int J Qual Health Care. 2024;36(1):mzad109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li HZ, Lin Z, Li ZZ, Yang ZY, Zheng Y, Li Y, Lu HD. Relationship between surgeon volume and outcomes in spine surgery: a dose-response meta-analysis. Ann Transl Med. 2018;6(22):441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farjoodi P, Skolasky RL, Riley LH. The effects of hospital and surgeon volume on postoperative complications after LumbarSpine surgery. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2011;36(24):2069-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarwahi V, Galina JM, Wendolowski S, DiMauro J-P, Lo Y, Amaral TD. Does surgical volume, surgeon's experience or the number of surgeons determine safety, efficacy and efficiency? Spine J. 2017;17(10):S180-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hines K, Philipp L, Thalheimer S, Montenegro TS, Gonzalez GA, Hughes LP, Leibold A, Mahtabfar A, Franco D, Heller JE, Jallo J, Prasad S, Sharan AD, Harrop JS. Increased surgeon-specific experience and volume is correlated with improved clinical outcomes in lumbar fusion patients. Clin Spine Surg. 2023;36(2):E86-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lad M, Gupta R, Para A, Gupta A, White MD, Agarwal N, Moore JM, Heary RF. An ACGME-based comparison of neurosurgical and orthopedic resident training in adult spine surgery via a case volume and hours-based analysis. J Neurosurg Spine. 2021;35(5):553-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shukla GG, Matur AV, Childress K, Tao X, Garcia-Vargas J, Mehta J, Garner RM, Gibson J, Cass D, Vorster P, Wu A, Street S, Duah HO, Motley B, Cheng J, Adogwa O. Surgeon experience matters: an exact matched analysis of TLIF outcomes demonstrates no difference in surgical outcomes between experienced neurosurgeons and orthopedic surgeons. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2024;49(11):772-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuruba V, Cherukuri AMK, Arul S, Alzarooni A, Biju S, Hassan T, Gupta R, Alasaadi S, Sikto JT, Muppuri AC, Siddiqui HF. Specialty impact on patient outcomes: paving a way for an integrated approach to spinal disorders. Cureus. 2023;15(9):e45962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satkunasivam R, Klaassen Z, Ravi B, Fok KH, Menser T, Kash B, Miles BJ, Bass B, Detsky AS, Wallis CJD. Relation between surgeon age and postoperative outcomes: a population-based cohort study. CMAJ. 2020;192(15):E385-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mussa B, Defrancisco B, Petracco P. Association between surgeon age and surgical complications: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Surg. 2025;244:116316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ells B, Canizares M, Charest-Morin R, Nataraj A, Bailey C, Wai E, Soroceanu A, Marion T, Dvorak M, Rampersaud YR, Fisher C, Wang Z, Attabib N, Christie S, Dea N, Kelly A, Singh S, Larue B, Weber M, Small C, Hall H, Glennie RA. Surgical outcomes and patient expectations and satisfaction in spine surgery stratified by surgeon age. JAMA Netw Open. 2025;8(4):e255984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald CL, Berreta RAS, Alsoof D, Homer A, Molino J, Ames CP, Shaffrey CI, Hamilton DK, Diebo BG, Kuris EO, Hart RA, Daniels AH. Treatment of adult deformity surgery by orthopedic and neurological surgeons: trends in treatment, techniques, and costs by specialty. Spine J. 2023;23(9):1365-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dada A, Dalle Ore C, Mummaneni PV, Patel A, Ambati V, Orrico KO, Tumial&#xe1;n LM, Cheng JS, Knightly JJ, DiGiorgio AM. The exponential growth of nonsurgeons performing fusions for low-back pain. J Neurosurg Spine. 2024;41(6):784-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaffrey CI, Buell TJ. Editorial. Training the next generation of spine surgeons: an orthopedic and neurosurgical collaboration with historical precedence. J Neurosurg Spine. 2021;35(5):549-51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladurner A, Giesinger K, Jost B, Zdravkovic V. The relationship between surgeon case load and revision rates in total hip arthroplasty: evidence from the Swiss National Joint Registry. Swiss Med Wkly. 2025;155:3850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravi B, Jenkinson R, Austin PC, Croxford R, Wasserstein D, Escott B, Paterson JM, Kreder H, Hawker GA. Relation between surgeon volume and risk of complications after total hip arthroplasty: propensity score matched cohort study. BMJ. 2014;348:g3284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqi A, Alamanda VK, Barrington JW, Chen AF, De A, Huddleston JI III, Bozic KJ, Lewallen D, Piuzzi NS, Mullen K, Porter KR, Springer BD. Effects of hospital and surgeon volume on patient outcomes after total joint arthroplasty: reported from the American Joint Replacement Registry. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2022;30(11):e811-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau RL, Perruccio AV, Gandhi R, Mahomed NN. The role of surgeon volume on patient outcome in total knee arthroplasty: a systematic review of the literature. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2012;13:250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valsamis EM, Collins GS, Pinedo-Villanueva R, Whitehouse MR, Rangan A, Sayers A, Rees JL. Association between surgeon volume and patient outcomes after elective shoulder replacement surgery using data from the National Joint Registry and Hospital Episode Statistics for England: population based cohort study. BMJ. 2023;381:e075355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadjadi R, Nosrat C, Su F, Lansdown DA, Feeley BT, Ma CB, Zhang AL. Impact of surgeon volume, experience, and training on outcomes after arthroscopic rotator cuff repair: a nationwide analysis of 1489 surgeons. JSES Int. 2024;8(4):837-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deemer AR, Drake JH, Littlefield CP, Egol KA. Surgeon volume impacts outcomes following ankle fracture repair. Foot Ankle Orthop. 2022;7(3):24730114221116790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon AP, Kane RL, Wang L, Wang L, Chung KC. Variation in surgeon proficiency scores and association with digit replantation outcomes. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(10):e2128765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung KC, Yoon AP, Malay S, Shauver MJ, Wang L, Kaur S; FRANCHISE Group. Patient-reported and functional outcomes after revision amputation and replantation of digit amputations: the FRANCHISE multicenter international retrospective cohort study. JAMA Surg. 2019;154(7):637-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hustedt JW, Bohl DD, Champagne L. The detrimental effect of decentralization in digital replantation in the United States: 15 years of evidence from the National Inpatient sample. J Hand Surg Am. 2016;41(5):593-601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu CC, Malay S, Chung TT, Loh CYY, Lin YT, Chung KC. The impact of hospital, surgeon, and patient characteristics on digit replantation decision: a national population study. Injury. 2020;51(11):2532-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown M, Lu Y, Chung KC, Mahmoudi E. Annual hospital volume and success of digital replantation. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2017;139(3):672-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck JD, Deegan JH, Rhoades D, Klena JC. Results of endoscopic carpal tunnel release relative to surgeon experience with the Agee technique. J Hand Surg Am. 2011;36(1):61-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agee JM, Peimer CA, Pyrek JD, Walsh WE. Endoscopic carpal tunnel release: a prospective study of complications and surgical experience. J Hand Surg Am. 1995;20(2):165-71; discussion 72.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>