<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41760069</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>105</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of preoperative blood lipid levels on early outcomes following arthroscopic rotator cuff repair: A retrospective analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e47818</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e47818</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e47818</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000047818</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Rotator cuff tears (RCTs), a prevalent shoulder condition, have seen advancements in treatment with medical technology. Arthroscopic minimally invasive surgery is now a primary approach due to its reduced trauma and complications, and the success of such repairs is crucial for patient recovery and quality of life. Recent research has indicated that dyslipidemia may hinder tendon healing. Thus, we aimed to investigate the relationship between preoperative lipid levels and postoperative outcomes, offering a scientific foundation for clinical practice. We retrospectively analyzed 104 patients who underwent arthroscopic rotator cuff repair at our hospital between April 2022 and January 2025. Each patient underwent a comprehensive blood lipid test within 1 week of presurgery. Functional assessments were conducted using the University of California-Los Angeles (UCLA) shoulder scoring scale and the Constant-Murley scoring scale, both preoperatively and 6 months postoperatively. Based on the UCLA scores, patients were categorized into excellent-recovery and poor-recovery groups. We examined the relationship between preoperative blood lipid levels and postoperative outcomes. Of the 104 patients diagnosed with RCTs, 68 exhibited excellent postoperative functional activity recovery, while 36 showed poor recovery. The poor recovery group displayed higher preoperative levels of total cholesterol (TC), total triglycerides (TG), and low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C) than the excellent recovery group, along with lower levels of high-density lipoprotein cholesterol (HDL-C) (all P-values were &lt;.05). A positive correlation was observed between the functional recovery status (assessed by the Constant-Murley score and UCLA score) of RCTs patients and preoperative HDL-C levels, while negative correlations were found with TC, TG, and LDL-C levels (all P-values were &lt;.05, among these indicators, TC exhibited a relatively strong correlation). The areas under the curve for predicting poor postoperative shoulder joint function recovery in RCTs patients were 0.820 for TC, 0.733 for TG, 0.641 for HDL-C, and 0.824 for LDL-C. TC and LDL-C demonstrated superior predictive values. Preoperative blood lipid levels in patients undergoing arthroscopic rotator cuff repair influence postoperative functional recovery. They serve as predictors for poor postoperative outcomes, aiding in the development of personalized clinical strategies to enhance patients postoperative quality of life.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Junbo</LastName><ForeName>Zhao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-7167-6988</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bone and Joint Sports Medicine, Fifth People's Hospital of Fuyang City, Fuyang City, Anhui Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiaodong</LastName><ForeName>Liu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jie</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiulong</LastName><ForeName>Liu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008055">Lipids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014280">Triglycerides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000070636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rotator Cuff Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001182" MajorTopicYN="Y">Arthroscopy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020127" MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery of Function</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008055" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lipids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057234" MajorTopicYN="N">Preoperative Period</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014280" MajorTopicYN="N">Triglycerides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">arthroscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lipid levels</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rotator cuff tears</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41760069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12956190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000047818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202602270-00075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>&#xdc;nl&#xfc; G, &#xc7;atma MF, Satilmi&#x15f; AB, et al. A comparison of the results of two different double-row repair techniques in arthroscopic repair of rotator cuff tears. Medicina (Kaunas). 2025;61:674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12028681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40282965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian Y, Huang H, Wan R, et al. Progress in studying the impact of hyperlipidemia and statins on rotator cuff injury and repair. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1279118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10641405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37965515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajalekshmi R, Agrawal DK. Understanding fibrous tissue in the effective healing of rotator cuff injury. J Surg Res (Houst). 2024;7:215&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11174978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38872898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanik EL, Keener JD, Lin SJ, et al. Identification of a novel genetic marker for risk of degenerative rotator cuff disease surgery in the UK biobank. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2021;103:1259&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8282705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33979311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo UG, Risi Ambrogioni L, Candela V, et al. Conservative versus surgical management for patients with rotator cuff tears: a systematic review and META-analysis. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2021;22:50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7796609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33419401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyffeler RW, Schenk N, Bissig P. Can a simple fall cause a rotator cuff tear? Literature review and biomechanical considerations. Int Orthop. 2021;45:1573&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8178131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33774700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duzgun I, Turgut E, Eraslan L, Elbasan B, Oskay D, Atay OA. Which method for frozen shoulder mobilization: manual posterior capsule stretching or scapular mobilization? J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2019;19:311&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6737560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31475938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu ZJ, Wei HW, Zheng WP, Wan L, Liao ZH, Chen S. Pro-oxidation status of rotator cuff tissue and expression of Beclin-1 and mTOR in patients with rotator cuff injury. Zhongguo Gu Shang. 2023;36:1136&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38130221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TT, Lin CH, Chang CL, Chi CH, Chang ST, Sheu WH. The effect of diabetes, hyperlipidemia, and statins on the development of rotator cuff disease: a nationwide, 11-year, longitudinal, population-based follow-up study. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43:2126&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26085191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sambandam SN, Khanna V, Gul A, Mounasamy V. Rotator cuff tears: an evidence based approach. World J Orthop. 2015;6:902&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4686437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26716086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thigpen CA, Shaffer MA, Gaunt BW, Leggin BG, Williams GR, Wilcox RB, 3rd. The American society of shoulder and elbow therapists&#x2019; consensus statement on rehabilitation following arthroscopic rotator cuff repair. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2016;25:521&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26995456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilotra M, O&#x2019;Brien MJ, Savoie FH, 3rd. Arthroscopic rotator cuff repair: indication and technique. Instr Course Lect. 2016;65:83&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27049183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao L, Zhao X, Mei L, et al. Dyslipidemia may impact initial recovery following arthroscopic rotator cuff repair: a retrospective study. J Orthop Surg Res. 2024;19:173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10921706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38454405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merlin Rajesh LLP, Radwan MM, Thankam FG, Agrawal DK. Rotator cuff tendon repair after injury in hyperlipidemic swine decreases biomechanical properties. J Orthop Sports Med. 2023;5:398&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10756634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38161622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatto AP, Hu DA, Feeley BT, Lansdown D. Dyslipidemia is associated with risk for rotator cuff repair failure: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JSES Rev Rep Tech. 2022;2:302&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10426695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37588872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai W, Xu Q, Li Q, et al. Piezoelectric nanofilms fabricated by coaxial electrospun polycaprolactone/barium titanate promote achilles tendon regeneration by reducing IL-17A/NF-&#x3ba;B-mediated inflammation. Bioact Mater. 2025;49:1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11914770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40110584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K, Deng G, Deng Y, et al. High cholesterol inhibits tendon-related gene expressions in tendon-derived stem cells through reactive oxygen species-activated nuclear factor-&#x3ba;B signaling. J Cell Physiol. 2019;234:18017&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30825206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K, Deng Y, Deng G, et al. High cholesterol induces apoptosis and autophagy through the ROS-activated AKT/FOXO1 pathway in tendon-derived stem cells. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2020;11:131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7082977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32197645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdani AN, Rai V, Agrawal DK. Rotator cuff health, pathology, and repair in the perspective of hyperlipidemia. J Orthop Sports Med. 2022;4:263&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9648405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36381991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Ren Y, Xu T, Geng J, Yang N, Wang R. Triglycerides: a sensitizer but not a trigger for hypertriglyceridemic acute pancreatitis. Dig Dis Sci. 2024;69:2123&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38609542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan HS, Wei L, Qu W, et al. Liver transplantation for homozygous familial hypercholesterolemia: a retrospective analysis from Chinese experience. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2025;20:26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11734353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39815304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park HB, Gwark JY, Kwack BH, Jung J. Hypo-high-density lipoproteinemia is associated with preoperative tear size and with postoperative retear in large to massive rotator cuff tears. Arthroscopy. 2020;36:2071&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32389773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia GH, Liu JN, Wong A, et al. Hyperlipidemia increases the risk of retear after arthroscopic rotator cuff repair. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2017;26:2086&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28735844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai J, Xu J, Ye Z, et al. Exosomes derived from kartogenin-preconditioned mesenchymal stem cells promote cartilage formation and collagen maturation for enthesis regeneration in a rat model of chronic rotator cuff tear. Am J Sports Med. 2023;51:1267&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36917828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolkart O, Liron T, Chechik O, et al. Statins enhance rotator cuff healing by stimulating the COX2/PGE2/EP4 pathway: an in vivo and in vitro study. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42:2869&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25184246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Oliveira LP, Vieira CP, Guerra FD, Almeida MS, Pimentel ER. Structural and biomechanical changes in the achilles tendon after chronic treatment with statins. Food Chem Toxicol. 2015;77:50&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25544391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira LP, Vieira CP, Marques PP, Pimentel ER. Do different tendons exhibit the same response following chronic exposure to statins? Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 2017;95:333&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28112540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng GJS, Lee MJH, Chen JY, Ang BFH, Hao Y, Lie DTT. Dyslipidemia with perioperative statin usage is not associated with poorer 24-month functional outcomes after arthroscopic rotator cuff surgery. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48:2518&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32692629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>