<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41769586</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Prospective Study of the Operative Treatment of Clavicular Fractures.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e102481</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e102481</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e102481</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.102481</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Objective This study aimed to evaluate the functional and radiological outcomes associated with the operative management of displaced midshaft clavicular fractures using pre-contoured locking compression plates (LCPs), specifically in cases that met surgical indications such as fracture displacement, shortening, or comminution. Methodology In this prospective study, 30 adult patients with displaced midshaft or lateral clavicular fractures underwent open reduction and internal fixation (ORIF) with pre-contoured LCPs at a tertiary care center. Patients were followed clinically for six months postoperatively. Functional outcomes were assessed using the Constant-Murley Score (CMS), and radiological union was evaluated through serial radiographs. Data were analyzed using SPSS Statistics version 25.0 (IBM Corp., Armonk, NY), and results were reported as mean &#xb1; standard deviation (SD). Results The mean age of the patients was 36.4 &#xb1; 10.2 years, with 21 patients (70%) being male. The mean time to radiographic union was 12.8 &#xb1; 2.3 weeks. At the final follow-up, the mean Constant-Murley Score (CMS) was 91.2 &#xb1; 6.4, with 24 patients (80%) demonstrating excellent shoulder function. Complications were limited to two patients (6.7%), while three patients (10%) experienced superficial infections or implant-related irritation. There were no observed cases of nonunion or implant failure. Conclusions Operative fixation of displaced clavicular fractures using pre-contoured LCPs provides stable fixation, facilitates early mobilization, and results in excellent functional recovery with minimal complications. Surgical management may be considered in active adults with displaced fractures to help optimize outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Bhakar et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhakar</LastName><ForeName>Ranj</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Trauma and Orthopaedics, Torbay and South Devon NHS Trust, Torquay, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chakrapani</LastName><ForeName>Arjun S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Trauma and Orthopaedics, Torbay and South Devon NHS Trust, Torquay, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaik</LastName><ForeName>Arfaz</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Croydon University Hospital, London, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma and Orthopaedics, Wrightington, Wigan and Leigh NHS Foundation Trust, Wigan, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alexander</LastName><ForeName>Aaron</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, University Hospital Llandough, Penarth, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murugesan</LastName><ForeName>Thivagar</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Shrewsbury and Telford NHS Foundation Trust, Shrewsbury, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anbazhagan</LastName><ForeName>Prasanna Kumar</ForeName><Initials>PK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Upper Gastrointestinal Surgery, Ashford and St Peter's Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Chertsey, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghent</LastName><ForeName>Dan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Core Medical Training, Queens Medical Centre, Nottingham, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clavicular fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional outcome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">locking compression plate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">operative fixation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prospective study</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Institutional Ethics Committee, Chhindwara Institute of Medical Sciences, Chhindwara, Madhya Pradesh issued approval CIMS/IRB/PG/2016/187. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41769586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12947958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.102481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Operative management of midshaft clavicle fractures demonstrates better long-term outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Yan MZ, Yuen WS, Yeung SC, et al. PLoS One. 2022;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9053819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35486618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The mechanism of clavicular fracture. A clinical and biomechanical analysis. Stanley D, Trowbridge EA, Norris SH. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 1988;70:461&#x2013;464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3372571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fractures of the clavicle: an overview. Donnelly TD, Macfarlane RJ, Nagy MT, Ralte P, Waseem M. Open Orthop J. 2013;7:329&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3805981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24155801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AAFP: Clavicle fractures.  [
Sep;
2025 
]. 2008. https://www.aafp.org/pubs/afp/issues/2008/0101/p65.html https://www.aafp.org/pubs/afp/issues/2008/0101/p65.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clavicle fractures: epidemiology, classification and treatment of 2 422 fractures in the Swedish Fracture Register; an observational study. Kihlstr&#xf6;m C, M&#xf6;ller M, L&#xf6;nn K, Wolf O. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2017;18:82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5312264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28202071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Systematic review of the complications of plate fixation of clavicle fractures. Wijdicks FJ, Van der Meijden OA, Millett PJ, Verleisdonk EJ, Houwert RM. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2012;132:617&#x2013;625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3332382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22237694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plate fixation of fresh displaced midshaft clavicle fractures. Shen WJ, Liu TJ, Shen YS. Injury. 1999;30:497&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10707218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonoperative treatment compared with plate fixation of displaced midshaft clavicular fractures. Surgical technique. Altamimi SA, McKee MD. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2008;90:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18310682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sling compared with plate osteosynthesis for treatment of displaced midshaft clavicular fractures: a randomized clinical trial. Virtanen KJ, Remes V, Pajarinen J, Savolainen V, Bj&#xf6;rkenheim JM, Paavola M. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2012;94:1546&#x2013;1553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22832887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonoperative treatment compared with plate fixation of displaced midshaft clavicular fractures. A multicenter, randomized clinical trial. Canadian Orthopaedic Trauma Society. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2007;89:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17200303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Open reduction and plate fixation versus nonoperative treatment for displaced midshaft clavicular fractures: a multicenter, randomized, controlled trial. Robinson CM, Goudie EB, Murray IR, et al. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2013;95:1576&#x2013;1584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24005198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A clinical method of functional assessment of the shoulder. Constant CR, Murley AH. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3791738/ Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1987;4:160&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3791738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rates of perioperative complications associated with laminectomies in patients with achondroplasia. Ain MC, Chang TL, Schkrohowsky JG, Carlisle ES, Hodor M, Rigamonti D. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2008;90:295&#x2013;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18245588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malunion after midshaft clavicle fractures in adults. Hillen RJ, Burger BJ, P&#xf6;ll RG, de Gast A, Robinson CM. Acta Orthop. 2010;81:273&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2876826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20367423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fractures of the clavicle in the adult. Epidemiology and classification. Robinson CM. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 1998;80:476&#x2013;484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9619941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estimating the risk of nonunion following nonoperative treatment of a clavicular fracture. Robinson CM, Court-Brown CM, McQueen MM, Wakefield AE. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2004;86:1359&#x2013;1365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15252081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical practice guidelines for antimicrobial prophylaxis in surgery. Bratzler DW, Dellinger EP, Olsen KM, et al. Am J Health Syst Pharm. 2013;70:195&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23327981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treatment of acute midshaft clavicle fractures: systematic review of 2144 fractures: on behalf of the Evidence-Based Orthopaedic Trauma Working Group. Zlowodzki M, Zelle BA, Cole PA, Jeray K, McKee MD. J Orthop Trauma. 2005;19:504&#x2013;507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16056089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Operative versus nonoperative care of displaced midshaft clavicular fractures: a meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. McKee RC, Whelan DB, Schemitsch EH, McKee MD. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2012;94:675&#x2013;684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22419410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>