<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41776977</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1643-3750</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical science monitor : international medical journal of experimental and clinical research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Monit</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Kantianism, Intercultural Differences, and Attitudes Toward Organ Donation Among First-Year Nursing Students.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e950445</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e950445</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e950445</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12659/MSM.950445</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>BACKGROUND The aim of this study was to evaluate if there are any intercultural differences between Polish and African students in perceiving some ethical issues of intensive therapy. Moreover, the influence of traits included in the Light Triad Scale (LTS) on these issues was checked. MATERIAL AND METHODS Forty-two Polish (PL) and 40 African (mainly Zimbabwe) English division (ED) first-year nursing students fulfilled a short survey containing LTS and 3 questions (with possible answers 1=strongly disagree to 5=strongly agree): (1) "Brain death does not exist". (2) "I would like to be an organ donor for transplantation if my brain dies". (3) "Each patient should be intensively treated even if the treatment is a source of extra suffering and there is no hope for full recovery". RESULTS The acceptance for being an organ donor was significantly lower in the ED group (r=-0.528; P&lt;0.001). Moreover, LTS Kantianism (perceiving others as "ends in themselves") correlated negatively with answers to the question "Brain death does not exist" (rho=-0.283; P=0.010*). It means those who do not believe in brain death tend to have lower Kantianism level. CONCLUSIONS There are numerous factors affecting attitudes toward organ donation in different countries (differences in education, traditional and religious beliefs, legal and ethical issues). According to the data, personality is another important field. What is interesting, there is no correlation between consideration of brain death and attitude toward becoming a donor. ED students usually believe in brain death but still rarely accept organ donation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mu&#x17c;a</LastName><ForeName>Marcin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4903-8774</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Powi&#x15b;la&#x144;ska Academy of Applied Sciences, Kwidzyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care, Ceynowa Specialist Hospital, Wejherowo, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Radkowski</LastName><ForeName>Pawe&#x142;</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care, Faculty of Medicine, Collegium Medicum, University of Warmia and Mazury, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care, Regional Specialist Hospital, Olsztyn, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care, Klinika-Hospital Zum Heiligen Geist, Fritzlar, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grabarczyk</LastName><ForeName>&#x141;ukasz</ForeName><Initials>&#x141;</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0022-2741</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Alarm Clock Clinic, Coma Recovery and Neurorehabilitation Center, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Monit</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9609063</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1234-1010</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013338" MajorTopicYN="Y">Students, Nursing</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009927" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tissue and Organ Procurement</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000941" MajorTopicYN="N">ethics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011044" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Poland</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001291" MajorTopicYN="Y">Attitude of Health Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014019" MajorTopicYN="N">Tissue Donors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001926" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain Death</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003431" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Cultural Comparison</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of interest:</b> None declared</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41776977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12969941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MSM.950445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">950445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Olawade DB, Odetayo A, Marinze S, et al. Organ transplantation in Africa: Confronting socioeconomic, cultural, and infrastructural hurdles. Curr Res Transl Med. 2025;73(3):103516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40319650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marv&#xe1;n ML, Mora-Gallegos J, Garc&#xed;a-Prieto C, et al. Knowledge and attitudes towards organ donation in a sample of physicians from two hospitals in Mexico. Gac Med Mex. 2022;158(5):289&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36572019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alobaidi S. Analysis of attitudes towards opt-out organ donation consent: A cross-sectional study among Saudi Arabian residents. Transplant Proc. 2024;56(9):1916&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39448274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naibauer S, Branagan WT, Lehto S, et al. Attitudes towards living organ donation: A cross-sectional survey study. Front Public Health. 2025;13:1552393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11979268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40206178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olawade DB, Marinze S, Qureshi N, et al. Transforming organ donation and transplantation: Strategies for increasing donor participation and system efficiency. Eur J Intern Med. 2025;133:14&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39572291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufman SB, Yaden DB, Hyde E, Tsukayama E. The light vs. dark triad of personality: Contrasting two very different profiles of human nature. Front Psychol. 2019;10:467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6423069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30914993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez EA, Ag&#xfc;ero-Flores M, Landa-Blanco M, et al. Moral injury and light triad traits: Anxiety and depression in health-care personnel during the coronavirus-2019 pandemic in Honduras. Hisp Health Care Int. 2021;19(4):230&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34664509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei Q, He Z, Koenig HG, et al. Light personality style and moral injury among Chinese health professionals. J Relig Health. 2023;62(6):3942&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37777659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocur D, Krok D, Fopka-Kowalczyk M, &#x17b;enda A. Spiritual care as a mediator in the relationship of the light and dark triad with life and work satisfaction among hospice workers. Med Pr Work Health Saf. 2025;76(2):77&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40337826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maralov VG, Maralova TP. The role of psychological capital in the development of the dark and light triad of personality traits in university students. Educ &amp; Pedag J. 2024;2(10):36&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kordbagheri M, Bagheri SM, Heris NJ, et al. The mediating role of psychological well-being in the relationship between the light triad of personality and sense of concordance with treatment adherence in patients with type 2 diabetes: A network analysis and structural equation modeling study. Acta Psychol (Amst) 2024;248:104361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38878474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasil M, Chopdar PK, Das SS, Buhalis D. Guests&#x2019; value co-creation behavior in airbnb: The role of Light Triad personality, perspective-taking, and host incivility. Int J Tourism Res. 2025;27:e70032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amreen K, Komal A, Faran M. Childhood neglect and malevolent creativity among emerging adults: exacerbating role of light triad traits. Res J Psychol. 2025;3(2):362&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerymski R, Krok D. Psychometric properties and validation of the Polish adaptation of the Light Triad Scale. Curr Issues Personal Psychol. 2019;7(4):341&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luki&#x107; P, &#x17d;ivanovi&#x107; M. Shedding light on the Light Triad: Further evidence on structural, construct, and predictive validity of the Light Triad. Pers Indiv Differs. 2021;178:110876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan SN, Okyere-Manu B. The belief in and veneration of ancestors in akan traditional thought: finding values for human well-being. Alternation. 2020;(30):11&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakari AA, Abbo Jimeta US, Abubakar MA, et al. Organ transplantation: Legal, ethical and Islamic perspective in Nigeria. Niger J Surg. 2012;18(2):53&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3762001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24027394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aissi W, Kaffel N, Bardi R, et al. Knowledge and attitudes toward organ donation among tunisian adults: Results of a national survey. Exp Clin Transplant. 2024;22(Suppl 1):224&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38385402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Vera C, O&#x2019;Diana AG, Villena AS, et al. Dark and Light Triad: A cross-cultural comparison of network analysis in 5 countries. Personality and Individual Differences. 2023;215:112377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dibaba FK, Goro KK, Wolide AD, et al. Knowledge, attitude and willingness to donate organ among medical students of Jimma University, Jimma Ethiopia: Cross-sectional study. BMC Public Health. 2020;20(1):799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7254737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32460739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waweru-Siika W, Clement ME, Lukoko L, et al. Brain death determination: The imperative for policy and legal initiatives in Sub-Saharan Africa. Global Public Health. 2015;12(5):589&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26563398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis A, Kumpfbeck A, Liebman J, et al. Barriers to the use of neurologic criteria to declare death in Africa. Am J Hosp and Palliat Med. 2021;39(2):243&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33783232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsacher A, Bade C, Ehlers J, Fehring L. How to effectively communicate health information on social media depending on the audience&#x2019;s personality traits: An experimental study in the context of organ donation in Germany. Soc Sci Med. 2023;335:116226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37734177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>