<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41930687</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1940-5480</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of the American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Am Acad Orthop Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Preoperative GLP-1 Receptor Agonist Use and Postoperative Outcomes in Orthopaedic Surgery: A Scoping Review of Perioperative and Recovery Outcomes.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5435/JAAOS-D-25-01571</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The rapid expansion of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonist (GLP-1 RA) use for weight management and diabetes has raised perioperative questions, particularly regarding delayed gastric emptying and infection risk. Emerging real-world data suggest a more nuanced perioperative profile. This scoping review synthesizes evidence on preoperative GLP-1 RA exposure and postoperative outcomes across orthopaedic procedures, with emphasis on soft-tissue sports medicine, and is intended to map associative perioperative outcomes rather than establish causality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Following Arksey-O'Malley and Joanna Briggs Institute methodology and PRISMA-ScR reporting, we searched PubMed, Scopus, Web of Science, CINAHL Ultimate, Academic Search Premier, and Ovid Emcare (2015 to 2025). Eligible studies evaluated adult orthopaedic patients with documented GLP-1 RA use and postoperative outcomes. Three reviewers independently screened and extracted study characteristics, exposure timing, perioperative management, and outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of 117 records screened, 35 studies met inclusion. Most were large retrospective cohorts spanning arthroplasty, spine fusion, trauma fixation, foot/ankle fusion, shoulder arthroplasty, and rotator cuff repair. Across hip, knee, and shoulder arthroplasty, GLP-1 RA use was generally associated with similar or lower 90-day complications, reduced periprosthetic joint infection, shorter length of stay, and fewer readmissions or revisions. Spine findings were mixed: Several cohorts showed lower infection and readmission, while others noted increased pneumonia, acute kidney injury, or pseudarthrosis in long-term semaglutide users. Trauma and ankle fracture cohorts showed no increase in short-term complications and in some cases lower mortality, with isolated signals for increased late fall-related injuries. Soft-tissue cohorts (rotator cuff repair and distal radius fixation) demonstrated fewer adverse events without increased aspiration or revision surgery risk. Functional outcomes (PROMIS) were rarely reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Preoperative GLP-1 RA exposure is not broadly associated with increased postoperative risk and often correlates with lower infection, readmission, and mortality rates-particularly in arthroplasty, spine, and ankle fracture fixation cohorts. Findings in spine surgery are more mixed and warrant cautious interpretation, especially with prolonged semaglutide exposure. Outcomes in sports-medicine procedures seem reassuring, although prospective multicenter studies with standardized perioperative protocols and PROMIS-based outcomes are needed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by the American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strickler</LastName><ForeName>Isabella</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-2434-0492</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the School of Medicine, Oakland University William Beaumont, Auburn Hills, Michigan (Strickler, Jensen, and Cragg), and the Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Corewell Health (Dean, McNassor, Guettler, and Bicos).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jensen</LastName><ForeName>Annabella</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cragg</LastName><ForeName>Kyle</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dean</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McNassor</LastName><ForeName>Ryan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guettler</LastName><ForeName>Joe</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bicos</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Am Acad Orthop Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9417468</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1067-151X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41930687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5435/JAAOS-D-25-01571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124635-990000000-01636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Drucker DJ: The GLP-1 journey: From discovery science to therapeutic impact. J Clin Invest 2024;134:e175634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shankar A, Sharma A, Vinas A, Chilton RJ: GLP-1 receptor agonists and delayed gastric emptying: Implications for invasive cardiac interventions and surgery. Cardiovasc Endocrinol Metab 2025;14:e00321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Z, Zong Y, Ma Y, et al.: Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor: Mechanisms and advances in therapy. Signal Transduct Target Ther 2024;9:234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le R, Nguyen MT, Allahwala MA, et al.: Cardiovascular protective properties of GLP-1 receptor agonists: More than just diabetic and weight loss drugs. J Clin Med 2024;13:4674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghusn W, Hurtado MD: Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists for obesity: Weight loss outcomes, tolerability, side effects, and risks. Obes Pillars 2024;12:100127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milder DA, Milder TY, Liang SS, Kam PCA: Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists: A narrative review of clinical pharmacology and implications for peri-operative practice. Anaesthesia 2024;79:735-747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Cao J, Chen J, Ning X: Risk factors for general complications after hip or knee replacement surgery in elderly patients: A single-center study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2025;26:596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal V, Amasa S, Karabacak M, Margetis K: Perioperative glucagon-like peptide-1 agonist use and rates of pseudarthrosis after single-level lumbar fusion: A large retrospective cohort study. Neurosurgery 2024;97:91-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onggo JR, Onggo JD, de Steiger R, Hau R: Greater risks of complications, infections, and revisions in the Obese versus non-obese total hip arthroplasty population of 2,190,824 patients: A meta-analysis and systematic review. Osteoarthritis Cartilage 2020;28:31-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sodhi N, Anis HK, Vakharia RM, et al.: What are risk factors for infection after primary or revision total joint arthroplasty in patients older than 80 years? Clin Orthop Relat Res 2020;478:1741-1751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang H, Zhu J, Ji F, Wang S, Xie Y, Fei H: Risk factors for postoperative complication after spinal fusion and instrumentation in degenerative lumbar scoliosis patients. J Orthop Surg Res 2014;9:15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong SH, Kwon SC, Lee JH, Moon S, Kim JI: Influence of diabetes mellitus on postoperative complications after total knee arthroplasty: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Medicina 2024;60:1757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su YC, Hsieh PC, Lai EC, Lin YC: Comparison of SGLT2 inhibitors versus GLP-1 receptor agonists and risks of osteoarthritis and arthroplasty in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Metab Res Rev 2024;40:e70051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao X, Ranganathan S, Van Halm-Lutterodt N, et al.: No difference in short-term outcomes from semaglutide treatment after cervical decompression and fusion. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2025;50:515-521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim BI, LaValva SM, Parks ML, et al.: GLP-1 receptor agonists decrease medical and surgical complications in morbidly Obese patients undergoing primary TKA. J Bone Joint Surg Am 2024;106:2213-2222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seddio AE, Gouzoulis M, Vasudevan RS, et al.: Semaglutide associated with improved postoperative outcomes following single-level posterior lumbar fusion for patients with type II diabetes. Spine J 2024;24:S52-S53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey H, O'Malley L: Scoping studies: Towards a methodological framework. Int J Soc Res Methodol 2005;8:19-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury A, Van Boxtel M, Hanley J: The impact of GLP-1 receptor agonists on postoperative outcomes following total shoulder arthroplasty. Semin Arthroplasty 2025;35:94-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsabbagh ZH, Haft M, Sudarsan M, et al.: Does use of GLP-1 agonists increase perioperative complications in patients undergoing shoulder arthroplasty? J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein AR, Olson D, Leucht P, et al.: Slimming the risks: GLP-1 receptor agonist therapy may reduce in-hospital complications and readmission rates for hip fractures compared with Obese patients not on these medications. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol 2025;35:377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heo KY, Goel RK, Woltemath A, et al.: GLP-1 receptor agonist use is not associated with increased complications after total hip arthroplasty in patients with type 2 diabetes. J Arthroplasty 2025;40:1413-1418.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzman JL, Haider MA, Cardillo C, et al.: Trends, demographics, and outcomes for GLP-1 receptor agonist use in total knee arthroplasty: An 11-year perspective. J Arthroplasty 2025;40:123-131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khak M, Adams JA, Hozien M, Ilyas AM: GLP-1 receptor agonist use in patients undergoing distal radius fracture surgery: A retrospective review of perioperative considerations. Cureus 2025;17:e89183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalid SI, Mirpuri P, Massaad E, et al.: Impact of semaglutide use for weight loss on TLIF outcomes. Clin Neurol Neurosurg 2025;242:108952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim BI, Khilnani TK, LaValva SM, et al.: Utilization of GLP-1 receptor agonists at the time of total hip arthroplasty for patients with morbid obesity. J Arthroplasty 2025;40:e1-e8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavu MS, Porto JR, Hecht CJII, et al.: The five-year incidence of progression to osteoarthritis and total joint arthroplasty in patients prescribed glucagon-like Peptide-1 receptor agonists. J Arthroplasty 2024;39:2433-2439.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawand JJ, Tansey PJ, Ghali A, et al.: GLP-1 receptor agonist use and perioperative complications following shoulder arthroplasty. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2024;33:e495-e503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levidy MF, Vatsia S, Tucker S, Rowe N, Macdonald A, Aynardi M: GLP-1 agonists' effect on infection and union after foot and ankle fusion procedures. Foot Ankle Int 2025;46:617-621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CP, Chung CH, Lu CH, et al.: Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonist therapy to attenuate the risk of knee osteoarthritis and total knee replacement in type 2 diabetes mellitus: A nation-wide cohort study. Medicine (Baltimore) 2024;103:e41243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magruder ML, Yao VJH, Rodriguez AN, Ng MK, Sasson V, Erez O: Does semaglutide use decrease complications and costs following total knee arthroplasty? J Arthroplasty 2023;38:2311-2315.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magruder ML, Miskiewicz MJ, Rodriguez AN, Mont MA: Semaglutide use prior to total hip arthroplasty results in fewer postoperative prosthetic joint infections and readmissions. J Arthroplasty 2024;39:716-720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud LI, Kehlet H, Madsbad S, et al.: Perioperative GLP-1RA management and aspiration risk in patients with diabetes undergoing fast-track hip and knee arthroplasty. Danish Med J 2025;72:A09240629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morningstar J, Lauck BJ, Bank N, Lalli T: Impact of GLP-1 receptor agonists on postoperative outcomes following ankle fracture ORIF. J Foot Ankle Surg 2025;64:644-648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng MK, Mastrokostas PG, Mastrokostas LE, et al.: Semaglutide use is associated with higher rates of pseudarthrosis and dysphagia after posterior cervical fusion. Spine J 2025;25:1974-1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira DE, Tummala S, Mittal MM, et al.: Perioperative GLP-1 receptor agonist use and long-term outcomes following lower extremity fracture fixation. Injury 2025;56:112746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranson R, Parel PM, Kirkland J, Durbin JW, Villa JC, Sterling R: GLP-1 agonists are protective against postoperative complications following total knee arthroplasty. Knee 2025;57:77-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen ST, Ilyas AM: GLP-1 receptor agonist use is not associated with increased reoperation risk following rotator cuff repair. J Orthop 2025;70:235-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seddio AE, Gouzoulis MJ, Vasudevan RS, et al.: Semaglutide utilization associated with reduced 90-day postoperative complications following single-level posterior lumbar fusion. Spine J 2025;25:485-493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seddio AE, Moran J, Gouzoulis MJ, et al.: Lower risk of postoperative complications and rotator cuff retear associated with semaglutide use in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Arthroscopy 2024;40:2031-2042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seddio AE, Vasudevan RS, Jonnalagadda A, Slevin JP, Grauer JN, Fram BR: Reduced 90-day cardiovascular and infectious complications after ankle ORIF with preoperative semaglutide. J Am Acad Orthop Surg 2025;33:e971-e978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seddio AE, Wilhelm CV, Gouzoulis MJ, et al.: Improved total shoulder arthroplasty outcomes associated with semaglutide in diabetes patients. JSES Int 2025;9:735-740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Lieu BA, Velichala SR, et al.: Short-term complications of preoperative weight-loss strategies in total knee arthroplasty: Bariatric surgery versus GLP-1 receptor agonists. J Arthroplasty 2025;40:1241-1251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidhu NS: Gastric ultrasound to assess the prokinetic efficacy of erythromycin in a patient taking GLP-1 receptor agonists. Anesth Rep 2024;12:e70008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verhey JT, Austin RP, Tarabichi S, et al.: GLP-1 agonists for weight loss: Do they increase complications in non-diabetic patients undergoing primary total hip arthroplasty? J Arthroplasty 2025;40:S101-S107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White CJK, Choudhury A, Bollepalli H, Kodra JD, Burton AT, Kraus JC: Preoperative GLP-1 receptor agonist use and postoperative outcomes following operative ankle fracture repair in patients with type 2 diabetes: A national database study. Foot Ankle Int 2025;46:1265-1274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiener JM, Sanghvi PA, Vlastaris K, et al.: GLP-1 receptor agonist medications alter outcomes of spine surgery: Analysis of 15,000+ patients. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2025;50:871-880.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie D, Englund M, Lane NE, et al.: Postoperative weight loss after anti-obesity medications and revision risk after joint replacement. JAMA Netw Open 2025;8:e2461200.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>