<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41863008</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-6215</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Trials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Trials</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>PARTIAL: study protocol for a clinical and cost-effectiveness of complex PARTIAL vs radical nephrectomy for clinically localised renal cell carcinoma randomised trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13063-026-09624-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Localised renal cell carcinoma is treated with radical nephrectomy (RN) or partial nephrectomy (PN). Nephron-sparing PN increases preservation of renal function, reducing incidence of end stage renal failure and associated cardiovascular events. In patients with exophytic T1a (&#x2264;&#x2009;4&#xa0;cm) tumours and normal contralateral kidney, PN is standard of care. In patients with T1b (&gt;&#x2009;4-7&#xa0;cm) or endophytic T1a tumours and normal contralateral kidney, the benefits of PN over RN are less clear as there are increased surgical complications and more tissue may be excised reducing the preservation of renal function. There are no high-quality studies to address if PN is superior to RN in these more complex cases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">PARTIAL is a pragmatic randomised controlled parallel group unblinded superiority trial with embedded internal pilot and economic and process evaluation. A total of 420 participants will be recruited in UK NHS centres with expertise in minimally invasive nephrectomy techniques. Eligible consenting adults with a single T1 renal cell carcinoma, normal contralateral kidney and equipoise within the multidisciplinary team confirming suitability to receive both interventions by minimally invasive approaches are randomised 1:1 to PN or RN. Patients with metastatic disease, existing chronic kidney disease, solitary functioning kidney, congenital renal abnormality, inherited kidney cancer syndrome, who lack capacity to consent or are pregnant or breast feeding are excluded. Primary outcomes are gains in preservation of renal function at 2&#xa0;years and surgical complications over the peri-operative period. Secondary outcomes are quality of life and recovery, cost and cost-effectiveness, rates of positive surgical margin, recurrence and cardiovascular events, overall survival, progression to chronic kidney disease and end stage renal failure, operative conversion and patient acceptability. Participants are followed up for 2&#xa0;years with outcomes collected from medical records and participant questionnaires.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">PARTIAL will determine if gains from PN are superior to RN and offset the potential harms and costs in complex T1 renal tumours suitable for either approach. If PN is not found to provide clinically significant gains and excess complications are confirmed, then a practice-changing case for RN as standard of care could be made.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ISRCTN 11293415. Registered prospectively on 19 January 2023.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Diana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Healthcare Randomised Trials, Aberdeen Centre for Evaluation, University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thomas</LastName><ForeName>Ruth</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Healthcare Randomised Trials, Aberdeen Centre for Evaluation, University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cotton</LastName><ForeName>Seonaidh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Healthcare Randomised Trials, Aberdeen Centre for Evaluation, University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Newlands</LastName><ForeName>Rumana</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aberdeen Centre for Evaluation, University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cooper</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aberdeen Centre for Evaluation, University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCann</LastName><ForeName>Sharon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aberdeen Centre for Evaluation, University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vale</LastName><ForeName>Luke</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>London School of Hygiene &amp; Tropical Medicine, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gillies</LastName><ForeName>Katie</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aberdeen Centre for Evaluation, University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bex</LastName><ForeName>Axel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Royal Free London NHS Foundation Trust, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Challacombe</LastName><ForeName>Ben</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guy's and St Thomas' NHS Foundation Trust, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kings College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Falloon</LastName><ForeName>Jemma</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Patient and Public Involvement Member Based in England, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>MacLennan</LastName><ForeName>Graeme</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Healthcare Randomised Trials, Aberdeen Centre for Evaluation, University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aberdeen Centre for Evaluation, University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Narahari</LastName><ForeName>Krishna</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiff University, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiff and Vale University Health Board, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nicol</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Royal Marsden NHS Foundation Trust, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sheerin</LastName><ForeName>Neil</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Newcastle upon Tyne, Newcastle, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stewart</LastName><ForeName>Grant D</ForeName><Initials>GD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tran</LastName><ForeName>Maxine</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heer</LastName><ForeName>Rakesh</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Imperial College London, London, UK. r.heer@imperial.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soomro</LastName><ForeName>Naeem</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5203-7695</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Newcastle Upon Tyne Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Newcastle, UK. n.soomro@nhs.net.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>NIHR133561</GrantID><Agency>Health Technology Assessment Programme</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Trials</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101263253</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1745-6215</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kidney cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nephron-sparing surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Radical nephrectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renal cell carcinoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renal function</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate {24}: This trial received ethical approval from South West &#x2013; Central Bristol Research Ethics Committee (22/SW/0171) on 12 December 2022. Written informed consent to participate is obtained from all participants. Written or verbal informed consent to participate in the process evaluation study is obtained from all participants and healthcare professionals. Consent for publication {32}: Not applicable as no details, images or videos relating to an individual person have been included in this publication. The template consent form (see Additional file 1), participant information leaflet (see Additional file 2) and decision-making tool supplement (see Additional file 3) are available as supplementary materials. Competing interests {28}: AB, BC, DC, JF, NSh and RT declare that they have no competing interests. DJ, GM, LV, RH, RN and SC declare grant funding paid to the institution for this research project. SM declares participation on the NIHR HTA funded LACI-3 TSC as an academic advisor. KG declares consultancy fees for a Global Clinical Trials Panel (with payments made to the institution) from Boehringer &amp; Ingelheim; honoraria for contribution to funding committee meetings for CRUK and MRC; participation on the NIHR HTA funded HAND2, FLARE and RIGHT TSCs; leadership or fiduciary roles on the MRC Clinical Training Panel, CRUK Population Health Panel and NIHR HTA CET Committee. GDS declares grants or contracts from AstraZeneca paid to the institution for the WIRE clinical trial; consultancy fees from Evinova for a workshop on a new product; support from MSD for attending ESMO 2023; paid roles as Associate Editor for the British Journal of Urology International and Clinical Directory (surgery) for the NATCAN National Kidney Cancer Audit; and an unpaid role as the chair of the kidney cancer pathway for Getting It Right First Time. MT declares leadership or fiduciary roles as an unpaid committee member for the NICE kidney cancer guidelines and for the European Association of Urologists Kidney Cancer guidelines. KN declares grants or contracts from Prostate Cymru, Welsh Govt Accelerate Programme, South East Wales Academic Health Science Partnership, Welsh Government Health Technology Grant, Health &amp; Care Research Wales Research Time Award (2023&#x2013;2026), and NIHR for TRAIN, ELIPSE, FOLLOW UP, TRANSLATE and for this research project; support for attending meetings as part of an NIHR grant; participation on the Quantum Tissue Biobank Oxford Advisory Board; and a private practice in Urology at Spire Cardiff Hospital including seeing patients with urological cancers and general urology conditions.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41863008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-026-09624-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13063-026-09624-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Smittenaar CR, Petersen KA, Stewart K, Moitt N. Cancer incidence and mortality projections in the UK until 2035. Br J Cancer. 2016;115(9):1147&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancer Research UK. Kidney cancer statistics. Available at: https://www.cancerresearchuk.org/health-professional/cancer-statistics/statistics-by-cancer-type/kidney-cancer. Accessed 14 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scosyrev E, Messing EM, Sylvester R, Campbell S, Van Poppel H. Renal function after nephron-sparing surgery versus radical nephrectomy: results from EORTC randomized trial 30904. Eur Urol. 2014;65(2):372&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell S, Uzzo RG, Allaf ME, Bass EB, Cadeddu JA, Chang A, et al. Renal mass and localized renal cancer: AUA guideline. J Urol. 2017;198(3):520&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi JE, You JH, Kim DK, Rha KH, Lee SH. Comparison of perioperative outcomes between robotic and laparoscopic partial nephrectomy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur Urol. 2015;67(5):891&#x2013;901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ljungberg B, Albiges L, Bedke J, Bex A, Capitanio U, Giles RH, et al. EAU guidelines on renal cell carcinoma. Arnhem: EAU Guidelines Office; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motzer RJ, Jonasch E, Agarwal N, Bhayani S, Bro WP, Chang SS, et al. Kidney cancer, version 2.2017, NCCN clinical practice guidelines in oncology. J Natl Compr Canc Netw. 2017;15(6):804&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buffi NM, Saita A, Lughezzani G, Porter J, Dell&#x2019;Oglio P, Amparore D, et al. Robot-assisted partial nephrectomy for complex (PADUA Score &#x2265;10) tumors: techniques and results from a multicenter experience at four high-volume centers. Eur Urol. 2020;77(1):95&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mir M, Derweesh I, Porpiglia F, Zargar H, Mottrie A, Autorino R. Partial nephrectomy versus radical nephrectomy for clinical T1b and T2 renal tumors: a systematic review and metaanalysis of comparative studies. Eur Urol. 2017;71(4):606&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierorazio PM, Johnson MH, Patel HD, Sozio SM, Sharma R, Iyoha E, et al. Management of renal masses and localized renal cancer: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Urol. 2016;196(4):989&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunath F, Schmidt S, Krabbe L, Miernik A, Dahm P, Cleves A, et al. Partial nephrectomy versus radical nephrectomy for clinical localised renal masses. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;2017(5):CD012045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Poppel H, Da Pozzo L, Albrecht W, Matveev V, Bono A, Borkowski A, et al. A prospective randomized EORTC intergroup phase 3 study comparing the complications of elective nephron-sparing surgery and radical nephrectomy for low-stage renal cell carcinoma. Eur Urol. 2007;51(6):1606&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Poppel H, Da Pozzo L, Albrecht W, Matveev V, Bono A, Borkowski A, et al. A prospective, randomised EORTC intergroup phase 3 study comparing the oncologic outcome of elective nephron-sparing surgery and radical nephrectomy for low-stage renal cell carcinoma. Eur Urol. 2011;59(4):543&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora S, Chun B, Ahlawat RK, Abaza R, Adshead J, Porter JR, et al. Conversion of robot-assisted partial nephrectomy to radical nephrectomy: a prospective multi-institutional study. Urology. 2018;113:85&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein G, Wang H, Elshabrawy A, Nashawi M, Gourley E, Liss M, et al. Analyzing national incidences and predictors of open conversion during minimally invasive partial nephrectomy for cT1 renal masses. J Endourol. 2021;35(1):30&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petros FG, Keskin SK, Yu K, Li R, Metcalfe MJ, Fellman BM, et al. Intraoperative conversion from partial to radical nephrectomy: incidence, predictive factors, and outcomes. Urology. 2018;116:114&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leppert JT, Lamberts RW, Thomas I, Chung BI, Sonn GA, Skinner EC, et al. Incident CKD after radical or partial nephrectomy. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2018;29(1):207&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tangri N, Grams ME, Levey AS, Coresh J, Appel LJ, Astor BC, et al. Multinational assessment of accuracy of equations for predicting risk of kidney failure: a meta-analysis. JAMA. 2016;315(2):164&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capitanio U, Terrone C, Antonelli A, Minervini A, Volpe A, Furlan M, et al. Nephron-sparing techniques independently decrease the risk of cardiovascular events relative to radical nephrectomy in patients with a T1a&#x2013;T1b renal mass and normal preoperative renal function. Eur Urol. 2015;67(4):683&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go AS, Chertow GM, Fan D, McCulloch CE, Hsu C. Chronic kidney disease and the risks of death, cardiovascular events, and hospitalization. N Engl J Med. 2004;351(13):1296&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ficarra V, Novara G, Secco S, Macchi V, Porzionato A, De Caro R, et al. Preoperative aspects and dimensions used for an anatomical (PADUA) classification of renal tumours in patients who are candidates for nephron-sparing surgery. Eur Urol. 2009;56(5):786&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiavina R, Novara G, Borghesi M, Ficarra V, Ahlawat R, Moon DA, et al. PADUA and R.E.N.A.L. nephrometry scores correlate with perioperative outcomes of robot&#x2010;assisted partial nephrectomy: analysis of the Vattikuti Global Quality Initiative in Robotic Urologic Surgery (GQI&#x2010;RUS) database. BJU Int. 2017;119(3):456&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mari A, Tellini R, Porpiglia F, Antonelli A, Schiavina R, Amparore D, et al. Perioperative and mid-term oncological and functional outcomes after partial nephrectomy for complex (PADUA score &#x2265;10) renal tumors: a prospective multicenter observational study (the RECORD2 Project). Eur Urol Focus. 2021;7(6):1371&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centre for Healthcare Randomised Trials, University of Aberdeen. PARTIAL trial website. Available at: https://w3.abdn.ac.uk/hsru/PARTIAL. Accessed 14 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>British Association of Urological Surgeons (BAUS). Section of oncology: BAUS nephrectomy audit 2019: analyses of nephrectomies performed between January 1st and December 31st 2019. Available at: https://www.baus.org.uk/professionals/baus_business/data_audit.aspx. Accessed 21 Sept 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Kidney Cancer Audit. National Kidney Cancer Audit: state of the nation report 2024. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Peng L, Cao D, Cheng B, Gou H, Li Y, et al. Comparison of perioperative outcomes of robot-assisted vs. laparoscopic radical nephrectomy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Oncol. 2020;10:551052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camp C, O&#x2019;Hara J, Hughes D, Adshead J. Short-term outcomes and costs following partial nephrectomy in England: a population-based study. Eur Urol Focus. 2018;4(4):579&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. Chronic kidney disease: assessment and management. Available at: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng203. Accessed 7 Mar 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UK Kidney Association. Adoption of the kidney failure risk equation. 2022. Available at: https://www.ukkidney.org/about-us/news/adoption-kidney-failure-risk-equation. Accessed 7 Mar 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delanaye P, Schaeffner E, Cozzolino M, Langlois M, Plebani M, Ozben T, et al. The new, race-free, Chronic Kidney Disease Epidemiology Consortium (CKD-EPI) equation to estimate glomerular filtration rate: is it applicable in Europe? A position statement by the European Federation of Clinical Chemistry and Laboratory Medicine (EFLM). Clin Chem Lab Med. 2022;61(1):44&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowalewski KF, M&#xfc;ller D, M&#xfc;hlbauer J, Hendrie JD, Worst TS, Wessels F, et al. The comprehensive complication index (CCI): proposal of a new reporting standard for complications in major urological surgery. World J Urol. 2021;39(5):1631&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowalewski K, M&#xfc;ller D, Kirchner M, Brinster R, M&#xfc;hlbauer J, Sidoti Abate MA, et al. Robotic-assisted versus conventional open partial nephrectomy (Robocop): a propensity score-matched analysis of 249 patients. Urol Int. 2021;105(5&#x2013;6):490&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slankamenac K, Graf R, Barkun J, Puhan MA, Clavien P. The comprehensive complication index: a novel continuous scale to measure surgical morbidity. Ann Surg. 2013;258(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aaronson NK, Ahmedzai S, Bergman B, Bullinger M, Cull A, Duez NJ, et al. The European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer QLQ-C30: a quality-of-life instrument for use in international clinical trials in oncology. J Natl Cancer Inst. 1993;85(5):365&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruish M. User&#x2019;s&#xa0;manual for the SF36v2 health survey. 3rd ed.&#xa0;Lincoln: QualityMetric Incorporated; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myles PS, Weitkamp B, Jones K, Melick J, Hensen S. Validity and reliability of a postoperative quality of recovery score: the QoR-40. Br J Anaesth. 2000;84(1):11&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLennan S, Imamura M, Lapitan MC, Omar MI, Lam TBL, Hilvano-Cabungcal AM, et al. Systematic review of oncological outcomes following surgical management of localised renal cancer. Eur Urol. 2012;61(5):972&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLennan S, Imamura M, Lapitan MC, Omar MI, Lam TBL, Hilvano-Cabungcal AM, et al. Systematic review of perioperative and quality-of-life outcomes following surgical management of localised renal cancer. Eur Urol. 2012;62(6):1097&#x2013;117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SP, Thompson RH, Boorjian SA, Weight CJ, Han LC, Murad MH, et al. Comparative effectiveness for survival and renal function of partial and radical nephrectomy for localized renal tumors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Urol. 2012;188(1):51&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breau RH, Kapoor A, Nash DM, Rowe N, Cristea O, Chan G, et al. Partial vs. radical nephrectomy and the risk of all-cause mortality, cardiovascular, and nephrological outcomes. Can Urol Assoc J. 2020;14(10):337&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekhon M, Cartwright M, Francis JJ. Development of a theory-informed questionnaire to assess the acceptability of healthcare interventions. BMC Health Serv Res. 2022;22(1):279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>COMET Initiative. Renal cancer Core Outcome Sets (R-COS) programme encompassing 1) localised renal cell carcinoma (RCC) 2) locally advanced RCC and 3) metastatic RCC. Available at: https://www.comet-initiative.org/Studies/Details/1406. Accessed 14 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y, Peng C, Wang H, Qian L. Comparison of the long-term follow-up and perioperative outcomes of partial nephrectomy and radical nephrectomy for 4 cm to 7 cm renal cell carcinoma: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Urol. 2019;19(1):48&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EAU Guidelines. Renal cell carcinoma. 2020. Available at: https://uroweb.org/guideline/renal-cellcarcinoma/. Accessed 7 Mar 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motzer RJ, Jonasch E, Michaelson MD, Nandagopal L, Gore JL, George S, et al. NCCN guidelines insights: kidney cancer, version 2.2020: featured updates to the NCCN guidelines. J Natl Compr Cancer Netw. 2019;17(11):1278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell SC, Uzzo RG, Karam JA, Chang SS, Clark PE, Souter L. Renal mass and localized renal cancer: evaluation, management, and follow-up: AUA guideline: part II. J Urol. 2021;206(2):209&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell SC, Clark PE, Chang SS, Karam JA, Souter L, Uzzo RG. Renal mass and localized renal cancer: evaluation, management, and follow-up: AUA guideline: part I. J Urol. 2021;206(2):199&#x2013;208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensalah K, Pantuck AJ, Rioux-Leclercq N, Thuret R, Montorsi F, Karakiewicz PI, et al. Positive surgical margin appears to have negligible impact on survival of renal cell carcinomas treated by nephron-sparing surgery. Eur Urol. 2010;57(3):466&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley CL, Cheville JC, Lohse CM, Zincke H, Frank I, Kwon ED, et al. A scoring algorithm to predict survival for patients with metastatic clear cell renal cell carcinoma: a stratification tool for prospective clinical trials. J Urol. 2005;174(5):1759&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapiro DD, Wells SA, Best SL, Hedican SP, Ziemlewicz TJ, Lubner MG, et al. Comparing outcomes for patients with clinical T1b renal cell carcinoma treated with either percutaneous microwave ablation or surgery. Urology. 2020;135:88&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis JJ, Johnston M, Robertson C, Glidewell L, Entwistle V, Eccles MP, et al. What is an adequate sample size? Operationalising data saturation for theory-based interview studies. Psychol Health. 2010;25(10):1229&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donovan JL, Rooshenas L, Jepson M, Elliott D, Wade J, Avery K, et al. Optimising recruitment and informed consent in randomised controlled trials: the development and implementation of the Quintet Recruitment Intervention (QRI). Curr Control Trials Cardiovasc Med. 2016;17(1):283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramsay C, Pickard R, Robertson C, Close A, Vale L, Armstrong N, et al. Systematic review and economic modelling of the relative clinical benefit and cost-effectiveness of laparoscopic surgery and robotic surgery for removal of the prostate in men with localised prostate cancer. Health Technol Assess. 2012;16(41):313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtis L, Burns A. Unit costs of health and social care 2020. Canterbury: Personal Social Services Research Unit, University of Kent; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS Reference costs. 2018/19 National cost collection data. Available at: https://www.england.nhs.uk/national-cost-collection/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazier J, Roberts J, Deverill M. The estimation a preference-based single index measure for health from the SF-36. J Health Econ. 2002;21(2):271&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews JN, Altman DG, Campbell MJ, Royston P. Analysis of serial measurements in medical research. BMJ. 1990;300(6719):230&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber JA, Thompson SG. Analysis of cost data in randomized trials: an application of the non-parametric bootstrap. Stat Med. 2000;19(23):3219&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenwick E, O&#x2019;Brien BJ, Briggs A. Cost-effectiveness acceptability curves - facts, fallacies and frequently asked questions. Health Econ. 2004;13(5):405&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacios DA, Zabor EC, Munoz-Lopez C, Roversi G, Mahmood F, Abramczyk E, et al. Does reduced renal function predispose to cancer-specific mortality from renal cell carcinoma? Eur Urol. 2021;79(6):774&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekhon M, Cartwright M, Francis JJ. Acceptability of healthcare interventions: an overview of reviews and development of a theoretical framework. BMC Health Serv Res. 2017;17(1):88&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Research. The PARTIAL study a randomised trial of the clinical and cost effectiveness of PARTIAL vs radical nephrectomy for clinically localised renal cell carcinoma. Available at: https://fundingawards.nihr.ac.uk/award/NIHR133561. Accessed 14 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houghton C, Dowling M, Meskell P, Hunter A, Gardner H, Conway A, et al. Factors that impact on recruitment to randomised trials in health care: a qualitative evidence synthesis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020;10(10):MR000045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson C, Rooshenas L, Paramasivan S, Elliott D, Jepson M, Strong S, et al. Development of a framework to improve the process of recruitment to randomised controlled trials (RCTs): the SEAR (Screened, Eligible, Approached, Randomised) framework. Curr Control Trials Cardiovasc Med. 2018;19(1):50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahar B, Gonzalgo ML. What is the current role of partial nephrectomy for T2 tumors? Can J Urol. 2017;24(2):8698&#x2013;704.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>