<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41745597</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2218-1989</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Metabolites</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Metabolites</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Metabolic Signatures Associated with the Effects of Aerobic Exercise on Depressive-like Behaviors in CUMS Rats.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">114</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/metabo16020114</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Objectives</b>: This study explored the antidepressant mechanisms of aerobic exercise in CUMS rats by analyzing urinary metabolomics (LC-MS and NMR), with the aim of providing both theoretical and practical support for exercise-based depression interventions. <b>Methods</b>: (1) Thirty-two Sprague-Dawley rats were acclimatized for one week and then randomly assigned to four groups (n = 8 per group): control (C), control + aerobic exercise group (E), CUMS model (D), and CUMS + exercise (DE). Groups D and DE were subjected to nine types of CUMS stimuli. Behavioral indicators were assessed weekly, and the successful establishment of the CUMS model was confirmed at week 3. Following successful modeling, rats in groups E and DE underwent four weeks of aerobic exercise training. Throughout this period, groups D and DE continued to receive CUMS exposure, while groups C and E were maintained under standard control conditions. (2) At the end of week 7, behavioral tests were repeated. Twelve-hour urine samples were collected for metabolomic analysis using liquid chromatography-mass spectrometry (LC-MS) and <sup>1</sup>H-NMR spectroscopy. The following morning, rats were euthanized under anesthesia. Whole blood was collected from the abdominal aorta, and serum was separated for subsequent biochemical assays. Bioinformatics approaches were employed to identify potential targets and signaling pathways associated with the antidepressant effects of aerobic exercise. (3) For statistical analysis, one-way or two-way analysis of variance (ANOVA) was applied to behavioral, physiological, and biochemical data, whereas multivariate statistical analysis was used for metabolomic data. <b>Results</b>: (1) By week 3, body mass, sucrose preference, rearing frequency, and the number of grid crossings were significantly lower in groups D and DE than in groups C and E (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.05 or <i>p</i> &lt; 0.01). These findings confirmed the successful establishment of the depression model. At week 7, all behavioral indicators in group DE showed significant recovery relative to group D (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.05 or <i>p</i> &lt; 0.01). (2) Compared with group C, corticosterone and blood ammonia levels were significantly elevated in group D (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.01). In contrast, these levels were markedly reduced in group DE compared with group D (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.01). (3) LC-MS analysis identified 25 urinary metabolites associated with depression in group D relative to group C. Among these, 21 were significantly downregulated and 4 were upregulated (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.05 or <i>p</i> &lt; 0.01), involving seven metabolic pathways. Following aerobic exercise intervention, six of these depression-related metabolites in group DE showed significant recovery (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.05 or <i>p</i> &lt; 0.01), which were associated with two metabolic pathways. (4) Integrated analysis of LC-MS and <sup>1</sup>H-NMR data revealed glutamine as a common differential metabolite, linked to three metabolic pathways. All metabolic pathways modulated by aerobic exercise were related to amino acid metabolism. (5) Bioinformatics analysis indicated that AKT1, MTOR, IL6, RAF1, and TNF were core targets through which aerobic exercise regulated urinary metabolism in CUMS rats. <b>Conclusions</b>: A four-week regimen of aerobic exercise significantly improved depressive-like behaviors and enhanced anti-fatigue capacity in CUMS rats. This exercise regimen promoted urinary metabolic remodeling, primarily through the modulation of amino acid metabolism. Furthermore, its antidepressant effect is likely mediated through the regulation of core tissue targets-including AKT1, mTOR, IL-6, RAF1, and TNF-thereby influencing key pathways such as PI3K-AKT, MAPK/ERK, and neuroinflammatory signaling.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiang</LastName><ForeName>Huan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Shanxi University, Taiyuan 030006, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Danhui</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-0787-6267</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Shanxi University, Taiyuan 030006, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Yuchen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Shanxi University, Taiyuan 030006, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Jiangtao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Changzhi Preschool Education College, Changzhi 046000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Yumei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7855-9099</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Shanxi University, Taiyuan 030006, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Metabolites</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101578790</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2218-1989</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">1H-NMR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CUMS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LC-MS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aerobic exercise</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41745597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12943010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/metabo16020114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">metabo16020114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Monroe S.M., Harkness K.L. Major Depression and Its Recurrences: Life Course Matters. Annu. Rev. Clin. Psychol. 2022;18:329&#x2013;357. doi: 10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-072220-021440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-072220-021440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L., Wang H., Chen X., Zhang Y., Zhang H., Xie P. Gut microbiota and its metabolites in depression: From pathogenesis to treatment. eBioMedicine. 2023;90:104527. doi: 10.1016/j.ebiom.2023.104527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2023.104527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10051028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36963238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nock N.L., Stoutenberg M., Cook D.B., Whitworth J.W., Janke E.A., Gordon A.J. Exercise as Medicine for People with a Substance Use Disorder: An ACSM Call to Action Statement. Curr. Sports Med. Rep. 2024;23:53&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1249/JSR.0000000000001140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0000000000001140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38315433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayor E. Neurotrophic effects of intermittent fasting, calorie restriction and exercise: A review and annotated bibliography. Front. Aging. 2023;4:1161814. doi: 10.3389/fragi.2023.1161814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fragi.2023.1161814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10273285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37334045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdirejei H.A., Peeri M., Azarbayzani M.A., Masrour F.F. Fluoxetine combined with swimming exercise synergistically reduces lipopolysaccharide-induced depressive-like behavior by normalizing the HPA axis and brain inflammation in mice. Pharmacol. Biochem. Behav. 2023;232:173640. doi: 10.1016/j.pbb.2023.173640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pbb.2023.173640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37741552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L., Tang J., Liang X., Li Y., Zhu P., Zhou M., Qin L., Deng Y., Li J., Wang Y., et al. Running exercise alleviates hippocampal neuroinflammation and shifts the balance of microglial M1/M2 polarization through adiponectin/AdipoR1 pathway activation in mice exposed to chronic unpredictable stress. Mol. Psychiatry. 2024;29:2031&#x2013;2042. doi: 10.1038/s41380-024-02464-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-024-02464-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38361125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou M., Fan Y., Xu L., Yu Z., Wang S., Xu H., Zhang J., Zhang L., Liu W., Wu L., et al. Microbiome and tryptophan metabolomics analysis in adolescent depression: Roles of the gut microbiota in the regulation of tryptophan-derived neurotransmitters and behaviors in human and mice. Microbiome. 2023;11:145. doi: 10.1186/s40168-023-01589-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40168-023-01589-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10311725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37386523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zackov&#xe1; L., J&#xe1;ni M., Br&#xe1;zail M., Nikolova Y.S., Mare&#x10c;kov&#xe1; K. Cognitive impairment and depression: Meta-analysis of structural magnetic resonance imaging studies. NeuroImage Clin. 2021;32:102830. doi: 10.1016/j.nicl.2021.102830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2021.102830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8473769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34560530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Li L., Chen J., Hu M., Zhang Y., Zhang X., Lu Y. Investigation of anti-depression effects and potential mechanisms of the ethyl acetate extract of Cynomorium songaricum Rupr. through the integration of in vivo experiments, LC-MS/MS chemical analysis, and a systems biology approach. Front. Pharmacol. 2023;14:1239197. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2023.1239197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2023.1239197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10634308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37954847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Yang X., Chen S., Wu L., Zhou J., Jia K., Ju W. Integrated Network Pharmacology and GC-MS-Based Metabolomics to Investigate the Effect of Xiang-Su Volatile Oil Against Menopausal Depression. Front. Pharmacol. 2021;12:765638. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2021.765638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2021.765638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8675254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34925022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi H., Guo Z., Jia X., Liu H., Ma L., Xue L. The key points in the pre-analytical procedures of blood and urine samples in metabolomics studies. Metabolomics. 2020;16:68. doi: 10.1007/s11306-020-01666-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11306-020-01666-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32451742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza A.L., Patti G.J. A Protocol for Untargeted Metabolomic Analysis: From Sample Preparation to Data Processing. Methods Mol. Biol. 2021;2276:357&#x2013;382. doi: 10.1007/978-1-0716-1266-8_27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-0716-1266-8_27</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9284939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34060055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Han Y., Zhou S., Tian J., Qin X., Ji C., Zhao W., Chen A. Serum metabolomic responses to aerobic exercise in rats under chronic unpredictable mild stress. Sci. Rep. 2022;12:4888. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-09102-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-09102-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8941184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35318439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Y., Jia Y., Tian J., Zhou S., Chen A., Luo X. Urine metabolomic responses to aerobic and resistance training in rats under chronic unpredictable mild stress. PLoS ONE. 2020;15:e0237377. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0237377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0237377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7423134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32785263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu B., Lin L., Su X. Global burden of depression or depressive symptoms in children and adolescents: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J. Affect. Disord. 2024;354:553&#x2013;562. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2024.03.074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2024.03.074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38490591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knezevic E., Nenic K., Milanovic V., Knezevic N.N. The Role of Cortisol in Chronic Stress, Neurodegenerative Diseases, and Psychological Disorders. Cells. 2023;12:2726. doi: 10.3390/cells12232726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells12232726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10706127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38067154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S., Chawla S., Kumar P., Ahmad R., Kumar Verma P. The chronic unpredictable mild stress (CUMS) Paradigm: Bridging the gap in depression research from bench to bedside. Brain Res. 2024;1843:149123. doi: 10.1016/j.brainres.2024.149123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2024.149123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39025397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mccarron R.M., Shapiro B., Rawles J., Luo J. Depression. Ann. Intern. Med. 2021;174:ITC65&#x2013;ITC80. doi: 10.7326/AITC202105180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/AITC202105180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33971098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-L&#xe1;zaro D., Mielgo-Ayuso J., Del Valle Soto M., Adams D.P., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Bernal J.J., Seco-Calvo J. The Effects of 6 Weeks of Tribulus terrestris L. Supplementation on Body Composition, Hormonal Response, Perceived Exertion, and CrossFit&#xae; Performance: A Randomized, Single-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Study. Nutrients. 2021;13:3969. doi: 10.3390/nu13113969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13113969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8623187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34836225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee E.H., Park J.Y., Kwon H.J., Han P.L. Repeated exposure with short-term behavioral stress resolves pre-existing stress-induced depressive-like behavior in mice. Nat. Commun. 2021;12:6682. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-26968-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-26968-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8602389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34795225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Chai X., Li X., Tan X., Yang Z. Legumain knockout improves repeated corticosterone injection-induced depression-like emotional and cognitive deficits. Behav. Brain Res. 2021;413:113464. doi: 10.1016/j.bbr.2021.113464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbr.2021.113464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kronsten V.T., Shawcross D.L. Hepatic encephalopathy and depression in chronic liver disease: Is the common link systemic inflammation? Anal. Biochem. 2022;636:114437. doi: 10.1016/j.ab.2021.114437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ab.2021.114437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34715068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan T., Li F., Xiong W., Wu B., Xiao F., He B., Jia Y. Nootkatone improves anxiety- and depression-like behavior by targeting hyperammonemia-induced oxidative stress in D-galactosamine model of liver injury. Environ. Toxicol. 2021;36:694&#x2013;706. doi: 10.1002/tox.23073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tox.23073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33270352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Xue X., Tian J., Qin X., Zhou S., Chen A., Han Y. Skeletal Muscle Metabolomic Responses to Endurance and Resistance Training in Rats under Chronic Unpredictable Mild Stress. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2021;18:1645. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18041645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18041645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7914905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33572176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Z., Ruan J., Liu X., Zheng H., Ruan J., Lu Y., Cheng B., Wu F., Wu J., Liu X., et al. Combining 1H-NMR-based metabonomics and network pharmacology to dissect the mechanism of antidepression effect of Milletia speciosa Champ on mouse with chronic unpredictable mild stress-induced depression. J. Pharm. Pharmacol. 2021;73:881&#x2013;892. doi: 10.1093/jpp/rgaa010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jpp/rgaa010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu D., Wang Z., Gao S., Han Y., Wang H., Li H., Yan H., Meng B., Mu Y., Jiang Y., et al. A rapid and sensitive LC-MS/MS method for determination of the active component K6 in serum of patients with depression. J. Pharm. Biomed. Anal. 2022;213:114691. doi: 10.1016/j.jpba.2022.114691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpba.2022.114691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35257982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng T., Huang F., Xu M., Li X., Zhang L., Yin B., Cai Y., Chen F., Zhang L., Zhang J., et al. Microbiota alterations leading to amino acid deficiency contribute to depression in children and adolescents. Microbiome. 2025;13:128. doi: 10.1186/s40168-025-02122-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40168-025-02122-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12087099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40390033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullah H., Khan A., Rengasamy K.R.R., Di Minno A., Sacchi R., Daglla M. The Efficacy of S-Adenosyl Methionine and Probiotic Supplementation on Depression: A Synergistic Approach. Nutrients. 2022;14:2751. doi: 10.3390/nu14132751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14132751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9268496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35807931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullah H., Diminno A., Esposito C., El-seedi H.R., Khalifa S.A.M., Baldi A., Greco A., Santonastaso S., Cioffi V., Sperandeo R., et al. Efficacy of a food supplement based on S-adenosyl methionine and probiotic strains in subjects with subthreshold depression and mild-to-moderate depression: A monocentric, randomized, cross-over, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Biomed. Pharmacother. 2022;156:113930. doi: 10.1016/j.biopha.2022.113930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2022.113930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36411659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tartt A.N., Mariani M.B., Hen R., Mann J.J., Boldrini M. Dysregulation of adult hippocampal neuroplasticity in major depression: Pathogenesis and therapeutic implications. Mol. Psychiatry. 2022;27:2689&#x2013;2699. doi: 10.1038/s41380-022-01520-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-022-01520-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9167750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35354926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sears S.M., Hewett S.J. Influence of glutamate and GABA transport on brain excitatory/inhibitory balance. Exp. Biol. Med. 2021;246:1069&#x2013;1083. doi: 10.1177/1535370221989263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1535370221989263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8113735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33554649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamelak M. Depression and the Glutamate/GABA-Glutamine Cycle. Curr. Neuropharmacol. 2024;23:75&#x2013;84. doi: 10.2174/1570159X22666240815120244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1570159X22666240815120244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11519819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39150032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J.Q., Derges J.D., Bodepudi A., Pokala N., Mao L.M. Roles of non-receptor tyrosine kinases in pathogenesis and treatment of depression. J. Integr. Neurosci. 2022;21:25. doi: 10.31083/j.jin2101025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31083/j.jin2101025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8850782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35164461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castr&#xe9;n E., Monteggia L.M. Brain-Derived Neurotrophic Factor Signaling in Depression and Antidepressant Action. Biol. Psychiatry. 2021;90:128&#x2013;136. doi: 10.1016/j.biopsych.2021.05.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2021.05.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34053675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza P.B., de Araujo Borba L., Castro de Jesus L., Valverde A.P., Gil-Mohapel J., Rodrigues A.L.S. Major Depressive Disorder and Gut Microbiota: Role of Physical Exercise. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2023;24:16870. doi: 10.3390/ijms242316870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms242316870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10706777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38069198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H., Sun K., Tian H., Chen X., Su S., Tu Y., Chen S., Wang J., Peng M., Zeng M., et al. Integrated metagenomic and metabolomic analysis reveals distinctive stage-specific gut-microbiome-derived metabolites in intracranial aneurysms. Gut. 2024;73:1662&#x2013;1674. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2024-332245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2024-332245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38960582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leclercq S., Ahmed H., Amadieu C., Petit G., Koistinen V., Leyrolle Q., Poncin M., St&#xe4;rkel P., Kok E., Karhunen P.J., et al. Blood metabolomic profiling reveals new targets in the management of psychological symptoms associated with severe alcohol use disorder. eLife. 2024;13:RP96937. doi: 10.7554/eLife.96937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.96937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11606602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39611656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng J., Hou J., Xiang H., Tian J., Qin X., Han Y. A Study on the Hippocampal Metabolomics Mechanism of Aerobic Exercise in Antidepressant Effects. J. Shanxi Univ. (Nat. Sci. Ed.) 2024;47:1277&#x2013;1288. doi: 10.13451/j.sxu.ns.2023150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13451/j.sxu.ns.2023150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garro-Mart&#xed;nez E., Fullana M.N., Florensa-Zanuy E., Senserrich J., Paz V., Ruiz-Bronchal E., Adell A., Castro E., D&#xed;az &#xc1;., Pazos &#xc1;., et al. mTOR Knockdown in the Infralimbic Cortex Evokes A Depressive-like State in Mouse. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2021;22:8671. doi: 10.3390/ijms22168671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22168671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8395521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34445375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazo C.E., Dlugos A.C., Sweeney K.R., Haus J.M., Angadi S.S., Carroll C.C., Dickinson J.M. The effects of acute aerobic and resistance exercise on mTOR signaling and autophagy markers in untrained human skeletal muscle. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2021;121:2913&#x2013;2924. doi: 10.1007/s00421-021-04758-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-021-04758-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10150453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34196787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yirmiya R. The inflammatory underpinning of depression: An historical perspective. Brain Behav. Immun. 2024;122:433&#x2013;443. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2024.08.048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2024.08.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39197544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseca T.R., Mendes T.T., Ramos G.P., Cabido C.E.T., Morandi R.F., Ferraz F.O., Miranda A.S., Mendon&#xe7;a V.A., Teixeira A.L., Silami-Garcia E., et al. Aerobic Training Modulates the Increase in Plasma Concentrations of Cytokines in response to a Session of Exercise. J. Environ. Public Health. 2021;2021:1304139. doi: 10.1155/2021/1304139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/1304139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7826215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33510799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang L., Gao W., Chen Y., Fang W., Lo H., Dai X., Zhang J., Chen W., Ye Q., Chen X., et al. LHPP in Glutamatergic Neurons of the Ventral Hippocampus Mediates Depression-like Behavior by Dephosphorylating CaMKII&#x3b1; and ERK. Biol. Psychiatry. 2024;95:389&#x2013;402. doi: 10.1016/j.biopsych.2023.08.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2023.08.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37678540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nayem J., Sarker R., Roknuzzaman A.S.M., Qusar M., Raihan S.Z., Islam R., Al Mahmud Z. Altered serum TNF-&#x3b1; and MCP-4 levels are associated with the pathophysiology of major depressive disorder: A case-control study results. PLoS ONE. 2023;18:e0294288. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0294288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0294288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10651034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37967104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S.H., Ko Y.J., Kim J.Y., Sim Y.J. Treadmill Running Improves Spatial Learning Memory Through Inactivation of Nuclear Factor Kappa B/Mitogen-Activated Protein Kinase Signaling Pathway in Amyloid-&#x3b2;-Induced Alzheimer Disease Rats. Int. Neurourol. J. 2021;25:S35&#x2013;S43. doi: 10.5213/inj.2142164.082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5213/inj.2142164.082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8171239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34053209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>