<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41800751</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-6623</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pain</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pain</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association between preinjury health factors and outcomes after minor to moderate motor vehicle crash injuries: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000003925</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Around 50% of individuals with minor to moderate motor vehicle crash injuries experience adverse health outcomes up to 2 years postinjury, yet the associations between preinjury health on postinjury outcomes are unclear. Understanding these associations could support risk stratification and inform targeted interventions for individuals at risk of poor postinjury outcomes. In this review, we synthesized the available evidence on these associations. We identified relevant observational studies using an electronic search of 6 databases. We assessed risk of bias using Quality in Prognosis Studies, conducted random-effects meta-analyses where possible, and provided a narrative synthesis where meta-analysis was not possible. We included 58 articles (32 study populations, n = 27,167) and conducted meta-analyses on data from 13 studies (n = 7829). Meta-analyses and narrative syntheses showed that preinjury pain doubled the odds of acute/subacute (adjusted odds ratio 2.02 [95% confidence interval 1.21-3.36]) and chronic (adjusted odds ratio 2.28 [95% confidence interval 1.52-3.43]) postinjury pain. Preinjury mental health conditions consistently predicted later mental health problems. Limited evidence indicated that preinjury pain was associated with subsequent mental health problems and perceived poor recovery, whereas preinjury mental health conditions were associated with later pain, physical disability, and lower quality of life. Across outcomes, associations with preinjury general health were absent or inconsistent; evidence for preinjury physical health, sleep, and history of injury was sparse. The certainty of evidence ranged from very low to moderate. In conclusion, evidence generally suggests that preinjury physical and psychological vulnerabilities may contribute to poor postinjury outcomes. Preinjury pain is the most robust predictor of postinjury pain, and preinjury mental health conditions may predispose individuals to later mental health problems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 International Association for the Study of Pain.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Wanyun</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RECOVER Injury Research Centre and NHMRC Centre for Research Excellence: Better Health Outcomes for Compensable Injury, The University of Queensland, Herston, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Innovation in Pain and Health Research (CIPHeR), The University of Queensland, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>STARS Education and Research Alliance, Surgical Treatment and Rehabilitation Service (STARS), The University of Queensland and Metro North Health, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Armfield</LastName><ForeName>Nigel</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RECOVER Injury Research Centre and NHMRC Centre for Research Excellence: Better Health Outcomes for Compensable Injury, The University of Queensland, Herston, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Innovation in Pain and Health Research (CIPHeR), The University of Queensland, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>STARS Education and Research Alliance, Surgical Treatment and Rehabilitation Service (STARS), The University of Queensland and Metro North Health, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Health Services Research, The University of Queensland, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Yanfei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RECOVER Injury Research Centre and NHMRC Centre for Research Excellence: Better Health Outcomes for Compensable Injury, The University of Queensland, Herston, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Innovation in Pain and Health Research (CIPHeR), The University of Queensland, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>STARS Education and Research Alliance, Surgical Treatment and Rehabilitation Service (STARS), The University of Queensland and Metro North Health, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sterling</LastName><ForeName>Michele</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8242-2685</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RECOVER Injury Research Centre and NHMRC Centre for Research Excellence: Better Health Outcomes for Compensable Injury, The University of Queensland, Herston, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Innovation in Pain and Health Research (CIPHeR), The University of Queensland, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>STARS Education and Research Alliance, Surgical Treatment and Rehabilitation Service (STARS), The University of Queensland and Metro North Health, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pain</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7508686</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0304-3959</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Preinjury health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Road traffic injury</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41800751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000003925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006396-990000000-01129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abedi M, Gane E, Aplin T, Zerguine H, Johnston V. Barriers and facilitators associated with return to work following minor to serious road traffic musculoskeletal injuries: a systematic review. J Occup Rehabil 2022;32:13&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agresti A. Categorical data analysis. Hoboken: Wiley-Interscience, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angerpointner K, Weber S, Tschech K, Schubert H, Herbst T, Ernstberger A, Kerschbaum M. Posttraumatic stress disorder after minor trauma: a prospective cohort study. Med Hypotheses 2020;135:109465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atherton K, Wiles NJ, Lecky FE, Hawes SJ, Silman AJ, Macfarlane GJ, Jones GT. Predictors of persistent neck pain after whiplash injury. Emerg Med J 2006;23:195&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajcar EA, Bieniek H, Br&#x105;czyk J, B&#x105;bel P. From past pain to future pain through the pain of others: information about other people's pain ratings can alleviate our subsequent pain. Eur J Pain 2023;27:378&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker SP, O'Neill B, Haddon W Jr, Long WB. The injury severity score: a method for describing patients with multiple injuries and evaluating emergency care. J Trauma 1974;14:187&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaudoin FL, Zhai W, Merchant RC, Clark MA, Kurz MC, Hendry P, Swor RA, Peak D, Pearson C, Domeier R, Ortiz C, McLean SA. Persistent and widespread pain among African-Americans six weeks after MVC: emergency department-based cohort study. West J Emerg Med 2020;22:139&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blincoe L, Miller T, Wang J-S, Swedler D, Coughlin T, Lawrence B, Guo F, Klauer S, Dingus T. The economic and societal impact of motor vehicle crashes, 2019 (Revised) (Report No. DOT HS 813 403). Washington, D.C., United States: National Highway Traffic Safety Administration; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohman T, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; P, Boyle E, Cassidy JD, Carroll LJ, Skillgate E. Prognosis of patients with whiplash-associated disorders consulting physiotherapy: development of a predictive model for recovery. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2012;13:264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortsov AV, Platts-Mills TF, Peak DA, Jones JS, Swor RA, Domeier RM, Lee DC, Rathlev NK, Hendry PL, Fillingim RB, McLean SA. Pain distribution and predictors of widespread pain in the immediate aftermath of motor vehicle collision. Eur J Pain 2013;17:1243&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bushnell MC, Case LK, Ceko M, Cotton VA, Gracely JL, Low LA, Pitcher MH, Villemure C. Effect of environment on the long-term consequences of chronic pain. PAIN 2015;156:S42&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo RY, Sise CB, Sise MJ, Bansal V. Quantifying the burden of pre-existing conditions in older trauma patients: a novel metric based on mortality risk. Am J Emerg Med 2019;37:1836&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell L, Smith A, McGregor L, Sterling M. Psychological factors and the development of chronic whiplash-associated disorder(s): a systematic review. Clin J Pain 2018;34:755&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancelliere C, Boyle E, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; P, Holm LW, Salmi L-R, Cassidy JD. Predicting nonrecovery in adults with incident traffic injuries including post-traumatic headache. Accid Anal Prev 2021;159:106265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancelliere C, Boyle E, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; P, Holm LW, Salmi LR, Cassidy JD. Development and validation of a model predicting post-traumatic headache six months after a motor vehicle collision in adults. Accid Anal Prev 2020;142:105580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson EB, Dalenberg CJ. A conceptual framework for the impact of traumatic experiences. Trauma, Violence, &amp; Abuse 2000;1:4&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carragee EJ. Validity of self-reported history in patients with acute back or neck pain after motor vehicle accidents. Spine J 2008;8:311&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll LJ, Cassidy JD, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; P. Frequency, timing, and course of depressive symptomatology after whiplash. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2006;31:E551&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll LJ, Ferrari R, Cassidy JD. Reduced or painful jaw movement after collision-related injuries: a population-based study. J Am Dental Assoc 2007;138:86&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll LJ, Holm LW, Hogg-Johnson S, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; P, Cassidy JD, Haldeman S, Nordin M, Hurwitz EL, Carragee EJ, van der Velde G, Peloso PM, Guzman J; Bone and Joint Decade 2000-2010 Task Force on Neck Pain and Its Associated Disorders. Course and prognostic factors for neck pain in whiplash-associated disorders (WAD): results of the bone and joint decade 2000&#x2013;2010 task force on neck pain and its associated disorders. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2008;33:S83&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carstensen TB, Fink P, Oernboel E, Kasch H, Jensen TS, Frostholm L. Sick leave within 5 years of whiplash trauma predicts recovery: a prospective cohort and register-based study. PLoS One 2015;10:e0130298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carstensen TBW, Frostholm L, Oernboel E, Kongsted A, Kasch H, Jensen TS, Fink P. Post-trauma ratings of pre-collision pain and psychological distress predict poor outcome following acute whiplash trauma: a 12-month follow-up study. PAIN 2008;139:248&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carstensen TBW, Ravn SL, Andersen TE, S&#xe6;ther SMM, &#xd8;rnb&#xf8;l E, Wellnitz KB, Kasch H, Frostholm L. Do acute illness perceptions moderate the association of pre-collision welfare benefits and later neck pain or disability following whiplash trauma? A prospective multicentre cohort study. J Clin Med 2024;13:7072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey PP, Feyer AM, Cameron ID. Course of recovery for whiplash associated disorders in a compensation setting. Injury 2015;46:2118&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clay FJ, Watson WL, Newstead SV, McClure RJ. A systematic review of early prognostic factors for persisting pain following acute orthopedic trauma. Pain Res Manag 2012;17:35&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corsalini M, Capodiferro S, Dell&#x2019;olio F, Albanese G, Quaranta N, Solarino B, Catapano S, Di Venere D. Cranio-mandibular disorders after whiplash injury: a mono-institutional clinical study on 31 patients. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2022;19:901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xf4;t&#xe9; P, Boyle E, Shearer HM, Stupar M, Jacobs C, Cassidy JD, Carette S, van der Velde G, Wong JJ, Hogg-Johnson S, Ammendolia C, Hayden JA, van Tulder M, Frank JW. Is a government-regulated rehabilitation guideline more effective than general practitioner education or preferred-provider rehabilitation in promoting recovery from acute whiplash-associated disorders? A pragmatic randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open 2019;9:e021283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covidence. A practical guide: Protocol Development for Systematic Reviews. Melbourne, Australia: Veritas Health Innovation Ltd; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davie G, Samaranayaka A, Derrett S. The role of pre-existing comorbidity on the rate of recovery following injury: a longitudinal cohort study. PLoS One 2018;13:e0193019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehring T, Ehlers A, Cleare AJ, Glucksman E. Do acute psychological and psychobiological responses to trauma predict subsequent symptom severities of PTSD and depression? Psychiatry Res 2008;161:67&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbers NA, Collie A, Hogg-Johnson S, Lippel K, Lockwood K, Cameron ID. Differences in perceived fairness and health outcomes in two injury compensation systems: a comparative study. BMC Public Health 2016;16:658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrell SF, Armfield NR, Kristjansson E, Niere K, Christensen SWM, Sterling M. Trajectories of cold but not mechanical sensitivity correspond with disability trajectories after whiplash injury. PAIN 2025;166:1328&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetz K, Lefering R, Kaske S. Pre-trauma pain is the strongest predictor of persistent enhanced pain patterns after severe trauma: results of a single-centre retrospective study. Medicina (Kaunas) 2023;59:1327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geldman M, Moore A, Cheek L. The effect of pre-injury physical fitness on the initial severity and recovery from whiplash injury, at six-month follow-up. Clin Rehabil 2008;22:364&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gennarelli TA, Wodzin E. AIS 2005: a contemporary injury scale. Injury 2006;37:1083&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgescu T, Nedelcea C. Pretrauma risk factors and posttraumatic stress disorder symptoms following subsequent exposure: multilevel and univariate meta-analytical approaches. Clin Psychol Psychother 2023;31:e2912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopinath B, Jagnoor J, Harris IA, Nicholas M, Casey P, Blyth F, Maher CG, Cameron ID. Prognostic indicators of social outcomes in persons who sustained an injury in a road traffic crash. Injury 2015;46:909&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopinath B, Jagnoor J, Harris IA, Nicholas M, Casey P, Blyth F, Maher CG, Cameron ID. Health-related quality of life 24 months after sustaining a minor musculoskeletal injury in a road traffic crash: a prospective cohort study. Traffic Inj Prev 2017;18:251&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopinath B, Jagnoor J, Kifley A, Dinh M, Craig A, Cameron ID. Predictors of health-related quality of life after non-catastrophic injury sustained in a road traffic crash. Ann Phys Rehabil Med 2020;63:280&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopinath B, Jagnoor J, Kifley A, Nicholas M, Blyth F, Kenardy J, Craig A, Cameron ID. Differential predictors of pain severity over 12 months following noncatastrophic injury sustained in a road traffic crash. The J Pain 2019;20:676&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopinath B, Jagnoor J, Nicholas M, Blyth F, Harris IA, Casey P, Cameron ID. Presence and predictors of persistent pain among persons who sustained an injury in a road traffic crash. Eur J Pain 2015;19:1111&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gozzard C, Bannister G, Langkamer G, Khan S, Gargan M, Foy C. Factors affecting employment after whiplash injury. J Bone Joint Surg Br 2001;83:506&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grinapol S, Greene T, Pagorek-Eshel S, Rodrig J, Halpern P, Gelkopf M. Prospective examination of daily life traumatic stress symptom expression following motor vehicle collisions. Psychol Trauma 2022;14:1212&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grooten WJA, Tseli E, &#xc4;ng BO, Boersma K, St&#xe5;lnacke BM, Gerdle B, Enthoven P. Elaborating on the assessment of the risk of bias in prognostic studies in pain rehabilitation using QUIPS-aspects of interrater agreement. Diagn Progn Res 2019;3:5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartling L, Pickett W, Brison RJ. Derivation of a clinical decision rule for whiplash associated disorders among individuals involved in rear-end collisions. Accid Anal Prev 2002;34:531&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayden JA, van der Windt DA, Cartwright JL, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; P, Bombardier C. Assessing bias in studies of prognostic factors. Ann Intern Med 2013;158:280&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendriks EJM, Scholten-Peeters GGM, van der Windt DAWM, Neeleman-van der Steen CWM, Oostendorp RAB, Verhagen AP. Prognostic factors for poor recovery in acute whiplash patients. PAIN 2005;114:408&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heron-Delaney M, Kenardy J, Charlton E, Matsuoka Y. A systematic review of predictors of posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD) for adult road traffic crash survivors. Injury 2013;44:1413&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heron-Delaney M, Warren J, Kenardy JA. Predictors of non-return to work 2 years post-injury in road traffic crash survivors: results from the UQ SuPPORT study. Injury 2017;48:1120&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA, Flemyng E, eds. Chapter 6: choosing effect measures and computing estimates of effect. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions version 65 (updated August 2024). Chichester, United Kingdom: John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA, Flemyng E, eds. Chapter 9: summarizing study characteristics and preparing for synthesis. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions version 65 (updated August 2024). Chichester, United Kingdom: John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm LW, Carroll LJ, David Cassidy J, Ahlbom A. Factors influencing neck pain intensity in whiplash-associated disorders in Sweden. Clin J Pain 2007;23:591&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hours M, Khati I, Charnay P, Chossegros L, Tardy H, Tournier C, Perrine A-L, Luaut&#xe9; J, Laumon B. One year after mild injury: comparison of health status and quality of life between patients with whiplash versus other injuries. J Rheumatol 2014;41:528&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huguet A, Hayden JA, Stinson J, McGrath PJ, Chambers CT, Tougas ME, Wozney L. Judging the quality of evidence in reviews of prognostic factor research: adapting the GRADE framework. Syst Rev 2013;2:71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irish L, Ostrowski SA, Fallon W, Spoonster E, Dulmen M, Sledjeski EM, Delahanty DL. Trauma history characteristics and subsequent PTSD symptoms in motor vehicle accident victims. J Trauma Stress 2008;21:377&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson MS, Boyle E, Hartvigsen J, Jensen Stochkendahl M, Carroll L, Cassidy JD. A population-based, incidence cohort study of mid-back pain after traffic collisions: factors associated with global recovery. Eur J Pain 2015;19:1486&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joormann J, McLean SA, Beaudoin FL, An X, Stevens JS, Zeng D, Neylan TC, Clifford G, Linnstaedt SD, Germine LT, Rauch SL, Musey PI, Hendry PL, Sheikh S, Jones CW, Punches BE, Fermann G, Hudak LA, Mohiuddin K, Murty V, McGrath ME, Haran JP, Pascual J, Seamon M, Peak DA, Pearson C, Domeier RM, Sergot P, Merchant R, Sanchez LD, Rathlev NK, Peacock WF, Bruce SE, Barch D, Pizzagalli DA, Luna B, Harte SE, Hwang I, Lee S, Sampson N, Koenen KC, Ressler KJ, Kessler RC. Socio-demographic and trauma-related predictors of depression within eight weeks of motor vehicle collision in the AURORA study. Psychol Med 2022;52:1934&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joormann J, Ziobrowski HN, King AJ, Gildea SM, Lee S, Sampson NA, House SL, Beaudoin FL, An X, Stevens JS, Zeng D, Neylan TC, Clifford GD, Linnstaedt SD, Germine LT, Bollen KA, Rauch SL, Haran JP, Storrow AB, Musey PI Jr, Hendry PL, Sheikh S, Jones CW, Punches BE, McGrath ME, Hudak LA, Pascual JL, Seamon MJ, Chang AM, Pearson C, Peak DA, Domeier RM, Rathlev NK, O'Neil BJ, Sanchez LD, Bruce SE, Miller MW, Pietrzak RH, Barch DM, Pizzagalli DA, Harte SE, Elliott JM, Koenen KC, McLean SA, Kessler RC. Prior histories of posttraumatic stress disorder and major depression and their onset and course in the three months after a motor vehicle collision in the AURORA study. Depress Anxiety 2022;39:56&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jull GA, S&#xf6;derlund A, Stemper BD, Kenardy J, Gross AR, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; P, Treleaven J, Bogduk N, Sterling M, Curatolo M. Toward optimal early management after whiplash injury to lessen the rate of transition to chronicity: discussion paper 5. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2011;36:S335&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamper SJ, Rebbeck TJ, Maher CG, McAuley JH, Sterling M. Course and prognostic factors of whiplash: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PAIN 2008;138:617&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenardy J, Heron-Delaney M, Warren J, Brown EA. Effect of mental health on long-term disability after a road traffic crash: results from the UQ SuPPORT study. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2015;96:410&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendrick D, Baker R, Hill T, Beckett K, Coupland C, Kellezi B, Joseph S, Barnes J, Sleney J, Christie N, Morriss R. Early risk factors for depression, anxiety and post-traumatic distress after hospital admission for unintentional injury: multicentre cohort study. J Psychosom Res 2018;112:15&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler RC, Ressler KJ, House SL, Beaudoin FL, An X, Stevens JS, Zeng D, Neylan TC, Linnstaedt SD, Germine LT, Musey PI Jr, Hendry PL, Sheikh S, Storrow AB, Jones CW, Punches BE, Datner EM, Mohiuddin K, Gentile NT, McGrath ME, van Rooij SJ, Hudak LA, Haran JP, Peak DA, Domeier RM, Pearson C, Sanchez LD, Rathlev NK, Peacock WF, Bruce SE, Miller MW, Joormann J, Barch DM, Pizzagalli DA, Sheridan JF, Smoller JW, Pace TWW, Harte SE, Elliott JM, Harnett NG, Lebois LAM, Hwang I, Sampson NA, Koenen KC, McLean SA. Socio-demographic and trauma-related predictors of PTSD within 8 weeks of a motor vehicle collision in the AURORA study. Mol Psychiatry 2021;26:3108&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kivioja J, Jensen I, Lindgren U. Early coping strategies do not influence the prognosis after whiplash injuries. Injury 2005;36:935&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kivioja J, Sj&#xe4;lin M, Lindgren U. Psychiatric morbidity in patients with chronic whiplash-associated disorder. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2004;29:1235&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JY, Walton DM, Tremblay P, May C, Millard W, Elliott JM, MacDermid JC. Defining pain and interference recovery trajectories after acute non-catastrophic musculoskeletal trauma through growth mixture modeling. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2020;21:615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis GC, Platts-Mills TF, Liberzon I, Bair E, Swor R, Peak D, Jones J, Rathlev N, Lee D, Domeier R, Hendry P, McLean SA. Incidence and predictors of acute psychological distress and dissociation after motor vehicle collision: a cross-sectional study. J Trauma Dissociation 2014;15:527&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayou R, Bryant B, Ehlers A. Prediction of psychological outcomes one year after a motor vehicle accident. Am J Psychiatry 2001;158:1231&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean SA, Ulirsch JC, Slade GD, Soward AC, Swor RA, Peak DA, Jones JS, Rathlev NK, Lee DC, Domeier RM, Hendry PL, Bortsov AV, Bair E. Incidence and predictors of neck and widespread pain after motor vehicle collision among US litigants and nonlitigants. PAIN 2014;155:309&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melsen WG, Bootsma MCJ, Rovers MM, Bonten MJM. The effects of clinical and statistical heterogeneity on the predictive values of results from meta-analyses. Clin Microbiol Infect 2014;20:123&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motor Accident Insurance Commission. Annual CTP scheme insights: 2022-23. Brisbane, Queensland, Australia: Queensland Government; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naylor JM, Bhandari P, Descallar J, Yang OO, Rider M, Mayland EC, Tang C, Brady B, Lim D, Santalucia Y, Gabbe BJ, Hassett G, Baker E. Comparison of short-term outcomes between people with and without a pre-morbid mental health diagnosis following surgery for traumatic hand injury: a prospective longitudinal study of a multicultural cohort. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2023;24:805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neylan TC, Kessler RC, Ressler KJ, Clifford G, Beaudoin FL, An X, Stevens JS, Zeng D, Linnstaedt SD, Germine LT, Sheikh S, Storrow AB, Punches BE, Mohiuddin K, Gentile NT, McGrath ME, van Rooij SJH, Haran JP, Peak DA, Domeier RM, Pearson C, Sanchez LD, Rathlev NK, Peacock WF, Bruce SE, Joormann J, Barch DM, Pizzagalli DA, Sheridan JF, Harte SE, Elliott JM, Hwang I, Petukhova MV, Sampson NA, Koenen KC, McLean SA. Prior sleep problems and adverse post-traumatic neuropsychiatric sequelae of motor vehicle collision in the AURORA study. Sleep 2021;44:zsaa200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obermann M, Nebel K, Riegel A, Thiemann D, Yoon MS, Keidel M, Stude P, Diener H, Katsarava Z. Incidence and predictors of chronic headache attributed to whiplash injury. Cephalalgia 2010;30:528&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osterland TB, Kasch H, Frostholm L, Bendix T, Jensen TS, Jensen JS, Carstensen TBW, Osterland TB, Jensen TS, Jensen JS, Carstensen TBW. Pre-collision medical diagnoses predict chronic neck pain following acute whiplash-trauma. Clin J Pain 2019;35:304&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacella-LaBarbara ML, Plaitano EG, Suffoletto BP, Kuhn E, Germain A, Jaramillo S, Repine M, Callaway CW. A longitudinal assessment of posttraumatic stress symptoms and pain catastrophizing after injury. Rehabil Psychol 2023;68:32&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, Shamseer L, Tetzlaff JM, Akl EA, Brennan SE, Chou R, Glanville J, Grimshaw JM, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Lalu MM, Li T, Loder EW, Mayo-Wilson E, McDonald S, McGuinness LA, Stewart LA, Thomas J, Tricco AC, Welch VA, Whiting P, Moher D. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ 2021;372:n71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palml&#xf6;f L, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; P, Holm LW, Carroll LJ, Cassidy D, Skillgate E. Are prevalent self-reported cardiovascular disorders associated with delayed recovery from whiplash-associated disorders: a population-based cohort study. Clin J Pain 2015;31:247&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadomanolakis-Pakis N, Munch PV, Carl&#xe9; N, Uhrbrand CG, Haroutounian S, Nikolajsen L. Prognostic clinical prediction models for acute post-surgical pain in adults: a systematic review. Anaesthesia 2024;79:1335&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pape E, Brox JI, Hagen KB, Natvig B, Schirmer H. Prognostic factors for chronic neck pain in persons with minor or moderate injuries in traffic accidents. Accid Anal Prev 2007;39:135&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papic C, Kifley A, Craig A, Grant G, Collie A, Pozzato I, Gabbe B, Derrett S, Rebbeck T, Jagnoor J, Cameron ID. Factors associated with long term work incapacity following a non-catastrophic road traffic injury: analysis of a two-year prospective cohort study. BMC Public Health 2022;22:1498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peairs EM, Chari T, Kuehn SJ, Valan B, Rowe DG, Hurley ET, Aitchison AH, Paul AV, Henriquez A, Hendren S, Lentz TA, P&#xe9;an CA, DeBaun M. The association of pre-existing mental health conditions and patient outcomes after lower extremity orthopaedic trauma: a scoping review. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol 2024;34:1111&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platts-Mills TF, Nebolisa BC, Flannigan SA, Richmond NL, Domeier RM, Swor RA, Hendry PL, Peak DA, Rathlev NK, Jones JS, Lee DC, Jones CW, McLean SA. Post-traumatic stress disorder among older adults experiencing motor vehicle collision: a multicenter prospective cohort study. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry 2017;25:953&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozzato I, Craig A, Gopinath B, Kifley A, Tran Y, Jagnoor J, Cameron ID. Outcomes after traffic injury: mental health comorbidity and relationship with pain interference. BMC Psychiatry 2020;20:189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozzato I, Tran Y, Gopinath B, Cameron ID, Craig A. The contribution of pre-injury vulnerability to risk of psychiatric morbidity in adults injured in a road traffic crash: comparisons with non-injury controls. J Psychiatr Res 2021;140:77&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozzato I, Tran Y, Gopinath B, Thuraisingham RA, Cameron ID, Craig A. The role of stress reactivity and pre-injury psychosocial vulnerability to psychological and physical health immediately after traumatic injury. Psychoneuroendocrinology 2021;127:105190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Queensland Government Open Data Portal. Compulsory Third Party (CTP) statistics: Injury severity costs breakdown. Brisbane, Queensland, Australia: Queensland Government; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radanov BP, Distefano G, Schnidrig A, Ballinari P. Role of psychosocial stress in recovery from common whiplash. Lancet 1991;338:712&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radanov BP, Distefano G, Schnidrig A, Sturzenegger M. Psychosocial stress, cognitive performance and disability after common whiplash. J Psychosom Res 1993;37:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radanov BP, Sturzenegger M, Di Stefano G. Long-term outcome after whiplash injury: a 2-year follow-up considering features of injury mechanism and somatic, radiologic, and psychosocial findings. Medicine 1995;74:281&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riley RD, Moons KGM, Snell KIE, Ensor J, Hooft L, Altman DG, Hayden J, Collins GS, Debray TPA. A guide to systematic review and meta-analysis of prognostic factor studies. BMJ 2019;364:k4597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robert LG. Converting an odds ratio to a range of plausible relative risks for better communication of research findings. BMJ 2014;348:f7450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roeckner AR, Oliver KI, Lebois LAM, van Rooij SJH, Stevens JS. Neural contributors to trauma resilience: a review of longitudinal neuroimaging studies. Transl Psychiatry 2021;11:508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salanti G. Statistical algorithms for the Calculator in Review Manager 5.2. London, United Kindom: The Cochrane Collaboration; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samoborec S, Ruseckaite R, Ayton D, Evans S. Biopsychosocial factors associated with non-recovery after a minor transport-related injury: a systematic review. PLoS One 2018;13:e0198352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samoborec S, Simpson P, Ruseckaite R, Ayton D, Evans SM. Biopsychosocial factors associated with poor health-related quality of life after minor to moderate transport-related injuries: insights into the victorian compensable population. J Rehabil Med 2020;52:jrm00018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scholten AC, Haagsma JA, Steyerberg EW, van Beeck EF, Polinder S. Assessment of pre-injury health-related quality of life: a systematic review. Popul Health Metrics 2017;15:10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz CE, Andresen EM, Nosek MA, Krahn GL; RRTC Expert Panel on Health Status Measurement. Response shift theory: important implications for measuring quality of life in people with disability. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2007;88:529&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serdar CC, Cihan M, Y&#xfc;cel D, Serdar MA. Sample size, power and effect size revisited: simplified and practical approaches in pre-clinical, clinical and laboratory studies. Biochem Med (Zagreb) 2021;31:010502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer WO, Skovron ML, Salmi LR, Cassidy JD, Duranceau J, Suissa S, Zeiss E. Scientific monograph of the Quebec Task Force on Whiplash-Associated disorders: redefining &#x201c;whiplash&#x201d; and its management. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 1995;20:1s&#x2013;73s.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens D. World Health Organization's international classification of functioning, disability and health: ICF. J Audiol Med 2001;10:vi&#x2013;x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterling M, Hendrikz J, Kenardy J. Compensation claim lodgement and health outcome developmental trajectories following whiplash injury: a prospective study. PAIN 2010;150:22&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterling M, Ritchie C, Rebbeck T, Cameron ID, Griffin A, Jagnoor J, Nicholas M, Nguyen H, Warren J. Comparison of the accuracy of WhipPredict to that of a modified version of the short-form &#xf6;rebro musculoskeletal pain screening questionnaire to predict poor recovery after whiplash injury. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 2021;51:207&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterner Y, Toolanen G, Gerdle B, Hildingsson C. The incidence of whiplash trauma and the effects of different factors on recovery. Clin Spine Surg 2003;16:195&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stupar M, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; P, Carroll LJ, Brison RJ, Boyle E, Shearer HM, Cassidy JD. Multivariable prediction models for the recovery of and claim closure related to post-collision neck pain and associated disorders. Chiropr Man Ther 2023;31:32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suliman S, Stein DJ, Seedat S. Clinical and neuropsychological predictors of posttraumatic stress disorder. Medicine (Baltimore) 2014;93:e113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treede RD, Rief W, Barke A, Aziz Q, Bennett MI, Benoliel R, Cohen M, Evers S, Finnerup NB, First MB, Giamberardino MA, Kaasa S, Korwisi B, Kosek E, Lavand'homme P, Nicholas M, Perrot S, Scholz J, Schug S, Smith BH, Svensson P, Vlaeyen JWS, Wang SJ. Chronic pain as a symptom or a disease: the IASP Classification of Chronic Pain for the International Classification of Diseases (ICD-11). PAIN 2019;160:19&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseli E, Boersma K, St&#xe5;lnacke BM, Enthoven P, Gerdle B, &#xc4;ng BO, Grooten WJA. Prognostic factors for physical functioning after multidisciplinary rehabilitation in patients with chronic musculoskeletal pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin J Pain 2019;35:148&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner MA, Taylor PJ, Neal LA. Physical and psychiatric predictors of late whiplash syndrome. Injury 2003;34:434&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulirsch JC, Weaver MA, Bortsov AV, Soward AC, Swor RA, Peak DA, Jones JS, Rathlev NK, Lee DC, Domeier RM, Hendry PL, McLean SA. No man is an island: living in a disadvantaged neighborhood influences chronic pain development after motor vehicle collision, and this effect is moderated by common genetic variation influencing HPA axis function. PAIN 2014;155:2116&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton DM, Macdermid JC, Giorgianni AA, Mascarenhas JC, West SC, Zammit CA. Risk factors for persistent problems following acute whiplash injury: update of a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 2013;43:31&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton DM, Pretty J, MacDermid JC, Teasell RW. Risk factors for persistent problems following whiplash injury: results of a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 2009;39:334&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson OD, Epi GDC, Gabbe BJ, Physio B, Cameron PA, Edwards ER, Richardson MD; on behalf of the Victorian Orthopaedic Trauma Outcome Registry Project Group. Predictors of moderate or severe pain 6 months after orthopaedic injury: a prospective cohort study. J Orthop Trauma 2009;23:139&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Road traffic injuries. Geneva: WHO, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong HY, Hendrix J, Schabrun S, Wyns A, Campenhout JV, Nijs J, Polli A. The role of the brain-derived neurotrophic factor in chronic pain: links to central sensitization and neuroinflammation. Biomolecules 2024;14:71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziobrowski HN, Holt-Gosselin B, Petukhova MV, King AJ, Lee S, House SL, Beaudoin FL, An X, Stevens JS, Zeng D, Neylan TC, Clifford GD, Linnstaedt SD, Germine LT, Bollen KA, Rauch SL, Haran JP, Storrow AB, Lewandowski C, Musey PI, Hendry PL, Sheikh S, Jones CW, Punches BE, Kurz MC, Swor RA, Hudak LA, Pascual JL, Seamon MJ, Harris E, Pearson C, Merchant RC, Domeier RM, Rathlev NK, O'Neil BJ, Sergot P, Sanchez LD, Bruce SE, Miller MW, Pietrzak RH, Joormann J, Barch DM, Pizzagalli DA, Harte SE, Elliott JM, Ressler KJ, McLean SA, Koenen KC, Kessler RC. Childhood adversities and risk of posttraumatic stress disorder and major depression following a motor vehicle collision in adulthood. Epidemiol Psychiatr Sci 2023;32:e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziobrowski HN, Kennedy CJ, Ustun B, House SL, Beaudoin FL, An XM, Zeng DL, Bollen KA, Petukhova M, Sampson NA, Puac-Polanco V, Lee S, Koenen KC, Ressler KJ, McLean SA, Kessler RC, AURORA Consortium, Stevens JS, Neylan TC, Clifford GD, Jovanovic T, Linnstaedt SD, Germine LT, Rauch SL, Haran JP, Storrow AB, Lewandowski C, Musey PI Jr, Hendry PL, Sheikh S, Jones CW, Punches BE, Lyons MS, Murty VP, McGrath ME, Pascual JL, Seamon MJ, Datner EM, Chang AM, Pearson C, Peak DA, Jambaulikar G, Merchant RC, Domeier RM, Rathlev NK, O'Neil BJ, Sergot P, Sanchez LD, Bruce SE, Pietrzak RH, Joormann J, Barch DM, Pizzagalli DA, Sheridan JF, Harte SE, Elliott JM, van Rooij SJH. Development and validation of a model to predict posttraumatic stress disorder and major depression after a motor vehicle collision. JAMA Psychiatry 2021;78:1228&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>