<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41726090</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1863-2521</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of children's orthopaedics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Child Orthop</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sociodemographic variables are rarely reported in randomized controlled trials investigating posterior spinal fusion for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: A systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>197</StartPage><EndPage>204</EndPage><MedlinePgn>197-204</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/18632521251411158</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Adolescent idiopathic scoliosis (AIS) develops between the ages of 10 and skeletal maturity and can lead to physical, psychosocial, and medical complications if untreated. Posterior spinal fusion (PSF) is the primary surgical intervention when bracing fails. Although sociodemographic factors affect access to care, surgical candidacy, perioperative risk, and recovery, these variables are rarely reported in randomized controlled trials (RCTs), limiting assessment of equity and generalizability in AIS outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Following Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses guidelines, PubMed, Embase, and Scopus were searched on 9 April 2024, using "posterior spinal fusion," "randomized controlled trial," and "adolescent idiopathic scoliosis." Inclusion criteria were full-text RCTs on PSF in AIS; exclusions were non-English publications, cadaver studies, and technique articles. Two authors independently screened studies, with disagreements resolved by a third. Extracted variables included demographics and social factors. Analyses used descriptive statistics, chi-squared tests, and Fisher's exact test (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Of 148 studies, 44 met the inclusion criteria. Age (97.7%) and sex (95.5%) were reported more frequently than race (6.8%) or ethnicity (9.1%) (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). No studies reported household income, insurance status, housing, employment, or education. Reporting did not differ by journal (Fisher's exact test, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.999) or publication year (chi-squared test, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.185), although reporting increased slightly after 2017.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">RCTs on PSF for AIS rarely report sociodemographic variables beyond age and sex. This gap limits understanding of whether outcomes are consistent across populations or if disparities exist in treatment response or recovery. Improved sociodemographic reporting is essential for transparency, external validity, and equity in AIS care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Systematic review of Level II.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brown</LastName><ForeName>Erin L</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Tulane University, New Orleans, LA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Kenneth T</ForeName><Initials>KT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-8303-367X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Tulane University, New Orleans, LA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koppala</LastName><ForeName>Bhavesh R</ForeName><Initials>BR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and Rehabilitation, Loyola University Medical Center, Maywood, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dhunna</LastName><ForeName>Daman P</ForeName><Initials>DP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8746-5489</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chobanian &amp; Avedisian School of Medicine, Boston University, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuzma</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8208-6850</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and Rehabilitation, Loyola University Medical Center, Maywood, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baksh</LastName><ForeName>Nikolas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and Rehabilitation, Loyola University Medical Center, Maywood, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Child Orthop</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101313582</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1863-2521</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent idiopathic scoliosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health equity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">posterior spinal fusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized controlled trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sociodemographic factors</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41726090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12920172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/18632521251411158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_18632521251411158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Konieczny MR, Senyurt H, Krauspe R. Epidemiology of adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. J Child Orthop 2013; 7(1): 3&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3566258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24432052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikanloo SR, Tarpada SP, Cho W. Etiology of adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a literature review. Asian Spine J 2019; 13(3): 519&#x2013;526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6547389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30744305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinstein SL, Dolan LA, Cheng JC, et al. Adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Lancet 2008; 371(9623): 1527&#x2013;1537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18456103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner SC, Lehman RA, Lenke LG. Surgical management of adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Semin Spine Surg 2015; 27(1): 33&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz A, Pawlik TM. Social determinants of health and surgical care. Curr Probl Surg 2023; 60(4): 101300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37087130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamalapathy PN, Dunne PJ, Yarboro S. National evaluation of social determinants of health in orthopedic fracture care: decreased social determinants of health is associated with increased adverse complications after surgery. J Orthop Trauma 2021; 36(7): e278&#x2013;e282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34941600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly KM, Theriot HG, Bourgeois JP, et al. Lack of demographic information in total hip arthroplasty/total knee arthroplasty randomized controlled trial publications. J Arthroplasty 2023; 38(3): 573&#x2013;577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36257508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler RA, Rosenzweig S, Myers L, et al. The impact of socioeconomic factors on outcome after THA: a prospective, randomized study. Clin Orthop Relat Res 2011; 469(2): 344&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3018201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20717856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mroz TE, Norvell DC, Ecker E, et al. Fusion versus nonoperative management for chronic low back pain: do sociodemographic factors affect outcome? Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2011; 36(21 Suppl.): S75&#x2013;S86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21952191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driessen R, Bhatia N, Gichoya JW, et al. Sociodemographic variables reporting in human radiology artificial intelligence research. J Am Coll Radiol 2023; 20(6): 554&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37148953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orkin AM, Nicoll G, Persaud N, et al. Reporting of sociodemographic variables in randomized clinical trials, 2014&#x2013;2020. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4(6): e2110700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8173372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34076703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul K, Sathianathen N, Dahm P, et al. Variation in accrual and race/ethnicity reporting in urological and nonurological related cancer trials. J Urol 2019; 202(2): 385&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31074679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirchner GJ, Kim AH, Smith NP, et al. Few randomized controlled trials in spine surgery in the United States include sociodemographic patient data: a systematic review. J Am Acad Orthop Surg 2023; 31(8): 421&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36735417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issa TZ, Lambrechts MJ, Canseco JA, et al. Reporting demographics in randomized control trials in spine surgery &#x2013; we must do better. Spine J 2023; 23(5): 642&#x2013;650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36400397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson DE, Duletzke NT, Pedigo EB, et al. Multimodal pain control in adolescent posterior spinal fusion patients: a double-blind, randomized controlled trial to validate the effect of gabapentin on postoperative pain control, opioid use, and patient satisfaction. Spine Deform 2020; 8: 177&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32026435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai YS, Niu YF, Chen ZQ, et al. Comparison of the pedicle screws placement between electronic conductivity device and normal pedicle finder in posterior surgery of scoliosis. J Spinal Disord Tech 2013; 26(6): 316&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22314520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betz RR, Petrizzo AM, Kerner PJ, et al. Allograft versus no graft with a posterior multisegmented hook system for the treatment of idiopathic scoliosis. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2006; 31(2): 121&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16418628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blank J, Flynn JM, Bronson W, et al. The use of postoperative subcutaneous closed suction drainage after posterior spinal fusion in adolescents with idiopathic scoliosis. J Spinal Disord Tech 2003; 16(6): 508&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14657746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canbolat N, Basaran I, Altun D, et al. Postoperative pain in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis surgery: a randomized controlled trial. Pain Physician 2022; 25(4): E589&#x2013;E596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35793183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan CYW, Chiu CK, Lee CK, et al. Usage of chewing gum in posterior spinal fusion surgery for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a randomized controlled trial. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2017; 42(19): 1427&#x2013;1433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28248896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen M, Zuk J, McKay N, et al. Intrathecal morphine versus extended-release epidural morphine for postoperative pain control in pediatric patients undergoing posterior spinal fusion. Anesth Analg 2017; 124(6): 2030&#x2013;2037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5438268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28448398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del&#xe9;crin J, Takahashi S, Gouin F, et al. A synthetic porous ceramic as a bone graft substitute in the surgical management of scoliosis: a prospective, randomized study. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2000; 25(5): 563&#x2013;569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10749632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Y, Liang J, Tong B, Shen J, Zhao H and, Li Q. Combined topical and intravenous administration of tranexamic acid further reduces postoperative blood loss in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis patients undergoing spinal fusion surgery: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2021; 22(1): 663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8351088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34372818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dromzee E, Tribot-Laspi&#xe8;re Q, Bachy M, et al. Efficacy of Integuseal for surgical skin preparation in children and adolescents undergoing scoliosis correction. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2012; 37(21): E1331&#x2013;E1335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22814302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elahwal L, Elmazny M, Elrahwan SM. The perioperative analgesic effect of opioid-free anesthesia using combination of dexmedetomidine, ketamine and lidocaine in adolescent patients undergoing scoliosis surgery: a randomized controlled trial. Egypt J Anaesth 2023; 39(1): 650&#x2013;656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdogan MA, Ozgul U, Ucar M, et al. Patient-controlled intermittent epidural bolus versus epidural infusion for posterior spinal fusion after adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2017; 42(12): 882&#x2013;886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27792112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdogan MA, Ozgul U, Ucar M, et al. Patient-controlled intermittent epidural bolus versus epidural infusion after adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: prospective, randomized, double-blinded study. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2017; 42(12): 882&#x2013;886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27792112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fons RA, Hainsworth KR, Michlig J, et al. Perioperative methadone for posterior spinal fusion in adolescents: results from a double-blind randomized-controlled trial. Paediatr Anaesth 2024; 34(5): 438&#x2013;447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38288667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furutani K, Deguchi H, Matsuhashi M, et al. A bolus dose of ketamine reduces the amplitude of the transcranial electrical motor-evoked potential: a randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled study. J Neurosurg Anesthesiol 2021; 33(3): 230&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31633576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg S, Thomas J, Darland H, et al. Ultrasonic bone scalpel does not reduce blood loss during posterior spinal fusion in patients with adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: randomized clinical trial. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2021; 46(13): 845&#x2013;851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34100838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauger VT, Voepel-Lewis TD, Burke CN, et al. Epidural analgesia compared with intravenous analgesia after pediatric posterior spinal fusion. J Pediatr Orthop 2009; 29(6): 588&#x2013;593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19700988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpern LM, Bronson WE, Kogan CJ. A new low dose of tranexamic acid for decreasing the rate of blood loss in posterior spinal fusion for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. J Pediatr Orthop 2021; 41(6): 333&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33826563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan MS, Choe NC, Chan CYW, et al. Effect of intraoperative autologous transfusion techniques on perioperative hemoglobin level in idiopathic scoliosis patients undergoing posterior spinal fusion: a prospective randomized trial. J Orthop Surg (Hong Kong) 2017; 25(2): 2309499017718951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28675975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan MS, Yunus SN, Ng CC, et al. Tranexamic acid in pediatric scoliosis surgery: a prospective randomized trial comparing high-dose and low-dose tranexamic acid in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis undergoing posterior spinal fusion surgery. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2021; 46(22): E1170&#x2013;E1177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33882541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helenius IJ, Keskinen H, Syv&#xe4;nen J, et al. Gelatine matrix with human thrombin decreases blood loss in adolescents undergoing posterior spinal fusion for idiopathic scoliosis. Bone Joint J 2016; 98-B(3): 395&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26920966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helenius L, Gerdhem P, Ahonen M, et al. Postoperative outcomes of pedicle screw instrumentation for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis with and without a subfascial wound drain: a multicentre randomized controlled trial. Bone Joint J 2022; 104-B(9): 1067&#x2013;1072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36047026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helenius L, Puhakka A, Manner T, et al. Preoperative pregabalin has no effect on intraoperative neurophysiological monitoring in adolescents undergoing posterior spinal fusion: a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Eur Spine J 2018; 27(2): 298&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29147795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helenius LL, Oksanen H, Lastikka M, et al. Preemptive pregabalin in children and adolescents undergoing posterior instrumented spinal fusion: a double-blinded, placebo-controlled, randomized clinical trial. J Bone Joint Surg Am 2020; 102(3): 205&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31770296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu M, Lai A, Zhang Z, et al. Intraoperative halo-femoral traction during posterior spinal arthrodesis for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis curves between 70&#xb0; and 100&#xb0;: a randomized controlled trial. J Neurosurg Spine 2022; 36(1): 78&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34479188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>I&#x15f;&#x131;k M, &#xd6;zdemir HM, Sakao&#x11f;ullar&#x131; A, et al. The efficacy of in situ local autograft in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis surgery: a comparison of three different grafting methods. Turk J Med Sci 2017; 47(6): 1728&#x2013;1735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29306231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klatt JW, Mickelson J, Hung M, et al. A randomized prospective evaluation of three techniques of postoperative pain management after posterior spinal instrumentation and fusion. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2013; 38(19): 1626&#x2013;1631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23715024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerner T, Bullmann V, Schulte TL, et al. A level-1 pilot study to evaluate ultraporous beta-tricalcium phosphate as a graft extender in posterior correction of adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Eur Spine J 2009; 18(2): 170&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2899343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19082847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang J, Qiu G, Chua S, et al. Comparison between subcutaneous closed-suction drainage and conventional closed-suction drainage in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis patients undergoing posterior instrumented spinal fusion: a randomized controlled trial. J Spinal Disord Tech 2013; 26(5): 256&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22134736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin DP, Bhalla T, Thung A, et al. Volatile agents or total intravenous anesthesia for neurophysiological monitoring during posterior spinal fusion in adolescents with idiopathic scoliosis: a preliminary study. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2014; 39(22): E1318&#x2013;E1324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25099322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin DP, Samora WP, 3rd, Beebe AC, et al. Analgesic effects of methadone and magnesium following posterior spinal fusion for idiopathic scoliosis in adolescents: a randomized controlled trial. J Anesth 2018; 32(5): 702&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30078167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayell A, Srinivasan I, Campbell F, et al. Analgesic effects of gabapentin after scoliosis surgery in children: a randomized controlled trial. Paediatr Anaesth 2014; 24(12): 1239&#x2013;1244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25230144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNeil N, Bastrom TP, Bartley CE, et al. Randomized controlled trial of energy healing effects on pain and anxiety in AIS posterior surgery: a pilot study. Spine Deform 2021; 9(4): 1029&#x2013;1034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33683643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Y, Lin T, Shao W, et al. Chewing gum on bowel function recovery after posterior spinal fusion surgery for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a prospective single-blind randomized controlled trial. Clin Spine Surg 2018; 31(3): 132&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29596213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naduvanahalli Vivekanandaswamy A, Prasad Shetty A, Mugesh Kanna R, et al. Safety and efficacy of dexmedetomidine in posterior spinal fusion surgery for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a prospective randomized study. Eur Spine J 2021; 30(3): 698&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32696258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Hara JF, Jr, Cywinski JB, Tetzlaff JE, et al. The effect of epidural vs intravenous analgesia for posterior spinal fusion surgery. Paediatr Anaesth 2004; 14(12): 1009&#x2013;1015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15601351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ovadia D, Drexler M, Kramer M, et al. Closed-wound subfascial suction drainage in posterior fusion surgery for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a prospective randomized controlled study. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2019; 44(6): 377&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30299415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieters BJ, Anderson JT, Price N, et al. Low-dose versus high-dose postoperative naloxone infusion combined with patient-controlled analgesia for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis surgery: a randomized controlled trial. Spine Deform 2018; 6(4): 430&#x2013;434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29886915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ransford AO, Morley T, Edgar MA, et al. Synthetic porous ceramic compared with autograft in scoliosis surgery: a prospective, randomized study of 341 patients. J Bone Joint Surg Br 1998; 80(1): 13&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9460945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma K, Errico T, Diefenbach C, et al. Relative efficacy of antifibrinolytics in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: a prospective randomized trial. J Bone Joint Surg Am 2014; 96(10): e80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24875032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright JG, Donaldson S, Howard A, et al. Are surgeons&#x2019; preferences for instrumentation related to patient outcomes? A randomized clinical trial of two implants for idiopathic scoliosis. J Bone Joint Surg Am 2007; 89(12): 2684&#x2013;2693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18056501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Zhu F, Zhu Z, et al. Comparison of two methods of incision closure in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis undergoing posterior spinal fusion surgery. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2014; 39(8): E481&#x2013;E485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24480945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan H, Jiang D, Xu L, et al. Does the full power-assisted technique used in pedicle screw placement affect the safety and efficacy of adolescent idiopathic scoliosis surgery? World Neurosurg 2018; 116: e79&#x2013;e85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29684515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Wang LN, Yang X, et al. Multiple-dose oral versus intravenous tranexamic acid for reducing postoperative blood loss and transfusion after adolescent scoliosis surgery: a randomized controlled trial. Spine J 2021; 21(2): 312&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33049411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bondar K, Nguyen A, Vatani J, Kessler J. The demographics and epidemiology of infantile, juvenile, and adolescent idiopathic scoliosis in a Southern California integrated health care system. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2021; 46(21): 1468&#x2013;1477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33813584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helenius I, Remes V, Yrj&#xf6;nen T, et al. Does gender affect outcome of surgery in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis? Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2005; 30(4): 462&#x2013;467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15706345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collis RW, Dry T, Chan G, et al. Sex-related difference in postoperative pain and opioid use following posterior spinal fusion for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Spine Deform 2024; 12(3): 711&#x2013;715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11068828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38329603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egede LE. Race, ethnicity, culture, and disparities in health care. J Gen Intern Med 2006; 21(6): 667&#x2013;669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1924616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16808759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erkkila IP, Reynolds CA, Weissman JP, et al. Factors associated with presentation of severe adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. JPOSNA 2023; 5(3): 651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12088244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40433348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaushal N, Orland KJ, Schwartz AM, et al. Effects of race on blood loss in spinal fusions for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. J Neurosurg Pediatr 2020; 27(2): 213&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33157524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsamadicy AA, Koo AB, David WB, et al. Impact of race on outcomes and healthcare utilization following spinal fusion for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Clin Neurol Neurosurg 2021; 206: 106634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33979695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alomari S, Planchard R, Azad TD, et al. Association of race with early outcomes of elective posterior spinal fusion for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: propensity-matched and subgroup analysis. World Neurosurg 2021; 150: e176&#x2013;e181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33684580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornley P, Garner S, Rogers KJ, et al. Socioeconomic, racial, and insurance disparities in clinical outcomes after surgery among patients with idiopathic scoliosis. J Pediatr Orthop 2024; 44(2): e163&#x2013;e167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37867376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orellana KJ, Lee J, Yang D, et al. Impact of social determinants of health on adolescent idiopathic scoliosis curve severity. J Pediatr Orthop 2024; 44(2): e168&#x2013;e173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37796167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg AR, Fano AN, Ball J, et al. Evaluating the readability of patient education materials for anterior vertebral body tethering, distraction-based methods, and posterior spinal fusion for the treatment of pediatric spinal deformity. Int J Spine Surg 2024; 18(2): 178&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11287801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38575337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang D, Jha S, Swallow J, et al. Preoperative patient education and smaller prescription quantity reduce opioid use after posterior spinal fusion for gt=: results of a prospective study. J Pediatr Orthop 2022; 42(8): e868&#x2013;e873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35856498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>