<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41657234</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2044</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Anaesthesia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Anaesthesia</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Peri-operative fasting in adults: an international, multidisciplinary consensus statement.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/anae.70130</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Evidence suggests that existing pre-operative fasting guidelines are associated with prolonged fasting times. Prolonged fasting, particularly from clear liquids, has the potential to harm patients through reduced peri-operative wellbeing; impaired glucose metabolism and peri-operative inflammatory response; delayed return of bowel function; and reduced muscle strength. Liberalisation of fasting practices has, therefore, become increasingly common. Such a change in practice dictates the need for updated practice guidance. We aimed to develop recommendations on peri-operative fasting that reflect increasing global awareness of the adverse effects of prolonged fasting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Following a systematic literature review, 13 draft recommendations related to peri-operative fasting were developed iteratively. These were modified during a three-round Delphi process by an international, multidisciplinary stakeholder panel, which included: patients; anaesthetists; surgeons; physicians; nurses; and members of relevant international organisations from five continents.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Sixty-eight stakeholders participated in the Delphi consensus process. The panel subsequently agreed on eight recommendations. We recommend continuing current practices on pre-operative fasting for solid food and non-clear liquids. We recommend encouraging clear liquids until 2&#x2009;h before the start of anaesthesia or sedation, unless institutional protocols allow for more liberal liquid intake. We further recommend implementation of institutional protocols that allow more liberal clear liquid intake &lt;&#x2009;2&#x2009;h before the start of anaesthesia or sedation. Salivation stimulants can be used until transfer for the procedure. Oral intake should be resumed as soon as clinically feasible. Preprocedural gastric ultrasound performed by a trained provider may be used to guide clinical decisions when additional information is required.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This international, multidisciplinary consensus statement aims to improve the quality of patient care by minimising periprocedural fasting times, within safe margins. To achieve this, liberalised pre-operative clear liquid intake regimens may be implemented with institutional protocols.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Anaesthesia published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Association of Anaesthetists.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>R&#xfc;ggeberg</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2561-0182</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesiology and Pain Therapy, Helios Klinikum Emil von Behring, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Boghdadly</LastName><ForeName>Kariem</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9912-717X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia and Peri-operative Care, Guy's and St Thomas' NHS Foundation Trust, Honorary Reader, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bilotta</LastName><ForeName>Federico</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care, Tor Vergata University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vaz</LastName><ForeName>Marta Dias</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2242-3701</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesiology, Unidade Local de Sa&#xfa;de de Gaia e Espinho, V. N. Gaia, Portugal, Centre for Health Technology and Services Research, Health Research Network (CINTESIS@RISE), Faculty of Medicine of the University of Porto, Porto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Camilleri Podesta</LastName><ForeName>Anne Marie</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7863-2038</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia, Intensive Care and Pain Medicine, Mater Dei Hospital, Malta.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jammer</LastName><ForeName>Ib</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6759-3929</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia and Intensive Care, Haukeland University Hospital, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schindler</LastName><ForeName>Ehrenfried</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2377-3327</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section for Paediatric Anaesthesiology, Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care Medicine, University Hospital Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elmawieh</LastName><ForeName>Jamie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7189-8984</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia, Surgery and Interventional Radiology, Gustave Roussy, Paris Saclay University, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagrebetsky</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9866-8417</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Mass General Brigham, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Anaesthesia</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370524</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0003-2409</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText Label="WHAT WE DID" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">An international group of doctors, nurses and patients worked together to create new recommendations that make fasting safer and more comfortable for people needing anaesthesia. They reviewed research and reached agreement on eight main recommendations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="WHY WE DID IT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Before an operation or procedure, people are told not to eat or drink for several hours so that their stomachs are empty when they receive anaesthesia. This is meant to reduce the small risk of food or liquid going into the lungs during anaesthesia. But many patients fast for much longer than needed, with some finding that this is often more than 14&#x2009;hours without food and 9&#x2009;hours without drinks. Long fasting times can make people feel tired, thirsty, anxious or weak, and can affect their recovery after surgery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="WHAT WE FOUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Adults should stop eating solid food and milk products 6&#x2009;hours before anaesthesia (8&#x2009;hours after a heavy or fatty meal). Clear drinks like water, tea, coffee with a little milk or juice can usually be taken until 2&#x2009;hours before surgery. Hospitals may also make protocols allowing clear drinks closer to the time of anaesthesia, such as permitting them to drink clear liquids until they are called for their procedure. Patients should start drinking and eating again as soon as they are able after the operation. Chewing gum or sucking sweets is acceptable until patients are taken for surgery. Overall, these recommendations aim to improve patient comfort, prevent harm from long fasting and support hospitals in adopting safe, modern fasting practices.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Anaesthesia published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Association of Anaesthetists.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clear liquids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">consensus statement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liberal fasting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peri&#x2010;operative fasting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary aspiration</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41657234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.70130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Beck MH, Balci&#x2010;Hakimeh D, Scheuerecker F, et&#xa0;al. Real&#x2010;world evidence: how long do our patients fast? Results from a prospective JAGO&#x2010;NOGGO&#x2010;multicenter analysis on perioperative fasting in 924 patients with malignant and benign gynecological diseases. Cancer 2023; 15: 1311. https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers15041311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camilleri Podesta AM, Sciberras S, Moisa E, et&#xa0;al. Preoperative fluid fasting practices across Europe: a prospective multicentre study. Eur J Anaesthesiol 2026; 43: 2347. https://doi.org/10.1097/EJA.0000000000002347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakulsaengprapha V, Daniel M, Cai J, Martinez DA, Mathews SC. Analysis of variation in pre&#x2010;procedural fasting duration for common inpatient gastrointestinal procedures. Transl Gastroenterol Hepatol 2022; 7: 39. https://doi.org/10.21037/tgh&#x2010;20&#x2010;280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Klerk ES, De Grunt MN, Hollmann MW, Preckel B, Hermanides J, Van Stijn MFM. Incidence of excessive preoperative fasting: a prospective observational study. Br J Anaesth 2023; 130: e440&#x2013;e442. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bja.2022.12.017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta D. Perioperative enteral fasting duration was commonly more than 10 h amongst patients undergoing extracapsular cataract extraction with intraocular lens implantation: a cross&#x2010;sectional single&#x2010;centric retrospective study from the United States. NMO Journal 2024; 18: 54&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.4103/jnmo.jnmo_16_24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witt L, Lehmann B, S&#xfc;mpelmann R, Dennhardt N, Beck CE. Quality&#x2010;improvement project to reduce actual fasting times for fluids and solids before induction of anaesthesia. BMC Anesthesiol 2021; 21: 254. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12871&#x2010;021&#x2010;01468&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xfc;ggeberg A, Meybohm P, Nickel EA. Preoperative fasting and the risk of pulmonary aspiration&#x2014;a narrative review of historical concepts, physiological effects, and new perspectives. BJA Open 2024; 10: 100282. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bjao.2024.100282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith I, Kranke P, Murat I, et&#xa0;al. Perioperative fasting in adults and children: guidelines from the European Society of Anaesthesiology. Eur J Anaesthesiol 2011; 28: 556&#x2013;569. https://doi.org/10.1097/EJA.0b013e3283495ba1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Society of Anesthesiologists. Practice guidelines for preoperative fasting and the use of pharmacologic agents to reduce the risk of pulmonary aspiration: application to healthy patients undergoing elective procedures. Anesthesiology 2017; 126: 376&#x2013;393. https://doi.org/10.1097/ALN.0000000000001452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi GP, Abdelmalak BB, Weigel WA, et&#xa0;al. 2023 American Society of Anesthesiologists practice guidelines for preoperative fasting: carbohydrate&#x2010;containing clear liquids with or without protein, chewing gum, and pediatric fasting duration&#x2014;a modular update of the 2017 American Society of Anesthesiologists practice guidelines for preoperative fasting. Anesthesiology 2023; 138: 132&#x2013;151. https://doi.org/10.1097/ALN.0000000000004381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dongare P, Bhaskar S, Harsoor S, et&#xa0;al. Perioperative fasting and feeding in adults, obstetric, paediatric and bariatric population: practice guidelines from the Indian Society of Anaesthesiologists. Indian J Anaesth 2020; 64: 556. https://doi.org/10.4103/ija.IJA_735_20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ANZCA. PG07 guideline on pre&#x2010;anaesthesia consultation and&#xa0;patient preparation 2024. https://www.anzca.edu.au/getContentAsset/d4eb4cab&#x2010;69e6&#x2010;4228&#x2010;8568&#x2010;bbc911c6c505/80feb437&#x2010;d24d&#x2010;46b8&#x2010;a858&#x2010;4a2a28b9b970/PG07&#x2010;Pre&#x2010;anaesthesia&#x2010;consultation&#x2010;2024.pdf?language=en (accessed 23/08/2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green SM, Leroy PL, Roback MG, et&#xa0;al. An international multidisciplinary consensus statement on fasting before procedural sedation in adults and children. Anaesthesia 2020; 75: 374&#x2013;385. https://doi.org/10.1111/anae.14892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldheiser A, Aziz O, Baldini G, et&#xa0;al. Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS) for gastrointestinal surgery, part 2: consensus statement for anaesthesia practice. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand 2016; 60: 289&#x2013;334. https://doi.org/10.1111/aas.12651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merchant RN, Chima N, Ljungqvist O, Kok JNJ. Preoperative fasting practices across three anesthesia societies: survey of practitioners. JMIR Perioper Med 2020; 3: e15905. https://doi.org/10.2196/15905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ka&#x161;ka M, Grosmanov&#xe1; T, Havel E, et&#xa0;al. The impact and safety of preoperative oral or intravenous carbohydrate administration versus fasting in colorectal surgery &#x2013; a randomized controlled trial. Wien Klin Wochenschr 2010; 122: 23&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00508&#x2010;009&#x2010;1291&#x2010;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Gao P, Guo X, Xu Q, Zhang YF, Wang GQ, Lin JY. Effect of low&#x2010;concentration carbohydrate on patient&#x2010;centered quality of recovery in patients undergoing thyroidectomy: a prospective randomized trial. BMC Anesthesiol 2021; 21: 103. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12871&#x2010;021&#x2010;01323&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B, Wang Y, Liu S, et&#xa0;al. A randomized controlled study of preoperative oral carbohydrate loading versus fasting in patients undergoing elective craniotomy. Clin Nutr 2019; 38: 2106&#x2013;2112. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnu.2018.11.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;avluk &#xd6;F, Ku&#x15f;&#xe7;u MA, G&#xfc;zelmeri&#x307;&#xc7; F, et&#xa0;al. Do preoperative oral carbohydrates improve postoperative outcomesin patients undergoing coronary artery bypass grafts? Turk J Med Sci 2017; 47: 1681&#x2013;1686. https://doi.org/10.3906/sag&#x2010;1703&#x2010;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi HC, Ibrahim Z, Abu Zaid Z, et&#xa0;al. Impact of enhanced recovery after surgery with preoperative whey protein&#x2010;infused carbohydrate loading and postoperative early oral feeding among surgical gynecologic cancer patients: an open&#x2010;labelled randomized controlled trial. Nutrients 2020; 12: 264. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu12010264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Zhang P, Liu MX, Ma JL, Wei XC, Fan D. Preoperative carbohydrate loading and intraoperative goal&#x2010;directed fluid therapy for elderly patients undergoing open gastrointestinal surgery: a prospective randomized controlled trial. BMC Anesthesiol 2021; 21: 157. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12871&#x2010;021&#x2010;01377&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizvanovi&#x107; N, Nesek Adam V, &#x10c;au&#x161;evi&#x107; S, Dervi&#x161;evi&#x107; S, Delibegovi&#x107; S. A randomised controlled study of preoperative oral carbohydrate loading versus fasting in patients undergoing colorectal surgery. Int J Color Dis 2019; 34: 1551&#x2013;1561. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00384&#x2010;019&#x2010;03349&#x2010;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Wang Y, Xiao Y, et&#xa0;al. Effect of different preoperative fasting time on safety and postoperative complications of painless gastrointestinal endoscopy for polyps in patients. Am J Transl Res 2021; 13: 8471&#x2013;8479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bubser F, Jakobsen K, Meco BC, et&#xa0;al. Impact of shorter preoperative fluid fasting on patient outcomes: a safe brain initiative retrospective cohort analysis. Anesth Analg 2025. Online ahead of print. https://doi.org/10.1213/ANE.0000000000007817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radtke FM, Franck M, MacGuill M, et&#xa0;al. Duration of fluid fasting and choice of analgesic are modifiable factors for early postoperative delirium. Eur J Anaesthesiol 2010; 27: 411&#x2013;416. https://doi.org/10.1097/EJA.0b013e3283335cee.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Noort HHJ, Lamers CR, Vermeulen H, Huisman&#x2010;de Waal G, Witteman BJM. Patient education regarding fasting recommendations to shorten fasting times in patients undergoing esophagogastroduodenoscopy: a controlled pilot study. Gastroenterol Nurs 2022; 45: 342&#x2013;353. https://doi.org/10.1097/SGA.0000000000000678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yurashevich M, Chow A, Kowalczyk JJ, Traynor AJ, Carvalho B. Preoperative fasting times for patients undergoing caesarean delivery: before and after a patient educational initiative. Turk J Anaesthesiol Reanim 2019; 47: 282&#x2013;286. https://doi.org/10.5152/tjar.2019.95770.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zia F, Cosic L, Wong A, et&#xa0;al. Effects of a short message service (SMS) by cellular phone to improve compliance with fasting guidelines in patients undergoing elective surgery: a retrospective observational study. BMC Health Serv Res 2021; 21: 27. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12913&#x2010;020&#x2010;06039&#x2010;y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downie S, Joss J, Sripada S. A prospective cohort study investigating the use of a surgical planning tool to improve patient fasting times in orthopaedic trauma. Surgeon 2019; 17: 80&#x2013;87. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surge.2018.05.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komatsu S, Yamashita C, Yatabe T, Kuriyama N, Nakamura T, Nishida O. Effect of multidisciplinary interventions in perioperative management center on duration of preoperative fasting: a single&#x2010;center before&#x2010;and&#x2010;after study. Fujita Med J 2022; 8: 108&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies A, Pang WS, Fowler T, Dewi F, Wright T. Preoperative fasting in the department of plastic surgery. BMJ Open Qual 2018; 7: e000161. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjoq&#x2010;2017&#x2010;000161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCracken GC, Montgomery J. Postoperative nausea and vomiting after unrestricted clear fluids before day surgery: a retrospective analysis. Eur J Anaesthesiol 2018; 35: 337&#x2013;342. https://doi.org/10.1097/EJA.0000000000000760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Checketts MR. Fluid fasting before surgery: the ultimate example of medical sophistry? Anaesthesia 2022; 78: 147&#x2013;149. https://doi.org/10.1111/anae.15925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsman M, Kappen TH, Vernooij LM, van der Hout EC, van Waes JA, van Klei WA. Association of a liberal fasting policy of clear fluids before surgery with fasting duration and patient well&#x2010;being and safety. JAMA Surg 2023; 158: 254&#x2013;263. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamasurg.2022.5867.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiles MD, Macdonald A. The effect of a &#x2018;Sip til Send&#x2019; policy on patient satisfaction: a quality improvement project. Anaesthesia Reports 2024; 12: e12271. https://doi.org/10.1002/anr3.12271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xfc;ggeberg A, Nickel EA. Unrestricted drinking before surgery: an iterative quality improvement study. Anaesthesia 2022; 77: 1386&#x2013;1394. https://doi.org/10.1111/anae.15855.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xfc;ggeberg A, Nickel EA. Unrestricted drinking before procedural sedation using fasting cards: a prospective observational quality improvement study. iGIE 2025; S2949708625001736. Online ahead of print. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.igie.2025.11.007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson H, Zar&#xe9;n B, Frykholm P. Low incidence of pulmonary aspiration in children allowed intake of clear fluids until called to the operating suite. Paediatr Anaesth 2015; 25: 770&#x2013;777. https://doi.org/10.1111/pan.12667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centre for Perioperative Care. Sip Til Send. https://www.cpoc.org.uk/guidelines&#x2010;and&#x2010;resources/guidelines&#x2010;resources/resources/sip&#x2010;til&#x2010;send (accessed 23/08/2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NSW Government. Sip Til Send. 2025. https://aci.health.nsw.gov.au/networks/anaesthesia&#x2010;perioperative&#x2010;care/resources/sip&#x2010;til&#x2010;send (accessed 23/08/2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sands R, Wiltshire R, Isherwood P. Preoperative fasting guidelines in National Health Service England Trusts: a thirst for progress. Br J Anaesth 2022; 129: e100&#x2013;e102. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bja.2022.07.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDougall KAR, Bushra SES, Kannan SG. &#x2018;Think Drink&#x2019; approach to minimize unnecessary preoperative fasting: 18&#x2009;years audit experience. Korean J Anesthesiol 2025; 78: 272&#x2013;278. https://doi.org/10.4097/kja.24489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markman P, Nolan T. Sip Til send: insights from the Australasian implementation survey. ANZCA Bull 2024; 33: 31&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saller T, Allmendinger J, Knabe P, et&#xa0;al. Feasibility and safety of Liberal fluid fasting in an orthogeriatric department: a prospective before&#x2010;and&#x2010;after cohort study. J Clin Med 2025; 14: 5477. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm14155477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas TE, Kranke P, Stegemann M, et&#xa0;al. Benefits in adults allowed to drink clear fluids before surgery until called to the operating room &#x2013; a randomised pilot study [HYDRATE&#x2010;trial]. Eur J Anaesthesiol 2025; 42: 2309. https://doi.org/10.1097/EJA.0000000000002309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xfc;ggeberg A, Meybohm P, Nickel EA. Patient safety in anaesthesia: the European Patient Safety Foundation and the German Coalition for Patient Safety &#x2018;Fasting Cards&#x2019; initiative. Br J Anaesth 2025; 134: 1256&#x2013;1258. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bja.2025.01.009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daly S, Mohamed O, Loughrey J, Kearsley R, Drew T. &#x2018;Sip 'til Send&#x2019;: a prospective study of the effect of a liberal fluid fasting policy on patient reported and haemodynamic variables at elective caesarean delivery. Int J Obstet Anesth 2024; 57: 103956. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijoa.2023.103956.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harnett C, Connors J, Kelly S, Tan T, Howle R. Evaluation of the &#x2018;Sip Til Send&#x2019; regimen before elective caesarean delivery using bedside gastric ultrasound: a paired cohort pragmatic study. Eur J Anaesthesiol 2024; 41: 129&#x2013;135. https://doi.org/10.1097/EJA.0000000000001926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warner MA, Warner ME, Weber JG. Clinical significance of pulmonary aspiration during the perioperative period. Anesthesiology 1993; 78: 56&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1097/00000542&#x2010;199301000&#x2010;00010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakai T, Planinsic RM, Quinlan JJ, Handley LJ, Kim T&#x2010;Y, Hilmi IA. The incidence and outcome of perioperative pulmonary aspiration in a university hospital: a 4&#x2010;year retrospective analysis. Anesth Analg 2006; 103: 941&#x2013;947. https://doi.org/10.1213/01.ane.0000237296.57941.e7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias Vaz M, Berra L, Bilotta F, Jochi G, Sessler D, Nagrebetsky A. Incidence and severity of perioperative pulmonary aspiration: a retrospective analysis of 1.2 million procedures. Eur J Anaesthesiol 2024; 41(e&#x2010;suppl. 62): 284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiles MD, El&#x2010;Boghdadly K, Mariano ER. How to conduct and report guidelines and position, best practice and consensus statements. Anaesthesia 2024; 79: 542&#x2013;547. https://doi.org/10.1111/anae.16260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kranke P, Afshari A, Meybohm P, Buhre W, Wiege S, Romero CS. Decoding the meaning of medical guidelines and their medicolegal implications. Eur J Anaesthesiol 2024; 41: 109&#x2013;114. https://doi.org/10.1097/EJA.0000000000001917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Vist GE, et&#xa0;al. GRADE: an emerging consensus on rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ 2008; 336: 924&#x2013;926. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.39489.470347.AD.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xfc;nger S, Payne SA, Brine J, Radbruch L, Brearley SG. Guidance on Conducting and REporting DElphi Studies (CREDES) in palliative care: recommendations based on a methodological systematic review. Palliat Med 2017; 31: 684&#x2013;706. https://doi.org/10.1177/0269216317690685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonner JJ, Vajjah P, Abduljalil K, et&#xa0;al. Does age affect gastric emptying time? A model&#x2010;based meta&#x2010;analysis of data from premature neonates through to adults. Biopharm Drug Dispos 2015; 36: 245&#x2013;257. https://doi.org/10.1002/bdd.1937.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkin J, Rele S, Sumithran P, et&#xa0;al. Association between glucagon&#x2010;like peptide&#x2010;1 receptor agonist use and peri&#x2010;operative pulmonary aspiration: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Anaesthesia 2025; 80: 846&#x2013;858. https://doi.org/10.1111/anae.16601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao MZX, Englesakis M, Perlas A. Gastric content and perioperative pulmonary aspiration in patients with diabetes mellitus: a scoping review. Br J Anaesth 2021; 127: 224&#x2013;235. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bja.2021.04.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Chen C, Wang J, Guo X, Deng YC, Liu L, Zhao C. Delayed gastric emptying in nondiabetic patients with end&#x2010;stage kidney disease. Ren Fail 2022; 44: 329&#x2013;335. https://doi.org/10.1080/0886022x.2022.2030754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang I, Schol J, Carbone F, et&#xa0;al. Prevalence of delayed gastric emptying in patients with gastroparesis&#x2010;like symptoms. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2023; 57: 773&#x2013;782. https://doi.org/10.1111/apt.17330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sastre JA, L&#xf3;pez T, Juli&#xe1;n R, et&#xa0;al. Assessing full stomach prevalence with ultrasound following preoperative fasting in diabetic patients with dysautonomia: a comparative observational study. Anesth Analg 2024; 139: 1300&#x2013;1308. https://doi.org/10.1213/ANE.0000000000007110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okabe T, Terashima H, Sakamoto A. Determinants of liquid gastric emptying: comparisons between milk and isocalorically adjusted clear fluids. Br J Anaesth 2015; 114: 77&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.1093/bja/aeu338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Uslu A, Bodin L, Andersson H, Modiri A&#x2010;R, Frykholm P. Effects of caloric and nutrient content of oral fluids on gastric emptying in volunteers: a randomised crossover study. Br J Anaesth 2024; 132: 260&#x2013;266. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bja.2023.10.030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin R, Gyawali I, Kennedy B, Garry N, Milne S, Tan T. An ultrasound assessment of gastric emptying following tea with milk in pregnancy: a randomised controlled trial. Eur J Anaesthesiol 2020; 37: 303&#x2013;308. https://doi.org/10.1097/EJA.0000000000001129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillyard S, Cowman S, Ramasundaram R, Seed PT, O'Sullivan G. Does adding milk to tea delay gastric emptying? Br J Anaesth 2014; 112: 66&#x2013;71. https://doi.org/10.1093/bja/aet261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen B, Larsen LP, Sivesgaard K, Juul S. Black or white coffee before anaesthesia? A randomised crossover trial. Eur J Anaesthesiol 2016; 33: 457&#x2013;462. https://doi.org/10.1097/EJA.0000000000000457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Practice guidelines for preoperative fasting and the use of pharmacologic agents to reduce the risk of pulmonary aspiration: application to healthy patients undergoing elective procedures. Anesthesiology 1999; 90: 896&#x2013;905. https://doi.org/10.1097/00000542&#x2010;199903000&#x2010;00034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsman M, Pouw N, Moons LMG, van Klei WA, Kappen TH. Gastric fluid volume in adults after implementation of a liberal fasting policy: a prospective cohort study. Br J Anaesth 2021; 127: e85&#x2013;e87. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bja.2021.06.006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo J&#x2010;S. The effect of liberal fluid fasting on gastric fluid volume in patients undergoing painless gastroscopy: a randomized controlled study. Am J Transl Res 2025; 17: 3514&#x2013;3520. https://doi.org/10.62347/LLMS3494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison CE, Ritchie&#x2010;McLean S, Jha A, Mythen M. Two hours too long: time to review fasting guidelines for clear fluids. Br J Anaesth 2020; 124: 363&#x2013;366. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bja.2019.11.036.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harsten A, Hjartarson H, Toksvig&#x2010;Larsen S. Total hip arthroplasty and perioperative oral carbohydrate treatment: a randomised, double&#x2010;blind, controlled trial. Eur J Anaesthesiol 2012; 29: 271&#x2013;274. https://doi.org/10.1097/EJA.0b013e3283525ba9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahraman M, &#xd6;terku&#x15f; M, Kahraman G. Stress and fluid restriction before anesthesia induction, investigation of the effects of the patient's clinic, endocrine responses, and the level of the Nesfatin&#x2010;1. J Surg Med 2021; 5: 491&#x2013;494. https://doi.org/10.28982/josam.812263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heijnen IMS, Dierselhuis EF, Frijlink MMS, Musters SCW, Waal GJH, Van Noort HHJ. Drink lemonade! Implementation of drinking 2 h before elective orthopedic surgery to reduce prolonged fasting. Nutr Clin Pract 2025; 40: 1538&#x2013;1551. https://doi.org/10.1002/ncp.70052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouvet L, Garrigue J, Desgranges F&#x2010;P, Piana F, Lamblin G, Chassard D. Women's view on fasting during labor in a tertiary care obstetric unit. A prospective cohort study. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol 2020; 253: 25&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejogrb.2020.07.041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xfc;ggeberg A, Nickel EA. Unrestricted drinking before surgery: a structured patient interview. Anaesthesia 2023; 78: 911&#x2013;913. https://doi.org/10.1111/anae.15997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowers SJ, Davis RP, Vlisides PE. Caffeine in the perioperative setting. Anesthesiology 2025; 142: 558&#x2013;566. https://doi.org/10.1097/ALN.0000000000005259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fennelly M, Galletly D c, Purdie GI. Is caffeine withdrawal the mechanism of postoperative headache? Anesth Analg 1991; 72: 449&#x2013;453. https://doi.org/10.1213/00000539&#x2010;199104000&#x2010;00006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UK Tea &amp; Infusions Association. Tea facts everyone should know&#x2026;. https://www.tea.co.uk/tea&#x2010;facts (accessed 17/11/2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baettig SJ, Filipovic MG, Hebeisen M, Meierhans R, Ganter MT. Pre&#x2010;operative gastric ultrasound in patients at risk of pulmonary aspiration: a prospective observational cohort study. Anaesthesia 2023; 78: 1327&#x2013;1337. https://doi.org/10.1111/anae.16117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlas A, Arzola C, Portela N, Mitsakakis N, Hayawi L, Van De Putte P. Gastric volume and antral area in the fasting state: a meta&#x2010;analysis of individual patient data. Anesthesiology 2024; 140: 991&#x2013;1001. https://doi.org/10.1097/ALN.0000000000004914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maseri A, Delhez Q, Dincq A&#x2010;S, Lacrosse D. Bridging the gap: understanding Belgian anesthesiologists' proficiency and training demands in gastric point&#x2010;of&#x2010;care ultrasound, a case&#x2010;based survey. BMC Med Educ 2024; 24: 383. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12909&#x2010;024&#x2010;05359&#x2010;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filipovic MG, Baettig SJ, Hebeisen M, Meierhans R, Ganter MT. Gastric ultrasound performance time and difficulty: a prospective observational study. Anaesthesia 2025; 80: 161&#x2013;169. https://doi.org/10.1111/anae.16472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wrobel JR, Magin JC, Koyama Y, et&#xa0;al. Developing a method for ultrasound estimation of gastric volume in patients with previous gastric sleeve. Reg Anesth Pain Med 2025. Epub 4 June. https://doi.org/10.1136/rapm&#x2010;2025&#x2010;106570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bang YJ, Lee J&#x2010;H, Kim CS, Lee Y&#x2010;Y, Min J&#x2010;J. Anxiolytic effects of chewing gum during preoperative fasting and patient&#x2010;centered outcome in female patients undergoing elective gynecologic surgery: randomized controlled study. Sci Rep 2022; 12: 4165. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;022&#x2010;07942&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Best GW, Fanning SB, Robertson IK, Blackford D, Mitchell BL. Assessing the effect of sugar&#x2010;free chewing gum use on the residual gastric volume of patients fasting for gastroscopy: a randomised controlled trial. Anaesth Intensive Care 2019; 47: 541&#x2013;547. https://doi.org/10.1177/0310057X19886881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia AKA, Furuya RK, Conchon MF, Rossetto EG, Dantas RAS, Fonseca LF. Menthol chewing gum on preoperative thirst management: randomized clinical trial. Rev Latino&#x2010;Am Enfermagem 2019; 27: e3180. https://doi.org/10.1590/1518&#x2010;8345.3070.3180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmawieh J, Nagrebetsky A, Dias Vaz M, et&#xa0;al. Chewing gum and postoperative nausea and vomiting: comment. Anesthesiology 2025; 143: 785&#x2013;786. https://doi.org/10.1097/ALN.0000000000005596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang H, Yang Y, Tong X, Zhang L, Fang A, Hong L. Gum chewing slightly enhances early recovery from postoperative ileus after cesarean section: results of a prospective, randomized, controlled trial. Am J Perinatol 2010; 27: 387&#x2013;391. https://doi.org/10.1055/s&#x2010;0029&#x2010;1243313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altraigey A, Ellaithy M, Atia H, Abdelrehim W, Abbas AM, Asiri M. The effect of gum chewing on the return of bowel motility after planned cesarean delivery: a randomized controlled trial. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med 2020; 33: 1670&#x2013;1677. https://doi.org/10.1080/14767058.2018.1526913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver CM, Warnakulasuriya S, McGuckin D, et&#xa0;al. Delivery of drinking, eating and mobilising (DrEaMing) and its association with length of hospital stay after major noncardiac surgery: observational cohort study. Br J Anaesth 2022; 129: 114&#x2013;126. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bja.2022.03.021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunawardhana AI. Knowledge, attitudes and practice of preoperative fasting guidelines in the National Hospital of Sri Lanka. Sri Lankan J Anaesthesiol 2012; 20: 92. https://doi.org/10.4038/slja.v20i2.4259.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>