<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41914751</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-445X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pressure-dependent coupling between arterial pressure and intercostal muscle blood-flow index during acute hypotension in humans.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/EP093687</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Regulation of respiratory muscle blood flow during acute systemic hypotension remains poorly understood in humans because continuous assessment of microvascular perfusion during rapid haemodynamic transients has been technically challenging. Using diffuse correlation spectroscopy, we investigated second-by-second coupling between mean arterial pressure (MAP) and intercostal muscle blood-flow index (BFI) during an abrupt hypotensive stimulus in healthy humans. Fifteen young men underwent 5&#xa0;min of suprasystolic bilateral thigh occlusion followed by rapid cuff release. The MAP and intercostal BFI were analysed at 1&#xa0;Hz over drop (0-10&#xa0;s) and recovery (10-20&#xa0;s) phases. Phase-specific MAP-BFI gain (%BFI per 1% change in MAP) was estimated using linear mixed-effects models, with within-participant centring. Immediately after cuff release, MAP and BFI decreased almost concomitantly, reached nadirs at &#x223c;10&#xa0;s and recovered towards baseline within the next &#x223c;10&#xa0;s. Phase-averaged reductions in BFI were associated with reductions in MAP during the drop phase (Pearson's r&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.66, P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.00701). Mixed-effects modelling revealed near-unity MAP-BFI gain in both phases (drop, 0.89 [95% confidence interval 0.63-1.15], P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001&#xa0;vs. 0, P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.417&#xa0;vs. 1; recovery, 0.95 [0.50-1.40], P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001&#xa0;vs. 0, P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.830&#xa0;vs. 1), with no phase difference (recovery-drop&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.06 [-0.46 to 0.58], P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.824). Individual-level gains showed greater variability, particularly during recovery. These findings demonstrate tight pressure-BFI coupling over seconds-long time scales, indicating that perfusion pressure is a key determinant of intercostal microvascular blood-flow dynamics during acute hypotensive stress.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Experimental Physiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ichinose</LastName><ForeName>Masashi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0281-3254</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Integrative Physiology Laboratory, School of Business Administration, Meiji University, Suginami-ku, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakabayashi</LastName><ForeName>Mikie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-1771-829X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Engineering, Niigata University, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Research Administration, Niigata University, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ono</LastName><ForeName>Yumie</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2176-4312</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Bioinformatics, School of Science and Technology, Meiji University, Kanagawa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>23K27978</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology of Japan</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9002940</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0958-0670</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diffuse correlation spectroscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">integrative haemodynamics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respiratory muscle blood flow</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41914751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP093687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Aaslid, R., Lindegaard, K. F., Sorteberg, W., &amp; Nornes, H. (1989). Cerebral autoregulation dynamics in humans. Stroke, 20(1), 45&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athanasopoulos, D., Louvaris, Z., Cherouveim, E., Andrianopoulos, V., Roussos, C., Zakynthinos, S., &amp; Vogiatzis, I. (2010). Expiratory muscle loading increases intercostal muscle blood flow during leg exercise in healthy humans. Journal of Applied Physiology, 109(2), 388&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubier, M., Murciano, D., Menu, Y., Boczkowski, J., Mal, H., &amp; Pariente, R. (1989). Dopamine effects on diaphragmatic strength during acute respiratory failure in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Annals of Internal Medicine, 110(1), 17&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bark, H., Supinski, G. S., Lamanna, J. C., &amp; Kelsen, S. G. (1987). Relationship of changes in diaphragmatic muscle blood flow to muscle contractile activity. Journal of Applied Physiology, 62(1), 291&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartlett, M. F., Palmero&#x2010;Canton, A., Oneglia, A. P., Mireles, J., Brothers, R. M., Trowbridge, C. A., Wilkes, D., &amp; Nelson, M. D. (2023). Epinephrine iontophoresis attenuates changes in skin blood flow and abolishes cutaneous contamination of near&#x2010;infrared diffuse correlation spectroscopy estimations of muscle perfusion. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 324(3), R368&#x2013;R380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellemare, F., &amp; Grassino, A. (1982). Effect of pressure and timing of contraction on human diaphragm fatigue. Journal of Applied Physiology: Respiratory, Environmental and Exercise Physiology, 53, 1190&#x2013;1195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellemare, F., Wight, D., Lavigne, C. M., &amp; Grassino, A. (1983). Effect of tension and timing of contraction on the blood flow of the diaphragm. Journal of Applied Physiology: Respiratory, Environmental and Exercise Physiology, 54, 1597&#x2013;1606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird, J. D., Lance, M. L., Banser, T. R. W., Thrall, S. F., Cotton, P. D., Lindner, J. R., Eves, N. D., Dominelli, P. B., &amp; Foster, G. E. (2024). Quantifying diaphragm blood flow with contrast&#x2010;enhanced ultrasound in humans. Chest, 166(4), 821&#x2013;834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, J., Bi, R., Ho, J. H., Thong, P. S., Soo, K. C. &amp;, &amp; Lee, K. (2012). Diffuse correlation spectroscopy with a fast fourier transform&#x2010;based software autocorrelator. Journal of biomedical optics, 17(9), 0970041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durduran, T., Choe, R., Baker, W. B., &amp; Yodh, A. G (2010). Diffuse optics for tissue monitoring and tomography. Reports on Progress in Physics, 73(7), 076701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelman, A., &amp; Hill, J. (2007). Data analysis using regression and multilevel/hierarchical models. Cambridge University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guenette, J. A., Vogiatzis, I., Zakynthinos, S., Athanasopoulos, D., Koskolou, M., Golemati, S., Vasilopoulou, M., Wagner, H. E., Roussos, C., Wagner, P. D., &amp; Boushel, R. (2008). Human respiratory muscle blood flow measured by near&#x2010;infrared spectroscopy and indocyanine green. Journal of Applied Physiology, 104(4), 1202&#x2013;1210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogarth, A. J., Mackintosh, A. F., &amp; Mary, D. A. (2007). Gender&#x2010;related differences in the sympathetic vasoconstrictor drive of normal subjects. Clinical Science, (London, England: 1979), 112(6), 353&#x2013;361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain, S. N., Roussos, C., &amp; Magder, S. (1989). Effects of tension, duty cycle, and arterial pressure on diaphragmatic blood flow in dogs. Journal of Applied Physiology, 66(2), 968&#x2013;976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichinose, M., Nakabayashi, M., &amp; Ono, Y. (2018). Sympathoexcitation constrains vasodilation in the human skeletal muscle microvasculature during postocclusive reactive hyperemia. American Journal of Physiology. Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 315(2), H242&#x2013;H253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichinose, M., Nakabayashi, M., &amp; Ono, Y. (2021). Rapid vasodilation within contracted skeletal muscle in humans: New insight from concurrent use of diffuse correlation spectroscopy and doppler ultrasound. American Journal of Physiology. Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 320(2), H654&#x2013;H667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichinose, M., Nakabayashi, M., &amp; Ono, Y. (2025). Muscle metaboreflex activation via postexercise ischemia increases intercostal muscle blood flow index without evidence of local vasoconstriction in humans. Journal of Applied Physiology, 139(4), 988&#x2013;999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichinose, M., Watanabe, K., Fujii, N., Kondo, N., &amp; Nishiyasu, T. (2013). Muscle metaboreflex activation speeds the recovery of arterial blood pressure following acute hypotension in humans. American Journal of Physiology. Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 304(11), H1568&#x2013;H1575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyner, M. J., &amp; Casey, D. P. (2015). Regulation of increased blood flow (hyperemia) to muscles during exercise: A hierarchy of competing physiological needs. Physiological Reviews, 95(2), 549&#x2013;601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsushita, H., Kurono, K., Nakabayashi, M., Sato, K., Morita, H., Yoshida, Y., Fukumitsu, M., Uemura, K., Kawada, T., Ichinose, M., Ono, Y., &amp; Saku, K. (2025). Non&#x2010;invasive monitoring of microcirculation dynamics in hypovolemic shock: A novel application of diffuse correlation spectroscopy. Intensive Care Medicine Experimental, 13(1), 53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakabayashi, M., Liu, S., Broti, N. M., Ichinose, M., &amp; Ono, Y. (2023). Deep&#x2010;learning&#x2010;based separation of shallow and deep layer blood flow rates in diffuse correlation spectroscopy. Biomedical optics express, 14(10), 5358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakabayashi, M., &amp; Ono, Y. (2017). Detection of Blood Flow Speed in Shallow and Deep Tissues Using Diffuse Correlation Spectroscopy. Advanced Biomedical Engineering, 6(0), 53&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson, M. S., Andersson&#x2010;Engels, S., Wilson, B. C., &amp; Osei, E. K. (1995). Absorption spectroscopy in tissue&#x2010;simulating materials: A theoretical and experimental study of photon paths. Applied Optics, 34(1), 22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinheiro, J. C., &amp; Bates, D. M. (2000). Mixed&#x2010;effects models in s and s&#x2010;plus. Springer&#x2010;Verlag.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues, A., Shingai, K., G&#xf3;mez, C. A., Rassam, P., Rozenberg, D., Goligher, E., Brochard, L., Roblyer, D., &amp; Reid, W. D. (2024). Continuous measurements of respiratory muscle blood flow and oxygen consumption using noninvasive frequency&#x2010;domain near&#x2010;infrared spectroscopy and diffuse correlation spectroscopy. Journal of Applied Physiology, 137(2), 382&#x2013;393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowell, L. B. (1993). Human cardiovascular control. Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saltin, B., &amp; Calbet, J. A. (2006). Point: In health and in a normoxic environment, VO2 max is limited primarily by cardiac output and locomotor muscle blood flow. Journal of Applied Physiology, 100(2), 744&#x2013;748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheel, A. W., Derchak, P. A., Morgan, B. J., Pegelow, D. F., Jacques, A. J., &amp; Dempsey, J. A. (2001). Fatiguing inspiratory muscle work causes reflex reduction in resting leg blood flow in humans. The Journal of Physiology, 537(1), 277&#x2013;289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St Croix, C. M., Morgan, B. J., Wetter, T. J., &amp; Dempsey, J. A. (2000). Fatiguing inspiratory muscle work causes reflex sympathetic activation in humans. The Journal of Physiology, 529(2), 493&#x2013;504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudhir, K., Chou, T. M., Mullen, W. L., Hausmann, D., Collins, P., Yock, P. G., &amp; Chatterjee, K. (1995). Mechanisms of estrogen&#x2010;induced vasodilation: In vivo studies in canine coronary conductance and resistance arteries. Journal of the American College of Cardiology, 26(3), 807&#x2013;814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogiatzis, I., Athanasopoulos, D., Habazettl, H., Kuebler, W. M., Wagner, H., Roussos, C., Wagner, P. D., &amp; Zakynthinos, S. (2009). Intercostal muscle blood flow limitation in athletes during maximal exercise. The Journal of Physiology, 587(14), 3665&#x2013;3677.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>