<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41881664</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2005-6443</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>47</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Korean journal of family medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Korean J Fam Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nutritional pathways from treatment to management of sarcopenia in patients with gastric cancer: a narrative review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>97</StartPage><EndPage>108</EndPage><MedlinePgn>97-108</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4082/kjfm.25.0215</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sarcopenia, characterized by the progressive loss of skeletal muscle mass and strength, represents a significant clinical concern among patients undergoing gastric cancer surgery. Postoperative individuals are particularly vulnerable due to gastrointestinal dysfunction, reduced nutrient intake, systemic inflammation, and treatment-induced metabolic stress. This condition is associated with higher complication rates, delayed recovery, chemotherapy intolerance, and decreased survival, underscoring the importance of early detection and effective nutritional management. This narrative review integrates and synthesizes recent evidence from clinical and experimental studies that explore the pathophysiology, diagnosis, and nutritional management of sarcopenia in gastric cancer. The review emphasizes key nutritional risk factors, assessment tools, and intervention strategies applicable to both preoperative and postoperative care. Validated methods such as SARC-F (strength, assistance with walking, rise from a chair, climb stairs, and falls), dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry, and computed tomography imaging play central roles in identifying muscle loss and functional decline. Evidence suggests that protein-enriched diets, branched-chain amino acids, omega-3 fatty acids, and micronutrients such as vitamin D and antioxidants help preserve muscle mass and improve recovery outcomes. Exercise and rehabilitation further enhance these benefits by synergistically promoting muscle protein synthesis and function. Moreover, emerging technologies-including artificial intelligence-assisted nutritional monitoring, nutrigenomics, and biomarker-based personalization-represent promising directions for individualized care. Sarcopenia in gastric cancer is a modifiable and clinically significant condition. Integrating personalized nutrition with structured rehabilitation can markedly enhance functional recovery, treatment tolerance, and quality of life. Future research should aim to develop precision-based nutritional algorithms and standardized diagnostic frameworks to optimize outcomes in this high-risk population.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swati</LastName><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, School of Allied Health Sciences, Manav Rachna International Institute of Research and Studies, Faridabad, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Mahak</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, School of Allied Health Sciences, Manav Rachna International Institute of Research and Studies, Faridabad, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agarwal</LastName><ForeName>Mohit</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fortis Hospital Shalimar Bagh, Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choudhary</LastName><ForeName>Divya</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rajiv Gandhi Cancer Institute, Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Korean J Fam Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101502902</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2005-6443</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cachexia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Malnutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutrition Therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Support</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sarcopenia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stomach Neoplasms</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<b>Conflict of interest</b>
. No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41881664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13033434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4082/kjfm.25.0215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">kjfm.25.0215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Smyth EC, Nilsson M, Grabsch HI, van Grieken NC, Lordick F. Gastric cancer. Lancet. 2020;396:635&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32861308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, Boirie Y, Bruyere O, Cederholm T, et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2019;48:16&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6322506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30312372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu M, Wang X, Zhou J, Wang J. Incidence and risk factors of sarcopenia in gastric cancer patients: a meta-analysis and systematic review. BMC Cancer. 2025;25:711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12004572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40241028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira M, Barreira AL, Sardinha F, Costa J, Rodrigues J, Goncalves A, et al. Sarcopenia in gastric cancer and body composition changes after gastrectomy. Port J Surg. 2021;51:51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi B, Liu S, Chen J, Liu J, Luo Y, Long L, et al. Sarcopenia is associated with perioperative outcomes in gastric cancer patients undergoing gastrectomy. Ann Nutr Metab. 2019;75:213&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31846973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaz Goncalves L, de Souza JS, Reitz LK, Godinho Mota JC. In: Nutrition and complementary medicine in cancer: an interdisciplinary approach. Rezaei N, editor. Springer; 2024. Nutritional management of sarcopenia in oncology; pp. 379&#x2013;406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin JX, Lin JP, Xie JW, Wang JB, Lu J, Chen QY, et al. Prognostic value and association of sarcopenia and systemic inflammation for patients with gastric cancer following radical gastrectomy. Oncologist. 2019;24:e1091&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6853105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30910865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landskron G, De la Fuente M, Thuwajit P, Thuwajit C, Hermoso MA. Chronic inflammation and cytokines in the tumor microenvironment. J Immunol Res. 2014;2014:149185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4036716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24901008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costamagna D, Costelli P, Sampaolesi M, Penna F. Role of inflammation in muscle homeostasis and myogenesis. Mediators Inflamm. 2015;2015:805172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4609834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26508819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merz KE, Thurmond DC. Role of skeletal muscle in insulin resistance and glucose uptake. Compr Physiol. 2020;10:785&#x2013;809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8074531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32940941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida T, Delafontaine P. Mechanisms of IGF-1-mediated regulation of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and atrophy. Cells. 2020;9:1970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7564605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32858949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cencioni C, Trestini I, Piro G, Bria E, Tortora G, Carbone C, et al. Gastrointestinal cancer patient nutritional management: from specific needs to novel epigenetic dietary approaches. Nutrients. 2022;14:1542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9024975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35458104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang MK, Lee HJ. Impact of malnutrition and nutritional support after gastrectomy in patients with gastric cancer. Ann Gastroenterol Surg. 2024;8:534&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11216795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38957563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosania R, Chiapponi C, Malfertheiner P, Venerito M. Nutrition in patients with gastric cancer: an update. Gastrointest Tumors. 2016;2:178&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4924460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27403412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan WL, Yun HB, Cheung EE, Liu M, Hou LY, Lam KO, et al. Association of sarcopenia with severe chemotherapy toxicities and survival in patients with advanced gastric cancer. Oncologist. 2024;29:e1272&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11449055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38885304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyatt H, Deminice R, Yoshihara T, Powers SK. Mitochondrial dysfunction induces muscle atrophy during prolonged inactivity: a review of the causes and effects. Arch Biochem Biophys. 2019;662:49&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6783132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30452895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TH, Koh KY, Lin KM, Chou CK. Mitochondrial dysfunction as an underlying cause of skeletal muscle disorders. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:12926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9653750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36361713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis MP, Panikkar R. Sarcopenia associated with chemotherapy and targeted agents for cancer therapy. Ann Palliat Med. 2019;8:86&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30525762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozzetti F. Chemotherapy-induced sarcopenia. Curr Treat Options Oncol. 2020;21:7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32002684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LK, Woo J, Assantachai P, Auyeung TW, Chou MY, Iijima K, et al. Asian Working Group for Sarcopenia: 2019 consensus update on sarcopenia diagnosis and treatment. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2020;21:300&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32033882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieffers JR, Bathe OF, Fassbender K, Winget M, Baracos VE. Sarcopenia is associated with postoperative infection and delayed recovery from colorectal cancer resection surgery. Br J Cancer. 2012;107:931&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3464761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22871883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prado CM, Baracos VE, McCargar LJ, Mourtzakis M, Mulder KE, Reiman T, et al. Body composition as an independent determinant of 5-fluorouracil-based chemotherapy toxicity. Clin Cancer Res. 2007;13:3264&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17545532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamran SM, Mirza ZE, Naseem A, Liaqat J, Fazal I, Alamgir W, et al. Therapeutic plasma exchange for coronavirus disease-2019 triggered cytokine release syndrome; a retrospective propensity matched control study. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0244853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7790281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33411791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang CL, Huang DD, Pang WY, Zhou CJ, Wang SL, Lou N, et al. Sarcopenia is an independent predictor of severe postoperative complications and long-term survival after radical gastrectomy for gastric cancer: analysis from a large-scale cohort. Medicine (Baltimore) 2016;95:e3164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4998538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27043677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilgour RD, Vigano A, Trutschnigg B, Hornby L, Lucar E, Bacon SL, et al. Cancer-related fatigue: the impact of skeletal muscle mass and strength in patients with advanced cancer. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2010;1:177&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3060645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21475694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin L, Birdsell L, Macdonald N, Reiman T, Clandinin MT, McCargar LJ, et al. Cancer cachexia in the age of obesity: skeletal muscle depletion is a powerful prognostic factor, independent of body mass index. J Clin Oncol. 2013;31:1539&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23530101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagh MS, Balan AK, Mathew AP, Rakesh CA, Krishna J, Chandramohan K, et al. Sarcopenia in gastric cancer and its impact on early postoperative outcome. Cancer Treat Res Commun. 2024;40:100829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39003233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess DL, Harmon C, Bhatia S, Williams GR, Giri S. SARC-F as a screening tool to detect computed tomography-based sarcopenia and myosteatosis among older adults with cancer. Cancer Med. 2023;12:20690&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10709718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37916460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishida Y, Maeda K, Nonogaki T, Shimizu A, Yamanaka Y, Matsuyama R, et al. SARC-F as a screening tool for sarcopenia and possible sarcopenia proposed by AWGS 2019 in hospitalized older adults. J Nutr Health Aging. 2020;24:1053&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12876781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33244560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadzibegovic S, Porthun J, Lena A, Weinlander P, Luck LC, Potthoff SK, et al. Hand grip strength in patients with advanced cancer: a prospective study. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2023;14:1682&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10401539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37318103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo Z, Chong F, Luo S, Li N, Tong N, Lu Z, et al. Grip-Strength-Lean-Mass Index (GSLMI) as a valuable tool for sarcopenia diagnosis and survival prognosis in cancer patients: a nationwide multicenter cohort study. J Nutr Health Aging. 2025;29:100409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12180012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39532047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salama MM, Bayoumi EM, Sayed MM, Abdul-Rahman SA, Saleh SA, Zaky AS, et al. Evaluation of handgrip strength as a predictor of sarcopenia in patients with HCV-related cirrhosis. Egypt Liver J. 2023;13:24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M, Lee CM, Kang BK, Ha TK, Choi YY, Lee SJ. Sarcopenia assessed with DXA and CT increases the risk of perioperative complications in patients with gastrectomy. Eur Radiol. 2023;33:5150&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36637463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JS, Kim YS, Kim EY, Jin W. Prognostic significance of CT-determined sarcopenia in patients with advanced gastric cancer. PLoS One. 2018;13:e0202700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6101416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30125312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malmstrom TK, Morley JE. SARC-F tool kit benefits [Internet]  CGA Toolkit Plus; 2013 [cited 2025 Apr 24]. Available from:  https://www.cgakit.com/sarc-f-questionnaire.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsui R, Inaki N, Tsuji T, Momosaki R, Fukunaga T. Impact of preoperative handgrip strength on postoperative outcome after radical gastrectomy for gastric cancer patients. J Clin Med. 2022;11:7129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9737860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36498702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen M, Davenport A. Hand grip strength index, a novel tool in risk-assessing multi-ethnic end-stage kidney disease patients treated by haemodialysis. J Hum Nutr Diet. 2025;38:10.1111/jhn.13414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11650533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39687979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuursma A, Stroot IA, Vermeulen KM, Slart RH, Greuter MJ, Mourits MJ, et al. Reliability, costs, and radiation dose of dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry in diagnosis of radiologic sarcopenia in surgically menopausal women. Insights Imaging. 2024;15:104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11001834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38589691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakehi S, Wakabayashi H, Nagai T, Isono E, Ninomiya J, Otsuka Y, et al. Cachexia risk classification using the Asian Working Group for Cachexia criteria in patients with dysphagia: a retrospective cohort study. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2025;70:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40935187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aversa Z, Bonetto A, Costelli P, Minero VG, Penna F, Baccino FM, et al. &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate (HMB) attenuates muscle and body weight loss in experimental cancer cachexia. Int J Oncol. 2011;38:713&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21184031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tayek JA, Bistrian BR, Hehir DJ, Martin R, Moldawer LL, Blackburn GL. Improved protein kinetics and albumin synthesis by branched chain amino acid-enriched total parenteral nutrition in cancer cachexia: a prospective randomized crossover trial. Cancer. 1986;58:147&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3085914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deutz NE, Safar A, Schutzler S, Memelink R, Ferrando A, Spencer H, et al. Muscle protein synthesis in cancer patients can be stimulated with a specially formulated medical food. Clin Nutr. 2011;30:759&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3964623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21683485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma C, Tsai H, Su W, Sun L, Shih Y, Wang J. Combination of arginine, glutamine, and omega-3 fatty acid supplements for perioperative enteral nutrition in surgical patients with gastric adenocarcinoma or gastrointestinal stromal tumor (GIST): a prospective, randomized, double-blind study. J Postgrad Med. 2018;64:155&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6066627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29848836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikuchi S, Takata N, Kuroda S, Umeda H, Tanabe S, Maeda N, et al. Impact of amino acids nutrition following gastrectomy in gastric cancer patients. Anticancer Res. 2022;42:3637&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35790296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun LC, Shih YL, Lu CY, Hsieh JS, Chuang JF, Chen FM, et al. Randomized, controlled study of branched chain amino acid-enriched total parenteral nutrition in malnourished patients with gastrointestinal cancer undergoing surgery. Am Surg. 2008;74:237&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18376691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Zhao H, Wang Y, Jing H, Ding Q, Xue J. Randomized clinical trial of arginine-supplemented enteral nutrition versus standard enteral nutrition in patients undergoing gastric cancer surgery. J Cancer Res Clin Oncol. 2013;139:1465&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11824343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23812551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molfino A, Emerenziani S, Tonini G, Santini D, Gigante A, Guarino MP, et al. Early impairment of food intake in patients newly diagnosed with cancer. Front Nutr. 2022;9:997813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9849803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36687669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Kiesswetter E, Drey M, Sieber CC. Nutrition, frailty, and sarcopenia. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2017;29:43&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28155181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartali B, Frongillo EA, Bandinelli S, Lauretani F, Semba RD, Fried LP, et al. Low nutrient intake is an essential component of frailty in older persons. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2006;61:589&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2645617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16799141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharya S, Bhadra R, Schols AM, van Helvoort A, Sambashivaiah S. Nutrition in the prevention and management of sarcopenia: a special focus on Asian Indians. Osteoporos Sarcopenia. 2022;8:135&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9805983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36605171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava S, Pandey VK, Singh A, Dar AH. Exploring the potential of treating sarcopenia through dietary interventions. J Food Biochem. 2024;2024:3018760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu E, Ji B, Jin K, Chen Y. Branched-chain amino acids catabolism and cancer progression: focus on therapeutic interventions. Front Oncol. 2023;13:1220638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10448767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37637065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaroenlapnopparat A, Bhatia K, Coban S. Inflammation and gastric cancer. Diseases. 2022;10:35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9326573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35892729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepretti M, Martucciello S, Burgos Aceves MA, Putti R, Lionetti L. Omega-3 fatty acids and insulin resistance: focus on the regulation of mitochondria and endoplasmic reticulum stress. Nutrients. 2018;10:350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5872768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29538286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam CN, Watt AE, Isenring EA, de van der Schueren MAE, van der Meij BS. The effect of oral omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acid supplementation on muscle maintenance and quality of life in patients with cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Nutr. 2021;40:3815&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34130028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feijo PM, Rodrigues VD, Viana MS, Dos Santos MP, Abdelhay E, Viola JP, et al. Effects of &#x3c9;-3 supplementation on the nutritional status, immune, and inflammatory profiles of gastric cancer patients: a randomized controlled trial. Nutrition. 2019;61:125&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30710885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recker RR. Calcium absorption and achlorhydria. N Engl J Med. 1985;313:70&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4000241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalcoli F, Zilli A, Conte D, Massironi S. Micronutrient deficiencies in patients with chronic atrophic autoimmune gastritis: a review. World J Gastroenterol. 2017;23:563&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5292330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28216963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Can B, Kara O, Kizilarslanoglu MC, Arik G, Aycicek GS, Sumer F, et al. Serum markers of inflammation and oxidative stress in sarcopenia. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2017;29:745&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27571781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang G, Hart R, Sholzberg M, Brezden-Masley C. Iron deficiency anemia in gastric cancer: a single site retrospective cohort study. J Clin Oncol. 2017;35(4_suppl):188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Chen J, Song C, Sun J, Liu W. Association between serum iron status and muscle mass in adults: results from NHANES 2015-2018. Front Nutr. 2022;9:941093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9309789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35898717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Zhang Z, Wang Y, Ma A, Li L, Zhao G. Iron status and sarcopenia-related traits: a bi-directional Mendelian randomization study. Sci Rep. 2024;14:9179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11035655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38649459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aapro M, Beguin Y, Bokemeyer C, Dicato M, Gascon P, Glaspy J, et al. Management of anaemia and iron deficiency in patients with cancer: ESMO clinical practice guidelines. Ann Oncol. 2018;29:iv96&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29471514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galli F, Bonomini M, Bartolini D, Zatini L, Reboldi G, Marcantonini G, et al. Vitamin E (alpha-tocopherol) metabolism and nutrition in chronic kidney disease. Antioxidants (Basel) 2022;11:989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9137556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35624853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khor SC, Abdul Karim N, Ngah WZ, Yusof YA, Makpol S. Vitamin E in sarcopenia: current evidences on its role in prevention and treatment. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2014;2014:914853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4109111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25097722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rino Y, Yukawa N, Sato T, Yamamoto N, Tamagawa H, Hasegawa S, et al. Vitamin E deficiency begins within 6 months after gastrectomy for gastric cancer. World J Surg. 2014;38:2065&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24668454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganapathy A, Nieves JW. Nutrition and sarcopenia: what do we know? Nutrients. 2020;12:1755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7353446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32545408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayland CR, Bennett MI, Allan K. Vitamin C deficiency in cancer patients. Palliat Med. 2005;19:17&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15690864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welch AA, Jennings A, Kelaiditi E, Skinner J, Steves CJ. Cross-sectional associations between dietary antioxidant vitamins C, E and carotenoid intakes and sarcopenic indices in women aged 18-79 years. Calcif Tissue Int. 2020;106:331&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7072069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31813016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balboa-Castillo T, Struijk EA, Lopez-Garcia E, Banegas JR, Rodriguez-Artalejo F, Guallar-Castillon P. Low vitamin intake is associated with risk of frailty in older adults. Age Ageing. 2018;47:872&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30052701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornsen T, Salvesen S, Berntsen S, Hetlelid KJ, Stea TH, Lohne-Seiler H, et al. Vitamin C and E supplementation blunts increases in total lean body mass in elderly men after strength training. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2016;26:755&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26129928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreto R, Waning DL, Gao H, Liu Y, Zimmers TA, Bonetto A. Chemotherapy-related cachexia is associated with mitochondrial depletion and the activation of ERK1/2 and p38 MAPKs. Oncotarget. 2016;7:43442&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5190036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27259276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belkhouribchia J, Pen JJ. Artificial intelligence in clinical nutrition: a narrative review. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2025 Nov 21; doi: 10.1016/j.clnesp.2025.11.142. [Epub].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnesp.2025.11.142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41285366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Chen H, Carrillo-Larco RM, Lim CCW, Mishra SR, Yuan C, et al. Association of dietary patterns and food groups intake with multimorbidity: a prospective cohort study. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2022;51:359&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36184228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prado CM, Purcell SA, Alish C, Pereira SL, Deutz NE, Heyland DK, et al. Implications of low muscle mass across the continuum of care: a narrative review. Ann Med. 2018;50:675&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6370503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30169116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelen MP, van der Meij BS, Deutz NE. Protein anabolic resistance in cancer: does it really exist? Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2016;19:39&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4731087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26560520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kussmann M, Fay LB. Nutrigenomics and personalized nutrition: science and concept. Per Med. 2008;5:447&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29783447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>