<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41715007</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2431</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical study on improving lung function in children after Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia (MMP) via traditional Chinese medicine meridian massage.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">233</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12887-026-06605-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Pneumonia impairs lung development, structure, and function during children&#x2019;s critical growth stages. Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM) boosts constitution, yet the efficacy of TCM meridian massage for post-pneumonia lung function improvement remains unclear. This study investigates its role as an adjuvant therapy for lung function recovery in post-discharge children with Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia (MMP).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Sixty-four MMP children with abnormal lung function at discharge (Jan 2023&#x2013;Dec 2024) were randomized to treatment (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;32) or control (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;32) groups. The treatment group received meridian massage (3 sessions/week for 1 month) with three acupoint categories: lung-ventilating/cough-relieving (Feishu BL13, Danzhong CV17), phlegm-resolving (Tiantu CV22, Fenglong ST40), and spleen-lung-nourishing (Zusanli ST36, Pishu BL20). The control group only underwent lung function re-evaluation 1 month post-discharge. Data were analyzed via Prism<sup>&#xae;</sup> 10.0.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Twenty-five treatment and 31 control patients completed follow-up finally. Baseline mixed-type lung function abnormalities and key parameters (e.g., FVC, FEV1) were comparable (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;0.05). At 1month post-discharge, recovery rates were 88.8% (22/25) vs. 41.9% (13/31) in the two groups, respectively. The treatment group showed superior improvements in large (FVC, FEV1, PEF) and small (MEF25, MEF50, MEF75, MMEF) airway parameters (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), with no difference in FEV1/FVC (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Meridian massage safely and effectively promotes lung function recovery in post-MMP children through anti-inflammatory immune modulation and meridian-<i>zang-fu</i> regulation. It provides a novel therapeutic option for post-pneumonia lung dysfunction and evidence-based support for preventing long-term pulmonary sequelae.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12887-026-06605-z.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Shanghai Jiao Tong University Affiliated Pudong New District People's Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Shanghai Jiao Tong University Affiliated Pudong New District People's Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heqing Community Health Service Center, Pudong New District, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Zhiwei</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Shanghai Jiao Tong University Affiliated Pudong New District People's Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Jinsheng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Shanghai Jiao Tong University Affiliated Pudong New District People's Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Suli</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Shanghai Jiao Tong University Affiliated Pudong New District People's Hospital, Shanghai, China. hai1362822@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>PDZY-2024-1214</GrantID><Agency>Training Program for Senior Inherited Talents of Traditional Chinese Medicine</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967804</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2431</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Childhood pneumonia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lung function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meridian massage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study protocol was approved by the Ethics Committee of Pudong New Area People&#x2019;s Hospital of Shanghai (Approval No.: 2025-LW-18). Consent for publication: All authors have read and agreed to the published version of the manuscript. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41715007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13020195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12887-026-06605-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12887-026-06605-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li Q, Liu H, Bai C, Jiang L, Su C, Qin X, Liu T, Gu X. A high-calorie diet exacerbates lipopolysaccharide-induced pneumonia by promoting acetate-mediated macrophage polarization via the HDAC9/10-HIF-1alpha-glycolysis axis. Front Immunol. 2025;16:1614768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2025.1614768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12510825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41080555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Zhu H, Zou X, Ye H, Zhong J, Xiang S, Lou Y, Mao J, Qi L, Hu X, et al. A brain-to-lung signal from GABAergic neurons to ADRB2(+) interstitial macrophages promotes pulmonary inflammatory responses. Immunity. 2025;58(8):2069&#x2013;85. e2069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.immuni.2025.05.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40466637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Gray AR, Hancox RJ. Predictors of lung function in early adulthood: A population-based cohort study. Respirology. 2024;29(10):897&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/resp.14732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38720400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang H, Dai J, Zhou G, Yang G, Zhang L, Yuan S, Zhang J, Chen J, Tang M, Lin J, et al. Changes in lung function in children after pneumonia: a multicenter study. Ital J Pediatr. 2025;51(1):252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13052-025-02092-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12355759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40817215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lassi ZS, Padhani ZA, Das JK, Salam RA, Bhutta ZA. Antibiotic therapy versus no antibiotic therapy for children aged 2 to 59 months with WHO-defined non-severe pneumonia and wheeze. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;1(1):CD009576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8092454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33469915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Kang F, Lai J, Deng X, Guo X, Liu S. Comparative effectiveness of phlegm-heat clearing Chinese medicine injections for AECOPD: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. J Ethnopharmacol. 2022;292:115043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2022.115043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35124185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen XM, Wang YL, Chen PP, Qi QQ, Huang LX. Clinical efficacy analysis of meridian regulation as adjuvant therapy for bronchiolitis in infants. Zhejiang J Traditional Chin Med. 2022;57(04):283&#x2013;4. (in Chinese).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu LL, Liu WP, Li YL, Cao M, Li LY, Ren XH, Yang S, QY Z. Clinical efficacy of Qingfei Juanyin Decoction combined with meridian massage in the treatment of pediatric pneumonia with syndrome of heat-fluid obstructing lung and its effects on TCM syndrome scores and inflammatory indexes. World J Integr Traditional Chin Western Med. 2023;18(01):164&#x2013;8. (in Chinese).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lew A, House S, Flaherty B, Ritter V, Botzheim B, Schroeder AR. Trends in lower respiratory tract diagnoses and nonrecommended bronchiolitis therapies. Pediatrics. 2025;156(5):e2025071946. 10.1542/peds.2025-071946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41151618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanojevic S, Kaminsky DA, Miller MR, Thompson B, Aliverti A, Barjaktarevic I, et al. ERS/ATS technical standard on interpretive strategies for routine lung function tests. Eur Respir J. 2022;60(1):2101499. 10.1183/13993003.01499-2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34949706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider JL, Rowe JH, Garcia-de-Alba C, Kim CF, Sharpe AH, Haigis MC. The aging lung: Physiology, disease, and immunity. Cell. 2021;184(8):1990&#x2013;2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2021.03.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8052295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33811810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi H, Wang T, Zhao Z, Norback D, Wang X, Li Y, Deng Q, Lu C, Zhang X, Zheng X, et al. Prevalence, risk factors, impact and management of pneumonia among preschool children in Chinese seven cities: a cross-sectional study with interrupted time series analysis. BMC Med. 2023;21(1):227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-023-02951-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10294363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37365601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collaro AJ, McElrea MS, Marchant JM, Chatfield MD, Sondergeld P, Perret JL, Vicendese D, Anuntaseree W, Dharmage SC, Chang AB. The effect of early childhood respiratory infections and pneumonia on lifelong lung function: a systematic review. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2023;7(6):429&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2352-4642(23)00030-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37037210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T, Ding L, Zhao M, Song S, Hou J, Li X, Li M, Yin K, Li X, Wang Z. Recent advances in the potential effects of natural products from traditional Chinese medicine against respiratory diseases targeting ferroptosis. Chin Med. 2024;19(1):49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13020-024-00918-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10958864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38519984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roosma E, van Gemert JP, de Zwart AES, van Leer-Buter CC, Hellemons ME, Berg EM, Luijk B, Hoek RAS, van Kessel DA, Akkerman OW, et al. The effect of COVID-19 on transplant function and development of CLAD in lung transplant patients: A multicenter experience. J Heart Lung Transpl. 2022;41(9):1237&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.healun.2022.06.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9212897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35843852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing Z, Sun T, Janssens JP, Chai D, Liu W, Tong Y, Wang Y, Ma Y, Pan M, Cui J, et al. Airflow obstruction and small airway dysfunction following pulmonary tuberculosis: a cross-sectional survey. Thorax. 2023;78(3):274&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2021-218345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9985725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35361688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie AI, Singayagam A, Mitchell S, Wedzicha JA, Shah A, Bloom CI. The effect of inhaled corticosteroids on pneumonia risk in patients with COPD-Bronchiectasis overlap: A UK Population-Based Case-Control study. Chest. 2023;164(4):875&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2023.06.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10808068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37419145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhedin S, Lundholm C, Osvald EC, Almqvist C. Pneumonia in infancy and risk for asthma: the role of Familial confounding and Pneumococcal vaccination. Chest. 2021;160(2):422&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2021.03.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8411448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33727032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y, Luo Y, Li L, Jiang X, Du Y, Wang J, Li H, Gu H, Li D, Tang H, et al. Immune response plays a role in Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1189647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1189647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10250694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37304280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Wen J, Yan Z, Zhou Y, Gong Z, Luo Y, Li Z, Zheng K, Zhang H, Ding N, et al. Suppressing neutrophil Itaconate production attenuates Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia. PLoS Pathog. 2024;20(11):e1012614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1012614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11567624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39499730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YS, Zhou YL, Bai GN, Li SX, Xu D, Chen LN, Chen X, Dong XY, Fu HM, Fu Z, et al. Expert consensus on the diagnosis and treatment of macrolide-resistant Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia in children. World J Pediatr. 2024;20(9):901&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12519-024-00831-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11422262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39143259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Y, Chen Z, Li Y, Lu Q, Li H, Han Y, Sun D, Li X. Combined therapy of Xiaoer Feire Kechuan oral liquid and Azithromycin for Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia in children: A systematic review &amp; meta-analysis. Phytomedicine. 2022;96:153899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phymed.2021.153899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35026500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Xu Z, Zahid Hossain M, Chang J, Su H, Hu J, Wang X, Zheng H, Wang N, Fan Y, et al. Impact of hot and cold nights on pneumonia hospitalisations in children under five years: evidence from low-, middle-, and high-income countries. Environ Int. 2024;192:109041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envint.2024.109041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39353211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Liu H, Chen Y, Yu J, Lin J, Sun Z, Li J, Bai G, Wen F, Xie Y, et al. Guideline on treating community-acquired pneumonia with Chinese patent medicines. Pharmacol Res. 2023;196:106919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2023.106919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37722517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Wang Y, Huang S, Qin X, Yan F, Shen M, et al. A critical overview of systematic reviews of Shenfu injection for heart failure. Cardiovasc Ther. 2021;2021:8816590. 10.1155/2021/8816590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7960068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33777184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei H, Ma Y, Wang L, Wang L, Xu L, Wang R. Effects of Shenfu injection on inflammatory factors and immune function in children with Mycoplasma pneumoniae: A protocol for a double-blind, randomized controlled trial. Med (Baltim). 2021;100(42):e27585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000027585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8542143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34678908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y, Dong HC, Zhang Y, Wang XA, Chen JY, Wang JJ. Application of traditional Chinese medicine integrated therapy based on tuina and herbal medicine in pediatric diarrhea. World J Gastroenterol. 2025;31(44):113017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v31.i44.113017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12678944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41356531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao M, Huang Z, Zheng J, Li W, Zhong Y, Ouyang T. MiR-340-5p alleviates AECOPD by targeting MAP3K2 via Qingjin Huatan Decoction therapy. J Leukoc Biol. 2025;117(4):qiaf021. 10.1093/jleuko/qiaf021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39973067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira CR, Carvalho J, Olimpio F, Vieira R, Aimbire F, Polonini H. Transfer factors peptides (Imuno TF((R))) modulate the lung inflammation and airway remodeling in allergic asthma. Front Immunol. 2022;13:1030252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.1030252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9846599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36685604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y, Xiong Y, Gu Y, Li Q, Liu Y. Chiropractic therapy modulated gut microbiota and attenuated allergic airway inflammation in an immature rat model. Med Sci Monit. 2020;26:e926039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MSM.926039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7532697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32990279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SC, Yu J, Wang HS, Wang DD, Sun Y, Cheng HL, Suen LK, Yeung WF. Parent-administered pediatric tuina for attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder symptoms in preschool children: A pilot randomized controlled trial embedded with a process evaluation. Phytomedicine. 2022;102:154191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phymed.2022.154191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35636174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Zhao C, Li M, Zhang L, Diao J, Wu Y, Yang T, Shi M, Lei Y, Wang Y, et al. Tuina therapy alleviates knee osteoarthritis by modulating PI3K/AKT/mTOR-mediated autophagy: an integrated machine learning and in vivo rat study. Front Immunol. 2025;16:1635818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2025.1635818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12520871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41103437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>