<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41731360</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2318</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC geriatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Geriatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Leg muscle microvascular function is associated with dynamic but not static balance performance in older adults.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12877-026-07213-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Balance impairments in older adults significantly increase fall risk and are a growing public health concern. While muscle strength and mass have been extensively studied in relation to balance, the role of skeletal muscle microvascular function remains unclear. The purpose of this study was to evaluate whether skeletal muscle microvascular function is associated with static and dynamic balance in healthy older adults.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This cross-sectional study included 57 healthy community-dwelling older adults aged 60-75. Static balance was assessed under four conditions (eyes open/closed, on firm/foam surface) using center of pressure metrics. Dynamic balance was evaluated using the Y Balance Test (YBT). Microvascular function of the tibialis anterior (TA) and medial gastrocnemius (MG) was assessed via near-infrared spectroscopy and post-occlusive reactive hyperemia, using TSI10 (initial reperfusion slope), TSI1/2 (recovery half-time), TSI<sub>desaturation</sub> (total desaturation magnitude), and TSI<sub>recovery</sub> (total recovery magnitude) as key indicators. Multiple linear regression analyses were performed to assess associations between microvascular and balance parameters, adjusting for age, sex, grip strength, body fat percentage, and estimated VO&#x2082;max.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">No significant associations were found between microvascular parameters and static balance outcomes across any testing conditions. For dynamic balance, after adjusting for age, sex, grip strength, body fat percentage, and estimated VO&#x2082;max, MG TSI<sub>recovery</sub> was significantly and positively associated with YBT performance on both dominant and non-dominant legs (both p &lt; 0.05). In addition, MG TSI10 was significantly associated with YBT performance on the dominant leg (p &lt; 0.05). No significant associations were found between TA microvascular parameters and dynamic balance performance (all p &gt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study demonstrates that microvascular function in the leg is associated with dynamic but not static balance performance in older adults.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leng</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, Central China Normal University, 382 Xiongchu Avenue, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Zitian</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, Central China Normal University, 382 Xiongchu Avenue, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Haizhen</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, Central China Normal University, 382 Xiongchu Avenue, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Yadan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, Central China Normal University, 382 Xiongchu Avenue, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Jiajing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, Central China Normal University, 382 Xiongchu Avenue, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shubo</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Globus Medical Inc, Audubon, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Chuan</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7996-8994</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, Central China Normal University, 382 Xiongchu Avenue, Wuhan, Hubei, China. chuanzhang@ccnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>82301791</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CCNU24JC040</GrantID><Agency>Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>31101222041</GrantID><Agency>Central China Normal University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Geriatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968548</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2318</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Older adults</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Y Balance Test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fall prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">near-infrared spectroscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postural control</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The authors state that their research was conducted ethically in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. This study was approved by the Institutional Review Board at Central China Normal University (approval No. CCNU-IRB-20403082A). The participants provided written informed consent to participate in the study prior to data collection. Consent for publication: Not applicable in this section. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41731360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-026-07213-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12877-026-07213-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tsai YC, Hsieh LF, Yang S. Age-related changes in posture response under a continuous and unexpected perturbation. J Biomech. 2014;47(2):482&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rath R, Wade MG. The Two Faces of Postural Control in Older Adults: Stability and Function. EBioMedicine. 2017;21:5&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Li Y, Yang GY, Jin K. Age-Related Dysfunction in Balance: A Comprehensive Review of Causes, Consequences, and Interventions. Aging Dis. 2024;16(2):714&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharya B, Maung A, Schuster K, Davis KA. The older they are the harder they fall: Injury patterns and outcomes by age after ground level falls. Injury. 2016;47(9):1955&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Li L, Mao M, et al. The relationships of postural stability with muscle strength and proprioception are different among older adults over and under 75 years of age. J Exerc Sci Fit. 2022;20(4):328&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daubney ME, Culham EG. Lower-extremity muscle force and balance performance in adults aged 65 years and older. Phys Ther. 1999;79(12):1177&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Ancum JM, Pijnappels M, Jonkman NH, et al. Muscle mass and muscle strength are associated with pre- and post-hospitalization falls in older male inpatients: a longitudinal cohort study. BMC Geriatr. 2018;18(1):116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunt E, Ong T, Gordon AL, Greenhaff PL, Gladman JRF. The clinical usefulness of muscle mass and strength measures in older people: a systematic review. Age Ageing. 2021;50(1):88&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paillard T. Relationship between Muscle Function, Muscle Typology and Postural Performance According to Different Postural Conditions in Young and Older Adults. Front Physiol. 2017;8:585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michel E, Zory R, Guerin O, Prate F, Sacco G, Chorin F. Assessing muscle quality as a key predictor to differentiate fallers from non-fallers in older adults. Eur Geriatr Med. 2024;15(5):1301&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpkins C, Yang F. Muscle power is more important than strength in preventing falls in community-dwelling older adults. J Biomech 2022;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muehlbauer T, Gollhofer A, Granacher U. Associations Between Measures of Balance and Lower-Extremity Muscle Strength/Power in Healthy Individuals Across the Lifespan: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2015;45(12):1671&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouveia ER, Ihle A, Gouveia BR, Kliegel M, Marques A, Freitas DL. Muscle Mass and Muscle Strength Relationships to Balance: The Role of Age and Physical Activity. J Aging Phys Act. 2020;28(2):262&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozkal O, Kara M, Topuz S, Kaymak B, Baki A, Ozcakar L. Assessment of core and lower limb muscles for static/dynamic balance in the older people: An ultrasonographic study. Age Ageing. 2019;48(6):881&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cawthon PM, Blackwell TL, Kritchevsky SB et al. Associations Between D3Cr Muscle Mass and Magnetic Resonance Thigh Muscle Volume With Strength, Power, Physical Performance, Fitness, and Limitations in Older Adults in the SOMMA Study. J Gerontol Biol Sci Med Sci 2024;79(4).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinenno FA, Jones PP, Seals DR, Tanaka H. Limb blood flow and vascular conductance are reduced with age in healthy humans: relation to elevations in sympathetic nerve activity and declines in oxygen demand. Circulation. 1999;100(2):164&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cilhoroz BT, Heckel AR, DeBlois JP, Keller A, Sosnoff JJ, Heffernan KS. Arterial stiffness and augmentation index are associated with balance function in young adults. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2023;123(4):891&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrera G, Bunout D, de la Maza MP, Leiva L, Hirsch S. Carotid ultrasound examination as an aging and disability marker. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2014;14(3):710&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heffernan KS, Chal&#xe9; A, Hau C, et al. Systemic vascular function is associated with muscular power in older adults. J Aging Res. 2012;2012:386387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welsch MA, Dobrosielski DA, Arce-Esquivel AA, et al. The association between flow-mediated dilation and physical function in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40(7):1237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross M, Kargl CK, Ferguson R, Gavin TP, Hellsten Y. Exercise-induced skeletal muscle angiogenesis: impact of age, sex, angiocrines and cellular mediators. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2023;123(7):1415&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groen BB, Hamer HM, Snijders T, et al. Skeletal muscle capillary density and microvascular function are compromised with aging and type 2 diabetes. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2014;116(8):998&#x2013;1005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quijoux F, Nicolai A, Chairi I, et al. A review of center of pressure (COP) variables to quantify standing balance in elderly people: Algorithms and open-access code. Physiol Rep. 2021;9(22):e15067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang HW, Chi SY, Tai TL, Li YH, Hwang YH. Impact of age on the postural stability measured by a virtual reality tracker-based posturography and a pressure platform system. BMC Geriatr. 2022;22(1):506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manor B, Costa MD, Hu K, et al. Physiological complexity and system adaptability: evidence from postural control dynamics of older adults. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2010;109(6):1786&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filipa A, Byrnes R, Paterno MV, Myer GD, Hewett TE. Neuromuscular training improves performance on the star excursion balance test in young female athletes. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2010;40(9):551&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leng B, Huang HZ, Zhang C. Effects of coffee intake on skeletal muscle microvascular reactivity at rest and oxygen extraction during exercise: a randomized cross-over trial. J Int Soc Sport Nutr 2024;21(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dellinger JR, Figueroa A, Gonzales JU. Reactive hyperemia half-time response is associated with skeletal muscle oxygen saturation changes during cycling exercise. Microvasc Res 2023:104569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares RN, Somani YB, Proctor DN, Murias JM. The association between near-infrared spectroscopy-derived and flow-mediated dilation assessment of vascular responsiveness in the arm. Microvasc Res. 2019;122:41&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nioka S, Kime R, Sunar U, et al. A novel method to measure regional muscle blood flow continuously using NIRS kinetics information. Dyn Med. 2006;5(1):5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrer-Uris B, Busquets A, Beslija F, Durduran T. Assessment of Microvascular Hemodynamic Adaptations in Finger Flexors of Climbers. Bioeng (Basel) 2024;11(4).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagat P, Kalcik Z, Bartik P, Siska L, Stefan L. A Simple Equation to Estimate Maximal Oxygen Uptake in Older Adults Using the 6 min Walk Test, Sex, Age and Body Mass Index. J Clin Med 2023;12(13).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Buchner A, Lang AG. Statistical power analyses using G*Power 3.1: tests for correlation and regression analyses. Behav Res Methods. 2009;41(4):1149&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Qian M, Kyler K, Xu J. Adipose Tissue-Endothelial Cell Interactions in Obesity-Induced Endothelial Dysfunction. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2021;8:681581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wildman RP, Mackey RH, Bostom A, Thompson T, Sutton-Tyrrell K. Measures of obesity are associated with vascular stiffness in young and older adults. Hypertension. 2003;42(4):468&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuevas-Trisan R. Balance problems and fall risks in the elderly. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am. 2017;28(4):727&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh P-C, Syu D-K, Ho C-C, Lee T-S. Associations of lower-limb muscle strength performance with static and dynamic balance control among older adults in Taiwan. Front Public Health. 2024;12:1226239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seals DR, Jablonski KL, Donato AJ. Aging and vascular endothelial function in humans. Clin Sci (Lond). 2011;120(9):357&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen TPJ, Crooijmans C, Pijls N, et al. Effects of age on microvascular function in patients with normal coronary arteries. EuroIntervention. 2024;20(11):e690&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Citherlet T, Raberin A, Manferdelli G, Mota GR, Millet GP. Age and sex differences in microvascular responses during reactive hyperaemia. Exp Physiol. 2024;109(5):804&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira GV, Soares RN, Volino-Souza M, Leitao R, Murias JM, Alvares TS. The effects of aging and cardiovascular risk factors on microvascular function assessed by near-infrared spectroscopy. Microvasc Res. 2019;126:103911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sipe CL, Ramey KD, Plisky PP, Taylor JD, Y-Balance Test. A Valid and Reliable Assessment in Older Adults. J Aging Phys Act. 2019;27(5):663&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanbhag J, Wolf A, Wechsler I, et al. Methods for integrating postural control into biomechanical human simulations: a systematic review. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2023;20(1):111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jasimi Zindashti N, Noamani A, Vette AH, Rouhani H. A narrative review on dynamic postural stability and neuromuscular control of balance. T Can Soc Mech Eng. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsson F, Halvorsen K, &#xc5;berg AC. Neuromuscular controller models for quantifying standing balance in older people: A systematic review. IEEE Rev Biomed Eng. 2021;16:560&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley DM, Williams ER, Cross JM, et al. Aerobic exercise improves microvascular function in older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(4):773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles M, Charifi N, Verney J, et al. Effect of endurance training on muscle microvascular filtration capacity and vascular bed morphometry in the elderly. Acta Physiol. 2006;187(3):399&#x2013;406.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>