<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41859671</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2673-6217</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in aging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Aging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research hotspots and trends in intrinsic capacity of older people in the context of population aging based on CiteSpace.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1640220</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1640220</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1640220</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fragi.2026.1640220</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To employ bibliometrics to identify the research hotspots and development trends of the intrinsic capacity of older people, thereby providing novel insights for future studies on the management of intrinsic capacity in older adults and further facilitating the advancement of healthy aging.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The literature on the intrinsic capacity of older people, published by China National Knowledge Infrastructure, Wanfang, VIP, and SinoMed, as well as the Web of Science Core Collection, was searched from January 2015 to December 2024. The Note Express 4.1.0 software was used for literature management, and the CiteSpace 6.4. R1 software was used to visually analyze the characteristics of the number of publications, countries, institutions, authors, and keywords, and to plot the relevant graphs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 97 Chinese literature and 745 English literature were included. The number of publications on the older adults' intrinsic capacity has shown an increasing trend both domestically and internationally. In the past 5&#xa0;years, intrinsic capacity has received extensive attention, with 96.9% of Chinese papers and 79.6% of English papers published from 2020 to 2024. European researchers collaborate closely, whereas Chinese research shows weaker collaboration and strong regionalism. Keyword analysis identified 6 clusters in Chinese literature and 17 in English. Chinese hotspots mainly include influencing factors, evaluation tools, chronic disease, grip strength, frailty, and falls. Future directions focus on quality of life, social support, and the recovery period. English studies center on association, management, muscle strength, frailty, exercise, and social support, with potential future directions in supplementation and inflammation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Currently, Chinese research primarily focuses on analyzing influencing factors, with relatively few studies examining intervention measures, while English research has progressed to exploring of intervention strategies. As population aging accelerates, cross-institutional and interdisciplinary cooperation is becoming a key trend. Future research should deepen understanding, particularly for high-risk groups, and explore the effects of supplements, the predictive role of inflammatory markers, and the effectiveness of interventions for this population. These endeavors will contribute to providing precise and personalized management programs for older adults, enhance social support and quality of life, and promote the comprehensive implementation of healthy aging strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Ren, Guo, Tian, Guo, Guo and Zhu.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Minhua</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Inner Mongolia Medical University, Hohhot, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Hongtao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, The Affiliated Hospital of Inner Mongolia Medical University, Hohhot, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Ye</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, The Affiliated Hospital of Inner Mongolia Medical University, Hohhot, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Yingjie</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Inner Mongolia Medical University, Hohhot, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Wanjun</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Inner Mongolia Medical University, Hohhot, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Liangjin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, The Affiliated Hospital of Inner Mongolia Medical University, Hohhot, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Aging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918231199706676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2673-6217</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bibliometrics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intrinsic capacity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">older people</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">research hotspot</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">research trend</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">visual analysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41859671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12996128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fragi.2026.1640220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1640220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amini N., Ibn Hach M., Lapauw L., Dupont J., Vercauteren L., Verschueren S., et al. (2024). Meta-analysis on the interrelationship between sarcopenia and mild cognitive impairment, Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and other forms of dementia. J. Cachexia, Sarcopenia Muscle 15 (4), 1240&#x2013;1253. 10.1002/jcsm.13485</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcsm.13485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11294028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38715252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beard J. R., Jotheeswaran A. T., Cesari M., Araujo de Carvalho I. (2019). The structure and predictive value of intrinsic capacity in a longitudinal study of ageing. BMJ Open 9 (11), e026119. 10.1136/bmjopen-2018-026119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2018-026119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6830681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31678933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beard J. R., Si Y., Liu Z., Chenoweth L., Hanewald K. (2022). Intrinsic capacity: validation of a new WHO concept for healthy aging in a longitudinal Chinese study. Journals Gerontology 77 (1), 94&#x2013;100. 10.1093/gerona/glab226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glab226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34343305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belloni G., Cesari M. (2019). Frailty and intrinsic capacity: two distinct but related constructs. Front. Med. 6, 133. 10.3389/fmed.2019.00133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2019.00133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6591451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31275941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao X., Yi X., Chen H., Tian Y., Li S., Zhou J. (2024). Prevalence of intrinsic capacity decline among community-dwelling older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Aging Clin. Exp. Res. 36 (1), 157. 10.1007/s40520-024-02816-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40520-024-02816-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11294388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39088112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cesari M., Araujo de Carvalho I., Amuthavalli Thiyagarajan J., Cooper C., Martin F. C., Reginster J. Y., et al. (2018). Evidence for the domains supporting the construct of intrinsic capacity. Journals Gerontology 73 (12), 1653&#x2013;1660. 10.1093/gerona/gly011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/gly011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29408961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cesari M., Sumi Y., Han Z. A., Perracini M., Jang H., Briggs A., et al. (2022). Implementing care for healthy ageing. BMJ Glob. Health 7 (2), e007778. 10.1136/bmjgh-2021-007778</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2021-007778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8860009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35185014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles A., Buckinx F., Locquet M., Reginster J. Y., Petermans J., Gruslin B., et al. (2020). Prediction of adverse outcomes in nursing home residents according to intrinsic capacity proposed by the world health organization. Journals Gerontology 75 (8), 1594&#x2013;1599. 10.1093/gerona/glz218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glz218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31562812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C. (2006). CiteSpace II: detecting and visualizing emerging trends and transient patterns in scientific literature. J. Am. Soc. Inf. Sci. Technol. 57 (3), 359&#x2013;377. 10.1002/asi.20317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/asi.20317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Chen C., Liu Z. (2015). The methodology function of CiteSpace mapping knowledge domains. Stud. Sci. Sci. 30 (2), 242&#x2013;253. 10.16192/j.cnki.1003-2053.2015.02.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16192/j.cnki.1003-2053.2015.02.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Assun&#xe7;&#xe3;o Cortez Corr&#xea;a L. C., Raffin J., Vellas B., Guerra R. O., de Souto Barreto P. (2025). Sex-specific associations of neurodegeneration and inflammatory biomarkers with intrinsic capacity in older adults: findings from the 4-year longitudinal multidomain Alzheimer&#x2019;s prevention trial (MAPT). Maturitas 193, 108191. 10.1016/j.maturitas.2024.108191</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2024.108191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39754932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao W. X., Liu J., Wang J., Jin Y. L., Yeung S. L. A., Lam T. H., et al. (2025). Association of intrinsic capacity with incident type 2 diabetes mellitus in older Chinese: guangzhou biobank cohort study. Archives Gerontology Geriatrics 129, 105687. 10.1016/j.archger.2024.105687</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.archger.2024.105687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39581158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giudici K. V., de Souto Barreto P., Guerville F., Beard J., Araujo de Carvalho I., Andrieu S., et al. (2019). Associations of C-reactive protein and homocysteine concentrations with the impairment of intrinsic capacity domains over a 5-year follow-up among community-dwelling older adults at risk of cognitive decline (MAPT study). Exp. Gerontol. 127, 110716. 10.1016/j.exger.2019.110716</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2019.110716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31493520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giudici K. V., de Souto Barreto P., Beard J., Cantet C., Araujo de Carvalho I., Rolland Y., et al. (2020). Effect of long-term omega-3 supplementation and a lifestyle multidomain intervention on intrinsic capacity among community-dwelling older adults: secondary analysis of a randomized, placebo-controlled trial (MAPT study). Maturitas 141, 39&#x2013;45. 10.1016/j.maturitas.2020.06.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2020.06.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33036701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Bautista E., de Souto Barreto P., Andrieu S., Rolland Y., Vellas B. MAPT/DSA group members are listed under &#x2018;Contributors&#x2019; (2021). Screening for intrinsic capacity impairments as markers of increased risk of frailty and disability in the context of integrated care for older people: secondary analysis of MAPT. Maturitas 150, 1&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.maturitas.2021.05.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2021.05.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34274071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W., Meng L., Han J., Yang B., Sun J., Guo Y., et al. (2024). Intrinsic capacity and its association with predictors among Chinese empty nest older adults in communities: a latent class analysis. BMC Geriatr. 24 (1), 1008. 10.1186/s12877-024-05583-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-024-05583-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11658339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39702076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu F. W., Sun C. Y., Su W. C., Chang C. M. (2025). Frailty and intrinsic capacity as predictors of recovery in older patients surgically treated for cancer: a longitudinal study. Cancer Nurs. 10.1097/NCC.0000000000001497</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NCC.0000000000001497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40179143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C. H., Okada K., Matsushita E., Uno C., Satake S., Martins B. A., et al. (2021). Dietary patterns and intrinsic capacity among community-dwelling older adults: a 3-year prospective cohort study. Eur. J. Nutr. 60 (6), 3303&#x2013;3313. 10.1007/s00394-021-02505-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00394-021-02505-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33598774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang B., Luo T., Jiang X. (2022). Correlation between decline in intrinsic capacity and blood pressure variability in elderly patients with hypertension. Chin. J. Geriatric Heart Brain Vessel Dis. 24 (7), 709&#x2013;712. 10.3969/j.issn.1009-0126.2022.07.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1009-0126.2022.07.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang A. C., Chen L. Y., Tseng S. H., Huang C. Y., Yen K. H., Chen L. K., et al. (2024). Intrinsic capacity transitions predict overall and cause-specific mortality, incident disability, and healthcare utilization. J. Nutr. Health &amp; Aging 28 (10), 100359. 10.1016/j.jnha.2024.100359</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnha.2024.100359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12877271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39277970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang X., Ma X., Chen F. (2023). Correlation between intrinsic capacity and quality of life in 1042 community elderly people in urumqi. J. Xinjiang Med. Univ. 46 (4), 561&#x2013;566. 10.3969/j.issn.1009-5551.2023.04.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1009-5551.2023.04.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones R., Taylor T. L., Mankowski R. T., Dodds F., Hankes M., Hobson J., et al. (2024). Exercise training to preserve vitality capacity in ageing. Exp. Physiol. 10.1113/EP091731</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP091731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39504077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang Y., Shi H., Zhang J., Meng X., Zhang C., Shen J., et al. (2024). The bidirectional relationship between intrinsic capacity and catastrophic health expenditure in China: a longitudinal study. Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 80 (3), glae301. 10.1093/gerona/glae301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glae301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39713966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke K., Wang M., Wang J. (2024). Research advances in influencing factors and enhancement strategies for older adults' intrinsic capacity. Mod. Nurse 31 (7), 6&#x2013;10. 10.19792/j.cnki.1006-6411.2024.20.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19792/j.cnki.1006-6411.2024.20.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolakowski M., Lupica A., Ben B. S., Djaja-Josko V., Kolakowski J., Cichocki J., et al. (2025). CAREUP: an integrated care platform with intrinsic capacity monitoring and prediction capabilities. Sensors 25 (3), 916. 10.3390/s25030916</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25030916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11819908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39943555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan Y., Salvador J. T., Zhang S., Wu M. (2025). The impact of community-based Tai chi exercise on intrinsic capacity improvement in the elderly: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Postgrad. Med. J., qgaf171. 10.1093/postmj/qgaf171</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/postmj/qgaf171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41075277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Huang F., Zhou J. (2022). Analysis of the correlation between the internal ability and self-efficacy of the elderly patients with stroke in the recovery period. J. Bingtuan Med. 20 (3), 62&#x2013;65. 10.3969/j.issn.1672-4356.2022.03.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1672-4356.2022.03.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Chhetri J. K., Chen Y. (2024). Reliability and validity of the Chinese version of WHO integrated care for older people screening tool. Chin. J. Clin. Healthc. 27 (5), 621&#x2013;625. 10.3969/J.issn.1672-6790.2024.05.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/J.issn.1672-6790.2024.05.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma L., Chhetri J. K., Zhang Y., Liu P., Chen Y., Li Y., et al. (2020). Integrated care for older people screening tool for measuring intrinsic capacity: preliminary findings from ICOPE pilot in China. Front. Med. 7, 576079. 10.3389/fmed.2020.576079</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2020.576079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7734133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33330532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma L., Chhetri J. K., Zhang L., Sun F., Li Y., Tang Z. (2021). Cross-sectional study examining the status of intrinsic capacity decline in community-dwelling older adults in China: prevalence, associated factors and implications for clinical care. BMJ Open 11 (1), e043062. 10.1136/bmjopen-2020-043062</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-043062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7786809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33402410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma L., Zheng E., Fang Y., Chen H., Zhou C., Cai S., et al. (2024). Sensitivity and specificity of three measures of intrinsic capacity in older people aged 80 and over in nursing homes. Clin. Interventions Aging 19, 2179&#x2013;2194. 10.2147/CIA.S486663</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CIA.S486663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11699827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39759395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maheshwari S., Dai C., Giri S., Harmon C., Tucker A., Fowler M. E., et al. (2024). Intrinsic capacity and survival among older adults with gastrointestinal malignancies: the cancer and aging resilience evaluation registry. Cancer 130 (20), 3530&#x2013;3539. 10.1002/cncr.35427</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.35427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38865419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan F. (2020). The elderly are the key prevention population of covid-19 -- an interview with professor zhongnanshan, academician of the Chinese academy of engineering and head of the high-level expert group of the national health Commission. China Med. Her. 17 (06), 1&#x2013;3. 10.20047/j.issn1673-7210.2020.06.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20047/j.issn1673-7210.2020.06.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R., Iriarte-Fern&#xe1;ndez M., Santaf&#xe9; G., Malanda A., Beard J. R., Garcia-Hermoso A., et al. (2023). Association of intrinsic capacity with incidence and mortality of cardiovascular disease: prospective study in UK biobank. J. Cachexia, Sarcopenia Muscle 14 (5), 2054&#x2013;2063. 10.1002/jcsm.13283</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcsm.13283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10570093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37434422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R., Borda M. G., S&#xe1;ez de Asteasu M. L., Izquierdo M. (2025). Intrinsic capacity as a predictor of depression onset in middle-aged and older adults: insights from the UK biobank. J. Affect. Disord. 388, 119590. 10.1016/j.jad.2025.119590</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2025.119590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40482680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-S&#xe1;nchez J. L., de Souto Barreto P., Ant&#xf3;n-Rodrigo I., Ram&#xf3;n-Espinoza F., Mar&#xed;n-Epelde I., S&#xe1;nchez-Latorre M., et al. (2022). Effects of a 12-week vivifrail exercise program on intrinsic capacity among frail cognitively impaired community-dwelling older adults: secondary analysis of a multicentre randomised clinical trial. Age Ageing 51 (12), afac303. 10.1093/ageing/afac303</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afac303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9799251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36580558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi X., Ouyang X., Shen L. (2023). Relationship between decline of intrinsic capacity and frailty in elderly inpatients. Pract. Geriatr. 37 (3), 256&#x2013;260. 10.3969/j.issn.1003-9198.2023.03.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1003-9198.2023.03.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si Y., Hanewald K., Chen S., Li B., Bateman H., Beard J. R. (2023). Life-course inequalities in intrinsic capacity and healthy ageing, China. Bull. World Health Organ. 101 (5), 307&#x2013;316C. 10.2471/BLT.22.288888</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2471/BLT.22.288888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10140694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37131938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song N., Zhou J., Zhang L. (2024). Association between intrinsic capacity and falls among older adults. China Prev. Med. J. 36 (1), 1&#x2013;4. 10.19485/j.cnki.issn2096-5087.2024.01.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19485/j.cnki.issn2096-5087.2024.01.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stolz E., Mayerl H., Freidl W., Roller-Wirnsberger R., Gill T. M. (2022). Intrinsic capacity predicts negative health outcomes in older adults. Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 77 (1), 101&#x2013;105. 10.1093/gerona/glab279</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glab279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8751795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34569602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun M., He Q., Sun N., Han Q., Wang Y., Zhao H., et al. (2024). Intrinsic capacity, polygenic risk score, APOE genotype, and risk of dementia: a prospective cohort study based on the UK biobank. Neurology 102 (12), e209452. 10.1212/WNL.0000000000209452</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000209452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38843484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda C., Guyonnet S., Sumi Y., Vellas B., Araujo de Carvalho I. (2020). Integrated care for older people and the implementation in the INSPIRE care cohort. J. Prev. Alzheimer&#x2019;s Dis. 7 (2), 70&#x2013;74. 10.14283/jpad.2020.8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14283/jpad.2020.8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32236394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UN (2022). World population prospects 2022. New York: United Nations.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO (2025). Integrated care for older people (ICOPE): guidance for person-centred assessment and pathways in primary care.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2015). World report on ageing and health. Geneva: World Health Organization.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2017). WHO clinical consortium on healthy ageing topic focus: frailty and intrinsic capacity report of consortium meeting 1&#x2013;2 December 2016. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Z., Yang Z., Zhao H. (2024). Development and reliability and validity test of the intrinsic capacity assessment scale for the older people. Chin. J. Nurs. 59 (15), 1852&#x2013;1859. 10.3761/j.issn.0254-1769.2024.15.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3761/j.issn.0254-1769.2024.15.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>You L., Xu W., Qi J. (2023). Correlation analysis between falls in hospitalized elderly patients and their intrinsic capacity. J. Qilu Nurs. 29 (1), 112&#x2013;115. 10.3969/j.issn.1006-7256.2023.01.035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1006-7256.2023.01.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu L., Zhang P., Miao M. (2018). A specific tertiary hospital undertakes relevant projects within the field of geriatric medicine research. Chin. J. Gerontology 38 (20), 5089&#x2013;5092. 10.3969/j.issn.1005-9202.2018.20.085</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1005-9202.2018.20.085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J., Jin Y., Si H., Bian Y., Liu Q. (2023). Relationship between intrinsic capacity and health-related quality of life among community-dwelling older adults: the moderating role of social support. Qual. Life Res. 33 (1), 267&#x2013;280. 10.1007/s11136-023-03520-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-023-03520-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37845404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue X., Wang M., Li W. (2024). Comparison of scoping review on intrinsic capacity assessment and outcome indicators in the elderly. Chin. Nurs. Res. 38 (1), 122&#x2013;129. 10.12102/j.issn.1009-6493.2024.01.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12102/j.issn.1009-6493.2024.01.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Wang J., Shen H. (2024). Correlation between potentially inappropriate medication and decline of intrinsic capacity in elderly inpatients. Chin. J. Multiple Organ Dis. Elder. 23 (7), 514&#x2013;518. 10.11915/j.issn.1671-5403.2024.07.11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11915/j.issn.1671-5403.2024.07.11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Yu W., Ren Y. (2024). Current status of intrinsic capacity of the elderly in medical-nursing combined institutions and its influencing factors. Anhui Med. J. 45 (9), 1165&#x2013;1171. 10.3969/j.issn.1000-0399.2024.09.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1000-0399.2024.09.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Zhang L., Wu G. (2023). Influence of intrinsic capacity decline on quality of life of the community elderly. Pract. Geriatr. 37 (10), 1014&#x2013;1018. 10.3969/j.issn.1003-9198.2023.10.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1003-9198.2023.10.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao S., Liu M., Chang Y. (2024). Cut-off value of grip strength and the relationship with intrinsic capability in Chinese elderly. Pract. Geriatr. 39 (3), 298&#x2013;302. 10.3969/j.issn.1003-9198.2025.03.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1003-9198.2025.03.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J., Ji X., Huang Y. (2024). New advances in frailty and intrinsic capacity under healthy ageing framework. Chin. J. Multiple Organ Dis. Elder. 23 (11), 872&#x2013;876. 10.11915/j.issn.1671-5403.2024.11.192</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11915/j.issn.1671-5403.2024.11.192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng G., Ou F., Chen S., Ji C., Chang Q., Wang D., et al. (2025). Associations of intrinsic capacity deficit proxy score and genetic susceptibility with incident chronic kidney disease and life expectancy. Journals Gerontology 80 (11), glaf187. 10.1093/gerona/glaf187</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glaf187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41105198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>