<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41717149</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS) Protocols and Their Impact on Quality of Care and Patient Safety in Peri-Anaesthesia Nursing: A Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e101821</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e101821</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e101821</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.101821</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This narrative review aimed to critically synthesise current evidence on Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS) protocols and their impact on quality of care and patient safety in peri-anaesthesia nursing, with particular emphasis on the Post-Anaesthesia Care Unit (PACU) and the immediate postoperative period. A narrative literature review was conducted to identify evidence related to ERAS implementation and peri-anaesthesia nursing practice. International databases, including PubMed and Elsevier, were searched for relevant publications addressing ERAS protocols, perioperative care, patient safety, and quality improvement. The review focused on studies published between 2019 and 2025. Peer-reviewed articles, clinical guidelines, and original studies relevant to peri-anaesthesia nursing and postoperative recovery were included, and the selected literature was screened and synthesised descriptively. The review demonstrated that ERAS protocols are associated with improved quality and patient safety outcomes during the peri-anaesthesia phase of care. Reported benefits included enhanced postoperative recovery and pain management, reduced complication rates, earlier mobilisation, and greater consistency in clinical practice within the PACU. The findings also highlighted the central role of peri-anaesthesia nurses in patient monitoring, education, and early recovery support, underscoring their contribution to successful ERAS implementation. Overall, ERAS protocols provide a structured framework for improving quality and patient safety in peri-anaesthesia nursing care. Strong peri-anaesthesia nursing involvement and effective multidisciplinary collaboration are essential for optimal implementation, particularly during immediate postoperative recovery. Further research focusing on peri-anaesthesia nursing-specific outcomes and experiences with ERAS pathways is warranted.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Bourazani et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bourazani</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology, Hellenic Anticancer Institute, Saint Savvas Hospital, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pappa</LastName><ForeName>Despoina</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing, Henry Dunant Hospital Center, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manthou</LastName><ForeName>Panagiota</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infection Prevention, University of West Attica, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chrysi</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surgery, Hellenic Anticancer Institute, Saint Savvas Hospital, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fasianos</LastName><ForeName>Christos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health, Hellenic Anticancer Institute, Saint Savvas Hospital, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enhanced recovery after surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eras protocols</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient safety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peri-anesthesia nursing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">perioperative care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality improvement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of care</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41717149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12914364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.101821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Enhanced recovery after surgery - ERAS-principles, practice and feasibility in the elderly. Ljungqvist O, Hubner M. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2018;30:249&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5856872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29453605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidelines for perioperative care in elective colorectal surgery: Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS&#xae;) Society Recommendations: 2018. Gustafsson UO, Scott MJ, Hubner M, et al. World J Surg. 2019;43:659&#x2013;695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30426190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Implementation of multiple enhanced recovery after surgery guidelines in Alberta, Canada. Nelson AJ, Faris P, Wasylak T, Nguyen T, Nelson G, Gramlich L. Clin Nutr. 2019;31:110&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enhanced recovery after surgery: implementing a new standard of surgical care. Altman AD, Helpman L, McGee J, Samou&#xeb;lian V, Auclair MH, Brar H, Nelson GS. CMAJ. 2019;191:0&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6488471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31036609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Implementation of eras protocol for cesarean section. Puji&#x107; B, Vejnovi&#x107; T, Jovanovi&#x107; L, Andjeli&#x107; N, Vejnovi&#x107; A, Palmer C. Acta Clin Croat. 2022;61:151&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9942459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36824633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Implementation of an ERAS pathway in colorectal surgery. Cavallaro P, Bordeianou L. Clin Colon Rectal Surg. 2019;32:102&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6395097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30833858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short-term outcome in robotic vs laparoscopic and open rectal tumor surgery within an ERAS protocol: a retrospective cohort study from the Swedish ERAS database. Asklid D, Ljungqvist O, Xu Y, Gustafsson UO. Surg Endosc. 2022;36:2006&#x2013;2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8847168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33856528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enhanced recovery after surgery: overarching themes of the ERAS&#xae; Society Guidelines &amp; Consensus Statements for Adult Specialty Surgery. Grant MC, Engelman DT. Perioper Med (Lond) 2025;14:120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12577217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41168801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barriers to implementation of enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) by a multidisciplinary team in China: a multicentre qualitative study. Wang D, Liu Z, Zhou J, et al. BMJ Open. 2022;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8921855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35288383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>What quality of care means? Exploring clinical nurses' perceptions on the concept of quality care: a qualitative study. Stavropoulou A, Rovithis M, Kelesi M, et al. Clin Pract. 2022;12:468&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9326653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35892437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sustaining perioperative patient safety improvement: the relevance of patient safety policies and contextual factors in European healthcare systems. Kristensen K, Wang S, Velasco DA, et al. Int J Qual Health Care. 2025;37:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12611545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41056419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard operating procedures as a trend in ensuring healthcare safety. Shestopalova TN, Gololobova TV. Health Risk Anal. 2018;2018:129&#x2013;137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of healthcare management protocols and their implications for the quality of patient care. Singh S, Joshi SV, Panigrahi S, Patange A, Upendra Sharma US. Health Leadersh Qual Life. 2023;2:23221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enhancing patient safety culture in hospitals. Mistri IU, Badge A, Shahu S. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10811440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38283419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of certification and accreditation on quality management in 4 clinical services in 73 European hospitals. Shaw CD, Groene O, Botje D, et al. Int J Qual Health Care. 2014;26:100&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4001697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24615598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Implementing ERAS: how we achieved success within an anesthesia department. Ellis DB, Agarwala A, Cavallo E, Linov P, Hidrue MK, Del Carmen MG, Sisodia R. BMC Anesthesiol. 2021;21:36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7863438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33546602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The multidisciplinary team (MDT) approach and quality of care. Taberna M, Gil Moncayo F, Jan&#xe9;-Salas E, et al. Front Oncol. 2020;10:85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7100151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32266126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Implementation of consensus-based perioperative care pathways to reduce clinical variation for elective surgery in an Australian private hospital: a mixed-methods pre-post study protocol. Pagano L, Hemmert C, Hirschhorn A, et al. BMJ Open. 2023;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10373689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37495386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enhanced recovery pathways improve early outcomes and reduce length of stay in primary hip and knee arthroplasty: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Sattler L, Puze E, Sands K, Talbot W. Int J Orthop Trauma Nurs. 2025;57:101186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40318430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Does implementation of an enhanced recovery after surgery program for hip replacement improve quality of recovery in an Australian private hospital: a quality improvement study. Tan NL, Hunt JL, Gwini SM. BMC Anesthesiol. 2018;18:64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6001129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29898653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enhanced recovery after surgery: exploring the advances and strategies. Jain SN, Lamture Y, Krishna M. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10654132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38022245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The quality improvement challenge - how nurses and allied health professionals can solve the knowing-doing gap in enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) Wainwright TW. Medicina (Kaunas) 2020;56:20652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7760031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33260932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS&#xae;): barriers and solutions for nurses. Balfour A, Amery J, Burch J, Smid-Nanninga H. Asia Pac J Oncol Nurs. 2022;9:100040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9130527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35647226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluating the role of nursing interventions in enhanced recovery after surgery for minimally invasive spine surgery: a retrospective analysis. Zhang D, Ding H, Shen C, Liu Y, Jia N. Front Surg. 2025;12:1519135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11880021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40046500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>