<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41866788</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1522-726X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Catheterization and cardiovascular interventions : official journal of the Society for Cardiac Angiography &amp; Interventions</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Catheter Cardiovasc Interv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Beyond Outcomes: Emotional and Technical Growth Following Procedural Complications.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ccd.70567</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Major procedural complications are an unavoidable feature of interventional cardiology and often represent pivotal inflection points in an operator's professional development. Beyond their immediate clinical consequences, these events can profoundly influence confidence, judgment, risk tolerance, and subsequent technical growth. Whether complications stimulate learning or precipitate persistent distress depends largely on how they are interpreted, discussed, and supported. This review examines the emotional and cognitive responses of interventional cardiologists following major procedural complications. We explore how cognitive bias, cognitive heuristics, perfectionism, moral injury, and threats to professional identity shape recovery, decision-making, and future procedural behavior. These forces may foster adaptive learning or drive maladaptive responses, including rumination, self-doubt, withdrawal, and risk aversion. Drawing on evidence from cognitive psychology, aviation safety, and established peer-support frameworks, we outline practical strategies to transform complications into opportunities for emotional and technical growth. Institutional approaches include psychologically safe debriefing, process-focused morbidity and mortality conferences, peer-support programs, leadership development, and accessible mental health resources. Individual strategies such as internal validation, narrative reframing, patient reconnection, mentorship, and structured reflective practice help restore confidence, preserve moral integrity, and reinforce professional identity by explicitly separating decision quality from outcomes. Supporting operator recovery after procedural complications is not ancillary to patient care; it is foundational to sustained technical excellence, sound clinical judgment, and compassionate practice. Integrating structured, stigma-free recovery pathways into interventional training and institutional culture should be recognized as a core component of patient safety and professional sustainability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Touma</LastName><ForeName>George</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>St George Private Hospital, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fairley</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0711-9499</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wellington Cardiology Department, Wellington Hospital, Wellington, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lombardi</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Washington Medicine and Heart Institute, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ada</LastName><ForeName>Cuneyt</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Macquarie University Hospital, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Bernard</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Unit, North Shore Hospital, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khialani</LastName><ForeName>Bharat</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tan Tock Seng Hospital, National Healthcare Group, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Catheter Cardiovasc Interv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100884139</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1522-1946</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41866788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ccd.70567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>T. D. Shanafelt and J. H. Noseworthy, &#x201c;Executive Leadership and Physician Well&#x2010;Being,&#x201d; Mayo Clinic Proceedings 92, no. 1 (January 2017): 129&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Touma, S. Fairley, W. Lombardi, C. Ada, B. Wong, and B. Khialani, &#x201c;When a Patient Dies During a Procedure: Navigating Operator Grief in Interventional Cardiology,&#x201d; Catheterization and Cardiovascular Interventions 106 (2025): 3642&#x2013;3648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. A. Armstrong, I. A. Dutescu, A. Tung, et al., &#x201c;Cognitive Biases in Surgery: Systematic Review,&#x201d; British Journal of Surgery 110, no. 6 (2023): 645&#x2013;654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Aylmore, S. Agarwal, H. J. Marcus, and A. Pandit, &#x201c;Cognitive Biases and Heuristics in Surgical Settings: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Annals of Surgery 282 (2025): 946&#x2013;953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. S. Blumenthal&#x2010;Barby and H. Krieger, &#x201c;Medicine and Heuristics: Cognitive Biases and Medical Decision&#x2010;Making,&#x201d; Journal of Evaluation in Clinical Practice 26, no. 6 (2020): 1547&#x2013;1557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Croskerry, D. M. Campion, and N. A. Pavlidis, &#x201c;Cognitive Biases Associated With Medical Decisions: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; BMC Medical Informatics and Decision Making 16 (2016): 123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Awanzo and J. Thompson, &#x201c;Cognitive Biases in Clinical Decision&#x2010;Making in Prehospital Critical Care: A Scoping Review,&#x201d; Scandinavian Journal of Trauma, Resuscitation and Emergency Medicine 33 (2025): 101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Baron and J. C. Hershey, &#x201c;Outcome Bias in Decision Evaluation,&#x201d; Journal of Personality and Social Psychology 54, no. 4 (1988): 569&#x2013;579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Dekker, Second Victim: Error, Guilt, Trauma and Resilience (CRC Press, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Kruger and D. Dunning, &#x201c;Unskilled and Unaware of it: How Difficulties in Recognizing One's Own Incompetence Lead to Inflated Self&#x2010;Assessments,&#x201d; Journal of Personality and Social Psychology 77, no. 6 (1999): 1121&#x2013;1134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. L. Hewitt and G. L. Flett, &#x201c;Perfectionism in the Self and Social Contexts: Conceptualization, Assessment, and Association With Psychopathology,&#x201d; Journal of Personality and Social Psychology 60, no. 3 (1991): 456&#x2013;470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. W. Enns and B. J. Cox, The Nature and Assessment of Perfectionism: A Critical Analysis (Oxford University Press, 2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Stoeber and K. Otto, &#x201c;Positive Conceptions of Perfectionism: Approaches, Evidence, Challenges,&#x201d; Personality and Social Psychology Review 10, no. 4 (2006): 295&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. P. Hill and T. Curran, &#x201c;Multidimensional Perfectionism and Burnout: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Personality and Social Psychology Review 20, no. 3 (2016): 269&#x2013;288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Prentice, D. Dorstyn, and A. Nguyen, &#x201c;Perfectionism and Psychological Distress Among Medical Students and Doctors: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; International Journal of Medical Education 11 (2020): 183&#x2013;194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. Gh&#xe9;z, et al., &#x201c;Surgeons&#x2019; Psychological Responses to Adverse Events and Complications: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Annals of Surgery 272, no. 6 (2020): 1062&#x2013;1070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Papanagnou, &#x201c;The Hidden Curriculum and Its Role in Physician Distress,&#x201d; Clin Teach 12, no. 5 (2015): 332&#x2013;337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Hodkinson, A. Zhou, J. Johnson, et al., &#x201c;Associations of Physician Burnout With Career Engagement and Quality of Patient Care: Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; BMJ (London) 378 (2022): e070442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Dean, S. Talbot, and A. Dean, &#x201c;Reframing Clinician Distress: Moral Injury Not Burnout,&#x201d; Federal Practitioner: For the Health Care Professionals of the VA, DoD, and PHS 36, no. 9 (2019): 400&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. D. Shanafelt, S. Boone, L. Tan, et al., &#x201c;Burnout and Satisfaction with Work&#x2010;Life Balance Among US Physicians Relative to the General US Population,&#x201d; Archives of Internal Medicine 172, no. 18 (2012): 1377&#x2013;1385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. F. Yalom, Existential psychotherapy (Basic Books, 1980).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. D. Scott, L. E. Hirschinger, K. R. Cox, M. McCoig, J. Brandt, and L. W. Hall, &#x201c;The Natural History of Recovery for the Healthcare Provider &#x2018;Second Victim&#x2019; After Adverse Patient Events,&#x201d; Quality and Safety in Health Care 18, no. 5 (2009): 325&#x2013;330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Ruiz&#x2010;Hern&#xe1;ndez and H. Bueno, &#x201c;Second Victims and Quality of Support Resources Among Cardiology Professionals,&#x201d; Rev Esp Cardiol (Eng Ed) 75, no. 8 (2022): 686&#x2013;688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. C. Clark, &#x201c;Work/Family Border Theory: A New Theory of Work/Family Balance,&#x201d; Human Relations 53, no. 6 (2000): 747&#x2013;770.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. A. Rando, Treatment of Complicated Mourning (Research Press, 1993), 495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. E. Bedell, K. Cadenhead, and T. B. Graboys, &#x201c;The Doctor's Letter of Condolence,&#x201d; New England Journal of Medicine 344 (2001): 1162&#x2013;1164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. H. Gallagher, D. Studdert, and W. Levinson, &#x201c;Disclosing Harmful Medical Errors to Patients,&#x201d; New England Journal of Medicine 356 (2007): 2713&#x2013;2719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. P. West, L. N. Dyrbye, and T. D. Shanafelt, &#x201c;Physician Burnout: Contributors, Consequences and Solutions,&#x201d; Journal of Internal Medicine 283, no. 6 (2018): 516&#x2013;529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Dong, F. C. Zhou, S. W. Xu, et al., &#x201c;Prevalence of Suicide&#x2010;Related Behaviors Among Physicians: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Suicide and Life&#x2010;Threatening Behavior 50, no. 6 (2020): 1264&#x2013;1275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Lofi, C. La Vecchia, C. Galassi, et al., &#x201c;Suicide Among Physicians and Health&#x2010;Care Workers: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; PLoS One 14, no. 12 (2019): e0225673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. S. Rotenstein, M. Torre, M. A. Ramos, et al., &#x201c;Prevalence of Burnout Among Physicians: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Journal of the American Medical Association 320, no. 11 (2018): 1131&#x2013;1150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Franklin&#x2010;Street, J. Lai, M. Grever, et al., &#x201c;The Relationship Between Physician Burnout and Depression, Anxiety, Suicidality and Substance Abuse: A Mixed&#x2010;Methods Systematic Review,&#x201d; Frontiers in Public Health 11 (2023): 1133484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Syed, Black Box Thinking: Why Most People Never Learn From Their Mistakes&#x2014;But Some Do (John Murray, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Sawyer, W. Eppich, M. Brett&#x2010;Fleegler, V. Grant, and A. Cheng, &#x201c;More Than One Way to Debrief: A Critical Review of Healthcare Simulation Debriefing Methods,&#x201d; Simulation in Healthcare: The Journal of the Society for Simulation in Healthcare 11, no. 3 (2016): 209&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Blankenship, J. A. Doll, F. Latif, et al., &#x201c;Best Practices for Cardiac Catheterization Laboratory Morbidity and Mortality Conferences,&#x201d; JACC: Cardiovascular Interventions 16 (2023): 503&#x2013;514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Y. Hu, &#x201c;Physicians' Needs in Coping with Emotional Stressors: The Case for Peer Support,&#x201d; Archives of Surgery 147, no. 3 (2012): 212&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Flanagan, R. Chadwick, J. Goodrich, C. Ford, and R. Wickens, &#x201c;Reflection for All Healthcare Staff: A National Evaluation of Schwartz Rounds,&#x201d; Journal of Interprofessional Care 34, no. 1 (2020): 140&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zwack and J. Schweitzer, &#x201c;If Every Fifth Physician Is Affected by Burnout, What About the Other Four? Resilience Strategies of Experienced Physicians,&#x201d; Academic Medicine 88, no. 3 (2013): 382&#x2013;389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. S. Krasner, &#x201c;Association of an Educational Program in Mindful Communication With Burnout, Empathy, and Attitudes Among Primary Care Physicians,&#x201d; Journal of the American Medical Association 302, no. 12 (2009): 1284&#x2013;1293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Mann, J. Gordon, and A. MacLeod, &#x201c;Reflection and Reflective Practice in Health Professions Education: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Advances in Health Sciences Education 14, no. 4 (2009): 595&#x2013;621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. E. Angus and J. D. McLeod, The Handbook of Narrative and Psychotherapy: Practice, Theory and Research (Sage Publications, 2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. J. Langer, Mindfulness (Addison&#x2010;Wesley, 1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. D. Pratt and B. R. Jachna, &#x201c;Implementing a Comprehensive Peer Support Program to Assist Healthcare Providers,&#x201d; Joint Commission Journal on Quality and Patient Safety/Joint Commission Resources 41, no. 10 (2015): 465&#x2013;471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. G. Ano and E. B. Vasconcelles, &#x201c;Religious Coping and Psychological Adjustment to Stress: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Psychology 61, no. 4 (2005): 461&#x2013;480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. I. Pargament, B. W. Smith, H. G. Koenig, and L. Perez, &#x201c;Patterns of Positive and Negative Religious Coping With Major Life Stressors,&#x201d; Journal for the Scientific Study of Religion 37, no. 4 (1998): 710&#x2013;724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. L. Park and J. H. Wortmann, &#x201c;Religion and Spirituality in Adjustment Following Trauma: A Review,&#x201d; Frontiers in Psychology 13 (2022): 915290.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>