<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41834808</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2590-1095</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Archives of rehabilitation research and clinical translation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arch Rehabil Res Clin Transl</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Safety and Benefits of Moderate to High Intensity Aerobic Exercise During the Subacute Phase of Stroke: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100551</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100551</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100551</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.arrct.2025.100551</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To determine the safety and efficacy of moderate to high intensity exercise for patients in the subacute phase of stroke recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Embase, PubMed, Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials, CINAHL, ClinicalTrials.gov, Google Scholar, and previous meta-analyses published between January 1994 and October 2024.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY SELECTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Title and abstract screening required consensus by 2 reviewers. A total of 27 randomized controlled trials met inclusion criteria. Studies were included if they enrolled participants &lt;6 months post stroke. Interventions were eligible if they were of moderate or high cardiovascular intensity as defined by the American College of Sports Medicine. Acceptable comparator groups included sham, low intensity interventions, no exercise, relaxation, or cognitive interventions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA EXTRACTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Three reviewers independently extracted data using the COVIDENCE platform, with each article reviewed by at least 2 individuals. Random effect meta-analyses were employed to generate pooled estimates of effects. Primary outcomes included severe cardiac and cerebral adverse events, measures of endurance, and gait speed. Secondary outcomes included death, blood pressure, balance, quality of life, and functional independence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SYNTHESIS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Several measures of endurance and gait speed were significantly improved with moderate to high intensity interventions (change in 6-minute walk test, mean difference (MD): 33.11 m; 95% CI, 23.24-42.98; <i>P&lt;</i>.001, <i>k</i>=15; change in peak work rate, MD: 9.28 watts; 95% CI, 5.20-13.37; <i>P</i>=.002; and change in fastest gait speed, MD: 0.12 m/s; 95% CI: 0.05-0.19; <i>P</i>=.003, <i>k</i>=10). Severe adverse cardiac/cerebral events (SAE), peak volume of oxygen, comfortable gait speed, and secondary outcomes did not significantly differ between groups (SAE incidence rate ratio: 1.45; 95% CI, 0.74-2.82; <i>P</i>=.245, <i>k</i>=11).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Moderate to high intensity exercise should be considered within acute rehabilitation facilities, skilled nursing facilities, and outpatient settings for patients in the subacute phase of post stroke rehabilitation and screened as appropriate. Physician collaboration for patient selection and continued active monitoring for SAEs is recommended.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harmon</LastName><ForeName>Erin Y</ForeName><Initials>EY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Department, James A. Eddy Research Institute, Sunnyview Rehabilitation Hospital, Schenectady, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Melewski</LastName><ForeName>Mel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurological Rehabilitation Institute, Sunnyview Rehabilitation Hospital, Schenectady, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Provost</LastName><ForeName>Dana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurological Rehabilitation Institute, Sunnyview Rehabilitation Hospital, Schenectady, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sonagere</LastName><ForeName>Matthew B</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Medicine &amp; Rehabilitation, Sunnyview Rehabilitation Hospital, Schenectady, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Arch Rehabil Res Clin Transl</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101763542</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2590-1095</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aerobic exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient safety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stroke</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41834808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12988557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arrct.2025.100551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2590-1095(25)00125-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Feigin V.L., Brainin M., Norrving B., et al. World Stroke Organization: Global Stroke Fact Sheet 2025. Int J Stroke. 2025;20:132&#x2013;144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11786524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39635884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornby T.G., Reisman D.S., Ward I.G., et al. Clinical practice guideline to improve locomotor function following chronic stroke, incomplete spinal cord injury, and brain injury. J Neurol Phys Ther. 2020;44:49&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31834165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo L., Meng H., Wang Z., et al. Effect of high-intensity exercise on cardiorespiratory fitness in stroke survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2020;63:59&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31465865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyne P., Miller A., Kubalak O., Mink C., Reisman D.S., Fulk G. Moderate to vigorous intensity locomotor training after stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis of mean effects and response variability. J Neurol Phys Ther. 2024;48:15&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10843766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37678805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baricich A., Borg M.B., Battaglia M., et al. High-intensity exercise training impact on cardiorespiratory fitness, gait ability, and balance in stroke survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Med. 2024;13:5498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11432212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39336984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouwer R., Wondergem R., Otten C., Pisters MF. Effect of aerobic training on vascular and metabolic risk factors for recurrent stroke: a meta-analysis. Disabil Rehabil. 2021;43:2084&#x2013;2091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31794269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stinear C., Ackerley S., Byblow W. Rehabilitation is initiated early after stroke, but most motor rehabilitation trials are not: a systematic review. Stroke. 2013;44:2039&#x2013;2045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23715959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dromerick A.W., Geed S., Barth J., et al. Critical Period After Stroke Study (CPASS): a phase II clinical trial testing an optimal time for motor recovery after stroke in humans. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2021;118</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8488696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34544853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernhardt J., Hayward K.S., Kwakkel G., et al. Agreed definitions and a shared vision for new standards in stroke recovery research: the Stroke Recovery and Rehabilitation Roundtable Taskforce. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2017;31:793&#x2013;799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28934920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joy M.T., Carmichael ST. Encouraging an excitable brain state: mechanisms of brain repair in stroke. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2021;22:38&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10625167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33184469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyne P. University of Cincinnati; Cincinnati: 2017. Aerobic deconditioning after stroke: optimizing outcome measures and interventions [dissertation]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzolini S., Robertson A.D., Oh P., et al. Aerobic training and mobilization early post-stroke: cautions and considerations. Front Neurol. 2019;10:1187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6872678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31803129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Wang J., Meng P., et al. Mid-term blood pressure variability is associated with clinical outcome after ischemic stroke. Am J Hypertens. 2017;30:968&#x2013;977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28633329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda K., Matsuo R., Kamouchi M., et al. Day-by-day blood pressure variability in the subacute stage of ischemic stroke and long-term recurrence. Stroke. 2022;53:70&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34496621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutros C.F., Khazaal W., Taliani M., Said Sadier N., Salameh P., Hosseini H. One-year recurrence of stroke and death in Lebanese survivors of first-ever stroke: time-to-event analysis. Front Neurol. 2022;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9702576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36452174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Xu J., Zhao X., et al. Association of hypertension with stroke recurrence depends on ischemic stroke subtype. Stroke. 2013;44:1232&#x2013;1237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23444308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rackoll T., Nave A.H., Ebinger M., et al. Physical Fitness Training in Patients with Subacute Stroke (PHYS-STROKE): safety analyses of a randomized clinical trial. Int J Stroke. 2022;17:93&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8739607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33724085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edward J.A. Cornwell WK 3rd. Impact of exercise on cerebrovascular physiology and risk of stroke. Stroke. 2022;53:2404&#x2013;2410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9246957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35506387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalo R., Zekja I., Kamberi F. Association of cardiovascular disease risk and health-related behaviors in stroke patients. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20:3693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9963426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36834389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alatawi SF. A comparison of three common rehabilitation interventions used to improve cardiovascular fitness after stroke: an overview of the literature. Biomed Res Int. 2023;2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10113054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37082188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balakatounis K.C., Angoules A.G., Angoules G.A., Panagiotopoulou KA. A review of the effectiveness of aerobic training in increasing endurance in subacute stroke patients. J Nov Physiother. 2017;7:334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billinger S.A., Arena R., Bernhardt J., et al. Physical activity and exercise recommendations for stroke survivors: a statement for healthcare professionals from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Stroke. 2014;45:2532&#x2013;2553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24846875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah S.M., Goodwill A.M., Seow H.C., Teo WP. Evidence of high-intensity exercise on lower limb functional outcomes and safety in acute and subacute stroke population: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;20:153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9819111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36612471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsden D.L., Dunn A., Callister R., Levi C.R., Spratt NJ. Characteristics of exercise training interventions to improve cardiorespiratory fitness after stroke: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2013;27:775&#x2013;788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23884014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang M.Y.C., Eng J.J., Dawson A.S., Gylfad&#xf3;ttir S. The use of aerobic exercise training in improving aerobic capacity in individuals with stroke: a meta-analysis. Clin Rehabil. 2006;20:97&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3167867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16541930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regan E.W., Handlery R., Beets M.W., Fritz SL. Are aerobic programs similar in design to cardiac rehabilitation beneficial for survivors of stroke? A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Heart Assoc. 2019;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6759893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31409176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoller O., de Bruin E.D., Knols R.H., Hunt KJ. Effects of cardiovascular exercise early after stroke: systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Neurol. 2012;12:45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3495034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22727172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C., Redgrave J., Shafizadeh M., Majid A., Kilner K., Ali AN. Aerobic exercise interventions reduce blood pressure in patients after stroke or transient ischaemic attack: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53:1515&#x2013;1525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29743171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penna L.G., Pinheiro J.P., Ramalho S.H., Ribeiro CF. Effects of aerobic physical exercise on neuroplasticity after stroke: systematic review. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2021;79:832&#x2013;843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34669820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saltychev M., Sj&#xf6;gren T., Barlund E., Laimi K., Paltamaa J. Do aerobic exercises really improve aerobic capacity of stroke survivors? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2016;52:233&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25573602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Geng D., Wang S., Sun G. Aerobic exercises and cognitive function in post-stroke patients: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Medicine (Baltimore) 2022;101</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9575743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36253969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayer J.F., Sandberg C.W., Mozeiko J., Madden E.B., Murray LL. Cognitive and linguistic benefits of aerobic exercise: a state-of-the-art systematic review of the stroke literature. Front Rehabil Sci. 2021;2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9397720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36188840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyne P., Welge J., Kissela B., Dunning K. Factors influencing the efficacy of aerobic exercise for improving fitness and walking capacity after stroke: a meta-analysis with meta-regression. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2017;98:581&#x2013;595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5868957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27744025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moncion K., Rodrigues L., Wiley E., et al. Aerobic exercise interventions for promoting cardiovascular health and mobility after stroke: a systematic review with Bayesian network meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2024;58:392&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38413134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mezzani A., Hamm L.F., Jones A.M., et al. Aerobic exercise intensity assessment and prescription in cardiac rehabilitation: a joint position statement of the European Association for Cardiovascular Prevention and Rehabilitation, the American Association of Cardiovascular and Pulmonary Rehabilitation and the Canadian Association of Cardiac Rehabilitation. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2013;20:442&#x2013;467. doi: 10.1177/2047487312460484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2047487312460484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23104970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson P.D., Buchner D., Pina I.L., et al. Exercise and physical activity in the prevention and treatment of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease: a statement from the Council on Clinical Cardiology (Subcommittee on Exercise, Rehabilitation, and Prevention) and the Council on Nutrition, Physical Activity, and Metabolism (Subcommittee on Physical Activity) Circulation. 2003;107:3109&#x2013;3116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12821592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions version 6.4 (updated August 2023). Available at:https://www.cochrane.org/authors/handbooks-and-manuals/handbook/archive/v6.4. Accessed April 22, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klassen T.D., Dukelow S.P., Bayley M.T., et al. Higher doses improve walking recovery during stroke inpatient rehabilitation. Stroke. 2020;51:2639&#x2013;2648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32811378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J.P., Thompson SG. Quantifying heterogeneity in a meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2002;21:1539&#x2013;1558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin H. Conversions between partial eta squared and Cohen&#x2019;s d. Available at: https://haiyangjin.github.io/2020/05/eta2d/. Accessed September 10, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrer M., Cuijpers P., Furukawa T.A., Ebert DD. Chapmann &amp; Hall/CRC Press; Boca Raton, FL and London: 2021. Doing meta-analysis with R: a hands-on guide.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKay-Lyons M., McDonald A., Matheson J., Eskes G., Klus MA. Dual effects of body-weight supported treadmill training on cardiovascular fitness and walking ability early after stroke: a randomized controlled trial. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2013;27:644&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23599221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yagiz G., Akaras E., Kubis H.P., Owen JA. The effects of resistance training on architecture and volume of the upper extremity muscles: a systematic review of randomised controlled trials and meta-analyses. Appl Sci. 2022;12:1593. doi: 10.3390/app12031593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app12031593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askim T., Dahl A.E., Aamot I.L., Hokstad A., Helbostad J., Indredavik B. High-intensity aerobic interval training for patients 3-9 months after stroke: a feasibility study. Physiother Res Int. 2014;19:129&#x2013;139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24375978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallesen H., Bjerk M., Pedersen A.R., Nielsen J.F., Evald L. The effects of high-intensity aerobic exercise on cognitive performance after stroke: a pilot randomised controlled trial. J Cent Nerv Syst Dis. 2019;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6477759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31040737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz-Leurer M., Shochina M., Carmeli E., Friedlander Y. The influence of early aerobic training on the functional capacity in patients with cerebrovascular accident at the subacute stage. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2003;84:1609&#x2013;1614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14639559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;nemann H., Bro&#x17c;ek J., Guyatt G., Oxman A. GRADE Handbook. 2013 editors.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulk G.D., He Y. Minimal clinically important difference of the 6-minute walk test in people with stroke. J Neurol Phys Ther. 2018;42:235&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30138230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilson J.K., Sullivan K.J., Cen S.Y., et al. Meaningful gait speed improvement during the first 60 days poststroke: minimal clinically important difference. Phys Ther. 2010;90:196&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2816032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20022995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson TJ. Detecting change in patients with stroke using the Berg Balance Scale. Aust J Physiother. 2001;47:29&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11552860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, et al. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions version 6.5 (updated August 2024). Available at: https://www.cochrane.org/authors/handbooks-and-manuals/handbook/current. Accessed December 1, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M., Hedges L.V., Higgins J.P., Rothstein H.R. A basic introduction to fixed-effect and random-effects models for meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods. 2010;1:97&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26061376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brauer S.G., Kuys S.S., Ada L., Paratz JD. IMproving Physical ACtivity after stroke via Treadmill training (IMPACT) and self-management: a randomized trial. Int J Stroke. 2022;17:1137&#x2013;1144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35102808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuys S.S., Brauer S.G., Ada L. Higher-intensity treadmill walking during rehabilitation after stroke in feasible and not detrimental to walking pattern or quality: a pilot randomized trial. Clin Rehabil. 2011;25:316&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20921032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds H., Steinfort S., Tillyard J., et al. Feasibility and adherence to moderate intensity cardiovascular fitness training following stroke: a pilot randomized controlled trial. BMC Neurol. 2021;21:132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7983371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33745454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanroy C., Feys H., Swinnen A., et al. Effectiveness of active cycling in subacute stroke rehabilitation: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2017;98:1576&#x2013;1585.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28284834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Las Heras B., Rodrigues L., Cristini J., et al. Investigating the acute and chronic effects of cardiovascular exercise on brain-derived neurotrophic factor in early subacute stroke. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2025;39:653&#x2013;665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12318165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40462267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters S., Hung S.H., Bayley M.T., et al. Safety and effectiveness of the Walk &#x2018;n Watch structured, progressive exercise protocol delivered by physical therapists for inpatient stroke rehabilitation in Canada: a phase 3, multisite, pragmatic, stepped-wedge, cluster-randomised controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2025;24:643&#x2013;655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40683274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrholz J., Werner C., Hesse S., Pohl M. Immediate and long-term functional impact of repetitive locomotor training as an adjunct to conventional physiotherapy for non-ambulatory patients after stroke. Disabil Rehabil. 2008;30:830&#x2013;836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17852272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eich H.J., Mach H., Werner C., Hesse S. Aerobic treadmill plus Bobath walking training improves walking in subacute stroke: a randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil. 2004;18:640&#x2013;651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15473116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nave A.H., Rackoll T., Grittner U., et al. Physical Fitness Training in Patients with Subacute Stroke (PHYS-STROKE): multicentre, randomised controlled, endpoint blinded trial. BMJ. 2019;366:l5101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6749174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31533934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ofori E.K., Frimpong E., Ademiluyi A., Olawale OA. Ergometer cycling improves the ambulatory function and cardiovascular fitness of stroke patients-a randomized controlled trial. J Phys Ther Sci. 2019;31:211&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6428648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30936633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toledano-Zarhi A., Tanne D., Carmeli E., Katz-Leurer M. Feasibility, safety and efficacy of an early aerobic rehabilitation program for patients after minor ischemic stroke: a pilot randomized controlled trial. NeuroRehabilitation. 2011;28:85&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21447908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz-Leurer M., Shochina M. The influence of autonomic impairment on aerobic exercise outcome in stroke patients. NeuroRehabilitation. 2007;22:267&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17971616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kono Y., Yamada S., Yamaguchi J., et al. Secondary prevention of new vascular events with lifestyle intervention in patients with noncardioembolic mild ischemic stroke: A single-center randomized controlled trial. Cerebrovasc Dis. 2013;36:88&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24029303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solianik R., Armanavi&#x10d;i&#x16b;t&#x117; J. Effects of aerobic exercise on cognitive function and affected arm function in individuals with ischemic stroke. Reabilitacijos mokslai: slauga, kineziterapija, ergoterapija. 2020;1(22)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outermans J.C., van Peppen R.P., Wittink H., Takken T., Kwakkel G. Effects of a high-intensity task-oriented training on gait performance early after stroke: a pilot study. Clin Rehabil. 2010;24:979&#x2013;987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20719820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askim T., M&#xf8;rkved S., Engen A., Roos K., Aas T., Indredavik B. Effects of a community-based intensive motor training program combined with early supported discharge after treatment in a comprehensive stroke unit: a randomized, controlled trial. Stroke. 2010;41:1697&#x2013;1703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20558830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizvi M.R., Sharma A., Malki A., Sami W. Enhancing cardiovascular health and functional recovery in stroke survivors: a randomized controlled trial of stroke-specific and cardiac rehabilitation protocols for optimized rehabilitation. J Clin Med. 2023;12:6589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10607659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37892727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim C. Multi-sensorimotor training improves proprioception and balance in subacute stroke patients: a randomized controlled pilot trial. Front Neurol. 2019;10:157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6407432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30881333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandberg K., Kleist M., Falk L., Enthoven P. Effects of twice-weekly intense aerobic exercise in early subacute stroke: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2016;97:1244&#x2013;1253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26903147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoller O., de Bruin E.D., Schindelholz M., Schuster-Amft C., de Bie R.A., Hunt KJ. Efficacy of feedback-controlled robotics-assisted treadmill exercise to improve cardiovascular fitness early after stroke: a randomized controlled pilot trial. J Neurol Phys Ther. 2015;39:156&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4484666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26050073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mead G.E., Greig C.A., Cunningham I., et al. Stroke: a randomized trial of exercise or relaxation. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2007;55:892&#x2013;899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17537090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornby T.G., Holleran C.L., Hennessy P.W. Variable Intensive Early Walking Poststroke (VIEWS): a randomized controlled trial. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2016;30:440&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26338433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch S., Tiozzo E., Simonetto M. Randomized trial of combined aerobic, resistance, and cognitive training to improve recovery from stroke: feasibility and safety. J Am Heart Assoc. 2020;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7660866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32394777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klassen T.D., Dukelow S.P., Bayley M.T. Determining optimal poststroke exercise: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial investigating therapeutic intensity and dose on functional recovery during stroke inpatient rehabilitation. Int J Stroke. 2019;14:80&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30010509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijkman M.O., Sandberg K., Kleist M., Falk L., Enthoven P. The exaggerated blood pressure response to exercise in the sub-acute phase after stroke is not affected by aerobic exercise. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2018;20:56&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8031265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29338111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanroy C., Vanlandewijck Y., Cras P. Does a cycling program combined with education and followed by coaching promote physical activity in subacute stroke patients? A randomized controlled trial. Disabil Rehabil. 2019;41:413&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29105516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandberg K., Kleist M., Wijkman M., Enthoven P. Effects of in-bed cycle exercise in patients with acute stroke: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Rehabil Res Clin Transl. 2020;2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7853346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33543108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosoi Y., Kamimoto T., Sakai K., Yamada M., Kawakami M. Estimation of minimal detectable change in the 10-meter walking test for patients with stroke: a study stratified by gait speed. Front Neurol. 2023;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10395330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37538254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin B., Zhang Z., Mei Y. Cumulative risk of stroke recurrence over the last 10 years: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurol Sci. 2021;42:61&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33040195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prosser J., MacGregor L., Lees K.R. Predictors of early cardiac morbidity and mortality after ischemic stroke. Stroke. 2007;38:2295&#x2013;2302. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.106.471813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.106.471813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17569877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozemek C., Bonikowske A.R., Christle J.W., Gallo PM. 12 ed. Wolters Kluwer Health; Philadelphia: 2025. ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai L., Wen Z., Yan X., Wu S., Chen J. Association of physical activity, sedentary behavior and stroke in older adults. Front Public Health. 2024;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11695361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39758197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>