<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41693235</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1611</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Psycho-oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Psychooncology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Impact of Mental Interventions on Psychological Adjustment and Social Recovery in Patients With Oral and Maxillofacial Tumors: A Scoping Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70376</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70376</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/pon.70376</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This scoping review aims to comprehensively evaluate psychological intervention strategies for patients undergoing surgical treatment for oral and maxillofacial tumors. By assessing the effectiveness of existing strategies and the theoretical models or behavior change techniques employed, the study seeks to provide evidence-based recommendations for designing targeted psychological intervention programs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The review adheres to the methodological framework of Arksey and O'Malley and incorporates guidance from the Joanna Briggs Institute (JBI) for scoping reviews. A systematic search was conducted across PubMed, Embase, Web of Science Core Collection, CNKI, Wanfang, VIP, and SinoMed databases for studies published up to November 1, 2024. Two reviewers independently conducted literature screening and data extraction. Findings were integrated through descriptive analysis and social network analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 88 studies published between 2004 and 2024 were included, covering 65 distinct intervention strategies and 37 outcome indicators. The interventions were founded on establishing trust between healthcare providers and patients, with health education as a cornerstone, Key strategies focused on individual psychological adjustment and behavioral change. Commonly reported outcomes included anxiety, depression, patient satisfaction, and quality of life. Social network analysis identified several behavior change strategies with high centrality, such as health education, psychological consolation, encouragement of self-expression and communication, relaxation training, mobilization of family and social support, cognitive-behavioral interventions, peer support, positive incentives, functional rehabilitation training, and meditation. These strategies demonstrated efficacy in alleviating psychological distress, facilitating cognitive restructuring, and improving quality of life and social functioning.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Patients undergoing surgery for oral and maxillofacial tumors face significant psychological and social challenges. The findings underscore the necessity of developing diverse, targeted, evidence-based psychological interventions tailored to the unique needs of this population, leveraging established behavior change techniques to improve postoperative psychological well-being and social recovery.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xin-Yao</ForeName><Initials>XY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, ShangHai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xue</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-7589-9937</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, ShangHai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, ShangHai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Fei</ForeName><Initials>YF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-7305-6054</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, ShangHai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Li-Li</ForeName><Initials>LL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, The Ninth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, ShangHai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Nursing</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000098583">Scoping Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Psychooncology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9214524</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1057-9249</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009062" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mouth Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000066498" MajorTopicYN="Y">Emotional Adjustment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000223" MajorTopicYN="Y">Adaptation, Psychological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012944" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Support</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000083626" MajorTopicYN="Y">Psychosocial Intervention</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral and maxillofacial tumors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychological health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scoping review</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41693235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.70376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Division of Oral and Maxillofacial Oncology,Chinese Society of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery. &#x201c;The Protocol of Treatment Guideline for Oral and Maxillofacial Malignant Neoplasms,&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Practical Stomatology 3, no. 7 (2010): 395&#x2013;403: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1674&#x2010;1595.2010.07.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Y. Zhang, Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery, 8th ed. (People's Medical Publishing House, 2020): [Chinese].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Bray, M. Laversanne, H. Sung, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Global Cancer Statistics 2022: GLOBOCAN Estimates of Incidence and Mortality Worldwide for 36 Cancers in 185 Countries,&#x201d; CA: A Cancer Journal for Clinicians 74, no. 3 (2024): 229&#x2013;263, https://doi.org/10.3322/caac.21834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Zhang, &#x201c;Challenges in the Diagnosis and Treatment of Oral and Maxillofacial Head and Neck Oncology,&#x201d; Journal of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery 30, no. 1 (2020): 1&#x2013;4: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1005&#x2010;4979.2020.01.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. C. C. Network, &#x201c;NCCN Clinical Practice Guidelines in Oncology: Head and Neck Cancers[EB/OL],&#x201d; (November 2024): [2024&#x2010;11&#x2010;27], https://nccn.medlive.cn/guide/detail/749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Yuan, B. Pan, W. Wang, L. Wang, X. Zhang, and Y. Gao, &#x201c;Prevalence and Predictors of Anxiety and Depressive Symptoms Among Patients Diagnosed With Oral Cancer in China: A Cross&#x2010;Sectional Study,&#x201d; BMC Psychiatry 20, no. 1 (2020): 394, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12888&#x2010;020&#x2010;02796&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. J. Mitchell, M. Chan, H. Bhatti, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Prevalence of Depression, Anxiety, and Adjustment Disorder in Oncological, Hematological, and Palliative&#x2010;Care Settings: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis of 94 Interview&#x2010;Based Studies,&#x201d; Lancet Oncology 12, no. 2 (2011): 160&#x2013;174, https://doi.org/10.1016/s1470&#x2010;2045(11)70002&#x2010;x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Mamatha, S. D. Saka, D. Mutthineni, D. N. Bhushanam, P. A. V. Teji, and T. Kala, &#x201c;Psychological Distress and Quality of Life Among Head and Neck Cancer Patients After 3&#x2010; and 6&#x2010;Months Post&#x2010;Treatment&#x2010;A Hospital&#x2010;Based Study,&#x201d; supplement, Journal of Pharmacy and BioAllied Sciences 16, no. S2 (2024): S1700&#x2013;S1704, https://doi.org/10.4103/jpbs.jpbs_1039_23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Wang, S. Qin, X. Li, W. L. Li, and T. Q. Lu, &#x201c;Study of Psychological Distress and Quality of Life in Patients With Oral Cancer,&#x201d; Shang Hai Kou Qiang Yi Xue 27, no. 5 (2018): 486&#x2013;490, https://doi.org/10.19439/j.sjos.2018.05.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. M. Gondivkar, G. S. Sarode, A. Warhekar, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Prevalence and Risk Factors of Suicidal Ideation in Oral Cancer: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; International Journal of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery 54, no. 4 (2024): 301&#x2013;307, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijom.2024.09.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Jiajuan, W. U. Fuli, D. Xiaobo, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effects of Attributional Psychological Adjustment on Postoperative Patients With Oral Cavity Cancer,&#x201d; Nursing Practice and Research 20, no. 23 (2023): 3492&#x2013;3497: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1672&#x2010;9676.2023.23.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. J. Raut, L. Shetty, A. Chhatriwala, T. K. Domah, and G. Camblay, &#x201c;Effect of Meditation and Relaxation Therapy on Preoperative Anxiety and Stress in Oral Squamous Cell Carcinoma Patients Scheduled for Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery: An Experimental Study,&#x201d; National Journal of Maxillofacial Surgery 15, no. 1 (2024): 67&#x2013;74, https://doi.org/10.4103/njms.njms_123_22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Khandpur, K. Kumar, S. Kumar, D. Mehrotra, and P. Mehra, &#x201c;A Single&#x2010;Blinded Assessment of the Effect of Communication on Psychological Burden Among Oral Cancer and Oral Potentially Malignant Disorder Patients,&#x201d; Journal of Oral Biology and Craniofacial Research 12, no. 4 (2022): 427&#x2013;430, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jobcr.2022.05.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Sun, X. Liu, X. Weng, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Narrative Therapy to Relieve Stigma in Oral Cancer Patients: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; International Journal of Nursing Practice 28, no. 4 (2022): e12926, https://doi.org/10.1111/ijn.12926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Arksey and L. O'Malley, &#x201c;Scoping Studies: Towards a Methodological Framework,&#x201d; International Journal of Social Research Methodology 8, no. 1 (2005): 19&#x2013;32, https://doi.org/10.1080/1364557032000119616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. C. Tricco, E. Lillie, W. Zarin, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;PRISMA Extension for Scoping Reviews (PRISMA&#x2010;ScR): Checklist and Explanation,&#x201d; Annals of Internal Medicine 169, no. 7 (2018): 467&#x2013;473, https://doi.org/10.7326/m18&#x2010;0850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Amir&#x2010;Behghadami and A. Janati, &#x201c;Population, Intervention, Comparison, Outcomes and Study (PICOS) Design as a Framework to Formulate Eligibility Criteria in Systematic Reviews,&#x201d; Emergency Medicine Journal: Engineering Management Journal 37, no. 6 (2020): 387, https://doi.org/10.1136/emermed&#x2010;2020&#x2010;209567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Borgatti, M. Everett, L. Freeman, &#x201c;UCINET for Windows: Software for Social Network Analysis,&#x201d; (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. A. Rhoten, B. A. Murphy, M. S. Dietrich, and S. H. Ridner, &#x201c;Depressive Symptoms, Social Anxiety, and Perceived Neck Function in Patients With Head and Neck Cancer,&#x201d; Head &amp; Neck 40, no. 7 (2018): 1443&#x2013;1452, https://doi.org/10.1002/hed.25129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. M. Chen, S. Hsu, C. Felix, J. Garst, and T. Yoshizaki, &#x201c;Effect of Psychosocial Distress on Outcome for Head and Neck Cancer Patients Undergoing Radiation,&#x201d; Laryngoscope 128, no. 3 (2018): 641&#x2013;645, https://doi.org/10.1002/lary.26751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Liu, N. Zhang, and Y. Cui, &#x201c;Research Progress on Psychosocial Factors on the Incidence and Prognosis of Cancer,&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Cancer Prevention and Treatment 27, no. 9 (2020): 750&#x2013;754: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.16073/j.cnki.cjcpt.2020.09.14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Scott, &#x201c;Social Network Analysis: Developments, Advances, and Prospects,&#x201d; Social Network Analysis and Mining 1, no. 1 (2011): 21&#x2013;26, https://doi.org/10.1007/s13278&#x2010;010&#x2010;0012&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Yang, C. Mingou, and C. Fengzhou, &#x201c;Influences of the Cognitive Behavior Therapy on Anxiety for Postoperative Patients With Oral and Maxillofacial Malignant Cancer in Surgery Intensive Care Unit,&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Practical Nursing 33, no. 23 (2017): 1802&#x2013;1805: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3760/cma.j.issn.1672&#x2010;7088.2017.23.012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G.F. Zhu, Effects of Cognitive&#x2010;Behavioral Intervention on the Psychological State of Tongue Cancer Patients Undergoing Free Flap Transplantation (Zhengzhou University school of Nursing, 2015): [Chinese].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Qingli, W. Xiaohui, L. Dandan, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effect of Psychological Intervention Based on Rosenthal Effect on Emotional State and Self&#x2010;Care Ability of Patients With Oral Cancer After Operation,&#x201d; China Journal of Health Psychology 31, no. 8 (2023): 1171&#x2013;1176: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.13342/j.cnki.cjhp.2023.08.011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Li, Z. Shi, and S. Fu, &#x201c;Application of the ABC Theory of Emotion Combined With &#x201c;Sunshine Mindset&#x201d; Intervention in Patients With Oral Cancer After Soft Tissue Defect Repair,&#x201d; International Journal of Nursing 42, no. 22 (2023): [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3760/cma.j.cn221370&#x2010;20221017&#x2010;00983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Y. Zhang, M. T. Xu, and Y. Y. Liu, &#x201c;Effects of Rational Emotive Therapy on Psychological Resilience, Negative Emotions, and Quality of Life in Postoperative Tongue Cancer Patients,&#x201d; International Journal of Nursing 40, no. 20 (2021): [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3760/cma.j.cn221370&#x2010;20190816&#x2010;01045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Liu, X. F. Huang, Y. Z. Xing, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effect of Rational Emotive Therapy on the Psychological Status and Life Quality of Patients With Tongue Carcinoma After Operation,&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Modern Nursing 18, no. 27 (2012): 3259&#x2013;3261: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3760/cma.j.issn.1674&#x2010;2907.2012.27.012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. H. Wang, &#x201c;Effects of Self&#x2010;Efficacy Intervention on Self&#x2010;Esteem and Body Image Disturbance in Oral Cancer Patients Undergoing Radical Surgery,&#x201d; Hebei Medical Journal 37, no. 14 (2015): 2211&#x2013;2213: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1002&#x2010;7386.2015.14.047.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. W. Zhao, &#x201c;Effects of Nursing Intervention Based on Maslow's Hierarchy of Needs Theory on Perioperative Oral Cancer Patients,&#x201d; Electronic Journal of General Stomatology 9, no. 27 (2022): 23&#x2013;25.29: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.19738/j.cnki.psy.2023.04.058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. D. Li, J. J. Jiao, D. D. Lu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Application of Transitional Nursing Based on Meleistransition Theory in Patients After Parotid Gland Tumor Resection,&#x201d; QiLu Journal of Nursing 29, no. 12 (2023): 1&#x2013;4: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1006&#x2010;7256.2023.12.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. F. Zhang and Y. J. Wang, &#x201c;Application Effect of the Health Belief Model in Patients With Mixed Parotid Tumors,&#x201d; Health Vocational Education 40, no. 3 (2022): 151&#x2013;153: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1671&#x2010;1246.2022.3.wszyjy202203063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. H. Lou, Y. B. Zheng, H. L. Liu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effect of Group Psychotherapy Based on Yalong's Interpersonal Dynamics Model on Coping Style, Stress Response and Life Meaning of Patients With Tongue Cancer,&#x201d; International Journal of Psychiatry 49, no. 6 (2022): [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.13479/j.cnki.jip.2022.06.038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. H. Wang, Y. G. Wang, D. D. Lu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effects of Yalom's Interpersonal Group Intervention on Coping Styles and Psychological Status of Oral Cancer Patients,&#x201d; Qilu Journal of Nursing 26, no. 7 (2020): [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1006&#x2010;7256.2020.07.012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Li, X. D. Zheng, J. An, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effect of Yalom Dynamic Group Psychotherapy on Patients Receiving Surgery for Tongue Carcinoma,&#x201d; Journal of Nursing 33, no. 20 (2018): [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3870/j.issn.1001&#x2010;4152.2018.20.091.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Gao, &#x201c;Effects of Empathy Nursing Combined With Health Education on Psychological State, Hope Level, and Quality of Life in Postoperative Oral and Maxillofacial Tumor Patients,&#x201d; Contemporary Nurse: Academic Edition 28, no. 9 (2021): 62&#x2013;64: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.19792/j.cnki.1006&#x2010;6411.2021.26.021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. M. Chen, M. E. Daly, E. Vazquez, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Depression Among Long&#x2010;Term Survivors of Head and Neck Cancer Treated With Radiation Therapy,&#x201d; JAMA Otolaryngology &#x2013; Head &amp; Neck Surgery 139, no. 9 (2013): 885&#x2013;889, https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaoto.2013.4072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. L. Siegel, K. D. Miller, and A. Jemal, &#x201c;Cancer Statistics, 2020,&#x201d; CA: A Cancer Journal for Clinicians 70, no. 1 (2020): 7&#x2013;30, https://doi.org/10.3322/caac.21590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Van der Elst, Y. Bardash, M. Wotman, D. Kraus, and T. Tham, &#x201c;The Prognostic Impact of Depression or Depressive Symptoms on Patients With Head and Neck Cancer: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Head &amp; Neck 43, no. 11 (2021): 3608&#x2013;3617, https://doi.org/10.1002/hed.26868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. K. Sharma, S. Patel, W. Ye, and S. L. Rohde, &#x201c;Association of Social Vulnerability on Survival, Treatment, and Presentation in Oral Cavity Cancer,&#x201d; Head &amp; Neck 45, no. 9 (2023): 2185&#x2013;2197, https://doi.org/10.1002/hed.27447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Liao, W. Hsu, W. Lo, P. W. Cheng, P. W. Shueng, and C. H. Hsieh, &#x201c;Health&#x2010;Related Quality of Life and Utility in Head and Neck Cancer Survivors,&#x201d; BMC Cancer 19, no. 1 (2019): 425, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12885&#x2010;019&#x2010;5614&#x2010;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. M. Guo, W. P. Wang, C. Y. Xu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Analysis of Psychological Distress and Related Factors in Postoperative Patients With Oral and Maxillofacial Malignancies,&#x201d; Journal of Nursing 36, no. 6 (2021): 88&#x2013;90: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3870/j.issn.1001&#x2010;4152.2021.06.088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Ellis, &#x201c;The Revised Abc's of Rational&#x2010;Emotive Therapy (RET),&#x201d; Journal of Rational&#x2010;Emotive and Cognitive&#x2010;Behavior Therapy 9, no. 3 (1991): 139&#x2013;172, https://doi.org/10.1007/bf01061227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Cohen and T. A. Wills, &#x201c;Stress, Social Support, and the Buffering Hypothesis,&#x201d; Psychological Bulletin 98, no. 2 (1985): 310&#x2013;357, https://doi.org/10.1037/0033&#x2010;2909.98.2.310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. F. Berkman and T. Glass, &#x201c;Social Integration, Social Networks, Social Support, and Health,&#x201d; in Social Epidemiology. 2nd (Oxford University Press, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. C. Reyes&#x2010;Gibby, K. O. Anderson, K. W. Merriman, K. H. Todd, S. S. Shete, and E. Y. Hanna, &#x201c;Survival Patterns in Squamous Cell Carcinoma of the Head and Neck: Pain as an Independent Prognostic Factor for Survival,&#x201d; Journal of Pain 15, no. 10 (2014): 1015&#x2013;1022, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpain.2014.07.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Song, A. Wei, H. Xu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;An ACC&#x2013;VTA&#x2013;ACC Positive&#x2010;Feedback Loop Mediates the Persistence of Neuropathic Pain and Emotional Consequences,&#x201d; Nature Neuroscience 27, no. 2 (2024): 272&#x2013;285, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593&#x2010;023&#x2010;01519&#x2010;w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zhu, H. Tang, W. Dong, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Distinct Thalamocortical Circuits Underlie Allodynia Induced by Tissue Injury and by Depression&#x2010;Like States,&#x201d; Nature Neuroscience 24, no. 4 (2021): 542&#x2013;553, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593&#x2010;021&#x2010;00811&#x2010;x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Nollet, W. Wisden, and N. P. Franks, &#x201c;Sleep Deprivation and Stress: A Reciprocal Relationship,&#x201d; Interface Focus 10, no. 3 (2020): 20190092, https://doi.org/10.1098/rsfs.2019.0092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. L. Liu, Y. R. Hou, X. L. Weng, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Study on the Application Effects of the Continued Psychological Care on Postoperative Patients With Oral and Maxillofacial Therioma,&#x201d; Journal of Qiqihar Medical College 41, no. 19 (2020): 2468&#x2013;2470: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3969/j.issn.1002&#x2010;1256.2020.19.035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Zhihong, Z. Chunxiao, T. Fan, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Meta&#x2010;Analysis of the Effect of Mental Health Literacy Intervention in Chinese People,&#x201d; Acta Psychology Sinica 52, no. 4 (2020): 497&#x2013;512: [Chinese], https://doi.org/10.3724/SP.J.1041.2020.00497.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>