<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41673833</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2482</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Life-threatening spinal cord injury and occult intercostal artery rupture following low-energy trauma in a patient with ankylosing spondylitis: a case report.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">200</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12893-026-03594-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Ankylosing spondylitis (AS) significantly increases vulnerability to severe spinal injuries from minor trauma due to rigid "bamboo spine" morphology and secondary osteoporosis. Isolated intercostal artery rupture without rib fractures is extremely rare in general trauma populations. The concurrent occurrence of multilevel spinal fractures with complete spinal cord injury and occult intercostal artery hemorrhage following low-energy blunt trauma in AS patients has rarely been documented, and the underlying pathophysiological mechanisms remain unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE PRESENTATION" NlmCategory="METHODS">A 43-year-old male with previously undiagnosed AS sustained a low-velocity bicycle collision, resulting in cervical and thoracic fracture-dislocation (C6-C7 and T11 bilateral laminae fractures) with complete spinal cord injury (ASIA Grade A, complete paraplegia), massive hemothorax, and active intercostal artery bleeding without significant rib fractures. Due to the patient's hemodynamic instability and altered consciousness on admission (hemorrhagic shock with SBP 63/40 mmHg), formal assessment of the bulbocavernosus reflex was not performed initially. The ASIA Grade A classification was based on complete absence of motor function (lower limbs 0/5) and sensory function below the T3 level, including absence of sacral sparing. Computed tomography angiography revealed active contrast extravasation from the right T10-level intercostal artery. Emergency transcatheter arterial angiography and embolization using coils and gelatin sponge particles successfully controlled the hemorrhage and stabilized the patient's hemodynamics. Following stabilization, staged posterior cervical (C5-C7) and thoracolumbar (T9-T12, L3-S1) pedicle screw-rod internal fixation with anterior cervical discectomy and fusion were performed. Despite postoperative complications including hospital-acquired pneumonia, pulmonary fungal infection (Candida albicans isolated from bronchoalveolar lavage, treated with intravenous fluconazole), and deep vein thrombosis, the patient demonstrated partial neurological recovery, with ASIA grade improving from Grade A (complete paraplegia) on admission to Grade C (incomplete paraplegia) at discharge on day 59. Serial neurological examinations documented the evolution from complete to incomplete injury (Table&#xa0;1). The patient was subsequently transferred to a specialized rehabilitation center for long-term functional training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This case illustrates the heightened and often unrecognized risk of complex, multisystem injuries in AS patients following seemingly minor trauma. Early recognition of hemothorax without rib fractures should raise high suspicion for intercostal artery injury, necessitating a lowered diagnostic threshold for computed tomography angiography. Transcatheter arterial embolization should be considered the first-line treatment for confirmed intercostal artery bleeding rather than a last resort. Prompt diagnosis, individualized multidisciplinary management, and early referral to specialized centers with interventional and spine surgical capabilities are essential for optimizing outcomes in these high-risk patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Zhongshan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Taihe Hospital, Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, 442012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Trauma Surgery, Taihe Hospital, Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, 442012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Xujia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging, Taihe Hospital, Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, 442012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xianyi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Taihe Hospital, Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, Hubei, 442012, China. hbsyyxy@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968567</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2482</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013167" MajorTopicYN="Y">Spondylitis, Ankylosing</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013119" MajorTopicYN="Y">Spinal Cord Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016103" MajorTopicYN="Y">Spinal Fractures</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014949" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wounds, Nonpenetrating</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013904" MajorTopicYN="N">Thoracic Vertebrae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002574" MajorTopicYN="N">Cervical Vertebrae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012421" MajorTopicYN="N">Rupture</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000063" MajorTopicYN="N">Accidents, Traffic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001642" MajorTopicYN="N">Bicycling</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ankylosing spondylitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intercostal artery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Interventional embolization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal cord injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Trauma</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This case report describes clinical care provided to a single patient and does not constitute research requiring formal ethical committee approval according to our institutional guidelines. Patient confidentiality has been maintained throughout, and all identifiable information has been removed. Consent for publication: Written informed consent was obtained from the patient for publication of this case report and any accompanying images. A copy of the written consent is available for review by the Editor of this journal. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41673833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12998082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12893-026-03594-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12893-026-03594-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hong YM, Yoon KT, Cho M. Primary biliary cholangitis with ankylosing spondylitis. Korean J Gastroenterol. 2022;79(6):270&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4166/kjg.2022.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12286314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35746842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pate D, Huslig EL. Atypical presentation of ankylosing spondylitis: a case study. J Manipulative Physiol Ther. 1985;8(2):105&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4009069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DY, Lee SJ, Ryu YJ, et al. Progressive pulmonary fibrocystic changes of both upper lungs in a patient with ankylosing spondylitis. Tuberc Respir Dis (Seoul). 2015;78(4):459&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4046/trd.2015.78.4.459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4620352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26508946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ognjenovic M, Raymond WD, Inderjeeth CA, et al. The risk and consequences of vertebral fracture in patients with ankylosing spondylitis: A Population-based data linkage study. J Rheumatol. 2020;47(11):1629&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3899/jrheum.190675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32062601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altenbernd J, Bitu S, Lemburg S, et al. Vertebral fractures in patients with ankylosing spondylitis: a retrospective analysis of 66 patients. Rofo. 2009;181(1):45&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2008-1027886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19085689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harlianto NI, Ezzafzafi S, Foppen W, et al. The prevalence of vertebral fractures in diffuse idiopathic skeletal hyperostosis and ankylosing spondylitis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. N Am Spine Soc J. 2024;17:100312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10869944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38370336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nemoto C, Ikegami Y, Suzuki T, et al. Repeated embolization of intercostal arteries after blunt chest injury. Gen Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2014;62(11):696&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11748-013-0269-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23728534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miettinen S, Hakala T. Traumatic intercostal arterial bleeding controlled with a novel surgical technique: a case report. J Med Case Rep. 2012;6:318. 10.1186/1752-1947-6-318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3469334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23009261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles YP, Buy X, Gangi A, et al. Fracture in ankylosing spondylitis after minor trauma: radiological pitfalls and treatment by percutaneous instrumentation. A case report. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2013;99(1):115&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.otsr.2012.09.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23270725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen DY, He ZM, Chen HJ, et al. Clinical characteristics and results of cervical spinal cord injury in the patients with ossification of the posterior longitudinal ligament. Zhonghua Wai Ke Za Zhi. 2007;45(6):370&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17537318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurik AG. Imaging the spine in arthritis-a pictorial review. Insights Imaging. 2011;2(2):177&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13244-010-0061-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3259357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22347946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam MS, Hasan MZ, Choudhury AAM, et al. A comprehensive analysis of surgical outcomes for spinal fractures in patients with ankylosing spondylitis: A 13-Year prospective study. Cureus. 2024;16(12):e76036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11744014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39835016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montala N, Juanola X, Collantes E, et al. Prevalence of vertebral fractures by semiautomated morphometry in patients with ankylosing spondylitis. J Rheumatol. 2011;38(5):893&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3899/jrheum.100851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21362760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang KH, Seok SY, Cho JH. Concurrently occurring spinal cord Cross-Section and aortic injury after a Chalk-Stick fracture and dislocation in patient with ankylosing spondylitis: clinical image. World Neurosurg. 2024;184:149&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wneu.2024.01.097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38278209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lifshutz J, Lidar Z, Maiman D. Thoracic aortic pseudoaneurysm after spine trauma in ankylosing spondylitis. Case report. J Neurosurg Spine. 2005;2(2):218&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/spi.2005.2.2.0218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15739538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei J, Xu S, Zhang M, et al. Arterial interventional embolization in the treatment of multiple injury complicated with rupture of intercostal artery and lumbar artery: a case report. Chin J Emerg Med. 2024;33(7):1039&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buleu F, Sirbu E, Caraba A et al. Heart involvement in inflammatory rheumatic diseases: A systematic literature review. Medicina (Kaunas). 2019;55(6)249. 10.3390/medicina55060249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6632037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31174287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartoloni E, Alunno A, Valentini V, et al. Targeting inflammation to prevent cardiovascular disease in chronic rheumatic diseases: myth or reality? Front Cardiovasc Med. 2018;5:177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2018.00177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6297850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30619884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Song Y, Dai S, et al. An applied anatomy study on bronchial artery and posterior intercostal artery. Sichuan Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban. 2003;34(4):711&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14619589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamdi M, Spano A, Landuyt KV, et al. The lateral intercostal artery perforators: anatomical study and clinical application in breast surgery. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2008;121(2):389&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.prs.0000298317.65296.cf</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18300954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miura H, Taira O, Hiraguri S, et al. Blunt thoracic injury. Jpn J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 1998;46(6):556&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF03250599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9720378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyahara S, Iwasaki A. Diagnosis and treatment of hemothorax. Kyobu Geka. 2015;68(8):650&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26197910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara A, Yanagawa Y, Kaneko N, et al. Indications for transcatheter arterial embolization in persistent hemothorax caused by blunt trauma. J Trauma. 2008;65(3):589&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18784572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed RM, Ali WA, AbdelHakam AM, et al. Detection of hepatocellular carcinoma feeding vessels: MDCT angiography with 3D reconstruction versus digital Subtraction angiography. BMC Med Imaging. 2024;24(1):250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12880-024-01408-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11412056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39294600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>