<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41775671</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1757-7861</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Orthopaedic surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Orthop Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Advances in Gait Alterations and Rehabilitation After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction: Biomechanics and Emerging Technologies.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/os.70261</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injuries are prevalent in sports and daily life, often leading to functional instability and long-term complications such as osteoarthritis. This literature review synthesizes advancements in postoperative gait analysis following ACL reconstruction (ACLR), focusing on biomechanical alterations, rehabilitation outcomes, and emerging technologies. Current methodologies, including three-dimensional motion capture, force plate kinetics, surface electromyography (sEMG), wearable sensors, machine learning and artificial intelligence, reveal persistent kinematic asymmetries, and altered joint loading patterns in ACLR patients. Rehabilitation interventions, such as neuromuscular training, biofeedback, and AI-assisted systems, show promise in restoring dynamic stability but require standardization and cost optimization. Limitations of existing studies include small sample sizes, short follow-up periods, and methodological inconsistencies. Future research should prioritize multicenter longitudinal studies, multimodal data integration, and AI-driven precision rehabilitation to optimize recovery and mitigate long-term risks. This study aims to elucidate the role of gait analysis in optimizing rehabilitation protocols and mitigating long-term complications by evaluating the strengths and limitations of existing approaches.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Orthopaedic Surgery published by Tianjin Hospital and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>TszLeung</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-8744-0675</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine Center, The First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>HengYu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine Center, The First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huo</LastName><ForeName>ZhenQiang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine Center, The First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>ZhiYu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine Center, The First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>JieRuo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine Center, The First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>XinYu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6337-8009</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of Fujian Medical University, Fuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, National Regional Medical Center, Binhai Campus of the First Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical University, Fuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fujian Provincial Institute of Orthopedics, The First Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical University, Fuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>82571554</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Orthop Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101501666</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1757-7853</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament injuries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomechanics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gait analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kinematic asymmetries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41775671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/os.70261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>L. Kohn, E. Rembeck, and A. Rauch, &#x201c;Verletzung des Vorderen Kreuzbandes Beim Erwachsenen: Diagnostik und Therapie,&#x201d; Orthopade 49, no. 11 (2020): 1013&#x2013;1028, https://doi.org/10.1007/s00132&#x2010;020&#x2010;03997&#x2010;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Maniar, E. Verhagen, A. L. Bryant, and D. A. Opar, &#x201c;Trends in Australian Knee Injury Rates: An Epidemiological Analysis of 228,344 Knee Injuries Over 20&#x2009;Years,&#x201d; Lancet Regional Health&#x2014;Western Pacific 21 (2022): 100409, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lanwpc.2022.100409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. C. Kaeding, B. L&#xe9;ger&#x2010;St&#x2010;Jean, and R. A. Magnussen, &#x201c;Epidemiology and Diagnosis of Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injuries,&#x201d; Clinics in Sports Medicine 36, no. 1 (2017): 1&#x2013;8, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.csm.2016.08.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. P. Boden and F. T. Sheehan, &#x201c;Mechanism of Non&#x2010;Contact ACL Injury: OREF Clinical Research Award 2021,&#x201d; Journal of Orthopaedic Research 40, no. 3 (2022): 531&#x2013;540, https://doi.org/10.1002/jor.25257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. H. Brophy, C. S. Gill, S. Lyman, R. P. Barnes, S. A. Rodeo, and R. F. Warren, &#x201c;Effect of Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction and Meniscectomy on Length of Career in National Football League Athletes: A Case Control Study,&#x201d; American Journal of Sports Medicine 37, no. 11 (2009): 2102&#x2013;2107, https://doi.org/10.1177/0363546509349035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. P. Boden, G. S. Dean, J. A. Feagin, and W. E. Garrett, &#x201c;Mechanisms of Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injury,&#x201d; Orthopedics 23, no. 6 (2000): 573&#x2013;578, https://doi.org/10.3928/0147&#x2010;7447&#x2010;20000601&#x2010;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Jarchi, J. Pope, T. K. M. Lee, L. Tamjidi, A. Mirzaei, and S. Sanei, &#x201c;A Review on Accelerometry&#x2010;Based Gait Analysis and Emerging Clinical Applications,&#x201d; IEEE Reviews in Biomedical Engineering 11 (2018): 177&#x2013;194, https://doi.org/10.1109/RBME.2018.2807182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Islam, M. Bennasar, K. Nicholas, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Nonproprietary Movement Analysis System (MoJoXlab) Based on Wearable Inertial Measurement Units Applicable to Healthy Participants and Those With Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction Across a Range of Complex Tasks: Validation Study,&#x201d; JMIR mHealth and uHealth 8, no. 6 (2020): e17872, https://doi.org/10.2196/17872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. B&#xfc;ttner, C. Lisee, E. Bjornsen, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Bilateral Waveform Analysis of Gait Biomechanics Presurgery to 12 Months Following ACL Reconstruction Compared to Controls,&#x201d; Journal of Orthopaedic Research 43, no. 2 (2025): 322&#x2013;336, https://doi.org/10.1002/jor.26001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Li, H. Huang, S. Zhang, S. Ren, and Q. Rong, &#x201c;Muscle Dynamics Analysis by Clustered Categories During Jogging in Patients With Anterior Cruciate Ligament Deficiency,&#x201d; BMC Musculoskeletal Disorders 24, no. 1 (2023): 919, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12891&#x2010;023&#x2010;07000&#x2010;w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Skvortsov, A. Altukhova, S. Kaurkin, and A. Akhpashev, &#x201c;Long&#x2010;Term Outcomes of Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction Based on Gait Analysis,&#x201d; Diagnostics (Basel, Switzerland) 14, no. 17 (2024): 1977, https://doi.org/10.3390/diagnostics14171977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Gao, H. Huang, Y. Yu, H. Liu, and Y. Ao, &#x201c;Effect of Knee Extension Constraint Training on Walking Biomechanics 6 Months After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction: A Double&#x2010;Blind Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial,&#x201d; Journal of Orthopaedic Surgery and Research 20, no. 1 (2025): 20, https://doi.org/10.1186/s13018&#x2010;024&#x2010;05447&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wu, H. Zhang, H. Cui, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Surface Electromyography and Gait Features in Patients After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction,&#x201d; Orthopaedic Surgery 17, no. 1 (2025): 62&#x2013;70, https://doi.org/10.1111/os.14256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Kokkotis, S. Moustakidis, T. Tsatalas, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Leveraging Explainable Machine Learning to Identify Gait Biomechanical Parameters Associated With Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injury,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 12, no. 1 (2022): 6647, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;022&#x2010;10666&#x2010;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Tedesco, C. Crowe, A. Ryan, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Motion Sensors&#x2010;Based Machine Learning Approach for the Identification of Anterior Cruciate Ligament Gait Patterns in On&#x2010;The&#x2010;Field Activities in Rugby Players,&#x201d; Sensors (Basel, Switzerland) 20, no. 11 (2020): 3029, https://doi.org/10.3390/s20113029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Kong, T. Yang, Q. Wang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;ACLD Patients Exhibit Additional Knee Kinematic Asymmetries at the Speed Level of Healthy Subjects,&#x201d; Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology 10 (2022): 930722, https://doi.org/10.3389/fbioe.2022.930722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Scataglini, E. Abts, C. Van Bocxlaer, M. den Van Bussche, S. Meletani, and S. Truijen, &#x201c;Accuracy, Validity, and Reliability of Markerless Camera&#x2010;Based 3D Motion Capture Systems Versus Marker&#x2010;Based 3D Motion Capture Systems in Gait Analysis: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Sensors (Basel, Switzerland) 24, no. 11 (2024): 3686, https://doi.org/10.3390/s24113686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Van Melick, R. E. H. Cingel, F. Brooijmans, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Evidence&#x2010;Based Clinical Practice Update: Practice Guidelines for Anterior Cruciate Ligament Rehabilitation Based on a Systematic Review and Multidisciplinary Consensus,&#x201d; British Journal of Sports Medicine 50, no. 24 (2016): 1506&#x2013;1515, https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2015&#x2010;095898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Neal, J. R. Williams, A. Alfayyadh, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Knee Joint Biomechanics During Gait Improve From 3 to 6 Months After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction,&#x201d; Journal of Orthopaedic Research 40, no. 9 (2022): 2025&#x2013;2038, https://doi.org/10.1002/jor.25250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Erhart&#x2010;Hledik, C. R. Chu, J. L. Asay, and T. P. Andriacchi, &#x201c;Longitudinal Changes in Knee Gait Mechanics Between 2 and 8&#x2009;Years After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction,&#x201d; Journal of Orthopaedic Research 36, no. 5 (2018): 1478&#x2013;1486, https://doi.org/10.1002/jor.23770.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Tan, A. A. Gatti, B. Fan, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Scoping Review of Portable Sensing for Out&#x2010;Of&#x2010;Lab Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injury Prevention and Rehabilitation,&#x201d; npj Digital Medicine 6, no. 1 (2023): 46, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41746&#x2010;023&#x2010;00782&#x2010;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. S. R. Jones, V. H. Stiles, J. Verheul, and I. S. Moore, &#x201c;Angular Velocities and Linear Accelerations Derived From Inertial Measurement Units Can Be Used as Proxy Measures of Knee Variables Associated With ACL Injury,&#x201d; Sensors (Basel) 22, no. 23 (2022): 9286, https://doi.org/10.3390/s22239286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. J. Capin, A. Khandha, R. Zarzycki, K. Manal, T. S. Buchanan, and L. Snyder&#x2010;Mackler, &#x201c;Gait Mechanics and Second ACL Rupture: Implications for Delaying Return&#x2010;To&#x2010;Sport: Gait Biomechanics and ACL Re&#x2010;Injury,&#x201d; Journal of Orthopaedic Research 35, no. 9 (2017): 1894&#x2013;1901, https://doi.org/10.1002/jor.23476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Lai, X. Chen, W. Huang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Whether Patients With Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction Walking at a Fast Speed Show More Kinematic Asymmetries?,&#x201d; Orthopaedic Surgery 16, no. 4 (2024): 864&#x2013;872, https://doi.org/10.1111/os.14017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. A. Knurr, S. A. Kliethermes, M. R. Stiffler&#x2010;Joachim, D. G. Cobian, G. S. Baer, and B. C. Heiderscheit, &#x201c;Running Biomechanics Before Injury and 1 Year After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction in Division I Collegiate Athletes,&#x201d; American Journal of Sports Medicine 49, no. 10 (2021): 2607&#x2013;2614, https://doi.org/10.1177/03635465211026665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Krishnakumar, B. J. F. Van Beijnum, C. T. M. Baten, P. H. Veltink, and J. H. Buurke, &#x201c;Estimation of Kinetics Using IMUs to Monitor and Aid in Clinical Decision&#x2010;Making During ACL Rehabilitation: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Sensors (Basel) 24, no. 7 (2024): 2163, https://doi.org/10.3390/s24072163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Saueressig, T. Braun, N. Steglich, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Primary Surgery Versus Primary Rehabilitation for Treating Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injuries: A Living Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; British Journal of Sports Medicine 56, no. 21 (2022): 1241&#x2013;1251, https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2021&#x2010;105359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Pairot&#x2010;de&#x2010;Fontenay, R. W. Willy, A. R. C. Elias, R. L. Mizner, M.&#x2010;O. Dub&#xe9;, and J.&#x2010;S. Roy, &#x201c;Running Biomechanics in Individuals With Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 49, no. 9 (2019): 1411&#x2013;1424, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;019&#x2010;01120&#x2010;x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Kotsifaki, V. Korakakis, E. King, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Aspetar Clinical Practice Guideline on Rehabilitation After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction,&#x201d; British Journal of Sports Medicine 57, no. 9 (2023): 500&#x2013;514, https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2022&#x2010;106158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. G. Culvenor, M. A. Girdwood, C. B. Juhl, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Rehabilitation After Anterior Cruciate Ligament and Meniscal Injuries: A Best&#x2010;Evidence Synthesis of Systematic Reviews for the OPTIKNEE Consensus,&#x201d; British Journal of Sports Medicine 56, no. 24 (2022): 1445&#x2013;1453, https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2022&#x2010;105495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Gokeler, A. Benjaminse, C. F. van Eck, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Return of Normal Gait as an Outcome Measurement in Acl Reconstructed Patients. A Systematic Review,&#x201d; International Journal of Sports Physical Therapy 8, no. 4 (2013): 441&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Liu, S. Li, J. Li, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Effects of Contralateral Limb Cross&#x2010;Education Training on Post&#x2010;Surgical Rehabilitation Outcomes in Patients With Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Journal of Orthopaedic Surgery and Research 20, no. 1 (2025): 118, https://doi.org/10.1186/s13018&#x2010;024&#x2010;05430&#x2010;3.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>