<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41845487</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1757-6512</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Stem cell research &amp; therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Stem Cell Res Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tanshinone IIA-pretreated mesenchymal stem cells alleviate neuroinflammation in 3&#xd7;Tg-AD mice via the TREM2/PI3K/Akt pathway.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13287-026-04954-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Neuroinflammation is a key pathogenic factor for neurodegenerative diseases. Mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) transplantation, as a potential strategy for regulating neuroinflammation, has received extensive attention. Our previous research revealed that compared with ordinary MSC, MSC pretreated with tanshinone IIA (TIIA), referred to as TIIA-MSC, exhibited superior anti-neuroinflammatory activity, but the mechanism of action remains unclear. To clarify the underlying mechanism, this study integrated in vitro and in vivo experiments and evaluated the therapeutic effect of TIIA-MSC in a triple-transgenic Alzheimer's disease mouse model (3&#xd7;Tg-AD mice) and explored its mechanism of action in a lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced BV2 microglial cell inflammation model. The results showed that TIIA-MSC could significantly improve the cognitive function of 3&#xd7;Tg-AD mice, increase brain glucose metabolism levels, promote the recovery of synaptic and mitochondrial structures, and effectively alleviate neuroinflammatory responses. In vitro experiments further verified the superior inhibitory effect of TIIA-MSC on microglial cell activation and proinflammatory factor release. Mechanistic studies have indicated that the triggering receptor expressed on myeloid cells 2 (TREM2) is the key molecule that mediates this process. The knockdown of TREM2 expression significantly weakened the anti-inflammatory effect of TIIA-MSC, suggesting that TREM2 plays a central role in this process. Further analysis revealed that by activating the phosphoinositide 3-kinase (PI3K)/protein kinase B (Akt) signaling pathway downstream of TREM2, TIIA-MSC may promote the transformation of the functional state of microglia from mainly proinflammatory to having neuroprotective and repair properties. This study systematically revealed the molecular mechanism by which TIIA-MSC regulate microglial cell phenotypic transformation through the TREM2/PI3K/Akt pathway and exert anti-neuroinflammatory effects, providing new ideas and an experimental basis for expanding the application of MSC in the treatment of neurodegenerative diseases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Jingjing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Third Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical University, (The First People's Hospital of Zunyi), Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ge</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Third Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical University, (The First People's Hospital of Zunyi), Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Third Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical University, (The First People's Hospital of Zunyi), Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Basic Pharmacology and Joint International Research Laboratory of Ethnomedicine of Ministry of Education, Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Nanqu</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Drug Clinical Trial Institution, Third Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical University, The First People's Hospital of Zunyi), Zunyi, Guizhou, China. hnq@zmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Third Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical University, (The First People's Hospital of Zunyi), Zunyi, Guizhou, China. luoyong@zmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>ZK [2024]-680</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Department of Guizhou Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ZK [2021]-570</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Department of Guizhou Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82160858</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>HZ-2022-45, [2024] No. 6, HZ-2025-06</GrantID><Agency>Zunyi Science and Technology Bureau</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ZSYS(2025)040</GrantID><Agency>Guizhou Provincial Science and Technology Department</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Stem Cell Res Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101527581</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1757-6512</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mesenchymal stem cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microglia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroinflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tanshinone IIA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Triggering receptor expressed on myeloid cells 2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The animal experiments were conducted in line with the ARRIVE guidelines 2.0. The study protocol titled &#x201c;Mechanistic Study of Tanshinone IIA-Conditioned Mesenchymal Stem Cells Regulating TREM2/DAP12 Signaling Pathway in the Treatment of Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease Neuroinflammation&#x201d; (Approval No. (2019)2-231, 11 Mar 2019) was reviewed and approved by the Ethical Committee for Animal Experiments of Zunyi Medical University. All animal experiments were performed under ethical supervision. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41845487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13287-026-04954-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13287-026-04954-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Huang N, et al. Biomaterials in Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease: An Anti-Neuroinflammatory Perspective. Adv Healthc Mater. 2025;14(19):e2500498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman O et al. Neuroinflammation and Disease: Pathways and Opportunities. Annu Rev Pharmacol Toxicol; 2025.18;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, et al. TDP-43 in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: pathophysiology and therapeutic strategies. Pharmacol Res. 2025;1 107977</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruk-S&#x142;omka M, et al. New Approaches to the Treatment of Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease. Pharmaceuticals (Basel). 2025;18:8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang N, et al. Tanshinone &#x399;&#x399;A-Incubated Mesenchymal Stem Cells Inhibit Lipopolysaccharide-Induced Inflammation of N9 Cells through TREM2 Signaling Pathway. Stem Cells Int. 2022;2:9977610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge Y, et al. A New Strategy for the Regulation of Neuroinflammation: Exosomes Derived from Mesenchymal Stem Cells. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2024;44(1):24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, et al. Exosomes derived from bone-marrow mesenchymal stem cells alleviate cognitive decline in AD-like mice by improving BDNF-related neuropathology. J Neuroinflammation. 2022;19(1):35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen C, et al. The Secretion from Bone Marrow Mesenchymal Stem Cells Pretreated with Berberine Rescues Neurons with Oxidative Damage Through Activation of the Keap1-Nrf2-HO-1 Signaling Pathway. Neurotox Res. 2020;38(1):59&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrzejewska A, et al. Mesenchymal Stem Cells for Neurological Disorders. Adv Sci (Weinh). 2021;8(7):2002944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi M, Chu F, Zhu J. Stem cells therapy in neurodegenerative and neuroimmune diseases: Current status of treatments and future prospects. Pharmacol Res. 2025;221:107960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isik S, et al. Advances in Neurodegenerative Disease Therapy: Stem Cell Clinical Trials and Promise of Engineered Exosomes. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2025;31(9):e70577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, et al. Hypoxic preconditioning improves the survival and neural effects of transplanted mesenchymal stem cells via CXCL12/CXCR4 signalling in a rat model of cerebral infarction. Cell Biochem Funct. 2019;37(7):504&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, et al. Isoflurane Preconditioning Promotes the Survival and Migration of Bone Marrow Stromal Cells. Cell Physiol Biochem. 2015;36(4):1331&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, et al. Targeted homing of CCR2-overexpressing mesenchymal stromal cells to ischemic brain enhances post-stroke recovery partially through PRDX4-mediated blood-brain barrier preservation. Theranostics. 2018;8(21):5929&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zong X, et al. Transplantation of VEGF-mediated bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells promotes functional improvement in a rat acute cerebral infarction model. Brain Res. 2017;1676:9&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morimoto J, et al. Electrical Stimulation Enhances Migratory Ability of Transplanted Bone Marrow Stromal Cells in a Rodent Ischemic Stroke Model. Cell Physiol Biochem. 2018;46(1):57&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim R, et al. Multiple Combination of Angelica gigas Extract and Mesenchymal Stem Cells Enhances Therapeutic Effect. Biol Pharm Bull. 2018;41(12):1748&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng X, et al. Astilbin improves the therapeutic effects of mesenchymal stem cells in AKI-CKD mice by regulating macrophage polarization through PTGS2-mediated pathway. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2024;15(1):427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan F, et al. Enhanced therapeutic effects of hypoxia-preconditioned mesenchymal stromal cell-derived extracellular vesicles in renal ischemic injury. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2025;16(1):39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, et al. Preconditioning of bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stromal cells by tetramethylpyrazine enhances cell migration and improves functional recovery after focal cerebral ischemia in rats. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2017;8(1):112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, et al. Natural bioactive compounds modified with mesenchymal stem cells: new hope for regenerative medicine. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2025;13:1446537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong C, et al. Recent Research Progress (2015&#x2013;2021) and Perspectives on the Pharmacological Effects and Mechanisms of Tanshinone IIA. Front Pharmacol. 2021;12:778847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F, et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials on the efficacy and safety of tanshinone IIA sodium sulfonate injection as adjunctive therapy for stroke. J Ethnopharmacol. 2025;353Pt B:p120413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong D, et al. Efficacy of tanshinone IIA and mesenchymal stem cell treatment of learning and memory impairment in a rat model of vascular dementia. J Tradit Chin Med. 2021;41(1):133&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang N, et al. Neuroprotective effect of tanshinone IIA-incubated mesenchymal stem cells on A&#x3b2;25-35-induced neuroinflammation. Behav Brain Res. 2019;365:48&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba Z, et al. Mesenchymal stem cells after the proprocessing of tanshinone IIA attenuate cognitive deficits and oxidative stress injury in an amyloid &#x3b2;-peptide (25&#x2013;35)-induced rodent model of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. NeuroReport. 2022;33(2):61&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, et al. Neuroprotective effect of tanshinone IIA-modified mesenchymal stem cells in a lipopolysaccharide-induced neuroinflammation model. Heliyon. 2024;10(8):e29424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Othman MZ, Hassan Z, Che AT, Has. Morris water maze: a versatile and pertinent tool for assessing spatial learning and memory. Exp Anim. 2022;71(3):264&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan F, et al. Icariin ameliorates memory deficits through regulating brain insulin signaling and glucose transporters in 3&#xd7;Tg-AD mice. Neural Regen Res. 2023;18(1):183&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashleigh T, Swerdlow RH, Beal MF. The role of mitochondrial dysfunction in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease pathogenesis. Alzheimers Dement. 2023;19(1):333&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M, et al. AMPK: A bridge between diabetes mellitus and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Behav Brain Res. 2021;400:113043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, et al. Dendrobium nobile Lindl. alkaloid decreases Tau hyperphosphorylation via regulating PI3K/Akt/GSK-3&#x3b2; pathway in vitro and in vivo. J Ethnopharmacol. 2024;322:117592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, et al. Natural bioactive compounds in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: From the perspective of type 3 diabetes mellitus. Front Aging Neurosci. 2023;15:1130253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, et al. Depletion of the triggering receptor expressed on myeloid cells 2 inhibits progression of renal cell carcinoma via regulating related protein expression and PTEN-PI3K/Akt pathway. Int J Oncol. 2016;49(6):2498&#x2013;506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H, Mu S, Qin W. Microglia TREM2 is required for electroacupuncture to attenuate neuroinflammation in focal cerebral ischemia/reperfusion rats. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2018;503(4):3225&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Q, et al. TREM2- and DAP12-dependent activation of PI3K requires DAP10 and is inhibited by SHIP1. Sci Signal. 2010;3(122):ra38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun M, et al. TREM-2 promotes host resistance against Pseudomonas aeruginosa infection by suppressing corneal inflammation via a PI3K/Akt signaling pathway. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2013;54(5):3451&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JG, et al. Protective effect of Tanshinone IIA against infarct size and increased HMGB1, NF&#x3ba;B, GFAP and apoptosis consequent to transient middle cerebral artery occlusion. Neurochem Res. 2014;39(2):295&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maione F, et al. Down regulation of pro-inflammatory pathways by tanshinone IIA and cryptotanshinone in a non-genetic mouse model of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Pharmacol Res. 2018;129:482&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang N, et al. Possible opportunities and challenges for traditional Chinese medicine research in 2035. Front Pharmacol. 2024;15:1426300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W, et al. The role of TREM2 in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: from the perspective of Tau. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2023;11:1280257.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>