<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41794784</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2731-4391</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of activity, sedentary and sleep behaviors</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Act Sedentary Sleep Behav</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Moving beyond cancer: longitudinal changes in 24-hour movement behaviors and their association with quality of life in breast cancer survivors.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s44167-026-00098-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Many breast cancer survivors experience persistent symptoms after treatment, impairing quality of life (QoL). At the same time, maintaining healthy levels of 24-hour movement behaviors (24h-MBs) i.e. engaging in 150 min of moderate-to-vigorous physical activity (PA) a week, several hours of light PA a day, limiting sedentary behavior during the day, and achieving restorative sleep, remains challenging. While these behaviors influence QoL individually, little is known about the combined impact of 24h-MBs in breast cancer survivorship. Therefore, this study aimed to 1) examine longitudinal changes in 24h-MBs across 1 week, 4 months, and 12 months post-surgery, 2) compare 24h-MBs of breast cancer survivors at 12-month post-surgery with healthy controls and 3) investigate associations between 24h-MBs and QoL in breast cancer survivors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The 24h-MBs were measured by a hip-worn Actigraph GT3X-BT&#x2009;+&#x2009;, and QoL by the McGill QoL questionnaire at 1 week, 4 months, and 12 months post-surgery. Compositional data analysis was used to account for the time-use interdependence of 24h-MBs. Multivariate linear mixed models assessed longitudinal changes in 24h-MBs, a MANOVA explored the group differences and regressions models examined associations between 24h-MBs and QoL at each timepoint.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Results from 184 breast cancer survivors (54&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;15 y/o) showed that sedentary behavior decreased while light and moderate-to-vigorous PA increased over 12 months (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Compared to 135 healthy women (44&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;10 y/o), breast cancer survivors at 12 months post-surgery showed 24h-MBs with more sleep (&gt;&#x2009;9h/night) and less low and moderate-to-vigorous PA (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). At 4 months post-surgery, light PA (relatively against the other behaviors) was associated with a better overall QoL, whereas longer sleep duration (relatively against the other behaviors) was associated with a worse overall QoL and less perceived support. No significant associations were found at 1 week and 12 months post-surgery. However, at all three timepoints, the most commonly self-reported impairing symptoms related to their QoL were fatigue, insomnia and pain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Breast cancer survivors gradually improved their 24h-MBs in the first year after surgery, but their 24h-MB profiles remained less favorable than those of healthy controls. More optimal post-surgery 24h-MBs were associated with a better QoL, emphasizing their relevance for recovery.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Willems</LastName><ForeName>Iris</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MOVEUP24, Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Craemer</LastName><ForeName>Marieke</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MOVEUP24, Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium. Marieke.decraemer@ugent.be.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dams</LastName><ForeName>Lore</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MOVANT, Department of Rehabilitation Sciences and Physiotherapy, University of Antwerp, Antwerpen, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van der Gucht</LastName><ForeName>Elien</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miatke</LastName><ForeName>Aaron</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Alliance for Research in Exercise, Nutrition and Activity, University of South Australia, Adelaide, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meeus</LastName><ForeName>Mira</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MOVANT, Department of Rehabilitation Sciences and Physiotherapy, University of Antwerp, Antwerpen, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Devoogdt</LastName><ForeName>Nele</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Lymphedema, University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Groef</LastName><ForeName>An</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MOVANT, Department of Rehabilitation Sciences and Physiotherapy, University of Antwerp, Antwerpen, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Act Sedentary Sleep Behav</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918664288206676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2731-4391</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">24-h movement behaviors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast cancer survivors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer-related symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sedentary behavior</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was approved by the Ethical Committee of the University Hospitals Leuven (s60702), Ethics Committee of Ghent University Hospital (ONZ-2022_0013) and registered at ClinicalTrails.gov (NCT03351075). Informed consent was provided, explained and signed by all participants prior to the start of the study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41794784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s44167-026-00098-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s44167-026-00098-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Registery BC. Cancer Fact Sheets 2023 [Available from: https://kankerregister.org/en/publicaties/cancer-fact-sheet-breast-cancer-2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt ME, Goldschmidt S, Hermann S, Steindorf K. Late effects, long-term problems and unmet needs of cancer survivors. Int J Cancer. 2022;151(8):1280&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Ligt KM, Heins M, Verloop J, Ezendam NPM, Smorenburg CH, Korevaar JC, et al. The impact of health symptoms on health-related quality of life in early-stage breast cancer survivors. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2019;178(3):703&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javan Biparva A, Raoofi S, Rafiei S, Pashazadeh Kan F, Kazerooni M, Bagheribayati F, et al. Global quality of life in breast cancer: systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Support Palliat Care. 2024;13(e3):e528&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke S, Wurz A, Bradshaw A, Saunders S, West MA, Brunet J. Physical activity and quality of life in cancer survivors: a meta-synthesis of qualitative research. Cancers (Basel). 2017. https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers9050053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun M, Liu C, Lu Y, Zhu F, Li H, Lu Q. Effects of physical activity on quality of life, anxiety and depression in breast cancer survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Asian Nurs Res. 2023;17(5):276&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratcliff CG, Zepeda SG, Hall MH, Tullos EA, Fowler S, Chaoul A, et al. Patient characteristics associated with sleep disturbance in breast cancer survivors. Support Care Cancer. 2021;29(5):2601&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leitzelar BN, Crawford SL, Levine B, Ylitalo KR, Colvin AB, Gabriel KP, et al. Physical activity and quality of life among breast cancer survivors: Pink SWAN. Support Care Cancer. 2025;33(2):101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SH, Jo HY. Factors associated with poor quality of life in breast cancer survivors: a 3-year follow-up study. Cancers (Basel). 2023. https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers15245809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aune D, Markozannes G, Abar L, Balducci K, Cariolou M, Nanu N, et al. Physical activity and health-related quality of life in women with breast cancer: a meta-analysis. JNCI Cancer Spectr. 2022. https://doi.org/10.1093/jncics/pkac072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liska TM, Kolen AM. The role of physical activity in cancer survivors&#x2019; quality of life. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2020;18(1):197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Dodd KW, Steeves J, McClain J, Alfano CM, McAuley E. Physical activity and sedentary behavior in breast cancer survivors: new insight into activity patterns and potential intervention targets. Gynecol Oncol. 2015;138(2):398&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng WH, Teo RH, Cheng LJ, Lau Y, Lau ST. Global prevalence of sleep disturbances among breast cancer survivors: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sleep Health. 2023;9(5):704&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Groef A, Geraerts I, Demeyer H, Van der Gucht E, Dams L, de Kinkelder C, et al. Physical activity levels after treatment for breast cancer: two-year follow-up. Breast. 2018;40:23&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinnessen R, Beijer S, Oerlemans S, Husson O, Mols F, Bours MJ, et al. Sleep quality and overall survival among cancer survivors in the Netherlands: a PROFILES registry study. Sleep Med. 2025;131:106488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strollo SE, Fallon EA, Gapstur SM, Smith TG. Cancer-related problems, sleep quality, and sleep disturbance among long-term cancer survivors at 9-years post diagnosis. Sleep Med. 2020;65:177&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirazipour CH, Raines C, Diniz MA, Salvy SJ, Haile RW, Freedland SJ, et al. The 24-hour movement paradigm: an integrated approach to the measurement and promotion of daily activity in cancer clinical trials. Contemp Clin Trials Commun. 2023;32:101081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SL, Brocklebank L, Kennedy F, Hamer M, Fisher A. The Application of the 24-Hour movement paradigm in people diagnosed with cancer: a scoping review. J Phys Act Health. 2025:1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hidde MC, Lyden K, Henry K, Leach HJ. Reallocating time to physical activity and sleep: associations with quality of life in cancer survivors. Support Care Cancer. 2022;30(9):7527&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzoni A-S, Strandberg E, B&#xf6;rjeson S, Sj&#xf6;vall K, Berntsen S, Demmelmaier I, et al. Reallocating sedentary time to physical activity: effects on fatigue and quality of life in patients with breast cancer in the Phys-Can project. Support Care Cancer. 2023;31(2):151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Roekel EH, Bours MJ, Breedveld-Peters JJ, Willems PJ, Meijer K, Kant I, et al. Modeling how substitution of sedentary behavior with standing or physical activity is associated with health-related quality of life in colorectal cancer survivors. Cancer Causes Control. 2016;27(4):513&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumuid D, Stanford TE, Pedi&#x161;i&#x107; &#x17d;, Maher C, Lewis LK, Mart&#xed;n-Fern&#xe1;ndez JA, et al. Adiposity and the isotemporal substitution of physical activity, sedentary time and sleep among school-aged children: a compositional data analysis approach. BMC Public Health. 2018;18(1):311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumuid D, Pedi&#x161;i&#x107; &#x17d;, Palarea-Albaladejo J, Mart&#xed;n-Fern&#xe1;ndez JA, Hron K, Olds T. Compositional data analysis in time-use epidemiology: what, why, how. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17072220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Groef A, Devoogdt N, Van der Gucht E, Dams L, Bernar K, Godderis L, et al. EduCan trial: study protocol for a randomised controlled trial on the effectiveness of pain neuroscience education after breast cancer surgery on pain, physical, emotional and work-related functioning. BMJ Open. 2019;9(1):e025742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vrieze T, Coeck D, Verbelen H, Devoogdt N, Tjalma W, Gebruers N. Cross-cultural psychometric evaluation of the Dutch McGill-QoL questionnaire for breast cancer patients. Facts Views Vis Obgyn. 2016;8(4):205&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migueles JH, Cadenas-Sanchez C, Ekelund U, Delisle Nystr&#xf6;m C, Mora-Gonzalez J, L&#xf6;f M, et al. Accelerometer data collection and processing criteria to assess physical activity and other outcomes: a systematic review and practical considerations. Sports Med. 2017;47(9):1821&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willems I, Verbestel V, Dumuid D, Calders P, Lapauw B, De Craemer M. A comparative analysis of 24-hour movement behaviors features using different accelerometer metrics in adults: Implications for guideline compliance and associations with cardiometabolic health. PLoS ONE. 2024;19(9):e0309931.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migueles JH, Rowlands AV, Huber F, Sabia S, van Hees VT. GGIR: a research community-driven open source r package for generating physical activity and sleep outcomes from multi-day raw accelerometer data. J Meas Phys Behav. 2019;2(3):188&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hees VT, Fang Z, Langford J, Assah F, Mohammad A, da Silva IC, et al. Autocalibration of accelerometer data for free-living physical activity assessment using local gravity and temperature: an evaluation on four continents. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2014;117(7):738&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hees VT, Sabia S, Anderson KN, Denton SJ, Oliver J, Catt M, et al. A novel, open access method to assess sleep duration using a wrist-worn accelerometer. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(11):e0142533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe4;h&#xe4;-Ypy&#xe4; H, Bretterhofer J, Husu P, Windhaber J, Vasankari T, Titze S, et al. Performance of different accelerometry-based metrics to estimate oxygen consumption during track and treadmill locomotion over a wide intensity range. Sensors. 2023. https://doi.org/10.3390/s23115073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe4;h&#xe4;-Ypy&#xe4; H, Husu P, Suni J, Vasankari T, Siev&#xe4;nen H. Reliable recognition of lying, sitting, and standing with a hip-worn accelerometer. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018;28(3):1092&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty A, Jackson D, Hammerla N, Pl&#xf6;tz T, Olivier P, Granat MH, et al. Large scale population assessment of physical activity using wrist worn accelerometers: the UK Biobank Study. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(2):e0169649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowlands AV, Edwardson CL, Davies MJ, Khunti K, Harrington DM, Yates T. Beyond cut points: accelerometer metrics that capture the physical activity profile. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018;50(6):1323&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Boogaart KG, Tolosana-Delgado R, Bren M. compositions: Compositional Data Analysis. R package version 2.0&#x2013;9, 2025 [Available from: https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=compositions.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miatke A, Stanford T, Olds T, Fraysse F, Maher C, Martin-Fernandez JA, et al. When the outcome is compositional&#x2013;a method for conducting compositional response linear mixed models for physical activity, sedentary behaviour and sleep research. medRxiv. 2025:2025.06.04.25328944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuinman MA, Gazendam-Donofrio SM, Hoekstra-Weebers JE. Screening and referral for psychosocial distress in oncologic practice: use of the Distress Thermometer. Cancer. 2008;113(4):870&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Team RC. R: a language and environment for statistical computing. Vienna, Austria.: R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt ME, Wiskemann J, Steindorf K. Quality of life, problems, and needs of disease-free breast cancer survivors 5 years after diagnosis. Qual Life Res. 2018;27(8):2077&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung W, Cho IY, Jung J, Cho MH, Koo HY, Park Y-MM, et al. Changes in physical activity and cardiovascular disease risk in cancer&#xa0;survivors: a nationwide cohort study. JACC: CardioOncology. 2024;6(6):879&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucas AR, Levine BJ, Avis NE. Posttreatment trajectories of physical activity in breast cancer survivors. Cancer. 2017;123(14):2773&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Z, Rundle A, Genkinger JM, Cheung YK, Ergas IJ, Roh JM, et al. Distinct trajectories of moderate to vigorous physical activity and sedentary behavior following a breast cancer diagnosis: the Pathways Study. J Cancer Surviv. 2020;14(3):393&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Chaput JP, Giangregorio LM, Janssen I, Saunders TJ, Kho ME, et al. Canadian 24-hour movement guidelines for adults aged 18&#x2013;64 years and adults aged 65 years or older: an integration of physical activity, sedentary behaviour, and sleep. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2020;45(10 (Suppl. 2)):S57&#x2013;S102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trivedi R, Man H, Madut A, Mather M, Elder E, Dhillon HM, et al. Irregular sleep/wake patterns are associated with reduced quality of life in post-treatment cancer patients: a study across three cancer cohorts. Front Neurosci. 2021;15:700923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rock CL, Thomson CA, Sullivan KR, Howe CL, Kushi LH, Caan BJ, et al. American cancer society nutrition and physical activity guideline for cancer survivors. CA Cancer J Clin. 2022;72(3):230&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, Borodulin K, Buman MP, Cardon G, et al. World Health Organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(24):1451&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R, Han J, Li S, Deng H, Jian T, Huang Z, et al. Interaction between sleep duration and physical activity on mortality among cancer survivors: findings from National health and nutrition examination surveys 2007&#x2013;2018. Front Public Health. 2025;13:1532320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zullig LL, Sung AD, Khouri MG, Jazowski S, Shah NP, Sitlinger A, et al. Cardiometabolic comorbidities in cancer&#xa0;survivors: JACC: CardioOncology State-of-the-Art Review. JACC: CardioOncology. 2022;4(2):149&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welch WA, Ehlers D, Gavin KL, Aguinaga S, Cottrell A, Nielsen A, et al. Effects of reallocating sedentary time with physical activity on quality of life indicators in breast cancer survivors. Psychooncology. 2019;28(7):1430&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Roekel EH, Duch&#xe2;teau J, Bours MJL, van Delden L, Breedveld-Peters JJL, Koole JL, et al. Longitudinal associations of light-intensity physical activity with quality of life, functioning and fatigue after colorectal cancer. Qual Life Res. 2020;29(11):2987&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfano CM, Lichstein KL, Vander Wal GS, Smith AW, Reeve BB, McTiernan A, et al. Sleep duration change across breast cancer survivorship: associations with symptoms and health-related quality of life. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2011;130(1):243&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clifford BK, Mizrahi D, Sandler CX, Barry BK, Simar D, Wakefield CE, et al. Barriers and facilitators of exercise experienced by cancer survivors: a mixed methods systematic review. Support Care Cancer. 2018;26(3):685&#x2013;700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Groef A, Van der Gucht E, Devoogdt N, Smeets A, Bernar K, Morlion B, et al. Returning to work after breast cancer surgery: a randomised controlled trial on the effect of pain neuroscience education. J Occup Rehabil. 2023;33(4):757&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>