<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41840606</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1477-3155</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of nanobiotechnology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Nanobiotechnology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Multi-functional self-powered nanofiber conduit for peripheral nerve regeneration and muscle atrophy prevention.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12951-026-04241-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Peripheral nerve injury (PNI) often leads to limited functional recovery in over 50% of patients, with current clinical strategies primarily relying on nerve grafts or conduits to bridge injury gaps. In the search of alternative solutions, self-powered biomaterials show significant potential in tissue engineering applications. This study designed a self-powered polycaprolactone/gelatin (PCL/gelatin) nanofiber conduit for sciatic nerve regeneration. The electrospun PCL/gelatin nanofiber conduit was characterized for its self-powering capability, mechanical strength, biocompatibility, and degradability. Functionalization of the nanofiber conduit with conductive polypyrrole (PPy) nanoparticles loaded with nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) enhanced anti-inflammatory and antioxidative effects and helped prevent muscle atrophy. Furthermore, the incorporation of conductive polymers reduced polarization cancellation and enabled the controlled release of NSAIDs through exercise-induced mechanical stimulation of the nanofiber conduit. Transcriptomic analyses confirmed that the nanofiber conduit promoted peripheral nerve regeneration and inhibited apoptosis by activating insulin signaling.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Renjie</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Provincial Engineering Research Center for High-Throughput Screening and Evaluation of Small Molecule Compounds, Institute of Medicine and Health, Jiangxi Academy of Sciences, Nanchang, 330096, Jiangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, City University of Hong Kong, Kowloon, 999077, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ke</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, City University of Hong Kong, Kowloon, 999077, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Si</LastName><ForeName>Yifan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Biomass Science and Engineering, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610065, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Kaisong</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, City University of Hong Kong, Kowloon, 999077, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jia</LastName><ForeName>Weibin</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Transvascular Implantation Devices, The Second Affiliated Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, 310053, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, City University of Hong Kong, Kowloon, 999077, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iqbal</LastName><ForeName>Saira</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, City University of Hong Kong, Kowloon, 999077, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Shuai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, City University of Hong Kong, Kowloon, 999077, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhai</LastName><ForeName>Zhenya</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Provincial Engineering Research Center for High-Throughput Screening and Evaluation of Small Molecule Compounds, Institute of Medicine and Health, Jiangxi Academy of Sciences, Nanchang, 330096, Jiangxi, China. zhaizhenyascau@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Engineering Laboratory for Extraction and Utilization of Functional Components in Medicinal and Edible Plants, Institute of Medicine and Health, Jiangxi Academy of Sciences, Nanchang, 330096, Jiangxi, China. zhaizhenyascau@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Jinlian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, City University of Hong Kong, Kowloon, 999077, Hong Kong SAR, China. jinliahu@cityu.edu.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Grant 9380116</GrantID><Agency>CityU Startup Grant</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Grant 52073241; Grant 51673162; Grant 15201719</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (NSFC)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CityU ref: 9231419</GrantID><Agency>Contract Research</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Nanobiotechnology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101152208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1477-3155</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drug delivery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle atrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nanofiber conduit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nerve repair</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-powered</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Consent to Participate and Consent to Publish. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41840606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12951-026-04241-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12951-026-04241-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yu TH, Xu YX, Ahmad MA, Javed R, Hagiwara H, Tian XH. Exosomes as a promising therapeutic strategy for peripheral nerve injury. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2021;19:2141&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Li P, Jia YY, Cui QJ, Zhang KX, Jiang JJ. Role of non-coding RNAs in axon regeneration after peripheral nerve injury. Int J Biol Sci. 2022;18:3435&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang LL, Li M, Wang W, Yu W, Liu H, Wang K, et al. Celecoxib alleviates denervation-induced muscle atrophy by suppressing inflammation and oxidative stress and improving microcirculation. Biochem Pharmacol. 2022;203:115186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stucky CL, Mikesell AR. Cutaneous pain in disorders affecting peripheral nerves. Neurosci Lett. 2021;765:136233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kou YH, Yu YL, Zhang YJ, Han N, Yin XF, Yuan YS, Yu F, Zhang DY, Zhang PX, Jiang BG. Repair of peripheral nerve defects by nerve transposition using small gap bio-sleeve suture with different inner diameters at both ends. Neural Regen Res. 2019;14:706&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contreras E, Traserra S, Bol&#xed;var S, For&#xe9;s J, Jose-Cunilleras E, Garc&#xed;a F, et al. Repair of long nerve defects with a new decellularized nerve graft in rats and in sheep. Cells. 2022;11:4074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong XH, Yang YY, Bao ZH, Midgley AC, Li F, Dai SX, Yang ZZ, Wang J, Liu L, Li W, Zheng Y, Liu S, Liu Y, Yu W, Liu J, Fan M, Zhu MF, Shen ZY, Gu XS, Kong DL. Micro-nanofiber composite biomimetic conduits promote long-gap peripheral nerve regeneration in canine models. Bioact Mater. 2023;30:98&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XL, Zhang TY, Li CC, Xu WJ, Guan YJ, Li XY, et al. Electrical stimulation accelerates Wallerian degeneration and promotes nerve regeneration after sciatic nerve injury. Glia. 2023;71:758&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu XL, Zou DR, Hu YH, He YS, Lu JY. Research progress of low-intensity pulsed ultrasound in the repair of peripheral nerve injury. Tissue Eng Part B Rev. 2023;29:414&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhi CW, Shi S, Meng S, Wu HB, Si Y, Zhang K, et al. A biocompatible and antibacterial all-textile structured triboelectric nanogenerator for self-powered tactile sensing. Nano Energy. 2023;115:108734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C, Tran VH, Wang JB, Fuh YK, Lin LW. Direct-write piezoelectric polymeric nanogenerator with high energy conversion efficiency. Nano Lett. 2010;10:639&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Hoseyni SM, Das R, Awais M, Basdogan I, Beker L. A flexible and biodegradable piezoelectric-based wearable sensor for non-invasive monitoring of dynamic human motions and physiological signals. Adv Mater. 2023;8:2300347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang RX, Sui JJ, Wang XD. Natural piezoelectric biomaterials: a biocompatible and sustainable building block for biomedical devices. ACS Nano. 2022;16:17708&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan XY, Chen HR, Xia H, Fu YQ, Yao JM, Ni QQ. Flexible energy harvester based on aligned PZT/SMPU nanofibers and shape memory effect for curved sensors. Compos Part B Eng. 2020;197:108169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou FX, Wang YS, Zheng YD, Xie YJ, Zhang H, Chen JS, Hussain MI, Meng HY, Peng J. A novel bioactive polyurethane with controlled degradation and L-Arg release used as strong adhesive tissue patch for hemostasis and promoting wound healing. Bioact Mater. 2022;17:471&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu XY, Si YF, Zhao YY, Ke QF, Hu JL. Electrospun textile strategies in tendon to bone junction reconstruction. Adv Fiber Mater. 2023;5:764&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliana RD, Aureliana S, Ana A, Paulo JB, Pedro LG. Electrospun polycaprolactone (PCL) degradation: an in Vitro and in Vivo study. Polymers. 2022;14:3397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan HH, Wang CK, Tia M, Su YM. Influence of water-to-cement ratio on piezoelectric properties of cement-based composites containing PZT particles. Constr Build Mater. 2020;239:117858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Yang K, Cheng HN, Ye T, Wang CX. A hydrophobic conductive strip with outstanding one-dimensional stretchability for wearable heater and strain sensor. Chem Eng J. 2021;404:126393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan LJ, Ma YJ, Cao XY, Jing YJ, Su M, Li JY, et al. PC@PPy porous membrane prepared by breath figure method with superior mechanical property for efficient solar interfacial evaporation. Chem Eng J. 2023;469:144059.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samanta D, Meiser JL, Zare RN. Polypyrrole nanoparticles for tunable, pH-sensitive and sustained drug release. Nanoscale. 2015;21:9497&#x2013;504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari S, Gaur A, Kumar C, Maiti P. Enhanced piezoelectric response in nanoclay induced electrospun PVDF nanofibers for energy harvesting. Energy. 2019;171:485&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jariwala T, Ico G, Tai Y, Park H, Myung NV, Nam J. Mechano-responsive piezoelectric nanofiber as an on-demand drug delivery vehicle. ACS Appl Bio Mater. 2021;4:3706&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Tan RJ, Zhang K, Meng S, Xu XY, Zhang Q, et al. Implantable heterogeneous triboelectric nanogenerator effectively prevents denervation-induced muscle atrophy. Nano Energy. 2024;125:109548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Park JG, Choe GE, Jeong SI, Kim HS, Lee JY. A gelatin/alginate double network hydrogel nerve guidance conduit fabricated by a chemical-free gamma radiation for peripheral nerve regeneration. Adv Healthc Mater. 2024;13:2400142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaefer T, Lengerke C. SOX2 protein biochemistry in stemness, reprogramming, and cancer: the PI3K/AKT/SOX2 axis and beyond. Oncogene. 2020;39:278&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzino A, Wuebben EL. Sox2/Oct4: a delicately balanced partnership in pluripotent stem cells and embryogenesis. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2016;1859:780&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagin M, Pernebrink M, Giubbolini S, Barone C, Sambruni G, Zhu Y, Chiara M, Ottolenghi S, Pavesi G, Wei CL, Cant&#xf9; C, Nicolis SK. Sox2 controls neural stem cell self-renewal through a Fos-centered gene regulatory network. Stem Cells. 2021;39:1107&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buganim Y, Faddah DA, Cheng AW, Itskovich E, Markoulaki S, Ganz K, et al. Single-cell expression analyses during cellular reprogramming reveal an early stochastic and a late hierarchic phase. Cell. 2012;150:1209&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Ferras O, Bernas G, Laberge-Perrault E, Pilon N. Induction and dorsal restriction of Paired-box 3 (Pax3) gene expression in the caudal neuroectoderm is mediated by integration of multiple pathways on a short neural crest enhancer. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2014;1839:546&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redolfi Riva E, &#xd6;zkan M, Contreras E, Pawar S, Zinno C, Escarda-Castro E, Kim J, Wieringa P, Stellacci F, Micera S, Navarro X. Beyond the limiting gap length: peripheral nerve regeneration through implantable nerve guidance conduits. Biomater Sci. 2024;12:1371&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng C, Hu JL, Huang HH, Zhu Y, Qin TW. Design of a smart nerve conduit based on a shape-memory polymer. Adv Mater Technol. 2016;1:1600015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Zhou JL. Humidity-dependent piezopotential properties of zinc oxide nanowires: insights from atomic-scale modelling. Nano Energy. 2018;50:298&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen RX, Wan Y, Wu WW, Yang C, He JH, Cheng JH, Jetter R, Ko FK, Chen YC. A lotus effect-inspired flexible and breathable membrane with hierarchical electrospinning micro/nanofibers and ZnO nanowires. Mater Des. 2019;162:246&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan RJ, Zhang S, Jia WB, Huang KS, Li M, Zhang K, Iqbal S, Si YF, Meng S, Fang WJ, Hu JL. Exercise-induced stimulation of self-powered nanofibers for aspirin/lysine delivery in the prevention of denervated muscle atrophy. ACS Nano. 2025;19:31481&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh SK, Park J, Na S, Kim MP, Ko H. A fully biodegradable ferroelectric skin sensor from edible porcine skin gelatine. Adv Sci. 2021;8:2005010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao HL, Chai SS, Tan ZF, Wu H, Mao X, Wei L, et al. Recent advances in physical sensors based on electrospinning technology. ACS Mater Lett. 2023;5:1627&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persano L, Dagdeviren C, Su Y, Zhang Y, Girardo S, Pisignano D, et al. High performance piezoelectric devices based on aligned arrays of nanofibers of poly(vinylidenefluoride-co-trifluoroethylene). Nat Commun. 2013;4:1633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho D. Artificial intelligence in cancer therapy. Science. 2020;367:982&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koriyama Y, Homma K, Sugitani K, Higuchi Y, Matsukawa T, Murayama D, Kato S. Upregulation of IGF-I in the goldfish retinal ganglion cells during the early stage of optic nerve regeneration. Neurochem Int. 2007;50:749&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang DH, Shin HY, Kwon MJ, Choi JY, Ryu B-Y, Kim BG. Survival of neural stem cell grafts in the lesioned spinal cord is enhanced by a combination of treadmill locomotor training via insulin-like growth factor-1 signaling. J Neurosci. 2014;34:12788&#x2013;800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govind S, Kozma R, Monfries C, Lim L, Ahmed S. Cdc42Hs facilitates cytoskeletal reorganization and neurite outgrowth by localizing the 58-kD insulin receptor substrate to filamentous actin. J Cell Biol. 2001;152:579&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalwat MA, Thurmond DC. Signaling mechanisms of glucose-induced F-actin remodeling in pancreatic islet &#x3b2; cells. Exp Mol Med. 2013;45:e37.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>