<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41635322</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intensive Conventional Rehabilitation for Reducing Upper Limb Co-contraction and Functional Improvement in Parkinson's Disease: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e100647</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e100647</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e100647</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.100647</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Upper limb dysfunction significantly impairs activities of daily living in patients with Parkinson's disease (PD). This dysfunction is partially attributable to abnormal muscle contraction. Although robot-assisted therapy improves upper limb function in patients with PD, these devices are expensive and not easily accessible in standard rehabilitation facilities. Non-robotic interventions, such as repetitive large-amplitude movements, improve upper-limb performance; however, whether these conventional exercises could improve co-contraction remains unclear. Herein, we present the case of a 70-year-old man with PD (Hoehn and Yahr Scale, stage 2) who presented with bradykinesia and difficulty moving his right arm. He underwent a two-week intensive rehabilitation program (1 h per day for five days a week) focusing on upper limb training. Following the intervention, the nine-hole peg test times and mean co-contraction index during reaching showed clinically significant improvements in both upper limbs, exceeding the minimal detectable change. This functional recovery was accompanied by a physiological reduction in muscle co-contraction. These results suggest that intensive conventional rehabilitation could be an effective and accessible alternative to robotic therapy for modulating muscle tone.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Kyota et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kyota</LastName><ForeName>Bando</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, National Center Hospital, National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry, Tokyo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sano</LastName><ForeName>Terunori</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Internal and Laboratory Medicine, National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry, Tokyo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miyazaki</LastName><ForeName>Yuta</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, National Center Hospital, National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry, Tokyo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takao</LastName><ForeName>Masaki</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Internal and Laboratory Medicine, National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry, Tokyo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hara</LastName><ForeName>Takatoshi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, National Center Hospital, National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry, Tokyo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">case report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">co-contraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electromyography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">parkinson&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">upper limb function</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: This work was supported by an Intramural Research Grant (5&#x2013;3) for Neurological and Psychiatric Disorders from the National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry (NCNP). Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41635322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12862226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.100647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Management of upper extremity dysfunction in people with Parkinson disease and Huntington disease: facilitating outcomes across the disease lifespan. Quinn L, Busse M, Dal Bello-Haas V. J Hand Ther. 2013;26:148&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23231827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Analysis of antagonistic co-contractions with motorized passive movement device in patients with Parkinson's disease. Kwon Y, Kim JW, Ho Y, Jeon HM, Bang MJ, Eom GM, Koh SB. Biomed Mater Eng. 2014;24:2291&#x2013;2297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25226929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quantitative assessment of co-contraction at the ankle joint in walking. Falconer K, Winter DA. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3987606/ Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1985;25:135&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3987606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robot-assisted arm training in patients with Parkinson's disease: a pilot study. Picelli A, Tamburin S, Passuello M, Waldner A, Smania N. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2014;11:28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3973978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24597524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparing exercise in Parkinson's disease-the Berlin LSVT&#xae;BIG study. Ebersbach G, Ebersbach A, Edler D, Kaufhold O, Kusch M, Kupsch A, Wissel J. Mov Disord. 2010;25:1902&#x2013;1908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20669294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LSVT-BIG therapy in Parkinson's disease: physiological evidence for proprioceptive recalibration. Peterka M, Odorfer T, Schwab M, Volkmann J, Zeller D. BMC Neurol. 2020;20:276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7353788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32652957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adult norms for the nine hole peg test of finger dexterity. Mathiowetz V, Weber K, Kashman N, Volland G. Occup Ther J Res. 1985;5:24&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3160243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The 9-hole PEG test of upper extremity function: average values, test-retest reliability, and factors contributing to performance in people with Parkinson disease. Earhart GM, Cavanaugh JT, Ellis T, Ford MP, Foreman KB, Dibble L. J Neurol Phys Ther. 2011;35:157&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22020457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>