<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41647927</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute Hemolytic Anemia Due to Glucose-6-Phosphate Dehydrogenase (G6PD) Deficiency Triggered by Helicobacter pylori Quadruple Therapy in a Jehovah's Witness: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e102977</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e102977</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e102977</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.102977</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) deficiency, the most common erythrocyte enzymatic disorder, predisposes patients to oxidative stress-induced acute hemolysis. Affected patients are at risk of developing hemolysis in the setting of triggers such as certain drugs, infections, or foods (fava beans). Although some drugs like antimalarials (primaquine, tafenoquine), sulfonamides, and dapsone are well-known triggers of hemolysis, reports of this adverse effect are rare with standard bismuth-based quadruple therapy for&#xa0;<i>Helicobacter pylori</i>. In this report, we present a 65-year-old male who developed profound anemia (hemoglobin 5.8 g/dL, drop of 4.4 points from baseline) within hours of initiating metronidazole- and tetracycline-containing quadruple therapy. Laboratory evaluation revealed reduced G6PD enzyme activity (3.8 U/g; normal 9.9-16.6 U/g), confirming acute hemolytic anemia secondary to G6PD deficiency. Notably, the patient was a Jehovah's Witness and declined all blood products, requiring atypical management. Quadruple therapy was discontinued, and the patient was managed with intravenous fluids, iron supplementation, and erythropoietin (EPO) therapy, resulting in gradual hematologic recovery. Regarding <i>H. pylori&#xa0;</i>treatment, the patient was initiated on triple therapy (clarithromycin, amoxicillin, proton pump inhibitor), without recurrence of hemolysis. This case highlights the rarity of G6PD deficiency as an etiology of unexplained hemolysis during initiation of <i>H. pylori</i> eradication therapy and underscores the importance of unique management strategies in the setting of blood transfusion refusal. Clinicians should maintain a high suspicion for G6PD deficiency in high-risk populations and exercise caution when prescribing oxidative regimens for&#xa0;<i>H. pylori</i> in these patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Dhami et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dhami</LastName><ForeName>Amandeep S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Wayne State University School of Medicine, Detroit, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koladiya</LastName><ForeName>Purvesh</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Wayne State University Detroit Medical Center, Detroit, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sahhar</LastName><ForeName>Fatin</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Wayne State University Detroit Medical Center, Detroit, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anemia management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bismuth quadruple therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">erythropoietin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">g6pd deficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ganzoni equation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">helicobacter pylori</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hemolytic anemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intravenous iron</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">jehovah&#x2019;s witness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxidative stress</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41647927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12872104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.102977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase--from oxidative stress to cellular functions and degenerative diseases. Ho HY, Cheng ML, Chiu DT. Redox Rep. 2007;12:109&#x2013;118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17623517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase, NADPH, and cell survival. Stanton RC. IUBMB Life. 2012;64:362&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3325335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22431005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The return of metabolism: biochemistry and physiology of the pentose phosphate pathway. Stincone A, Prigione A, Cramer T, et al. Biol Rev Camb Philos Soc. 2015;90:927&#x2013;963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4470864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25243985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The global prevalence of glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nkhoma ET, Poole C, Vannappagari V, Hall SA, Beutler E. Blood Cells Mol Dis. 2009;42:267&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19233695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology of glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency in 10 malaria-endemic countries in sub-Saharan Africa: a systematic review. Taleb M, Brahim AT, Yebouk C, Khairy T, Ishagh B, Lyoussi B, Ghaber SM. Pan Afr Med J. 2025;50:7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11991299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40225210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACG clinical guideline: treatment of Helicobacter pylori infection. Chey WD, Howden CW, Moss SF, Morgan DR, Greer KB, Grover S, Shah SC. Am J Gastroenterol. 2024;119:1730&#x2013;1753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39626064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metronidazole promotes oxidative stress and DNA fragmentation-mediated myocardial injury in albino mice. Co&#x15f;kun F, Yal&#xe7;&#x131;n E, &#xc7;avu&#x15f;o&#x11f;lu K. Chemosphere. 2024;352:141382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38331262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intravenous iron-dextran: therapeutic and experimental possibilities. Ganzoni AM. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/5413918/ Schweiz Med Wochenschr. 1970;100:301&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5413918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FERGIcor, a randomized controlled trial on ferric carboxymaltose for iron deficiency anemia in inflammatory bowel disease. Evstatiev R, Marteau P, Iqbal T, et al. Gastroenterology. 2011;141:846&#x2013;853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21699794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration. Highlights of prescribing information: ELITEK (rasburicase)  [
Sep;
2025 
]. 2009. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2009/103946s5083lbl.pdf https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2009/103946s5083lbl.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidance for using tafenoquine for prevention and antirelapse therapy for malaria - United States, 2019. Haston JC, Hwang J, Tan KR. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2019;68:1062&#x2013;1068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6871897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31751320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>