<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41836570</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2214-031X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>56</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of orthopaedic translation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Orthop Translat</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>How to choose treatment for patients who are eligible for both unicompartmental knee arthroplasty and high tibial osteotomy?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>101023</StartPage><MedlinePgn>101023</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">101023</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jot.2025.10.015</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Osteoarthritis (OA) is highly prevalent among older adults, with most cases beginning as early unicompartmental arthritis. Surgical treatments, such as unicompartmental knee arthroplasty (UKA) or high tibial osteotomy (HTO), are chosen based on the patient's intra-articular or extra-articular deformity. However, there are overlapping 'gray areas' in the classic indications for these two surgical methods, making the decision between these two procedures less straightforward. Several recent studies have underscored the importance of refining these indications. For example, multiple long-term studies have demonstrated the durability of UKA in well-selected patients, while others suggest that HTO may offer superior functional outcomes in younger, active individuals. Research has increasingly focused on identifying key preoperative factors that could better predict the success of these procedures. For instance, preoperative exercise intensity, which reflects the patient's physical activity levels and joint adaptability, has been shown to significantly influence post-surgical outcomes for both UKA and HTO. This study aims to bridge the current gap in surgical decision-making by assessing a range of preoperative factors, including exercise intensity, meniscal status, anatomical structure, soft tissue laxity, bone marrow edema, spontaneous insufficiency fractures of the knee, osteoporosis, as well as basic demographic data such as gender, age, and weight. The goal is to develop more robust and scientifically grounded criteria for determining the most appropriate surgical treatment particularly for patients in the 'gray areas' of indications. By establishing these more refined standards, orthopedic surgeons will be better positioned to optimize patient outcomes and reduce the risk of revision surgeries. The Translational Potential of this Article: This study systematically evaluated a range of preoperative factors to enhance surgical decision-making for patients who fall within the "gray areas" of UKA and HTO indications. By refining patient selection, this approach aims to improve individualized treatment, optimize postoperative functional recovery, and reduce revision rates. In addition, it seeks to establish a scalable predictive model and decision-making framework, offering evidence-based support for the standardization and refinement of surgical strategies in osteoarthritis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Jianbin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xi'an Key Laboratory of Arthritis Pathogenesis and Precision Treatment, Xi'an, 710054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Zhibo</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xi'an Key Laboratory of Arthritis Pathogenesis and Precision Treatment, Xi'an, 710054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xi'an Key Laboratory of Arthritis Pathogenesis and Precision Treatment, Xi'an, 710054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Singapore</Country><MedlineTA>J Orthop Translat</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101625127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2214-031X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High tibial osteotomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Indication standards</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Preoperative factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surgical decision-making</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Unicompartmental arthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Unicompartmental knee arthroplasty</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest. The outside source of funds was not involved in data collection, data analysis, preparation or editing of the manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41836570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12988496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jot.2025.10.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2214-031X(25)00178-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhao X.W., Fan Z.R., Ma J.X., Ma X.L., Wang Y., Bai H.H., et al. Reinforcement strategy for medial open-wedge high tibial osteotomy: a finite element evaluation of the additional opposite screw technique and bone grafts. Comput Methods Progr Biomed. 2022;213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34808530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma L. Osteoarthritis of the knee. N Engl J Med. 2021;384(1):51&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33406330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo U.G., Loppini M., Trovato U., Rizzello G., Maffulli N., Denaro V. No difference between unicompartmental versus total knee arthroplasty for the management of medial osteoarthtritis of the knee in the same patient: a systematic review and pooling data analysis. Br Med Bull. 2015;114(1):65&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25743408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pongcharoen B., Liengwattanakol P., Boontanapibul K. Comparison of functional recovery between unicompartmental and total knee arthroplasty: a randomized controlled trial. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2023;105(3):191&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36542689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li O.L., Pritchett S., Giffin J.R., Spouge A.R.I. High tibial osteotomy: an update for radiologists. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2022;218(4):701&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34817194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian X., Han C., Wang J., Tan Y., Zhu G., Lei M., et al. Distal tibial tuberosity high tibial osteotomy using an image enhancement technique for orthopedic scans in the treatment of medial compartment knee osteoarthritis. Comput Methods Progr Biomed. 2020;191</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32146210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tay M.L., Young S.W., Frampton C.M., Hooper G.J. The lifetime revision risk of unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. Bone Joint Lett J. 2022;104-b(6):672&#x2013;679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35638212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertsson O., A W.D. The risk of revision after TKA is affected by previous HTO or UKA. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2015;473(1):90&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4390918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24898530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacquet C., Gulagaci F., Schmidt A., Pendse A., Parratte S., Argenson J.N., et al. Opening wedge high tibial osteotomy allows better outcomes than unicompartmental knee arthroplasty in patients expecting to return to impact sports. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2020;28(12):3849&#x2013;3857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32008058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoorntje A., Pronk Y., Brinkman J.M., van Geenen R.C.I., van Heerwaarden R.J. High tibial osteotomy versus unicompartmental knee arthroplasty for kellgren-lawrence grade 3-4 knee osteoarthritis in younger patients: comparable improvements in patient-reported outcomes, adjusted for osteoarthritis grade and sex. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(11):4861&#x2013;4870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10598142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37572139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song S.J., Bae D.K., Kim K.I., Park C.H. Long-term survival is similar between closed-wedge high tibial osteotomy and unicompartmental knee arthroplasty in patients with similar demographics. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2019;27(4):1310&#x2013;1319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30719541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter D.J., Bierma-Zeinstra S. Osteoarthritis Lancet. 2019;393(10182):1745&#x2013;1759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31034380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belsey J., Yasen S.K., Jobson S., Faulkner J., Wilson A.J. Return to physical activity after high tibial osteotomy or unicompartmental knee arthroplasty: a systematic review and pooling data analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(5):1372&#x2013;1380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8020302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32960075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoorntje A., Kuijer P., van Ginneken B.T., Koenraadt K.L.M., van Geenen R.C.I., Kerkhoffs G., et al. Prognostic factors for return to sport after high tibial osteotomy: a directed acyclic graph approach. Am J Sports Med. 2019;47(8):1854&#x2013;1862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6604251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31157542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekhtiari S., Haldane C.E., de Sa D., Simunovic N., Musahl V., Ayeni O.R. Return to work and sport following high tibial osteotomy: a systematic review. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2016;98(18):1568&#x2013;1577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27655985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim C.W., Lee C.R., Son G.H. Type of medial meniscus tear does not affect the clinical and radiological outcomes of medial opening-wedge high tibial osteotomy. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(11):5025&#x2013;5033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37676499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S.J., Aadalen K.J., Malaviya P., Lorenz E.P., Hayden J.K., Farr J., et al. Tibiofemoral contact mechanics after serial medial meniscectomies in the human cadaveric knee. Am J Sports Med. 2006;34(8):1334&#x2013;1344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16636354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M.S., Koh I.J., Kim C.K., Choi K.Y., Kang K.H., In Y. Preoperative medial meniscal extrusion is associated with patient-reported outcomes after medial opening wedge high tibial osteotomy. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48(10):2376&#x2013;2386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32631156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H.Y., Kwak W.K., Lee C.H., Kang J.K., Song E.K., Seon J.K. Extent of preoperative medial meniscal extrusion influences intermediate-term outcomes after medial opening-wedge high tibial osteotomy. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2022;104(4):316&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34767542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C.H., Yang H.Y., Seon J.K. Increased medial meniscus extrusion led to worse clinical outcomes after medial opening-wedge high tibial osteotomy. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(4):1614&#x2013;1622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36083355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry A.K., Lavoie-Gagne O., Knapik D.M., Maheshwer B., Hodakowski A., Gursoy S., et al. Examining the efficacy of medial Meniscus Posterior root repair: a meta-analysis and systematic review of biomechanical and clinical outcomes. Am J Sports Med. 2023;51(7):1914&#x2013;1926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35384728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi Y.S., Chang M.J., Lee J.H., Lee J.H., D'Lima D.D., Kim T.W., et al. Repair of medial meniscus posterior root tear is effective for root healing and cartilage regeneration in opening wedge high tibial osteotomy. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(12):5799&#x2013;5811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37940662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke X., Qiu J., Chen S., Sun X., Wu F., Yang G., et al. Concurrent arthroscopic meniscal repair during open-wedge high tibial osteotomy is not clinically beneficial for medial meniscus posterior root tears. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2021;29(3):955&#x2013;965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32390120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H., Li Q., Zhang Z., Feng A., Qin S., Liu L., et al. Better clinical outcomes and return to sport rates with additional medial meniscus root tear repair in high tibial osteotomy for medial compartmental knee osteoarthritis. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024;32(7):1753&#x2013;1765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38643405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hohmann E. Editorial commentary: medial meniscal root repair May not be required during knee medial-compartment unloading high tibial osteotomy. Arthroscopy. 2020;36(9):2476&#x2013;2477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32891248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J.S., Lim J.K., Choi H.G., Jeong H.W., Park S.B., Shim S.J., et al. Excessively increased joint-line obliquity after medial opening-wedge high tibial osteotomy is associated with inferior radiologic and clinical outcomes: what is permissible joint-line obliquity. Arthroscopy. 2022;38(6):1904&#x2013;1915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34785297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Servant C. Editorial commentary: avoid creating an oblique joint line after an opening medial wedge high tibial osteotomy. Arthroscopy. 2022;38(6):1916&#x2013;1918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35660185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakayama H., Schr&#xf6;ter S., Yamamoto C., Iseki T., Kanto R., Kurosaka K., et al. Large correction in opening wedge high tibial osteotomy with resultant joint-line obliquity induces excessive shear stress on the articular cartilage. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2018;26(6):1873&#x2013;1878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28831525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J.H., Bin S.I., Kim J.M., Lee B.S. What is an acceptable limit of joint-line obliquity after medial open wedge high tibial osteotomy? Analysis based on midterm results. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48(12):3028&#x2013;3035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32941061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiramatsu K., Yamada Y., Nakamura N., Mitsuoka T. Factors associated with postoperative knee joint line obliquity after medial open wedge high tibial osteotomy. Am J Sports Med. 2022;50(6):1651&#x2013;1658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35293800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim T.W., Lee S.H., Lee J.Y., Lee Y.S. Effect of fibular height and lateral tibial condylar geometry on lateral cortical Hinge fracture in open wedge high tibial osteotomy. Arthroscopy. 2019;35(6):1713&#x2013;1720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31078358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida K., Kubota M., Kaneko H., Kim Y., Kobayashi K., Hada S., et al. Higher fibular head is a risk for lateral Hinge fracture in medial open wedge high tibial osteotomy. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(11):4935&#x2013;4941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37598110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi H.G., Kim J.S., Jung Y.S., Yoo H.J., Lee Y.S. Prediction and development of preventive strategies for lateral Hinge fracture during opening wedge high tibial osteotomy based on osteotomy configurations. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(11):2942&#x2013;2954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34328812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H.Y., Seon J.K. Editorial commentary: alignment for open-wedge high tibial osteotomy can be planned using the hip-knee-ankle angle and the weightbearing line. Arthroscopy. 2023;39(5):1232&#x2013;1234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37019535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feucht M.J., Winkler P.W., Mehl J., Bode G., Forkel P., Imhoff A.B., et al. Isolated high tibial osteotomy is appropriate in less than two-thirds of varus knees if excessive overcorrection of the medial proximal tibial angle should be avoided. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2021;29(10):3299&#x2013;3309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8458209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32691093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J.G., Han S.B., Jang K.M. Association of preoperative tibial varus deformity with joint line orientation and clinical outcome after open-wedge high tibial osteotomy for medial compartment osteoarthritis: a propensity score-matched analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(13):3551&#x2013;3560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34623942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim G.W., Kang J.K., Song E.K., Seon J.K. Increased joint obliquity after open-wedge high tibial osteotomy induces pain in the lateral compartment: a comparative analysis of the minimum 4-year follow-up outcomes using propensity score matching. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2021;29(10):3495&#x2013;3502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33151363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogawa H., Matsumoto K., Akiyama H. ACL degeneration after an excessive increase in the medial proximal tibial angle with medial open wedge high tibial osteotomy. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2019;27(10):3374&#x2013;3380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30656374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erlichman R.E., Adams J.B., Berend K.R., Lombardi A.V., Jr., Crawford D.A. Impact of proximal tibial varus anatomy on survivorship after medial unicondylar knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplast. 2023;38(7):1251&#x2013;1256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36603744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi N.H. Editorial commentary: Knee preoperative medial laxity May result in overcorrection or Varus recurrence after open-wedge high tibial osteotomy. Arthroscopy. 2022;38(5):1555&#x2013;1556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35501020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee D.H., Park S.C., Park H.J., Han S.B. Effect of soft tissue laxity of the knee joint on limb alignment correction in open-wedge high tibial osteotomy. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2016;24(12):3704&#x2013;3712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26154482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heijens E., Kornherr P., Meister C. The coronal hypomochlion: a tipping point of clinical relevance when planning valgus producing high tibial osteotomies. Bone Joint Lett J. 2016;98-b(5):628&#x2013;633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27143733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee D.K., Wang J.H., Won Y., Min Y.K., Jaiswal S., Lee B.H., et al. Preoperative latent medial laxity and correction angle are crucial factors for overcorrection in medial open-wedge high tibial osteotomy. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2020;28(5):1411&#x2013;1418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30980121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takayama K., Ishida K., Muratsu H., Kuroda Y., Tsubosaka M., Hashimoto S., et al. The medial tibial joint line elevation over 5 mm restrained the improvement of knee extension angle in unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2018;26(6):1737&#x2013;1742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29124288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>So S.Y., Lee S.S., Jung E.Y., Kim J.H., Wang J.H. Difference in joint line convergence angle between the supine and standing positions is the most important predictive factor of coronal correction error after medial opening wedge high tibial osteotomy. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2020;28(5):1516&#x2013;1525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31289915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobi M., Villa V., Reischl N., Demey G., Goy D., Neyret P., et al. Factors influencing posterior tibial slope and tibial rotation in opening wedge high tibial osteotomy. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2015;23(9):2762&#x2013;2768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24912576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim G.B., Kim K.I., Song S.J., Lee S.H. Increased posterior tibial slope after medial open-wedge high tibial osteotomy May result in degenerative changes in anterior cruciate ligament. J Arthroplast. 2019;34(9):1922&#x2013;1928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31103360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter D.J., Guermazi A., Lo G.H., Grainger A.J., Conaghan P.G., Boudreau R.M., et al. Evolution of semi-quantitative whole joint assessment of knee OA: MOAKS (MRI osteoarthritis knee score) Osteoarthr Cartil. 2011;19(8):990&#x2013;1002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4058435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21645627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H.Y., Kwak W.K., Song E.K., Seon J.K. Preoperative bone marrow Edema negatively impacts 10-Year outcomes after unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplast. 2023;38(3):456&#x2013;463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36265722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs C.A., Christensen C.P., Karthikeyan T. Subchondral bone marrow edema had greater effect on postoperative pain after medial unicompartmental knee arthroplasty than total knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplast. 2016;31(2):491&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26474951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H.Y., Kang S.J., Kwak W.K., Song E.K., Seon J.K. The influence of preoperative tibial bone marrow edema on outcomes after medial opening-wedge high tibial osteotomy. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2020;102(23):2068&#x2013;2076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33060426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareek A., Parkes C.W., Bernard C., Camp C.L., Saris D.B.F., Stuart M.J., et al. Spontaneous Osteonecrosis/Subchondral insufficiency fractures of the knee: high rates of conversion to surgical treatment and arthroplasty. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2020;102(9):821&#x2013;829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malghem J., Lecouvet F., Vande Berg B., Kirchgesner T., Omoumi P. Subchondral insufficiency fractures, subchondral insufficiency fractures with osteonecrosis, and other apparently spontaneous subchondral bone lesions of the knee-pathogenesis and diagnosis at imaging. Insights Imaging. 2023;14(1):164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10545656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37782395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matzkin E. Editorial commentary: spontaneous insufficiency fracture of the knee, formerly known as spontaneous osteonecrosis of the knee, may benefit from combined mosaicplasty and high tibial osteotomy: better together. Arthroscopy. 2023;39(2):347&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36604001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soucacos P.N., Xenakis T.H., Beris A.E., Soucacos P.K., Georgoulis A. Idiopathic osteonecrosis of the medial femoral condyle. Classification and treatment. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1997;(341):82&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9269159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marti C.B., Rodriguez M., Zanetti M., Romero J. Spontaneous osteonecrosis of the medial compartment of the knee: a MRI follow-up after conservative and operative treatment, preliminary results. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2000;8(2):83&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10795669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukai S., Nakagawa Y., Nishitani K., Sakai S., Nakamura R., Takahashi M. Mosaicplasty with high tibial osteotomy for knee subchondral insufficiency fracture had better magnetic resonance observation of cartilage repair tissue scores with less bone marrow edema and better plug union and less plug necrosis compared with mosaicplasty alone. Arthroscopy. 2023;39(2):337&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36064155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greco N.J., Lombardi A.V., Jr., Hurst J.M., Morris M.J., Berend K.R. Medial unicompartmental knee arthroplasty for the treatment of focal femoral osteonecrosis. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2019;101(12):1077&#x2013;1084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31220024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon J.R., Ko S.N., Jung K.Y., Lee Y., Park J.O., Shin Y.S. Risk of revision following total knee arthroplasty or high tibial osteotomy: a nationwide propensity-score-matched study. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2019;101(9):771&#x2013;778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31045664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linde K.N., Madsen F., Puhakka K.B., Langdahl B.L., S&#xf8;balle K., Krog-Mikkelsen I., et al. Preoperative systemic bone quality does not affect tibial component migration in knee arthroplasty: a 2-Year radiostereometric analysis of a hundred consecutive patients. J Arthroplast. 2019;34(10):2351&#x2013;2359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31202639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahrend M.D., Petzold D., Schuster P., Herbst M., Ihle C., Mayer P., et al. Higher conversion rate to knee arthroplasty in female patients following medial open-wedge high tibial osteotomy. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024;32(10):2562&#x2013;2572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38415780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royon T., Foissey C., Fontalis A., Planchet F., Servien E., Batailler C., et al. Gender does not influence outcomes and complications in medial unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024;32(10):2551&#x2013;2561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38680026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Primeau C.A., Birmingham T.B., Leitch K.M., Willits K.R., Litchfield R.B., Fowler P.J., et al. Total knee replacement after high tibial osteotomy: time-to-event analysis and predictors. CMAJ (Can Med Assoc J) 2021;193(5) E158-e66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7954572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33526542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin C., Song E.K., Santoso A., Ingale P.S., Choi I.S., Seon J.K. Survival and risk factor analysis of medial open wedge high tibial osteotomy for unicompartment knee osteoarthritis. Arthroscopy. 2020;36(2):535&#x2013;543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31901391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S.H., Seo H.Y., Kim H.R., Song E.K., Seon J.K. Older age increases the risk of revision and perioperative complications after high tibial osteotomy for unicompartmental knee osteoarthritis. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8692610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34934052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constantin H., Salmon L.J., Russell V., Sundaraj K., Roe J.P., Pinczewski L.A. 20-Year outcomes of high tibial osteotomy: determinants of survival and functional outcome. Am J Sports Med. 2024;52(2):344&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38243788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J.H., Bin S.I., Kim J.M., Lee B.S. Cartilage status, rather than chronologic age, determines the outcomes of open wedge high tibial osteotomy: a cartilage status-matched cohort study. Arthroscopy. 2021;37(9):2915&#x2013;2922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salman L.A., Abudalou A., Khatkar H., Ahmed G., Dakin S.G., Kendrick B., et al. Impact of age on unicompartmental knee arthroplasty outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(3):986&#x2013;997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9957860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36063186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M., Chen J., Shi Lu C., Lo N.N., Yeo S.J. No differences in outcomes scores or survivorship of unicompartmental knee arthroplasty between patients younger or older than 55 years of Age at minimum 10-Year followup. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2019;477(6):1434&#x2013;1446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6554132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31094840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh G.S., Corvi J.J., Grace T.R., Eralp I., Small I., Lonner J.H. Octogenarians undergoing medial unicompartmental knee arthroplasty have similar patient-reported outcomes as their younger counterparts. J Arthroplast. 2021;36(11):3656&#x2013;3661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34226083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosso F., Rossi R., Cantivalli A., Pilone C., Bonasia D.E. Joint line obliquity does not affect the outcomes of opening wedge high tibial osteotomy at an average 10-Year Follow-up. Am J Sports Med. 2022;50(2):461&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34854734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbst M., Ahrend M.D., Gr&#xfc;nwald L., Fischer C., Schr&#xf6;ter S., Ihle C. Overweight patients benefit from high tibial osteotomy to the same extent as patients with normal weights but show inferior mid-term results. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2022;30(3):907&#x2013;917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8901480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33570698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H., Wang T., Li C., Yu J., Zhu R., Wang M., et al. Development and validation of a nomogram for predicting the risk of immediate postoperative deep vein thrombosis after open wedge high tibial osteotomy. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(11):4724&#x2013;4734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37378681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal N., To K., Zhang B., Khan W. Obesity does not adversely impact the outcome of unicompartmental knee arthroplasty for osteoarthritis: a meta-analysis of 80,798 subjects. Int J Obes. 2021;45(4):715&#x2013;724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33214703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagge A., Jensen C.B., Mikkelsen M., Gromov K., Nielsen C.S., Troelsen A. Obese patients achieve good improvements in patient-reported outcome measures after medial unicompartmental knee arthroplasty despite a lower preoperative Score. J Arthroplast. 2023;38(2):252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36096272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giordano L., Maffulli N., Morenghi E., Quaglia A., Prospero E., Rosa F., et al. A BMI above 30 results in satisfying outcomes in patients undergoing fixed-bearing lateral unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(3):1106&#x2013;1112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9734769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36478285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molloy J., Kennedy J., Jenkins C., Mellon S., Dodd C., Murray D. Obesity should not be considered a contraindication to medial Oxford UKA: long-term patient-reported outcomes and implant survival in 1000 knees. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2019;27(7):2259&#x2013;2265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6609589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30361754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S., Lim W.J., Chen J.Y., Lo N.N., Chia S.L., Tay D.K.J., et al. The influence of obesity on clinical outcomes of fixed-bearing unicompartmental knee arthroplasty: a ten-year follow-up study. Bone Joint Lett J. 2019;101-b(2):213&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30700121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nettrour J.F., Ellis R.T., Hansen B.J., Keeney J.A. High failure rates for unicompartmental knee arthroplasty in morbidly Obese patients: a two-year minimum Follow-Up Study. J Arthroplast. 2020;35(4):989&#x2013;996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31796233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn J.H., Kang H.W., Yang T.Y., Lee J.Y. Risk factors of post-operative malalignment in fixed-bearing medial unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. Int Orthop. 2016;40(7):1455&#x2013;1463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26452679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray D.W., Parkinson R.W. Usage of unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. Bone Joint Lett J. 2018;100-b(4):432&#x2013;435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29629577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tay M.L., Monk A.P., Frampton C.M., Hooper G.J., Young S.W. A comparison of clinical thresholds for revision following total and unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. Bone Joint Lett J. 2023;105-b(3):269&#x2013;276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36854342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster P., Ge&#xdf;lein M., Schlumberger M., Mayer P., Mayr R., Oremek D., et al. Ten-Year results of medial open-wedge high tibial osteotomy and chondral resurfacing in severe medial osteoarthritis and varus malalignment. Am J Sports Med. 2018;46(6):1362&#x2013;1370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29589953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida S., Nishitani K., Yoshitomi H., Kuriyama S., Nakamura S., Fujii T., et al. Knee alignment correction by high tibial osteotomy reduces symptoms and synovial inflammation in knee osteoarthritis accompanied by macrophage phenotypic change from M1 to M2. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2023;75(6):950&#x2013;960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36530127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghomrawi H.M., Eggman A.A., Pearle A.D. Effect of age on cost-effectiveness of unicompartmental knee arthroplasty compared with total knee arthroplasty in the U.S. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2015;97(5):396&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4344593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25740030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouguennec N., Mergenthaler G., Gicquel T., Briand C., Nadau E., Pailh&#xe9; R., et al. Medium-term survival and clinical and radiological results in high tibial osteotomy: factors for failure and comparison with unicompartmental arthroplasty. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2020;106(8s) S223-s30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32863169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu S.Q., Wong C.C., Chuang A.E., Chen C.H., Tan C.A., Weng P.W. Unicompartmental knee arthroplasty versus opening-wedge high tibial osteotomy for spontaneous osteonecrosis of the knee: a retrospective cohort study. Orthop J Sports Med. 2024;12(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11544757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39525353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross M.B., Yi P.Y., Moric M., Sporer S.M., Berger R.A., Della Valle C.J. Revising an HTO or UKA to TKA: is it more like a primary TKA or a revision TKA? J Arthroplast. 2014;29(9 Suppl):229&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25015755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge H., Huang Y., Yan H., Zeng Y., Zeng J. What is the difference in proprioception between single condylar arthroplasty and high tibial osteotomy? A comparative study on both knees of the same patient. J Orthop Surg Res. 2023;18(1):486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10327313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37415243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh I.J., Kim M.S., Sohn S., Song K.Y., Choi N.Y., Jung H., et al. Predictive factors for satisfaction after contemporary unicompartmental knee arthroplasty and high tibial osteotomy in isolated medial femorotibial osteoarthritis. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2019;105(1):77&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30509622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazl&#x131;g&#xfc;l A.S., G&#xfc;rler A., Tecimel O., Y&#x131;lmaz S., Do&#x11f;an M., Akkaya M. The effect of high tibial osteotomy and unicompartmental knee arthroplasty on patellofemoral joint in young patients with medial knee arthrosis. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2024;144(9):3989&#x2013;3994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39271496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J.G., Han S.B., Jang K.M., Shin S.M. Differential effects of tibia varus deformity on clinical outcomes following high tibial osteotomy and unicompartmental knee arthroplasty for moderate medial compartment osteoarthritis with moderate varus alignment. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2025;145(1):119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39798035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryu S.M., Park J.W., Na H.D., Shon O.J. High tibial osteotomy versus unicompartmental knee arthroplasty for medial compartment arthrosis with kissing lesions in relatively young patients. Knee Surg Relat Res. 2018;30(1):17&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5853178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29298462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyatt F.W., Al-Dadah O. Unicompartmental knee arthroplasty vs high tibial osteotomy for knee osteoarthritis: a comparison of clinical and radiological outcomes. World J Orthoped. 2024;15(5):444&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11145972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38835690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M.S., Koh I.J., Sohn S., Jeong J.H., In Y. Unicompartmental knee arthroplasty is superior to high tibial osteotomy in post-operative recovery and participation in recreational and sports activities. Int Orthop. 2019;43(11):2493&#x2013;2501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30565177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guy S., Saithna A., Ferreira A., Carrozzo A., Vieira T.D., Ollivier M.P., et al. The influence of tibial tubercle-sparing slope-reducing osteotomy on patellar height in patients undergoing revision ACL reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2024;52(4):919&#x2013;927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38385201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Cano J.P. Editorial commentary: Anterolateral Hinge position decreases the slope in opening-wedge high tibial osteotomy: a key point in treating an anterior cruciate ligament-deficient, varus knee. Arthroscopy. 2021;37(5):1585&#x2013;1587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33896510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider A., Gaillard R., Gunst S., Batailler C., Neyret P., Lustig S., et al. Combined ACL reconstruction and opening wedge high tibial osteotomy at 10-year follow-up: excellent laxity control but uncertain return to high level sport. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2020;28(3):960&#x2013;968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31312875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh G.S., Zeng G.J., Chen J.Y., Lo N.N., Yeo S.J., Liow M.H.L. Preoperative flexion contracture does not compromise the outcomes and survivorship of medial fixed bearing unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplast. 2021;36(10):3406&#x2013;3412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34090691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purcell R.L., Cody J.P., Ammeen D.J., Goyal N., Engh G.A. Elimination of preoperative flexion contracture as a contraindication for unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2018;26(7):e158&#x2013;e163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29494465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J.H., Bin S.I., Kim J.M., Lee B.S., Choe J.S., Cho H.K. Flexion contracture can be relieved by concurrent notchplasty in medial open wedge high tibial osteotomy. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2021;107(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34314903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M., Li T., Tian J., Zhang L., Wang Y., Li S., et al. Engineering single-component antibacterial anti-inflammatory polyitaconate-based Hydrogel for promoting Methicillin-Resistant staphylococcus aureus-infected wound healing and skin regeneration. ACS Nano. 2024;18(1):395&#x2013;409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38150353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fassihi S.C., Gu A., Wessel L.E., Thakkar S.C., Sculco P.K., Ast M.P. Prior knee arthroscopy increases the failure rate of subsequent unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplast. 2021;36(5):1556&#x2013;15561.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33250328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deckey D.G., Boddu S.P., Christopher Z.K., Spangehl M.J., Clarke H.D., Gililland J.M., et al. Rheumatoid Arthritis is not a contraindication to unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplast. 2024;39(8):2003&#x2013;2006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38428692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iveson J.M., Longton E.B., Wright V. Comparative study of tibial (single) and tibiofemoral (double) osteotomy for osteoarthrosis and rheumatoid arthritis. Ann Rheum Dis. 1977;36(4):319&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1006692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">901030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao X., Li Z., An S., Huang J., Feng M., Cao G. Does diabetes mellitus increase the incidence of early thrombosis in deep vein following unicompartmental knee arthroplasty: a retrospective cohort study. BMC Geriatr. 2022;22(1):448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9128116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35610582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekhtiari S., Bozzo A., Madden K., Winemaker M.J., Adili A., Wood T.J. Unicompartmental knee arthroplasty: survivorship and risk factors for revision: a population-based cohort study with minimum 10-Year Follow-up. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2021;103(23):2170&#x2013;2176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34547009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berk A.N., Gachigi K.K., Trofa D.P., Piasecki D.P., Fleischli J.E., Saltzman B.M. Early postoperative complications and associated variables after high tibial osteotomy and distal femoral osteotomy: a 15-Year experience from a single academic institution. Am J Sports Med. 2023;51(10):2574&#x2013;2582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37417330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>