<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41710222</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2279-9028</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of public health research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Public Health Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Empowering communities in cholera outbreak response: Local perspectives from Sidama, Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>22799036261423664</StartPage><MedlinePgn>22799036261423664</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">22799036261423664</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/22799036261423664</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Cholera remains a persistent public health challenge in low-resource settings, where effective multi-sectoral coordination and meaningful community engagement are often limited. This cross-sectional study examined the socioeconomic and contextual factors influencing community participation during a recent cholera outbreak in Ethiopia's Sidama Region. The study assessed levels of involvement across preparedness, response, and recovery phases to inform context-specific strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A community-based cross-sectional survey was conducted between June and August 2023 among 613 residents in the Sidama Region following a cholera outbreak. A structured checklist assessed sociodemographic characteristics, knowledge, attitudes, practices, and engagement in preparedness, detection/response, and recovery activities. Logistic regression analysis was used to identify factors associated with low engagement.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Engagement was measured using Likert-scale items across preparedness, surveillance, response, and coordination domains. The overall community engagement index was 48%, indicating that fewer than half of participants were actively involved in outbreak management. Key barriers included poor socioeconomic status (33%), large household size exceeding four members (82%), and low educational attainment, with 27% having no formal education. Low engagement was significantly more likely among participants with poor wealth status (AOR 2.98), households with three or more children under 5&#x2009;years (AOR 12.6), individuals with poor knowledge of cholera (AOR 2.51), and males compared to females (AOR 1.87).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Community engagement in the cholera outbreak response was suboptimal. Poverty, large household, and low educational attainment were the principal barriers. Addressing these constraints is essential to strengthen early detection, improve response effectiveness, and sustain cholera control through enhanced community involvement.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abayneh</LastName><ForeName>Aschalew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0091-1731</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ethiopian Public Health Institute, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, CAPHRI School for Public Health and Primary Care, Maastricht University, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sasie</LastName><ForeName>Sileshi Demelash</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ethiopian Public Health Institute, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, CAPHRI School for Public Health and Primary Care, Maastricht University, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mengesha</LastName><ForeName>Selamawit</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sidama Regional Health-Bureau, Hawassa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spigt</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, CAPHRI School for Public Health and Primary Care, Maastricht University, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Public Health Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101580775</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2279-9028</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sidama</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cholera outbreak</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">community engagement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">emergency response</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41710222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12909772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/22799036261423664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_22799036261423664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ali M, Nelson AR, Lopez AL, et al. Updated global burden of cholera in endemic countries. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 2015; 9(6): e0003832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4455997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26043000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinede G, Abagero A, Tolosa T. Cholera outbreak in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia: a case-control study. PLoS One 2020; 15(7): e0235440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7332024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32614915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>mondiale de la Sant&#xe9; O. Cholera vaccines: WHO position paper&#x2013;August 2017 [Vaccins antichol&#xe9;riques: Note de synth&#xe8;se de l&#x2019;OMS&#x2013;ao&#xfb;t 2017]. Vaccine 2018; 36(24): 3418&#x2013;3420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29555219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohene S-A, Klenyuie W, Sarpeh M, et al. Assessment of the response to cholera outbreaks in two districts in Ghana. Infect Dis Poverty 2016; 5(1): 1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5090876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27802834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khonje A, Metcalf CA, Diggle E, et al. Cholera outbreak in districts around Lake Chilwa, Malawi: lessons learned. Malawi Med J 2012; 24(2): 29&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3588220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23638267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaffga NH, Tauxe RV, Mintz ED. Cholera: a new homeland in Africa? Am J Trop Med Hyg 2007; 77(4): 705&#x2013;713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17978075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deen J, von Seidlein L, Luquero FJ, et al. The scenario approach for countries considering the addition of oral cholera vaccination in cholera preparedness and control plans. Lancet Infect Dis 2016; 16(1): 125&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26494426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO community engagement framework for quality, people-centred and resilient health services. World Health Organization, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedson J, Jalloh MF, Pedi D, et al. Community engagement in outbreak response: lessons from the 2014&#x2013;2016 Ebola outbreak in Sierra Leone. BMJ Glob Health 2020; 5(8): e002145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32830128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cambaza E, Mongo E, Anapakala E, et al. Outbreak of cholera due to cyclone Kenneth in northern Mozambique, 2019. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2019; 16(16): 2925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6720437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31443180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukuruva CT. Community-based emergency management: A case study on a cholera outbreak in Zimbabwe. Auckland University of Technology, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadri J, Sauvageot D, Njanpop-Lafourcade BM, et al. Sensitivity, specificity, and public-health utility of clinical case definitions based on the signs and symptoms of cholera in Africa. Am J Trop Med Hyg 2018; 98(4): 1021&#x2013;1030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5928804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29488455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry Akintobi T, Jacobs T, Sabbs D, et al. Community engagement of African Americans in the era of COVID-19: considerations, challenges, implications, and recommendations for public health. Prev Chronic Dis 2020; 17: E83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7458103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32790605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan Y, O&#x2019;Sullivan T, Brown A, et al. Public health emergency preparedness: a framework to promote resilience. BMC Public Health 2018; 18: 1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6280369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30518348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorensen W, Smith J. Recent cholera epidemics originating in Latin America: contrasts and comparisons with social and Public Health Implications. Curr Pol Econ South Central Am 2016; 9(3): 405&#x2013;441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tareke KG, Solomon N, Teshome F. Barriers for the functional implementation of Community Health Volunteers in Health Developmental army in Debre Libanos District, Oromia, Ethiopia: a descriptive qualitative study. J Multidiscip Healthc 2022; 15: 103&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8760987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35046664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omaswa F, Boufford JI. Strong ministries for strong health systems: a strategy for health systems strengthening: supporting ministerial health leadership. Kampala (Uganda): African Centre for Global Health and Social Transformation, The New York Academy of Medicine and the Rockefeller Foundation, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO&#x2019;s response to health emergencies: annual report 2023. World Health Organization, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bain LE, Ngwayu Nkfusai C, Nehwu Kiseh P, et al. Community-engagement in research in humanitarian settings. Front Public Health 2023; 11: 1208684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10470624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37663852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothman KJ, Greenland S, Lash TL. Modern epidemiology. Wolters Kluwer Health/Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins Philadelphia, 2008. Vol. 3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janz NK, Becker MH. The health belief model: a decade later. Health Educ Q 1984; 11(1): 1&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6392204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakefield MA, Loken B, Hornik RC. Use of mass media campaigns to change health behaviour. Lancet 2010; 376(9748): 1261&#x2013;1271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4248563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20933263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtis V, Cairncross S, Yonli R. Review: domestic hygiene and diarrhoea &#x2013; pinpointing the problem. Trop Med Int Health 2000; 5(1): 22&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10672202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R, Sharman R, Rao HR, et al. Design principles for critical incident response systems. Inf Syst E-Bus Manag 2007; 5(3): 201&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobena D, Gudina EK, Fetensa G, et al. Risk Communication and Community Engagement (RCCE) implementations to control cholera outbreak in Oromia region, Ethiopia. Trop Med Health 2025; 53(1): 4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11726941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39800749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabassum S, Naeem A, Iqbal H, et al. Cholera outbreak amidst an economic crisis and Covid-19 pandemic in Pakistan. Ann Med Surg 2022; 81: 104374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9428832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36060438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization. Disease outbreak news; Cholera &#x2013; global situation, https://www.who.int/emergencies/disease-outbreak-news/item/2023-DON437 (2023, accessed 10 November 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. COVID-19 strategic preparedness and response plan: operational planning guidelines to support country preparedness and response. World Health Organization, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. COVID-19 global risk communication and community engagement strategy, December 2020-May 2021: interim guidance. World Health Organization, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta SS, Gupta SS. Social mobilization for cholera prevention &amp; control in India: building on the existing framework. Vaccine 2020; 38 Suppl 1: A181&#x2013;A183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31331775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murali K, Balagopalan N, Benawri J, et al. Knowledge, attitude, and practices related to COVID-19 among poor and marginalized communities in central India: a cross-sectional study. PLoS One 2022; 17(4): e0264639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8986002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35385512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>South J, Stansfield J, Aml&#xf4;t R, et al. Sustaining and strengthening community resilience throughout the COVID-19 pandemic and beyond. Perspect Public Health 2020; 140(6): 305&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7683884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32820710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed AAO, Elhassan EAM, Mohamed AO, et al. Knowledge, attitude and practice of the Sudanese people towards COVID-19: an online survey. BMC Public Health 2021; 21(1): 1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7856621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33535995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malaeb D, Sallam M, Younes S, et al. Knowledge, attitude, and practice in a sample of the Lebanese population regarding cholera. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2022; 19(23): 16243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9735709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36498316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>