<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41693719</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1735-4668</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Iranian journal of child neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Iran J Child Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effects of Nebivolol on Moderate Traumatic Brain Injury in a Rat Model: Implications for Pediatric Neuroprotection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>17</StartPage><EndPage>24</EndPage><MedlinePgn>17-24</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.22037/ijcn.v20i1.50529</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Traumatic Brain Injury (TBI) is a significant public health problem. Nuclear factor E2-related factor 2 (Nrf2) is a transcription factor regulating oxidative stress and inflammation after TBI. This study examined the neuroprotective potential of Nebivolol in a rat model of moderate TBI, with a focus on implications for pediatric therapy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS &amp; METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Twenty-one male Wistar rats (230&#x202f;&#xb1;&#x202f;10 g) were included. The animals were trained using the Morris Water Maze (MWM) test, and mTBI was induced using a pendulum-based method. Nebivolol was administered at a dose of 0.05 mg/kg daily from day 8 to day 21 post-injury. Behavioral assessments were performed using the MWM, while structural brain changes were evaluated via micro-computed tomography (micro-CT). Inflammatory biomarkers were also analyzed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The results revealed significant post-TBI increases in inflammatory markers (CRP, cortisol) and decreases in prolactin levels in control animals (p&lt;0.01). Nebivolol treatment attenuated these biochemical changes while maintaining cardiovascular stability. The MWM demonstrated improved late-phase cognitive recovery in Nebivolol-treated subjects despite initial learning impairment. Nebivolol treatment significantly attenuated these biochemical changes. While early learning in the MWM was impaired, animals treated with Nebivolol established superior late-phase cognitive recovery. It suggests enhanced neuroplasticity. Nebivolol also maintained cardiovascular stability without inducing bradycardia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The results demonstrated that Nebivolol treatment significantly modulates TBI-induced physiological changes, such as CRP and cortisol, while maintaining cardiovascular stability. Although it showed protective effects against TBI-related stress responses, the observed neuroendocrine alterations suggest complex systemic interactions. Nebivolol reduces inflammation, stabilizes cardiovascular function, and finally promotes cognitive rehab. The pleiotropic profile of Nebivolol promises reliable research in pediatric-focused models and forthcoming clinical trials.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esfahani</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Ali Akbar</ForeName><Initials>MAA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma Research Center, Clinical Sciences Institute, Baqiyatallah University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genetics, Faculty of Advanced Sciences and Technology, Tehran Medical Sciences, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Faghih</LastName><ForeName>Hossein</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma Research Center, Clinical Sciences Institute, Baqiyatallah University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Talebi</LastName><ForeName>Samira</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine Genetic, National Institute of Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eslamian</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma Research Center, Clinical Sciences Institute, Baqiyatallah University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rasouli</LastName><ForeName>Hamid Reza</ForeName><Initials>HR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma Research Center, Clinical Sciences Institute, Baqiyatallah University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmadpour</LastName><ForeName>Fathollah</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma Research Center, Clinical Sciences Institute, Baqiyatallah University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>Iran J Child Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101463836</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1735-4668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cortisol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nebivolol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prolactin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Traumatic brain injury</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41693719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12904295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22037/ijcn.v20i1.50529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Maas AI, Menon DK, Adelson PD, Andelic N, Bell MJ, Belli A, Bragge P, Brazinova A, B&#xfc;ki A, Chesnut RM, Citerio G. Traumatic brain injury: integrated approaches to improve prevention, clinical care, and research. The Lancet Neurology. 2017 ;16(12):987&#x2013;1048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29122524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAllister TW. Neurobiological consequences of traumatic brain injury. Dialogues in clinical neuroscience. 2011 Sep;13(3):287&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3182015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22033563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon DW, McGeachy MJ, Bay&#x131;r H, Clark RS, Loane DJ, Kochanek PM. The far-reaching scope of neuroinflammation after traumatic brain injury. Nature Reviews Neurology. 2017 Mar;13(3):171&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5675525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28186177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Q. Role of nrf2 in oxidative stress and toxicity. Annual review of pharmacology and toxicology. 2013 Jan;53(1):401&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4680839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23294312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y, Mahmood A, Chopp M. Animal models of traumatic brain injury. Nature Reviews Neuroscience. 2013 Feb;14(2):128&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3951995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23329160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marmarou A, Foda MA, Van Den Brink W, Campbell J, Kita H, Demetriadou K. A new model of diffuse brain injury in rats: Part I: Pathophysiology and biomechanics. Journal of neurosurgery. 1994 Feb;80(2):291&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8283269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shultz SR, Bao F, Omana V, Chiu C, Brown A, Cain DP. Repeated mild lateral fluid percussion brain injury in the rat causes cumulative long-term behavioral impairments, neuroinflammation, and cortical loss in an animal model of repeated concussion. Journal of neurotrauma. 2012 Jan;29(2):281&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21933013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osier ND, Dixon CE. The controlled cortical impact model: applications, considerations for researchers, and future directions. Frontiers in neurology. 2016 Aug;7:134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4987613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27582726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;nzel T, Gori T. Nebivolol: the somewhat-different &#x3b2;-adrenergic receptor blocker. Journal of the American College of Cardiology. 2009 Oct;54(16):1491&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19815121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dursun S, &#xc7;uhadar S, K&#xf6;seoglu M, Atay A, Aktas SG. The anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effects of pravastatin and nebivolol in rat aorta. The Anatolian Journal of Cardiology. 2014 May;14(3):229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24936540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ungvari Z, Bailey-Downs L, Gautam T, Jimenez R, Losonczy G, Zhang C, Ballabh P, Recchia FA, Wilkerson DC, Sonntag WE, Pearson K. Adaptive induction of NF-E2-related factor-2-driven antioxidant genes in endothelial cells in response to hyperglycemia. American Journal of Physiology-Heart and Circulatory Physiology. 2011 Apr;300(4):H1133&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3075025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21217061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GRAHAM Neil, SHARP SN, David J. Understanding neurodegeneration after traumatic brain injury: from mechanisms to clinical trials in dementia. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry .2019;90(11):1221&#x2013;1233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6860906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31542723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EARLY A, Alexandria N, et al. Effects of advanced age upon astrocyte-specific responses to acute traumatic brain injury in mice. Journal of Neuroinflammation. 2020 :1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7158022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32290848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x11f;uzo&#x11f;lu AS, &#x15e;enol N, Doguc D, Ta&#x15f;an &#x15e;, Erzurumlu Y, A&#x15f;c&#x131; H. The Effect of Nebivolol on Acute Brain Damage in a Rat Model of Lps-Induced Inflammation. Medical Journal of S&#xfc;leyman Demirel University. 2025 Mar;:32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pessina A C. Metabolic effects and safety profile of nebivolol. Journal of cardiovascular pharmacology . 38(Suppl 3):2001&#x2013;S33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11811391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metineren Hasan, et al. &#x201c;Effect of nebivolol on fracture healing: An experimental rat model. Advances in clinical and experimental medicine : official organ Wroclaw Medical University . 2017;26 :919&#x2013;923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29068591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadrhaghighi G, Abbaszadeh S, Babataheri S, Garjani A, Soraya H. Effects of pre-treatment with metoprolol and diltiazem on cerebral ischemia/reperfusion-induced injuries. Brazilian Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences. 2022;58:e21086.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Ma L, Habibi J, Whaley-Connell A, Hayden MR, Tilmon RD, Brown AN, Kim JA, DeMarco VG, Sowers JR. Nebivolol improves diastolic dysfunction and myocardial remodeling through reductions in oxidative stress in the Zucker obese rat. Hypertension. 2010 Apr;55(4):880&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2841702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20176997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go&#x15b;ciniak A, Stasi&#x142;owicz-Krzemie&#x144; A, Michniak-Kohn B, Fiedor P, Cielecka-Piontek J. One Molecule, Many Faces: Repositioning Cardiovascular Agents for Advanced Wound Healing. Molecules. 2024 Jun;29(12):2938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11206936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38931002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evanson NK, Veldhi P, Scherpenberg C, Riccobono JM, Eid H, McGuire JL. Extracranial effects of traumatic brain injury: A narrative review. Clinics and Practice. 2025 Feb;15(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11941004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40136583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinoshita K. Traumatic brain injury: pathophysiology for neurocritical care. Journal of intensive care. 2016 Apr;4(1):29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4847183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27123305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troost R, et al. Nebivolol decreases systemic oxidative stress in healthy volunteers. British journal of clinical pharmacology. 2000;50(4): 377&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2014994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11012562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Groot AA, et al. ,Antioxidant activity of nebivolol in the rat aorta. Journal of cardiovascular pharmacology. 2004;43(1): 148&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14668581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason, R.P, et al. Effect of nebivolol on endothelial nitric oxide and peroxynitrite release in hypertensive animals: role of antioxidant activity. Journal of cardiovascular pharmacology, 2006. 48. Journal of cardiovascular pharmacology. 2006;48(1): 862&#x2013;869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16891916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garb&#xe1;n H.J. Estrogen receptor-mediated vascular responsiveness to nebivolol: a novel endothelium-related mechanism of therapeutic vasorelaxation. Journal of cardiovascular pharmacology. 2004;43(5): 638&#x2013;644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15071350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grundt C, et al. Evidence for an estradiol-agonistic action of nebivolol in spontaneously hypertensive rats. Journal of hypertension. 2007; 25(5): 1001&#x2013;1007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17414664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Segura L.M. Neuroprotection by estradiol. Progress in neurobiology, 2001;63(1): 29&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11040417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azcoitia I. Doncarlos, and L.M. Garcia-Segura, Estrogen and brain vulnerability. Neurotoxicity research. 2002;(4):235&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12829404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manthey D M, Gamerdinger C. The selective &#x3b2;1&#x2010;adrenoceptor antagonist nebivolol is a potential oestrogen receptor agonist with neuroprotective abilities. British journal of pharmacology. 2010;159(6): 1264&#x2013;1273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2848930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20128815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhadri N R. Nebivolol, a &#x3b2;-blocker abrogates streptozotocin-induced behavioral, biochemical, and neurophysiological deficit by attenuating oxidative-nitrosative stress: a possible target for the prevention of diabetic neuropathy. Naunyn-Schmiedeberg's archives of pharmacology, 2018;391(2): 207&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29322226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evanson NK, Veldhi P, Scherpenberg C, Riccobono JM, Eid H, McGuire JL. Extracranial effects of traumatic brain injury: A narrative review. Clinics and Practice. 2025 Feb;15(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11941004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40136583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasouli HR, Mohammadian Salim M, Talebi S, Eslamian M, Ahmadpour F. The efficacy of buprenorphine on moderate traumatic brain injury in the rat model. Neurological Research. 2023 Nov;45(11):1055&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37695813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>