<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41865658</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-2793</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>162</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nurse education today</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nurse Educ Today</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Surviving the tsunami of an ageing academic workforce: Mentorship for the next generation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>107082</StartPage><MedlinePgn>107082</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nedt.2026.107082</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0260-6917(26)00110-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The Australian nursing academic workforce is undergoing a significant demographic shift, characterised by accelerated retirement and departure of senior academics. This trend threatens continuity of mentorship, academic leadership, and institutional knowledge, with potential implications for early- and mid-career nurse academics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To explore nurse academics' lived experiences of senior mentorship loss and to examine perceived impacts on induction, workload, role clarity, succession planning, and resilience within a regional university context.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">A qualitative study informed by a hermeneutic phenomenological orientation, an interpretive approach concerned with understanding meaning derived from lived experience.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Three face-to-face focus groups were conducted with early- and mid-career nurse academics (3 groups; N&#xa0;=&#xa0;15; n&#xa0;=&#xa0;5 per group) at a regional Australian university. Data were analysed using reflexive thematic analysis following Braun and Clarke's six-phase analytic process to identify shared patterns of meaning across participants' accounts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Five themes were identified: (1) Loss of Institutional Knowledge and Mentorship; (2) Inadequate Induction and Orientation Processes; (3) Workload Intensification and Role Ambiguity Following Senior Academic Loss; (4) Organisational Gaps in Succession Planning and Communication; and (5) Strategies for Recovery, Retention, and Resilience. Participants described emotional and professional strain associated with mentorship voids, unclear expectations, increased invisible workload, and inconsistent organisational responses during workforce transition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The findings underscore mentorship as a critical element of academic sustainability and highlight limitations in existing induction, workload, and knowledge-transfer systems during periods of senior workforce attrition. Strengthening formalised and integrated mentorship and succession-support mechanisms may assist nursing education leaders to enhance retention, professional identity, and workforce resilience.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moloney</LastName><ForeName>Clint</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing and Midwifery, University of Southern Queensland, Toowoomba, Queensland, Australia; Centre for Health Research, University of Southern Queensland, Toowoomba, Queensland, Australia. Electronic address: clint.moloney@unisq.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Issac</LastName><ForeName>Hancy</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, Nursing, Southern Cross University, Gold Coast, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roderick</LastName><ForeName>Geraldine</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing and Midwifery, University of Southern Queensland, Toowoomba, Queensland, Australia; Centre for Health Research, University of Southern Queensland, Toowoomba, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Scotland</Country><MedlineTA>Nurse Educ Today</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8511379</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0260-6917</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Academic retention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Institutional knowledge loss</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mentorship</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing academia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Succession planning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Workforce sustainability</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41865658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nedt.2026.107082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0260-6917(26)00110-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>