<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41744287</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2865</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physiotherapy research international : the journal for researchers and clinicians in physical therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Physiother Res Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integrating Non-Invasive Brain Stimulation With Post-Stroke Rehabilitation: A Systematized Review of Synergistic Neuroplasticity Based Interventions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70179</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70179</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/pri.70179</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Physiotherapy promotes experience-dependent neuroplasticity after stroke; however, recovery often plateaus despite intensive training. Non-invasive brain stimulation (NIBS) may enhance cortical excitability and increase responsiveness to motor practice, but the extent of synergistic benefit remains unclear. This systematic review aimed to evaluate randomized controlled trials (RCTs) integrating physiotherapy with NIBS and to determine whether combined interventions improve motor, gait, hand, and cognitive outcomes compared with physiotherapy alone or sham stimulation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A PRISMA-guided search was conducted across six databases from inception to August 2025, identifying RCTs that combined physiotherapy with NIBS modalities including transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS), transcranial alternating current stimulation (tACS), repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS), and transcranial spinal direct current stimulation (tsDCS). Risk of bias was assessed using the Cochrane RoB 2 tool and the PEDro scale. Owing to substantial heterogeneity, a meta-analysis was not feasible and findings were synthesized narratively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Fifteen RCTs involving 440 participants were included. Combined NIBS-physiotherapy interventions produced heterogeneous but generally favorable improvements, with stronger effects observed when anodal tDCS was delivered concurrently with high-intensity, task-specific rehabilitation such as robotic therapy, modified constraint-induced movement therapy, or virtual-reality-based training. Gait-related improvements were more consistent in individuals with chronic stroke undergoing robot-assisted or treadmill-based training, whereas trials in subacute stroke reported mixed results. Multisite neuromodulation approaches, including combined cortical and spinal stimulation or peripheral nerve stimulation, have demonstrated promising but preliminary effects, and few studies have reported mechanistic neurophysiological biomarkers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Overall, the findings indicate that NIBS is most effective when functioning as a cortical "primer" during intensive, task-specific physiotherapy, with benefits influenced by stroke chronicity, behavioral context, and stimulation parameters. Future studies should prioritize standardized protocols, mechanistic biomarkers, and stratified trial designs to optimize clinical translation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ravichandran</LastName><ForeName>Hariharasudhan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0703-9675</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Alva's College of Physiotherapy and Research Centre, Moodbidri, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shetty</LastName><ForeName>Kshama Susheel</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1479-4983</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Alva's College of Physiotherapy and Research Centre, Moodbidri, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lingadahalli</LastName><ForeName>Bhavana</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-3157-4731</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Alva's College of Physiotherapy and Research Centre, Moodbidri, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meethal</LastName><ForeName>Anjana Uthroth</ForeName><Initials>AU</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-5466-2584</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Alva's College of Physiotherapy and Research Centre, Moodbidri, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Physiother Res Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9612022</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1358-2267</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gait</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroplasticity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non&#x2010;invasive brain stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">robotic rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stroke rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">upper limb function</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41744287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pri.70179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Ballester, B. R., M. Maier, A. Duff, et&#xa0;al. 2019. &#x201c;A Critical Time Window for Recovery Extends Beyond One&#x2010;Year Post&#x2010;Stroke.&#x201d; Journal of Neurophysiology 122, no. 1: 350&#x2013;357. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00762.2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson, B., A. Bhattacharya, C. Sarica, et&#xa0;al. 2024. &#x201c;Neuromodulation Techniques&#x2014;From Non&#x2010;Invasive Brain Stimulation to Deep Brain Stimulation.&#x201d; Neurotherapeutics: The Journal of the American Society for Experimental Neuro Therapeutics 21, no. 3: e00330. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neurot.2024.e00330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodderi, T., D. M. N. Chua, K. M. Chan, R. K. Balasubramanium, and M. Kothari. 2025. &#x201c;Principles of Neural Plasticity and Motor Learning in Swallowing Exercise Protocols for Older Adults: A Mapping Review.&#x201d; International Journal of Speech Language Pathology: 1&#x2013;19: Advance online publication. https://doi.org/10.1080/17549507.2025.2573336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donkor, E. S. 2018. &#x201c;Stroke in the 21st Century: A Snapshot of the Burden, Epidemiology, and Quality of Life.&#x201d; Stroke Research and Treatment 2018: 3238165. https://doi.org/10.1155/2018/3238165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evancho, A., W. J. Tyler, and K. McGregor. 2023. &#x201c;A Review of Combined Neuromodulation and Physical Therapy Interventions for Enhanced Neurorehabilitation.&#x201d; Frontiers in Human Neuroscience 17: 1151218. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2023.1151218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigin, V. L., M. Brainin, B. Norrving, et&#xa0;al. 2025. &#x201c;World Stroke Organization: Global Stroke Fact Sheet 2025.&#x201d; International Journal of Stroke: official journal of the International Stroke Society 20, no. 2: 132&#x2013;144. https://doi.org/10.1177/17474930241308142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fusco, A., F. Assenza, M. Iosa, et&#xa0;al. 2014. &#x201c;The Ineffective Role of Cathodal Tdcs in Enhancing the Functional Motor Outcomes in Early Phase of Stroke Rehabilitation: An Experimental Trial.&#x201d; BioMed Research International 2014: 547290&#x2013;547299. https://doi.org/10.1155/2014/547290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganguly, K., P. Khanna, R. J. Morecraft, and D. J. Lin. 2022. &#x201c;Modulation of Neural Co&#x2010;Firing to Enhance Network Transmission and Improve Motor Function After Stroke.&#x201d; Neuron 110, no. 15: 2363&#x2013;2385. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2022.06.024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gazerani, P. 2025. &#x201c;The Neuroplastic Brain: Current Breakthroughs and Emerging Frontiers.&#x201d; Brain Research 1858: 149643. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2025.149643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geroin, C., A. Picelli, D. Munari, A. Waldner, C. Tomelleri, and N. Smania. 2011. &#x201c;Combined Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation and Robot&#x2010;Assisted Gait Training in Patients With Chronic Stroke: A Preliminary Comparison.&#x201d; Clinical Rehabilitation 25, no. 6: 537&#x2013;548. https://doi.org/10.1177/0269215510389497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaberzadeh, S., M. Malekahmad, R. Liu, and M. Zoghi. 2025. &#x201c;Effects of a Single Session 400 Hz Transcranial Pulsed Current Stimulation on Corticospinal and Corticocortical Excitability and Hand Dexterity: A Double&#x2010;Blind RCT.&#x201d; Psychophysiology 62, no. 7: e70112. https://doi.org/10.1111/psyp.70112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kesikburun, S. 2022. &#x201c;Non&#x2010;Invasive Brain Stimulation in Rehabilitation.&#x201d; Turkish journal of physical medicine and rehabilitation 68, no. 1: 1&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.5606/tftrd.2022.10608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko, M. H., J. Y. Yoon, Y. J. Jo, et&#xa0;al. 2022. &#x201c;Home&#x2010;Based Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation to Enhance Cognition in Stroke: Randomized Controlled Trial.&#x201d; Stroke 53, no. 10: 2992&#x2013;3001. https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.121.037629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuipers, J. A., N. H. Hoffman, F. R. Carrick, and M. Jemni. 2025. &#x201c;Reconnecting Brain Networks After Stroke: A Scoping Review of Conventional, Neuromodulatory, and Feedback&#x2010;Driven Rehabilitation Approaches.&#x201d; Brain Sciences 15, no. 11: 1217. https://doi.org/10.3390/brainsci15111217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang, C. E., K. J. Waddell, J. Barth, C. L. Holleran, M. J. Strube, and M. D. Bland. 2021. &#x201c;Upper Limb Performance in Daily Life Approaches Plateau Around Three to Six Weeks Post&#x2010;Stroke.&#x201d; Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair 35, no. 10: 903&#x2013;914. https://doi.org/10.1177/15459683211041302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langhorne, P., O. Wu, H. Rodgers, A. Ashburn, and J. Bernhardt. 2017. &#x201c;A Very Early Rehabilitation Trial After Stroke (AVERT): A Phase III, Multicentre, Randomised Controlled Trial.&#x201d; Health Technology Assessment 21, no. 54: 1&#x2013;120. https://doi.org/10.3310/hta21540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon, D., M. Cortes, J. Elder, et&#xa0;al. 2017. &#x201c;Tdcs Does Not Enhance the Effects of Robot&#x2010;Assisted Gait Training in Patients With Subacute Stroke.&#x201d; Restorative Neurology and Neuroscience 35, no. 4: 377&#x2013;384. https://doi.org/10.3233/RNN&#x2010;170734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, D. J., S. C. Cramer, P. Boyne, P. Khatri, and J. W. Krakauer. 2025. &#x201c;High&#x2010;Dose, High&#x2010;Intensity Stroke Rehabilitation: Why Aren'T we Giving It?&#x201d; Stroke 56, no. 5: 1351&#x2013;1364. https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.124.043650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maier, M., B. R. Ballester, and P. F. M. J. Verschure. 2019. &#x201c;Principles of Neurorehabilitation After Stroke Based on Motor Learning and Brain Plasticity Mechanisms.&#x201d; Frontiers in Systems Neuroscience 13: 74. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnsys.2019.00074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manji, A., K. Amimoto, T. Matsuda, Y. Wada, A. Inaba, and S. Ko. 2018. &#x201c;Effects of Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation over the Supplementary Motor Area Body Weight&#x2010;Supported Treadmill Gait Training in Hemiparetic Patients After Stroke.&#x201d; Neuroscience Letters 662: 302&#x2013;305. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2017.10.049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naro, A., A. Bramanti, A. Leo, et&#xa0;al. 2017. &#x201c;Effects of Cerebellar Transcranial Alternating Current Stimulation on Motor Cortex Excitability and Motor Function.&#x201d; Brain Structure and Function 222, no. 6: 2891&#x2013;2906. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429&#x2010;016&#x2010;1355&#x2010;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochi, M., S. Saeki, T. Oda, Y. Matsushima, and K. Hachisuka. 2013. &#x201c;Effects of Anodal and Cathodal Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation Combined With Robotic Therapy on Severely Affected Arms in Chronic Stroke Patients.&#x201d; Journal of Rehabilitation Medicine 45, no. 2: 137&#x2013;140. https://doi.org/10.2340/16501977&#x2010;1099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, A. S., and B. Thompson. 2024. &#x201c;Non&#x2010;Invasive Brain Stimulation and Vision Rehabilitation: A Clinical Perspective.&#x201d; Clinical and Experimental Optometry 107, no. 6: 594&#x2013;602. https://doi.org/10.1080/08164622.2024.2349565.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul, T., M. Cieslak, L. Hensel, et&#xa0;al. 2022. &#x201c;The Role of Corticospinal and Extrapyramidal Pathways in Motor Impairment After Stroke.&#x201d; Brain communications 5, no. 1: fcac301. https://doi.org/10.1093/braincomms/fcac301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picelli, A., E. Chemello, P. Castellazzi, et&#xa0;al. 2015. &#x201c;Combined Effects of Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation (Tdcs) and Transcutaneous Spinal Direct Current Stimulation (tsDCS) on Robot&#x2010;Assisted Gait Training in Patients With Chronic Stroke: A Pilot, Double Blind, Randomized Controlled Trial.&#x201d; Restorative Neurology and Neuroscience 33, no. 3: 357&#x2013;368. https://doi.org/10.3233/RNN&#x2010;140474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi, S., L. Cao, Q. Wang, Y. Sheng, J. Yu, and Z. Liang. 2024. &#x201c;The Physiological Mechanisms of Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation to Enhance Motor Performance: A Narrative Review.&#x201d; Biology 13, no. 10: 790. https://doi.org/10.3390/biology13100790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha, S., E. Silva, &#xc1;. Foerster, et&#xa0;al. 2016. &#x201c;The Impact of Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation (tDCS) Combined With Modified Constraint&#x2010;Induced Movement Therapy (mCIMT) on Upper Limb Function in Chronic Stroke: A Double&#x2010;Blind Randomized Controlled Trial.&#x201d; Disability &amp; Rehabilitation 38, no. 7: 653&#x2013;660. https://doi.org/10.3109/09638288.2015.1055382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sattler, V., B. Acket, N. Raposo, et&#xa0;al. 2015. &#x201c;Anodal tDCS Combined With Radial Nerve Stimulation Promotes Hand Motor Recovery in the Acute Phase After Ischemic Stroke.&#x201d; Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair 29, no. 8: 743&#x2013;754. https://doi.org/10.1177/1545968314565465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo, H. G., W. H. Lee, S. H. Lee, Y. Yi, K. D. Kim, and B. M. Oh. 2017. &#x201c;Robotic&#x2010;Assisted Gait Training Combined With Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation in Chronic Stroke Patients: A Pilot Double&#x2010;Blind, Randomized Controlled Trial.&#x201d; Restorative Neurology and Neuroscience 35, no. 5: 527&#x2013;536. https://doi.org/10.3233/RNN&#x2010;170745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, H., V. Y. Vishnu, N. Kumar, et&#xa0;al. 2020. &#x201c;Efficacy of Low&#x2010;Frequency Repetitive Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation in Ischemic Stroke: A Double&#x2010;Blind Randomized Controlled Trial.&#x201d; Archives of rehabilitation research and clinical translation 2, no. 1: 100039. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arrct.2020.100039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, Q. R., M. T. Hu, W. Feng, K. P. Li, and W. Wang. 2022. &#x201c;Narrative Review of Noninvasive Brain Stimulation in Stroke Rehabilitation.&#x201d; Medical Science Monitor: International Medical Journal of Experimental and Clinical Research 28: e938298. https://doi.org/10.12659/MSM.938298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straudi, S., F. Fregni, C. Martinuzzi, C. Pavarelli, S. Salvioli, and N. Basaglia. 2016. &#x201c;tDCS and Robotics on Upper Limb Stroke Rehabilitation: Effect Modification by Stroke Duration and Type of Stroke.&#x201d; BioMed Research International 2016: 5068127&#x2013;5068128. https://doi.org/10.1155/2016/5068127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, S. E. D., D. Levenstein, B. Li, et&#xa0;al. 2024. &#x201c;Synaptic Homeostasis Transiently Leverages Hebbian Mechanisms for a Multiphasic Response to Inactivity.&#x201d; Cell Reports 43, no. 4: 113839. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2024.113839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triccas, L. T., J. H. Burridge, A. Hughes, G. Verheyden, M. Desikan, and J. Rothwell. 2015. &#x201c;A Double&#x2010;Blinded Randomised Controlled Trial Exploring the Effect of Anodal Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation and Uni&#x2010;Lateral Robot Therapy for the Impaired Upper Limb in Sub&#x2010;Acute and Chronic Stroke.&#x201d; NeuroRehabilitation 37, no. 2: 181&#x2013;191. https://doi.org/10.3233/NRE&#x2010;151251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, X., L. Cui, J. Wang, W. Feng, Y. Bao, and Q. Xie. 2020. &#x201c;Effects of Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation With Virtual Reality on Upper Limb Function in Patients With Ischemic Stroke: A Randomized Controlled Trial.&#x201d; Journal of NeuroEngineering and Rehabilitation 17, no. 1: 73. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12984&#x2010;020&#x2010;00699&#x2010;x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye, Q., X. Wang, T. Li, J. Xu, and X. Ye. 2025. &#x201c;Clinical Efficacy of NIBS in Enhancing Neuroplasticity for Stroke Recovery.&#x201d; Journal of Neuroscience Methods 417: 110399. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneumeth.2025.110399.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>