<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41642342</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1618-2650</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Analytical and bioanalytical chemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Anal Bioanal Chem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Supramolecular solvents based on deep eutectic solvents and hexafluorobutanol for the extraction of aristolochic acids from natural plants.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00216-026-06357-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In this study, a new liquid phase microextraction method was developed by combining micelle-mediated extraction of aristolochic acids (AAs) in traditional Chinese medicines with polyfluorinated alcohol solutions, and subsequent preconcentration via deep eutectic solvent (DES)-induced supramolecular solvent (SUPRAS) formation. The preparation of SUPRASs with polyfluorinated alcohols functioning as amphiphiles and the DESs acting as coacervation agents is demonstrated for the first time. Different polyfluorinated alcohols and DESs were examined for the extraction and preconcentration of AAs. The SUPRAS prepared from hexafluorobutanol (HFB) and a DES based on (1) octanol:(2) fenchyl alcohol achieved the highest extraction efficiency. Compared to traditionally used surfactants such as octanol, octanoic acid, and octylamine, HFB exhibited better extraction efficiency of AAs. The optimized method provided good linearity in the range of 0.14-500&#xa0;&#xb5;g&#xa0;g<sup>-1</sup> for AA-I and 0.1-600&#xa0;&#xb5;g&#xa0;g<sup>-1</sup> for AA-II with determination coefficients higher than 0.9961. The limits of detection were 0.03-0.04&#xa0;&#xb5;g&#xa0;g<sup>-1</sup>, which were lower than those of the limits stipulated by the Chinese Pharmacopoeia (0.001%, w/w). The extraction recoveries ranged between 89.2 and 107.8%. The conventional methods for extracting analytes from solid samples typically involve an initial extraction phase utilizing hazardous organic solvents. The developed method can be applied to extract and preconcentrate a wide range of trace analytes from different solid samples by eliminating the need for harmful organic solvents. The developed method is efficient and reliable and can be applied to determine AAs in natural plants.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH, DE part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Wenxu</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering, Yunnan Open University, Kunming, 650504, Yunnan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Kunming University, Kunming, 650214, Yunnan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ge</LastName><ForeName>Dandan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5827-7454</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering, Yunnan Open University, Kunming, 650504, Yunnan, China. dandangeiris@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Feie</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering, Yunnan Open University, Kunming, 650504, Yunnan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Kunming University, Kunming, 650214, Yunnan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Chunyan</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering, Yunnan Open University, Kunming, 650504, Yunnan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weng</LastName><ForeName>Zhehui</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering, Yunnan Open University, Kunming, 650504, Yunnan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Yao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering, Yunnan Open University, Kunming, 650504, Yunnan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2025Y1060</GrantID><Agency>Education Department Project of Yunnan Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>202101BA070001-051</GrantID><Agency>Special Basic Cooperative Research Programs of Yunnan Provincial Undergraduate Universities' Association</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>202301BA070001-020</GrantID><Agency>Special Basic Cooperative Research Programs of Yunnan Provincial Undergraduate Universities' Association</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Anal Bioanal Chem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101134327</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1618-2642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aristolochic acids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep eutectic solvent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hexafluorobutanol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High-performance liquid chromatography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Supramolecular solvent</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41642342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00216-026-06357-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00216-026-06357-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Xu Y, Lin Y, Niu J, Gao X, Wang W, Qian S. Development of chemiluminescent enzyme immunoassay for the detection of aristolochic acid I in patent medicines and cosmetics. Toxicon. 2025;260:108362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40239745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.toxicon.2025.108362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y, Wu Y-W, Shen Q-X, Cao J. Targeted metabolomics assisted rapid screening and characterization of aristolochic acids and their DNA adducts in Aristolochia plants by ultra-high performance liquid chromatography coupled with ion mobility quadrupole time-of-flight mass spectrometry. J Chromatogr A. 2024;1734:465317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39216282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chroma.2024.465317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu H, Chen G, Wang L, Cui X, Wang Q, Li W, Chang C, Guo Q, Luo Z, Fu Q. Adenine-coated magnetic multiwalled carbon nanotubes for the selective extraction of aristolochic acids based on multiple interactions. J Chromatogr A. 2020;1627:461382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32823094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chroma.2020.461382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng R, Mao X, Yu J, Liu F, Guo L, Luo D, Wan Y. A dispersive solid-phase extraction method for the determination of Aristolochic acids in Houttuynia cordata based on MIL-101(Fe): an analytes-oriented adsorbent selection design. Food Chem. 2023;407:135074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36493489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2022.135074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Zhang Y, Lan A, Li M, Xia M, Huang C, Lou D. Aristolochic acid I abnormally activates the wnt7b/&#x3b2;-catenin signaling pathway and affects the repair of renal tubules. Chem-Biol Interact. 2025;408:111413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39921188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cbi.2025.111413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komatsu M, Funakoshi T, Aki T, Unuma K. Aristolochic acid-induced DNA adduct formation triggers acute DNA damage response in rat kidney proximal tubular cells. Toxicol Lett. 2025;406:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39955082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.toxlet.2025.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Chan CK, Wong YL, Chan KK, Chan HW, Chan W. Cooking methods employing natural anti-oxidant food additives effectively reduced concentration of nephrotoxic and carcinogenic aristolochic acids in contaminated food grains. Food Chem. 2018;264:270&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29853376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2018.05.052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jelakovi&#x107; B, Dika &#x17d;, Arlt VM, Stiborova M, Pavlovi&#x107; NM, Nikoli&#x107; J, Colet J-M, Vanherweghem JL, Nortier JL. Balkan endemic nephropathy and the causative role of aristolochic acid. Semin Nephrol. 2019;39:284&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31054628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semnephrol.2019.02.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukinich-Gruia AT, Nortier J, Pavlovi&#x107; NM, Milovanovi&#x107; D, Popovi&#x107; M, Dr&#x103;ghia LP, P&#x103;unescu V, Tatu CA. Aristolochic acid I as an emerging biogenic contaminant involved in chronic kidney diseases: a comprehensive review on exposure pathways, environmental health issues and future challenges. Chemosphere. 2022;297:134111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35231474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.134111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmeiser HH, Kucab JE, Arlt VM, Phillips DH, Hollstein M, Gluhovschi G, Velciov S. Evidence of exposure to aristolochic acid in patients with urothelial cancer from a Balkan endemic nephropathy region of Romania. Environ Mol Mutagen. 2012;53:636&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22987305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/em.21732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Q, Pei J, Poon J, Lau AY, Zhang L, Wang YH, Liu C, Huang LF. Worldwide research trends on aristolochic acids (1957-2017): suggestions for researchers. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(5):e0216135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31048858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6497264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0216135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji H, Zhang G, Zhou X. Rapid simultaneous determination of thirteen aristolochic acids analogs in Aristolochiaceae plants by ultra-high-performance liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry in dynamic multiple reaction monitoring mode. J Chromatogr B. 2023;1225:123753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jchromb.2023.123753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu X, Liu Y, Li W, Bai Y, Liao Y, Liu H. Determination of dissociation constants of aristolochic acid I and II by capillary electrophoresis with carboxymethyl chitosan-coated capillary. Talanta. 2011;85(1):813&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21645779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2011.03.088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J, Zheng Z, Jia Z, Wang J, Lin X. Multivariate surface self-assembly strategy to fabricate ionic covalent organic framework surface grafting monolithic sorbent for enrichment of aristolochic acids prior to high performance liquid chromatography analysis. J Chromatogr A. 2024;1713:464504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37979512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chroma.2023.464504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W, Shi Z, Zhang J, Zeng T, He Y, Cai Z. Analysis of aristolochic acid I in mouse serum and tissues by using magnetic solid-phase extraction and UHPLC-MS/MS. Talanta. 2021;235:122774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34517632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2021.122774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Li X, Yan X, Tian M. Solid-phase extraction of aristolochic acid I from natural plant using dual ionic liquid-immobilized ZIF-67 as sorbent. Separations. 2021;8(2):22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/separations8020022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afshar-Mogaddam M, Yadeghari A, Jouyban A. An overview on analytical methods for quantitative determination of aristolochic acids. Curr Anal Chem. 2020;16(5):533&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1573411014666180704124213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araya M, Garc&#xed;a S, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Teuber M. Rapid identification and simultaneous quantification of aristolochic acids by HPLC-DAD and confirmations by MS in Aristolochia chilensis using a limited biomass. J Anal Methods Chem. 2018;2018:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/5036542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong E-S, Woo S-O, Yong Y-L. Pressurized liquid extraction of berberine and aristolochic acids in medicinal plants. J Chromatogr A. 2000;904:57&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11209901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0021-9673(00)00914-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Wang M, Zhao J, Guo H, Gao X, Xiong Z, Zhao L. Ultrasound-assisted emulsification liquid phase microextraction method based on deep eutectic solvent as extraction solvent for determination of five pesticides in traditional Chinese medicine. J Pharm Biomed Anal. 2019;166:213&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30660036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpba.2019.01.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin W, Zhou T, Li G. Recent advances of modern sample preparation techniques for traditional Chinese medicines. J Chromatogr A. 2019;1606:460377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31358297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chroma.2019.460377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Y, Yang H, Li Z, Zhang W, Guo L, Zhang Y, Jiang Y. Intelligent transformation of ultrasound-assisted novel solvent extraction plant active ingredients: tools for machine learning and deep learning. Food Chem. 2025;486:144649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40349518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2025.144649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma S, Cai C, Lu Q, Tan Z. A review of green solvents for the extraction and separation of bioactive ingredients from natural products. Food Chem. 2025;478:143703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40054198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2025.143703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Chen J, Wang H, Wang X, Xiao Y. Hexafluoroisopropanol-alkanol based high-density supramolecular solvents: fabrication, characterization and application potential as restricted access extractants. Anal Chim Acta. 2020;1124:20&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32534672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aca.2020.05.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Z-F, Han X, Nie C-D, Yang H, Fu Y-J. A customizable CO<sub>2</sub>-responsive supramolecular solvent for the simultaneous extraction of multi-polar phytochemicals from plants. Microchem J. 2025;210:112959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.microc.2025.112959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tutar BK, Tutar &#xd6;F, Bodur S, Derin Y, Tutar A, Bak&#x131;rdere S. Determination of copper at trace levels in fennel tea samples by flame atomic absorption spectrometry after the implementation of simultaneous complexation and supramolecular solvent based spraying assisted liquid phase microextraction. J Food Compos Anal. 2025;137:106993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfca.2024.106993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed HEH, Kori AH, Gumus ZP, Soylak M. Supramolecular solvent-based liquid&#x2013;liquid microextraction (SUPRAS-LLME) of Sudan dyes from food and water samples with HPLC. Microchem J. 2024;201:110682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.microc.2024.110682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Wang X, Hong S, Zhou H, Cao X, Li K, Zhang Q, Yao C, Chen W, Li W, Song W, Rao Q. A novel approach based on supramolecular solvents microextraction for quick detection of perfluoroalkyl acids and their precursors in aquatic food. J Hazard Mater. 2024;480:136169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39418903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.136169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradi M, Yamini Y, Feizi N. Development and challenges of supramolecular solvents in liquid-based microextraction methods. Trends Anal Chem. 2021;138:116231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trac.2021.116231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurashov Y, Pochivalov A, Petrova A, Safonova E, Garmonov S, Bulatov A. Supramolecular solvents based on hydrophobic natural deep eutectic solvents and primary amines for preconcentration and determination of enrofloxacin in milk. Talanta. 2024;279:126666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39116727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2024.126666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Z-H, Wang J-D, Liu L, Ruan L-D, Gu Q, Yan X-Y, Fu L-N, Zhao P-Q, Zhang S, Fu Y-J. A green and designable natural deep eutectic solvent-based supramolecular solvents system: efficient extraction and enrichment for phytochemicals. Chem Eng J. 2023;457:141333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.141333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Z-H, Liu L, Gu Q, Wang J-D, Liu G-S, Zhou Q, Dong X-Y, Zhang S, Fu Y-J. Novel natural deep eutectic solvent-based supramolecular solvents designed for extracting phytochemicals from pigeon pea leaves and its scale-up and recovery process. Ind Crops Prod. 2023;204:117240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.indcrop.2023.117240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang P, Liang X, Wang Y, Gao L, Huang G, Wang J, Pan F. Novel polymer electrolytes for rechargeable magnesium batteries prepared based on deep eutectic solvents. Chem Eng J. 2025;512:162804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.162804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krekhova F, Lusnikova K, Melesova M, Shishov A, Bulatov A. Deep eutectic solvent-based extraction approach for separation of fluoroquinolones from soil and sediment followed by their chromatographic determination. Talanta. 2025;295:128345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40412195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2025.128345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu W, Yu Y, Weng Z, Huang Y, Li Y, Ge D. Supramolecular solvent for the vortex-assisted dispersive liquid&#x2013;liquid microextraction of aristolochic acids from Aristolochia debilis prior to HPLC-DAD. Microchem J. 2024;206:111608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.microc.2024.111608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moggi G, Pianca M, Russo S, Costa G. Fluoroalcohols as solvents for aliphatic polyamides. J Fluorine Chem. 1980;16:615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-1139(00)84117-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, Pai N, Chen X, Wang B, Gao S, Ge D. Hexafluorobutanol primary alcohol ethoxylate-based supramolecular solvent formation and their application in direct microextraction of malachite green and crystal violet from lake sediments. Anal Bioanal Chem. 2023;415:5353&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37389597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00216-023-04810-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spicher S, Grimme S. Robust atomistic modeling of materials, organometallic, and biochemical system. Angew Chem Int Ed Engl. 2020;59(36):15665&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32343883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7267649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202004239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bannwarth C, Caldeweyher E, Ehlert S, Hansen A, Pracht P, Seibert J, Spicher S, Grimme S. Extended tight-binding quantum chemistry methods. Wiley Interdiscip Rev Comput Mol Sci. 2021;11(2):e1493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wcms.1493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neese F. The ORCA program system. Wiley Interdiscip Rev Comput Mol Sci. 2012;2:73&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wcms.81</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud AR, Hebishy AMS, Moneim AEA, Abdelfattah MS. Preparation of a new ternary deep eutectic solvent for the green extraction of sulfated polysaccharides from Codium vermilara: a Box&#x2013;Behnken optimization study. J Mol Liq. 2025;439:128929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2025.128929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Z, Zhou Y, Zhang Y, Bai J, Wang J, Guo H, Chen Y. Ultrasonic-assisted deep eutectic solvent extraction: process optimization of cordycepin from Cordyceps sinensis and antioxidant activity evaluation. Microchem J. 2025;218:115681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.microc.2025.115681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banjare MK, Behera K, Rub MA, Ghosh KK. Micellization behavior of an imidazolium surface-active ionic liquid within aqueous solutions of deep eutectic solvents: a comparative spectroscopic study. RSC Adv. 2025;15(20):15879&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40370844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12076072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D5RA01940K</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vakh C, Yahya LA, Mako&#xb4;s-Che&#x142;stowska P, Tobiszewski M. Deep eutectic solvent-induced coacervation in micellar solution of alkyl polyglucoside surfactant: supramolecular solvent formation and application in food analysis. Talanta. 2025;292:127930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40101685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2025.127930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maliyakal J, Vadnere N, Bherje S, Patel M. Sustainability assessment of PDE-5 inhibitor analysis: a comparative study using AGREE, AGREEPrep, complex GAPI, and BAGI. Trends Environ Anal. 2025;47:e00273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.teac.2025.e00273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang ZH, Chen YZ, Guo B, Chen B, Ma M. Rapid determination of aristolochic acids in environmental water using ultrasonic-assisted dispersive liquid-liquid microextraction coupled with high performance liquid chromatography. Chin J Anal Chem. 2023;51:1793&#x2013;801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu H, Chen G, Wang L, Cui X, Luo Z, Jing W, Chang C, Zeng A, Zhang J, Fu Q. Metal-organic framework grafted with melamine for the selective recognition and miniaturized solid phase extraction of aristolochic acid &#x2160; from traditional Chinese medicine. J Chromatogr A. 2021;1647:462155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33957350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chroma.2021.462155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge Y, Guo P, Xu X, Chen G, Zhang X, Shu H, Zhang B, Luo Z, Chang C, Fu Q. Selective analysis of aristolochic acid I in herbal medicines by dummy molecularly imprinted solid-phase extraction and HPLC. J Sep Sci. 2017;40(13):2791&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28520091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jssc.201700116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang L, Tian M, Yan X, Xiao W, Row KH. Dual ionic liquid-immobilized silicas for multi-phase extraction of aristolochic acid from plants and herbal medicines. J Chromatogr A. 2019;1592:31&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30630617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chroma.2019.01.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu K, Zhang Z, Zhao D, Li L, Yang C, Zeng H, Zhang S, Zhang Z. Berberine-based hypercrosslinked polymer: advanced solid-phase microextraction for high-throughput analysis of aristolochic acids in environmental water and herbal plants. Talanta. 2025;285:127333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39673978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2024.127333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu H, Ge Y, Xu X, Guo P, Luo Z, Du W, Chang C, Liu R, Fu Q. Hybrid-type carbon microcoil-chitosan composite for selective extraction of aristolochic acid I from Aristolochiaceae medicinal plants. J Chromatogr A. 2018;1561:13&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29803429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chroma.2018.05.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Chen J, Qiu B, Zhou L, Liu R-Y, Huang J-F, He Y, Xie Q. Optimization of ultrasound-assisted deep eutectic solvents extraction of rutin from Ilex asprella using response surface methodology. Sci Rep. 2025;15:6205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39979528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11842778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-90536-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Wu P, Li Y, Zhang L, Zhou Y. Natural deep eutectic solvents as new green solvents to extract anthraquinones from Rheum palmatum L. RSC Adv. 2018;8:15069&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35541349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9079993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C7RA13581E</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>