<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41869243</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Conservative Management of Acute Anterior Cruciate Ligament Rupture in Recreational Athletes: A Pilot Case Series.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103860</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103860</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103860</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103860</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Surgical anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction (ACLR) remains the standard treatment for acute anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) rupture in highly active individuals but entails surgical risks, prolonged recovery, and incomplete return to sport in some cases. Conservative approaches enhanced with biologics, such as platelet-rich plasma (PRP) or autologous conditioned serum (ACS), have gained interest as potential alternatives in selected patients. This study aimed to describe ligament healing, clinical stability, and short-term return to sport in recreational athletes with acute ACL rupture treated conservatively with intra-articular PRP or ACS plus structured rehabilitation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This retrospective pilot case series included eight recreational athletes (four females, median age 32 years) with magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and clinically confirmed acute ACL rupture (&lt;4 weeks from trauma) who opted for non-operative care. All received four ultrasound-guided intra-articular injections of PRP (GPS III; Warsaw, IN: Zimmer Biomet) or ACS (Orthokine) over six weeks, followed by a standardized rehabilitation protocol. MRI evaluation at 21-24 weeks assessed ACL continuity (grade 0-3). Clinical assessment included the pivot-shift test graded according to the International Knee Documentation Committee (IKDC) grading system, instrumented Lachman testing, the Tegner Activity Scale (TAS), and the International Knee Documentation Committee (IKDC) score at 24 weeks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">MRI showed restored ACL continuity in all patients (grade 0 in 7/8; grade 1 in 1/8). Post-treatment pivot-shift testing showed grade 0 in 7/8 patients and grade 1 in 1/8 patients, while the Lachman test was negative in all patients. All patients returned to recreational sports within six months post-injury. No re-ruptures or complications were observed during a minimum six-month follow-up after return to sport.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study shows that intra-articular biologics (PRP or ACS) combined with structured rehabilitation were associated with MRI continuity, clinical stability, and safe return to sport at six months in recreational athletes with acute ACL rupture. This conservative treatment could be considered an alternative, and further investigation is warranted.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Balboa-Alonso et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Balboa-Alonso</LastName><ForeName>Mar&#xed;a</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency Medicine, University Hospital San Juan de Alicante, Alicante, ESP.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalo-Orden</LastName><ForeName>Jose-Manuel</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Animal Medicine and Surgery, University of Le&#xf3;n, Le&#xf3;n, ESP.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Corral-Fontecha</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiology, University Hospital of Le&#xf3;n, Le&#xf3;n, ESP.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gomez-Gonz&#xe1;lez</LastName><ForeName>Susana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Anthropology, University of Le&#xf3;n, Le&#xf3;n, ESP.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>D&#xed;az-G&#xe1;llego</LastName><ForeName>Luis</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics and Traumatology, University Hospital of Le&#xf3;n, Le&#xf3;n, ESP.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salvador-Mar&#xed;n</LastName><ForeName>Jorge</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics and Traumatology, Hospital General Universitario Dr. Balmis de Alicante, Alicante, ESP.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Balboa-Arregui</LastName><ForeName>Oscar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interventional Radiology, University Hospital of Le&#xf3;n, Le&#xf3;n, ESP.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autologous conditioned serum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">conservative treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mri</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">platelet-rich plasma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recreational athletes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41869243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13004635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Clinical practice. Anterior cruciate ligament tear. Spindler KP, Wright RW. N Engl J Med. 2008;359:2135&#x2013;2142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3782299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19005197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winner of the 2008 systematic review competition: knee osteoarthritis after anterior cruciate ligament injury. &#xd8;iestad BE, Engebretsen L, Storheim K, Risberg MA. Am J Sports Med. 2009;37:1434&#x2013;1443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19567666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High prevalence of knee osteoarthritis, pain, and functional limitations in female soccer players twelve years after anterior cruciate ligament injury. Lohmander LS, Ostenberg A, Englund M, Roos H. Arthritis Rheum. 2004;50:3145&#x2013;3152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15476248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Partial tearing of the anterior cruciate ligament: diagnosis and treatment. Temponi EF, de Carvalho J&#xfa;nior LH, Sonnery-Cottet B, Chambat P. Rev Bras Ortop. 2015;50:9&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4519562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26229890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Editorial commentary: technical advances in fixation for arthroscopic anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction won't take the place of good technique&#x2026;or a strong arm! Weiss WM. Arthroscopy. 2018;34:2675&#x2013;2676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30173807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surgical versus conservative interventions for anterior cruciate ligament ruptures in adults. Linko E, Harilainen A, Malmivaara A, Seitsalo S. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15846618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anterior cruciate ligament tears: conservative or surgical treatment? A critical review of the literature. Delinc&#xe9; P, Ghafil D. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2012;20:48&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21773828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Return to play of rugby players after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction using hamstring autograft: return to sports and graft failure according to age. Takazawa Y, Ikeda H, Saita Y, et al. Arthroscopy. 2017;33:181&#x2013;189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27514942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isolated partial rupture of the anterior cruciate ligament. Long-term follow-up of 56 cases. Bak K, Scavenius M, Hansen S, N&#xf8;rring K, Jensen KH, J&#xf8;rgensen U. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 1997;5:66&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9228310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Japanese Orthopaedic Association (JOA) clinical practice guidelines on the management of anterior cruciate ligament injury - secondary publication. Ishibashi Y, Adachi N, Koga H, Kondo E, Kuroda R, Mae T, Uchio Y. J Orthop Sci. 2020;25:6&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31843222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanosurgical and bioengineering treatment of human anterior cruciate ligament tears with ultrasound-guided injection of modified platelet-rich plasma using human cell memory based on clinical, ultrasound, MRI, and nanoscope analyses: a double-blind randomized trial. Wasilczyk C. J Clin Med. 2024;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11084372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38731004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Current concepts for anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a criterion-based rehabilitation progression. Adams D, Logerstedt DS, Hunter-Giordano A, Axe MJ, Snyder-Mackler L. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2012;42:601&#x2013;614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3576892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22402434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The long-term consequence of anterior cruciate ligament and meniscus injuries: osteoarthritis. Lohmander LS, Englund PM, Dahl LL, Roos EM. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35:1756&#x2013;1769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17761605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medial meniscus extrusion is directly correlated with medial tibial osteophyte in patients received reconstruction surgery for anterior cruciate ligament injury: a longitudinal study. Hada S, Kaneko H, Liu L, et al. Osteoarthr Cartil Open. 2022;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9718326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36474799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Partial anterior cruciate ligament tears treated with intraligamentary plasma rich in growth factors. Seijas R, Ares O, Cusc&#xf3; X, Alvarez P, Steinbacher G, Cugat R. World J Orthop. 2014;5:373&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4095032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25035842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The influence of locally applied platelet-derived growth factor-BB on free tendon graft remodeling after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Weiler A, F&#xf6;rster C, Hunt P, et al. Am J Sports Med. 2004;32:881&#x2013;891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15150033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction using biologic augmentation in patients 21 years of age and younger. Berdis AS, Veale K, Fleissner Jr PR. Arthroscopy. 2019;35:3107&#x2013;3113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31439458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conservative vs surgical treatment of anterior cruciate ligament rupture: a systematic review. Papaleontiou A, Poupard AM, Mahajan UD, Tsantanis P. Cureus. 2024;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11027445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38646275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collagen-platelet composite enhances biomechanical and histologic healing of the porcine anterior cruciate ligament. Joshi SM, Mastrangelo AN, Magarian EM, Fleming BC, Murray MM. Am J Sports Med. 2009;37:2401&#x2013;2410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2856313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19940313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonoperative choice of anterior cruciate ligament partial tear: ultrasound-guided platelet-rich plasma injection. You CK, Chou CL, Wu WT, Hsu YC. J Med Ultrasound. 2019;27:148&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6905270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31867179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leukocyte concentration and composition in platelet-rich plasma (PRP) influences the growth factor and protease concentrations. Kobayashi Y, Saita Y, Nishio H, et al. J Orthop Sci. 2016;21:683&#x2013;689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27503185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platelet-rich plasma: a milieu of bioactive factors. Boswell SG, Cole BJ, Sundman EA, Karas V, Fortier LA. Arthroscopy. 2012;28:429&#x2013;439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22284405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platelet-rich plasma in growth factors. A new door to regenerative medicine. Alcaraz-Rubio J, Oliver-Iguacel A, S&#xe1;nchez-L&#xf3;pez JM. https://www.medigraphic.com/cgi-bin/new/resumenI.cgi?IDREVISTA=280&amp;IDARTICULO=59346&amp;IDPUBLICACION=5912 Rev Hematol Mex. 2015;16:128&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conservative treatment using platelet-rich plasma for acute anterior cruciate ligament injuries in highly active patients: a retrospective survey. Hada S, Hada M, Yoshida K, Kaneko H, Saita Y, Kubota M, Ishijima M. Cureus. 2024;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10898500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38414705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Can platelet-rich plasma enhance anterior cruciate ligament and meniscal repair? Hutchinson ID, Rodeo SA, Perrone GS, Murray MM. J Knee Surg. 2015;28:19&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25101873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical and arthroscopic outcome of single bundle anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: comparison of remnant preservation versus conventional technique. Choi S, Kim MK, Kwon YS, Kang H. Knee. 2017;24:1025&#x2013;1032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28818360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans J, Mabrouk A, Nielson JL. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing; 2023. Anterior cruciate ligament knee injury.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29763023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lysholm score and Tegner activity level in individuals with normal knees. Briggs KK, Steadman JR, Hay CJ, Hines SL. Am J Sports Med. 2009;37:898&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19307332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The lateral pivot shift: a symptom and sign of anterior cruciate ligament insufficiency. Galway HR, MacIntosh DL. https://journals.lww.com/corr/citation/1980/03000/The_Lateral_Pivot_Shift__A_Symptom_and_Sign_of.8.aspx Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1980;147:45&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7371314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dynamic intraligamentary stabilization (DIS) for treatment of acute anterior cruciate ligament ruptures: case series experience of the first three years. Henle P, R&#xf6;der C, Perler G, Heitkemper S, Eggli S. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2015;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4341869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25813910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>