<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41896922</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1741-7015</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Motor-related reorganization in left inferior frontal gyrus after subcortical stroke: neurochemical basis and response to targeted neuromodulation.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12916-026-04810-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The left inferior frontal gyrus (IFG) is implicated in both language and motor processes. Its functional reorganization post-stroke, particularly in motor dysfunction without aphasia, remains poorly understood. We investigated effective connectivity (EC) alterations of the left IFG and their neurochemical basis, and responsiveness to neuromodulation in subcortical stroke.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Cross-sectional analysis included 32 left (LSS) and 27 right (RSS) stroke patients and 40 healthy controls (HCs). Seed-based EC of the left IFG was derived from resting-state fMRI and was compared between groups. Relationships between EC, neurotransmitter density, lesion-derived neurotransmitter indices, and Fugl-Meyer Assessment (FMA) scores were examined. Longitudinally, 30 patients received 14 sessions of cathodal-contralesional sensorimotor cortex (SMC), anodal-ipsilesional M1, or sham transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS), synchronized with upper limb training. Pre-post FMA and EC changes were compared.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Both LSS and RSS groups showed increased EC from the left IFG to the right cerebellum posterior lobe (CPL) and superior frontal gyrus (SFG), whereas only LSS group showed decreased EC from the left CPL to the left IFG. EC from the left IFG to the right CPL positively correlated with FMA, while EC from the left CPL to the left IFG negatively correlated with FMA in LSS. These EC alterations were significantly associated with serotonergic, dopaminergic, and GABAergic neurotransmitter densities. Crucially, IFG-to-SFG connectivity mediated the relationship between lesion-derived neurotransmitter network damage and lower-limb motor deficits. Longitudinal intervention revealed that different tDCS protocols distinctively modulated the left IFG's EC, with the most robust changes induced by cathodal stimulation of the contralesional SMC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Collectively, motor-related reorganization occurs in the left IFG post-stroke, characterized by altered EC patterns that are (1) correlated with motor performance, (2) underpinned by specific neurochemical systems, and (3) mediate post-stroke motor impairment. These reorganizations are plastic and respond specifically to targeted neuromodulation, highlighting the left IFG as a potential novel therapeutic target for motor recovery and informing personalized rehabilitation strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">All data used in the present study were obtained from the research trials registered on ClinicalTrials.gov (NCT05648552; submitted 5 December 2022) and www.chictr.org.cn (ChiCTR2100044970; submitted 3 April 2021).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hong</LastName><ForeName>Wenjun</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital, Affiliated Hospital of Medical School, Nanjing University, Nanjing, 210008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yaxi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital, Affiliated Hospital of Medical School, Nanjing University, Nanjing, 210008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital, Affiliated Hospital of Medical School, Nanjing University, Nanjing, 210008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Yanan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital, Affiliated Hospital of Medical School, Nanjing University, Nanjing, 210008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Zaixing</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital, Affiliated Hospital of Medical School, Nanjing University, Nanjing, 210008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Guanchun</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital, Affiliated Hospital of Medical School, Nanjing University, Nanjing, 210008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Rong</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital, Affiliated Hospital of Medical School, Nanjing University, Nanjing, 210008, China. xurong3973@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Zhiyong</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, National Clinical Research Center for Child Health, Hangzhou, 310003, China. zhaozhiyong_zju@zju.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Biomedical Engineering of Ministry of Education, Department of Biomedical Engineering, College of Biomedical Engineering &amp; Instrument Science, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, 310027, China. zhaozhiyong_zju@zju.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05648552</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>82002378</GrantID><Agency>Youth Program of the National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022-LCYJ-PY-27</GrantID><Agency>funding for Clinical Trials from the Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital, Affiliated Hospital of Medical School, Nanjing University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>YKK20068</GrantID><Agency>Medical Science and Technology Development Foundation, Nanjing Department of Health</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101190723</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1741-7015</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Motor function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurotransmitters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resting-state fMRI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stroke</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transcranial direct current stimulation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was approved by the Ethics Committee of Drum Tower Hospital, Nanjing University School of Medicine (approval number: 2022&#x2013;251-02, 2020&#x2013;381-02), and was conducted in accordance with the Helsinki Declaration. All participants provided written informed consent. Consent for publication: All authors have read the manuscript and provided consent for publication. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41896922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-026-04810-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12916-026-04810-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Go AS, Mozaffarian D, Roger VL, Benjamin EJ, Berry JD, Blaha MJ, et al. Heart disease and stroke statistics--2014 update: a report from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2014;129(3):e28&#x2013;92. https://doi.org/10.1161/01.cir.0000441139.02102.80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwakkel G, Kollen B, Twisk J. Impact of time on improvement of outcome after stroke. Stroke. 2006;37(9):2348&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonkhoff AK, Rehme AK, Hensel L, Tscherpel C, Volz LJ, Espinoza FA, et al. Dynamic connectivity predicts acute motor impairment and recovery post-stroke. Brain Commun. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1093/braincomms/fcab227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin S, Ferrante M, Bruera A, Hartwigsen G. Causal contributions of left inferior and medial frontal cortex to semantic and executive control. Commun Biol. 2025;8(1):1343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura D. Acquisition of a motor skill after left-hemisphere damage. Brain. 1977;100(3):527&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodale MA. Hemispheric differences in motor control. Behav Brain Res. 1988;30(2):203&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaum M, Pinzuti E, Sebastian A, Lieb K, Fries P, Mobascher A, et al. Right inferior frontal gyrus implements motor inhibitory control via beta-band oscillations in humans. Elife. 2021. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.61679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong W, Liu Z, Zhang X, Li M, Yu Z, Wang Y, et al. Distance-related functional reorganization predicts motor outcome in stroke patients. BMC Med. 2024;22(1):247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z. Resting-state functional abnormalities in ischemic stroke: a meta-analysis of fMRI studies. Brain Imaging Behav. 2024;18(6):1569&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liebrand M, Karabanov A, Antonenko D, Fl&#xf6;el A, Siebner HR, Classen J, et al. Beneficial effects of cerebellar tDCS on motor learning are associated with altered putamen-cerebellar connectivity: a simultaneous tDCS-fMRI study. Neuroimage. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2020.117363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz R, Buchholz A, Frey BM, B&#xf6;nstrup M, Cheng B, Thomalla G, et al. Enhanced effective connectivity between primary motor cortex and intraparietal sulcus in well-recovered stroke patients. Stroke. 2016;47(2):482&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ti C-HE, Hu C, Yuan K, Chu WC-W, Tong RK-Y. Uncovering the neural mechanisms of inter-hemispheric balance restoration in chronic stroke through EMG-driven robot hand training: insights from dynamic causal modeling. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng. 2024;32:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F, Chen C, Bai Z, Hong W, Wang S, Tang C. Specific subsystems of the inferior parietal lobule are associated with hand dysfunction following stroke: a cross&#x2010;sectional resting&#x2010;state fMRI study. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2022;28(12):2116&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F, Chen C, Hong W, Bai Z, Wang S, Lu H, et al. Selectively disrupted sensorimotor circuits in chronic stroke with hand dysfunction. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2022;28(5):677&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olafson E, Russello G, Jamison KW, Liu H, Wang D, Bruss JE, et al. Frontoparietal network activation is associated with motor recovery in ischemic stroke patients. Commun Biol. 2022;5(1):993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu S-P, Lu C-F, Lin B-F, Tang C-W, Kuo IJ, Tsai Y-A, et al. Effects of bihemispheric transcranial direct current stimulation on motor recovery in subacute stroke patients: a double-blind, randomized sham-controlled trial. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12984-023-01153-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar CA, Welsh JM, Lench D, Harmsen IE, Jensen JH, Grewal P, et al. Concurrent tDCS-fMRI after stroke reveals link between attention network organization and motor improvement. Sci Rep. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-70083-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Chen Y, Tu S, Lin J, Lin Y, Xu S, et al. Dual&#x2010;tDCS combined with sensorimotor training promotes upper limb function in subacute stroke patients: a randomized, double&#x2010;blinded, sham&#x2010;controlled study. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1111/cns.14530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves PN, Nozais V, Hansen JY, Corbetta M, Nachev P, Martins IP, et al. Neurotransmitters&#x2019; white matter mapping unveils the neurochemical fingerprints of stroke. Nat Commun. 2025;16(1):2555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch PJ, Frey BM, Backhaus W, Petersen N, Girard G, Wr&#xf3;bel PP, et al. Neurotransmitter-informed connectivity maps and their application for outcome inference after stroke. Brain. 2025;148(11):3935&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh JS, Choo YJ, Chang MC. Effect of selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors on motor recovery after stroke: a systematic meta-analysis. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2023;102(12):1097&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen JY, Shafiei G, Markello RD, Smart K, Cox SML, N&#xf8;rgaard M, et al. Mapping neurotransmitter systems to the structural and functional organization of the human neocortex. Nat Neurosci. 2022;25(11):1569&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Li M, Zhuang Y, Lin Z, Nie B, Lei J, et al. Combination of fMRI and PET reveals the beneficial effect of three-phase enriched environment on post-stroke memory deficits by enhancing plasticity of brain connectivity between hippocampus and peri-hippocampal cortex. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2024;30(3):e14466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Stephenson MC, Morris PG, Jackson SR. tDCS-induced alterations in GABA concentration within primary motor cortex predict motor learning and motor memory: a 7 T magnetic resonance spectroscopy study. Neuroimage. 2014;99:237&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel HJ, Romanzetti S, Pellicano A, Nitsche MA, Reetz K, Binkofski F. Proton magnetic resonance spectroscopy of the motor cortex reveals long term GABA change following anodal transcranial direct current stimulation. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):2807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi S, Cao L, Wang Q, Sheng Y, Yu J, Liang Z. The physiological mechanisms of transcranial direct current stimulation to enhance motor performance: a narrative review. Biology. 2024. https://doi.org/10.3390/biology13100790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friston KJ, Williams S, Howard R, Frackowiak RS, Turner R. Movement-related effects in fMRI time-series. Magn Reson Med. 1996;35(3):346&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seth AK, Chorley P, Barnett LC. Granger causality analysis of fMRI BOLD signals is invariant to hemodynamic convolution but not downsampling. Neuroimage. 2013;65:540&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao Z, Banaschewski T, Bokde ALW, Desrivi&#xe8;res S, Flor H, Grigis A, et al. Hemispheric asymmetry in cortical thinning reflects intrinsic organization of the neurotransmitter systems and homotopic functional connectivity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2023;120(42):e2306990120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diveica V, Riedel MC, Salo T, Laird AR, Jackson RL, Binney RJ. Graded functional organization in the left inferior frontal gyrus: evidence from task-free and task-based functional connectivity. Cereb Cortex. 2023;33(23):11384&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen KP, Person AL. Cerebellar circuit computations for predictive motor control. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2025;26(9):538&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dust J, Rice LC, Lee MM, Tegiacchi RF, Stoodley CJ. Cerebellar tDCS modulates corticocortical functional networks in a regionally specific manner. J Neurosci. 2026. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0499-25.2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramnani N. The primate cortico-cerebellar system: anatomy and function. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2006;7(7):511&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soleimani B, Dallasta I, Das P, Kulasingham JP, Girgenti S, Simon JZ, et al. Altered directional functional connectivity underlies post-stroke cognitive recovery. Brain Commun. 2023;5(3):fcad149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christidi F, Orgianelis I, Merkouris E, Koutsokostas C, Tsiptsios D, Karavasilis E, et al. A comprehensive review on the role of resting-state functional magnetic resonance imaging in predicting post-stroke motor and sensory outcomes. Neurol Int. 2024;16(1):189&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delion T, Jacquemont T, Daghsen L, Valabregue R, Beanato E, Hummel F, et al. Resting-state cortico-cerebellar connectivity correlates with post-stroke motor recovery - a prospective functional MRI study. Cerebellum. 2025;24(1):28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu P, Dong R, Wang X, Tang Y, Liu Y, Wang C, et al. Neuroimaging of motor recovery after ischemic stroke - functional reorganization of motor network. Neuroimage Clin. 2024;43:103636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos B, Choi H, DeMarco AT, Seydell-Greenwald A, Hussain SJ, Joy MT, et al. Rethinking remapping: circuit mechanisms of recovery after stroke. J Neurosci. 2023;43(45):7489&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huvermann DM, Berlijn AM, Thieme A, Erdlenbruch F, Groiss SJ, Deistung A, et al. The cerebellum contributes to prediction error coding in reinforcement learning in humans. J Neurosci. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1972-24.2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boven E, Pemberton J, Chadderton P, Apps R, Costa RP. Cerebro-cerebellar networks facilitate learning through feedback decoupling. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahshahani L, King M, Nettekoven C, Ivry RB, Diedrichsen J. Selective recruitment of the cerebellum evidenced by task-dependent gating of inputs. Elife. 2024. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.96386.3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pemberton J, Chadderton P, Costa RP. Cerebellar-driven cortical dynamics can enable task acquisition, switching and consolidation. Nat Commun. 2024;15(1):10913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harquel S, Cadic-Melchior A, Morishita T, Fleury L, Witon A, Ceroni M, et al. Stroke recovery-related changes in cortical reactivity based on modulation of intracortical inhibition. Stroke. 2024;55(6):1629&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okabe N, Wei X, Abumeri F, Batac J, Hovanesyan M, Dai W, et al. Parvalbumin interneurons regulate rehabilitation-induced functional recovery after stroke and identify a rehabilitation drug. Nat Commun. 2025;16(1):2556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang G, Chen P, Chen G, Yang Z, Ma W, Yan H, et al. Effects of bright light therapy on cingulate cortex dynamic functional connectivity and neurotransmitter activity in young adults with subthreshold depression. J Affect Disord. 2025;374:330&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manca R, De Marco M, Soininen H, Ruffini L, Venneri A. Changes in neurotransmitter-related functional connectivity along the Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease continuum. Brain Commun. 2025;7(1):fcaf008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Chen X, Cheng J, Wei F, Hou H, Li J, et al. Functional connectivity gradients and neurotransmitter maps among patients with mild cognitive impairment and depression symptoms. J Psychiatry Neurosci. 2025;50(1):E11&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari F, Gorini A, Hoyer S, Villa RF. Glutamate metabolism in cerebral mitochondria after ischemia and post&#x2010;ischemic recovery during aging: relationships with brain energy metabolism. J Neurochem. 2018;146(4):416&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertels H, Vicente-Ortiz G, El Kanbi K, Takeoka A. Neurotransmitter phenotype switching by spinal excitatory interneurons regulates locomotor recovery after spinal cord injury. Nat Neurosci. 2022;25(5):617&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fourneau J, Bareyre FM. Semaphorin7A: its role in the control of serotonergic circuits and functional recovery following spinal cord injury. Neural Regen Res. 2022;17(5):959&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pluta R, Januszewski S. Gut microbiota neurotransmitters: influence on risk and outcome of ischemic stroke. Neural Regen Res. 2022. https://doi.org/10.4103/1673-5374.363829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volpicelli F, Speranza L, di Porzio U, Crispino M, Perrone-Capano C. The serotonin receptor 7 and the structural plasticity of brain circuits. Front Behav Neurosci. 2014;8:318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speranza L, di Porzio U, Viggiano D, de Donato A, Volpicelli F. Dopamine: the neuromodulator of long-term synaptic plasticity, reward and movement control. Cells. 2021. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells10040735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daigle TL, Ferris MJ, Gainetdinov RR, Sotnikova TD, Urs NM, Jones SR, et al. Selective deletion of GRK2 alters psychostimulant-induced behaviors and dopamine neurotransmission. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2014;39(10):2450&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen D, Liu C, Wang F, Li P, Wei Z, Nie D, et al. Structure-function interrelationships and associated neurotransmitter profiles in drug-na&#xef;ve benign childhood epilepsy with central-temporal spikes patients. Eur Radiol. 2025;35(1):417&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Huang S, Yu X, Li L, Yang M, Liang S, et al. Altered thalamic neurotransmitters metabolism and functional connectivity during the development of chronic constriction injury induced neuropathic pain. Biol Res. 2020;53(1):36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Song X, &#xd6;ng&#xfc;r D, Du F. Association of default-mode network neurotransmitters and inter-network functional connectivity in first episode psychosis. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2023;48(5):781&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abboud R, Noronha C, Diwadkar VA. Motor system dysfunction in the schizophrenia diathesis: neural systems to neurotransmitters. Eur Psychiatry. 2020;44:125&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav D, Kumar P. Restoration and targeting of aberrant neurotransmitters in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease therapeutics. Neurochem Int. 2022. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuint.2022.105327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitsche MA, Kuo MF, Karrasch R, W&#xe4;chter B, Liebetanz D, Paulus W. Serotonin affects transcranial direct current-induced neuroplasticity in humans. Biol Psychiatry. 2009;66(5):503&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leow LA, Jiang J, Bowers S, Zhang Y, Dux PE, Filmer HL. Intensity-dependent effects of tDCS on motor learning are related to dopamine. Brain Stimul. 2024;17(3):553&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo L, Beaupain MC, Ghanavati E, Kuo MF, Nitsche MA. Neurochemical mechanisms underlying serotonergic modulation of neuroplasticity in humans. Brain Stimul. 2024;17(2):421&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo L, Mosayebi-Samani M, Ghanavati E, Nitsche MA, Kuo MF. Dosage-dependent impact of acute serotonin enhancement on transcranial direct current stimulation effects. Int J Neuropsychopharmacol. 2021;24(10):787&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonteneau C, Merida I, Redoute J, Haesebaert F, Lancelot S, Costes N, et al. Modulation of dopaminergic transmission and brain activity by frontotemporal tDCS: a multimodal PET-MR imaging study. Brain Stimul. 2025;18(4):1065&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hoornweder S, Vanderzande L, Bloemers E, Verstraelen S, Depestele S, Cuypers K, et al. The effects of transcranial direct current stimulation on upper-limb function post-stroke: a meta-analysis of multiple-session studies. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132(8):1897&#x2013;918.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juan D, Yao W, Li J, Yang F, Hu J, Xu Q, et al. Motor network reorganization after repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation in early stroke patients: a resting state fMRI study. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2022;36(1):61&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du J, Yang F, Hu J, Hu J, Xu Q, Cong N, et al. Effects of high- and low-frequency repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation on motor recovery in early stroke patients: evidence from a randomized controlled trial with clinical, neurophysiological and functional imaging assessments. Neuroimage Clin. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nicl.2018.101620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong W, Lin Q, Cui Z, Liu F, Xu R, Tang C. Diverse functional connectivity patterns of resting-state brain networks associated with good and poor hand outcomes following stroke. Neuroimage Clin. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nicl.2019.102065.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiori V, Kunz L, Kuhnke P, Marangolo P, Hartwigsen G. Transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) facilitates verb learning by altering effective connectivity in the healthy brain. Neuroimage. 2018;181:550&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chesters J, M&#xf6;tt&#xf6;nen R, Watkins KE. Transcranial direct current stimulation over left inferior frontal cortex improves speech fluency in adults who stutter. Brain. 2018;141(4):1161&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Chang Y, Zhao S, Jones JA, Chen X, Gan C, et al. The left inferior frontal gyrus is causally linked to vocal feedback control: evidence from high-definition transcranial alternating current stimulation. Cereb Cortex. 2023;33(9):5625&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y, Jiao F, Batsikadze G, Yavari F, Nitsche MA. The impact of the left inferior frontal gyrus on fear extinction: a transcranial direct current stimulation study. Brain Stimul. 2024;17(4):816&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Fuccio R, Lardone A, De Luca M, Ali L, Limone P, Marangolo P. Neurobiological effects of transcranial direct current stimulation over the inferior frontal gyrus: a systematic review on cognitive enhancement in healthy and neurological adults. Biomedicines. 2024. https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines12061146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson CL, Attwood L. The impact of gender on stroke pathology and treatment. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2016;67:119&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>