<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41863196</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1525-5069</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>179</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Epilepsy &amp; behavior : E&amp;B</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Epilepsy Behav</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integrating social and neurobehavioral understandings of epilepsy stigma into personalized care strategies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>111002</StartPage><MedlinePgn>111002</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.yebeh.2026.111002</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1525-5050(26)00123-X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>There is a bidirectional relationship between epilepsy-related stigma (ERS) and medical outcomes. ERS negatively influences treatment adherence and disease management, whereas insufficient medical improvement can, in turn, exacerbate ERS. ERS remains a significant challenge, often leading to delays in diagnosis, limiting appropriate therapies, and creating difficulties in social integration for patients with epilepsy. Even when treatment successfully achieves seizure cessation, failure to address ERS can limit patient social integration, reduce quality of life, and hamper long-term psychosocial recovery. Previous studies suggest that a holistic and personalized medicine approach that addresses both the medical and psychosocial aspects of epilepsy, with a particular focus on reducing ERS, can significantly improve diagnosis and treatment outcomes. Integrating culturally sensitive mental health support and community-specific advocacy initiatives targeting ERS reduction into the routine management of epilepsy can promote clinical and psychosocial outcomes and help patients in their reintegration into normal daily life. Key initiatives may include personalized counseling to mitigate the emotional and psychological impact of ERS, targeted cultural competency training for healthcare professionals, and public awareness campaigns. Integrating these strategies into comprehensive epilepsy care is particularly important for marginalized populations, where poverty and limited healthcare access exacerbate ERS. A personalized anti-ERS plan that integrates individualized clinical management with targeted interventions designed for the specific ERS experiences of each patient can improve treatment adherence, enhance cognitive and emotional well-being, and promote better social integration by addressing both the psychological and social dimensions of ERS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghorbannezhad</LastName><ForeName>Ghazaleh</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience Research Center, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gorji</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shefa Neuroscience Research Center, Khatam Alanbia Hospital, Tehran, Iran; Epilepsy Research Center, M&#xfc;nster University, M&#xfc;nster, Germany; Department of Neurosurgery, M&#xfc;nster University, M&#xfc;nster, Germany. Electronic address: gorjial@uni-muenster.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Epilepsy Behav</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100892858</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1525-5050</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antiepileptic drugs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intractable epilepsy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Personalized medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Temporal lobe epilepsy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41863196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2026.111002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1525-5050(26)00123-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>