<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41672744</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1747-0080</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrition &amp; dietetics : the journal of the Dietitians Association of Australia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutr Diet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The implementation and evaluation of a flexible, mixed-model food service system for a greenfield hospital.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1747-0080.70072</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The opening of a new digital metropolitan hospital with surgical and subacute cohorts required a flexible food service model to meet diverse patient needs. This project aimed to design, implement and evaluate such a system, optimising service efficiencies and patient experience.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A flexible, mixed-model food service was designed by reviewing research, consulting experts, and gathering consumer feedback. The Knowledge-To-Action framework guided the model's development and implementation. Key features included an on-demand meal ordering system on the surgical ward; efficient and safe communal dining and snack services for long-stay patients; routine patient food intake hospital-wide to proactively identify at-risk patients; innovative waste and cost recovery strategies. Evaluation was based on the quadruple aims of healthcare measuring patient satisfaction, malnutrition prevalence, mealtime assistance, food waste and cost, and staff satisfaction. The success of targeted implementation strategies was also monitored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Patients were highly satisfied with the food service model (4.6/5, n&#x2009;=&#x2009;1284). High rates of mealtime assistance (&gt;90% over 3&#x2009;years) were achieved, and malnutrition prevalence was 21% (82/369) over the 3&#x2009;years. Low plate waste (3-year average 16.5%) and an average food cost per meal of $4.73 were reported. Staff satisfaction was high, with a culture of success noted.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This flexible, mixed model food service met the needs of different patient cohorts across surgical, subacute and outpatient services, optimising service efficiencies, patient outcomes and staff satisfaction. This project serves as a guide for creating food service models that address diverse patient needs in hospital settings, translating contemporary evidence into practice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Nutrition &amp; Dietetics published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd on behalf of Dietitians Australia.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ellick</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dietetics &amp; Food Services, Surgical, Treatment &amp; Rehabilitation Service (STARS), Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Movement and Nutrition Science, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition Research Collaborative, Royal Brisbane &amp; Women's Hospital, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olufson</LastName><ForeName>Hannah</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7679-5709</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dietetics &amp; Food Services, Surgical, Treatment &amp; Rehabilitation Service (STARS), Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition Research Collaborative, Royal Brisbane &amp; Women's Hospital, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>STARS Education &amp; Research Alliance, STARS, University of Queensland &amp; Metro North Health, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Health Services Research, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Young</LastName><ForeName>Adrienne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4498-4342</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition Research Collaborative, Royal Brisbane &amp; Women's Hospital, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Health Services Research, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dietetics &amp; Food Services, Royal Brisbane &amp; Women's Hospital, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Banks</LastName><ForeName>Merrilyn</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition Research Collaborative, Royal Brisbane &amp; Women's Hospital, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dietetics &amp; Food Services, Royal Brisbane &amp; Women's Hospital, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Nutr Diet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101143078</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1446-6368</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">food service</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mealtimes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">person&#x2010;centred care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">subacute care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">technology</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41672744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1747-0080.70072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Agarwal E, Ferguson M, Banks M, Bauer J, Capra S, Isenring E. Nutritional status and dietary intake of acute care patients: results from the nutrition care day survey 2010. Clin Nutr. 2012;31(1):41&#x2010;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright OR, Connelly LB, Capra S, Hendrikz J. Determinants of foodservice satisfaction for patients in geriatrics/rehabilitation and residents in residential aged care. Health Expect. 2013;16(3):251&#x2010;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke C, Stack C, Martin M. Lack of meaningful activity on acute physical hospital wards: older people's experiences. Br J Occup Ther. 2017;81(1):15&#x2010;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns N, Hartwell H, Morgan M. Improving the provision of meals in hospital. The patients' viewpoint. Appetite. 2010;54(1):181&#x2010;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assaf A. The popularity of foodservice systems in Australian hospitals. J Foodservice. 2009;20(1):47&#x2010;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregoire MB. Foodservice organizations: a managerial and systems approach. Systems Approach to a Foodservice Organization. 9th ed. Pearson; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCray S, Maunder K, Krikowa R, MacKenzie&#x2010;Shalders K. Room service improves nutritional intake and increases patient satisfaction while decreasing food waste and cost. J Acad Nutr Diet. 2018;118(2):284&#x2010;293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuperberg K, Caruso A, Dello S, Mager D. How will a room service delivery system affect dietary intake, food costs, food waste and patient satisfaction in a paediatric hospital? A pilot study. J Foodservice. 2008;19(5):255&#x2010;261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcason W. What is the current direction for hospital room service? J Acad Nutr Diet. 2012;112(3):456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinninella E, Raoul P, Maccauro V, et al. Hospital services to improve nutritional intake and reduce food waste: a systematic review. Nutrients. 2023;15(2):310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLymont V, Cox S, Stell F. Improving patient meal satisfaction with room service meal delivery. J Nurs Care Qual. 2003;18:27&#x2010;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaren&#x2010;Hedwards T, D'Cunha K, Elder&#x2010;Robinson E, et al. Effect of communal dining and dining room enhancement interventions on nutritional, clinical and functional outcomes of patients in acute and sub&#x2010;acute hospital, rehabilitation and aged&#x2010;care settings: a systematic review. Nutr Diet. 2022;79(1):140&#x2010;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pashley A, Young A, Wright O. Foodservice systems and mealtime models in rehabilitation: scoping review. J Adv Nurs. 2022;78(11):3559&#x2010;3586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nutrition and Menu Work Group, Statewide Services. Queensland Health Nutrition Standards for Meals and Menus. 2022 https://www.health.qld.gov.au/__data/assets/pdf_file/0030/156288/qh-nutrition-standards.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olufson HT, Ellick J, McCoy S, Barrimore SE, Knowlman T, Young AM. An overlooked challenge: a retrospective audit of overnutrition in hospital rehabilitation wards. Health. 2025;13(2):188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flint K, Matthews&#x2010;Rensch K, Flaws D, Mudge A, Young A. Mealtime care and dietary intake in older psychiatric hospital inpatient: a multiple case study. J Adv Nurs. 2021;77(3):1490&#x2010;1500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faulkner GEJ, Gorczynski PF, Cohn TA. Psychiatric illness and obesity: recognizing the &#x201c;obesogenic&#x201d; nature of an inpatient psychiatric setting. Psychiatr Serv. 2009;60(4):538&#x2010;541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Australian Institute of Health and Welfare. Australia's Health 2014, Sub&#x2010;Acute and Non&#x2010;acute Hospital Care. Australia's Health Series no. 14. Cat. no. AUS 178. Australian Institute of Health and Welfare; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney S, Zulli A, Walton K. Patient satisfaction and energy intakes are enhanced by point of service meal provision. Nutr Diet. 2009;66(4):212&#x2010;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitchumoni CS, Chaudhari R. Anorexia, appetite, hunger, and satiety in older adults. In: Pitchumoni CS, Dharmarajan TS, eds. Geriatric Gastroenterology. Springer International Publishing; 2021:411&#x2010;438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonsson AS, Nyberg M, Jonsson IM, Ostrom A. Older patients' perspectives on mealtimes in hospitals: a scoping review of qualitative studies. Scand J Caring Sci. 2021;35(2):390&#x2010;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKenzie&#x2010;Shalders K, Maunder K, So D, Norris R, McCray S. Impact of electronic bedside meal ordering systems on dietary intake, patient satisfaction, plate waste and costs: a systematic literature review. Nutr Diet. 2020;77(1):103&#x2010;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell JJ, Young A, Hill J, et al. Rationale and developmental methodology for the SIMPLE approach: a systematised, interdisciplinary malnutrition pathway for implementation and evaluation in hospitals. Nutr Diet. 2018;75(2):226&#x2010;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell JJ, Young A, Hill JM, et al. Systematised, interdisciplinary malnutrition program for impLementation and evaluation delivers improved hospital nutrition care processes and patient reported experiences&#x2014;an implementation study. Nutr Diet. 2021;78(5):466&#x2010;475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rushton A, Edwards A, Bauer J, Bell JJ. Dietitian assistant opportunities within the nutrition care process for patients with or at risk of malnutrition: a systematic review. Nutr Diet. 2021;78(1):69&#x2010;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rushton A, Young A, Keller H, Bauer J, Bell J. Delegation opportunities for malnutrition care activities to dietitian assistants&#x2014;findings of a multi&#x2010;site survey. Health. 2021;9(4):446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellick J, McCoy S, Olufson H, Adams A, Banks M, Young A. Harnessing delegation and technology to identify and manage malnutrition in a digital hospital: an implementation study. Nutr Diet. 2025;82(2):218&#x2010;230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellick J, Pashley A, Cave D, Nelson O, Wright O. &#x2018;On&#x2010;demand&#x2019; snack service in a rehabilitation setting: impact on satisfaction, intake, waste and costs. Nutr Diet. 2024;81(4):454&#x2010;463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham ID, Logan J, Harrison MB, et al. Lost in knowledge translation: time for a map? J Contin Educ Health Prof. 2006;26(1):13&#x2010;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogrinc G, Davies L, Goodman D, Batalden P, Davidoff F, Stevens D. SQUIRE 2.0 (standards for QUality improvement reporting excellence): revised publication guidelines from a detailed consensus process. BMJ Qual Saf. 2016;25(12):986&#x2010;992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodenheimer T, Sinsky C. From triple to quadruple aim: care of the patient requires care of the provider. Ann Fam Med. 2014;12(6):573&#x2010;576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbey KL, Wright OR, Capra S. Menu planning in residential aged care&#x2010;the level of choice and quality of planning of meals available to residents. Nutrients. 2015;7(9):7580&#x2010;7592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watterson C, Fraser A, Banks M, et al. Evidence based practice guidelines for the nutritional management of malnutrition in adult patients across the continuum of care. Nutr Diet. 2009;66(3):S1&#x2010;S34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Thielke R, Payne J, Gonzalez N, Conde JG. Research electronic data capture (REDCap)&#x2014;a metadata&#x2010;driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J Biomed Inform. 2009;42(2):377&#x2010;381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Minor BL, et al. The REDCap consortium: building an international community of software platform partners. J Biomed Inform. 2019;95:103208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BPA Analytics. Home Page [Internet]. n.d. [cited 2025 Apr 10]. Available from: https://bpanz.com/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olufson HT, Ottrey E, Green TL, Young AM. Enhancing or impeding? The influence of digital systems on interprofessional practice and person&#x2010;centred care in nutrition care systems across rehabilitation units. Nutr Diet. 2024;81(5):552&#x2010;562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts S, Marshall AP, Gonzalez R, Chaboyer W. Technology to engage hospitalised patients in their nutrition care: a qualitative study of usability and patient perceptions of an electronic foodservice system. J Hum Nutr Diet. 2017;30(5):563&#x2010;573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young AM, Hickman I, Campbell K, Wilkinson SA. Implementation science for dietitians: the &#x2018;what, why and how&#x2019; using multiple case studies. Nutr Diet. 2021;78(3):276&#x2010;285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazzard E, Barone L, Mason M, Lambert K, McMahon A. Patient&#x2010;centred dietetic care from the perspectives of older malnourished patients. J Hum Nutr Diet. 2017;30(5):574&#x2010;587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young AM, Mudge AM, Banks MD, Ross LJ, Daniels L. Encouraging, assisting and time to EAT: improved nutritional intake for older medical patients receiving protected mealtimes and/or additional nursing feeding assistance. Clin Nutr. 2013;32(4):543&#x2010;549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall S, Young A, Bauer J, Isenring E. Malnutrition in geriatric rehabilitation: prevalence, patient outcomes, and criterion validity of the scored patient&#x2010;generated subjective global assessment and the mini nutritional assessment. J Acad Nutr Diet. 2016;116(5):785&#x2010;794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young AM, de Jersey SJ, Ellick J, Lewis CA, Banks M. Comparison of patient food intake, satisfaction and meal quality between two meal service styles in a geriatric inpatient unit. J Nutr Gerontol Geriatr. 2018;37(3&#x2013;4):158&#x2010;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozica&#x2010;Olenski S, Treleaven E, Hewitt M, et al. Patient&#x2010;reported experiences of mealtime care and food access in acute and rehabilitation hospital settings: a cross&#x2010;sectional survey. J Hum Nutr Diet. 2021;34:687&#x2010;694.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young AM. Solving the wicked problem of hospital malnutrition. Nutr Diet. 2015;72(3):200&#x2010;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olufson H, Ottrey E, Young A, Green T. Opportunity, hierarchy, and awareness: an ethnographic exploration across rehabilitation units of interprofessional practice in nutrition and mealtime care. J Interprof Care. 2023;1&#x2010;10:1&#x2010;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross LJ, Mudge AM, Young AM, Banks M. Everyone's problem but nobody's job: staff perceptions and explanations for poor nutritional intake in older medical patients. Nutr Diet. 2011;68(1):41&#x2010;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins J, Porter J. Quantifying waste and its costs in hospital foodservices. Nutr Diet. 2023;80(2):192&#x2010;200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Queensland Government. Green Metro North Sustainability Strategy 2021&#x2010;2026. [Cited 2025 Jan 5]. Available from: https://metronorth.health.qld.gov.au/wp&#x2010;content/uploads/2021/04/green&#x2010;mn&#x2010;sustainability&#x2010;strategy&#x2010;21&#x2010;26.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook N, Goodwin D, Porter J, Collins J. Food and food&#x2010;related waste management strategies in hospital food services: a systematic review. Nutr Diet. 2023;80(2):116&#x2010;142.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>