<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41663711</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rheological investigation of the effects of tea polyphenols on SBS-modified bitumen before and after short-term aging.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7842</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-39300-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Despite the elucidated antioxidant mechanisms of tea polyphenols (TP) in bitumen, their influence on the rheological behavior of SBS (styrene&#x2013;butadiene&#x2013;styrene)-modified bitumen remains unclear. To address this gap, TP (0%, 3%, 6%, 9%, and 12%) was incorporated into 4.5% SBS-modified bitumen to prepare five binders, which were then subjected to thermo-oxidative aging, yielding ten samples. Subsequently, a series of rheological tests, including frequency sweep, multiple stress creep and recovery, linear amplitude sweep, and low-temperature relaxation, were conducted to analyze their behavior. Furthermore, high- and low-temperature rheological models were developed for all binders. The results indicate that TP increases the complex modulus and reduces the phase angle of SBS-modified bitumen, thereby enhancing its elastic response, with the optimum effect achieved at a 3% dosage. At this content, under the unaged condition, the SBS/TP composite-modified bitumen also exhibits the greatest fatigue life. Moreover, TP enhances the high-temperature elastic recovery and deformation resistance of binders, as evidenced by increased recovery rate and reduced non-recoverable creep compliance and creep compliance. Notably, TP compromises the low-temperature stress relaxation capability of SBS-modified bitumen, as indicated by higher max stress, shear stress ratio, relaxation time, and model parameter A, along with a lower model parameter n.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Zhang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Anhui Communications Vocational and Technical College, Hefei, 230051, China. hanzhang0000371@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Liang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Anhui Communications Vocational and Technical College, Hefei, 230051, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Pengxuan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Anhui Communications Vocational and Technical College, Hefei, 230051, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Anhui University of Applied Technology, Hefei, 230011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>AZCJ2024098</GrantID><Agency>Anhui Provincial Educational Teaching Research Planning Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024AH050271</GrantID><Agency>Key Projects of Anhui Provincial Higher Education Institutions</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2025AHGXZK30978</GrantID><Agency>Anhui Provincial Department of Education Scientific Research Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bitumen</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LAS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MSCR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stress relaxation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Styrene-butadiene-styrene (SBS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tea polyphenols</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41663711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12953600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-39300-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-39300-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wei, J., Chen, Q., Du, J., Liu, K. &amp; Jiang, K. Study on the durability of acid rain Erosion-Resistant asphalt mixtures. <i>Materials</i><b>15</b>, 1849 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15051849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8911858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35269080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, B., Yu, X., Dong, F., Zu, Y. &amp; Huang, J. Influence of asphalt mixture workability on the distribution uniformity of asphalt, aggregate particles and asphalt film during mixing process. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>377</b>, 131128 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji, X. et al. Reconstruction and evolution of 3D model on asphalt pavement surface texture using digital image processing technology and accelerated pavement testing. <i>Road. Mater. Pavement Des.</i><b>25</b>, 1694&#x2013;1719 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14680629.2023.2268750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;k, B. V. &amp; &#xd6;zdemir, A. M. Rheological investigation and optimization of crumb rubber-modified bitumen production conditions in the plant and laboratory. <i>Appl. Rheol</i>. <b>35</b>, 20250048 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/arh-2025-0048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, W., Cavalli, M. C., Jiang, W. &amp; Kringos, N. Differing perspectives on the use of high-content SBS polymer-modified bitumen. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>411</b>, 134433 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, X. et al. Evolution of rheological performance and chemical composition in crumb rubber/recycled plastic composite-modified asphalt binder during long-term aging. <i>Chem. Eng. J.</i><b>519</b>, 165534 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.165534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H. et al. Comparative investigation of different blends ageing behaviours for short-term thermal oxidation ageing mechanism of SBS-modified bitumen. <i>Road. Mater. Pavement Des.</i><b>24</b>, 1088&#x2013;1102 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14680629.2022.2060126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayedzada, S. E., Ozdemir, A. M., Yalcin, E. &amp; Yilmaz, M. Investigation of mechanical properties of hot mix asphalts with modified binders with SBS, 611 and 701 polymers. <i>Polym. Bull.</i><b>81</b>, 3695&#x2013;3724 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00289-023-04893-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zdemir, A. M. Experimental evaluation and 3D finite element simulation of creep behaviour of SBS modified asphalt mixture. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>460</b>, 139821 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laukkanen, O. V., Soenen, H., Winter, H. H. &amp; Sepp&#xe4;l&#xe4;, J. Low-temperature rheological and morphological characterization of SBS modified bitumen. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>179</b>, 348&#x2013;359 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.05.160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, W. et al. Preparation and pavement performance of highly viscoelastic antifatigue asphalt. <i>J. Mater. Civ. Eng.</i><b>37</b>, 04025058 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/JMCEE7.MTENG-19461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zdemir, A. M., Yal&#xe7;&#x131;n, B. F. &amp; Y&#x131;lmaz, M. Effect of polymer modification on bitumen rheology: A comparative study of bitumens obtained from different sources. <i>Appl. Rheol</i>. <b>35</b>, 20250049 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/arh-2025-0049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, Y. et al. Novel multidimensional composite development for aging resistance of SBS-Modified asphalt by attaching zinc oxide on expanded vermiculite. <i>Energy Fuels</i>. <b>38</b>, 16772&#x2013;16781 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. et al. Comparative analysis of four styrene-butadiene-styrene (SBS) structure repair agents in the rejuvenation of aged SBS-modified bitumen. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>476</b>, 141232 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.141232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yalcin, E. et al. Evaluation of asphalt anti-cracking performance of SBS polymer with SCB method and deep learning. <i>Heliyon</i><b>10</b>, e39613 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e39613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11532877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39498054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Q., He, Z., Lu, Y. &amp; Zhang, X. The influence of zinc oxide-silicate composites on the aging resistance of asphalt. <i>Alex Eng. J.</i><b>93</b>, 288&#x2013;294 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aej.2024.02.068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, T., Jiang, K., Liu, K. &amp; Li, Q. Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy characterization of aging properties of graphene oxide modified asphalt binder. <i>Int. J. Adhes. Adhes.</i><b>139</b>, 103974 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijadhadh.2025.103974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, B., Liu, P., Zhao, Y., Li, X. &amp; Cao, G. Effect of graphene oxide in different phases on the high temperature rheological properties of asphalt based on grey relational and principal component analysis. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>362</b>, 129714 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, C., Li, D., Zhang, H., Wang, Z. &amp; Li, J. Synergistic effect of surface modified nano-zinc oxide and organic vermiculite on long-term ultraviolet and thermal-oxidative aging resistance of different asphalt binders. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>409</b>, 133832 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Z., Zhang, H., Zhu, C. &amp; Zhao, B. Rheological examination of aging in bitumen with inorganic nanoparticles and organic expanded vermiculite. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>101</b>, 884&#x2013;891 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.10.153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, S. et al. Effect of Antioxidant/CA-LDHs on the properties of SBS-Modified bitumen. <i>J. Mater. Civ. Eng.</i><b>36</b>, 04023604 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/JMCEE7.MTENG-16896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, P. et al. Effect of layered double hydroxides on the VOCs emission and the properties of SBS modified asphalt. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>439</b>, 137398 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang, C., Wang, S., Zhang, Y. &amp; Zhang, Y. Improving the aging resistance of asphalt by addition of zinc dialkyldithiophosphate. <i>Fuel</i><b>85</b>, 1060&#x2013;1066 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2005.08.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, P., Dong, Z., Tan, Y. &amp; Liu, Z. Anti-ageing properties of styrene&#x2013;butadiene&#x2013;styrene copolymer-modified asphalt combined with multi-walled carbon nanotubes. <i>Road. Mater. Pavement Des.</i><b>18</b>, 533&#x2013;549 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14680629.2016.1181561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, W. et al. Enhancement of asphalt properties through SBS and CNT synergism: A comprehensive multi-scale analysis. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>505</b>, 144747 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.144747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leopoldini, M., Russo, N. &amp; Toscano, M. The molecular basis of working mechanism of natural polyphenolic antioxidants. <i>Food Chem.</i><b>125</b>, 288&#x2013;306 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2010.08.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S., Wang, H. &amp; Yang, J. Assessment and mechanism of antioxidant activity of phenols as asphalt antioxidants. <i>Int. J. Pavement Eng.</i><b>25</b>, 2335316 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10298436.2024.2335316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen, J. C. A review of the fundamentals of asphalt oxidation: Chemical, Physicochemical, physical Property, and durability relationships. <i>Transp Res. Circ</i> (2009). https://api.semanticscholar.org/CorpusID:52237388</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S. et al. Biomass waste to produce bio oil as rejuvenator for asphalt based on pyrolysis technology. <i>Int. J. Pavement Eng.</i><b>25</b>, 2287695 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10298436.2023.2287695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, D. et al. Chemical composition-driven performance evaluation model for sbs-modified asphalt using multivariate statistical. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 43313 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-27348-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12686402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41360852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, S., He, R., Chen, H., Li, W. &amp; Li, G. Rheological properties of SBS/CRP composite modified asphalt under different aging treatments. <i>Materials</i><b>13</b>, 4921 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma13214921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7663548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33147755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. Research on the optimal dosage of Bio-Oil/Lignin composite modified asphalt based on rheological and Anti-Aging properties. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>389</b>, 131796 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao, Y. et al. Exploring the potential of stabilized natural rock asphalt to enhance high-viscosity modified asphalt: A physicochemical and rheological perspective. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>494</b>, 143476 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.143476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, W. et al. Analysis of thermal susceptibility and rheological properties of asphalt binder modified with microwave activated crumb rubber. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>377</b>, 134488 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.134488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, L., Zhu, J., Yang, Y., Zheng, M. &amp; Yang, J. Experiment and representation of stress relaxation behavior of crumb rubber modified asphalt. <i>Int. J. Pavement Res. Technol.</i><b>18</b>, 275&#x2013;285 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42947-023-00344-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, S., Liu, X. &amp; Erkens, S. Towards critical low-temperature relaxation indicators for effective rejuvenation efficiency evaluation of rejuvenator-aged bitumen blends. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>426</b>, 139092 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.139092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nouali, M., Dony, A. &amp; Carter, A. Evaluation of fatigue life of asphalt binders using the time sweep and linear amplitude sweep tests: A literature review. <i>J. Traffic Transp. Eng. Engl. Ed.</i><b>11</b>, 1210&#x2013;1242 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, M. et al. Study on the viscoelastic behaviour of the modified asphalt containing multi-walled carbon nanotubes (MWCNTs) and crumb rubber (CR). <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>311</b>, 125244 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusoff, N. I., Md., Shaw, M. T. &amp; Airey, G. D. Modelling the linear viscoelastic rheological properties of bituminous binders. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>25</b>, 2171&#x2013;2189 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2010.11.086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, W. et al. Prediction of rheological properties of high polymer-modified asphalt binders based on BAS-BP neural network and functional groups. <i>Fuel</i><b>379</b>, 132989 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, M. et al. A solid&#x2013;solid phase change filler with enhanced thermal properties for cooling asphalt mastic. <i>Sol Energy</i>. <b>242</b>, 105&#x2013;118 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2022.07.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H., Xu, G., Chen, X., Wang, R. &amp; Shen, K. Effect of long-term laboratory aging on rheological properties and cracking resistance of polymer-modified asphalt binders at intermediate and low temperature range. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>226</b>, 767&#x2013;777 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.07.206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Airey, G. Rheological properties of styrene butadiene styrene polymer modified road bitumens&#x22c6;. <i>Fuel</i><b>82</b>, 1709&#x2013;1719 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0016-2361(03)00146-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, X. &amp; Isacsson, U. Rheological characterization of styrene-butadiene-styrene copolymer modified bitumens. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>11</b>, 23&#x2013;32 (1997).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0950-0618(96)00033-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, W. &amp; Tang, N. Characterizing SBS modified asphalt with sulfur using multiple stress creep recovery test. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>93</b>, 514&#x2013;521 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.06.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv, S. et al. Improvements on high-temperature stability, rheology, and stiffness of asphalt binder modified with waste crayfish shell powder. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>264</b>, 121745 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.121745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skronka, G., Blascik, M., Vacin, O. &amp; Jasso, M. Impact of shear stress levels on validity of MSCR tests. <i>Road. Mater. Pavement Des.</i><b>24</b>, 1820&#x2013;1836 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14680629.2022.2106293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, W. et al. Investigation of LAS-based fatigue evaluation methods for high-viscosity modified asphalt binders with high-content polymers. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>422</b>, 135810 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H., Zeiada, W., Al-Khateeb, G. G., Shanableh, A. &amp; Samarai, M. Use of the multiple stress creep recovery (MSCR) test to characterize the rutting potential of asphalt binders: A literature review. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>269</b>, 121320 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing, B., Fan, W., Lyu, Y., Che, J. &amp; Zhuang, C. Influences of ball-milled limestone particle sizes and shapes on asphalt mastic stress relaxation behavior. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>255</b>, 119396 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>