<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41654737</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2261</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC cardiovascular disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Cardiovasc Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of epigallocatechin-3-gallate on left ventricular remodeling and functional recovery following aortic coarctation surgery.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">217</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12872-026-05579-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the effects of Epigallocatechin-3-gallate (EGCG) on left ventricular remodeling and functional recovery in mice subjected to pressure overload and subsequent unloading.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A mouse model of left ventricular hypertrophy was established via transverse aortic constriction (TAC). A subset of these animals underwent a second surgery to release aorta coarctation, simulating left ventricular pressure unloading. Mice in both pressure overload and unloading conditions received an intraperitoneal injection of EGCG (40&#xa0;mg/kg per day) for 4 weeks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">EGCG treatment significantly improved cardiac function, as indicated by increased ractional shortening (FS) and ejection fraction (EF), and reduced heart weight to body weight (HW/BW) and heart weight to tibia length (HW/TL) ratios, as well as LVIDd, LVIDs, LVEDV, and LVESV (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) at 8 weeks post-TAC surgery. EGCG treatment combined with pressure unloading had a cardioprotective effect on ventricular remodeling in mice with pressure overload, as evidenced by improvements in FS and EF and reductions in LVIDd, LVIDs, LVEDV, LVESV, HW/BW ratio, and HW/TL ratio (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Following EGCG treatment, echocardiography further confirmed a notable thinning of the left ventricle wall in mice subjected to pressure unloading. In addition, transmission electron microscopy demonstrated improved sarcomere organization and increased mitochondrial density, while wheat germ agglutinin staining showed a marked reduction in cardiomyocyte surface area (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) in mice with left ventricular pressure overload or unloading.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">These findings suggest that EGCG exerts protective effects against pressure overload-induced myocardial remodeling and augments cardiac recovery following pressure unloading. Unlike previous studies, our model uniquely evaluates EGCG&#x2019;s role across both disease progression and recovery phases, highlighting its novel therapeutic potential in post-repair cardiac remodeling.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Siyuan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology Children's Hospital of Chongqing Medical University, Chongqing City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Child Health and Disorders, Chongqing City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education Key Laboratory of Child Development and Disorders, Chongqing City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China International Science and Technology Cooperation base of Child development and Critical Disorders, Chongqing City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chongqing Key Laboratory of Structural Birth Defect and Reconstruction, Chongqing City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology Children's Hospital of Chongqing Medical University, Chongqing Key Laboratory of Structural Birth Defect and Reconstruction, Chongqing City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Child Health and Disorders, Chongqing City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education Key Laboratory of Child Development and Disorders, Chongqing City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China International Science and Technology Cooperation base of Child development and Critical Disorders, Chongqing City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chongqing Key Laboratory of Structural Birth Defect and Reconstruction, Chongqing City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology Children's Hospital of Chongqing Medical University, Chongqing Key Laboratory of Structural Birth Defect and Reconstruction, Chongqing City, China. Dundao999@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Child Health and Disorders, Chongqing City, China. Dundao999@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education Key Laboratory of Child Development and Disorders, Chongqing City, China. Dundao999@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China International Science and Technology Cooperation base of Child development and Critical Disorders, Chongqing City, China. Dundao999@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chongqing Key Laboratory of Structural Birth Defect and Reconstruction, Chongqing City, China. Dundao999@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Lifei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology Children's Hospital of Chongqing Medical University, Chongqing City, China. lifeiliu@hospital.cqmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Child Health and Disorders, Chongqing City, China. lifeiliu@hospital.cqmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education Key Laboratory of Child Development and Disorders, Chongqing City, China. lifeiliu@hospital.cqmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China International Science and Technology Cooperation base of Child development and Critical Disorders, Chongqing City, China. lifeiliu@hospital.cqmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chongqing Key Laboratory of Structural Birth Defect and Reconstruction, Chongqing City, China. lifeiliu@hospital.cqmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Cardiovasc Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968539</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2261</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aortic coarctation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiac remodeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EGCG</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Green tea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pressure overload</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ventricular hypertrophy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The animal study was reviewed and approved by Ethics Committee of Chongqing Medical University (No.CHCMU-IACUC20240628003). This study adheres to internationally accepted standards for animal research, following the 3Rs principle. The ARRIVE guidelines were employed for reporting experiments involving live animals, promoting ethical research practices. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41654737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12977714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12872-026-05579-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12872-026-05579-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dijkema EJ, Leiner T, Grotenhuis HB. Diagnosis, imaging and clinical management of aortic coarctation. Heart. 2017;103(15):1148&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/heartjnl-2017-311173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28377475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karaosmanoglu AD, Khawaja RD, Onur MR, Kalra MK. CT and MRI of aortic coarctation: pre- and postsurgical findings. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2015;204(3):W224&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2214/AJR.14.12529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25714305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardoso G, Abecasis M, Anjos R, Marques M, Koukoulis G, Aguiar C, Neves JP. Aortic coarctation repair in the adult. J Card Surg. 2014;29(4):512&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocs.12367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24894975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arya B, Maskatia SA. Coarctation of the aorta: prenatal assessment, postnatal management and neonatal outcomes. Semin Perinatol. 2022;46(4):151584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semperi.2022.151584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35422354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holzer RJ, Gauvreau K, McEnaney K, Watanabe H, Ringel R. Long-Term outcomes of the coarctation of the aorta stent trials. Circulation Cardiovasc Interventions. 2021;14(6):e010308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCINTERVENTIONS.120.010308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34039015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Florianczyk T, Werner B. Assessment of left ventricular diastolic function in children after successful repair of aortic coarctation. Clin Res Cardiology: Official J German Cardiac Soc. 2011;100(6):493&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00392-010-0272-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3100502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21193915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombardi KC, Northrup V, McNamara RL, Sugeng L, Weismann CG. Aortic stiffness and left ventricular diastolic function in children following early repair of aortic coarctation. Am J Cardiol. 2013;112(11):1828&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2013.07.052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24035164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egbe AC, Qureshi MY, Connolly HM. Determinants of left ventricular diastolic function and exertional symptoms in adults with coarctation of aorta. Circulation Heart Fail. 2020;13(2):e006651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCHEARTFAILURE.119.006651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7041882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32059629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weismann CG, Maretic A, Grell BS, &#xc5;kesson A, Hlebowicz J, Liuba P. Multimodal assessment of vascular and ventricular function in children and adults with repaired aortic coarctation. Int J Cardiol. 2021;323:47&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2020.08.095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32889020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuzaki S, Darcha C. Antifibrotic properties of epigallocatechin-3-gallate in endometriosis. Hum Reprod (Oxford England). 2014;29(8):1677&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/humrep/deu123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24876174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun TL, Liu Z, Qi ZJ, Huang YP, Gao XQ, Zhang YY. (-)-Epigallocatechin-3-gallate (EGCG) attenuates arsenic-induced cardiotoxicity in rats. Food Chem Toxicology: Int J Published Br Industrial Biol Res Association. 2016;93:102&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fct.2016.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27170490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mokra D, Joskova M, Mokry J. Therapeutic effects of green tea polyphenol (&#x2013;)-Epigallocatechin-3-Gallate (EGCG) in relation to molecular pathways controlling Inflammation, oxidative Stress, and apoptosis. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;24(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9820274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36613784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudrapal M, Khairnar SJ, Khan J, Dukhyil AB, Ansari MA, Alomary MN, Alshabrmi FM, Palai S, Deb PK, Devi R. Dietary polyphenols and their role in oxidative Stress-Induced human diseases: insights into protective Effects, antioxidant potentials and Mechanism(s) of action. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13:806470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.806470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8882865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35237163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brimson JM, Prasanth MI, Kumaree KK, Thitilertdecha P. Tea plant (Camellia sinensis): A current update on use in Diabetes, Obesity, and cardiovascular disease. Nutrients. 2022;15(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9823498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36615695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H, Gan C, Xiang Z, Xiang T, Li J, Huang X, Qin X, Liu T, Sheng J, Wang X. Targeting the TNF-&#x3b1;-TNFR interaction with EGCG to block NF-&#x3ba;B signaling in human synovial fibroblasts. Biomed pharmacotherapy = Biomedecine Pharmacotherapie. 2023;161:114575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2023.114575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36963358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie LW, Cai S, Zhao TS, Li M, Tian Y. Green tea derivative (-)-epigallocatechin-3-gallate (EGCG) confers protection against ionizing radiation-induced intestinal epithelial cell death both in vitro and in vivo. Free Radic Biol Med. 2020;161:175&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2020.10.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33069855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu G, Cheng H, Guo H, Li Z, Li D, Xie Z. Tea polyphenol EGCG ameliorates obesity-related complications by regulating lipidomic pathway in leptin receptor knockout rats. J Nutr Biochem. 2023;118:109349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnutbio.2023.109349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37085056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadaki M, Vikhorev PG, Marston SB, Messer AE. Uncoupling of myofilament Ca2&#x2009;+&#x2009;sensitivity from troponin I phosphorylation by mutations can be reversed by epigallocatechin-3-gallate. Cardiovascular Res. 2015;108(1):99&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cvr/cvv181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4905512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26109583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laudadio E, Minnelli C, Amici A. Liposomal formulations for an efficient encapsulation of Epigallocatechin-3-gallate: an in- Silico/Experimental approach. Molecules. 2018;23(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6017453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29462955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu P, Huang J, Mei W, Zeng X, Wang C, Wen C, Xu J. Epigallocatechin-3-gallate protects cardiomyocytes from hypoxia-reoxygenation damage via Raising autophagy related 4&#xa0;C expression. Bioengineered. 2021;12(2):9496&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21655979.2021.1996018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8810140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34699312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen DD, Dong YG, Liu D, He JG. Epigallocatechin-3-gallate attenuates cardiac hypertrophy in hypertensive rats in part by modulation of mitogen-activated protein kinase signals. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 2009;36(9):925&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-1681.2009.05173.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19298531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Zhao W, Liu J, Gan Y, Liu L, Tian J. Epigallocatechin-3 gallate prevents pressure overload-induced heart failure by up-regulating SERCA2a via histone acetylation modification in mice. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(10):e0205123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0205123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6171916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30286210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, Peng C, Huang L, Luo X, Mao Q, Wu S, Zhang H. EGCG prevents pressure overload&#x2013;induced myocardial remodeling by downregulating overexpression of HDAC5 in mice. Int J Mol Med. 2022;49(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34841436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zupcic A, Latic N. Ablation of vitamin D signaling in cardiomyocytes leads to functional impairment and stimulation of Pro-Inflammatory and Pro-Fibrotic gene regulatory networks in a left ventricular hypertrophy model in mice. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25(11).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11172934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38892126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf8;rnstad JL, Skrbic B, Sjaastad I, Bj&#xf8;rnstad S, Christensen G, T&#xf8;nnessen T. A mouse model of reverse cardiac remodelling following banding-debanding of the ascending aorta. Acta Physiologica (Oxford England). 2012;205(1):92&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.2011.02369.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21974781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinheimer CJ, Kovacs A, Evans S, Matkovich SJ, Barger PM, Mann DL. Load-Dependent changes in left ventricular structure and function in a pathophysiologically relevant murine model of reversible heart failure. Circulation Heart Fail. 2018;11(5):e004351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCHEARTFAILURE.117.004351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5935139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29716898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia Q, Yang R. Epigallocatechin-3-gallate attenuates myocardial fibrosis in diabetic rats by activating autophagy. Experimental Biology Med (Maywood NJ). 2022;247(17):1591&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15353702221110646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9554167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35833541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sari N, Katanasaka Y, Sugiyama Y, Sunagawa Y, Miyazaki Y, Funamoto M, Shimizu S, Shimizu K, Murakami A, Mori K, et al. Zerumbone prevents pressure overload-induced left ventricular systolic dysfunction by inhibiting cardiac hypertrophy and fibrosis. Phytomedicine: Int J Phytotherapy Phytopharmacology. 2021;92:153744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phymed.2021.153744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34563985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Z, Yan R, Liu J, Dai H, Zhu Y, Zhang F, Zhang L, Yan S. Lactate dehydrogenase and aspartate aminotransferase levels associated with the severity of COVID&#x2013;19: A systematic review and meta&#x2013;analysis. Experimental Therapeutic Med. 2023;25(5):221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/etm.2023.11920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10133797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37123202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virag JA, Rolle ML, Reece J, Hardouin S, Feigl EO, Murry CE. Fibroblast growth factor-2 regulates myocardial infarct repair: effects on cell proliferation, Scar contraction, and ventricular function. Am J Pathol. 2007;171(5):1431&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2353/ajpath.2007.070003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2043505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanner MA, Maitz CA, Grisanti LA. Immune cell &#x3b2;(2)-adrenergic receptors contribute to the development of heart failure. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2021;321(4):H633&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.00243.2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8816326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34415184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenzweig R, Kumar V. Estrogen Receptor-&#x3b2; agonists modulate T-Lymphocyte activation and ameliorate left ventricular remodeling during chronic heart failure. Circulation Heart Fail. 2022;15(7):e008997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCHEARTFAILURE.121.008997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9308745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35730443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnett DK, Blumenthal RS, Albert MA, Buroker AB, Goldberger ZD, Hahn EJ, Himmelfarb CD, Khera A, Lloyd-Jones D, McEvoy JW, et al. 2019 ACC/AHA guideline on the primary prevention of cardiovascular disease: A report of the American college of Cardiology/American heart association task force on clinical practice guidelines. Circulation. 2019;140(11):e596&#x2013;646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7734661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30879355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souders CA, Borg TK, Banerjee I, Baudino TA. Pressure overload induces early morphological changes in the heart. Am J Pathol. 2012;181(4):1226&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajpath.2012.06.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3463627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22954422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Zhu X, Shi L, Wang J, Xu Q, Yu B, Qu A. A time-series minimally invasive transverse aortic constriction mouse model for pressure overload-induced cardiac remodeling and heart failure. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2023;10:1110032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2023.1110032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9986492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36891245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yarbrough WM, Mukherjee R, Ikonomidis JS, Zile MR, Spinale FG. Myocardial remodeling with aortic stenosis and after aortic valve replacement: mechanisms and future prognostic implications. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2012;143(3):656&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtcvs.2011.04.044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3210937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21762938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Momose Y, Maeda-Yamamoto M, Nabetani H. Systematic review of green tea Epigallocatechin gallate in reducing low-density lipoprotein cholesterol levels of humans. Int J Food Sci Nutr. 2016;67(6):606&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09637486.2016.1196655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27324590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kochman J, Jakubczyk K. Health benefits and chemical composition of Matcha green tea: A review. Molecules. 2020;26(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7796401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33375458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu FW, Lv YL, Zhong YF, Xue YN, Wang Y, Zhang LY, Hu X, Tan WQ. Beneficial Effects of Green Tea EGCG on Skin Wound Healing: A Comprehensive Review. Molecules (Basel, Switzerland). 2021;26(20).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8540743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34684703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohd Sabri NA, Lee SK, Murugan DD, Ling WC. Epigallocatechin gallate (EGCG) alleviates vascular dysfunction in angiotensin II-infused hypertensive mice by modulating oxidative stress and eNOS. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):17633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-21107-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9587239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36271015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang JH, Chang SL, Hong PD, Chen PN, Hsu CH, Lu YY, Chen YC. Epigallocatechin-3-gallate modulates arrhythmogenic activity and calcium homeostasis of left atrium. Int J Cardiol. 2017;236:174&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2017.01.090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28117139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim CJ, Kim JM, Lee SR, Jang YH, Kim JH, Chun KJ. Polyphenol (-)-epigallocatechin gallate targeting myocardial reperfusion limits infarct size and improves cardiac function. Korean J Anesthesiology. 2010;58(2):169&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4097/kjae.2010.58.2.169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2872859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20498796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend PA, Scarabelli TM, Pasini E, Gitti G, Menegazzi M, Suzuki H, Knight RA, Latchman DS, Stephanou A. Epigallocatechin-3-gallate inhibits STAT-1 activation and protects cardiac myocytes from ischemia/reperfusion-induced apoptosis. FASEB Journal: Official Publication Federation Am Soc Experimental Biology. 2004;18(13):1621&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.04-1716fje</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15319365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>