<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41826633</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute muscle damage responses in elbow flexors following eccentric quasi-isometric exercise.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-43855-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to compare acute muscle damage responses of the elbow flexors following eccentric quasi-isometric (EQI) and eccentric (ECC) exercise. Thirty healthy young men were randomly assigned to EQI or ECC (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;15/group). Participants performed five sets of dumbbell elbow flexion to volitional failure. Maximal voluntary isometric contraction (MVC), elbow joint range of motion (ROM), upper arm circumference (CIR), pressure pain threshold (PPT), plasma creatine kinase (CK), and myoglobin (Mb) were measured before, immediately after, and 1, 2, 3, and 7 days post-exercise. Time under tension (TUT) was recorded. TUT was approximately 3.5-fold longer in EQI than ECC. ECC induced greater reductions in MVC (-&#x2009;30% vs. -15%) and ROM (-&#x2009;27% vs. -13%), and larger increases in CIR (+&#x2009;5% vs. +2%). Peak CK (11,601&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;9,483 vs. 135.2&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;33.1 IU/L) and Mb (406.7&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;271.8 vs. 17.7&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;6.2 ng/mL) were markedly higher following ECC. Distal PPT was 13-19% lower in ECC. Most variables returned to baseline by day 7 in EQI. Despite longer TUT, EQI induced substantially less acute muscle damage and faster recovery than ECC when both were performed to volitional failure at the same relative external load.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Chin</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Sport Coaching Science, Chinese Culture University, No. 55, Hwa- Kang Rd., Yang-Ming-Shan, Taipei City, 11114, Taiwan (R.O.C.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Chiang</LastName><ForeName>Tsung-Lin</ForeName><Initials>TL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Sport Coaching Science, Chinese Culture University, No. 55, Hwa- Kang Rd., Yang-Ming-Shan, Taipei City, 11114, Taiwan (R.O.C.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chan</LastName><ForeName>Shih-Hsuan</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Sport Coaching Science, Chinese Culture University, No. 55, Hwa- Kang Rd., Yang-Ming-Shan, Taipei City, 11114, Taiwan (R.O.C.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsu</LastName><ForeName>Chih-Hsiang</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education Office, National Taipei University of Technology, No.1, Sec. 3, Zhongxiao E. Rd., Da-an District, Taipei City, 106, Taiwan (R.O.C.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Huey-June</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Sport Coaching Science, Chinese Culture University, No. 55, Hwa- Kang Rd., Yang-Ming-Shan, Taipei City, 11114, Taiwan (R.O.C.). wuhc0123@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MOST 109-2410-H-034-041</GrantID><Agency>National Taiwan University of Science and Technology</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Contraction characteristics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exhaustive exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanical tension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance exercise</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical approval: This study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki and was approved by the Institutional Review Board of Fu Jen Catholic University (FJU-IRB No: C108083). Consent to participate: All participants provided written informed consent prior to participation.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41826633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-43855-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-43855-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;en&#x131;&#x15f;&#x131;k, S., Akova, B., &#x15e;ekir, U. &amp; G&#xfc;r, H. Effects of muscle architecture on eccentric exercise induced muscle damage responses. J. Sports Sci. Med. 20, 655&#x2013;664. https://doi.org/10.52082/jssm.2021.655 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka, K. &amp; Newton, M. Concentric or eccentric training effect on eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. Med. Sci. Sports. Exerc. 34, 63&#x2013;69. https://doi.org/10.1097/00005768-200201000-00011 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royer, N., Nosaka, K., Doguet, V. &amp; Jubeau, M. Neuromuscular responses to isometric, concentric and eccentric contractions of the knee extensors at the same torque-time integral. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 122, 127&#x2013;139. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-021-04817-y (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proske, U. &amp; Morgan, D. L. Muscle damage from eccentric exercise: Mechanism, mechanical signs, adaptation and clinical applications. J. Physiol. 537, 333&#x2013;345. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.00333.x (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman, D., Newton, M., Sacco, P. &amp; Nosaka, K. Greater muscle damage induced by fast versus slow velocity eccentric exercise. Int. J. Sports Med. 27, 591&#x2013;598. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-2005-865920 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas, J., Pearson, S., Ross, A. &amp; McGuigan, M. Eccentric exercise: Physiological characteristics and acute responses. Sports Med. 47, 663&#x2013;675. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-016-0624-8 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sto&#x17e;er, A., Vodopivc, P. &amp; Kri&#x17e;an&#x10d;i&#x107; Bombek, L. Pathophysiology of exercise-induced muscle damage and its structural, functional, metabolic, and clinical consequences. Physiol. Res. 69, 565&#x2013;598. https://doi.org/10.33549/physiolres.934371 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad, A. et al. Relationship between eccentric-exercise-induced loss in muscle function to muscle soreness and tissue hardness. Healthcare 10, 96. https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare10010096 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson, P. M. &amp; Hubal, M. J. Exercise-induced muscle damage in humans. Am. J. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 81, S52-69. https://doi.org/10.1097/00002060-200211001-00007 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake, J. M., Neubauer, O., Della Gatta, P. A. &amp; Nosaka, K. Muscle damage and inflammation during recovery from exercise. J. Appl. Physiol. 122, 559&#x2013;570. https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00971.2016 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson, E. S., Clarkson, P. M. &amp; Tarnopolsky, M. A. Perspectives on exertional rhabdomyolysis. Sports Med. 47, 33&#x2013;49. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-017-0689-z (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oranchuk, D. J., Storey, A. G., Nelson, A. R. &amp; Cronin, J. B. Scientific basis for eccentric quasi-isometric resistance training: A narrative review. J. Strength Cond. Res. 33, 2846&#x2013;2859. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000003291 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li&#x10d;en, U., Oranchuk, D. J. &amp; Kozinc, &#x17d;. Exploring the biomechanics and fatigue patterns of eccentric quasi-isometric muscle actions in the knee extensors and flexors. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 124, 3409&#x2013;3419. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-024-05544-w (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oranchuk, D. J., Nelson, A. R., Storey, A. G., Diewald, S. N. &amp; Cronin, J. B. Short-term neuromuscular, morphological, and architectural responses to eccentric quasi-isometric muscle actions. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 121, 141&#x2013;158. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-020-04512-4 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oranchuk, D. J. et al. Kinetic and kinematic profile of eccentric quasi-isometric loading. Sports Biomechanics 23, 758&#x2013;771. https://doi.org/10.1080/14763141.2021.1890198 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnusson, S. P. &amp; Kjaer, M. The impact of loading, unloading, ageing and injury on the human tendon. J. Physiol. 597, 1283&#x2013;1298. https://doi.org/10.1113/jp275450 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guilhem, G., Cornu, C. &amp; Gu&#xe9;vel, A. Neuromuscular and muscle-tendon system adaptations to isotonic and isokinetic eccentric exercise. Ann. Phys. Rehabil. Med. 53, 319&#x2013;341. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rehab.2010.04.003 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson, Z., Wang, S., Cornish, S. &amp; Scribbans, T. D. Isotonic resistance exercise outperforms eccentric quasi-isometric resistance exercise for increasing elbow flexor muscle thickness and estimated one-repetition maximum in untrained individuals: Exploring the influence of sex and volume. Appl. Physiol. Nutr. Metab. https://doi.org/10.1139/apnm-2025-0039 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyer, R. et al. Heavy slow resistance versus eccentric training as treatment for Achilles tendinopathy: A randomized controlled trial. Am. J. Sports Med. 43, 1704&#x2013;1711. https://doi.org/10.1177/0363546515584760 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kongsgaard, M. et al. Corticosteroid injections, eccentric decline squat training and heavy slow resistance training in patellar tendinopathy. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 19, 790&#x2013;802. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0838.2009.00949.x (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kri&#x17e;aj, L., &#x160;arabon, N. &amp; Kozinc, &#x17d;. Acute fatiguing effects and biomechanical characteristics of a single bout eccentric quasi-isometric resistance exercise of ankle plantar flexors. Front. Bioeng. Biotechnol. 13, 1517098. https://doi.org/10.3389/fbioe.2025.1517098 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson, Z. J., Wang, S., Cornish, S. M. &amp; Scribbans, T. D. Exploring the acute muscle fatigue response in resistance trained individuals during eccentric quasi-isometric elbow flexions-a cross-sectional comparison of repetition and sex. Sports Biomech. https://doi.org/10.1080/14763141.2023.2269543 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, T. C. et al. Damage and the repeated bout effect of arm, leg, and trunk muscles induced by eccentric resistance exercises. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 29, 725&#x2013;735. https://doi.org/10.1111/sms.13388 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baroni, B. M. et al. Full range of motion induces greater muscle damage than partial range of motion in elbow flexion exercise with free weights. J. Strength Cond. Res. 31, 2223&#x2013;2230. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000001562 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deyhle, M. R., Tiede, D., Xin, L., Hyldahl, R. D. &amp; Hubal, M. J. Common markers of muscle damage are associated with divergent gene expression patterns after eccentric contractions. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 56, 1108&#x2013;1117. https://doi.org/10.1249/mss.0000000000003399 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen, G., Mikkelsen, U. R., Raastad, T. &amp; Peake, J. M. Leucocytes, cytokines and satellite cells: What role do they play in muscle damage and regeneration following eccentric exercise?. Exerc. Immunol. Rev. 18, 42&#x2013;97 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sewright, K. A., Hubal, M. J., Kearns, A., Holbrook, M. T. &amp; Clarkson, P. M. Sex differences in response to maximal eccentric exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 40, 242&#x2013;251. https://doi.org/10.1249/mss.0b013e31815aedda (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dannecker, E. A. et al. Sex differences in exercise-induced muscle pain and muscle damage. J. Pain. 13, 1242&#x2013;1249. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpain.2012.09.014 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, T. C. et al. Comparison among three different intensities of eccentric contractions of the elbow flexors resulting in the same strength loss at one day post-exercise for changes in indirect muscle damage markers. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 120, 267&#x2013;279. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-019-04272-w (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau, W. Y., Blazevich, A. J., Newton, M. J., Wu, S. S. &amp; Nosaka, K. Assessment of muscle pain induced by elbow-flexor eccentric exercise. J. Athl. Train. 50, 1140&#x2013;1148. https://doi.org/10.4085/1062-6050-50.11.05 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakeman, R. Recommended effect size statistics for repeated measures designs. Behav. Res. Methods. 37, 379&#x2013;384. https://doi.org/10.3758/bf03192707 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen, J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences 2nd Edition. (routledge, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ueda, H., Tsuchiya, Y. &amp; Ochi, E. Fast-velocity eccentric cycling exercise causes greater muscle damage than slow eccentric cycling. Front. Physiol. 11, 596640. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2020.596640 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman, D. W., Newton, M., McGuigan, M. &amp; Nosaka, K. Effect of lengthening contraction velocity on muscle damage of the elbow flexors. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 40, 926&#x2013;933. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0b013e318168c82d (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doguet, V. et al. Neuromuscular changes and damage after isoload versus isokinetic eccentric exercise. Med. Sci. Sports. Exerc. 48, 2526&#x2013;2535. https://doi.org/10.1249/mss.0000000000001042 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tee, J. C., Bosch, A. N. &amp; Lambert, M. I. Metabolic consequences of exercise-induced muscle damage. Sports Med. 37, 827&#x2013;836. https://doi.org/10.2165/00007256-200737100-00001 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macaluso, F., Isaacs, A. W. &amp; Myburgh, K. H. Preferential type II muscle fiber damage from plyometric exercise. J. Athl. Train. 47, 414&#x2013;420. https://doi.org/10.4085/1062-6050-47.4.13 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyldahl, R. D. &amp; Hubal, M. J. Lengthening our perspective: morphological, cellular, and molecular responses to eccentric exercise. Muscle Nerve. 49, 155&#x2013;170. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.24077 (2014).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>