<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41896592</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2730-664X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Communications medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Commun Med (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of oliceridine on hypoxia during sedated hysteroscopy: a Phase 4 randomized clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s43856-026-01562-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Hypoxia is a common complication in hysteroscopic surgery under sedation with conventional opioids. Oliceridine, a novel G protein-biased &#x3bc;-opioid receptor agonist, provides effective analgesia with fewer opioid-related adverse events, but its impact on intraoperative hypoxia in hysteroscopy remains unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a single-center, prospective, double-blind, randomized clinical trial (TRN: ChiCTR2400090351), patients scheduled for hysteroscopic surgery under sedation were enrolled. Participants were randomized (1:1) to receive sufentanil (0.15&#x2009;&#x3bc;g&#xb7;kg&#x207b;&#xb9;) or oliceridine (40&#x2009;&#x3bc;g&#xb7;kg&#x207b;&#xb9;), combined with propofol (1.5&#x2009;mg&#xb7;kg&#x207b;&#xb9;). The primary outcome was the incidence of intraoperative hypoxia from sedative drug initiation to hysteroscopy completion. Secondary outcomes included subclinical respiratory depression, severe hypoxia, airway interventions, supplemental propofol requirements, pain scores, arterial blood gas analysis, and patient and surgeon satisfaction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among 492 randomized patients, 482 (98%) completed the trial. The incidence of intraoperative hypoxia is significantly lower in the oliceridine group (24 [9.8%] of 246 patients) than that in the sufentanil group (48 [19.5%] of 246 patients; RR, 0.50 [95% CI, 0.32-0.79]; P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002). The lowest oxygen saturation is higher in the oliceridine group (99.0 [94.0, 100.0] vs 97.0 [90.0, 100.0], P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Compared to sufentanil group, oliceridine group requires less propofol intraoperatively (median difference: 10.0&#x2009;mg, 95% CI: 0.0 to 14.5; P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.03), has lower PaCO<sub>2</sub> in Post-Anesthesia Care Unit (median difference: 1.0&#x2009;mmHg, 95% CI: 0.0 to 2.0; P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.02) and a reduced base excess (mean difference: 0.34&#x2009;mmol/L, 95% CI: 0.03 to 0.66; P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.03). In addition, both patient satisfaction and surgeon satisfaction are significantly higher (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.003 and P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002) in oliceridine group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Oliceridine reduces the incidence of intraoperative hypoxia during hysteroscopic surgery under sedation, suggesting it may be a safer alternative to sufentanil.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Ye</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Anaesthesiology (Shanghai Jiaotong University, Ministry of Education), Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Tao</LastName><ForeName>Mingshu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The Affiliated Hospital of Xuzhou Medical University, Xuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Medical Products Administration Key Laboratory for Research and Evaluation of Narcotic and Psychotropic Drugs &amp; Jiangsu Province Key Laboratory of Anesthesiology &amp; Jiangsu Key Laboratory of Applied Technology of Anesthesia and Analgesia, Xuzhou Medical University, Xuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Biran</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Xia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Laboratory of Gynecologic Oncology, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sino European Life Expert Centre, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Xinyu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Jun-Li</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8932-4743</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The Affiliated Hospital of Xuzhou Medical University, Xuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Medical Products Administration Key Laboratory for Research and Evaluation of Narcotic and Psychotropic Drugs &amp; Jiangsu Province Key Laboratory of Anesthesiology &amp; Jiangsu Key Laboratory of Applied Technology of Anesthesia and Analgesia, Xuzhou Medical University, Xuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Weifeng</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1979-6304</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Anaesthesiology (Shanghai Jiaotong University, Ministry of Education), Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Liqun</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5801-7890</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China. lqyang72721@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Anaesthesiology (Shanghai Jiaotong University, Ministry of Education), Shanghai, China. lqyang72721@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Song</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7997-274X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Renji Hospital, Shanghai Jiaotong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China. zhangsong1031@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Anaesthesiology (Shanghai Jiaotong University, Ministry of Education), Shanghai, China. zhangsong1031@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>82371536</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82371517</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U23A2050</GrantID><Agency>&#xc9;cole Nationale d'Ing&#xe9;nieurs de Saint-Etienne (National Engineering School of Saint-&#xc9;tienne)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Commun Med (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918250414506676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2730-664X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>During hysteroscopic surgery, patients are often given medicines to reduce pain and discomfort. However, commonly used pain drugs can slow breathing and lead to low oxygen levels, which may be dangerous. Oliceridine is a new pain medicine designed to reduce these breathing-related side effects. In this study, nearly 500 women undergoing hysteroscopic surgery were randomly given either oliceridine or a conventional opioid, together with propofol. We closely monitored SpO<sub>2</sub> levels, breathing, and recovery. The results showed that patients receiving oliceridine had a lower incidence of intraoperative hypoxia and required less propofol. Patients and surgeons were also more satisfied. These findings suggest that oliceridine may be a safer sedation option for routine hysteroscopic procedures.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41896592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43856-026-01562-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s43856-026-01562-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shen, Y., Yang, W., Liu, J. &amp; Zhang, Y. Minimally invasive approaches for the early detection of endometrial cancer. Mol. Cancer 22, 53 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huchon, C. et al. Operative hysteroscopy vs vacuum aspiration for incomplete spontaneous abortion: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA 329, 1197&#x2013;1205 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orlando, M. S. &amp; Bradley, L. D. Implementation of office hysteroscopy for the evaluation and treatment of intrauterine pathology. Obstet. Gynecol. 140, 499&#x2013;513 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans, I. et al. Performance of the WID-qEC test versus sonography to detect uterine cancers in women with abnormal uterine bleeding (EPI-SURE): a prospective, consecutive observational cohort study in the UK. Lancet Oncol. 24, 1375&#x2013;1386 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, S., Choi, S. L., Nahm, F. S., Ryu, J. H. &amp; Do, S. H. Dexmedetomidine-remifentanil vs propofol-remifentanil for monitored anesthesia care during hysteroscopy: Randomized, single-blind, controlled trial. Medicine 99, e22712 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X., Li, S. &amp; Liu, J. Efficacy and safety of remimazolam besylate versus propofol during hysteroscopy: single-centre randomized controlled trial. BMC Anesthesiol. 21, 156 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bingol Tanriverdi, T., Koceroglu, I., Devrim, S. &amp; Gura Celik, M. Comparison of sedation with dexmedetomidine vs propofol during hysteroscopic surgery: Single-centre randomized controlled trial. J. Clin. Pharm. Ther. 44, 312&#x2013;317 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leverve, X. Metabolic and nutritional consequences of chronic hypoxia. Clin. Nutr. 17, 241&#x2013;251 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawley, J. S. et al. Normobaric hypoxia and symptoms of acute mountain sickness: elevated brain volume and intracranial hypertension. Ann. Neurol. 75, 890&#x2013;898 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, T. et al. Chronic intermittent hypoxia disrupts protective microgliosis in ischemic proliferative retinopathy. J. Neuroinflammation 22, 82 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neubauer, S., Newell, J. B. &amp; Ingwall, J. S. Metabolic consequences and predictability of ventricular fibrillation in hypoxia. A 31P- and 23Na-nuclear magnetic resonance study of the isolated rat heart. Circulation 86, 302&#x2013;310 (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez-Gerez, E., Fleming, I. N. &amp; Parson, S. H. A role for spinal cord hypoxia in neurodegeneration. Cell Death Dis. 10, 861 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, G. K. Hypoxia. 3. Hypoxia and neurotransmitter synthesis. Am. J. Physiol. Cell Physiol. 300, C743&#x2013;C751 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forceon AURbtASoAT, Non-Anesthesiologists SaAb. Practice guidelines for sedation and analgesia by non-anesthesiologists. Anesthesiology 96, 1004&#x2013;1017 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deitch, K., Miner, J., Chudnofsky, C. R., Dominici, P. &amp; Latta, D. Does end tidal CO<sub>2</sub> monitoring during emergency department procedural sedation and analgesia with propofol decrease the incidence of hypoxic events? A randomized, controlled trial. Ann. Emerg. Med. 55, 258&#x2013;264 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, M. &amp; Zhang, Y. Propofol addiction: the mechanism issues we need to know. Anesthesiol. Perioper. Sci. https://doi.org/10.1007/s44254-023-00046-y (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein, C. Opioid receptors. Annu Rev. Med. 67, 433&#x2013;451 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>French, A. R. &amp; van Rijn, R. M. An updated assessment of the translational promise of G-protein-biased kappa opioid receptor agonists to treat pain and other indications without debilitating adverse effects. Pharm. Res. 177, 106091 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler, E. R., Shah, M., Gruschkus, S. K. &amp; Raju, A. Cost and quality implications of opioid-based postsurgical pain control using adminis- trative claims data from a large health system: opioid-related adverse events and their impact on clinical and economic outcomes. J. Hum. Pharmacol. Drug Ther. 33, 383&#x2013;391 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahan, A. et al. Benefit and risk evaluation of biased mu-receptor agonist oliceridine versus morphine. Anesthesiology 133, 559&#x2013;568 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang, Y. et al. Molecular recognition of morphine and fentanyl by the human mu-opioid receptor. Cell 185, 4361&#x2013;4375.e4319 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simons, P. et al. Respiratory effects of biased ligand oliceridine in older volunteers: a pharmacokinetic-pharmacodynamic comparison with morphine. Anesthesiology 138, 249&#x2013;263 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soergel, D. G. et al. Biased agonism of the mu-opioid receptor by TRV130 increases analgesia and reduces on-target adverse effects versus morphine: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover study in healthy volunteers. Pain 155, 1829&#x2013;1835 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergese, S. D. et al. ATHENA: a phase 3, open-label study of the safety and effectiveness of oliceridine (TRV130), a G-protein selective agonist at the micro-opioid receptor, in patients with moderate to severe acute pain requiring parenteral opioid therapy. J. Pain. Res 12, 3113&#x2013;3126 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daksla, N., Wang, A., Jin, Z., Gupta, A. &amp; Bergese, S. D. Oliceridine for the management of moderate to severe acute postoperative pain: a narrative review. Drug Des. Devel Ther. 17, 875&#x2013;886 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, Y. et al. High-flow nasal oxygen reduces the incidence of hypoxia in sedated hysteroscopy for assisted reproduction. Front Med. 9, 929096 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Wang, X., Liu, H. &amp; Han, R. Effect of butorphanol on visceral pain in patients undergoing gastrointestinal endoscopy: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Anesthesiol. 23, 93 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeWire, S. M. et al. A G protein-biased ligand at the mu-opioid receptor is potently analgesic with reduced gastrointestinal and respiratory dysfunction compared with morphine. J. Pharm. Exp. Ther. 344, 708&#x2013;717 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu, J., Hu, W., Lu, Y. &amp; Tang, H. Efficacy and safety of oliceridine treatment in patients with postoperative pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Expert Rev. Clin. Pharm. 16, 589&#x2013;599 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill, R. et al. Assessment of the potential of novel and classical opioids to induce respiratory depression in mice. Br. J. Pharm. 180, 3160&#x2013;3174 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, B. et al. A comparative evaluation of the safety and efficacy of oliceridine and sufentanil in gastrointestinal endoscopy: a single-center, randomized controlled trial. Drug Des. Devel Ther. 19, 5111&#x2013;5121 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biskupiak, J., Oderda, G., Brixner, D. &amp; Wandstrat, T. L. Gastrointestinal adverse effects associated with the use of intravenous oliceridine compared with intravenous hydromorphone or fentanyl in acute pain management utilizing adjusted indirect treatment comparison methods. J. Comp. Eff. Res. 13, e230041 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wani, S. et al. Obesity as a risk factor for sedation-related complications during propofol-mediated sedation for advanced endoscopic procedures. Gastrointest. Endosc. 74, 1238&#x2013;1247 (2011).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>