<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41888789</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1477-3155</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of nanobiotechnology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Nanobiotechnology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Endothelialized human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cell-derived exosomes enhances angiogenesis and stabilizes the blood-spinal cord barrier after spinal cord injury.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12951-026-04309-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Restoration of vascular structure and function is pivotal for neurological recovery following spinal cord injury (SCI), yet repairing the blood-spinal cord barrier (BSCB) remains a significant challenge. In this study, we demonstrate that exosomes (Exos) derived from endothelialized human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells (E&#x2011;UCMSCs) markedly enhance angiogenesis, improve vascular function, and promote neurological recovery. Human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells were induced to differentiate into endothelial&#x2011;like cells, and RNA&#x2011;sequencing revealed upregulation of genes associated with angiogenesis and vascular barrier integrity, alongside activation of relevant signaling pathways. In a co&#x2011;culture system, E&#x2011;UCMSC&#x2011;derived Exos significantly enhanced bEnd.3 cell migration and BSCB stability. To enable targeted delivery to neovasculature, Exos were engineered with RGD peptides (RGD&#x2011;E&#x2011;UCMSC&#x2011;Exos) via lentiviral modification. In vivo, these modified Exos preferentially localized to neovascular endothelial cells, promoted angiogenesis, reinforced BSCB integrity, and improved neurological outcomes in SCI mouse models. Proteomic profiling identified key angiogenic and barrier&#x2011;stabilizing factors carried by RGD&#x2011;E&#x2011;UCMSC&#x2011;Exos, including MMP2, FLT1, TIMP1, GAS6, CTHRC1, and NEO1, which likely mediate their therapeutic effects. Collectively, these findings provide novel mechanistic insights and establish a novel strong preclinical foundation for exosome&#x2011;based therapies in SCI.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Quanbo</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital, Hengyang Medical School, University of South China, Hengyang, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Wentao</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital, Hengyang Medical School, University of South China, Hengyang, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Cardiovascular Disease, The First Affiliated Hospital, Hengyang Medical School, University of South China, Hengyang, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xue</LastName><ForeName>Jingbo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital, Hengyang Medical School, University of South China, Hengyang, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xuelin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital, Hengyang Medical School, University of South China, Hengyang, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Jinghua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital, Hengyang Medical School, University of South China, Hengyang, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Zhun</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital, Hengyang Medical School, University of South China, Hengyang, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ming</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital, Hengyang Medical School, University of South China, Hengyang, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yunlong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital, Hengyang Medical School, University of South China, Hengyang, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ouyang</LastName><ForeName>Zhihua</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital, Hengyang Medical School, University of South China, Hengyang, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Cheng</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital, Hengyang Medical School, University of South China, Hengyang, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Yiguo</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital, Hengyang Medical School, University of South China, Hengyang, Hunan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Liyuan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery and Orthopaedics, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, China. jiangliyuanxy@csu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Organ Injury, Aging and Regenerative Medicine of Hunan Province, Changsha, Hunan, China. jiangliyuanxy@csu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Geriatric Disorders, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, China. jiangliyuanxy@csu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital, Hengyang Medical School, University of South China, Hengyang, Hunan, China. xieyong@usc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>82572949 and 82202722</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>82502905</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024JJ6636 and 2025JJ40098</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Hunan Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2025JJ60555</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Hunan Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>24B0395</GrantID><Agency>Research Foundation of Education Bureau of Hunan Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Nanobiotechnology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101152208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1477-3155</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Angiogenesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood-spinal cord barrier</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endothelialized human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Engineered exosomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal cord injury</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: All procedures were approved by The First Affiliated Hospital of University of South China (2025LL0205001) and were conducted in accordance with established guidelines. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41888789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12951-026-04309-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12951-026-04309-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Global. regional, and national burden of spinal cord injury, 1990&#x2013;2019: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019. Lancet Neurol. 2023;22:1026&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Shang Z, Zhang W, Hu X, Shen R, Zhang K, Zhang Y, Zhang L, Liu B, Pang M, Rong L. Global, regional, and national burden of spinal cord injury from 1990 to 2021 and projections for 2050: A systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease 2021 study. Ageing Res Rev. 2025;103:102598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin LY, Li J, Wang KF, Xia WW, Zhu ZQ, Wang CR, et al. Blood-spinal cord barrier in spinal cord injury: a review. J Neurotrauma. 2021;38:1203&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran AP, Warren PM, Silver J. The biology of regeneration failure and success after spinal cord injury. Physiol Rev. 2018;98:881&#x2013;917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figley SA, Khosravi R, Legasto JM, Tseng YF, Fehlings MG. Characterization of vascular disruption and blood-spinal cord barrier permeability following traumatic spinal cord injury. J Neurotrauma. 2014;31:541&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar H, Ropper AE, Lee S-H, Han I. Propitious therapeutic modulators to prevent blood-spinal cord barrier disruption in spinal cord injury. Mol Neurobiol. 2017;54:3578&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aub&#xe9; B, L&#xe9;vesque SA, Par&#xe9; A, Chamma &#xc9;, K&#xe9;bir H, Gorina R, L&#xe9;cuyer MA, Alvarez JI, De Koninck Y, Engelhardt B, et al. Neutrophils mediate blood-spinal cord barrier disruption in demyelinating neuroinflammatory diseases. J Immunol. 2014;193:2438&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolma S, Kumar H. Neutrophil, extracellular matrix components, and their interlinked action in promoting secondary pathogenesis after spinal cord injury. Mol Neurobiol. 2021;58:4652&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao T, Chen H, Huang W, Xu S, Liu P, Zou W, Pang M, Xu Y, Bai X, Liu B, et al. hUC-MSC-mediated recovery of subacute spinal cord injury through enhancing the pivotal subunits beta3 and gamma2 of the GABA(A) receptor. Theranostics. 2022;12:3057&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro TB, Duarte AS, Longhini AL, Pradella F, Farias AS, Luzo AC, Oliveira AL. Olalla Saad ST: Neuroprotection and immunomodulation by xenografted human mesenchymal stem cells following spinal cord ventral root avulsion. Sci Rep. 2015;5:16167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Pang M, Chen YY, Zhang LM, Liu H, Tan J, Liu B, Rong LM. Human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells to treat spinal cord injury in the early chronic phase: study protocol for a prospective, multicenter, randomized, placebo-controlled, single-blinded clinical trial. Neural Regen Res. 2020;15:1532&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Lin Y, Liu Q, He J, Xiang P, Wang D, Hu X, Chen J, Zhu W, Yu H. Growth differentiation factor 11 promotes differentiation of MSCs into endothelial-like cells for angiogenesis. J Cell Mol Med. 2020;24:8703&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning H, Liu G, Lin G, Yang R, Lue TF, Lin CS. Fibroblast growth factor 2 promotes endothelial differentiation of adipose tissue-derived stem cells. J Sex Med. 2009;6:967&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu X, Zhang Y, Zhao X, Zhang S, Wu J, Guo H, Hu Y. Enhancement of endothelial differentiation of adipose derived mesenchymal stem cells by a three-dimensional culture system of microwell. Biomaterials. 2015;53:600&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung E, Ou S, Ahn SS, Yeo H, Lee YH, Shin SY. The JNK-EGR1 signaling axis promotes TNF-alpha-induced endothelial differentiation of human mesenchymal stem cells via VEGFR2 expression. Cell Death Differ. 2023;30:356&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CH, Wang TM, Young TH, Lai YK, Yen ML. The critical role of ECM proteins within the human MSC niche in endothelial differentiation. Biomaterials. 2013;34:4223&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rani S, Ritter T. The Exosome - A Naturally Secreted Nanoparticle and its Application to Wound Healing. Adv Mater. 2016;28:5542&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rani S, Ryan AE, Griffin MD, Ritter T. Mesenchymal stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles: toward cell-free therapeutic applications. Mol Ther. 2015;23:812&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu A, Lin D, Zhao H, Chen L, Cai B, Lin K, Shen SG. Optimized BMSC-derived osteoinductive exosomes immobilized in hierarchical scaffold via lyophilization for bone repair through Bmpr2/Acvr2b competitive receptor-activated Smad pathway. Biomaterials. 2021;272:120718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CP, Mardini O, Ericsson M, Prabhakar S, Maguire C, Chen JW, Tannous BA, Breakefield XO. Dynamic biodistribution of extracellular vesicles in vivo using a multimodal imaging reporter. ACS Nano. 2014;8:483&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arosio D, Casagrande C, Manzoni L. Integrin-mediated drug delivery in cancer and cardiovascular diseases with peptide-functionalized nanoparticles. Curr Med Chem. 2012;19:3128&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danhier F, Le Breton A, Preat V. RGD-based strategies to target alpha(v) beta(3) integrin in cancer therapy and diagnosis. Mol Pharm. 2012;9:2961&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Wu J, Wu J, Fan Q, Zhou J, Wu J, Liu S, Zang J, Ye J, Xiao M, et al. Exosome-mediated targeted delivery of miR-210 for angiogenic therapy after cerebral ischemia in mice. J Nanobiotechnol. 2019;17:29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo CC, Pereira NB, Pereira LX, Oliveira LAM, Campos PP, Andrade SP, Moro L. Double immunofluorescence labeling for CD31 and CD105 as a marker for polyether polyurethane-induced angiogenesis in mice. Histol Histopathol. 2019;34:257&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casella GT, Marcillo A, Bunge MB, Wood PM. New vascular tissue rapidly replaces neural parenchyma and vessels destroyed by a contusion injury to the rat spinal cord. Exp Neurol. 2002;173:63&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fassbender JM, Whittemore SR, Hagg T. Targeting microvasculature for neuroprotection after SCI. Neurotherapeutics. 2011;8:240&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck KD, Nguyen HX, Galvan MD, Salazar DL, Woodruff TM, Anderson AJ. Quantitative analysis of cellular inflammation after traumatic spinal cord injury: evidence for a multiphasic inflammatory response in the acute to chronic environment. Brain. 2010;133:433&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Liu H, Yang M, Bai Y, Ren H, Zou Y, et al. RNA-seq based transcriptome analysis of endothelial differentiation of bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2020;59:834&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotoh S, Kawabori M, Fujimura M. Intranasal administration of stem cell-derived exosomes for central nervous system diseases. Neural Regen Res. 2024;19:1249&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo S, Perets N, Betzer O, Ben-Shaul S, Sheinin A, Michaelevski I, et al. Intranasal delivery of mesenchymal stem cell derived exosomes loaded with phosphatase and tensin homolog siRNA repairs complete spinal cord injury. ACS Nano. 2019;13:10015&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng H, Li Y, Ji W, Zhao R, Lu Z, Shen J, Wu Y, Wang J, Hao Q, Wang J, et al. Intranasal Administration of Self-Oriented Nanocarriers Based on Therapeutic Exosomes for Synergistic Treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease. ACS Nano. 2022;16:869&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Sun Y, Liu Y, Zhao J, Liu Q, Xu J, Qin Y, He R, Yuan F, Wu T, et al. Targeted Delivery of RGD-CD146(+)CD271(+) Human Umbilical Cord Mesenchymal Stem Cell-Derived Exosomes Promotes Blood-Spinal Cord Barrier Repair after Spinal Cord Injury. ACS Nano. 2023;17:18008&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer I, Dulin JN, Lane MA. Transplanting neural progenitor cells to restore connectivity after spinal cord injury. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2020;21:366&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye J, Jin S, Cai W, Chen X, Zheng H, Zhang T, Lu W, Li X, Liang C, Chen Q, et al. Rationally Designed, Self-Assembling, Multifunctional Hydrogel Depot Repairs Severe Spinal Cord Injury. Adv Healthc Mater. 2021;10:e2100242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan J, Miao X, Schluter D, Lin L, Wang X. Extracellular vesicles in neuroinflammation: pathogenesis, diagnosis, and therapy. Mol Ther. 2021;29:1946&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simons M, Gordon E, Claesson-Welsh L. Mechanisms and regulation of endothelial VEGF receptor signalling. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2016;17:611&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Duan C, Wang P, Zhang S, Gao Y, Lu S, et al. 4-octyl itaconate alleviates myocardial ischemia-reperfusion injury through promoting angiogenesis via ERK signaling activation. Adv Sci (Weinh). 2025;12(10):2411554. https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202411554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamaya S, Ozawa H, Kanno H, Kishimoto KN, Sekiguchi A, Tateda S, Yahata K, Ito K, Shimokawa H, Itoi E. Low-energy extracorporeal shock wave therapy promotes vascular endothelial growth factor expression and improves locomotor recovery after spinal cord injury. J Neurosurg. 2014;121:1514&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widenfalk J, Lipson A, Jubran M, Hofstetter C, Ebendal T, Cao Y, Olson L. Vascular endothelial growth factor improves functional outcome and decreases secondary degeneration in experimental spinal cord contusion injury. Neuroscience. 2003;120:951&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laronha H, Caldeira J. Structure and function of human matrix metalloproteinases. Cells 2020;9(5):1076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanjul-Fernandez M, Folgueras AR, Cabrera S, Lopez-Otin C. Matrix metalloproteinases: evolution, gene regulation and functional analysis in mouse models. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2010;1803:3&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gialeli C, Theocharis AD, Karamanos NK. Roles of matrix metalloproteinases in cancer progression and their pharmacological targeting. FEBS J. 2011;278:16&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verslegers M, Lemmens K, Van Hove I, Moons L. Matrix metalloproteinase-2 and &#x2212; 9 as promising benefactors in development, plasticity and repair of the nervous system. Prog Neurobiol. 2013;105:60&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim C, Kim HJ, Lee H, Lee H, Lee SJ, Lee ST, et al. Mesenchymal stem cell transplantation promotes functional recovery through MMP2/STAT3 related astrogliosis after spinal cord injury. Int J Stem Cells. 2019;12:331&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myngbay A, Manarbek L, Ludbrook S, Kunz J. The Role of Collagen Triple Helix Repeat-Containing 1 Protein (CTHRC1) in Rheumatoid Arthritis. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:2426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toomey BH, Mitrovic SA, Lindner-Liaw M, Leon Vazquez RG, Kacer D, Ryzhov S, Prudovsky I, Lindner V. Activated CTHRC1 promotes glycolysis in endothelial cells: Implications for metabolism and angiogenesis. Vascul Pharmacol. 2023;153:107246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang ZY, Zhen ZD, Fan DY, Wang PG, An J. Axl alleviates neuroinflammation and delays Japanese encephalitis progression in mice. Virol Sin. 2021;36:667&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian P, Zhang H, Ye C, Luo C, Jiang H, Wang Y, Dong Y, Yang J, Zhang F, Wang X, et al. GAS6 as a potential target to alleviate neuroinflammation during Japanese encephalitis in mouse models. J Neuroinflammation. 2024;21:231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson RA, Griffiths SC, van de Haar LL, Malinauskas T, van Battum EY, Zelina P, Schwab RA, Karia D, Malinauskaite L, Brignani S, et al. Simultaneous binding of Guidance Cues NET1 and RGM blocks extracellular NEO1 signaling. Cell. 2021;184:2103&#x2013;e21202131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao LL, Hu JX, Li Q, Lee D, Ren X, Zhang JS, Sun D, Zhang HS, Wang YG, Mei L, Xiong WC. Astrocytic neogenin/netrin-1 pathway promotes blood vessel homeostasis and function in mouse cortex. J Clin Invest. 2020;130:6490&#x2013;509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei B, Liu W, Jin L, Huang Y, Cheng W, Fan H, Su S, Jin F, Zhang X, Yang Z, et al. Hepcidin depending on astrocytic NEO1 ameliorates blood-brain barrier dysfunction after subarachnoid hemorrhage. Cell Death Dis. 2024;15:569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabral-Pacheco GA, Garza-Veloz I, Castruita-De la Rosa C, Ramirez-Acuna JM, Perez-Romero BA, Guerrero-Rodriguez JF, et al. The roles of matrix metalloproteinases and their inhibitors in human diseases. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(24):9739. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms21249739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu MB, Wang W, Gao JM, Li F, Shi JS, Gong QH. Icariside II attenuates cerebral ischemia/reperfusion-induced blood-brain barrier dysfunction in rats via regulating the balance of MMP9/TIMP1. Acta Pharmacol Sin. 2020;41:1547&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang J, Kang Y, Huang L, Wu L, Peng Y. TIMP1 preserves the blood-brain barrier through interacting with CD63/integrin beta 1 complex and regulating downstream FAK/RhoA signaling. Acta Pharm Sin B. 2020;10:987&#x2013;1003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang T, Chen H, Hu L, Ye J, Jing C, Xu C, Wu X, Chen Y, Chen Z, Zhou H, et al. TIMP1 protects against blood-brain barrier disruption after subarachnoid haemorrhage by inhibiting ubiquitination of astrocytic beta1-integrin. Stroke Vasc Neurol. 2024;9:671&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merlini M, Rafalski VA, Rios Coronado PE, Gill TM, Ellisman M, Muthukumar G, Subramanian KS, Ryu JK, Syme CA, Davalos D, et al. Fibrinogen Induces Microglia-Mediated Spine Elimination and Cognitive Impairment in an Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease Model. Neuron. 2019;101:1099&#x2013;e11081096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLarnon JG. A leaky blood-brain barrier to fibrinogen contributes to oxidative damage in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Antioxidants (Basel). 2021;11(1):102. https://doi.org/10.3390/antiox11010102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bessa-Gon&#xe7;alves M, Ribeiro-Machado C, Costa M, Ribeiro CC, Barbosa JN, Barbosa MA, Santos SG. Magnesium incorporation in fibrinogen scaffolds promotes macrophage polarization towards M2 phenotype. Acta Biomater. 2023;155:667&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>