<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41834045</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1749-799X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of orthopaedic surgery and research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Orthop Surg Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy and safety of perioperative intravenous dexamethasone in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients undergoing total hip arthroplasty: a prospective randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13018-026-06808-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to evaluate the efficacy and safety of perioperative intravenous dexamethasone (Dexa) in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) undergoing total hip arthroplasty (THA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this prospective, single-blind randomized trial (Registration No.: MR-45-23-047982; Registration Date: December 7, 2023), 60 T2DM patients undergoing THA were assigned to either the Dexa or control group. Outcomes included white blood cell count (WBC), C-reactive protein (CRP), visual analogue scale (VAS) scores, blood glucose, nausea and vomiting, medication requirements, complications, and hospital stay.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Compared with controls, the Dexa group had lower WBC on postoperative days 2&#x2009;~&#x2009;3 (day 2: 9.20&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.28 vs.10.56&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.34&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>9</sup>/L, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.007; day 3: 8.02&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.34 vs. 9.22&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.49&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>9</sup>/L, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002)and reduced CRP on days 1&#x2009;~&#x2009;3 (day 1: 38.20 vs. 63.50&#xa0;mg/L, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.040; day 2: 86.00 vs. 101.50&#xa0;mg/L, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.010; day 3: 78.00 vs. 95.20&#xa0;mg/L, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.044). Transient hyperglycemia was observed in the Dexa group on postoperative day 1, with higher median blood glucose (8.90 vs. 8.35 mmol/L, P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01) and peak glucose (11.80 vs. 10.35 mmol/L, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.031) but showed no differences thereafter. VAS pain scores at rest and during activity were lower in the Dexa group on postoperative days 1&#x2009;~&#x2009;2 (all P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01). Dexa reduced the need for rescue tramadol (4 vs. 12 patients, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.020) and metoclopramide (1 vs. 8 patients, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.026), and lowered PONV incidence (3.33% vs. 23.30%, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.026). Hospital stay was shorter in the Dexa group (5.67&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.13 vs. 6.70&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.29 days, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002), with no differences in 90-day complications (all P&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Perioperative Dexa administration improves early recovery outcomes in patients with T2DM undergoing THA without compromising short-term safety, although it may cause transient hyperglycemia. However, the relatively small sample size, limited follow-up period, and lack of systematic evaluation of potential complications highlight the need for larger, longer-term studies to further strengthen these observations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Wen-Hui</ForeName><Initials>WH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jinan University, Guangzhou, 510630, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery and Sports Medicine, Guangxi Academy of Medical Sciences, People's Hospital of Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, Nanning, 530021, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Fu-Lin</ForeName><Initials>FL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jinan University, Guangzhou, 510630, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery and Sports Medicine, Guangxi Academy of Medical Sciences, People's Hospital of Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, Nanning, 530021, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Wen-Wen</ForeName><Initials>WW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jinan University, Guangzhou, 510630, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery and Sports Medicine, Guangxi Academy of Medical Sciences, People's Hospital of Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, Nanning, 530021, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Xiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery and Sports Medicine, Guangxi Academy of Medical Sciences, People's Hospital of Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, Nanning, 530021, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zheng-Liang</ForeName><Initials>ZL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery and Sports Medicine, Guangxi Academy of Medical Sciences, People's Hospital of Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, Nanning, 530021, People's Republic of China. 974035822@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Dong</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery and Sports Medicine, Guangxi Academy of Medical Sciences, People's Hospital of Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, Nanning, 530021, People's Republic of China. gjydyxwk@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Z-A20220109</GrantID><Agency>Guangxi Health Commission Plan Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Z20200911</GrantID><Agency>Guangxi Health Commission Plan Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>YWJKJJHKYJJ-B20128DS</GrantID><Agency>Beijing Medical and Health Public Welfare Foundation Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Grant Nos. AA23023004</GrantID><Agency>Guangxi Science and Technology Major Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Orthop Surg Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101265112</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1749-799X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dexamethasone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Perioperative management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Total hip arthroplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted in accordance with the ethical principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. The study protocol was approved by the Ethics Committee of the People's Hospital of Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region (Approval No.: KY-ZC-2022-109). Prior to enrollment, all participants provided written informed consent. The trial was registered with the National Health Information Security Platform and the Medical Research Registration and Filing Information System (Trial Registration No.: MR-45-23-047982). Consent for publication: Written informed consent for publication of the clinical details was obtained from the patient. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41834045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-026-06808-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13018-026-06808-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dissanayake R, Du HN,Robertson IK, et al. Does dexamethasone reduce hospital readiness for discharge, pain, nausea, and early patient satisfaction in hip and knee arthroplasty? a Randomized, Controlled Tria. J Arthroplast. 2018;33(11):3429&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apfel CC, Korttila K, Abdalla M, et al. A factorial trial of six interventions for the prevention of postoperative nausea and vomiting. N Engl J Med. 2004;350(24):51&#x2013;2441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villar J, Ferrando C,Mart&#xed;nez D, et al. Dexamethasone treatment for the acute respiratory distress syndrome: a multicentre, randomised controlled trial. Lancet Respiratory Med. 2020;8(3):267&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes PJ, Adcock IM. Glucocorticoid resistance in inflammatory diseases. Lancet. 2009;373(9678):1905&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xe4;cke H, D&#xf6;cke WD, Asadullah K. Mechanisms involved in the side effects of glucocorticoids. Pharmacol Ther. 2002;96(1):23&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudy MD, Ahuja NK, Aaronson AJ. Diabetes and hyperglycemia in lower-extremity total joint arthroplasty. Jbjs Rev. 2018;6(5):10&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo Y, Wang C, Yin D, et al. Efficacy of dexamethasone in reducing pain and inflammation and accelerating total hip arthroplasty postoperative recovery: a randomized controlled trial. J Perianesthesia Nurs. 2024;39(4):589&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alessio-mazzola M, D&#x2019;andrea G, Abu-mukh A, et al. Effect of systemic steroids administration in the clinical outcome of total hip arthroplasty: a systematic review and meta-analysis of prospective randomized controlled trials[J]. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2024;145(1):78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogurtsova K, Guariguata L, Barengo NC, et al. Idf diabetes atlas: global estimates of undiagnosed diabetes in adults for 2021. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2022;183:109118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazela P, Sewerynek E. Effect of Chronic Inflammation on Bone Density in Type 2 Diabetes Following Total Hip Arthroplasty[J]. Ortop Traumatologia Rehabilitacja. 2023;25(6):307&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stryker LS, Abdel MP, Morrey ME, et al. Elevated postoperative blood glucose and preoperative hemoglobin a1c are associated with increased wound complications following total joint arthroplasty. J Bone Joint Surg. 2013;95(9):808&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wier J, Liu KC,Richardson MK, et al. Higher blood glucose levels on the day of surgery are associated with an increased risk of periprosthetic joint infection after total hip arthroplasty. J Bone Joint Surg. 2024;106(4):276&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams V, Ansari MJU,Jaju A, et al. Impact of perioperative dexamethasone on hospital length of stay and glycemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes undergoing total hip arthroplasty. J Patient-centered Res Reviews. 2023;10(1):4&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei Y, Huang Z, Huang Q, et al. Is a Split-dose intravenous dexamethasone regimen superior to a single high dose in reducing pain and improving function after total hip arthroplasty? a randomized blinded placebo-controlled trial. Bone Joint J. 2020;102&#x2013;B(11):1497&#x2013;504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen DC, Jedrzynski NA,Michelson JD, et al. The effect of dexamethasone on postoperative blood glucose in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus undergoing total joint arthroplasty. J Arthroplast. 2020;35(3):671&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arraut J, Thomas J, Oakley CT, et al. Effects of dexamethasone on postoperative glycemic control in diabetic patients following primary total joint arthroplasty: a retrospective cohort study. J Arthroplast. 2023;38(7):138&#x2013;1442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Chen Y, Li Y, et al. Enhanced recovery after surgery in patients after hip and knee arthroplasty: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Postgrad Med J. 2024;100(1181):159&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G, Gong M, Wang Y, et al. Effect of methylprednisolone on pain management in total knee or hip arthroplasty. Clin J Pain. 2018;34(10):967&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cain DW, Cidlowski JA. Immune regulation by glucocorticoids. Nat Rev Immunol. 2017;17(4):233&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#x105;dek A, Liszka H, Zaj&#x105;c M. The effect of pre-operative high doses of methylprednisolone on pain management and convalescence after total hip replacement in elderly: a double-blind randomized study. Int Orthop. 2021;45(4):857&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mckee MD. Efficacy and safety of steroid use for postoperative pain relief. J Bone Joint Surg Am Vol. 2007;89(5):11341134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Wang Q, Li D, et al. Meta-analysis of retrospective studies suggests that the pre-operative opioid use is associated with an increased risk of adverse outcomes in total hip and or knee arthroplasty. Int Orthop. 2021;45(8):1923&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan MD. Depression effects on long-term prescription opioid use, abuse, and addiction. Clin J Pain. 2018;34(9):878&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan TCW, Cheung CW, Wong SSC, et al. Preoperative dexamethasone for pain relief after total knee arthroplasty. Eur J Anaesthesiol. 2020;37(12):1157&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly ME, Turcotte JJ, Aja JM, et al. Impact of dexamethasone on length of stay and early pain control in direct anterior approach total hip arthroplasty with neuraxial anesthesia. J Arthroplast. 2021;36(3):1009&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arraut J, Thomas J, Oakley CT, et al. The aahks best podium presentation research award: a second dose of dexamethasone reduces postoperative opioid consumption and pain in total joint arthroplasty. J Arthroplast. 2023;38(7):21&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovac AL. Update on the management of postoperative nausea and vomiting. Drugs. 2013;73(14):1525&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Yang Q,Lin J, et al. Risk Factors of postoperative nausea and vomiting after total hip arthroplasty or total knee arthroplasty: a retrospective study. Annals Translational Med. 2020;8(17):1088&#x2013;1088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho YJ, Choi GJ, Ahn EJ, et al. Pharmacologic interventions for postoperative nausea and vomiting after thyroidectomy: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(1):243865.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaikh SI, Nagarekha D, Hegade G, et al. Postoperative nausea and vomiting: a simple yet complex problem. Anesthesia Essays Resear. 2016;10(3):388&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan TJ, Belani KG, Bergese S, et al. Fourth consensus guidelines for the management of postoperative nausea and vomiting. Anesth Analgesia. 2020;131(2):411&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laufenberg-feldmann R,M&#xfc;ller M, Ferner M, et al. Is &#x2018;anxiety sensitivity&#x2019; predictive of postoperative nausea and vomiting?. Eur J Anaesthesiol. 2019;36(5):369&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bustos FP, Coobs BR,Moskal JT. A retrospective analysis of the use of intravenous dexamethasone for postoperative nausea and vomiting in total joint replacement. Arthroplasty Today. 2019;5(2):211&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Backes JR, Bentley JC, Politi JR, et al. Dexamethasone reduces length of hospitalization and improves postoperative pain and nausea after total joint arthroplasty. J Arthroplast. 2013;28(8):11&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui A, Fan H, Zhang Y, et al. Dexamethasone-induced Kr&#xfc;ppel-like factor 9 expression promotes hepatic gluconeogenesis and hyperglycemia. J Clin Invest. 2019;129(6):2266&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mou P, Zhao X, Cai X, et al. The Effect of preoperative different dexamethasone regimens on postoperative glycemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus undergoing total joint arthroplasty: a retrospective cohort study. J Orthop Surg Res. 2024;19(1):14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kremers HM, Lewallen LW, Mabry TM, et al. Diabetes mellitus, hyperglycemia, hemoglobin A1c and the risk of prosthetic joint infections in total hip and knee arthropLasty. J Arthroplast. 2015;30(3):439&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heckmann ND, Wang JC, Piple AS, et al. Is Intraoperative dexamethasone utilization associated with increased rates of periprosthetic joint infection following total joint arthroplasty?. J Arthroplast. 2023;38(2):224&#x2013;2311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones IA, Wier J, Liu KC, et al. Dexamethasone-associated hyperglycemia is not associated with infectious complications after total joint arthroplasty in diabetic patients. J Arthroplast. 2024;39(8):43&#x2013;525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson AB, Bala A, Wellman SS, et al. Perioperative dexamethasone administration does not increase the incidence of postoperative infection in total hip and knee arthroplasty: a retrospective analysis. J Arthroplast. 2016;31(8):1784&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vuorinen MA, Palanne RA, M&#xe4;kinen TJ, et al. Infection safety of dexamethasone in total hip and total knee arthroplasty: a study of eighteen thousand, eight hundred and seventy two operations. Int Orthop. 2019;43(8):1787&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koning ACAM, Meulen MVD,Schaap D, et al. Neuropsychiatric adverse effects of synthetic glucocorticoids: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Endocrinol Metabolism. 2024;109(6):1442&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>