<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41851777</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1749-799X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of orthopaedic surgery and research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Orthop Surg Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Arthroscopic dual-reduction fixation for acromioclavicular joint dislocation: transosseous and half-cerclage fixation outcomes.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13018-026-06802-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">To our knowledge, this is the first clinical outcome study of the arthroscopic dual-reduction fixation technique combining transosseous and U-shaped half-cerclage suspensory constructs for acromioclavicular joint dislocation(ACJ). This study evaluates the clinical outcomes of an arthroscopic dual-reduction fixation technique for the treatment of ACJ dislocation and compares it with the traditional single bundle coracoclavicular (CC) ligament reconstruction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This retrospective study included 30 patients with acute acromioclavicular joint dislocation, divided into an arthroscopic dual-reduction fixation group (Group 1, n&#x2009;=&#x2009;12) and a traditional suture-button reconstruction with a looped clavicular plate group (Group 2, n&#x2009;=&#x2009;18). All patients were followed up postoperatively for at least 6 months. Postoperative evaluations were performed using patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs) to assess shoulder joint function and pain relief. Changes in shoulder joint range of motion (ROM) were recorded and compared between the two groups. Additionally, X-ray imaging was used to measure the coracoclavicular distance (CCD) and the extent of the clavicular bone tunnel widening (CBTW) in both groups, assessing the reduction and stability of the ACJ. Postoperative complications were also recorded and analyzed for both groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The body mass index (BMI) and surgical duration in Group 1 were significantly higher than those in Group 2, while the follow-up period in Group 2 was significantly longer than in Group 1. In terms of functional scores, no significant differences were found between the two groups at any follow-up time point. However, the VAS score at 3 months postoperatively was significantly lower in Group 1 than in Group 2 (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Regarding shoulder joint ROM recovery, Group 1 demonstrated more significant improvement at 3 months postoperatively compared to Group 2 (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Radiographic findings showed that the CCD at 6 months postoperatively was significantly smaller in Group 1 compared to Group 2 (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), and the degree of bone tunnel enlargement was notably smaller. In terms of complications, Group 1 had only one case of complication, while Group 2 had nine cases of recurrence of instability, AC arthritis, and implant sinking or migration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Arthroscopic dual-reduction fixation was associated with the combined use of transosseous passage and a U-shaped half-cerclage suspensory construct fixation, with improved maintenance of reduction, less clavicular tunnel enlargement, and fewer complications compared with traditional single-bundle reconstruction in the early postoperative period.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yanbo</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Sports Medicine and Arthroscopy, Fuyang People's Hospital Affiliated to Anhui Medical University, Anhui, 236000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yanlong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Sports Medicine and Arthroscopy, Fuyang People's Hospital Affiliated to Anhui Medical University, Anhui, 236000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zhenyu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Sports Medicine and Arthroscopy, Fuyang People's Hospital Affiliated to Anhui Medical University, Anhui, 236000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Dongqiang</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Sports Medicine and Arthroscopy, Fuyang People's Hospital, Anhui, 236000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Jiehao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency, Fuyang City People's Hospital, Anhui, 236000, China. 2960008045@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Biao</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Sports Medicine and Arthroscopy, Fuyang People's Hospital Affiliated to Anhui Medical University, Anhui, 236000, China. happygb@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>FY2023-028</GrantID><Agency>The Project of Scientific Research Topics of Fuyang Municipal Health Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>FY2023-028</GrantID><Agency>The Project of Scientific Research Topics of Fuyang Municipal Health Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>FY2023-028</GrantID><Agency>The Project of Scientific Research Topics of Fuyang Municipal Health Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>FY2023-028</GrantID><Agency>The Project of Scientific Research Topics of Fuyang Municipal Health Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>FY2023-028</GrantID><Agency>The Project of Scientific Research Topics of Fuyang Municipal Health Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>FY2023-028</GrantID><Agency>The Project of Scientific Research Topics of Fuyang Municipal Health Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Orthop Surg Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101265112</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1749-799X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acromioclavicular joint dislocation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Arthroscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dual-reduction fixation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Early clinical outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">U-shaped half-cerclage</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Institutional Review Board and the Ethics Committee of Fuyang People&#x2019;s Hospital ([2025]168). We also followed the Declaration of Helsinki. Written informed consent to participate was obtained from all adult participants. No participants were younger than 18 years of age. Consent for publication: As no participants were younger than 18 years of age, written informed consent for publication was obtained from the patients themselves. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41851777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-026-06802-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13018-026-06802-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Haugaard KB, Bak K, Seem K, H&#xf6;lmich P, Barfod KW. Rockwood type III is the most common type of acromioclavicular joint dislocation: a prospective cohort study investigating the incidence and epidemiology of acute acromioclavicular joint dislocations in an urban population. Shoulder Elbow. 2023;15(5):505&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.1177/17585732221123314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berthold DP, Muench LN, Dyrna F, et al. Current concepts in acromioclavicular joint (AC) instability - a proposed treatment algorithm for acute and chronic AC-joint surgery. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2022;23(1):1078. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12891-022-05935-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minkus M, Wieners G, Maziak N, Plachel F, Scheibel M, Kraus N. The ligamentous injury pattern in acute acromioclavicular dislocations and its impact on clinical and radiographic parameters. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2021;30(4):795&#x2013;805. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jse.2020.10.026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Cai L, Fan M, Yu P, Tu D. Subacromial osteolysis following hook plate fixation for acromioclavicular dislocation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2024;33(9):2086&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jse.2024.03.018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim B, Chai A, Jassim S, Shaalan M. Tightrope vs. hook plate fixation for acute acromioclavicular joint dislocation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JSES Rev Rep Tech. 2025;5(3):477&#x2013;86. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xrrt.2025.04.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman MD. Editorial commentary: suture button-anchor fixation is preferable to hook plate fixation for acute acromioclavicular joint dislocations: form and function need to be united. Arthroscopy. 2021;37(5):1424&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arthro.2021.01.051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y, Wang J, Lv J, et al. Predicting reduction loss risk after acromioclavicular joint dislocation treated with the endobutton device. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2025;26(1):912. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12891-025-09190-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon N, Choi NH, Ha JH, Kim M, Lim TK. Clavicular tunnel complications after coracoclavicular reconstruction in acute acromioclavicular dislocation: coracoid loop versus coracoid tunnel fixation. Clin Orthop Surg. 2022;14(1):128&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.4055/cios21094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venjakob AJ, Salzmann GM, Gabel F, et al. Arthroscopically assisted 2-bundle anatomic reduction of acute acromioclavicular joint separations: 58-month findings. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41(3):615&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1177/0363546512473438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park I, Lee S, Shin SJ. Arthroscopic-assisted double-bundle coracoclavicular ligament reconstruction using cortical fixation buttons with suture tape provides superior vertical stability than the single-bundle reconstruction for acute acromioclavicular joint dislocation. Arthroscopy. 2023;39(2):213&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arthro.2022.09.018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jen CL, Toon DH, Tan CH. Radiological study of the Asian coracoid process and clavicle: implications for coracoclavicular ligament reconstruction. Chin J Traumatol. 2020;23(1):56&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjtee.2019.05.007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai W, Gong X, Zhao Y, et al. Establishing the minimal clinically important difference, substantial clinical benefit, and patient acceptable symptomatic state for patient-reported outcome measures after primary posterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with a minimum 5-year follow-up. Am J Sports Med. 2025;53(11):2600&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1177/03635465251359568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tossy JD, Mead NC, Sigmond HM. Acromioclavicular separations: useful and practical classification for treatment. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1963;28:111&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;ark&#xe7;&#x131; E, Polat AE, G&#xfc;rp&#x131;nar T. The frequency of reduction loss after arthroscopic fixation of acute acromioclavicular dislocations using a double-button device, and its effect on clinical and radiological results. J Orthop Surg Res. 2020;15(1):136. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13018-020-01674-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo YS, Tsai AG, Ranawat AS, et al. A biomechanical analysis of the native coracoclavicular ligaments and their influence on a new reconstruction using a coracoid tunnel and free tendon graft. Arthroscopy. 2010;26(9):1153&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arthro.2009.12.031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel R, Ghandour M, Sammartino F, et al. Predictors of tunnel widening after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2025;53(13):3108&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1177/03635465251382911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterman BR. Editorial commentary: tunnel widening and loss of reduction may be inevitable after acromioclavicular stabilization with cortical suspensory devices whether inset (top hats) or onlay (buttons). Arthroscopy. 2023;39(11):2281&#x2013;2. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arthro.2023.06.039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo JB, Lee DH, Kim KB, Yoo JS. Coracoid clavicular tunnel angle is related with loss of reduction in a single-tunnel coracoclavicular fixation using a dog bone button in acute acromioclavicular joint dislocation. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2019;27(12):3835&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00167-019-05731-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue D, Furuhata R, Kaneda K, et al. Clavicle fracture at the suture hole after acromioclavicular joint reconstruction using a suture-button: a case report. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2019;20(1):333. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12891-019-2720-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellington IJ, Hawthorne BC, Ford B, et al. Biomechanical efficacy of tape cerclage as an augment or stand-alone for coracoclavicular ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2023;51(1):198&#x2013;204. https://doi.org/10.1177/03635465221134812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combalia A, Combalia M, Mu&#xf1;oz-Mahamud E. Acromioclavicular dislocation associated with fracture of the coracoid process: a series of cases and review of the literature. Int Orthop. 2025;49(5):1223&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00264-025-06435-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barth J, Duparc F, Andrieu K, et al. Is coracoclavicular stabilisation alone sufficient for the endoscopic treatment of severe acromioclavicular joint dislocation (Rockwood types III, IV, and V)? Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2015;101(8 Suppl):S297&#x2013;303. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.otsr.2015.09.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoriati AA, Antonios T, Fozo ZA, et al. Is there a role for acromioclavicular (AC) joint capsular repair and reconstruction in high-grade AC separations? A systematic review. EFORT Open Rev. 2025;10(2):115&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1530/EOR-2023-0121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theopold J, Sch&#xf6;bel T, Fischer JP, et al. Acromioclavicular joint reconstruction: an additional acromioclavicular cerclage does not improve horizontal stability in double coraco-clavicular tunnel technique. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2019;27(12):3827&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00167-019-05674-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimmeyer M, Hees T, Buijze GA, Lafosse L, Lafosse T. High vertical and horizontal stability at short-term follow-up after an all-endoscopic double cerclage endobutton technique for acute acromioclavicular joint separations. Arthroscopy. 2024;40(12):2786&#x2013;97. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arthro.2024.03.031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambro&#x17e;i&#x10d; M, Cimerman M, Omahen K, Jakli&#x10d; M, Kralj-Igli&#x10d; V, Kova&#x10d;i&#x10d; L. No short-term effects of acromioclavicular joint augmentation in acute acromioclavicular joint stabilization surgery: a randomized controlled clinical trial on 70 patients. J Clin Med. 2025;14(9):3161. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm14093161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng L, Zheng Y, Chen S, et al. Single tunnel technique versus coracoid sling technique for arthroscopic treatment of acute acromioclavicular joint dislocation. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):4244. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-07644-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkoheji M, El-Daou H, Lee J, Carlos A, Di Mascio L, Amis AA. Acromioclavicular joint reconstruction implants have differing ability to restore horizontal and vertical plane stability. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2021;29(12):3902&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00167-021-06700-x.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>