<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41730413</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2090-1224</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of advanced research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Adv Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Review of research advances in the cerebral lymphatic system and neurological disorders.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2090-1232(26)00164-5</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jare.2026.02.032</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The identification of the central lymphatic system represents a significant advancement in contemporary neuroscientific research. As a vital conduit connecting the central nervous system to the peripheral lymphatic network, the primary components of the central lymphatic system, the glymphatic system and meningeal lymphatic vessels, maintain homeostasis within the central microenvironment through cerebrospinal fluid circulation, metabolic waste clearance, and immune cell trafficking. Recent studies affirm that structural and functional perturbations within the central lymphatic apparatus can lead to the accrual of neurotoxic proteins such as amyloid-&#x3b2; and tau, thereby contributing to the pathogenesis of neurodegenerative conditions like Alzheimer's and Parkinson's diseases. Additionally, in cerebrovascular pathology, impaired drainage mechanisms exacerbate blood-brain barrier disruption and cerebral edema, thereby impairing neurological recovery. Moreover, this system modulates immune cell infiltration and plays a pivotal role in the etiology and progression of multiple sclerosis, central nervous system infections, and intracranial neoplasms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This review aimed to systematically synthesize the core components of the cerebral lymphatic system, namely the glymphatic system and meningeal lymphatic vessels, and clearly outline the key influencing factors, including aquaporin-4 activity, aging, hemodynamics, sleep, and circadian rhythms. The study aimed to emphasize the mechanisms by which the cerebral lymphatic system influences neurological pathology and summarize emerging therapeutic avenues targeting lymphatic pathways within the central nervous system.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="KEY SCIENTIFIC CONCEPTS OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Evidence suggests that the targeted modulation of the cerebral lymphatic system has the potential to treat various neurological diseases. Nevertheless, our understanding of the molecular mechanisms remains in its early stages, with significant research gaps. Consequently, future investigations should focus on molecular characterization to identify specific therapeutic targets, thereby facilitating the translation of preclinical insights into clinical practice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Zhaoxia</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Shengjing Hospital of China Medical University, 36 Sanhao St, Shenyang 110004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Jiayi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Developmental Cell Biology, Key Laboratory of Cell Biology, Ministry of Public Health, and Key Laboratory of Medical Cell Biology, Ministry of Education, China Medical University, Shenyang, China. Electronic address: weijycmu@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jue</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Shengjing Hospital of China Medical University, 36 Sanhao St, Shenyang 110004, China. Electronic address: ywang90@cmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Egypt</Country><MedlineTA>J Adv Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101546952</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2090-1224</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glymphatic system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meningeal lymphatic vessels</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurological disorders</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41730413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jare.2026.02.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2090-1232(26)00164-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>