<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41695729</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2218-5836</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of orthopedics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Orthop</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Magnetic resonance imaging tissue bridges: An emerging biomarker for prognostication in traumatic spinal cord injury.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>115848</StartPage><MedlinePgn>115848</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">115848</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5312/wjo.v17.i2.115848</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Traumatic spinal cord injury (SCI) remains one of the most challenging conditions in neuro-orthopedics, and functional recovery outcomes are mainly unpredictable. A recent prospective study provided compelling evidence that quantitative magnetic resonance imaging biomarkers, particularly midsagittal tissue bridge dimensions, could serve as valuable predictors of neurological recovery following acute SCI. By correlating tissue bridge measurements at 1 month and 6 months with motor and sensory improvements, a clinically meaningful imaging-based prognostic model was developed. Moreover, the inverse association among canal compromise, lesion size, and functional outcomes highlighted the importance of early structural preservation in SCI management. This study emphasized the growing potential of magnetic resonance imaging as both a diagnostic and prognostic tool, with significant implications for patient stratification in clinical and research settings. Future research incorporating tissue bridge biomarkers with advanced imaging techniques and neuroregenerative therapies may further refine personalized rehabilitation strategies for SCI patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2026. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Yao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound Imaging, Postgraduate Union Training Base of Xiangyang No. 1 People's Hospital, Xiangyang 441000, Hubei Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Ni-Na</ForeName><Initials>NN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardio-Thoracic Surgery, Xiangyang No. 1 People's Hospital, Hubei University of Medicine, Xiangyang 441000, Hubei Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gan</LastName><ForeName>Ling</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound Imaging, Postgraduate Union Training Base of Xiangyang No. 1 People's Hospital, Xiangyang 441000, Hubei Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jia-Qi</ForeName><Initials>JQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound Imaging, Postgraduate Union Training Base of Xiangyang No. 1 People's Hospital, Xiangyang 441000, Hubei Province, China. 347235272@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Orthop</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576349</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2218-5836</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic resonance imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurological recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal cord injury</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All the authors report no relevant conflicts of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41695729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12898891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5312/wjo.v17.i2.115848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Eli I, Lerner DP, Ghogawala Z. Acute Traumatic Spinal Cord Injury. Neurol Clin. 2021;39:471&#x2013;488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33896529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adegeest CY, Ter Wengel PV, Peul WC. Traumatic spinal cord injury: acute phase treatment in critical care. Curr Opin Crit Care. 2023;29:659&#x2013;665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37909371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gedde MH, Lilleberg HS, A&#xdf;mus J, Gilhus NE, Rekand T. Traumatic vs non-traumatic spinal cord injury: A comparison of primary rehabilitation outcomes and complications during hospitalization. J Spinal Cord Med. 2019;42:695&#x2013;701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6830275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30943115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandrow-Feinberg HR, Houl&#xe9; JD. Exercise after spinal cord injury as an agent for neuroprotection, regeneration and rehabilitation. Brain Res. 2015;1619:12&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4540698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25866284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chay W, Kirshblum S. Predicting Outcomes After Spinal Cord Injury. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am. 2020;31:331&#x2013;343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32624098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts TT, Leonard GR, Cepela DJ. Classifications In Brief: American Spinal Injury Association (ASIA) Impairment Scale. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2017;475:1499&#x2013;1504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5384910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27815685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LM, Wang F, Mishra A, Yang PF, Sengupta A, Reed JL, Gore JC. Longitudinal multiparametric MRI of traumatic spinal cord injury in animal models. Magn Reson Imaging. 2023;102:184&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10528214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37343904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobran M, Aiudi D, Liverotti V, Fasinella MR, Lattanzi S, Melchiorri C, Iacoangeli A, Campa S, Polonara G. Prognostic MRI parameters in acute traumatic cervical spinal cord injury. Eur Spine J. 2023;32:1584&#x2013;1590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36882580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freund P, Seif M, Weiskopf N, Friston K, Fehlings MG, Thompson AJ, Curt A. MRI in traumatic spinal cord injury: from clinical assessment to neuroimaging biomarkers. Lancet Neurol. 2019;18:1123&#x2013;1135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31405713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfyffer D, Smith AC, Weber KA 2nd, Grillhoesl A, Mach O, Draganich C, Berliner JC, Tefertiller C, Leister I, Maier D, Schwab JM, Thompson A, Curt A, Freund P. Prognostic value of tissue bridges in cervical spinal cord injury: a longitudinal, multicentre, retrospective cohort study. Lancet Neurol. 2024;23:816&#x2013;825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12128092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38945142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh R, Gautam S, Aggarwal S, Kaur S, Jain M. Correlation of magnetic resonance imaging biomarkers (tissue bridges) with neurological recovery following traumatic spinal cord injury. World J Orthop. 2025;16:110426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12679140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41355832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connor JR, Thornton WA, Weber KA, Pfyffer D, Freund P, Tefertiller C, Smith AC. Reliability of SCIseg Automated Measurement of Midsagittal Tissue Bridges in Spinal Cord Injuries Using an External Dataset. Top Spinal Cord Inj Rehabil. 2025;31:39&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12199566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40585009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang SK. Measuring the value of MRI: Comparative effectiveness &amp; outcomes research. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2019;49:e78&#x2013;e84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30632255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keenan KE, Biller JR, Delfino JG, Boss MA, Does MD, Evelhoch JL, Griswold MA, Gunter JL, Hinks RS, Hoffman SW, Kim G, Lattanzi R, Li X, Marinelli L, Metzger GJ, Mukherjee P, Nordstrom RJ, Peskin AP, Perez E, Russek SE, Sahiner B, Serkova N, Shukla-Dave A, Steckner M, Stupic KF, Wilmes LJ, Wu HH, Zhang H, Jackson EF, Sullivan DC. Recommendations towards standards for quantitative MRI (qMRI) and outstanding needs. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2019;49:e26&#x2013;e39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6663309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30680836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Li QX, Cao LX, Wang G, Chan DKY, Bettencourt C, Milward AE. Editorial: Human brain banking - Bridging brain health and precision neurology. Front Neurol. 2023;14:1322200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10641812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37965174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kesselring J. Neurorehabilitation: a bridge between basic science and clinical practice. Eur J Neurol. 2001;8:221&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11328329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderberg L, Aldskogius H, Holtz A. Spinal cord injury--scientific challenges for the unknown future. Ups J Med Sci. 2007;112:259&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18484069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkemade A, Gro&#xdf;mann R, Bazin PL, Forstmann BU. Mixed methodology in human brain research: integrating MRI and histology. Brain Struct Funct. 2023;228:1399&#x2013;1410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10335951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37365411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Wang G, Li Z, Li H, Zheng J, Hu Y, Cao X, Liao C, Ye H, Tian Q. Artificial intelligence for neuro MRI acquisition: a review. MAGMA. 2024;37:383&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38922525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gore JC. Artificial intelligence in medical imaging. Magn Reson Imaging. 2020;68:A1&#x2013;A4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31857130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghaderi S, Mohammadi M, Sayehmiri F, Mohammadi S, Tavasol A, Rezaei M, Ghalyanchi-Langeroudi A. Machine Learning Approaches to Identify Affected Brain Regions in Movement Disorders Using MRI Data: A Systematic Review and Diagnostic Meta-analysis. J Magn Reson Imaging. 2024;60:2518&#x2013;2546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38538062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavdas I, Glocker B, Rueckert D, Taylor SA, Aboagye EO, Rockall AG. Machine learning in whole-body MRI: experiences and challenges from an applied study using multicentre data. Clin Radiol. 2019;74:346&#x2013;356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30803815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousef H, Malagurski Tortei B, Castiglione F. Predicting multiple sclerosis disease progression and outcomes with machine learning and MRI-based biomarkers: a review. J Neurol. 2024;271:6543&#x2013;6572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11447111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39266777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfyffer D, Huber E, Sutter R, Curt A, Freund P. Tissue bridges predict recovery after traumatic and ischemic thoracic spinal cord injury. Neurology. 2019;93:e1550&#x2013;e1560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6815206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31541012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfyffer D, Vallotton K, Curt A, Freund P. Tissue bridges predict neuropathic pain emergence after spinal cord injury. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:1111&#x2013;1117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7509517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32788257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab ME, Br&#xf6;samle C. Regeneration of lesioned corticospinal tract fibers in the adult rat spinal cord under experimental conditions. Spinal Cord. 1997;35:469&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9232753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J, Yang X, Xu F, Li H. Application of Diffusion Tensor Imaging (DTI) in the Diagnosis of HIV-Associated Neurocognitive Disorder (HAND): A Meta-Analysis and a System Review. Front Neurol. 2022;13:898191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9302369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35873786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kollmer J, Kessler T, Sam G, Hayes JM, Lentz SI, Heiland S, Bendszus M, Wick W, Weiler M. Magnetization transfer ratio: a quantitative imaging biomarker for 5q spinal muscular atrophy. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28:331&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32918834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolff SD, Balaban RS. Magnetization transfer imaging: practical aspects and clinical applications. Radiology. 1994;192:593&#x2013;599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8058919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saccaro LF, Crokaert J, Perroud N, Piguet C. Structural and functional MRI correlates of inflammation in bipolar disorder: A systematic review. J Affect Disord. 2023;325:83&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36621677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>