<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41680876</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2050-7283</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Latent profile analysis and associated factors of kinesophobia in patients with hip fractures.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">365</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40359-026-04131-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">This cross-sectional study aimed to explore the potential categories of kinesiophobia in hip fractures patients, analyze the characteristic differences and associated factors across these categories, and thereby provide evidence-based references for clinical nursing practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This study followed the Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) guidelines. 381 hip fractures patients completed self-report measures assessing kinesiophobia and relevant correlates of kinesiophobia (e.g., pain, self-efficacy, family care level, frailty) from July 2024 to December 2024. Latent profile analysis was used to identify the heterogeneous subgroups, and logistic regression analysis was conducted to explore the related associated factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">There were two latent profiles of kinesiophobia: mild kinesiophobia - active participation type (40.6%) and severe kinesiophobia - exercise avoidance type (59.4%). Educational level, pain, and self-efficacy were significant psychological influences on kinesiophobia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Clinical nurses can adopt targeted rehabilitation nursing intervention based on the different category characteristics and relevant associated factors to reduce the level of kinesiophobia in hip fracture patients and promote smooth recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s40359-026-04131-2.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xinxia</LastName><ForeName>Wu</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Trauma Orthopedics Ward &#x2161;, The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, No. 120, Wanshui Road, Shushan District, Hefei City, 230033, Anhui Province, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dalin</LastName><ForeName>Kuang</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Trauma Orthopedics Ward &#x2161;, The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, No. 120, Wanshui Road, Shushan District, Hefei City, 230033, Anhui Province, PR China. 2574219604@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Juan</LastName><ForeName>Jin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Trauma Orthopedics Ward &#x2161;, The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, No. 120, Wanshui Road, Shushan District, Hefei City, 230033, Anhui Province, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mingzhe</LastName><ForeName>Dai</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Trauma Orthopedics Ward &#x2161;, The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, No. 120, Wanshui Road, Shushan District, Hefei City, 230033, Anhui Province, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lixia</LastName><ForeName>Zhang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Trauma Orthopedics Ward &#x2161;, The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, No. 120, Wanshui Road, Shushan District, Hefei City, 230033, Anhui Province, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiling</LastName><ForeName>Fang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Trauma Orthopedics Ward &#x2161;, The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, No. 120, Wanshui Road, Shushan District, Hefei City, 230033, Anhui Province, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Jiang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Trauma Orthopedics Ward &#x2161;, The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, No. 120, Wanshui Road, Shushan District, Hefei City, 230033, Anhui Province, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023AH053289</GrantID><Agency>the Anhui Province Key Project of Natural Science Research in Colleges and Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022zhyx-C32</GrantID><Agency>the Anhui Province Translational Medicine Research Institute Research Fund Cultivation Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101627676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-7283</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="eng"><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">&#x2022; Hip fracture patients exhibited two distinct patterns of kinesophobia. &#x2022; 59.4% of participants were classified as the &#x2018;severe kinesiophobia - exercise avoidance type&#x2019;. &#x2022; Higher levels of kinesiophobia were associated with greater self-efficacy and pain and lower educational level. &#x2022; This research contributed a novel perspective to the understanding of kinesiophobia in the hip fracture population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s40359-026-04131-2.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Associated factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-sectional studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hip fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kinesophobia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: All procedures performed in studies involving human participants were conducted in accordance with the ethical standards of the institutional and/or national research committee and with the 1964 Helsinki Declaration and its later amendments or comparable ethical standards. Approval for the study was obtained from the Biomedical Ethics Committee, First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University (reference: PJ2025-03-45). Patient consent statement: After securing the requisite approvals from the relevant hospital departments, the study&#x2019;s objectives, the method for completing the questionnaire, and the principles of confidentiality were thoroughly explained to the participants. Informed consent was obtained from all participants in this study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41680876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12998125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40359-026-04131-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40359-026-04131-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li X, Yelong D, Zhaohui L, et al. Analysis of epidemiological characteristics of hip fractures in elderly patients in China [J]. J Practical Orthop. 2021;27(7):601&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong XF, Li XP, Zhang LX, et al. Current status and distribution of hip fractures among older adults in China[J]. Osteoporos Int. 2021;32(9):1785&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-021-05849-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33655399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kori SH, Miller RP, Todd DD. Kinesiophobia: a new view of chronic pain behaviour [J]. Pain Management. 1990;3(1):35&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lethem J, Slade PD, Troup JD, et al. Outline of a Fear-Avoidance model of exaggerated pain perception&#x2013;I [J]. Behav Res Ther. 1983;21(4):401&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0005-7967(83)90009-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6626110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Huiping Z, Yancai L, Yanjin, et al. Research on the influencing factors of kinesiophobia in patients after total knee arthroplasty [J]. Chin J Nurs. 2021;56(10):1460&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Amiry B, Rahim A, Knutsson B, et al. Kinesiophobia and its association with functional outcome and quality of life 6&#x2013;8 years after total hip arthroplasty[J]. Acta Orthop Traumatol Turc. 2022;56(4):252&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5152/j.aott.2022.21318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9612671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35968616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsaleem MK, Alkhars AM, Alalwan HA, et al. Kinesiophobia Post Total Hip Arthroplasty: ARetrospective Study[J] Cureus. 2021;13(6):e15991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8318043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34336482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yumei Z, Xue S, Li W, et al. Current status and influencing factors of kinesiophobia in elderly patients after hip fracture surgery [J]. J Jining Med Univ. 2023;46(03):163&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jingjing K, Hongyu W, Yunyun T. Analysis of the current situation and influencing factors of kinesiophobia in patients with hip fractures [J]. J Integr Traditional Chin Western Med (English Edition). 2022;8(03):175&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sentandreu-Ma&#xf1;&#xf3; T, Deka P, Almenar L, Tom&#xe1;s JM, Ferrer-Sargues FJ, L&#xf3;pez-Vilella R, et al. Kinesiophobia and associated variables in patients with heart failure Eur. J Cardiovasc Nurs. 2024;23(3):221&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurjcn/zvad072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37534763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malfliet A, Kregel J, Meeus M, Roussel N, Danneels L, Cagnie B, et al. Blended-learning pain neuroscience education for people with chronic spinal pain: randomized controlled multicenter trial phys. Ther. 2018;98(5):357&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29669079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Yang Q, Li T, et al. Prevalence and influencing factors of kinesiophobia in patients with heart disease: a meta-analysis and systematic review. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):18956. Published 2024 Aug 15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-69929-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11327283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39147837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gen&#xe7; FZ, Bilgili N. The relationship between kinesiophobic attitude and frailty in older people. Int J Nurs Pract. 2025;31(2):e70002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijn.70002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11911037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40090671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin J, Xiong J, Chen C, et al. Influencing factors of kinesiophobia in older patients with chronic heart failure: A structural equation model. Clin Cardiol. 2023;46(7):729&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/clc.24024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10352966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37114367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Z, Wu Y, Liu M, Wang X, Wang J, Wang Z, et al. Heterogeneous trajectories of kinesiophobia and their effects on rehabilitation outcomes after total knee arthroplasty: a prospective cohort study. J Orthop Surg Res. 2023;18(1):449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-023-03881-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10290332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37353854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Yang Q, Li T, Xie H, Zeng B, Zha L, et al. Prevalence and influencing factors of kinesiophobia in patients with heart disease: a meta-analysis and systematic review sci. Rep. 2024;14(1):18956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11327283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39147837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen Zhonglin X, Jinyan WH. Principles, steps and procedures of latent class models [J]. J East China Normal Univ (Educational Sci Edition). 2023;41(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weller BE, Bowen NK, Faubert SJ. Latent class analysis: a guide to best practice [J]. J Black Psychol. 2020;46(4):287&#x2013;311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0095798420930932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spurk D, Hirschi A, Wang M, et al. Latent profile analysis: A review and how to guide of its application within vocational behavior research [J]. J Vocat Behav. 2020;120:103445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jvb.2020.103445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourhoseinghoil MA, Vahedi M, Rahimzadeh M. Sample size calculation in medical studies. Gastroenterol Hepatol Bed Bench. 2013;6(1):14&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4017493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24834239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Yajuan X, Ming W, Kena, et al. Comparison of four pain assessment scales in patients undergoing radiofrequency ablation for atrial fibrillation [J]. J Nurs. 2024;39(4):29&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarzer R, Aristi B. Optimistic self-beliefs: assessment of general perceived self-efficacy in thirteen cultures[J]. World Psychol. 1997;3(1/2):177&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CK, Hu ZF, Liu Y. Research on the reliability and validity of the general self-efficacy scale [J]. Chinese Journal of Applied Psychology. 2001;7(1):37-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SMILKSTEIN G. The physician and family function assessment[J]. Family Syst Med 1984; 2(3):263&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu F, Yuan G. Family APGAR questionnaire and its clinical application [J]. Foreign Med Sciences: Hosp Manage. 1995;02:56&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murali-Krishnan R, Iqbal J, Rowe R et al. Impact of frailty on outcomes after percutaneous coronary intervention: a prospective cohort study[J]. Open Heart 2015; 2(1): e000294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4567783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26380099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Yin C, Yanpei Y, Xiaoli, et al. Chinese version of the frailty risk screening tool for elderly inpatients and its reliability and validity study [J]. Chin J Practical Nurs. 2018;34(20):1526&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WOBY S R, ROACH N K, URMSTON M et al. Psychometric properties of the TSK-11: a shortened version of the Tampa scale for Kinesiophobia[J]. Pain, 2005;117(1/2):137&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16055269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Libo L, Yanjin X, Qiulu, et al. Reliability and validity study of the Chinese version of the kinesiophobia assessment short form in patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty [J]. Chin J Behav Med Brain Sci. 2019;28(3):270&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Rongjing H, Xuyan, Guanmei J. A review of the scope of postoperative kinesiophobia in elderly orthopedic patients [J]. Chin J Nurs. 2024;59(05):626&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower ES, Wetherell JL, Petkus AJ et al. Fear of falling after hip fracture: prevalence, course, and relationship with One-Year functional Recovery[J]. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2016; 24(12): 1228&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5136326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27726939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belova AN, habanova MA, ushin VO, et al. Kinesiophobia in patients requiring hip and knee endoprosthetics: severity and provoking factors[J]. Vopr Kurortol Fizioter Lech Fiz Kult. 2022;99(6):34&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17116/kurort20229906134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36538402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>You J, Wang C, Lindsey R, et al. Personality, coping strategies and emotional adjustment among Chinese cancer patients of different ages[J]. Eur J Cancer Care. 2018;27(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28975690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Cencen. Analysis of influencing factors of kinesiophobia in female breast cancer patients after surgery [D]. Chengdu: Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Yaxin S, Wenfeng J, Guanhua, et al. Qualitative study on the formation causes of high levels of kinesiophobia in patients with first acute myocardial infarction [J]. J Nurs. 2022;37(7):23&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aleksic M, Selakovic I, Tomanovic Vujadinovic S. Understanding kinesiophobia: predictors and influence on early functional outcomes in patients with total knee arthroplasty [J]. Geriatrics. 2024;9(4):98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11353930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39195133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nambi G, Basuodan RM, Alwhaibi RM, Ebrahim EE, Verma A, Syed S, Pakkir Mohamed SH, Aldhafian OR, Nwihadh NA, Saleh AK. Clinical and endocrinological responses to different exercise training methods in chronic low back pain: a randomized controlled trial. Endocr Metab Immune Disord Drug Targets. 2023;23:801&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1871530323666221031151721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36321229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalem M, Kocao&#x11f;lu H, Duman B et al. Prospective associations between fear of Falling, Anxiety, Depression, and pain and functional outcomes following surgery for intertrochanteric hip Fracture[J]. Orthop Surg Rehabil 2023;14: 21514593231193234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10403981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37545567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Min Q, Wenkai Y, Ling, et al. Latent profile analysis and influencing factors of kinesiophobia in peritoneal Dialysis patients [J]. Chin J Nurs. 2025;60(9):1080&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Huijie W, Wenjuan L. The effect of Self-Efficacy intervention on kinesiophobia in patients undergoing revision of anterior cruciate ligament [J]. Chin J Orthop Surg. 2024;32(12):1146&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>