<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41672417</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1528-1132</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical orthopaedics and related research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Orthop Relat Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Body Fat Percentage But Not BMI Was Related to Clinical Function in Patients With Adhesive Capsulitis After Manipulation Under Anesthesia.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CORR.0000000000003834</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Adhesive capsulitis can substantially impair shoulder function, and manipulation under anesthesia is commonly used for patients with persistent symptoms, yet outcomes vary widely. Previous research has suggested that obesity, commonly assessed through BMI, influences recovery in musculoskeletal conditions. However, BMI does not differentiate between fat and lean mass, which may be more relevant to tissue healing and functional recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="QUESTIONS/PURPOSES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">(1) Does body fat percentage, rather than BMI, predict clinical outcomes after manipulation under anesthesia for adhesive capsulitis? (2) Do patients with different body fat percentage levels experience distinct postoperative clinical outcomes? (3) Are common metabolic comorbidities independent predictors of poor surgical recovery in this population?</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Between December 2022 and December 2023, we treated 280 patients with adhesive capsulitis. Of these, 28% (78 of 280) of patients experienced satisfactory outcomes after nonsurgical treatment, 2% (6 of 280) of patients had concurrent shoulder disorders, and 4% (10 of 280) of patients lacked detailed clinical evaluations. The remaining 66% (186 of 280) of patients underwent manipulation under anesthesia and were the focus of this prospective, observational study. Among these patients, we excluded 0.5% (1 of 186) who received an additional nerve block treatment, 3% (5 of 186) who were transitioned to arthroscopic release, and 2% (4 of 186) who developed surgical complications. Additionally, 4% (7 of 186) of patients were excluded because they did not meet the minimum follow-up duration of 6 months, and 2% (3 of 186) of patients withdrew consent. Thus, 166 patients who underwent manipulation under anesthesia for refractory unilateral adhesive capsulitis at a tertiary care hospital were included in the final analysis. The mean age of the study population was 54 &#xb1; 8 years, 27% (44 of 166) of patients were male, and 26% (43 of 166) had left-sided involvement. Regarding comorbidities, 22% (36 of 166) of patients had diabetes, 24% (40 of 166) had hypertension, 23% (38 of 166) had hyperlipidemia, and 13% (22 of 166) had thyroid disorders. Preoperative body fat percentage was measured using bioelectrical impedance analysis 1 day before manipulation under anesthesia, and patients were categorized into sex-stratified body fat percentage groups. In addition to standard demographic and anthropometric assessments, patients were asked preoperatively whether they had a history of diabetes, hypertension, hyperlipidemia, or thyroid disorders. Venous blood samples were also collected after overnight fasting to assess fasting blood glucose, glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c), triglycerides, total cholesterol, low-density lipoprotein (LDL), and high-density lipoprotein (HDL) levels. Functional outcomes were assessed at baseline and 6 months postoperatively, including passive ROM, the Constant-Murley score, Oxford shoulder score (OSS), and VAS for pain. Log-binomial regression was used to compare the predictive value of body fat percentage versus BMI on achieving excellent functional recovery (a Constant-Murley score more than 90). One-way ANOVA with post hoc tests were applied to examine differences in functional outcomes across body fat percentage categories. Additional log-binomial regression and multivariate linear regression models were constructed to evaluate the independent effects of metabolic comorbidities (including diabetes, hyperlipidemia, HbA1c, LDL) on recovery outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">After adjusting for other metabolic factors, including diabetes, hyperlipidemia, hypertension, and thyroid disease, we found that body fat percentage, but not BMI, predicted excellent recovery (a Constant-Murley score more than 90): Patients with low and healthy body fat percentages showed higher likelihoods of good outcomes compared with those with an obesity-level body fat percentage (relative risk [RR] 8 [95% confidence interval (CI) 2 to 38] and 14 [95% CI 3 to 64], respectively, with obesity defined as the reference with an RR of 1; p &lt; 0.001). At 6 months after manipulation under anesthesia, female patients with low, healthy, and overweight body fat percentages demonstrated better forward elevation compared with those with an obesity-level body fat percentage (low- versus obesity-level percentages, mean difference 15&#xb0; [95% CI 9&#xb0; to 22&#xb0;]; p &lt; 0.001; healthy versus obesity, mean difference 15&#xb0; [95% CI 9&#xb0; to 20&#xb0;]; p &lt; 0.001; overweight versus obesity, mean difference 8&#xb0; [95% CI 2&#xb0; to 14&#xb0;]; p = 0.004). Male patients showed similar differences with ROM. In addition, female patients with low and healthy body fat percentages demonstrated better Constant-Murley scores compared with those with an obesity-level body fat percentage (low- versus obesity-level percentages, mean difference 8 [95% CI 4 to 12]; p &lt; 0.001; healthy versus obesity, mean difference 10 [95% CI 6 to 14]; p &lt; 0.001; healthy versus overweight, mean difference 6 [95% CI 3 to 9]; p &lt; 0.001). Female patients with low body fat percentages showed elevated pain during activity compared with obesity (low- versus obesity-level percentages, mean difference 1.2 on a 10-point VAS [95% CI 0.4 to 2.0]; p = 0.001). Furthermore, the presence of diabetes and hyperlipidemia were independently associated with a reduced likelihood of excellent recovery (no diabetes versus diabetes, RR 5 [95% CI 2 to 15]; p = 0.004; no hyperlipidemia versus hyperlipidemia, 6 [95% CI 2 to 17]; p &lt; 0.001). After controlling for demographic factors (including sex, age, and duration of symptoms) and major metabolic comorbidities (including diabetes, hypertension, hyperlipidemia, and thyroid disease), we further examined which specific metabolic biomarkers were associated with postoperative ROM. Higher body fat percentage (B = -0.36 [95% CI -0.51 to -0.20]), HbA1c (B = -0.96 [95% CI -1.39 to -0.52]), triglycerides (B = -0.82 [95% CI -1.27 to -0.36]), and low-density lipoprotein (B = -0.93 [95% CI -1.62 to -0.25]) were each associated with lower forward elevation ROM at 6 months. Similarly, higher body fat percentage (B = -0.33 [95% CI -0.65 to -0.003]), HbA1c (B = -1.09 [95% CI -1.53 to -0.65]), and triglycerides (B = -0.78 [95% CI -1.25 to -0.31]) were each associated with lower Constant-Murley score at 6 months.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In our study, body fat percentage was a more relevant indicator than BMI for postoperative functional recovery after manipulation under anesthesia. Tailored rehabilitation strategies, which prioritize pain management for patients with low body fat percentages and mobility restoration for groups with high body fat percentages, may help reduce the risk of poor clinical function. A comprehensive preoperative assessment that includes a body composition analysis and metabolic profiling may enhance risk stratification and guide personalized rehabilitation strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level II, therapeutic study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of the Association of Bone and Joint Surgeons.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Hengzhi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine and Orthopedic Surgery, the Second Affiliated Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sports Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics Research Institute of Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Junchao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine and Orthopedic Surgery, the Second Affiliated Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sports Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics Research Institute of Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xinji</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine and Orthopedic Surgery, the Second Affiliated Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sports Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics Research Institute of Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cai</LastName><ForeName>Honglu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine and Orthopedic Surgery, the Second Affiliated Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sports Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics Research Institute of Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Canlong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine and Orthopedic Surgery, the Second Affiliated Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sports Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Xuesong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine and Orthopedic Surgery, the Second Affiliated Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sports Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics Research Institute of Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Weiliang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine and Orthopedic Surgery, the Second Affiliated Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sports Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics Research Institute of Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Motor System Disease Research and Precision Therapy of Zhejiang Province, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Center of Motor System Disease of Zhejiang Province, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stage Key Laboratory of Transvascular Implantation Devices, Hangzhou, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Orthop Relat Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0075674</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0009-921X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Each author certifies that there are no funding or commercial associations (consultancies, stock ownership, equity interest, patent/licensing arrangements, etc.) that might pose a conflict of interest in connection with the submitted article related to the author or any immediate family members. All ICMJE Conflict of Interest Forms for authors and Clinical Orthopaedics and Related Research&#xae; editors and board members are on file with the publication and can be viewed on request.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41672417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CORR.0000000000003834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00003086-990000000-02322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ackermann PW, Hart DA. Influence of comorbidities: neuropathy, vasculopathy, and diabetes on healing response quality. Adv Wound Care (New Rochelle). 2013;2:410-421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando A, Hamada J, Hagiwara Y, Sekiguchi T, Koide M, Itoi E. Short-term clinical results of manipulation under ultrasound-guided brachial plexus block in patients with idiopathic frozen shoulder and diabetic secondary frozen shoulder. Open Orthop J. 2018;12:99-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa F, Swamy G, Salem H, et al. Chronic adhesive capsulitis (frozen shoulder): comparative outcomes of treatment in patients with diabetes and obesity. J Clin Orthop Trauma. 2019;10:265-268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancienne JM, Brockmeier SF, Rodeo SA, Werner BC. Perioperative serum lipid status and statin use affect the revision surgery rate after arthroscopic rotator cuff repair. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45:2948-2954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen MY, Meng XF, Han YP, Yan JL, Xiao C, Qian LB. Profile of crosstalk between glucose and lipid metabolic disturbance and diabetic cardiomyopathy: inflammation and oxidative stress. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2022;13:983713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis-Wilson HC, Johnston CD, Young E, et al. Effects of BMI on walking speed and gait biomechanics after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53:108-114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyer BP, Burton C, Rathod-Mistry T, Blagojevic-Bucknall M, van der Windt DA. Diabetes as a prognostic factor in frozen shoulder: a systematic review. Arch Rehabil Res Clin Transl. 2021;3:100141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esser N, Legrand-Poels S, Piette J, Scheen AJ, Paquot N. Inflammation as a link between obesity, metabolic syndrome and type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2014;105:141-150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fermont AJ, Wolterbeek N, Wessel RN, Baeyens JP, de Bie RA. Prognostic factors for successful recovery after arthroscopic rotator cuff repair: a systematic literature review. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2014;44:153-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galindo RJ, Beck RW, Scioscia MF, Umpierrez GE, Tuttle KR. Glycemic monitoring and management in advanced chronic kidney disease. Endocr Rev. 2020;41:756-774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griggs SM, Ahn A, Green A. Idiopathic adhesive capsulitis. A prospective functional outcome study of nonoperative treatment. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2000;82:1398-1407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SW, Lin JW, Wang WT, Wu CW, Liou TH, Lin HW. Hyperthyroidism is a risk factor for developing adhesive capsulitis of the shoulder: a nationwide longitudinal population-based study. Sci Rep. 2014;4:4183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jespersen E, Verhagen E, Holst R, et al. Total body fat percentage and body mass index and the association with lower extremity injuries in children: a 2.5-year longitudinal study. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:1497-1502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalinkovich A, Livshits G. Sarcopenic obesity or obese sarcopenia: a cross talk between age-associated adipose tissue and skeletal muscle inflammation as a main mechanism of the pathogenesis. Ageing Res Rev. 2017;35:200-221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kindler JM, Kelly A, Khoury PR, Levitt Katz LE, Urbina EM, Zemel BS. Bone mass and density in youth with type 2 diabetes, obesity, and healthy weight. Diabetes Care. 2020;43:2544-2552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laslett LL, Burnet SP, Redmond CL, McNeil JD. Predictors of shoulder pain and shoulder disability after one year in diabetic outpatients. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2008;47:1583-1586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledford CK, Millikan PD, Nickel BT, et al. Percent body fat is more predictive of function after total joint arthroplasty than body mass index. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2016;98:849-857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leuti A, Fazio D, Fava M, Piccoli A, Oddi S, Maccarrone M. Bioactive lipids, inflammation and chronic diseases. Adv Drug Deliv Rev. 2020;159:133-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macchi M, Spezia M, Elli S, Schiaffini G, Chisari E. Obesity increases the risk of tendinopathy, tendon tear and rupture, and postoperative complications: a systematic review of clinical studies. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2020;478:1839-1847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazurek T, Zhang L, Zalewski A, et al. Human epicardial adipose tissue is a source of inflammatory mediators. Circulation. 2003;108:2460-2466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millar NL, Meakins A, Struyf F, et al. Frozen shoulder. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2022;8:59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller GD, Nicklas BJ, Davis C, Loeser RF, Lenchik L, Messier SP. Intensive weight loss program improves physical function in older obese adults with knee osteoarthritis. Obesity (Silver Spring). 2006;14:1219-1230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miscio G, Guastamacchig G, Brunani A, Priano L, Baudo S, Mauro A. Obesity and peripheral neuropathy risk: a dangerous liaison. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2005;10:354-358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyatake K, Wakita R, Fujisawa T, et al. Satisfaction of patients with frozen shoulder following silent manipulation: a prospective observation study. Sci Rep. 2024;14:22409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najafi F, Darbandi M, Neya SK, et al. Epidemiology of musculoskeletal disorders among Iranian adults: results from a non-communicable disease cohort study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2023;24:315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oikonomou EK, Antoniades C. The role of adipose tissue in cardiovascular health and disease. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2019;16:83-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouchi N, Parker JL, Lugus JJ, Walsh K. Adipokines in inflammation and metabolic disease. Nat Rev Immunol. 2011;11:85-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padwal R, Leslie WD, Lix LM, Majumdar SR. Relationship among body fat percentage, body mass index, and all-cause mortality: a cohort study. Ann Intern Med. 2016;164:532-541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, Green S, Kramer S, et al. Manual therapy and exercise for adhesive capsulitis (frozen shoulder). Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014;2014:CD011275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palanne R, Rantasalo M, Vakkuri A, Olkkola KT, Vahlberg T, Skants N. Fat tissue is a poor predictor of 1 year outcomes after total knee arthroplasty: a secondary analysis of a randomized clinical trial. Scand J Surg. 2023;112:22-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey V, Madi S. Clinical guidelines in the management of frozen shoulder: an update! Indian J Orthop. 2021;55:299-309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasqualini I, Rossi LA, Oyem PC, Tanoira I, Hurley ET, Ranalletta M. Time required to achieve clinically significant outcomes after anteroinferior arthroscopic capsular release for shoulder adhesive capsulitis. Orthop J Sports Med. 2024;12:23259671241275653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rangan A, Brealey SD, Keding A, et al. Management of adults with primary frozen shoulder in secondary care (UK FROST): a multicentre, pragmatic, three-arm, superiority randomised clinical trial. Lancet. 2020;396:977-989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redler LH, Dennis ER. Treatment of adhesive capsulitis of the shoulder. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2019;27:e544-e554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes C, Leyland KM, Peat G, Cooper C, Arden NK, Prieto-Alhambra D. Association between overweight and obesity and risk of clinically diagnosed knee, hip, and osteoarthritis: a population-based cohort study. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2016;68:1869-1875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saltiel AR, Olefsky JM. Inflammatory mechanisms linking obesity and metabolic disease. J Clin Invest. 2017;127:1-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundararajan SR, Dsouza T, Rajagopalakrishnan R, Bt P, Arumugam P, Rajasekaran S. Arthroscopic capsular release versus manipulation under anaesthesia for treating frozen shoulder - a prospective randomised study. Int Orthop. 2022;46:2593-2601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung CM, Jung TS, Park HB. Are serum lipids involved in primary frozen shoulder? A case-control study. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2014;96:1828-1833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tashani OA, Astita R, Sharp D, Johnson MI. Body mass index and distribution of body fat can influence sensory detection and pain sensitivity. Eur J Pain. 2017;21:1186-1196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torensma B, Thomassen I, van Velzen M, In 't Veld BA. Pain experience and perception in the obese subject systematic review. Obes Surg. 2016;26:631-639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venturini PJF, Aily JB, de Almeida AC, Mattiello SM. Body fat percentage influences more the pain during activities than sex and age in people with knee osteoarthritis. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2025;42:506-512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent HK, Raiser SN, Vincent KR. The aging musculoskeletal system and obesity-related considerations with exercise. Ageing Res Rev. 2012;11:361-373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wearing SC, Hennig EM, Byrne NM, Steele JR, Hills AP. Musculoskeletal disorders associated with obesity: a biomechanical perspective. Obes Rev. 2006;7:239-250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanik EL, Colditz GA, Wright RW, et al. Risk factors for surgery due to rotator cuff disease in a population-based cohort. Bone Joint J. 2020;102:352-359.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>