<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41851769</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Alterations in Muscle Contractile Properties, Structure, and Function During 10-Day Bed Rest, Post-Recovery, and Following COVID-19 Lockdown.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003986</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Tensiomyography detects early hallmarks of bed-rest-induced atrophy. We aimed to identify early tensiomyography alterations in six muscles during a 10-day bed rest (BR10), followed by a 30-day recovery period (R+30), and to compare these changes with those observed after the 50-day COVID-19 lockdown in ten healthy males (22.9&#xb1;5.0 years).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Tensiomyography and muscle thickness (assessed by ultrasound imaging) were assessed at baseline, during bed rest, at BR10, R+30, and after the COVID-19 lockdown. Additional assessments included vertical jump performance (force plate), body composition (bioimpedance), physical activity (GPAQ), and lower back pain (VAS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">By BR10, participants experienced a 1.9% body mass loss, a 3.8% increase in fat mass, and a 2.4% reduction in muscle mass. While anthropometric parameters returned to baseline by R+30, fat mass increased again by 3.9% post-lockdown. Jump height declined by 10.1% at BR10, returned to baseline at R+30, and remained stable thereafter. Muscle thickness decreased by 7.0% in the vastus lateralis at BR10 and by 10.1% post-lockdown. Tensiomyographic amplitude increased in five leg muscles prior to BR10, recovered at R+30 and increased again after the COVID-19 lockdown, while a reduction was observed in the erector spinae within the first 48 hours, coinciding with reported lower back pain. In the erector spinae, both delay and contraction time decreased during BR10 and post-lockdown, while contraction time of the biceps femoris increased before BR10 and remained elevated post-lockdown.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The observed post COVID-19 lockdown alterations in tensiomyographic parameters followed the same trend as those induced by bed rest, albeit with smaller magnitude. These findings support the utility of TMG as a sensitive and non-invasive method for monitoring muscle responses across different disuse paradigms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bo&#x161;tjan</LastName><ForeName>&#x160;imuni&#x10d;</ForeName><Initials>&#x160;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Kinesiology Research, Science and Research Centre Koper, Koper, SLOVENIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fabio</LastName><ForeName>Sarto</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Padova, Padua, ITALY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Studies and Activities for Space "Giuseppe Colombo", University of Padova, Padua, ITALY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martino</LastName><ForeName>Franchi</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Padova, Padua, ITALY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elena</LastName><ForeName>Monti</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Padova, Padua, ITALY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baxter Laboratory for Stem Cell Biology, Department of Microbiology and Immunology, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rado</LastName><ForeName>Pi&#x161;ot</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Kinesiology Research, Science and Research Centre Koper, Koper, SLOVENIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marco</LastName><ForeName>Narici V</ForeName><Initials>NV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Kinesiology Research, Science and Research Centre Koper, Koper, SLOVENIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Padova, Padua, ITALY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CIR-MYO Myology Center, University of Padua, Padua, ITALY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ATROPHY</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DISUSE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SKELETAL MUSCLE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TENSIOMYOGRAPHY</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ULTRASOUND</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest and Funding Source: n/a Acknowledgments: The authors thank the participants who participated in the bed rest study, the support staff of the Institute for Kinesiology Research (ZRS Koper, Koper, Slovenia), the medical personnel of the General Hospital Isola (Izola, Slovenia) where the bed rest study was carried out. Authors disclose any perceived or potential conflict of interest, financial or otherwise for this study. The results of the study are presented clearly, honestly, and without fabrication, falsification, or inappropriate data manipulation. The results of the present study do not constitute endorsement by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41851769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-990000000-01028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>