<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41855113</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-509X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of head trauma rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Head Trauma Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Factors Associated With Return-to-Learn Duration After Concussion in US Service Academy Cadets and Midshipmen.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/HTR.0000000000001156</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Patterns of clinical recovery and factors that may influence return to activity after concussion have been well studied; however, data regarding return-to-learn (RTL) duration after concussion and factors that influence this period have not been adequately explored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="HYPOTHESIS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We have hypothesized that sport level, sex, concussion history, and initial symptom burden will be associated with RTL duration after concussion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study was conducted at US military service academies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">This was a prospective cohort study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 1509 service academy cadets (41% female, 20.2 &#xb1; 1.48 y, 174.9 &#xb1; 10.3 cm, 73.8 &#xb1; 14.0 kg) who sustained a concussion during the study period from December 2014 to March 2020 were included.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN MEASURES" NlmCategory="METHODS">The primary outcome of interest was time elapsed between an incident injury and self-reported return to normal academic performance. All participants provided baseline demographics, including sex (male, female), sport level (varsity, non-varsity), and concussion history (yes, no). Participants completed standardized concussion assessments at regular time points. Initial symptom burden was collected within 48 hours after injury, and self-reported RTL duration was collected during the unrestricted return-to-activity (URTA) evaluation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">On average, RTL duration was faster in men (8.1 &#xb1; 11.2 days) than in women (13.6 &#xb1; 20.3 days). Univariate models demonstrated that participants with an initial symptom burden &#x2264;6 returned sooner than those endorsing 7-15 symptoms (HR = 0.73, 95% CI = 0.64-0.83, P &#x2264; .001) and &#x2265;16 symptoms (HR = 0.56, 95% CI = 0.48-0.65, P &#x2264; .001). Sex (HR = 0.70, 95% CI = 0.62-0.77, P &#x2264; .001), and sport level (HR = 0.66, 95% CI = 0.59-0.73, P &#x2264; .001) also contributed to RTL duration in the univariate model. In the multivariable model, participants with an initial symptom burden &#x2264;6 returned 25%-41% sooner than those endorsing 7-15 symptoms (HR = 0.75, 95% CI = 0.65-0.86, P &#x2264; .001) and &#x2265;16 symptoms (HR = 0.59, 95% CI = 0.51-0.69, P &#x2264; .001). Sex (HR = 0.71, 95% CI = 0.64-0.80, P &#x2264; .001) and sport level (HR = 0.75, 95% CI = 0.67-0.85, P &lt; .001) also contributed to RTL duration in the multivariable model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">RTL duration for men, varsity athletes, and individuals with fewer initial symptoms after injury was significantly faster than for women, nonvarsity athletes, and individuals with a greater initial symptom burden.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ross</LastName><ForeName>Jeremy D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Author Affiliations: John A. Feagin Jr Sports Medicine Fellowship (Ross, Aderman, Malvasi, and Cameron), Keller Army Hospital, United States Military Academy, West Point, New York; Extremity Trauma and Amputation Center of Excellence (Roach), Defense Health Agency, Falls Church, Virginia and Department of Clinical Investigation, Womack Army Medical Center, Fort Bragg, North Carolina; United States Naval Academy (Susmarski), Annapolis, Maryland; United States Coast Guard Academy (Brodeur), New London, Connecticut; United States Air Force Academy (McGinty, Robb, and Jackson), USAFA, Colorado Springs, Colorado; University of Michigan Concussion Center (Broglio), Ann Arbor, Michigan; Medical College of Wisconsin (McCrea), Milwaukee, Wisconsin; Indiana University School of Medicine (McAllister), Indianapolis, Indiana; and Uniformed Services University of Health Sciences (Aderman, Pasquina, and Cameron), Bethesda, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aderman</LastName><ForeName>Michael J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1679-2738</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roach</LastName><ForeName>Megan H</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malvasi</LastName><ForeName>Steven R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Susmarski</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brodeur</LastName><ForeName>Rachel M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McGinty</LastName><ForeName>Gerald</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robb</LastName><ForeName>Joel</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jackson</LastName><ForeName>Jon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Broglio</LastName><ForeName>Steven P</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCrea</LastName><ForeName>Michael A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McAllister</LastName><ForeName>Thomas W</ForeName><Initials>TW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pasquina</LastName><ForeName>Paul F</ForeName><Initials>PF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cameron</LastName><ForeName>Kenneth L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Head Trauma Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8702552</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0885-9701</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concussion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">military</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">return-to-learn</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41855113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HTR.0000000000001156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001199-990000000-00352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aderman MJ, Brett BL, Malvasi SR, et al. Association between symptom burden at initiation of a graduated return to activity protocol and time to return to unrestricted activity after concussion in service academy cadets. Am J Sports Med. 2022;50:823&#x2013;833. doi: 10.1177/03635465211067551</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465211067551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carney N, Ghajar J, Jagoda A, et al. Concussion guidelines step 1: systematic review of prevalent indicators. Neurosurgery. 2014;75(Suppl 1):S3&#x2013;S15. doi: 10.1227/NEU.0000000000000433</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1227/NEU.0000000000000433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory P, Meeuwisse W, Dvorak J, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport&#x2014;the 5th international conference on concussion in sport held in Berlin, October 2016. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:838&#x2013;847. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2017-097699</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-097699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broglio SP, Cantu RC, Gioia GA, et al. National athletics trainers' association position statement: management of sport concussion. J Athl Train. 2014;49:245&#x2013;265. doi: 10.4085/1062-6050-49.1.07</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-49.1.07</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patricios JS, Schneider KJ, Dvorak J, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport: the 6th international conference on concussion in sport-Amsterdam, October 2022. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57:695&#x2013;711. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2023-106898</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-106898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Collegiate Athletic Association Sports Medicine Handbook. 24th ed. Natl Colledigate Ath Assn; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley TA, Baugh CM, Meehan WP, et al. Concussion management plan compliance: a study of NCAA power 5 conference schools. Orthop J Sports Med. 2017;5:2325967117702606. doi: 10.1177/2325967117702606</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967117702606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeMatteo C, Stazyk K, Giglia L, et al. A balanced protocol for return to school for children and youth following concussive injury. Clin Pediatr (Phila). 2015;54:783&#x2013;792. doi: 10.1177/0009922814567305</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0009922814567305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetta J, Starkweather A, Huggins R, et al. Implementation of return to learn protocols for student athletes with sport and recreation related concussion: an integrative review of perceptions, challenges and successes. J Sch Nurs. 2023;39:18&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1177/10598405211056646</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10598405211056646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Neill JA, Cox MK, Clay OJ, et al. A review of the literature on pediatric concussions and return-to-learn (RTL): implications for RTL policy, research, and practice. Rehabil Psychol. 2017;62:300&#x2013;323. doi: 10.1037/rep0000155</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/rep0000155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iverson GL, Gardner AJ, Terry DP, et al. Predictors of clinical recovery from concussion: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:941&#x2013;948. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2017-097729</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-097729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Pelt KL, Allred CD, Brodeur R, et al. Concussion-recovery trajectories among tactical athletes: results from the CARE consortium. J Athl Train. 2020;55:658&#x2013;665. doi: 10.4085/1062-6050-10-19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-10-19</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang EX, Hwang CE, Nguyen JN, et al. Factors associated with a prolonged time to return to play after a concussion. Am J Sports Med. 2022;50:1695&#x2013;1701. doi: 10.1177/03635465221083646</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465221083646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Lauro C, Johnson BR, McGinty G, et al. Reconsidering return-to-play times: a broader perspective on concussion recovery. Orthop J Sports Med. 2018;6. doi: 10.1177/2325967118760854</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967118760854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putukian M, Purcell L, Schneider KJ, et al. Clinical recovery from concussion-return to school and sport: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57:798&#x2013;809. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2022-106682</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2022-106682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putukian M, D'Alonzo BA, Campbell-McGovern CS, et al. The ivy league-big ten epidemiology of concussion study: a report on methods and first findings. Am J Sports Med. 2019;47:1236&#x2013;1247. doi: 10.1177/0363546519830100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546519830100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Master CL, Katz BP, Arbogast KB, et al. Differences in sport-related concussion for female and Male athletes in comparable collegiate sports: a study from the NCAA-DoD concussion assessment, research and education (CARE) consortium. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55:1387&#x2013;1394. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2020-103316</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-103316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memmini AK, Snedden TR, Boltz AJ, et al. Factors influencing time to return to learn among NCAA student-athletes enrolled in the concussion assessment, research, and education (CARE) study. Sports Med. 2024;54:1965&#x2013;1977. doi: 10.1007/s40279-024-01999-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-01999-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasserman EB, Bazarian JJ, Mapstone M, et al. Academic dysfunction after a concussion among US high school and college students. Am J Public Health. 2016;106:1247&#x2013;1253. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2016.303154</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2016.303154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broglio SP, McCrea M, McAllister T, et al. A national study on the effects of concussion in collegiate athletes and US military service academy members: the NCAA-DoD concussion assessment, research and education (CARE) consortium structure and methods. Sports Med. 2017;47:1437&#x2013;1451. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0707-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0707-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurtubise JM, Hughes CE, Sergio LE, et al. Comparison of baseline and postconcussion SCAT3 scores and symptoms in varsity athletes: an investigation into differences by sex and history of concussion. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2018;4:e000312. doi: 10.1136/bmjsem-2017-000312</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2017-000312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropr Med. 2016;15:155&#x2013;163. doi: 10.1016/j.jcm.2016.02.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcm.2016.02.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin EY, Nelson LD, Barr WB, et al. Reliability and validity of the sport concussion assessment tool-3 (SCAT3) in high school and collegiate athletes. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44:2276&#x2013;2285. doi: 10.1177/0363546516648141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546516648141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downey RI, Hutchison MG, Comper P. Determining sensitivity and specificity of the sport concussion assessment tool 3 (SCAT3) components in university athletes. Brain Inj. 2018;32:1345&#x2013;1352. doi: 10.1080/02699052.2018.1484166</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02699052.2018.1484166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durlak JA. How to select, calculate, and interpret effect sizes. J Pediatr Psychol. 2009;34:917&#x2013;928. doi: 10.1093/jpepsy/jsp004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jpepsy/jsp004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schober P, Boer C, Schwarte LA. Correlation coefficients: appropriate use and interpretation. Anesth Analg. 2018;126:1763&#x2013;1768. doi: 10.1213/ANE.0000000000002864</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1213/ANE.0000000000002864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;brien RM. A caution regarding rules of thumb for variance inflation factors. Qual Quant. 2007;41:673&#x2013;690. doi: 10.1007/s11135-006-9018-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11135-006-9018-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covassin T, Moran R, Elbin RJ. Sex differences in reported concussion injury rates and time loss from participation: an update of the national collegiate athletic association injury surveillance program from 2004-2005 through 2008-2009. J Athl Train. 2016;51:189&#x2013;194. doi: 10.4085/1062-6050-51.3.05</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-51.3.05</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putukian M, Aubry M, McCrory P. Return to play after sports concussion in elite and non-elite athletes? Br J Sports Med. 2009;43(Suppl 1):i28-i31. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2009.058230</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2009.058230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishay AE, Jallow O, Jo J, et al. Return-to-learn following sport-related concussion: a systematic review. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2025;36:173&#x2013;185. doi: 10.3171/2025.1.PEDS24482</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2025.1.PEDS24482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross JD, Cameron KL, Colsant BJ, et al. Leadership lessons in concussion management for team Physicians. Sports Med Arthrosc Rev. 2021;29:191&#x2013;199. doi: 10.1097/JSA.0000000000000326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSA.0000000000000326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulhus DL, Vazire S. The self-report method. In: Robins RW, Fraley RC, Krueger RF, eds Handbook of Research Methods in Personality Research. The Guilford Press; 2007:224&#x2013;239.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>