<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41743420</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-042X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Findings from interviews with pilots on spatial disorientation: training, temporal dynamics and countermeasures.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1620737</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1620737</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1620737</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphys.2025.1620737</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Spatial disorientation (SD) remains a prevalent issue in aviation, accounting for a disproportionate amount of Class A mishaps and fatalities. The current literature lacks specificity necessary to capture aspects of SD that may be essential in developing methods for detection and mitigation. This investigation focuses on the temporal progression of SD events in flight, elements of SD training facilitating recognition, recovery or avoidance of SD events, and considerations for SD countermeasures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We developed a mixed-methods research study involving a questionnaire followed by a semi-structured interview to evaluate perception of spatial disorientation within a pilot population. Thirteen pilots participated with a mean age was 60 years (range: 35-76), and a median of 6,000 (range: 317-19050 h) flight hours.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Pilots reported common chronological stages of recognizing and responding to SD events defined as a habitual reaction to direct attention to instrument displays, an analytical investigation of the true aircraft state, followed by a calculated control response if warranted. Pilots estimated that the typical duration an SD event may go unrecognized is on the order of 1-15 s. Estimates for the durations of the various stages of response suggest events last on the order of 1's to 10's of seconds. The psychological and physiological recovery associated with experiencing an SD event often persists for 10's of seconds to minutes following recognition and recovery of the aircraft. SD-specific training was said to have positive impacts on understanding conditions where SD is likely to occur, and may reduce the duration it goes unrecognized. However, it does not appear to have much direct influence on recovery <i>during</i> an SD event.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Pilots suggest that real-time detection and pilot aiding systems would be acceptable additions to the flight deck, with caveats of signal detection performance, maintaining anonymity, and intended use of data collected. Through rich interview reports, we built a model of the temporal dynamics of SD events. This model can serve as a tool for improving specific aspects of SD training, developing computational SD detection methods, and designing targeted countermeasure systems for avoiding and/or mitigating the impacts of SD on pilot safety and performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Dixon, Clark and Endsley.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dixon</LastName><ForeName>J B</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Charles Stark Draper Laboratory, Inc., Cambridge, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clark</LastName><ForeName>T K</ForeName><Initials>TK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Colorado, Boulder, Boulder, CO, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Endsley</LastName><ForeName>T C</ForeName><Initials>TC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Charles Stark Draper Laboratory, Inc., Cambridge, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-042X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aviation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">countermeasures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mixed methods</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spatial disorientation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thematic analysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Authors JD and TE were employed by The Charles Stark Draper Laboratory, Inc. The remaining author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest. The handling editor EG declared past co-authorships with the author TC.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41743420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12929113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2025.1620737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1620737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>
Albery W. B. (2007). Multisensory cueing for enhancing orientation information during flight. Aviat. Space, Environ. Med.
78 (5), B186&#x2013;B190. Available online at: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17547319/.

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17547319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelaki D. E., McHenry M. Q., Dickman J. D., Newlands S. D., Hess B. J. (1999). Computation of inertial motion: neural strategies to resolve ambiguous otolith information. J. Neurosci. 19 (1), 316&#x2013;327. 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.19-01-00316.1999</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.19-01-00316.1999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6782388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9870961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benson A. J. (1999). Spatial disorientation - general aspects. Editors Medicine A., Ernsting J., Nicholson A. N., Rainford D. J. (London: Butterworths; ), 277&#x2013;296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bles W. (2008). Spatial disorientation training: demonstration and avoidance. (France: North Atlantic Treaty Organization, Research and Technology Organization: Neuilly-sur-Seine Cedex; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bliss J. P., Freeland M. J., Millard J. C. (1999). &#x201c;Alarm related incidents in aviation: a survey of the aviation safety reporting system database,&#x201d; in Proceedings of the human factors and ergonomics society annual meeting (Los Angeles, CA: SAGE Publications Sage CA; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boril J., Smrz V., Petru A., Blasch E., Leuchter J., Frantis J., et al. (2018). &#x201c;Survey of spatial disorientation and sensory illusion among air force pilots,&#x201d; in 2018 IEEE/AIAA 37th digital avionics systems conference (DASC), (London, United Kingdom: IEEE; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Braithwaite C. M. G. (2002) &#x201c;Spatial disorientation: towards international standardization,&#x201d; in Spatial disorientation in military vehicles: causes, consequences and cures. Available online at: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9819157/.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braithwaite M. G., Durnford S. J., Crowley J. S., Rosado N. R., Albano J. P. (1998). Spatial disorientation in US Army rotary-wing operations. Aviat. Space, Environmental Medicine 69, (11), 1031&#x2013;1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9819157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V., Clarke V. (2006). Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual. Research Psychology 3 (2), 77&#x2013;101. 10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brill J. C., Lawson B., Rupert A. H. (2016). &#x201c;Countermeasures for loss of situation awareness: error filtering strategies for 3-dimensional audio,&#x201d; in 2016 IEEE aerospace conference, (IEEE; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung B. (2013). Spatial disorientation: more than just illusion. Aviat. Space, Environ. Med. 84 (11), 1211&#x2013;1214. 10.3357/asem.3657.2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3357/asem.3657.2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24279238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Cheung B., Money K., Wright H., Bateman W. (1995). Spatial disorientation-implicated accidents in Canadian forces, 1982-92. Aviat. Space Environmental Medicine
66 (6), 579&#x2013;585. Available online at: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7646410/.

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7646410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark T. K., Newman M. C., Karmali F., Oman C. M., Merfeld D. M. (2019). Mathematical models for dynamic, multisensory spatial orientation perception. Prog. Brain Research 248, 65&#x2013;90. 10.1016/bs.pbr.2019.04.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/bs.pbr.2019.04.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31239146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Collins D. L., Harrison G. (1995). Spatial disorientation episodes among F-15C pilots during operation desert storm. J. Vestibular Research Equilibrium Orientation
5 (6), 405&#x2013;410. Available online at: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8589852/.

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8589852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell J. W. (2014). A concise introduction to mixed methods research. California: SAGE Publications, Inc.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell J. W., Creswell J. D. (2018). Research design: qualitative, quantitative, and mixed methods approaches. Fifth. (Thousand Oaks, California: SAGE Publications, Inc.).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon S. R., Wickens C. D., McCarley J. S. (2007). On the independence of compliance and reliance: are automation false alarms worse than misses? Hum. Factors 49 (4), 564&#x2013;572. 10.1518/001872007X215656</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1518/001872007X215656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17702209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon J. B., Endsley T., Clark T. K. (2019). &#x201c;A mathematical model-based metric of spatial disorientation for use in triggering active countermeasures,&#x201d; in Proceedings of the human factors and ergonomics society annual meeting (Los Angeles, CA: SAGE Publications Sage CA; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Durnford S. J., DeRoche S. L., Harper J. P., Trudeau L. A. (1996). Spatial disorientation: a survey of US Army rotary-wing aircrew. (Fort Rucker, AL: Army Aeromedical Research Lab; ). Available online at: https://apps.dtic.mil/sti/tr/pdf/ADA307857.pdf.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edgington E. S. (1967). Review of the discovery of grounded theory: strategies for qualitative research. Can. Psychologist/Psychologie Canadienne 8a (4), 360. 10.1037/h0083159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/h0083159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksson L. (2009). Toward a visual flow integrated display format to combat pilot spatial disorientation. Int. J. Aviat. Psychol. 20 (1), 1&#x2013;24. 10.1080/10508410903415922</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10508410903415922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaydos S. J., Harrigan M. J., Bushby A. J. (2012). Ten years of spatial disorientation in U.S. Army rotary-wing operations. Aviat. Space Environ. Med. 83 (8), 739&#x2013;745. 10.3357/asem.3196.2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3357/asem.3196.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22872986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibb R., Ercoline B., Scharff L. (2011). Spatial disorientation: decades of pilot fatalities. Aviat. Space, Environ. Med. 82 (7), 717&#x2013;724. 10.3357/asem.3048.2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3357/asem.3048.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21748911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert C. D., Sigman M. (2007). Brain states: top-down influences in sensory processing. Neuron 54 (5), 677&#x2013;696. 10.1016/j.neuron.2007.05.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2007.05.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17553419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groen E. L., Bos J., Houben M. (2016). &#x201c;Pilot perception model supports the analysis of vestibular illusions in flight accidents,&#x201d; in AIAA guidance, navigation, and control conference.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Holmes S. R., Bunting A., Brown D. L., Hiatt K. L., Braithwaite M. G., Harrigan M. J. (2003a). Survey of spatial disorientation in military pilots and navigators. Aviat. Space Environ. Medicine
74 (9), 957&#x2013;965. Available online at: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14503674/.

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14503674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes S. R., Bunting A., Bostock S., Brown L., Hiatt K., Braithwaite M., et al. (2003b). Preliminary survey of spatial disorientation in UK military pilots and navigators. (Farnborough, United Kingdom: Qinetiq Ltd Centre For Human Sciences; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isreal J., Chesney G. L., Wickens C. D., Donchin E. (1980). P300 and tracking difficulty: evidence for a multiple capacity view of attention. Psychophysiology 17 (3), 259&#x2013;273. 10.1111/j.1469-8986.1980.tb00146.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8986.1980.tb00146.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7384376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson R. B., Onwuegbuzie A. J., Turner L. A. (2016). Toward a definition of mixed methods research. J. Mixed Methods Res. 1 (2), 112&#x2013;133. 10.1177/1558689806298224</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1558689806298224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kuipers A., Kappers A., van Holten C. R., van Bergen J. H. W., Oosterveld W. J. (1990). Spatial disorientation incidents in the RNLAF F 16 and F 5 aircraft and suggestions for prevention. AGARD Situational Aware. Aerosp. Operations (SEE N 90-28972 23-53), 25&#x2013;40. Available online at: https://apps.dtic.mil/sti/tr/pdf/ADA223939.pdf.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kynor D. B. (2002). Disorientation analysis and prediction system. (USAF: WPAFB, OH; ), p. 77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee A. T. (2017). Flight simulation: virtual environments in aviation. (Oxfordshire, United Kingdom: Routledge; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewkowicz R., Biernacki M. P. (2020). A survey of spatial disorientation incidence in Polish military pilots. Int. J. Occup. Med. Environ. Health 33 (6), 791&#x2013;810. 10.13075/ijomeh.1896.01621</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13075/ijomeh.1896.01621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33029026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malcolm R. (1984). The Malcolm horizon: history and future. NASA. Dryden Flight Research Center Peripheral Vision Horizon Display (PVHD), 11&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews R. S., Previc F., Bunting A. (2002). &#x201c;USAF spatial disorientation survey,&#x201d; in Paper to be presented at the spatial disorientation in military vehicles: causes, consequences and cures, a symposium organised by the NATO human factors and medicine panel (Spain: La Caoruna; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGrath B. J. (2000) &#x201c;Tactile instrument for aviation,&#x201d; in Naval aerospace medical research lab pensacola fl.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Navathe P. D., Singh B. (1994). Prevalence of spatial disorientation in Indian Air Force aircrew. Aviat. Space Environ. Medicine
65, 1082&#x2013;1085. Available online at: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7872907/.

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7872907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Newman D. G., Faicd A. (2007). An overview of spatial disorientation as a factor in aviation accidents and incidents. Aust. Transp. Saf. Bur. Canberra City. Available online at: http://www.dviaviation.com/files/45147727.pdf.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman M., Lawson B. D., McGrath B. J., Rupert A. H. (2014). &#x201c;Perceptual modeling as a tool to prevent aircraft upset associated with spatial disorientation,&#x201d; in AIAA guidance, navigation, and control conference.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neil P., Hamilton B. A., Miller M. (2017). &#x201c;USAF spatial disorientation prevention: a meta-analytical human systems integration perspective,&#x201d; in 19th international symposium on aviation psychology.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onur C., Bozan A., Pritchett A. (2014). &#x201c;Computational modeling to predict pilot&#x2019;s expectation of the aircraft state given vestibular and visual cues,&#x201d; in 2014 systems and information engineering design symposium (SIEDS) (IEEE; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osei-Amanfi M. (2018). A case study exploration of strategies to avoid cloud computing data breaches. (Grand Canyon University; ProQuest Dissertations &amp; Theses Global; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paillard A. C., Quarck G., Denise P. (2014). Sensorial countermeasures for vestibular spatial disorientation. Aviat. Space Environ. Med. 85 (5), 563&#x2013;567. 10.3357/asem.3735.2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3357/asem.3735.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24834571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennings H. J. M., Oprins E. A. P. B., Wittenberg H., Houben M. M. J., Groen E. L. (2020). Spatial disorientation survey among military pilots. Aerosp. Med. Hum. Perform. 91 (1), 4&#x2013;10. 10.3357/AMHP.5446.2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3357/AMHP.5446.2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31852567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poisson R. J., Miller M. E. (2014). Spatial disorientation mishap trends in the U.S. Air Force 1993&#x2013;2013. Aviat. Space Environ. Med. 85 (9), 919&#x2013;924. 10.3357/ASEM.3971.2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3357/ASEM.3971.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25197890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Previc F. H., Ercoline W. R. (2004) &#x201c;Spatial disorientation in aviation,&#x201d; in Progress in astronautics and aeronautics, American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, 203. 576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Previc F. H. (2012). The effects of a novel head-mounted symbology on spatial disorientation and flight performance in US Air Force Pilots. (Wright-Patterson AFB, Ohio: School of Aerospace Medicine; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj A. K., Braithwaite G. (1999). The tactile situation awareness system in rotary wing aircraft: flight test results. Curr. Aeromed. Issues Rotary Wing Operations 5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roscoe S. N. (1997). Gateway. (Wright-Patterson AFB, Ohio: Crew System Ergonomics Information Analysis Center; ), vol 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rupert A. H. (2000). An instrumentation solution for reducing spatial disorientation mishaps. IEEE Eng. Med. Biol. Mag. 19 (2), 71&#x2013;80. 10.1109/51.827409</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/51.827409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10738664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sipes W. E., Lessard C. S. (2000). A spatial disorientation survey of experienced instructor pilots. IEEE Eng. Med. Biol. Mag. 19 (2), 35&#x2013;42. 10.1109/51.827403</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/51.827403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10738658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Small R. L., Keller J. W., Wickens C. D., Socash C., Ronan A. M., Fisher A. M. (2006). Multisensory integration for pilot spatial orientation. (Boulder, Colorado: Micro Analysis And Design; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Small R. L., Keller J. W., Wickens C., Oman C. M., Jones T. D. (2011). Modeling and mitigating spatial disorientation in low G environments. (Cambridge, MA: Alion Science and Technology Corp. and Massachusetts Institute of Technology; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stott J. R. R. (2013). Orientation and disorientation in aviation. Extreme Physiology Med. 2 (2), 2. 10.1186/2046-7648-2-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2046-7648-2-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3710190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23849216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swihart D. E., Barfield A. F., Griffin E. M., Lehmann R. C., Whitcomb S. C., Flynn B. (2011). Automatic ground collision avoidance system design, integration, &amp; flight test. IEEE Aerosp. Electron. Syst. Mag. 26 (5), 4&#x2013;11. 10.1109/MAES.2011.5871385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MAES.2011.5871385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tormes F. R., Guedry F. E., Jr (1974). Disorientation phenomena in naval helicopter pilots. (Pensacola, FL: Naval Aerospace Medical Research Lab; ).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1147873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tornero Aguilera J. F., Gil-Cabrera J., Clemente-Suarez V. J. (2020). Determining the psychophysiological responses of military aircrew when exposed to acute disorientation stimuli. BMJ Mil. Health 168, 112&#x2013;116. 10.1136/bmjmilitary-2020-001417</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjmilitary-2020-001417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32205329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Erp J. B., Groen E. L., Bos J. E., van Veen H. A. H. C. (2006). A tactile cockpit instrument supports the control of self-motion during spatial disorientation. Hum. Factors 48 (2), 219&#x2013;228. 10.1518/001872006777724435</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1518/001872006777724435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16884044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickens C. D. (2002). Situation awareness and workload in aviation. Curr. Directions Psychological Science 11 (4), 128&#x2013;133. 10.1111/1467-8721.00184</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1467-8721.00184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickens C. D. (2008). Multiple resources and mental workload. Hum. Factors 50 (3), 449&#x2013;455. 10.1518/001872008X288394</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1518/001872008X288394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18689052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickens C. D., Small R. L., Fisher A. M., Keller J. W., Socash C. M. (2007). &#x201c;On line and off-line tools for preventing and analyzing vestibular spatial disorientation mishaps: a summary of the Alion-MA&amp;D/Air force research program,&#x201d; in 2007 international symposium on aviation psychology.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young L. (2003). &#x201c;Spatial orientation,&#x201d; in Principles and practice of aviation psychology. Editor Tsang P.S., Vidulich M.A. (Mahwah, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum; ).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>