<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41772702</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-6215</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Trials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Trials</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The clinical efficacy of virtual reality technology based on the mirror neuron theory in upper limb rehabilitation of stroke patients: a protocol for a randomized clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13063-026-09557-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">While mirror neuron-based rehabilitation approaches demonstrate efficacy in post-stroke upper limb motor recovery. Crucially, whether sequential activation of sensory mirror neurons preceding motor mirror neurons enhances functional outcomes remains unsubstantiated. Furthermore, conventional protocols require auditory-controlled environments and sustained high-attentional engagement for optimal efficacy. This study proposes a novel integrated intervention incorporating somatosensory observation (SO) components into Graded Motor Imagery (GMI), augmented by virtual reality (VR) technology to enhance participant engagement and attentional allocation. This synergistic approach aims to potentiate sensorimotor cortical integration, thereby optimizing upper limb recovery trajectory and clinical outcomes in stroke patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Sixty patients were randomized into four experimental groups: the conventional GMI Group received standard graded motor imagery; the SO-GMI Group incorporated SO with GMI; the VR-GMI Group implemented GMI through virtual reality; and the VR-SO-GMI Group combined SO and GMI within a VR environment. All interventions followed a standardized 4-week protocol. Resting-state functional MRI (rs-fMRI) assessed neuroplastic changes at baseline and post-intervention. Upper limb functional recovery was evaluated using three validated metrics: Fugl-Meyer Assessment for Upper Extremity (FMA-UE), Action Research Arm Test (ARAT), and Modified Barthel Index (MBI), administered at treatment initiation, week 2 (mid-intervention), and week 4 (conclusion) to track therapeutic efficacy. The study flow diagram is Fig. 1.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The purpose of this clinical trial is to observe the efficacy of increased SO in GMI on the recovery of upper limb motor function after cerebral stroke through a randomized controlled clinical trial, and to explore the clinical efficacy after implementing the above therapy using immersive VR technology, as well as to further investigate whether this research protocol can achieve the neurophysiological mechanism of "sensory-motor" linkage in the brain. This research method is widely applicable to patients with poor motor function and those with limitations in active movement. At the same time, VR technology allows for one-to-many training. At the same time, VR technology can conduct one-to-many training. This study aims to improve the efficacy of graded exercise therapy for upper limb rehabilitation in cerebral stroke and provide a new method that requires less physical effort, saves manpower, and has a wide range of applicability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">China Clinical Trial Registry ChiCTR2400084611. Registered on 21 May 2024.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wen</LastName><ForeName>Sha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Medicine Department, General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, No.807, Shengli South Street, Yinchuan City, Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region, 750001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Shiqiang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Medicine Department, General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, No.807, Shengli South Street, Yinchuan City, Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region, 750001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jingkai</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Medicine Department, General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, No.807, Shengli South Street, Yinchuan City, Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region, 750001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Wenjun</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Rehabilitation Center, Zhongwei Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, West of Ninggang Avenue, Shapotou District, Zhongwei City, Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region, 755000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Qi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Medicine Department, General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, No.807, Shengli South Street, Yinchuan City, Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region, 750001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Ruizhu</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Medicine Department, General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, No.807, Shengli South Street, Yinchuan City, Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region, 750001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jing</LastName><ForeName>Huiming</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Medicine Department, General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, No.807, Shengli South Street, Yinchuan City, Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region, 750001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Ning</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7510-702X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Medicine Department, General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, No.807, Shengli South Street, Yinchuan City, Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region, 750001, China. 13995310532@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2022BEG02047</GrantID><Agency>The Key Research and Development Project of the Science and Technology Department of Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Trials</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101263253</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1745-6215</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mirror neurons</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stroke</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Upper limb</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Virtual reality</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate {24}: The study protocol and informed consent documents received ethical approval from the Institutional Review Board of the General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University on 1 April 2024 (Approval No.KYLL-2024&#x2013;0226). Prior to trial participation, written informed consent will be obtained from all participants along with legally authorized representatives or guardians. Consent for publication {32}: All research participants were explicitly informed of, and consented to, the publication of study outcomes. This agreement expressly prohibits the disclosure of any individually identifiable information or personal health details in accordance with institutional privacy protocols and international data protection standards. Competing interests {28}: The authors disclose no competing interests, whether financial or non-financial, that could influence the design, execution, or interpretation of the reported research findings.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41772702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-026-09557-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13063-026-09557-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li X, Wang Y, Zhang Q, Liu R, Chen Z, Zhou H. The relationship between the functional status of upper extremity motor neurons and motor function and prognosis in stroke patients. Front Neurol. 2024;15:1466252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzolatti G, Craighero L. The mirror-neuron system. Annu Rev Neurosci. 2004;27:169&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Errante A, De Marco D, Ciricugno A, Fogassi L, Rozzi S. Mirror neurons are a class of neurons, originally discovered in the premotor cortex. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2019;33(6):419&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia F, Guo Z, Wang X, Li H, Zhang Y, Chen L. Effect of graded motor imagery combined with repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation on upper extremity motor function in stroke patients: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2024;105(5):819&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu P, Huang Y, Li Z, Zhang W, Xu L, Wang Q. Sequential neural activity in sensorimotor area and mirror neural system for graded mirror therapy with imagined hand movements. Neurorehabil. 2021;49(4):641&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung WB, Jiang H, Lee S, Kim SG. Dissection of brain-wide resting-state and functional somatosensory circuits by fMRI with optogenetic silencing. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2022;119:2113313119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isayama R, Nakazawa K, Yano K, Honda T, Gomi H. Rubber hand illusion modulates the influences of somatosensory and parietal inputs to the motor cortex. J Neurophysiol. 2019;121(2):563&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Th&#xf8;gersen M, Cooper K, Zabjek K, Andrysek J, Chau T. Removing own-limb visual input using mixed reality (MR) produces a &#x201c;telescoping&#x201d; illusion in healthy individuals. Behav Brain Res. 2018;347:263&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z, Zhang L, Chen X, Li W, Wang H, Liu Y. Comparison of sensory observation and somatosensory stimulation in mirror neurons and the sensorimotor network: a task-based fMRI study. Front Neurol. 2022;13:916990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisch SJH, Perrucci MG, Ferretti A, Del Gratta C, Romani GL, Gallese V. The sense of touch: embodied simulation in a visuotactile mirroring mechanism for observed animate or inanimate touch. J Cogn Neurosci. 2008;20(9):1611&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang M, Zhang J, Huang R, Zhao L. Diffusion tensor imaging study of virtual reality training on upper limb function in post-stroke hemiplegic patients. Chin J Phys Med Rehabil. 2022;44(2):131&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ventura S, Marchetti P, Ba&#xf1;os R, Tessari A. Body ownership illusion through virtual reality as modulator variable for limbs rehabilitation after stroke: a systematic review. Virtual Reality. 2023;27:2481&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekbib DB, Zhao Z, Wang J, Xu B, Zhang L, Cheng J. A novel fully immersive virtual reality environment for upper extremity rehabilitation in patients with stroke. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2021;1493(1):75&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gangemi A, De Luca R, Fabio RA, Lauria P, Rifici C, Pollicino P, et al. Effects of virtual reality cognitive training on neuroplasticity: a quasi-randomized clinical trial in patients with stroke. Biomedicines. 2023;11(12):3225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, Zhang H, Wang X, Li T, Liu F. What else is happening to the mirror neurons?&#x2014;A bibliometric analysis of mirror neuron research trends and future directions (1996&#x2013;2024). Brain Behav. 2025;152025(15):e70486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capozio A, Mart&#xed;nez-P&#xe9;rez R, Shinozaki M, Sarah LA. A single session of motor imagery paired with spinal stimulation improves manual dexterity and increases cortical excitability after spinal cord injury. Clin Neurophysiol. 2025;174:160&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bondi E, Ding YD, Zhang YS, Maggioni E, He B. Investigating the neurovascular coupling across multiple motor execution and imagery conditions: a whole-brain EEG-informed fMRI analysis. Neuroimage. 2025;317:121311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asan AS, McIntosh JR, Carmel JB. Targeting sensory and motor integration for recovery of movement after CNS injury. Front Neurosci. 2022;15:791824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebisch SJH, Perrucci MG, Ferretti A, Gratta CD, Romani GL, Gallese V. The sense of touch: embodied simulation in a visuotactile mirroring mechanism for observed animate or inanimate touch. J Cogn Neurosci. 2008;20(9):1611-1623.22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holle H, Banissy MJ, Ward J. Functional and structural brain differences associated with mirror-touch synaesthesia. Neuroimage. 2013;83:1041&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keysers C, Wicker B, Gazzola V, Anton JL, Fogassi L, Gallese V. A touching sight: SII/PV activation during the observation and experience of touch. Neuron. 2004;42(2):335&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison I, Lloyd D, di Pellegrino G, Roberts N. Vicarious responses to pain in anterior cingulate cortex:is empathy a multisensory issue? Cogn Affect Behav Neurosci. 2004;4(2):270&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zandvliet SB, Kwakkel G, Nijland RHM, van Wegen EEH, Meskers CGM. Is recovery of somatosensory impairment conditional for upper-limb motor recovery early after stroke? Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2020;34(5):403&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaefer M, Heinze HJ, Rotte M. Embodied empathy for tactile events: interindividual differences and vicarious somatosensory responses during touch observation. Neuroimage. 2012;60(2):952&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer K, Kaplan JT, Essex R, Damasio H, Damasio A. Seeing touch is correlated with content-specific activity in primary somatosensory cortex. Cereb Cortex. 2011;21(9):2113&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keser Z, Dehghani N, Jones S, Francisco GE, Yozbatiran N. Neuromodulation for post-stroke motor recovery: a narrative review of invasive and non-invasive tools. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2023;23(12):893&#x2013;906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohashi H, Gribble PL, Ostry DJ. Somatosensory cortical excitability changes precede those in motor cortex during human motor learning. J Neurophysiol. 2019;122(4):1397&#x2013;405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs MF, Tsang P, Lee KG, Asmussen MJ, Zapallow CM, Nelson AJ. 30 Hz theta-burst stimulation over primary somatosensory cortex modulates corticospinal output to the hand. Brain Stimul. 2014;7(2):269&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>