<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41795119</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ecological momentary assessment of the stress-recovery process through technology mHealth in sports: a scoping review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-026-01634-8</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guillen Cots</LastName><ForeName>Joel</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-0184-9377</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Sport Psychology, Department of Basic Psychology, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Bellaterra, Spain. joel.guillen@uab.cat.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Research Institute, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Bellaterra, Spain. joel.guillen@uab.cat.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Capdevila</LastName><ForeName>Lluis</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7319-4745</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Sport Psychology, Department of Basic Psychology, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Bellaterra, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Research Institute, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Bellaterra, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Losilla</LastName><ForeName>Josep-Maria</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5140-5847</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychobiology and Methodology of Health Sciences, Faculty of Psychology, Autonomous University of Barcelona, Bellaterra, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parrado</LastName><ForeName>Eva</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3072-0810</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Sport Psychology, Department of Basic Psychology, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Bellaterra, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Research Institute, Universitat Aut&#xf2;noma de Barcelona, Bellaterra, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>PID2019-107473RB-C21</GrantID><Agency>Ministerio de Ciencia, Innovaci&#xf3;n y Universidades</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>PID2022-141403NB-I00</GrantID><Agency>Ministerio de Ciencia, Innovaci&#xf3;n y Universidades</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2021SGR-00806</GrantID><Agency>Departament de Recerca i Universitats, Generalitat de Catalunya</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Athlete monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EMA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">training load</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">well-being</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not aplicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41795119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01634-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-026-01634-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Skau S, Sundberg K, Kuhn H-G. A Proposal for a Unifying Set of Definitions of Fatigue. Front Psychol. 2021;12. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.739764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidari J, Beckmann J, Bertollo M, Brink M, Kallus KW, Robazza C, et al. Multidimensional Monitoring of Recovery Status and Implications for Performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14:2&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2017-0669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellmann M, Bertollo M, Bosquet L, Brink M, Coutts AJ, Duffield R, et al. Recovery and Performance in Sport: Consensus Statement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13:240&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2017-0759.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorpe RT, Atkinson G, Drust B, Gregson W. Monitoring Fatigue Status in Elite Team-Sport Athletes: Implications for Practice. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2016-0434. S2-27-S2-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuigan H, Hassm&#xe9;n P, Rosic N, Stevens CJ. Training monitoring methods used in the field by coaches and practitioners: A systematic review. Int J Sports Sci Coach. 2020;15:439&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1177/1747954120913172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Monitoring Training Load to Understand Fatigue in Athletes. Sports Med. 2014;44:139&#x2013;47. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-014-0253-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. Load Management in Basketball. In: Laver L, Kocaoglu B, Cole B, Arundale AJH, Bytomski J, Amendola A, editors. Basketball Sports Medicine and Science. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer; 2020. pp. 815&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-662-61070-1_64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Marcora SM, Coutts AJ. Internal and External Training Load: 15 Years On. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14:270&#x2013;3. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2018-0935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanrenterghem J, Nedergaard NJ, Robinson MA, Drust B. Training Load Monitoring in Team Sports: A Novel Framework Separating Physiological and Biomechanical Load-Adaptation Pathways. Sports Med. 2017;47:2135&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-017-0714-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourdon PC, Cardinale M, Murray A, Gastin P, Kellmann M, Varley MC, et al. Monitoring Athlete Training Loads: Consensus Statement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12:S2&#x2013;170. https://doi.org/10.1123/IJSPP.2017-0208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Ronda L, Beanland E, Whitehead S, Sweeting A, Clubb J. Tracking Systems in Team Sports: A Narrative Review of Applications of the Data and Sport Specific Analysis. Sports Med - Open. 2022;8:15. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40798-022-00408-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutts AJ, Crowcroft S, Kempton T. Developing athlete monitoring systems: Theoretical basis and practical applications. Recovery and Well-being in Sport and Exercise. Routledge; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Halson S, Burke LM, Balagu&#xe9; G, Farrow D. An Integrated, Multifactorial Approach to Periodization for Optimal Performance in Individual and Team Sports. 2018. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2018-0093</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop PA, Jones E, Woods AK. Recovery From Training: A Brief Review: Brief Review. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:1015. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e31816eb518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xfc;king P, Achtzehn S, Holmberg H-C, Sperlich B. Integrated Framework of Load Monitoring by a Combination of Smartphone Applications, Wearables and Point-of-Care Testing Provides Feedback that Allows Individual Responsive Adjustments to Activities of Daily Living. Sensors. 2018;18:1632. https://doi.org/10.3390/s18051632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weaving D, Jones B, Till K, Abt G, Beggs C. The Case for Adopting a Multivariate Approach to Optimize Training Load Quantification in Team Sports. Front Physiol. 2017;8. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2017.01024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Assembly 71. mHealth: use of appropriate digital technologies for public health: report by the Director-General. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiffman S, Stone AA, Hufford MR. Ecological Momentary Assessment. Annu Rev Clin Psychol. 2008;4 Volume 4, 2008:1&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.clinpsy.3.022806.091415</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West SW, Clubb J, Torres-Ronda L, Howells D, Leng E, Vescovi JD, et al. More than a Metric: How Training Load is Used in Elite Sport for Athlete Management. Int J Sports Med. 2021;42:300&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1055/a-1268-8791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montull L, Slap&#x161;inskait&#x117;-Dackevi&#x10d;ien&#x117; A, Kiely J, Hristovski R, Balagu&#xe9; N. Integrative Proposals of Sports Monitoring: Subjective Outperforms Objective Monitoring. Sports Med - Open. 2022;8:41. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40798-022-00432-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmerman WP, Abbiss CR, Lawler NG, Stanley M, Raynor AJ. Athlete monitoring perspectives of sports coaches and support staff: A scoping review. Int J Sports Sci Coach. 2024;19:1813&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.1177/17479541241247131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox JL, Stanton R, Sargent C, Wintour S-A, Scanlan AT. The Association Between Training Load and Performance in Team Sports: A Systematic Review. Sports Med. 2018;48:2743&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-018-0982-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petway AJ, Freitas TT, Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Medina Leal D, Alcaraz PE. Training load and match-play demands in basketball based on competition level: A systematic review. PLoS ONE. 2020;15:e0229212. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0229212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saw AE, Main LC, Gastin PB. Monitoring the athlete training response: subjective self-reported measures trump commonly used objective measures: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:281&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2015-094758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira JE, Forte P, Ferraz R, Leal M, Ribeiro J, Silva AJ, et al. Monitoring Accumulated Training and Match Load in Football: A Systematic Review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:3906. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18083906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adesida Y, Papi E, McGregor AH. Exploring the Role of Wearable Technology in Sport Kinematics and Kinetics: A Systematic Review. Sensors. 2019;19:1597. https://doi.org/10.3390/s19071597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummins C, Orr R, O&#x2019;Connor H, West C. Global Positioning Systems (GPS) and Microtechnology Sensors in Team Sports: A Systematic Review. Sports Med. 2013;43:1025&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-013-0069-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seshadri DR, Li RT, Voos JE, Rowbottom JR, Alfes CM, Zorman CA, et al. Wearable sensors for monitoring the internal and external workload of the athlete. Npj Digit Med. 2019;2:71. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41746-019-0149-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaren SJ, Macpherson TW, Coutts AJ, Hurst C, Spears IR, Weston M. The Relationships Between Internal and External Measures of Training Load and Intensity in Team Sports: A Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48:641&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-017-0830-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helwig J, Diels J, R&#xf6;ll M, Mahler H, Gollhofer A, Roecker K, et al. Relationships between External, Wearable Sensor-Based, and Internal Parameters: A Systematic Review. Sensors. 2023;23:827. https://doi.org/10.3390/s23020827.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson N, Robinson DG, Verhagen E, Fagher K, Edouard P, Rojas-Valverde D, et al. Under-representation of women is alive and well in sport and exercise medicine: what it looks like and what we can do about it. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2023;9. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjsem-2023-001606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Jager E, Caulfield B, Angelidi E, MacNamee Brian HS. Wearable-Derived Heart Rate Variability Across the Menstrual Cycle, Hormonal Contraceptive Use, and Reproductive Life Stages in Females: A Living Systematic Review. Sports Med. 2026. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-025-02388-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, O&#x2019;Brien KK, Colquhoun H, Levac D, et al. PRISMA Extension for Scoping Reviews (PRISMA-ScR): Checklist and Explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169:467&#x2013;73. https://doi.org/10.7326/M18-0850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillen J, Capdevila L, Losilla J-M, Parrado E. Ecological Momentary Assessment of the stress-recovery process through technology mHealth in sports: a scoping review protocol. INPLASY - International Platform of Registered Systematic Review and Meta-analysis Protocols; 2023. https://doi.org/10.37766/inplasy2023.3.0089</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGowan J, Sampson M, Salzwedel DM, Cogo E, Foerster V, Lefebvre C. PRESS Peer Review of Electronic Search Strategies: 2015 Guideline Statement. J Clin Epidemiol. 2016;75:40&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2016.01.021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rethlefsen ML, Kirtley S, Waffenschmidt S, Ayala AP, Moher D, Page MJ, et al. PRISMA-S: an extension to the PRISMA Statement for Reporting Literature Searches in Systematic Reviews. Syst Rev. 2021;10:39. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13643-020-01542-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Number of European Smartphone Users Accessing News Surges. 74% Over Past Year. Comscore, Inc. https://www.comscore.com/Insights/Press-Releases/2012/3/Number-of-European-Smartphone-Users-Accessing-News-Surges-74-Percent-Over-Past-Year</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanning J, Mullen SP, McAuley E. Increasing Physical Activity With Mobile Devices: A Meta-Analysis. J Med Internet Res. 2012;14:e2171. https://doi.org/10.2196/jmir.2171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant MJ, Booth A. A typology of reviews: an analysis of 14 review types and associated methodologies. Health Inf Libr J. 2009;26:91&#x2013;108. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1471-1842.2009.00848.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, Martin DT, Mujika I, Goosey-Tolfrey VL, et al. Defining Training and Performance Caliber: A Participant Classification Framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021;17:317&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell PG, Stewart IB, Sirotic AC, Drovandi C, Foy BH, Minett GM. Analysing the predictive capacity and dose-response of wellness in load monitoring. J Sports Sci. 2021;39:1339&#x2013;47. https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2020.1870303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullahi Y, Coetzee B, van den Berg L. Relationships Between Results of an Internal and External Match Load Determining Method in Male, Singles Badminton Players. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:1111&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000002115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askow AT, Lobato AL, Arndts DJ, Jennings W, Kreutzer A, Erickson JL, et al. Session Rating of Perceived Exertion (sRPE) Load and Training Impulse Are Strongly Correlated to GPS-Derived Measures of External Load in NCAA Division I Women&#x2019;s Soccer Athletes. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2021;6. https://doi.org/10.3390/jfmk6040090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellinger PM, Ferguson C, Newans T, Minahan CL. No Influence of Prematch Subjective Wellness Ratings on External Load During Elite Australian Football Match Play. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020;15:801&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2019-0395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisschoff CA, Coetzee B, Esco MR. Relationship between heart rate, heart rate variability, heart rate recovery and global positioning system determined match characteristics of male, elite, African badminton players. Int J Perform Anal SPORT. 2016;16:881&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrismas BCR, Taylor L, Thornton HR, Murray A, Stark G. External training loads and smartphone-derived heart rate variability indicate readiness to train in elite soccer. Int J Perform Anal SPORT. 2019;19:143&#x2013;52. https://doi.org/10.1080/24748668.2019.1578097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente FM. Associations between wellness and internal and external load variables in two intermittent small-sided soccer games. Physiol Behav. 2018;197:9&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physbeh.2018.09.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clements E, Ehrmann F, Clark A, Jones M, McCall A, Duffield R. Influence of Travel Demands and Match Load on Recovery Following Postmatch Travel in National-Team Footballers. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2025;1&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2024-0211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conte D, Kamarauskas P, Ferioli D, Scanlan AT, Kamandulis S, Paulauskas H, et al. Workload and well-being across games played on consecutive days during in-season phase in basketball players. J Sports Med Phys Fit. 2021;61. https://doi.org/10.23736/s0022-4707.20.11396-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conte D, Guerriero A, Lupo C, Schultz Arruda AF, Kamarauskas P. Influence of Congested Match Schedules, Pre-Match Well-Being and Level of Opponents on Match Loads during World Rugby Women&#x2019;s Sevens Series. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph182212132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa J, Figueiredo P, Nakamura F, Rago V, Rebelo A, Brito J. Intra-individual variability of sleep and nocturnal cardiac autonomic activity in elite female soccer players during an international tournament. PLoS ONE. 2019;14:e0218635. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0218635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croteau F, Gaudet S, Briand J, Cl&#xe9;ment J. Case study of IMU loads and self-reported fatigue monitoring of water polo goalkeepers preparing for the Olympic games. Front Sports Act Living. 2023;5:1198003&#x2013;1198003. https://doi.org/10.3389/fspor.2023.1198003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crouch AK, Jiroutek MR, Snarr RL, Bunn JA. Relationship between pre-training wellness scores and internal and external training loads in a Division I women&#x2019;s lacrosse team. J Sports Sci. 2021;39:1070&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2020.1857106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullen BD, McCarren AL, Malone S. Ecological validity of self-reported wellness measures to assess pre-training and pre-competition preparedness within elite Gaelic football. Sport Sci Health. 2021;17:163&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Dios-&#xc1;lvarez V, Su&#xe1;rez-Iglesias D, Bouzas-Rico S, Alkain P, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Conde A, Ay&#xe1;n-P&#xe9;rez C. Relationships between RPE-derived internal training load parameters and GPS-based external training load variables in elite young soccer players. Res Sports Med. 2023;31:58&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delaney JA, Duthie GM, Thornton HR, Pyne DB. Quantifying the relationship between internal and external work in team sports: development of a novel training efficiency index. Sci Med Footb. 2018;2:149&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.1080/24733938.2018.1432885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douchet T, Humbertclaude A, Cometti C, Paizis C, Babault N. Quantifying Accelerations and Decelerations in Elite Women Soccer Players during Regular In-Season Training as an Index of Training Load. Sports Basel Switz. 2021;9. https://doi.org/10.3390/sports9080109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Draper G, Wright M, Chesterton P, Atkinson G. The tracking of internal and external training loads with next-day player-reported fatigue at different times of the season in elite soccer players. Int J SPORTS Sci Coach. 2021;16:793&#x2013;803. https://doi.org/10.1177/1747954121988960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis M, Penny R, Wright B, Noon M, Myers T, Akubat I. The dose-response relationship between training-load measures and aerobic fitness in elite academy soccer players. Sci Med Footb. 2021;5:128&#x2013;36. https://doi.org/10.1080/24733938.2020.1817536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans DA, Jackson DT, Kelly AL, Williams CA, McAuley ABT, Knapman H, et al. Monitoring Postmatch Fatigue During a Competitive Season in Elite Youth Soccer Players. J Athl Train. 2022;57:184&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.4085/1062-6050-0245.21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez D, Moya D, Cadefau JA, Carmona G, Fern&#xe1;ndez D, Moya D, et al. Integrating External and Internal Load for Monitoring Fitness and Fatigue Status in Standard Microcycles in Elite Rink Hockey. Front Physiol. 2021;12:698463. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2021.698463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields JB, Merigan JM, Gallo S, White JB, Jones MT. External and Internal Load Measures During Preseason Training in Men Collegiate Soccer Athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35:2572&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000004092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox JL, O&#x2019;Grady CJ, Scanlan AT. The Relationships Between External and Internal Workloads During Basketball Training and Games. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020;15:1081&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2019-0722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox JL, Stanton R, Scanlan AT. A Comparison of Training and Competition Demands in Semiprofessional Male Basketball Players. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2018;89:103&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.1080/02701367.2017.1410693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gielen J, Mehuys E, Berckmans D, Meeusen R, Aerts J-M. Monitoring Internal and External Load During Volleyball Competition. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022;17:640&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2021-0217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Fimbres RA, Ramirez-Siqueiros MG, Reynoso-Sanchez LF, Quezada-Chacon JT, Miranda-Mendoza J, Hernandez-Cruz G. A new approach to quantify internal and external training load for intermittent sports. BIOTECNIA. 2019;21:26&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Garc&#xed;a J, Romero-Moraleda B. The Impact of a Congested Competition Schedule on Load, Recovery, and Well-Being in Under-16 Female Soccer Players: A Comparison between Starters and Non-Starters during a Development Tournament. Appl Sci-BASEL. 2024;14. https://doi.org/10.3390/app14178066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govus AD, Coutts A, Duffield R, Murray A, Fullagar H. Relationship Between Pretraining Subjective Wellness Measures, Player Load, and Rating-of-Perceived-Exertion Training Load in American College Football. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13:95&#x2013;101. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2016-0714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grace S, Cooley A, Smith AM, Parker P, Bunn JA. Relationship Between Sleep Quality, Wellness, and Training Load in Division I Women&#x2019;s Lacrosse Athletes. J Sport Behav. 2023;46:29&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heishman AD, Curtis MA, Saliba E, Hornett RJ, Malin SK, Weltman AL, NONINVASIVE ASSESSMENT OF INTERNAL AND EXTERNAL PLAYER LOAD: IMPLICATIONS FOR OPTIMIZING ATHLETIC PERFORMANCE. J STRENGTH Cond Res. 2018;32:1280&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000002413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson MJ, Fransen J, McGrath JJ, Harries SK, Poulos N, Coutts AJ. Individual Factors Affecting Rugby Sevens Match Performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14:620&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2018-0133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ihsan M, Tan F, Sahrom S, Choo HC, Chia M, Aziz AR. Pre-game perceived wellness highly associates with match running performances during an international field hockey tournament. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17:593&#x2013;602. https://doi.org/10.1080/17461391.2017.1301559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James C, Dhawan A, Jones T, Pok C, Yeo V, Girard O. Minimal Agreement between Internal and External Training Load Metrics across a 2-wk Training Microcycle in Elite Squash. J Sports Sci Med. 2021;20:101&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.52082/jssm.2021.101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javaloyes A, Mateo-March M, Manresa-Rocamora A, Sanz-Quinto S, Moya-Ram&#xf3;n M. The Use of a Smartphone Application in Monitoring HRV during an Altitude Training Camp in Professional Female Cyclists: A Preliminary Study. Sensors. 2021;21. https://doi.org/10.3390/s21165497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe5;rstr&#xf6;m A, Swar&#xe9;n M, Bj&#xf6;rklund G. Discrepancies in internal and external training load measurements during low-intensity biathlon training. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;6:1455900. https://doi.org/10.3389/fspor.2024.1455900.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kniubaite A, Skarbalius A, Clemente FM, Conte D. Quantification of external and internal match loads in elite female team handball. Biol SPORT. 2019;36:311&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.5114/biolsport.2019.88753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacome M, Simpson B, Broad N, Buchheit M. Monitoring Players&#x2019; Readiness Using Predicted Heart-Rate Responses to Soccer Drills. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13:1273&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2018-0026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lempke AFD, Hart JM, Hryvniak DJ, Rodu JS, Hertel J. Prospective running assessments among division I cross-country athletes. Phys Ther SPORT. 2022;55:37&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ptsp.2022.02.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long JW, Brown D, Farrell J, Gonzalez M, Cheever K. Relationship between Workload, Psychological State and Recovery in Female Soccer Athletes. Int J Sports Med. 2024;45:829&#x2013;36. https://doi.org/10.1055/a-2304-3694.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Laval I, Cirer-Sastre R, Sitko S, Corbi F, Vaquera A, Calleja-Gonzalez J, Relationship, between methodologies for load control in professional basketball. Rev Int Med Cienc Act Fis Deporte. 2022;22:649&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.15366/rimcafd2022.87.014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mara JK, Thompson KG, Pumpa KL, Ball NB. Periodization and Physical Performance in Elite Female Soccer Players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10:664&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matos S, Clemente FM, Brand&#xe3;o A, Pereira J, Rosemann T, Nikolaidis PT, et al. Training Load, Aerobic Capacity and Their Relationship With Wellness Status in Recreational Trail Runners. Front Physiol. 2019;10:1189. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2019.01189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson KD, Quiggle GT. Tensiomyographical responses to accelerometer loads in female collegiate basketball players. J Sports Sci. 2017;35:2334&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2016.1266378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pexa BS, Johnston CJ, Taylor JB, Ford KR. Training Load and Current Soreness Predict Future Delayed Onset Muscle Soreness in Collegiate Female Soccer Athletes. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2023;18:38&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Power CJ, Fox JL, Teramoto M, Dalbo VJ, Scanlan AT. Training and Game Loads Across Noncongested and Congested Weekly Microcycles During the Regular Season in a Semiprofessional Women&#x2019;s Basketball Team. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2024;19:1455&#x2013;66. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2023-0448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabbani A, Kargarfard M, Castagna C, Clemente FM, Twist C. Associations Between Selected Training-Stress Measures and Fitness Changes in Male Soccer Players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14:1050&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2018-0462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rago V, Muschinsky A, Deylami K, Vigh-Larsen JF, Mohr M. Game Demands of a Professional Ice Hockey Team with Special Emphasis on Fatigue Development and Playing Position. J Hum Kinet. 2022;84:195&#x2013;205. https://doi.org/10.2478/hukin-2022-000078.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahilly DO, Whelan N, Moane S, The effects of gps metrics, training and competition load on recovery in elite male gaelic football players. J Aust Strength Cond. 2023;31:16&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reina M, Mancha-Triguero D, Garc&#xed;a-Santos D, Garc&#xed;a-Rubio J, Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez SJ. [Comparison of three methods of quantifying the training load in basketball]. RICYDE Rev Int Cienc Deporte. 2019;15:368&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.5232/ricyde2019.05805. Comparaci&#xf3;n de tres m&#xe9;todos de cuantificaci&#xf3;n de la carga de entrenamiento en baloncesto.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinhardt L, Schulze S, Schwesig R, Kurz E. Physical Match Performance in Sub-elite Soccer Players - Introduction of a new Index. Int J Sports Med. 2020;41:858&#x2013;66. https://doi.org/10.1055/a-1165-1950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renaghan E, Wittels HL, Wittels SH, Wishon MJ, Hecocks D, Wittels ED, et al. Internal or External Training Load Metrics: Which Is Best for Tracking Autonomic Nervous System Recovery and Function in Collegiate American Football? J Funct Morphol Amp Kinesiol. 2024;9:5&#x2013;null.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-S&#xe1;nchez J, Botella J, Felipe Hern&#xe1;ndez JL, Le&#xf3;n M, Paredes-Hern&#xe1;ndez V, Colino E, et al. Heart Rate Variability and Physical Demands of In-Season Youth Elite Soccer Players. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18041391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sansone P, Ceravolo A, Tessitore A, External. Internal, Perceived Training Loads and Their Relationships in Youth Basketball Players Across Different Positions. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022;17:249&#x2013;55. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2020-0962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sansone P, Tessitore A, Makivic B, Ferioli D, Conte D. The Relationships Between Training-Load Models in 3 x 3 Basketball Games. Int J SPORTS Physiol Perform. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2024-0452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scanlan AT, Wen N, Tucker PS, Dalbo VJ. The relationships between internal and external training load models during basketball training. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28:2397&#x2013;405. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000000458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Lockie RG, Knight TJ, Clark AC, Janse de Jonge XAK. A comparison of methods to quantify the in-season training load of professional soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2013;8:195&#x2013;202. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.8.2.195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott D, Lovell R. Individualisation of speed thresholds does not enhance the dose-response determination in football training. J Sports Sci. 2018;36:1523&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2017.1398894.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva B, Cruz G, Rocha-Rodrigues S, Clemente FM. Monitoring physical performance and training load in young surf athletes. J Hum SPORT Exerc. 2021;16:261&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.14198/jhse.2021.162.03.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva P, Santos ED, Grishin M, Rocha JM. Validity of Heart Rate-Based Indices to Measure Training Load and Intensity in Elite Football Players. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32:2340&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000002057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson MJ, Jenkins DG, Scanlan AT, Kelly VG. Relationships Between External- and Internal-Workload Variables in an Elite Female Netball Team and Between Playing Positions. Int J SPORTS Physiol Perform. 2020;15:841&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2019-0619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobolewski EJ. The Relationships between Internal and External Load Measures for Division I College Football Practice. SPORTS. 2020;8. https://doi.org/10.3390/sports8120165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suarez-Arrones L, Torre&#xf1;o N, Requena B, De S&#xe1;ez E, Casamichana D, Barbero-Alvarez JC, et al. Match-play activity profile in professional soccer players during official games and the relationship between external and internal load. J Sports Med Phys Fit. 2015;55:1417&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira JE, Forte P, Ferraz R, Branquinho L, Morgans R, Silva AJ, et al. Resultant equations for training load monitoring during a standard microcycle in sub-elite youth football: a principal components approach. PeerJ. 2023;11:e15806&#x2013;15806. https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.15806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tendero-Ortiz E, Johnson MJ, Horsfall CM, Vondrasek JD, Grosicki GJ, Riemann BL, et al. Tournament Recovery Profiles and Physical Demands in a Collegiate Women&#x2019;s Tennis Team. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38:1786&#x2013;92. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000004876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tometz MJ, Jevas SA, Esposito PM, Annaccone AR. Validation of Internal and External Load Metrics in NCAA D1 Women&#x2019;s Beach Volleyball. J STRENGTH Cond Res. 2022;36:2223&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000003963.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torreno N, Munguia-Izquierdo D, Coutts A, de Villarreal ES, Asian-Clemente J, Suarez-Arrones L, et al. Relationship Between External and Internal Loads of Professional Soccer Players During Full Matches in Official Games Using Global Positioning Systems and Heart-Rate Technology. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11:940&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2015-0252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villaseca-Vicu&#xf1;a R, Perez-Contreras J, Zabaloy S, Merino-Mu&#xf1;oz P, Valenzuela L, Burboa J, et al. Comparison of Match Load and Wellness between Friendly and World Cup Matches in Elite Female Soccer Players. Appl Sci-BASEL. 2023;13. https://doi.org/10.3390/app13031612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellman AD, Coad SC, Flynn PJ, Siam TK, McLellan CP, Perceived wellness associated with practice, and competition in national collegiate athletic association division i football players. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:112&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000002169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiig H, Andersen TE, Luteberget LS, Spencer M. Individual Response to External Training Load in Elite Football Players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020;15:696&#x2013;704. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2019-0453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zafar A, Guay S, Vinet S, Pilon F, Martens G, Prince F, et al. Heart Rate Dynamics and Quantifying Physical Fatigue in Canadian Football. Appl Sci-BASEL. 2024;14. https://doi.org/10.3390/app14125340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rago V, Fernandes T, Mohr M. Identifying Key Training Load and Intensity Indicators in Ice Hockey Using Unsupervised Machine Learning. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2025;96:21&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.1080/02701367.2024.2360162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabost-Garcia G, Colmena V, Aguilar-Tor&#xe1;n J, Vieyra Gal&#xed; J, Punter-Villagrasa J, Casals-Terr&#xe9; J, et al. Non-Invasive Multiparametric Approach To Determine Sweat&#x2013;Blood Lactate Bioequivalence. ACS Sens. 2023;8:1536&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1021/acssensors.2c02614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neupert E, Holder T, Gupta L, Jobson SA. More than metrics: The role of socio-environmental factors in determining the success of athlete monitoring. J Sports Sci. 2024;42:323&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2024.2330178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad M, Stylianides G, Djaoui L, Dellal A, Chamari K. Session-RPE Method for Training Load Monitoring: Validity, Ecological Usefulness, and Influencing Factors. Front Neurosci. 2017;11. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2017.00612.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>