<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41917926</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2482</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of sedation methods on early postoperative cognitive decline in patients undergoing hip fracture surgery with spinal anesthesia: a prospective cohort study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12893-026-03706-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Early postoperative cognitive decline is common in elderly patients undergoing hip fracture surgery and may contribute to delayed recovery and diminished long-term independence. Although spinal anesthesia is associated with reduced systemic cognitive burden, intraoperative sedation remains necessary and may influence neurocognitive outcomes. Dexmedetomidine and ketamine are sedative agents with proposed neuroprotective properties; however, their comparative cognitive safety in the context of spinal anesthesia remains poorly understood. Thus, our study aim to compare early postoperative cognitive outcomes between intravenous dexmedetomidine and ketamine used for intraoperative sedation during spinal anesthesia in elderly patients undergoing hip fracture surgery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this prospective observational cohort study, elderly patients undergoing hip fracture surgery under spinal anesthesia were enrolled to compare the effects of dexmedetomidine and ketamine on early postoperative cognitive function. The primary outcome was MMSE score on postoperative days 1 and 3. Secondary outcomes included Clock Drawing Test (CDT) scores, length of stay, and perioperative complications. Cognitive assessments were conducted preoperatively, and postoperatively on days 1 and 3 by blinded clinicians.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Eighty-two patients [dexmedetomidine (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;41), and ketamine (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;41)] were analyzed. Baseline demographics and clinical characteristics were comparable. Postoperative MMSE scores were significantly higher in the dexmedetomidine group on both day 1 (21.4&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.0 vs. 17.1&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;5.4; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) and day 3 (21.9&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;3.9 vs. 17.6&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;5.7; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Both groups exhibited a decline in MMSE scores on postoperative day 1, with partial recovery by day 3; scores remained significantly lower than baseline levels (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01 for both groups). The magnitude of MMSE decline was statistically smaller in the dexmedetomidine group compared to the ketamine group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Similarly, CDT scores declined from baseline on postoperative day 1, and showed moderate improvement by day 3. However, no significant differences were observed in CDT scores or complication rates between groups. Sedation depth and intraoperative analgesia were comparable, aside from transient differences at the 5th minute post-sedation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Dexmedetomidine was associated with less early postoperative MMSE decline compared with ketamine in elderly patients undergoing hip fracture surgery under spinal anesthesia. These findings reflect differences in early postoperative cognitive trajectory rather than established postoperative cognitive dysfunction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Date of Registration: 02/02/2023 (Retrospectively registered). https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT05737459.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc7;etinkaya</LastName><ForeName>Ahmet Said</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Reanimation, Karab&#xfc;k University Training and Research Hospital, Karab&#xfc;k, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yurtlu</LastName><ForeName>Derya Arslan</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Reanimation, Izmir Faculty of Medicine, University of Health Sciences, Bayrakl&#x131; City Hospital, Refik Sevket Ince District, 2148/11 Street, Number:1/11 Bayrakli, Izmir, Turkey. darslanyurtlu@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>T&#xfc;zen</LastName><ForeName>Ahmet Salih</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Reanimation, Izmir Katip &#xc7;elebi University Atat&#xfc;rk Training and Research Hospital, Izmir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05737459</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968567</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2482</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dexmedetomidine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hip fractures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ketamine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postoperative cognitive impairment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal anesthesia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Approval was obtained from the Izmir Katip Celebi University Faculty of Clinical Research Ethics Committee (Dated: 14.04.2022, number: 33). Written informed consent was obtained from all participants. In cases where patients were physically unable to provide written consent due to limitations such as upper extremity fractures or visual impairment, consent was obtained from their legally authorized representatives in accordance with institutional ethical guidelines. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Consent for publication: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41917926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12893-026-03706-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12893-026-03706-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Roche JJW, Wenn RT, Sahota O, Moran CG. Effect of comorbidities and postoperative complications on mortality after hip fracture in elderly people: prospective observational cohort study. BMJ. 2005;331(7529):1374. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.38643.663843.55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klestil T, R&#xf6;der C, Stotter C, Winkler B, Nehrer S, Lutz M, et al. Impact of timing of surgery in elderly hip fracture patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2018;8:13933. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-32098-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin HS, McBride RL, Hubbard RE. Frailty and anesthesia &#x2013; risks during and post-surgery. Local Reg Anesth. 2018;11:61&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.2147/LRA.S142996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dent E, Morley JE, Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Woodhouse L, Rodr&#xed;guez-Ma&#xf1;as L, Fried LP, et al. Physical frailty: ICFSR international clinical practice guidelines for identification and management. J Nutr Health Aging. 2019;23(9):771&#x2013;87. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12603-019-1273-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antoniadou E, Giusti E, Capodaglio P, Han DS, Gimigliano F, Guzman J, et al. Frailty recommendations and guidelines: an evaluation of the implementability and a critical appraisal of clinical applicability by the ISPRM Frailty Focus Group. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2024;60(4):530&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.23736/S1973-9087.24.08486-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha AIL, Veronese N, de Melo Borges S, Ricci NA. Frailty as a predictor of adverse outcomes in hospitalized older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ageing Res Rev. 2019;56:100960. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arr.2019.100960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotekar N, Kuruvilla CS, Murthy V. Post-operative cognitive dysfunction in the elderly: a prospective clinical study. Indian J Anaesth. 2014;58(3):263&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.4103/0019-5049.135034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudolph JL, Marcantonio ER. Postoperative delirium: acute change with long-term implications. Anesth Analg. 2011;112(5):1202&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.1213/ANE.0b013e3182147f6d.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monk TG, Price CC. Postoperative cognitive disorders. Curr Opin Crit Care. 2011;17(4):376&#x2013;81. https://doi.org/10.1097/MCC.0b013e328348bece.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao MZ, Liu CX, Zhou LG, Yang Y, Wang Y. Postoperative delirium, neuroinflammation, and influencing factors of postoperative delirium: A review. Med (Baltim). 2023;102(12):e32991. https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000032991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Shen X. Postoperative delirium in the elderly: the potential neuropathogenesis. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2018;30(11):1287&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40520-018-1008-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evered LA, Silbert BS. Postoperative cognitive dysfunction and noncardiac surgery. Anesth Analg. 2018;127(2):496&#x2013;505. https://doi.org/10.1213/ANE.0000000000003514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silbert B, Evered L, Scott DA, McMahon S, Choong P, Ames D, et al. Preexisting cognitive impairment is associated with postoperative cognitive dysfunction after hip joint replacement surgery. Anesthesiology. 2015;122(6):1224&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.1097/ALN.0000000000000671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryson GL, Wyand A, Wozny D, Rees L, Taljaard M, Nathan H. The clock drawing test is a poor screening tool for postoperative delirium and cognitive dysfunction after aortic repair. Can J Anaesth. 2011;58(3):267&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12630-010-9448-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deiner S, Luo X, Lin HM, Sessler DI, Saager L, Sieber FE, et al. Intraoperative infusion of dexmedetomidine for prevention of postoperative delirium and cognitive dysfunction in elderly patients undergoing major elective noncardiac surgery: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Surg. 2017;152(8):e171505. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamasurg.2017.1505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J, Vacas S, Feng X, Lutrin D, Uchida Y, Lai IK, et al. Dexmedetomidine prevents cognitive decline by enhancing resolution of high mobility group box 1 protein-induced inflammation through a vagomimetic action in mice. Anesthesiology. 2018;128(5):921&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1097/ALN.0000000000002038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avidan MS, Maybrier HR, Abdallah AB, Jacobsohn E, Vlisides PE, Pryor KO, et al. Intraoperative ketamine for prevention of postoperative delirium or pain after major surgery in older adults: an international, multicentre, double-blind, randomised clinical trial. Lancet. 2017;390(10091):267&#x2013;75. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(17)31467-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KH, Kim JY, Kim JW, Park JS, Lee KW, Jeon SY. Influence of ketamine on early postoperative cognitive function after orthopedic surgery in elderly patients. Anesth Pain Med (Seoul). 2015;5(4):e28844. https://doi.org/10.5812/aapm.28844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su X, Meng ZT, Wu XH, Cui F, Li HL, Wang DX, et al. Dexmedetomidine for prevention of delirium in elderly patients after non-cardiac surgery: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet. 2016;388(10054):1893&#x2013;902. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(16)30580-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr ZJ, Cios TJ, Potter KF, Swick JT. Does dexmedetomidine ameliorate postoperative cognitive dysfunction? A brief review of the recent literature. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2018;18(12):94. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11910-018-0873-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Zhu Y, Liu Z, Ruan L. Effect of dexmedetomidine on postoperative cognitive dysfunction in elderly patients after general anaesthesia: a meta-analysis. J Int Med Res. 2016;44(6):1182&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1177/0300060516671623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, Pocock SJ, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Vandenbroucke JP. The Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. J Clin Epidemiol. 2008;61(4):344&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2007.11.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou R, Gordon DB, de Leon-Casasola OA, Rosenberg JM, Bickler S, Brennan T, et al. Management of postoperative pain: a clinical practice guideline from the American Pain Society, the American Society of Regional Anesthesia and Pain Medicine, and the American Society of Anesthesiologists&#x2019; Committee on Regional Anesthesia, Executive Committee, and Administrative Council. J Pain. 2016;17(2):131&#x2013;57. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpain.2015.12.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schofield P, Dunham M, Martin D, Bellamy G, Francis SA, Sookhoo D, et al. Evidence-based clinical practice guidelines on the management of pain in older people: a summary report. Br J Pain. 2020;16(1):6&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1177/2049463720976155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koc Okudur S, Dokuzlar O, Usarel C, Soysal P, Isik AT. Validity and reliability of rapid cognitive screening test for Turkish older adults. J Nutr Health Aging. 2019;23(1):68&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12603-018-1107-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kucukdeveci AA, Kutlay S, Elhan AH, Tennant A. Preliminary study to evaluate the validity of the Mini-Mental State Examination in a normal population in Turkey. Int J Rehabil Res. 2005;28(1):77&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1097/00004356-200503000-00011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abualrob H, Afeef VM, Shurman A, Shulkin A, Azizudin A, Hillier L, et al. Scoping review exploring the impact of hip fracture in older adults with cognitive impairment or dementia. BMJ Open. 2025;15:e093893. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2024-093893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz DP, Adunuri N, Gill SS, Rochon PA. Prevalence of dementia and cognitive impairment among older adults with hip fractures. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2011;12(8):556&#x2013;64. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jamda.2010.12.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Munster BC, De Rooij SE, Delirium. A synthesis of current knowledge. Clin Med (Lond). 2014;14(2):192&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.7861/clinmedicine.14-2-192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slor CJ, Witlox J, Jansen RW, Adamis D, Meagher DJ, Tieken E, et al. Affective functioning after delirium in elderly hip fracture patients. Int Psychogeriatr. 2013;25(3):445&#x2013;55. https://doi.org/10.1017/S1041610212001962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Yang R, Xie X, Dai H, Pan L. Effects of dexmedetomidine on early postoperative cognitive function and postoperative inflammatory response: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Front Neurol. 2024;15:1422049. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2024.1422049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Wu A, Zhang M. Effects of dexmedetomidine on early cognitive function in elderly patients after abdominal surgery: a meta-analysis. Minerva Anestesiol. 2023;89(9):1034&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.23736/S0375-9393.23.17399-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Yin Q, Xun X, He J, Yu D, Wang Z, et al. The effect of intraoperative dexmedetomidine on cognitive dysfunction after surgery: a updated meta-analysis. J Cardiothorac Surg. 2021;16(1):351. https://doi.org/10.1186/S13019-021-01736-Z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Kang H, Fan J, Cao G, Liu B. Influence of dexmedetomidine on postoperative cognitive dysfunction in the elderly: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Brain Behav. 2022;12(8):e2665. https://doi.org/10.1002/BRB3.2665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng T, Lv J, Cui Y, Li XF, Zhang Q. Effectiveness of dexmedetomidine on postoperative cognitive dysfunction in elderly patients with fracture: a systematic review. Med (Baltim). 2023;102(8):e31749. https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000031749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Leng Y, Yuan X, Yang Y, Zhou C, Liu H. Efficacy of perioperative dexmedetomidine in postoperative pain and neurocognitive functions in orthopedic surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis with trial sequential analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Surg. 2025;111:3525&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1097/JS9.0000000000002315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng K, Long J, Li Y, Hu J. Preventing postoperative cognitive dysfunction using anesthetic drugs in elderly patients undergoing noncardiac surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Surg. 2023;109:21&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1097/JS9.0000000000000001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Xu S, Zhang Y, Huang Y. Effects of anesthetic adjunctive agents on postoperative cognitive dysfunction in elderly patients undergoing noncardiac surgery: A Bayesian network meta-analysis. Brain Behav. 2023;13(9):e03149. https://doi.org/10.1002/brb3.3149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudetz JA, Iqbal Z, Gandhi SD, Patterson KM, Byrne AJ, Hudetz AG, et al. Ketamine attenuates post-operative cognitive dysfunction after cardiac surgery. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2009;53(7):864&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1399-6576.2009.01978.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Zhuang Y, Wu W, Huang J, Huang H, Wang L. Post-operative cognitive dysfunction in patients following gastrointestinal endoscopic treatment. Appl Neuropsychol Adult. 2025;32:307&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.1080/23279095.2023.2168543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieber FE, Neufeld KJ, Gottschalk A, Bigelow GE, Oh ES, Rosenberg PB, et al. Effect of Depth of Sedation in Older Patients Undergoing Hip Fracture Repair on Postoperative Delirium: The STRIDE Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Surg. 2018;153:987&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.1001/JAMASURG.2018.2602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julieb&#xf8; V, Bj&#xf8;ro K, Krogseth M, Skovlund E, Ranhoff AH, Wyller TB. Risk factors for preoperative and postoperative delirium in elderly patients with hip fracture. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2009;57:1354&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.1111/J.1532-5415.2009.02377.X.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou JS, Chen Z, Liu YY, Zhong ML, Zhong Q, Wei J, et al. Observation on the Analgesic Effect of Different Doses of a Combination of Esketamine and Dexmedetomidine Administered for Percutaneous Endoscopic Transforaminal Discectomy: A Randomized, Double-Blind Controlled Trial. CNS Drugs. 2024;38:547&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.1007/S40263-024-01083-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ather R, Nikhar SA, Kar AK, Durga P, Prasanna PL. Comparison of the effect of intraoperative dexmedetomidine versus ketamine on postoperative analgesia in fracture femur patients operated under subarachnoid block &#x2013; A prospective randomized double-blind controlled trial. J Anaesthesiol Clin Pharmacol. 2024;40:605. https://doi.org/10.4103/JOACP.JOACP_67_23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Sharkawy R. Efficacy of Adding Low-Dose Ketamine to Dexmedetomidine Versus Low-Dose Ketamine and Propofol for Conscious Sedation in Patients Undergoing Awake Fiber-optic Intubation. Anesth Essays Res. 2019;13:73. https://doi.org/10.4103/AER.AER_181_18.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>