<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41652402</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2474</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC musculoskeletal disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Arthroscopic transosseous anchorless versus suture anchor repair for rotator cuff tears: a meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">206</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12891-026-09557-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Arthroscopic transosseous anchorless repair (TOA) has re-emerged as an alternative to suture anchor repair (AR) for rotator cuff tears, offering potential biomechanical advantages and cost savings. However, comparative efficacy remains debated. This meta-analysis evaluates clinical and structural outcomes of TOA versus AR techniques.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Following Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines, six databases were systematically searched until May 2025. Comparative studies reporting functional scores (Constant, ASES), range of motion (ROM), visual analog scale (VAS) pain score, and retear rates were included. Risk of bias was assessed using Cochrane RoB 2 for randomized trials and MINORS for non-randomized studies. Meta-analyses used mean differences (MD) or risk ratios (RR) with 95% confidence intervals (CI).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Eight included studies demonstrated no statistically significant differences in most outcomes. Pooled analysis revealed no statistically significant differences in functional recovery (Constant score: MD&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.54, 95%CI: -0.08 to 3.16, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.06; ASES score: MD&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.64, 95%CI: -0.62 to 3.90, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.15) or postoperative pain (VAS: MD&#x2009;=&#x2009;&#x2212;&#x2009;0.05, 95%CI: &#x2212;0.36 to 0.26, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.76). Retear rates were comparable between TOA (13.2%) and AR (15.6%) groups (RR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.84, 95%CI: 0.49&#x2013;1.46, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.55). However, TOA showed superior improvement in abduction ROM (MD&#x2009;=&#x2009;10.51, 95%CI: 5.29&#x2013;15.72, <i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.0001), while external rotation, internal rotation, and forward flexion showed no inter-group differences. Subgroup analyses confirmed equivalent outcomes when TOA was compared specifically to double-row or single-row anchor techniques.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This meta-analysis demonstrates that TOA yields comparable clinical and structural outcomes to AR for rotator cuff tears. The only observed advantage of TOA was a statistically superior improvement in abduction range of motion. Therefore, TOA represents a viable alternative to anchor-based techniques in clinical practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12891-026-09557-8.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Na</LastName><ForeName>Yuyan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Inner Mongolia Medical University, No.59, Horqin South Road, Saihan District, Hohhot City, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Xi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Inner Mongolia Medical University, Hohhot, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zongbo</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Inner Mongolia Medical University, Hohhot, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Yuting</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region People's Hospital, Hohhot, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jingjuan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Inner Mongolia Medical University, Hohhot, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Litian</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quality Management Department, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Inner Mongolia Medical University, No.59, Horqin South Road, Saihan District, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, Hohhot City, China. zj18715892040@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Yizhong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Inner Mongolia Medical University, No.59, Horqin South Road, Saihan District, Hohhot City, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, China. 18004876325@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024MS08008</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024SGGZ099</GrantID><Agency>Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region Public Hospital High Level Clinical Specialist Development Technology Program</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>NYJXGGSJ2024011</GrantID><Agency>Teaching Reform Research and Practice Project of Inner Mongolia Medical University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968565</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2474</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anchor repair</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rotator cuff tears</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transosseous anchorless repair</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41652402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12977394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-026-09557-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12891-026-09557-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Goodman RS. Abnormal findings on magnetic resonance images of asymptomatic shoulders. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1996;78(4):633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/00004623-199604000-00020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8609145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lapner P, Henry P, Athwal GS, Moktar J, McNeil D, MacDonald P. Treatment of rotator cuff tears: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Shoulder Elb Surg. 2022;31(3):e120&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.jse.2021.11.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jse.2021.11.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34906681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaughlin HL. Lesions of the musculotendinous cuff of the shoulder. The exposure and treatment of tears with Retraction. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1944;1994(304):3&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8020230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Z, Wu S, Yang Y, Ren T, Zhang KW. Comparison of arthroscopic Single-row and Double-row repair for rotator cuff injuries with different tear sizes: A systematic review and Meta-analysis. Orthop J Sports Med. 2023;11(8):23259671231180854. 10.1177/23259671231180854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671231180854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10467404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37655249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saridakis P, Jones G. Outcomes of single-row and double-row arthroscopic rotator cuff repair: a systematic review. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2010;92(3):732&#x2013;42. 10.2106/JBJS.I.01295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.I.01295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20194334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ro K, Pancholi S, Son HS, Rhee YG. Perianchor cyst formation after arthroscopic rotator cuff repair using All-Suture-Type, Bioabsorbable-Type, and PEEK-Type anchors. Arthroscopy. 2019;35(8):2284&#x2013;92. 10.1016/j.arthro.2019.03.032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2019.03.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31350085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black EM, Austin LS, Narzikul A, Seidl AJ, Martens K, Lazarus MD. Comparison of implant cost and surgical time in arthroscopic transosseous and transosseous equivalent rotator cuff repair. J Shoulder Elb Surg. 2016;25(9):1449&#x2013;56. 10.1016/j.jse.2016.01.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jse.2016.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27068378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong HJ, Lee JS, Kim YK, Rhee SM, Oh JH. Arthroscopic transosseous anchorless rotator cuff repair reduces bone defects related to peri-implant cyst formation: a comparison with conventional suture anchors using propensity score matching. Clin Shoulder Elb. 2023;26(3):276&#x2013;86. 10.5397/cise.2023.00052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5397/cise.2023.00052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10497926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37559521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atoun E, Kane LT, Abboud JA, Arthroscopic. Needle-Based, transosseous rotator cuff repair. Arthrosc Tech. 2020;9(1):e57&#x2013;63. 10.1016/j.eats.2019.09.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eats.2019.09.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6993199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32021775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park MC, Cadet ER, Levine WN, Bigliani LU, Ahmad CS. Tendon-to-bone pressure distributions at a repaired rotator cuff footprint using transosseous suture and suture anchor fixation techniques. Am J Sports Med. 2005;33(8):1154&#x2013;9. 10.1177/0363546504273053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546504273053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16000662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sano H, Yamashita T, Wakabayashi I, Itoi E. Stress distribution in the supraspinatus tendon after tendon repair: suture anchors versus transosseous suture fixation. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35(4):542&#x2013;6. 10.1177/0363546506296310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546506296310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17218657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urita A, Funakoshi T, Horie T, Nishida M, Iwasaki N. Difference in vascular patterns between transosseous-equivalent and transosseous rotator cuff repair. J Shoulder Elb Surg. 2017;26(1):149&#x2013;56. 10.1016/j.jse.2016.06.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jse.2016.06.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27545051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundar S, Sane RM, Sundaramoorthy R, Ashraf M, Rajan DV. Evaluating transosseous anchorless repair for arthroscopic rotator cuff surgery: a comparative study with double row anchor repair. Clin Shoulder Elb. 2025;28(1):23&#x2013;30. 10.5397/cise.2024.00556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5397/cise.2024.00556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11938928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39627980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesriga MM, Mesregah MK, Dewidar AA, Saad HE, Ebied AM. Outcomes of arthroscopic rotator cuff repair via single-row anchor technique versus transosseous anchorless technique: A randomized controlled trial. J Clin Orthop Trauma. 2025;64:102951. 10.1016/j.jcot.2025.102951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcot.2025.102951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11919305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40109510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Giorgi S, Ottaviani G, Bianchi FP, Delmedico M, Suma M, Moretti B. Single-row versus transosseous technique in the arthroscopic treatment of rotator cuff tears: a meta-analysis. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol. 2024;34(1):31&#x2013;8. 10.1007/s00590-023-03657-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00590-023-03657-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10771355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37561195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinitz A, Buxbaumer P, Hackl M, Buess E. Arthroscopic transosseous anchorless rotator cuff repair using the X-Box technique. Arthrosc Tech. 2019;8(2):e175&#x2013;81. 10.1016/j.eats.2018.10.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eats.2018.10.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6411501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30906688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71. 10.1136/bmj.n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amir-Behghadami M, Janati A, Population. Intervention, Comparison, outcomes and study (PICOS) design as a framework to formulate eligibility criteria in systematic reviews. Emerg Med J. 2020;37(6):387. 10.1136/emermed-2020-209567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/emermed-2020-209567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32253195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:l4898. 10.1136/bmj.l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.l4898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slim K, Nini E, Forestier D, Kwiatkowski F, Panis Y, Chipponi J. Methodological index for non-randomized studies (minors): development and validation of a new instrument. ANZ J Surg. 2003;73(9):712&#x2013;6. 10.1046/j.1445-2197.2003.02748.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1445-2197.2003.02748.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12956787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binder H, Buxbaumer P, Steinitz A, Waibl B, Sonnenschein M, Hackl M, Buess E. Arthroscopic anchorless transosseous rotator cuff repair produces equivalent clinical outcomes and imaging results as a standard suture Bridge technique with anchors. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2022;4(6):e2025&#x2013;34. 10.1016/j.asmr.2022.09.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asmr.2022.09.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9791879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36579043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garofalo R, Calbi R, Castagna A, Cesari E, Budeyri A, Krishnan SG. Is there a difference in clinical outcomes and repair integrity between arthroscopic single-row versus transosseous (anchorless) fixation? A retrospective comparative study. J Orthop Sci. 2018;23(5):770&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.jos.2018.05.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jos.2018.05.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30213364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirakawa Y, Manaka T, Ito Y, Nakazawa K, Iio R, Kubota N, Nakamura H. Comparison of cost, surgical time, and clinical results between arthroscopic transosseous rotator cuff repair with lateral cortical augmentation and arthroscopic transosseous equivalent suture bridge: A propensity score-matched analysis. J Orthop Sci. 2024;29(2):529&#x2013;36. 10.1016/j.jos.2023.02.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jos.2023.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36822948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randelli P, Stoppani CA, Zaolino C, Menon A, Randelli F, Cabitza P. Advantages of arthroscopic rotator cuff repair with a transosseous suture technique: A prospective randomized controlled trial. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45(9):2000&#x2013;9. 10.1177/0363546517695789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546517695789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28339286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#x131;rat A, Ayd&#x131;n M, Tecimel O, &#xd6;&#xe7;g&#xfc;der A, Saniso&#x11f;lu Y, U&#x11f;urlu M. Comparison of the clinical and radiological outcomes of arthroscopic transosseous and transosseous-equivalent double-row rotator cuff repair techniques. Acta Orthop Traumatol Turc. 2020;54(2):178&#x2013;85. 10.5152/j.aott.2020.02.37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5152/j.aott.2020.02.37</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7286160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32254034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J, Luo M, Pan J, Liang G, Feng W, Zeng L, et al. Risk factors affecting rotator cuff retear after arthroscopic repair: a meta-analysis and systematic review. J Shoulder Elb Surg. 2021;30(11):2660&#x2013;70. 10.1016/j.jse.2021.05.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jse.2021.05.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34089878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong HY, Kim HJ, Jeon YS, Rhee YG. Factors predictive of healing in large rotator cuff tears: is it possible to predict retear preoperatively? Am J Sports Med. 2018;46(7):1693&#x2013;700. 10.1177/0363546518762386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546518762386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29595993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotta T, Yamashita T. Osteolysis of the inferior surface of the acromion caused by knots of the suture thread after rotator cuff repair surgery: knot impingement after rotator cuff repair. J Shoulder Elb Surg. 2010;19(8):e17&#x2013;23. 10.1016/j.jse.2010.07.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jse.2010.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21070953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>