<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article article-type="review-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Eur Rev Aging Phys Act</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Eur Rev Aging Phys Act</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2917</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">erapa</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>European Review of Aging and Physical Activity</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">1813-7253</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1861-6909</issn><publisher><publisher-name>BMC</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12752335</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12752335.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12752335</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12752335</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41388441</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s11556-025-00392-9</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">392</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Review</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>The impact of creatine supplementation associated with resistance training on muscular strength and lean tissue mass in the aged: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names initials="S">ShaoChun</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Huang</surname><given-names initials="N">Nan</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names initials="W">WenJuan</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>OuYang</surname><given-names initials="X">XinYe</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Luo</surname><given-names initials="Y">Yun</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff5">5</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhong</surname><given-names initials="Y">YanBiao</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff5">5</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names initials="M">MaoYuan</given-names></name><address><email>wmy.gmu.kf@gmail.com</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff5">5</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names initials="L">Li</given-names></name><address><email>376264093@gmu.edu.cn</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff5">5</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/01tjgw469</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.440714.2</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1797 9454</institution-id><institution>School of Rehabilitation Medicine, Gannan Medical University, </institution></institution-wrap>341000 Ganzhou City, Jiangxi Province, China </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/040gnq226</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.452437.3</institution-id><institution>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, The First Affiliated Hospital of Gannan Medical University, </institution></institution-wrap>341000 Ganzhou City, Jiangxi Province, China </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label>Ganzhou Key Laboratory of Rehabilitation Medicine, 341000 Ganzhou City, Jiangxi Province, China </aff><aff id="Aff4"><label>4</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/01tjgw469</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.440714.2</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1797 9454</institution-id><institution>The First Clinical Medical College of Gannan Medical University, </institution></institution-wrap>341000 Ganzhou City, Jiangxi Province, China </aff><aff id="Aff5"><label>5</label>Ganzhou Intelligent Rehabilitation Technology Innovation Center, 341000 Ganzhou City, Jiangxi Province, China </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>13</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>22</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">479313</issue-id><elocation-id>26</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>30</day><month>5</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>15</day><month>11</month><year>2025</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>13</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>31</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2025-12-31 10:25:12.790"><day>31</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>© The Author(s) 2025</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article’s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article’s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>. The Creative Commons Public Domain Dedication waiver (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</ext-link>) applies to the data made available in this article, unless otherwise stated in a credit line to the data.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="11556_2025_Article_392.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1" abstract-type="structured"><sec><title>Background</title><p id="Par1">Sarcopenia is an age-related decline in muscle strength and mass, which significantly impacts the quality of life for older adults. Resistance training (RT) is well established as an effective intervention for sarcopenia. Some studies suggest that additional benefits may be obtained when RT is combined with creatine supplement (Cr). However, critical confounding factors, such as age and intervention duration, have not been systematically controlled in previous investigations. This systematic review and meta-analysis aims to quantify the efficacy of Cr + RT on appendicular muscle strength and lean tissue mass in older adults, with a particular emphasis on temporal effect modification through duration-stratified subgroup analyses.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p id="Par2">We conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials (RCTs) through searches across eight databases. Eligible studies involved aged individuals undergoing resistance training (2–3 sessions/week) with Cr or placebo (PL) for 8-104 weeks. After screening, 8 RCTs (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 482 participants) were included, assessing outcomes of lean tissue mass, chest press, and leg press strength.</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p id="Par3">Compared to PL + RT, Cr + RT significantly improved lower limb strength (SMD = 0.29 [95% CI 0.00-0.57]; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.05) and lean tissue mass (SMD = 0.27 [95% CI 0.02–0.53]; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.03), but did not show significant improvements in upper extremity muscle strength. Subgroup analysis revealed intervention duration effects: interventions lasting ≤ 32 weeks (5 studies) showed better upper limb strength gains (SMD = 0.45 [95% CI 0.14–0.77]; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.005) and increases in lean tissue mass (SMD = 0.57 [95% CI 0.19–0.96]; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.004).</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusions</title><p id="Par4">Cr + RT can significantly increase muscle strength and lean tissue mass in older adults, particularly in interventions lasting up to 32 weeks. These time-dependent effects highlight the importance of intervention duration in nutritional ergogenic strategies for sarcopenia management. </p></sec><sec><title>Trial registration</title><p id="Par5">This systematic review has the registration number CRD420251018405 on PROSPERO.</p></sec><sec><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s11556-025-00392-9.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>Aging</kwd><kwd>Sarcopenia</kwd><kwd>Exercise</kwd><kwd>Dietary supplements</kwd><kwd>Muscle performance</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution>Major Project Of Ganzhou Science And Technology Bureau</institution></funding-source><award-id>2023LNS37155</award-id><principal-award-recipient><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>MaoYuan</given-names></name></principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution>The Postgraduate Innovation Special Fund Project Of Gannan Medical University</institution></funding-source><award-id>YC2024⁃X014</award-id><principal-award-recipient><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>MaoYuan</given-names></name></principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>© European Group for Research into Elderly and Physical Activity (EGRIPA) 2025</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par23">The progressive skeletal muscle atrophy and dynapenia associated with aging represent hallmark physiological manifestations of senescence, culminating in sarcopenia, a critical public health challenge confronting aging populations globally. As defined by the European Working Group on Sarcopenia (EWGSOP), this condition is characterized diagnostically by the concurrent deterioration of muscle tissue mass and functional capacity (encompassing strength and physical performance) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>]. Epidemiological surveillance data from the World Health Organization (WHO) support that sarcopenia related complications elevate the annual fall incidence by 40% among adults aged 65 years and older, with associated healthcare expenditures constituting 12–18% of total chronic disease costs in geriatrics, an expanding financial burden that parallels demographic aging trends (WHO, 2023) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. Notably, this degenerative process does not commence exclusively in what is traditionally considered old age. Compelling evidence indicates that a significant decline in muscle mass and function commonly initiates around the age of 50 [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>]. Beyond the age of 50 years, loss of leg muscle mass (1–2% per year) and loss of strength (1.5–5% per year) have been reported [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>]. This has led entities such as the WHO to frequently categorize individuals aged 50 years and above within the “older adult” demographic for global aging surveillance to ensure consistency in monitoring and reporting [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. Consequently, interventional research targeting this earlier age window is critical for developing strategies to delay the onset of sarcopenia. Notably, these degenerative processes exhibit marked anatomical specificity, with lower extremity strength declining at 3.2% annually compared to 1.5% in the upper limbs. This disproportionate deterioration underlies functional impairments, which manifest clinically as stair-climbing disability in 74% of community-dwelling elders [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>]. Such pathophysiological heterogeneity critically undermines the therapeutic efficacy of conventional resistance training. While RT remains a cornerstone intervention for mitigating musculoskeletal decline [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>], its anabolic responsiveness is significantly reduced in older adults compared to younger populations. This age-related anabolic blunting has been mechanistically linked to endocrine alterations (e.g., hypogonadism), anabolic resistance syndromes, and mitochondrial dysfunction [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>].</p><p id="Par24">Creatine supplement (Cr), an exogenously administered ergogenic aid with established safety profiles, may potentiate RT-induced muscular adaptations through phosphagen system enhancement. Current evidence suggests Cr + RT improves lean tissue mass and lower extremity strength in older adults [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>], while demonstrating equivocal efficacy for upper limb hypertrophy [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>]. Extant meta-analyses in this domain predominantly focus on younger demographics or heterogeneous age cohorts [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>]. Illustratively, Ye et al.‘s meta-analysis of nutritional interventions demonstrated lean tissue mass accrual in young-to-middle-aged populations [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>]. Critical methodological limitations persist in geriatric-focused research, including inadequate sample sizes, inconsistent intervention durations [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>]. Although Chilibeck et al.‘s meta-analysis of 22 RCTs (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 721) confirmed Cr + RT increases in lean tissue mass (+ 1.37 kg) and appendicular strength in older adults [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>], temporal patterns of therapeutic efficacy remain uncharacterized. Conversely, emerging data from younger cohorts (&lt;50 years old) suggest that treatment effects are both dose-dependent and sexually dimorphic. These findings necessitate further validation in older populations [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>].</p><p id="Par25">Through comprehensive systematic review and meta-analytic methodology, this investigation was designed to address two principal research questions: (1) whether the combined intervention of Cr + RT exhibits anatomical region-specific efficacy, differentially influencing upper extremity versus lower extremity muscle strength and lean tissue mass parameters within geriatric populations; (2) whether a quantifiable “dose-response threshold” exists between intervention duration and therapeutic outcomes, potentially revealing an optimal temporal threshold for clinical application. While previous meta-analyses have authoritatively established the general efficacy of Cr + RT in older adults (Devries &amp; Phillips, 2014; Candow et al., 2014) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>], their scope was primarily confined to aggregated whole-body outcomes. They were consequently limited in exploring the potential anatomical heterogeneity of the muscular response and left unaddressed the critical question of an optimal intervention duration. Furthermore, as the most up-to-date synthesis on this topic, our analysis incorporates a significant body of primary evidence published since the previous meta-analyses, thereby enhancing the statistical power and precision of the conclusions. To bridge these knowledge gaps, this meta-analysis provides a significant methodological and clinical advancement: (1) perform an anatomical region-specific assessment of Cr + RT effects (i.e., upper vs. lower extremity) to inform targeted, region-focused rehabilitation strategies; and (2) quantitatively define a precise time-dependent efficacy threshold for intervention planning. The resultant evidence not only establishes an empirical foundation for individualized sarcopenia management protocols but further elucidates, through rigorous subgroup analysis of intervention timelines, distinct therapeutic advantages associated with 32-week treatment cycles. These findings hold dual implications for both public health policy development regarding anti-aging strategies and the refinement of clinical rehabilitation paradigms targeting age-related musculoskeletal degeneration.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Materials and methods</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Search strategy</title><p id="Par26">The design and conduct of this systematic review were guided by the standards outlined in the Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>]. The reporting of the review protocol was prepared in accordance with the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses for Protocols (PRISMA-P) statemen [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>]. On February 27, 2025, a systematic search was performed across PubMed, Cochrane Library, Embase, Web of Science, China National Knowledge Infrastructure, China Science and Technology Journal Database, Wanfang Data, and Chinese Biomedical Literature Database using the following MeSH terms: “Sarcopenia”, “Resistance training”, “Creatine”, and “Muscle strength”. The search was limited to publications from the preceding decade (2015–2025). Detailed information is provided in Additional file 1. All retrieved records were imported into EndNote 20 for deduplication and preliminary screening. Duplicate records were identified and removed using EndNote 20, followed by the exclusion of systematic reviews and non-original research. Titles and abstracts were then screened against predefined eligibility criteria. Studies that did not meet the intervention criteria or research focus were excluded at this stage. Eligible studies underwent full-text assessment against predefined inclusion/exclusion criteria. Two independent researchers (S.C.L. and N.H.) conducted this process in parallel, with discrepancies resolved through consultation with a third investigator (L.X.).</p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Inclusion and exclusion criteria</title><p id="Par27">Inclusion criteria were formulated following the PICOS framework (Participants, Interventions, Comparators, Outcomes, Study design). Eligible studies met the following criteria: (1) Randomized controlled trials (RCTs) investigating combined Cr and RT effects on muscle strength and lean tissue mass in older adults; (2) Study populations with mean age ≥ 50 years (This threshold was selected based on the established onset of clinically meaningful decline in muscle strength and mass [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>] and aligns with the criteria adopted by prior seminal meta-analyses and review in this field [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>], reflecting the onset of accelerated lean mass and strength decline.), without demographic restrictions; (3) Outcome measures including muscle strength (e.g., maximal voluntary contraction) and lean tissue mass (assessed via dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry [DEXA]), with ≥ 8-week interventions; (4) Comparator groups receiving PL or no treatment; (5) Peer-reviewed journal publications.</p><p id="Par28">Exclusion criteria comprised: (1) Non-randomized controlled trials, observational studies without control groups, or studies lacking comparator arms; (2) Incomplete outcome data or failure to stratify results by age cohort; (3) Populations with uncontrolled comorbidities or absolute contraindications to RT; (4) Unreported creatine supplementation protocols (dosage/duration/administration); (5) Unavailable full-text articles.</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Methodological quality assessment of included studies</title><p id="Par29">In this systematic review, a hierarchical strategy was employed for literature quality assessment, sequentially evaluating individual study risk of bias, the overall certainty of the evidence body, and methodological rigor. First, two researchers independently evaluated and cross-checked the quality of the literature using the Cochrane Risk of Bias tool (RoB 2.0) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>], with each evaluation criterion classified as “low risk,” “high risk,” or “unclear risk.” This assessment of individual studies’ risk of bias laid the groundwork for the subsequent overall evaluation of the evidence body for specific outcomes. Subsequently, to evaluate the overall certainty of the evidence for each primary outcome (e.g., muscle mass, muscle strength), we employed the Grading of Recommendations, Assessment, Development, and Evaluations (GRADE) approach. Two researchers independently operated this process, judging the certainty of evidence as High, Moderate, Low, or Very Low based on predefined criteria for downgrading and upgrading (including risk of bias, imprecision, inconsistency, indirectness, and publication bias) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>]. This process specifically integrated the results from the aforementioned RoB 2.0 assessment to inform the judgment within the ‘Risk of Bias’ domain of the GRADE framework.</p><p id="Par30">Additionally, the Physiotherapy Evidence Database (PEDro) scale was employed to appraise the methodological rigor of included studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. Two investigators conducted blinded independent evaluations of methodological quality (items 2–9) and statistical reporting quality (items 10–11). Study quality was categorized into four grades according to predefined criteria: excellent (9–10 points), good (6–8 points), fair (4–5 points), and poor (&lt; 4 points) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>]. Discrepancies arising from these dual assessment processes were resolved through consensus-based discussions within the research team.</p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Data extraction</title><p id="Par31">This systematic review employed a structured data extraction protocol aligned with PRISMA 2020 guidelines, encompassing four domains: (1) Study metadata: authorship, publication year, and trial design components (randomization sequence generation, allocation concealment, and blinding procedures); (2) Participant profiles: sample size stratified by baseline characteristics, age/sex distributions, and eligibility criteria; (3) Intervention parameters: creatine monohydrate supplementation (dosage [g/kg/day], dosing frequency, and duration) with placebo controls matched for caloric content; (4) Training regimen: weekly session frequency and total intervention duration under certified supervision. The primary endpoint assessed maximal dynamic strength through standardized one-repetition maximum (1RM) or 10-repetition maximum (10RM) testing protocols. Secondary outcomes evaluated lean tissue mass via DEXA scans conducted after 12-hour fasting periods.</p><p id="Par32">Ancillary outcome measures encompassed quarterly-monitored attrition rates, intention-to-treat (ITT) analyses, and standardized adverse event documentation protocols. The data extraction workflow strictly adhered to PRISMA guidelines, with implementation of dual-independent verification and cross-validation mechanisms to ensure both data integrity and completeness. Furthermore, regarding eligible studies included in our systematic review that lacked sufficient pre-post intervention metrics documentation, formal email correspondence was initiated with corresponding authors to request supplemental methodological details.</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Data analysis</title><p id="Par33">For studies reporting solely mean differences with standard deviations between pre- and post-intervention measurements, the standard deviation (SD) of change scores was calculated using the validated formula from the Caughlan Manual for Systematic Intervention Evaluation (Eq. 3.2a, 2023 edition) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>]. The utilization of a correlation coefficient (<italic toggle="yes">r</italic> = 0.8) adhered to the methodological practice established by the Chilibeck research team in resistance training meta-analyses [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. In their analytical approach, unreported pre-post correlations were typically addressed using Bayesian estimation methods informed by domain-specific prior knowledge [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>]</p><p id="Par34">
<disp-formula id="Equa"><tex-math id="d33e523">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\begin{aligned}\;SD\_\{change\;score\}=\surd (&amp;\left(D\_pre\right)\hat{}2\;+\;\left(D\_post\right)\hat{}2 \\ &amp; -\;2\cdot r\cdot D\_pre\cdot D\_post )\end{aligned}$$\end{document}</tex-math></disp-formula>
</p><p id="Par35">The meta-analysis was conducted using Review Manager 5.3 software (The Cochrane Collaboration, 2024), with all forest plots constructed using the DerSimonian-Laird random-effects model for calculating standardized mean differences (SMD) and 95% confidence intervals (95% CI) to evaluate intergroup effect differences. Effect sizes were interpreted according to the Hopkins classification system, where effect magnitudes were categorized as: &lt;0.20 (trivial), 0.20–0.59 (small), 0.60–1.19 (moderate), and ≥ 1.20 (large) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>]. Statistical significance was defined as α = 0.05 for all inferential analyses.</p><p id="Par36">Heterogeneity assessment was performed through Chi-squared and I<sup>2</sup> statistics, with the latter quantifying the proportion of total variation attributable to between-study heterogeneity (low: &lt;50%; moderate: 50–75%; high: &gt;75%) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>]. Meanwhile, Subgroup analyses were stratified by intervention duration (≤ 32 weeks vs. ≥54 weeks) to explore potential sources of heterogeneity and examine the temporal influence on musculoskeletal outcomes.</p><p id="Par37">Furthermore, given that multiple studies in this meta-analysis contributed more than one correlated effect size (e.g., reporting upper-body strength, lower-body strength, and muscle mass simultaneously), we additionally performed Robust Variance Estimation (RVE) to account for this dependency and verify the robustness of our findings. This analysis was conducted using the metafor and clubSandwich packages in R (version 4.5.0), employing the correlated effects working model and the CR2 variance estimator to obtain more reliable statistical inferences.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec9"><title>Number and characteristics of included studies</title><p id="Par38">This study adhered to the PRISMA 2020 guideline for conducting the literature screening. The systematic literature search yielded a total of 2,171 records. After the removal of 1,372 duplicates, a total of 799 records underwent title and abstract screening. Following this primary phase, 16 full-text articles were assessed for eligibility. Ultimately, 8 randomized controlled trials (RCTs) met all pre-defined criteria and were included in the quantitative synthesis (meta-analysis). A complete flow diagram of the study selection process, with reasons for exclusion at the full-text stage, is provided in Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>.</p><p id="Par39">
<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><p>Flowchart of the study selection process</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e561" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="11556_2025_392_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par40">The characteristics of the eight eligible studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>] comprising the final analysis are detailed in Tables <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref> and <xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref>. A total of 482 participants were enrolled across these studies, with the cohort comprising untrained healthy older men and postmenopausal women, all with a mean age of ≥ 50 years. Notably, 6 studies enrolled healthy or postmenopausal women [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>], while 5 studies included untrained healthy older men [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>]. Regarding intervention protocols, all participants were randomized to receive either Cr or Pl during supervised RT sessions conducted 2–3 times weekly. The study durations ranged from 8 to 104 weeks, with three distinct dosing strategies employed: 1 study used a Cr dose of 0.14 g/kg/day [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>], 1 study used a dose of 5 g/day [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>], and the remaining 6 studies used a relative dosage strategy of 0.1 g/kg/day [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>]. In terms of study outcomes, compared with the control group, 4 studies reported a positive effect of Cr on muscular strength via 1RM or 10RM testing [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>], and 4 studies reported positive effects of Cr on muscle mass by DEXA testing [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>]. 8 studies systematically documented adverse events, which primarily manifested as transient gastrointestinal discomfort and mild muscle cramping, with no serious adverse events recorded.</p><p id="Par41">
<table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Characteristics of Included Studies</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Author<break/>(Year)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Population</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">country</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = Per<break/>Group</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Age(year)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Intervention<break/>Supplement ation</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Training Frequency and Volume</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Training<break/>Intensity</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">OutcomeMeasure<break/>(Italics Indicate Effect<break/>Significant Cr)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Duration</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Bernat et al.</p><p>(2019) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>untrained</p><p>healthy aging males</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Canada</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>24</p><p>Cr = 12</p><p>PI = 12</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 59.0 ± 7.0</p><p>Pl: 58.1 ± 5.8</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 0.1 g/kg/day</p><p>PI: 0.1 g malt/kg/day</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>RT 2x/week</p><p>4 sets (lower body exercise) 3 sets</p><p>(upper body exercise)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">80% 1-RM</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>MS: 1RM (leg press, chest press,</p><p>and Elbow and</p><p>knee flexion and extension)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8 weeks</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Amiri et al.*</p><p>(2023) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>untrained</p><p>healthy older adults</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Iran</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>45</p><p>Cr = 15</p><p>PI = 15</p><p>CG = 15</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 61.2 ± 0.706</p><p>Pl: 61.3 ± 3.157</p><p>CG: 62.5 ± 2.547</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 0.1 g/kg/day</p><p>PI: 0.1 g malt/kg/day</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>RT 3x/week</p><p>3 sets × 10 reps</p><p>(7 exercises)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">75% 1-RM</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>MS: 1RM (leg extension and curl</p><p>machine, bench press, lateral pull down, barbell curl,</p><p>overhead press, and</p><p>triceps extension)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10 weeks</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Candow et al.*</p><p>(2015) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Healthy ≥ 50 years older adults</p><p>(women were</p><p>postmenopausal)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Canada</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>39</p><p>CrB = 15</p><p>CrA = 12</p><p>Pl = 12</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>CrB: 53.2 ± 2.5</p><p>CrA: 55.5 ± 3.5</p><p>Pl: 57.2 ± 6.5</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 0.1 g Cr + 0.1 g</p><p>malt/kg/day</p><p>Pl: 0.2 g malt/kg/day</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>RT 3x/week</p><p>3 sets × 10 reps</p><p>(11 exercises)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>10-RM</p><p>(To failure)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>MS: 1RM (Cr before and</p><p>After-leg press and chest press)</p><p>BC: DEXA (Cr after-muscle mass)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">32 weeks</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Chilibeck et al.</p><p>(2015) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Postmenopausal</p><p>women</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Canada</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>33</p><p>Cr = 15</p><p>Pl = 18</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 57 ± 4</p><p>Pl: 57 ± 7</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 0.1 g Cr/kg/day</p><p>Pl: 0.1 g malt/kg/day</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>RT 3x/week</p><p>3 sets × 10 reps</p><p>(14 exercises)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">80% 1-RM</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>MS: 1RM (bench press</p><p>And hack squat)</p><p>BC: DEXA (muscle mass)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">52 weeks</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Chilibeck et al.</p><p>(2023) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>postmenopausal</p><p>women</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Canada</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>237</p><p>Cr = 120</p><p>Pl = 117</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 59.0 ± 5.6</p><p>Pl: 59.0 ± 5.7</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 0.14 Cr + 0.14 g</p><p>malt/kg/day</p><p>Pl: 0.28 g mait/kg/day</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>RT 3x/week</p><p>2 sets × 8 reps</p><p>(12 exercises)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">80% 1-RM</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>MS: 1RM (hack squat and</p><p>bench press)</p><p>BC: DEXA (muscle mass)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>104</p><p>weeks</p></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Johannsmeyer et al.*</p><p>(2016) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Older adults</p><p>(women were</p><p>postmenopausal)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Canada</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>31</p><p>Cr = 14</p><p>Pl = 17</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 58.0 ± 3.0</p><p>Pl: 57.6 ± 5.0</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 0.1 g Cr + 0.1 g</p><p>Dextrose/kg/day</p><p>Pl: 0.2 g textrose/kg/day</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>RT 3x/week</p><p>2 sets × 10 reps</p><p>(4 exercises)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">80% 1-RM and 30% 1-RM</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>MS: 1RM (leg press, chest press,</p><p>hack Squat and lateral pull-down)</p><p>BC: DEXA (muscle mass)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12 weeks</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Candow et al.*</p><p>(2021) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Healthy older males</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Canada</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>46</p><p>Cr = 21</p><p>Pl = 25</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 58.0 ± 6.0</p><p>Pl: 56.0 ± 5.0</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 0.1 g Cr/kg/day</p><p>Pl: 0.1 g malt/kg/day</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>RT 3x/week</p><p>3 sets × 10 reps</p><p>(12 exercises)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">80% 1-RM</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>MS: 1RM (bench press</p><p>And hack squat)</p><p>BC: DEXA (muscle mass)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">52 weeks</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Pinto et al.</p><p>(2016) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">healthy older adults</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Brazil</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>27</p><p>Cr = 13</p><p>Pl = 14</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 67.4 ± 4.7</p><p>Pl: 67.1 ± 6.3</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Cr: 5 g Cr/day</p><p>Pl: 5 g malt/day</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>RT 3x/week</p><p>3 sets × 10 reps</p><p>(14 exercises)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>10- RM</p><p>(To failure)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>MS: 10RM (bench press</p><p>and leg press)</p><p>BC: DEXA (musicle mass)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12 weeks</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p><italic toggle="yes">Cr</italic> creatine, <italic toggle="yes">Pl</italic> placebo, malt maltodextrin, <italic toggle="yes">RT</italic> resistance training, <italic toggle="yes">MS</italic> muscle strength, <italic toggle="yes">1RM</italic> 1-repetition maximum, <italic toggle="yes">10RM</italic> 10-repetition maximum, <italic toggle="yes">BC</italic> body composition, <italic toggle="yes">CrB</italic> Cr-Before, Cr-After*From the studies that included males and females</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par42">
<table-wrap id="Tab2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Baseline, post-intervention, and change values for primary outcomes in studies included in the systematic review and meta-analysis</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Author<break/>(Year)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cr(Baseline Mean ± SD)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">PI(Baseline Mean ± SD)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cr(Post Mean ± SD)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">PI(Post Mean ± SD)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cr (Δ Mean)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">PI(Δ Mean)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cr <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>(Within-group)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">PI <italic toggle="yes">P</italic>(Within)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic>(Between-group<break/>vs. PL)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Significant effect(Yes/No)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Bernat et al.</p><p>(2019) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>265 ± 81(LB)</p><p>78.66 ± 16.81(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>240.5 ± 105.76(UB)</p><p>76.66 ± 12.6(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>409.5 ± 137.03(LB)</p><p>78.66 ± 19(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>324.41 ± 133.9(LB)</p><p>76.66 ± 17.58(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>144.5(LB)</p><p>19.00(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>83.91(LB)</p><p>17.58(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.044(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.711(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Yes(LB)</p><p>No(UB)</p></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Amiri et al.</p><p>(2023) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>33.61 ± 36.38(LB)</p><p>32.15 ± 21.8(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>9.62 ± 9.16(LB)</p><p>19.62 ± 9.81(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>50.53 ± 52.61(LB)</p><p>47 ± 31.53(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>14.42 ± 12.69(LB)</p><p>25.68 ± 14.4(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>13.54(LB)</p><p>14.85(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>4.81(LB)</p><p>6.06(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.001(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.001(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.001(LB)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(UB)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Yes(LB)</p><p>Yes(UB)</p></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Candow et al.</p><p>(2015) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>137.4 ± 55.9(CrB + LB)</p><p>144.4 ± 53.9(CrA + LB)</p><p>50 ± 26.2(CrB + UB)</p><p>43.2 ± 16.3(CrA + UB)</p><p>46.6 ± 10.8(CrA + MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>134.6 ± 53.8(LB)</p><p>49.3 ± 20.2(UB)</p><p>41.7 ± 8.7(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>174.1 ± 70.4(CrB + LB)</p><p>185.2 ± 58.3(CrA + LB)</p><p>65.2 ± 33.6(CrB + UB)</p><p>58.9 ± 29.8(CrA + UB)</p><p>49.6 ± 11.8(CrA + MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>140.1 ± 35.2(LB)</p><p>51.2 ± 16.4(UB)</p><p>42.2 ± 9.1(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>36.6(CrB + LB)</p><p>40.8(CrA + LB)</p><p>15.2(CrB + UB)</p><p>15.7(CrA + UB)</p><p>1.8(CrB + MM)</p><p>2.8(CrA + MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>5.6(LB)</p><p>1.9(UB)</p><p>0.5(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(CrA + LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(CrB + LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(CrB + UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(CrA + UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(CrA + MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.025(CrA + LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.025(CrA + UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.025(CrB + LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.025(CrB + UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.025(CrA + MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes(CrA + LB)Yes(CrA + LB༉Yes(CrB + UB) Yes(CrA + UB) Yes(CrA + MM)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Chilibeck et al.</p><p>(2015) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>-(LB)</p><p>-(UB)</p><p>-(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>-(LB)</p><p>-(UB)</p><p>-(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>-(LB)</p><p>-(UB)</p><p>-(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>-(LB)</p><p>-(UB)</p><p>-(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>54(LB)</p><p>18(UB)</p><p>−1.0(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>50(LB)</p><p>11(UB)</p><p>−1.3(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.01(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>-(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(UB)</p><p>-(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>No(LB)</p><p>Yes(UB) No(MM)</p></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Chilibeck et al.</p><p>(2023) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>57.6 ± 21.6(LB)</p><p>32.1 ± 12.7(UB)</p><p>41.4 ± 6.2(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>56.6 ± 24(LB)</p><p>30.6 ± 10.9(UB)</p><p>40.3 ± 5.3(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>84.4 ± 28.1(LB)</p><p>42.6 ± 14.1(UB)</p><p>43.5 ± 6.3(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>82.7 ± 25(LB)</p><p>41.4 ± 14(UB)</p><p>42.1 ± 5.4(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>26.8(LB)</p><p>10.5(UB)</p><p>2.1(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>26.1(LB)</p><p>10.80(UB)</p><p>1.8(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.0001(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.0001(UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.0001(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.0001(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.0001(UB) <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.0001(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.97(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.2(UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.046(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>No(LB)</p><p>No(UB) Yes(MM)</p></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Johannsmeyer et al.</p><p>(2016) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>100 ± 37.3(lLB)</p><p>62 ± 27.4(UB)</p><p>-(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>102.8 ± 35.1(LB)</p><p>61.1 ± 29.8(UB)</p><p>-(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>121.6 ± 46.1(LB)</p><p>77.3 ± 32.8(UB)</p><p>-(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>120.3 ± 36.7(LB)</p><p>73.6 ± 36.3(UB)</p><p>-(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>27.7(LB)</p><p>15.3(UB)</p><p>-(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>35.8(LB)</p><p>12.5(UB)</p><p>-(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.001(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001(UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.001(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001(UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>-(LB)</p><p>-(UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.007(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>No(LB)</p><p>No(UB) Yes(MM)</p></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Candow et al.</p><p>(2021) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>111 ± 53.8(LB)</p><p>97 ± 33(UB)</p><p>62.80 ± 8.60(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>105 ± 56.9(LB)</p><p>92.00 ± 36.3(UB)</p><p>62.2 ± 11.3(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>180 ± 54.3(LB)</p><p>108 ± 17.1(UB)</p><p>61.9 ± 8.3(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>181 ± 58.8(LB)</p><p>114 ± 29.9(UB)</p><p>60.3 ± 9.2(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>69(LB)</p><p>11.00(UB)</p><p>−0.9(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>76(LB)</p><p>22(UB)</p><p>−1.9(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.005(UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.007(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.05(UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.05(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.650(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.350(UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.333(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>No(LB)</p><p>No(UB)</p><p>No(MM)</p></td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Pinto et al.</p><p>(2016) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>60.4 ± 35.5(LB)</p><p>14.7 ± 7.1(UB)</p><p>38.3 ± 8(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>57.6 ± 26(LB)</p><p>16 ± 5.5(UB)</p><p>40.4 ± 8.6(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>114.6 ± 41.3(LB)</p><p>26.2 ± 8.7(UB)</p><p>40.1 ± 8.7(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>128.6 ± 53.4(LB)</p><p>26.7 ± 7.7(UB)</p><p>40.9 ± 9.3(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>54.2(LB)</p><p>11.5(UB)</p><p>1.8(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>71(LB)</p><p>10.7(UB)</p><p>0.5(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.0001(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.0001(UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.01(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.0001(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.0001(UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.143(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.05(LB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.05(UB)</p><p><italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.02(MM)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>No(LB)</p><p>No(UB) Yes(MM)</p></td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p><italic toggle="yes">Cr</italic> creatine, <italic toggle="yes">Pl</italic> placebo, <italic toggle="yes">MS</italic> muscle strength, <italic toggle="yes">MM</italic> muscle mass, <italic toggle="yes">LB</italic> lower body, <italic toggle="yes">UB</italic> upper body, <italic toggle="yes">CrB</italic> Cr-Before,<italic toggle="yes"> CrA</italic> Cr-After</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Quality of the research methodology</title><p id="Par43">The methodological quality assessment was conducted using the Cochrane Risk of Bias Tool 2.0, with detailed results visualized in Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>. 8 incorporated studies implemented randomization and double-blinding procedures [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>]. However, the randomization process raised unclear risk for the majority of studies (approximately 75%) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>], primarily due to inadequate reporting of allocation concealment methods. In contrast, most studies (approximately 88%) were judged to be at low risk of bias for both deviations from intended interventions and measurement of the outcome [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>], reflecting robust blinding and the use of objective outcome measures. Assessments for bias arising from missing outcome data and the selection of reported results yielded mixed judgments. Specifically, 50% of the included studies were rated as having unclear risk [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>], a small proportion were judged to be at low risk [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>], and another small proportion [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>] were classified as high risk—with the relatively high attrition rate during the study process identified as the primary contributing factor to the high-risk rating. Overall, the majority of studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>] (approximately 75%) were rated as having unclear risk regarding their overall assessment, largely driven by uncertainties in the randomization process. </p><p id="Par44">Furthermore, the overall certainty of the evidence for the critical outcomes was evaluated using the GRADE approach. The evidence certainty was rated as moderate for both upper and lower limb muscle strength, and as low for muscle mass. As detailed in Table <xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref>, the primary reasons for downgrading the evidence were the risk of bias (identified in the RoB 2.0 assessment) and imprecision (reflected in the sample size was too small).</p><p id="Par45">
<fig id="Fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><p>Risk of Bias summary plot</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1741" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="11556_2025_392_Fig2_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par46">
<table-wrap id="Tab3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>GRADE evidence profile for outcomes among trials included in the systematic review</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">№ of studies<break/>(participants)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Study design</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Risk of bias</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Inconsistency</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Indirectness</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Imprecision</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Other considerations</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cr + RT</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">pl + RT</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Absolute<break/>(95% CI)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Quality</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Importance</th></tr><tr><th align="left" colspan="12" rowspan="1">muscle strength of the upper body</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8(407)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">RCTs</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">serious<sup>a</sup></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">not serious</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">not serious</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">not serious</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">none</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">200</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">207</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>SMD <bold>0.25</bold></p><p>(0.03 lower to 0.54 higher)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>⨁⨁⨁◯</p><p>Moderate<sup>a</sup></p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">CRITICAL</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="12" rowspan="1">muscle strength of the lower body</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8(407)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">RCTs</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">serious<sup>a</sup></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">not serious</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">not serious</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">not serious</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">none</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">200</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">207</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>SMD <bold>0.29</bold></p><p>(0 to 0.57 higher)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>⨁⨁⨁◯</p><p>Moderate<sup>a</sup></p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">CRITICAL</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="12" rowspan="1">muscle mass</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6(354)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">RCTs</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">serious<sup>b</sup></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">not serious</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">not serious</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">serious<sup>c</sup></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">none</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">173</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">181</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>SMD <bold>0.27</bold></p><p>(0.02 higher to 0.53 higher)</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>⨁⨁◯◯</p><p>Low<sup>b, c</sup></p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">CRITICAL</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>(a) Inadequate allocation concealment; (b) High dropout rates in most studies; (c) The sample size was too small (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> &lt; 400)</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par47">We also assessed the methodological quality of the included studies using the PEDro scale, with the results presented in Table <xref rid="Tab4" ref-type="table">4</xref>. Among the 8 studies, 4 studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>] were rated as excellent and 4 studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>] as good. Notably, while the PEDro scale provides itemized quality assessments, 38% of studies failed to adequately document allocation procedures despite appropriate description of randomization methods [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>]; 50% lacked explicit declaration of intention-to-treat analysis adherence [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>]; while 75% exhibited participant dropout rates exceeding 15% [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>].</p><p id="Par48">
<table-wrap id="Tab4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4</label><caption><p>PEDro score (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 8)</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Study</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Random Allocation</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Concealed<break/>Allocation</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Groups Similar at Baseline</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Participant Blinding</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Therapis Blinding</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Examiner Blinding</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 15% Dropouts</th><th align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Intention to Treat Analysis</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Between Group Difference Reported</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Point Estimate<break/>and Variability<break/>Reported</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Total<break/>(0–10)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Bernat et al.</p><p>(2019) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Amiri et al.*</p><p>(2023) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Candow et al.</p><p>(2015) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Chilibeck et al.</p><p>(2015) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Chilibeck et al.</p><p>(2023) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Johansmeyer et al(2016) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>]</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Candow et al.*</p><p>(2021) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><p>Pinto et al.</p><p>(2016) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>]</p></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">N</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Y</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p><italic toggle="yes">Y</italic> yes, <italic toggle="yes">N</italic> no</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Meta-analysis results</title><sec id="Sec12"><title>Upper limb muscle strength</title><p id="Par49">As shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>, a total of 8 studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>] investigating Cr + RT were pooled using SMD with random-effects models to assess upper limb muscle strength outcomes. The meta-analysis demonstrated no statistically significant difference between Cr and PL in upper limb muscle strength (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.08; I<sup>2</sup> = 42%; SMD = 0.25 [95% CI −0.03−0.54]). To analyze the sources of heterogeneity <italic toggle="yes">(p</italic> = 0.09, I<sup>2</sup> = 42%) and the effect of intervention time on upper limb muscle strength, we performed subgroup analyses of study intervention times. No significant effect was observed for Cr versus PL in studies with intervention periods ≥ 52 weeks (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.97; I<sup>2</sup> = 48%; SMD = 0.01 [95% CI −0.43−0.41]). In contrast, Cr significantly improved upper limb muscle strength versus PL in interventions ≤ 32 weeks (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.005; I<sup>2</sup> = 0%; SMD = 0.45 [95% CI 0.14–0.77]).</p><p id="Par50">
<fig id="Fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><p>Forest plot for analysis of muscle strength of the upper body during the bench press or chest press exercise, separated by subgroups according to study duration (up to 32 weeks and ≥ 52 weeks)</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e2333" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="11556_2025_392_Fig3_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec13"><title>Lower limb muscle strength</title><p id="Par51">As shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>, a total of 8 studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>] assessing Cr + RT were meta-analyzed using SMD under random-effects models for lower limb muscle strength outcomes. The meta-analysis revealed a borderline significant improvement in lower limb muscle strength with Cr versus PL (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.05; I² = 40%; SMD = 0.29 [95% CI 0.00–0.57.00.57]), demonstrating moderate heterogeneity (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.10, I² = 40%). Subgroup analyses were performed to investigate intervention duration effects, stratified by ≥ 52 weeks and ≤ 32 weeks. No significant differences were observed between the ≥ 52-week and ≤ 32-week subgroups (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &gt;0.05 for interaction). In both subgroups, Cr demonstrated no statistically significant effects versus PL (≥ 52 weeks: <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.18; I² = 0%; SMD = 0.17 [95% CI −0.08−0.42]; ≤32 weeks: <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.06; I² =52%; SMD = 0.45 [95% CI −0.01−0.91])</p><p id="Par52">
<fig id="Fig4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 4</label><caption><p>Forest plot for analysis of muscle strength of the lower body during the leg press or hack exercise, separated by subgroups according to study duration (up to 32 weeks and ≥ 54 weeks)</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e2372" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="11556_2025_392_Fig4_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec14"><title>Lean body mass</title><p id="Par53">As shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>, a total of 6 studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>] investigating Cr + RT were meta-analyzed using SMD under random-effects models for lean tissue mass outcomes. The pooled analysis demonstrated a significant increase in lean tissue mass with Cr versus PL (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.03; I² = 18%; SMD = 0.27 [95% CI 0.02–0.53]), demonstrating low heterogeneity (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.30, I² = 18%). Subgroup analyses were conducted to examine intervention duration effects, stratified into ≥ 52-week and ≤ 32-week cohorts. No significant effect was observed for Cr versus PL in the ≥ 52-week subgroup (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.51; I<sup>2</sup> = 0%; SMD = 0.08 [95% CI −0.17−0.34]). In contrast, Cr significantly improved lean tissue mass versus PL in the ≤ 32-week subgroup (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.004; I<sup>2</sup> = 0%; SMD = 0.57 [95% CI 0.19–0.96]).</p><p id="Par54">
<fig id="Fig5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 5</label><caption><p> Forest plot for muscle mass, separated by subgroups according to study duration (up to 32 weeks and ≥ 54 weeks)</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e2412" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="11556_2025_392_Fig5_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec15"><title>Publication bias</title><p id="Par55">Given the limited sample size of included randomized controlled trials (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 8), formal publication bias assessment was not performed following methodological standards recommending a minimum of 10 studies for reliable funnel plot/Egger’s test applications [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>]. Quantitative verification was deliberately omitted due to the known reduced statistical power (&lt; 50%) of bias detection methods in small meta-analyses. This conservative approach prevents overinterpretation of potentially unreliable bias indicators. </p></sec><sec id="Sec16"><title>Sensitivity analysis</title><p id="Par56">To verify the robustness of the primary results, we employed RVE to account for the dependency of multiple effect sizes within studies. The RVE analysis revealed that the pooled effect size remained statistically significant (Hedges’ g = 0.327, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.017, [95% ci 0.063–0.591]). Detailed data can be found in Additional file 1. This result is consistent in both direction and significance with the findings from the primary random-effects model analysis, thereby strongly confirming the reliability of our main findings.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec17"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par57">This systematic review provides a comprehensive evaluation of Cr + RT for modulating sarcopenia-related parameters in older adults, establishing an evidence-based framework for optimizing exercise-nutritional interventions. Through meta-analysis of 8 randomized controlled trials, Cr + RT demonstrated superior efficacy versus RT + PL in enhancing lower extremity muscle strength and lean tissue mass. This not only confirms previous findings in geriatric cohorts but, more importantly, extends the evidence for effective intervention through subgroup analyses and delineates an optimal efficacy window lasting up to 32 weeks. Stratified subgroup analyses revealed critical temporal dynamics: Interventions ≤ 32 weeks yielded significantly greater improvements in muscle strength and lean tissue mass compared to ≥ 52-week regimens, mirroring Santos et al.‘s non-linear duration-response relationship (the research demonstrated significant improvements in muscle strength and mass among older women following short-term interventions of 6 to 24 weeks) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>]. The ≤ 32-week cutoff was selected based on a natural clustering of study durations, providing a clear demarcation between short-to-medium and long-term interventions. Building upon their conclusions, the present study further defines a more robust temporal efficacy window, indicating that the significant benefits of Cr + RT can be sustained for up to 32 weeks, thereby extending and refining the existing evidence on effective intervention periods. This dose-response pattern suggests diminishing returns with prolonged intervention, potentially attributable to creatine-mediated osmotic saturation thresholds. This phenomenon, including CRT downregulation after long-term exposure, has been described in reviews by Dolan et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>]. The observed temporal sensitivity implies cyclical supplementation strategies may optimize outcomes. These biochemical adaptations are a priority research direction with direct implications for clinical protocol standardization in age-related muscle wasting. The hypothesized mechanism and clinical significance will be systematically discussed later.</p><sec id="Sec18"><title>Selection of the study population</title><p id="Par58">The selection of older adults as the target population was based on their elevated sarcopenia risk profile, characterized by progressive muscle mass depletion (1–3% annual loss) and accelerated lower limb strength decline (≥ 3%/year) that clinically manifests as increased fall incidence (OR = 2.1–3.4) and compromised independence in activities of daily living (ADLs) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>]. Age-related anabolic resistance, characterized by a 40–60% reduction in testosterone and DHEA levels, a 30% decrease in muscle protein synthesis rates, and mitochondrial dysfunctions such as a 25% lower ATP production capacity, significantly impairs the responsiveness to resistance training compared to younger individuals [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>]. Cr, as a well-tolerated exogenous supplement, demonstrates unique therapeutic potential through phosphocreatine system potentiation (enhancing ATP regeneration by 15–20% during high-intensity contractions) and osmotic-mediated cell signaling pathways that may synergize with RT-induced mechanical stimuli [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. Despite these mechanistic advantages, current evidence remains disproportionately focused on young adults (78% of RCTs in populations &lt; 50 years) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>], with existing geriatric trials constrained by methodological limitations including small samples, heterogeneous intervention durations (12–54 weeks), and insufficient anatomical stratification—particularly regarding upper vs. lower extremity adaptations [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>]. Our investigation tackles these limitations by conducting thorough subgroup stratification based on intervention duration. This approach provides a quantitative synthesis of the temporal efficacy patterns of Cr + RT in older adults, thus establishing a robust evidence base for developing personalized sarcopenia management protocols.</p></sec><sec id="Sec19"><title>Research mechanisms</title><p id="Par59">While the present meta-analysis did not directly elucidate underlying mechanisms, our synthesis of extant studies supports the hypothesis that creatine’s ergogenic effects on muscle strength may stem from enhanced Phosphocreatine (PCr) energy buffering capacity. Mechanistic evidence indicates Cr amplifies ATP resynthesis efficiency through dose-dependent increases in intramyocellular PCr stores, critical for sustaining high-intensity contractions [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>]. Notably, geriatric populations exhibit 30–40% lower basal PCr reserves versus young adults [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>], yet randomized trials demonstrate 12-week creatine supplementation restores PCr availability to 85–90% of youthful levels during RT sessions, preferentially enhancing type II fiber endurance through improved excitation-contraction coupling efficiency [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>]. Complementary rodent studies by Hespel et al. provide direct experimental validation: In aged rat quadriceps models, 8-week Cr administration elevated PCr concentrations by 27.3 ± 2.1%, concurrent with 19% improvement in maximal tetanic force production. Establishing temporal concordance between PCr repletion and functional gains [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref>]. This mechanistic consistency across human and animal models, particularly the dose-responsive PCr restoration patterns, strengthens the biological plausibility of PCr-mediated adaptation as a primary pathway for Cr + RT synergism in sarcopenia mitigation.</p><p id="Par60">We also postulate an alternative mechanistic pathway involving mTORC1 activation: Cr induced osmotic stress may stimulate mTORC1 signaling, thereby potentiating ribosomal biogenesis and subsequent myofibrillar protein accretion. This mechanism was also validated in the in vitro experiments of Deldicque et al. which showed that Cr intervention significantly up-regulated the level of mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) phosphorylation in a model of senescent myoblasts, and they found that the degree of mTOR signaling activation showed a significant positive correlation with the rate of myosin heavy chain synthesis by further analysis [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>]. Although this mechanism has a certain degree of plausibility, more in vitro studies are needed for further validation compared with the phosphocreatine energy buffering mechanism.</p></sec><sec id="Sec20"><title>Innovative and applied value of the research</title><p id="Par61">Consensus with prior research: This investigation corroborates existing evidence by replicating the critical finding of Chilibeck et al. that Cr + RT substantially improves lower limb strength, with 85% concordance in effect size magnitudes [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>]. Our data further validate the dosing framework established by Candow et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref>], which demonstrated significant efficacy with a lower-dose, protein-combined protocol (0.1 g/kg/d) without a loading phase in older. Notably, the absence of significant upper limb strength improvements with creatine supplementation contrasts with prior meta-analytic conclusions, yet al.igns mechanistically with Forbes et al.‘s hypothesis regarding differential fiber-type distributions [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>]. The reduced proportion of type II muscle fibers in upper versus lower extremities provides a plausible biological rationale for this anatomical disparity in treatment responsiveness [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref>].</p><p id="Par62">The present study presents a unique perspective: Our subgroup analyses based on intervention duration revealed that creatine supplementation for ≤ 32 weeks was significantly more effective than for ≥ 54 weeks in enhancing muscle strength and lean body mass. This finding supports the hypothesis put forth by Dolan et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref>], which suggests that “long-term Cr may lead to an adaptive decrease in myocyte osmolality.” From a clinical standpoint, improvements in upper extremity strength can enhance patients’ ability to perform self-care tasks, such as feeding and transferring. Moreover, a 5–8% increase in lower extremity strength can reduce the risk of falls by 20% [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>]. By integrating short-term nutritional interventions on this basis, we not only lower treatment costs and enhance rehabilitation efficiency but also improve elderly patients’ tolerance and compliance. This shift promotes a transition in clinical strategies from passive care to active muscular reconstruction. Lower body strength, which is often significantly impacted by the aging process, plays a crucial role in maintaining mobility in real-life scenarios [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref>]. Activities of daily living, such as climbing stairs, walking, and performing household tasks, are highly correlated with mobility [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>]. The enhancement of lower limb strength observed in this study can effectively improve quality of life and demonstrates clear practical value. In conclusion, further optimization of the intervention cycle in future studies could significantly reduce healthcare costs, streamline sports nutrition interventions, improve patient compliance, and diminish health risks.</p></sec><sec id="Sec21"><title>Limitations</title><p id="Par63">A strength of this study is the adoption of two statistical approaches for verification. Although the traditional random-effects model forest plot provides an intuitive visualization of the results, we supplemented it with the more advanced RVE method to appropriately address the issue of effect size dependency in meta-analysis, which enhances the credibility of our conclusions. However, this study also has many limitations. The limitations of this study are primarily as follows: (1) The restricted inclusion of only 8 randomized controlled trials with limited cumulative sample sizes may compromise statistical power and external validity [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>]. Furthermore, quantitative assessment of publication bias was precluded by the insufficient number of eligible studies; (2) While overall bias risk was rated as unclear risk, 6 included trials [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>] exhibited attrition rates exceeding 15%, compounded by 4 studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>] omitting intentionto-treat reporting-methodological gaps that may inflate intervention efficacy estimates through selection bias; (3) Though our temporal analysis identified superior efficacy for 32-week interventions, unaccounted sex-specific variations in hormonal profiles (particularly postmenopausal estrogen decline versus androgen levels in males) could modulate creatine metabolism efficiency, necessitating future sex-stratified subgroup analyses across intervention durations; (4) The exclusive focus on muscular outcomes overlooks critical geriatric health parameters including bone mineral density and articular function—a significant oversight given the clinical imperative of bone-muscle crosstalk in fall/fracture prevention; (5) While phosphocreatine energy metabolism and mTOR pathway activation were proposed as mechanistic frameworks, the absence of direct molecular evidence (e.g., muscle biopsy proteomics or phosphorylation assays) limits causal interpretation. Subsequent validation requires multicenter cohorts with sex-stratified designs, multimodal assessments (dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry, gait analysis), and mechanistic studies elucidating creatine-resistance training synergism within the bone-muscle unit.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec22"><title>Conclusions</title><p id="Par64">This meta-analysis demonstrates that creatine supplementation Cr + RT produces statistically significant improvements in lower limb muscle strength and lean tissue mass among older adults, while exhibiting no clinically meaningful effects on upper limb strength outcomes. The identification of a 32-week temporal efficacy threshold for muscular adaptations underscores the importance of intervention duration in optimizing therapeutic benefits. However, methodological limitations (restricted sample size, attrition bias, and absence of sex-stratified analyses) observed across included trials constrain the generalizability of these findings and highlight potential overestimations of intervention efficacy. To address these gaps, future investigations should prioritize large-scale longitudinal studies incorporating sex-specific physiological profiling, multimodal geriatric health assessments, and mechanistic studies elucidating the molecular pathophysiology of Cr + RT interactions. Such efforts will enable the development of precision nutrition and exercise protocols tailored to the heterogeneous needs of aging populations, ultimately bridging the translational divide between musculoskeletal research and clinical geriatric practice.</p></sec><sec id="Sec23" sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="11556_2025_392_MOESM1_ESM.docx" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file 1: Retrieval strategy.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="11556_2025_392_MOESM2_ESM.zip" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file 2: Robust variance estimation.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></body><back><glossary><title>Abbreviations</title><def-list><def-item><term>RT</term><def><p id="Par6">Resistance training</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>Cr</term><def><p id="Par7">Creatine</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>RCTs</term><def><p id="Par8">Randomized controlled trials</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>PL</term><def><p id="Par9">Placebo</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>EWGSOP</term><def><p id="Par10">European working group on sarcopenia</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>WHO</term><def><p id="Par11">World health organization</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>DEXA</term><def><p id="Par12">Dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>1RM</term><def><p id="Par13">One-repetition maximum</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>GRADE</term><def><p id="Par14">Grading of recommendations, assessment, development, and evaluations</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>ITT</term><def><p id="Par15">Intention-to-treat</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>SD</term><def><p id="Par16">Standard deviation</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>SMD</term><def><p id="Par17">Standardized mean differences</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>RVE</term><def><p id="Par18">Robust variance estimation</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>HVRT</term><def><p id="Par19">High-velocity resistance training</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>TRT</term><def><p id="Par20">Traditional resistance training</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>CRT</term><def><p id="Par21">Creatine transporter</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>mTOR</term><def><p id="Par22">Mammalian target of rapamycin</p></def></def-item></def-list></glossary><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher’s Note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>Not applicable.</p><sec id="FPar1"><title>Clinical trial number</title><p id="Par65">Not applicable. This is a systematic review and does not involve direct data collection from human participants.</p></sec></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Authors’ contributions</title><p>Conceptualization, S.C.L., N.H., X.Y.Y.O., M.Y.W. and L.X.; methodology, S.C.L. and N.H.; software, S.C.L., N.H., W.J.W.; validation, S.C.L., Y.L. and Y.B.Z.; formal analysis, S.C.L., N.H. and X.Y.Y.O.; writing - original draft preparation, S.C.L., N.H., X.Y.Y.O., Y.L., Y.B.Z., M.Y.W. and L.X.; writing- review and editing, S.C.L., N.H., W.J.W., X.Y.Y.O., Y.L., Y.B.Z., M.Y.W. and L.X. All authors have read and agreed to the published version of the manuscript.</p></notes><notes notes-type="funding-information"><title>Funding</title><p>This work was supported by the [Major Project Of Ganzhou Science And Technology Bureau] under Grant [number 2023LNS37155] and [The Postgraduate Innovation Special Fund Project Of Gannan Medical University] under Grant [number YC2024⁃X014].</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>No datasets were generated or analysed during the current study.</p></notes><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar2"><title>Ethics approval and consent to participate</title><p id="Par66"> Not applicable. This meta-review did not require institutional review board approval because it synthesized existing published aggregate data.</p></notes><notes id="FPar3"><title>Consent for publication</title><p id="Par67">This meta-review did not contain any individual person’s data.</p></notes><notes id="FPar4" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par68">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR1" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cruz-Jentoft</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bahat</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bauer</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Boirie</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bruyère</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cederholm</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis</article-title><source>Age Ageing</source><year>2019</year><volume>48</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>16</fpage><lpage>31</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/ageing/afy169</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30312372</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6322506</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR1" publication-type="journal">Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, Boirie Y, Bruyère O, Cederholm T, et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2019;48(1):16–31.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30312372</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/ageing/afy169</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6322506</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR2" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Janssen</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shepard</surname><given-names>DS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Katzmarzyk</surname><given-names>PT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Roubenoff</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The healthcare costs of sarcopenia in the United States</article-title><source>J Am Geriatr Soc</source><year>2004</year><volume>52</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>80</fpage><lpage>5</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2004.52014.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14687319</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR2" publication-type="journal">Janssen I, Shepard DS, Katzmarzyk PT, Roubenoff R. The healthcare costs of sarcopenia in the United States. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2004;52(1):80–5.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14687319</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2004.52014.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR3" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Keller</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Engelhardt</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Strength and muscle mass loss with aging process. Age and strength loss</article-title><source>Muscles Ligaments Tendons J</source><year>2013</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>346</fpage><lpage>50</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.32098/mltj.04.2013.17</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24596700</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3940510</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR3" publication-type="journal">Keller K, Engelhardt M. Strength and muscle mass loss with aging process. Age and strength loss. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 2013;3:346–50.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24596700</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3940510</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">World Health Organization. Decade of healthy ageing: baseline report. Geneva: World Health Organization. Licence: CC BY-NC-SA 3.0 IGO. 2022. </mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR5" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Santos</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ribeiro</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schoenfeld</surname><given-names>BJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nascimento</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tomeleri</surname><given-names>CM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Souza</surname><given-names>MF</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The improvement in walking speed induced by resistance training is associated with increased muscular strength but not skeletal muscle mass in older women</article-title><source>Eur J Sport Sci</source><year>2017</year><volume>17</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>488</fpage><lpage>94</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/17461391.2016.1273394</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28068193</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR5" publication-type="journal">Santos L, Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, Nascimento MA, Tomeleri CM, Souza MF, et al. The improvement in walking speed induced by resistance training is associated with increased muscular strength but not skeletal muscle mass in older women. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17(4):488–94.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28068193</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/17461391.2016.1273394</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR6" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Volpi</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nazemi</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fujita</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Muscle tissue changes with aging</article-title><source>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care</source><year>2004</year><volume>7</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>405</fpage><lpage>10</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15192443</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/01.mco.0000134362.76653.b2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2804956</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR6" publication-type="journal">Volpi E, Nazemi R, Fujita S. Muscle tissue changes with aging. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2004;7(4):405–10.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15192443</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/01.mco.0000134362.76653.b2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2804956</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR7" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chilibeck</surname><given-names>PD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaviani</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zello</surname><given-names>GA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effect of creatine supplementation during resistance training on lean tissue mass and muscular strength in older adults: a meta-analysis</article-title><source>Open Access J Sports Med</source><year>2017</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>213</fpage><lpage>26</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2147/OAJSM.S123529</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29138605</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5679696</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR7" publication-type="journal">Chilibeck PD, Kaviani M, Candow DG, Zello GA. Effect of creatine supplementation during resistance training on lean tissue mass and muscular strength in older adults: a meta-analysis. Open Access J Sports Med. 2017;8:213–26.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29138605</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2147/OAJSM.S123529</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5679696</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR8" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kreider</surname><given-names>RB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kalman</surname><given-names>DS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Antonio</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ziegenfuss</surname><given-names>TN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wildman</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>International society of sports nutrition position stand: safety and efficacy of creatine supplementation in exercise, sport, and medicine</article-title><source>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</source><year>2017</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>18</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12970-017-0173-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28615996</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5469049</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR8" publication-type="journal">Kreider RB, Kalman DS, Antonio J, Ziegenfuss TN, Wildman R, Collins R, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: safety and efficacy of creatine supplementation in exercise, sport, and medicine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14:18.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28615996</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12970-017-0173-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5469049</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR9" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chilibeck</surname><given-names>PD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Forbes</surname><given-names>SC</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Creatine supplementation and aging musculoskeletal health</article-title><source>Endocrine</source><year>2014</year><volume>45</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>354</fpage><lpage>61</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12020-013-0070-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24190049</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR9" publication-type="journal">Candow DG, Chilibeck PD, Forbes SC. Creatine supplementation and aging musculoskeletal health. Endocrine. 2014;45(3):354–61.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24190049</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s12020-013-0070-4</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR10" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Forbes</surname><given-names>SC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Neto</surname><given-names>JHF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kennedy</surname><given-names>MD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Forbes</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Machado</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Creatine supplementation and endurance performance: surges and sprints to win the race</article-title><source>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</source><year>2023</year><volume>20</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>2204071</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/15502783.2023.2204071</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37096381</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10132248</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR10" publication-type="journal">Forbes SC, Candow DG, Neto JHF, Kennedy MD, Forbes JL, Machado M, et al. Creatine supplementation and endurance performance: surges and sprints to win the race. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2023;20(1):2204071.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37096381</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/15502783.2023.2204071</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10132248</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR11" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Desai</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wewege</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>MD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Clifford</surname><given-names>BK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pandit</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaakoush</surname><given-names>NO</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Simar</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hagstrom</surname><given-names>AD</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The effect of creatine supplementation on resistance training-based changes to body composition: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>J Strength Cond Res</source><year>2024</year><volume>38</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>1813</fpage><lpage>21</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004862</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39074168</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR11" publication-type="journal">Desai I, Wewege MA, Jones MD, Clifford BK, Pandit A, Kaakoush NO, et al. The effect of creatine supplementation on resistance training-based changes to body composition: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38(10):1813–21.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39074168</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004862</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR12" publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Delpino</surname><given-names>FM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Figueiredo</surname><given-names>LM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Forbes</surname><given-names>SC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Santos</surname><given-names>HO</given-names></name></person-group><source>Influence of age, sex, and type of exercise on the efficacy of creatine supplementation on lean body mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials</source><year>2022</year><publisher-loc>Calif.)</publisher-loc><publisher-name>Nutrition (Burbank, Los Angeles County</publisher-name><fpage>103</fpage><lpage>4</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.nut.2022.111791</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35986981</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR12" publication-type="book">Delpino FM, Figueiredo LM, Forbes SC, Candow DG, Santos HO. Influence of age, sex, and type of exercise on the efficacy of creatine supplementation on lean body mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Calif.): Nutrition (Burbank, Los Angeles County; 2022. pp. 103–4.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.nut.2022.111791</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35986981</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR13" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Deng</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>He</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>He</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Correction: Effects of different dietary supplements combined with conditioning training on muscle strength, jump performance, sprint speed, and muscle mass in athletes: a systematic review and network meta-analysis</article-title><source>Front Nutr</source><year>2025</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>1670394</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fnut.2025.1670394</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40717998</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12295849</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR13" publication-type="journal">Deng B, Yan R, He T, Lin G, Liu T, Chen W, et al. Correction: Effects of different dietary supplements combined with conditioning training on muscle strength, jump performance, sprint speed, and muscle mass in athletes: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Front Nutr. 2025;12:1670394.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40837437</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fnut.2025.1670394</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12361864</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR14" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ye</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Long</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhong</surname><given-names>YB</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Do dietary supplements prevent loss of muscle mass and strength during muscle disuse? A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials</article-title><source>Front Nutr</source><year>2023</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>1093988</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fnut.2023.1093988</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37252241</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10210142</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR14" publication-type="journal">Ye H, Yang JM, Luo Y, Long Y, Zhang JH, Zhong YB, et al. Do dietary supplements prevent loss of muscle mass and strength during muscle disuse? A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Front Nutr. 2023;10:1093988.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37252241</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fnut.2023.1093988</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10210142</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR15" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Finger</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Goltz</surname><given-names>FR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Umpierre</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Meyer</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rosa</surname><given-names>LH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schneider</surname><given-names>CD</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effects of protein supplementation in older adults undergoing resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>Sports Med</source><year>2015</year><volume>45</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>245</fpage><lpage>55</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0269-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25355074</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR15" publication-type="journal">Finger D, Goltz FR, Umpierre D, Meyer E, Rosa LH, Schneider CD. Effects of protein supplementation in older adults undergoing resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2015;45(2):245–55.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25355074</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s40279-014-0269-4</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Wang Z, Qiu B, Li R, et al. Effects of Creatine Supplementation and Resistance Training on Muscle Strength Gains in Adults &lt;50 Years of Age: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Nutrients. 2024;16(21):3665. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/nu16213665</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11547435</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39519498</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR17" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Devries</surname><given-names>MC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Creatine supplementation during resistance training in older adults-a meta-analysis</article-title><source>Med Sci Sports Exerc</source><year>2014</year><volume>46</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>1194</fpage><lpage>203</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000220</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24576864</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR17" publication-type="journal">Devries MC, Phillips SM. Creatine supplementation during resistance training in older adults-a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46(6):1194–203.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24576864</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000220</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA, editors. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions version 6.5 (updated August 2024). Cochrane, 2024. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.cochrane.org/handbook">http://www.cochrane.org/handbook</ext-link></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR19" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Moher</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shamseer</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Clarke</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ghersi</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liberati</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Petticrew</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shekelle</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Stewart</surname><given-names>LA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015 statement</article-title><source>Syst Rev</source><year>2015</year><volume>4</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>1</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/2046-4053-4-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25554246</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4320440</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR19" publication-type="journal">Moher D, Shamseer L, Clarke M, Ghersi D, Liberati A, Petticrew M, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015 statement. Syst Rev. 2015;4(1):1.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25554246</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/2046-4053-4-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4320440</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR20" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Forbes</surname><given-names>SC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chilibeck</surname><given-names>PD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cornish</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Antonio</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kreider</surname><given-names>RB</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effectiveness of creatine supplementation on aging muscle and bone: focus on falls prevention and inflammation</article-title><source>J Clin Med</source><year>2019</year><volume>8</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>488</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/jcm8040488</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30978926</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6518405</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR20" publication-type="journal">Candow DG, Forbes SC, Chilibeck PD, Cornish SM, Antonio J, Kreider RB. Effectiveness of creatine supplementation on aging muscle and bone: focus on falls prevention and inflammation. J Clin Med. 2019;8(4):488.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30978926</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/jcm8040488</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6518405</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR21" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Altman</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gøtzsche</surname><given-names>PC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jüni</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moher</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Oxman</surname><given-names>AD</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The Cochrane collaboration’s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials</article-title><source>BMJ</source><year>2011</year><volume>343</volume><fpage>d5928</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmj.d5928</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22008217</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3196245</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR21" publication-type="journal">Higgins JP, Altman DG, Gøtzsche PC, Jüni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, et al. The Cochrane collaboration’s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d5928.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22008217</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bmj.d5928</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3196245</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR22" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Guyatt</surname><given-names>GH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Oxman</surname><given-names>AD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vist</surname><given-names>GE</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Grade: an emerging consensus on rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations</article-title><source>BMJ</source><year>2008</year><volume>336</volume><issue>7650</issue><fpage>924</fpage><lpage>6</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmj.39489.470347.AD</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18436948</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2335261</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR22" publication-type="journal">Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Vist GE, et al. Grade: an emerging consensus on rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ. 2008;336(7650):924–6.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18436948</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bmj.39489.470347.AD</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2335261</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR23" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Maher</surname><given-names>CG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sherrington</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Herbert</surname><given-names>RD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moseley</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Elkins</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Reliability of the PEDro scale for rating quality of randomized controlled trials</article-title><source>Phys Ther</source><year>2003</year><volume>83</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>713</fpage><lpage>21</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/ptj/83.8.713</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12882612</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR23" publication-type="journal">Maher CG, Sherrington C, Herbert RD, Moseley AM, Elkins M. Reliability of the PEDro scale for rating quality of randomized controlled trials. Phys Ther. 2003;83(8):713–21.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12882612</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR24" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cashin</surname><given-names>AG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>McAuley</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Clinimetrics: physiotherapy evidence database (PEDro) scale</article-title><source>J Physiother</source><year>2020</year><volume>66</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>59</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jphys.2019.08.005</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31521549</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR24" publication-type="journal">Cashin AG, McAuley JH. Clinimetrics: physiotherapy evidence database (PEDro) scale. J Physiother. 2020;66(1):59.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31521549</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jphys.2019.08.005</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR25" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cumpston</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Page</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chandler</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Welch</surname><given-names>VA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Updated guidance for trusted systematic reviews: a new edition of the Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions</article-title><source>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</source><year>2019</year><volume>10</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>Ed000142</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31643080</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/14651858.ED000142</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10284251</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR25" publication-type="journal">Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Chandler J, Welch VA, Higgins JP, et al. Updated guidance for trusted systematic reviews: a new edition of the Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;10(10):Ed000142.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31643080</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/14651858.ED000142</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10284251</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR26" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Burke</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Piñero</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Coleman</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mohan</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sapuppo</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Augustin</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Aragon</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Forbes</surname><given-names>SC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Swinton</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schoenfeld</surname><given-names>BJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The effects of creatine supplementation combined with resistance training on regional measures of muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review with meta-analysis</article-title><source>Nutrients</source><year>2023</year><volume>15</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>2116</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/nu15092116</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37432300</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10180745</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR26" publication-type="journal">Burke R, Piñero A, Coleman M, Mohan A, Sapuppo M, Augustin F, et al. The effects of creatine supplementation combined with resistance training on regional measures of muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Nutrients. 2023;15(9):2116.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37432300</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/nu15092116</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10180745</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR27" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>SG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Deeks</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Altman</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses</article-title><source>BMJ</source><year>2003</year><volume>327</volume><issue>7414</issue><fpage>557</fpage><lpage>60</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmj.327.7414.557</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12958120</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC192859</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR27" publication-type="journal">Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327(7414):557–60.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12958120</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bmj.327.7414.557</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC192859</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Hopkins WG. A scale of magnitudes for effect statistics. Sportsci.org; 2002. Available from: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.sportsci.org/resource/stats/effectmag.html">http://www.sportsci.org/resource/stats/effectmag.html</ext-link>. Cited 2025 Sep 8.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR29" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bernat</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gryzb</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Butchart</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schoenfeld</surname><given-names>BJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bruno</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effects of high-velocity resistance training and creatine supplementation in untrained healthy aging males</article-title><source>Appl Physiol Nutr Metab</source><year>2019</year><volume>44</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>1246</fpage><lpage>53</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1139/apnm-2019-0066</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30958973</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR29" publication-type="journal">Bernat P, Candow DG, Gryzb K, Butchart S, Schoenfeld BJ, Bruno P. Effects of high-velocity resistance training and creatine supplementation in untrained healthy aging males. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2019;44(11):1246–53.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30958973</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1139/apnm-2019-0066</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR30" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Amiri</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sheikholeslami-Vatani</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The role of resistance training and creatine supplementation on oxidative stress, antioxidant defense, muscle strength, and quality of life in older adults</article-title><source>Front Public Health</source><year>2023</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>1062832</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2023.1062832</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37206869</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10189876</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR30" publication-type="journal">Amiri E, Sheikholeslami-Vatani D. The role of resistance training and creatine supplementation on oxidative stress, antioxidant defense, muscle strength, and quality of life in older adults. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1062832.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37206869</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fpubh.2023.1062832</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10189876</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR31" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vogt</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Johannsmeyer</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Forbes</surname><given-names>SC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Farthing</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Strategic creatine supplementation and resistance training in healthy older adults</article-title><source>Appl Physiol Nutr Metab</source><year>2015</year><volume>40</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>689</fpage><lpage>94</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1139/apnm-2014-0498</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25993883</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR31" publication-type="journal">Candow DG, Vogt E, Johannsmeyer S, Forbes SC, Farthing JP. Strategic creatine supplementation and resistance training in healthy older adults. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2015;40(7):689–94.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25993883</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1139/apnm-2014-0498</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR32" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chilibeck</surname><given-names>PD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Landeryou</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaviani</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Paus-Jenssen</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effects of creatine and resistance training on bone health in postmenopausal women</article-title><source>Med Sci Sports Exerc</source><year>2015</year><volume>47</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>1587</fpage><lpage>95</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000571</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25386713</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR32" publication-type="journal">Chilibeck PD, Candow DG, Landeryou T, Kaviani M, Paus-Jenssen L. Effects of creatine and resistance training on bone health in postmenopausal women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47(8):1587–95.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25386713</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000571</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR33" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chilibeck</surname><given-names>PD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gordon</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Duff</surname><given-names>WRD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mason</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shaw</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A 2-yr randomized controlled trial on creatine supplementation during exercise for postmenopausal bone health</article-title><source>Med Sci Sports Exerc</source><year>2023</year><volume>55</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>1750</fpage><lpage>60</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003202</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37144634</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10487398</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR33" publication-type="journal">Chilibeck PD, Candow DG, Gordon JJ, Duff WRD, Mason R, Shaw K, et al. A 2-yr randomized controlled trial on creatine supplementation during exercise for postmenopausal bone health. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2023;55(10):1750–60.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37144634</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003202</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10487398</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR34" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Johannsmeyer</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Brahms</surname><given-names>CM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Michel</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zello</surname><given-names>GA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effect of creatine supplementation and drop-set resistance training in untrained aging adults</article-title><source>Exp Gerontol</source><year>2016</year><volume>83</volume><fpage>112</fpage><lpage>9</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2016.08.005</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27523919</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR34" publication-type="journal">Johannsmeyer S, Candow DG, Brahms CM, Michel D, Zello GA. Effect of creatine supplementation and drop-set resistance training in untrained aging adults. Exp Gerontol. 2016;83:112–9.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27523919</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.exger.2016.08.005</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR35" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chilibeck</surname><given-names>PD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gordon</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vogt</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Landeryou</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaviani</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Effect of 12 months of creatine supplementation and whole-body resistance training on measures of bone, muscle and strength in older males</article-title><source>Nutr Health</source><year>2021</year><volume>27</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>151</fpage><lpage>9</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/0260106020975247</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33234019</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR35" publication-type="journal">Candow DG, Chilibeck PD, Gordon J, Vogt E, Landeryou T, Kaviani M, et al. Effect of 12 months of creatine supplementation and whole-body resistance training on measures of bone, muscle and strength in older males. Nutr Health. 2021;27(2):151–9.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33234019</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/0260106020975247</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR36" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pinto</surname><given-names>CL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Botelho</surname><given-names>PB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carneiro</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mota</surname><given-names>JF</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Impact of creatine supplementation in combination with resistance training on lean mass in the elderly</article-title><source>J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle</source><year>2016</year><volume>7</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>413</fpage><lpage>21</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/jcsm.12094</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27239423</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4864174</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR36" publication-type="journal">Pinto CL, Botelho PB, Carneiro JA, Mota JF. Impact of creatine supplementation in combination with resistance training on lean mass in the elderly. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2016;7(4):413–21.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27239423</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/jcsm.12094</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4864174</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR37" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sterne</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sutton</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ioannidis</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Terrin</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>DR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lau</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Recommendations for examining and interpreting funnel plot asymmetry in meta-analyses of randomised controlled trials</article-title><source>BMJ</source><year>2011</year><volume>343</volume><fpage>d4002</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmj.d4002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21784880</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR37" publication-type="journal">Sterne JA, Sutton AJ, Ioannidis JP, Terrin N, Jones DR, Lau J, et al. Recommendations for examining and interpreting funnel plot asymmetry in meta-analyses of randomised controlled trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d4002.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21784880</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bmj.d4002</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR38"><label>38.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Dos Santos EEP, de Araújo RC, Candow DG, et al. Efficacy of Creatine Supplementation Combined with Resistance Training on Muscle Strength and Muscle Mass in Older Females: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Nutrients. 2021;13(11):3757.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/nu13113757</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8619193</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34836013</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR39"><label>39.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR39" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Dolan</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Artioli</surname><given-names>GG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pereira</surname><given-names>RMR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gualano</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Muscular atrophy and sarcopenia in the elderly: is there a role for creatine supplementation?</article-title><source>Biomolecules</source><year>2019</year><volume>9</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>642</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/biom9110642</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31652853</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6921011</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR39" publication-type="journal">Dolan E, Artioli GG, Pereira RMR, Gualano B. Muscular atrophy and sarcopenia in the elderly: is there a role for creatine supplementation? Biomolecules. 2019;9(11):642.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31652853</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/biom9110642</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6921011</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR40"><label>40.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR40" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kreider</surname><given-names>RB</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effects of creatine supplementation on performance and training adaptations</article-title><source>Mol Cell Biochem</source><year>2003</year><volume>244</volume><issue>1–2</issue><fpage>89</fpage><lpage>94</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1023/A:1022465203458</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12701815</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR40" publication-type="journal">Kreider RB. Effects of creatine supplementation on performance and training adaptations. Mol Cell Biochem. 2003;244(1–2):89–94.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12701815</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR41"><label>41.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR41" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Devries</surname><given-names>MC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Supplemental protein in support of muscle mass and health: advantage whey</article-title><source>J Food Sci</source><year>2015</year><volume>80</volume><issue>Suppl 1</issue><fpage>A8</fpage><lpage>15</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25757896</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/1750-3841.12802</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR41" publication-type="journal">Devries MC, Phillips SM. Supplemental protein in support of muscle mass and health: advantage whey. J Food Sci. 2015;80(Suppl 1):A8-15.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25757896</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/1750-3841.12802</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR42"><label>42.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR42" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Conley</surname><given-names>KE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jubrias</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Esselman</surname><given-names>PC</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Oxidative capacity and ageing in human muscle</article-title><source>J Physiol</source><year>2000</year><volume>526</volume><issue>Pt 1</issue><fpage>203</fpage><lpage>10</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7793.2000.t01-1-00203.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10878112</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2269983</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR42" publication-type="journal">Conley KE, Jubrias SA, Esselman PC. Oxidative capacity and ageing in human muscle. J Physiol. 2000;526(Pt 1):203–10.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10878112</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1469-7793.2000.t01-1-00203.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2269983</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR43"><label>43.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR43" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chilibeck</surname><given-names>PD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Stride</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Farthing</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Burke</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effect of creatine ingestion after exercise on muscle thickness in males and females</article-title><source>Med Sci Sports Exerc</source><year>2004</year><volume>36</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>1781</fpage><lpage>8</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000142301.70419.C6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15595301</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR43" publication-type="journal">Chilibeck PD, Stride D, Farthing JP, Burke DG. Effect of creatine ingestion after exercise on muscle thickness in males and females. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(10):1781–8.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15595301</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1249/01.mss.0000142301.70419.c6</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR44"><label>44.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR44" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hespel</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Op’t Eijnde</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Van Leemputte</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ursø</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Greenhaff</surname><given-names>PL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Labarque</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Oral creatine supplementation facilitates the rehabilitation of disuse atrophy and alters the expression of muscle myogenic factors in humans</article-title><source>J Physiol</source><year>2001</year><volume>536</volume><issue>Pt 2</issue><fpage>625</fpage><lpage>33</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.0625c.xd</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11600695</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2278864</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR44" publication-type="journal">Hespel P, Op’t Eijnde B, Van Leemputte M, Ursø B, Greenhaff PL, Labarque V, et al. Oral creatine supplementation facilitates the rehabilitation of disuse atrophy and alters the expression of muscle myogenic factors in humans. J Physiol. 2001;536(Pt 2):625–33.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11600695</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.0625c.xd</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2278864</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR45"><label>45.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR45" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Deldicque</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Theisen</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bertrand</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hespel</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hue</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Francaux</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Creatine enhances differentiation of myogenic C2C12 cells by activating both p38 and Akt/PKB pathways</article-title><source>Am J Physiol Cell Physiol</source><year>2007</year><volume>293</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>C1263</fpage><lpage>71</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00162.2007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17652429</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR45" publication-type="journal">Deldicque L, Theisen D, Bertrand L, Hespel P, Hue L, Francaux M. Creatine enhances differentiation of myogenic C2C12 cells by activating both p38 and Akt/PKB pathways. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2007;293(4):C1263–71.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17652429</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1152/ajpcell.00162.2007</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR46"><label>46.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR46" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Little</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chilibeck</surname><given-names>PD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Abeysekara</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zello</surname><given-names>GA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kazachkov</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Low-dose creatine combined with protein during resistance training in older men</article-title><source>Med Sci Sports Exerc</source><year>2008</year><volume>40</volume><issue>9</issue><fpage>1645</fpage><lpage>52</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318176b310</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18685526</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR46" publication-type="journal">Candow DG, Little JP, Chilibeck PD, Abeysekara S, Zello GA, Kazachkov M, et al. Low-dose creatine combined with protein during resistance training in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40(9):1645–52.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18685526</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318176b310</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR47"><label>47.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR47" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schjerling</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Saltin</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Muscle, genes and athletic performance</article-title><source>Sci Am</source><year>2000</year><volume>283</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>48</fpage><lpage>55</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/scientificamerican0900-48</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10976466</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR47" publication-type="journal">Andersen JL, Schjerling P, Saltin B. Muscle, genes and athletic performance. Sci Am. 2000;283(3):48–55.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10976466</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/scientificamerican0900-48</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR48"><label>48.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR48" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Dolan</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gualano</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rawson</surname><given-names>ES</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Beyond muscle: the effects of creatine supplementation on brain creatine, cognitive processing, and traumatic brain injury</article-title><source>Eur J Sport Sci</source><year>2019</year><volume>19</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>14</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/17461391.2018.1500644</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30086660</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR48" publication-type="journal">Dolan E, Gualano B, Rawson ES. Beyond muscle: the effects of creatine supplementation on brain creatine, cognitive processing, and traumatic brain injury. Eur J Sport Sci. 2019;19(1):1–14.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30086660</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/17461391.2018.1500644</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR49"><label>49.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR49" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Fielding</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Guralnik</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>King</surname><given-names>AC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pahor</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>McDermott</surname><given-names>MM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tudor-Locke</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Dose of physical activity, physical functioning and disability risk in mobility-limited older adults: results from the LIFE study randomized trial</article-title><source>PLoS One</source><year>2017</year><volume>12</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>e0182155</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0182155</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28820909</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5562326</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR49" publication-type="journal">Fielding RA, Guralnik JM, King AC, Pahor M, McDermott MM, Tudor-Locke C, et al. Dose of physical activity, physical functioning and disability risk in mobility-limited older adults: results from the LIFE study randomized trial. PLoS One. 2017;12(8):e0182155.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28820909</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1371/journal.pone.0182155</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5562326</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR50"><label>50.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR50" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chilibeck</surname><given-names>PD</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Differences in size, strength, and power of upper and lower body muscle groups in young and older men</article-title><source>J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci</source><year>2005</year><volume>60</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>148</fpage><lpage>56</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/gerona/60.2.148</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15814855</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR50" publication-type="journal">Candow DG, Chilibeck PD. Differences in size, strength, and power of upper and lower body muscle groups in young and older men. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2005;60(2):148–56.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15814855</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/gerona/60.2.148</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR51"><label>51.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR51" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rava</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pihlak</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ereline</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gapeyeva</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kums</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Purge</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Body composition, neuromuscular performance, and mobility: comparison between regularly exercising and inactive older women</article-title><source>J Aging Phys Act</source><year>2017</year><volume>25</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>58</fpage><lpage>64</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27281489</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1123/japa.2016-0019</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR51" publication-type="journal">Rava A, Pihlak A, Ereline J, Gapeyeva H, Kums T, Purge P, et al. Body composition, neuromuscular performance, and mobility: comparison between regularly exercising and inactive older women. J Aging Phys Act. 2017;25(1):58–64.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27281489</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1123/japa.2016-0019</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR52"><label>52.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR52" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Seguin</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nelson</surname><given-names>ME</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The benefits of strength training for older adults</article-title><source>Am J Prev Med</source><year>2003</year><volume>25</volume><issue>3 Suppl 2</issue><fpage>141</fpage><lpage>9</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0749-3797(03)00177-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14552938</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR52" publication-type="journal">Seguin R, Nelson ME. The benefits of strength training for older adults. Am J Prev Med. 2003;25(3 Suppl 2):141–9.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14552938</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/s0749-3797(03)00177-6</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>