<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">31989592</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2362</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>50</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of clinical investigation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Clin Invest</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exercise training improves sleep quality: A randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e13202</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e13202</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/eci.13202</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Exercise holds promise as a non-pharmacological intervention for the improvement of sleep quality. Therefore, this study investigates the effects of different training modalities on sleep quality parameters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIAL &amp; METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 69 (52.7% women) middle-aged sedentary adults were randomized to (a) control group, (b) physical activity recommendation from the World Health Organization, (c) high-intensity interval training (HIIT) and (d) high-intensity interval training group adding whole-body electromyostimulation training (HIITEMS). Sleep quality was assessed using the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI) scale and accelerometers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">All intervention groups showed a lower PSQI global score (all P &lt; .022). HIIT-EMS group improved all accelerometer parameters, with higher total sleep time and sleep efficiency, and lower wake after sleep onset (all P &lt; .016). No differences were found between groups in any sleep quality parameter.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In conclusion, exercise training induced an improvement in subjective sleep quality in sedentary middleaged adults. Moreover, HIIT-EMS training showed an improvement in objective sleep quality parameters (total sleep time, sleep efficiency and wake after sleep onset) after 12 weeks of exercise intervention. The changes observed in the HIIT-EMS group were not statistically different to the other exercise modalities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Stichting European Society for Clinical Investigation Journal Foundation.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jurado-Fasoli</LastName><ForeName>Lucas</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5254-1816</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departament of Medical Physiology, School of Medicine, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PROmoting FITness and Health through Physical Activity Research Group (PROFITH), Department of Physical Education and Sports, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De-la-O</LastName><ForeName>Alejandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departament of Medical Physiology, School of Medicine, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Molina-Hidalgo</LastName><ForeName>Cristina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departament of Medical Physiology, School of Medicine, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Migueles</LastName><ForeName>Jairo H</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PROmoting FITness and Health through Physical Activity Research Group (PROFITH), Department of Physical Education and Sports, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castillo</LastName><ForeName>Manuel J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departament of Medical Physiology, School of Medicine, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amaro-Gahete</LastName><ForeName>Francisco J</ForeName><Initials>FJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departament of Medical Physiology, School of Medicine, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PROmoting FITness and Health through Physical Activity Research Group (PROFITH), Department of Physical Education and Sports, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>FPU14/04172</GrantID><Agency>Spanish Ministry of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>FPU15/03960</GrantID><Agency>Spanish Ministry of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>University of Granada</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Clin Invest</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0245331</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0014-2972</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concurrent training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high-intensity interval training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep quality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep quantity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">whole-body electromyostimulation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31989592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/eci.13202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Crowley K. Sleep and sleep disorders in older adults. Neuropsychol Rev. 2011;21(1):41-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stranges S, Tigbe W, Thorogood M, et al. Sleep problems: an emerging global epidemic? Findings from the INDEPTH WHO-SAGE study among more than 40,000 older adults from 8 countries across Africa and Asia. Sleep. 2012;35(8):1173-1181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang P, Ho K, Chen H, Chien M. Exercise training improves sleep quality in middle-aged and older adults with sleep problems: a systematic review. J Physiother. 2012;58(3):157-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovacevic A, Mavros Y, Heisz JJ, Fiatarone Singh MA. The effect of resistance exercise on sleep: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Sleep Med Rev. 2018;39:52-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lie JD, Tu KN, Shen DD, Candidate P, Wong BM, Candidate P. Pharmacological treatment of insomnia. Pharm Ther. 2015;40(11):759-769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abad VC, Guilleminault C. Diagnosis and treatment of sleep disorders: a brief review for clinicians. Dialogues Clin Neurosci. 2003;5(4):371-388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikic A, Pietrolungo CE. Effects of diet on sleep quality. Adv Nutr. 2016;7(5):938-949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kline CE. The bidirectional relationship between exercise and sleep: implications for exercise adherence and sleep improvement. Am J Lifestyle Med. 2014;8(6):375-379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolezal BA, Neufeld EV, Boland DM, Martin JL, Cooper CB. Interrelationship between sleep and exercise: a systematic review. Adv Prev Med. 2017;2017:1364387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passos GS, Poyares D, Santana MG, Tufik S. Effect of acute physical exercise on patients with chronic primary insomnia. J Clin Sleep Med. 2010;6(3):270-275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaro-Gahete FJ, De-la-O A, Jurado-Fasoli L, et al. Exercise training as S-Klotho protein stimulator in sedentary healthy adults: rationale, design, and methodology. Contemp Clin Trials Commun. 2018;11:10-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz KF, Altman DG, Moher D, et al. CONSORT 2010 statement: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. BMC Med. 2010;8(1):18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz K, Grimes D. Generation of allocation sequences in randomised trials: chance, not choice. Lancet. 2002;359(9305):515-519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slade SC, Dionne CE, Underwood M, Buchbinder R. Consensus on exercise reporting template (CERT): explanation and elaboration statement. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(23):1428-1437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simera I, Moher D, Hoey J, Schulz KF, Altman DG. A catalogue of reporting guidelines for health research. Eur J Clin Invest. 2010;40(1):35-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Global Recommendations on Physical Activity for Health. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organzation Publications; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Laursen PB. High-intensity interval training, solutions to the programming puzzle: part I: cardiopulmonary emphasis. Sport Med. 2013;43(5):313-338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh sleep quality index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989;28(2):193-213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migueles JH, Ulf CC, Nystro CD. Accelerometer data collection and processing criteria to assess physical activity and other outcomes: a systematic review and practical considerations. Sport Med. 2017;47(9):1821-1845.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hees VT, Gorzelniak L, Dean Le&#xf3;n EC, et al. Separating movement and gravity components in an acceleration signal and implications for the assessment of human daily physical activity. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(4):e61691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hees VT, Sabia S, Anderson KN, et al. Open access method to assess sleep duration using a Wrist-Worn accelerometer. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(11):e0142533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh A. The role and validity of actigraphy in sleep medicine: an update. Sleep Med Rev. 2011;15(4):259-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balke B, Ware R. An experimental study of physical fitness of Air Force personnel. US Armed Forces Med J. 1959;10(6):675-688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kredlow MA, Capozzoli MC, Hearon BA, Calkins AW, Otto MW. The effects of physical activity on sleep: a meta-analytic review. J Behav Med. 2015;38(3):427-449.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jubeau M, Sartorio A, Marinone PG, et al. Comparison between voluntary and stimulated contractions of the quadriceps femoris for growth hormone response and muscle damage. J Appl Physiol. 2007;104(1):75-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copinschi G, Nedeltcheva A, Leproult R, et al. Sleep disturbances, daytime sleepiness, and quality of life in adults with growth hormone deficiency. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2010;95(5):2195-2202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W, Weissenfels A, Willert S, et al. Efficacy and safety of low frequency Whole-Body Electromyostimulation (WB-EMS) to improve health-related outcomes in non-athletic adults. A systematic review. Front Physiol. 2018;9:573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchida S, Shioda K, Morita Y, Kubota C, Ganeko M, Takeda N. Exercise effects on sleep physiology. Front Neurol. 2012;3:1-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willand MP, Rosa E, Michalski B, et al. Electrical muscle stimulation elevates intramuscular BDNF and GDNF mRNA following peripheral nerve injury and repair in rats. Neuroscience. 2016;334:93-104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteiro BC, Monteiro S, Candida M, et al. Relationship between brain-derived neurotrofic factor (Bdnf) and sleep on depression: a critical review. Clin Pract Epidemiol Ment Heal. 2017;13(1):213-219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truong AD, Kho ME, Brower RG, Feldman DR, Colantuoni E, Needham DM. Effects of neuromuscular electrical stimulation on cytokines in peripheral blood for healthy participants: a prospective, single-blinded Study. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2017;37(3):255-262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krueger JM. The role of cytokines in sleep regulation. Curr Pharm Des. 2009;14(32):3409-3416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boerio D, Jubeau M, Zory R, Maffiuletti NA. Central and peripheral fatigue after electrostimulation-induced resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(6):973-978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallampalli MP, Carter CL. Exploring sex and gender differences in sleep health: a society for women's health research report. J Women's Heal. 2014;23(7):553-562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan V, Collop NA. Gender differences in sleep disorders. Curr Opin Pulm Med. 2006;12(6):383-389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheel AW. Sex differences in the physiology of exercise: an integrative perspective. Exp Physiol. 2016;101(2):211-212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bredella MA. Sex differences in body composition. In: Mauvais-Jarvis F, ed. Sex and Gender Factors Affecting Metabolic Homeostasis, Diabetes and Obesity. Cham: Springer International Publishing; 2017:9-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mallah MH, Juraschek SP, Whelton S, et al. Sex differences in cardiorespiratory fitness and all-cause mortality: the Henry ford exercise testing (FIT) project. Mayo Clin Proc. 2016;91(6):755-762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller AEJ, MacDougall JD, Tarnopolsky MA, Sale DG. Gender differences in strength and muscle fiber characteristics. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1993;66(3):254-262.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>