<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35291639</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>81</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Variations in Internal and External Training Load Measures and Neuromuscular Performance of Professional Soccer Players During a Preseason Training Period.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>149</StartPage><EndPage>162</EndPage><MedlinePgn>149-162</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/hukin-2022-0012</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We described the internal and external training loads (TLs) experienced by soccer players over a 4-week preseason, examined their effects on vertical jump (VJ) performance, and investigated the relationships between different TL variables. Eighteen professional soccer players performed 17 training sessions and 1 friendly-match (FM) over the preseason. The internal TL was obtained using the session-rating of perceived exertion method. The external TL variables collected were total and high-intensity distances, body-load, and high-metabolic power distance via the GPS system. VJ performance was assessed 13 times throughout the study. Moreover, total quality recovery and delayed onset muscle soreness were assessed before every training session as a measure of recovery status. Players were divided, using a median split analysis, into two groups, according to their VJ performance (i.e., "lower" and "higher" VJ). External TL variables displayed similar variations across training sessions and were significantly interrelated (r ranging from 0.48 to 0.88). In periods where higher internal TLs were detected, impaired recovery status was noticed. Notably, the higher VJ group exhibited decreased jump performance at post-test and higher internal and external TLs across the entire preseason (compared to the lower VJ group). From our results it is suggested that professional soccer players with higher VJ performance are potentially more susceptible to concurrent training effects.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 Lucas A. Pereira, Tom&#xe1;s T. Freitas, Vinicius Zanetti, Irineu Loturco, published by Sciendo.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pereira</LastName><ForeName>Lucas A</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NAR - Nucleus of High Performance in Sport, Sao Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Movement Sciences, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Freitas</LastName><ForeName>Tom&#xe1;s T</ForeName><Initials>TT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NAR - Nucleus of High Performance in Sport, Sao Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Movement Sciences, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCAM Research Center for High Performance Sport - Catholic University of Murcia, UCAM, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences, Catholic University of Murcia (UCAM), Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zanetti</LastName><ForeName>Vinicius</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Red Bull Brazil Football, Jarin&#xfa;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loturco</LastName><ForeName>Irineu</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NAR - Nucleus of High Performance in Sport, Sao Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Movement Sciences, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of South Wales, Pontypridd, Wales, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">football</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">monitoring systems</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle power</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">team-sports</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tracking systems</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35291639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8884880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2022-0012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">hukin-2022-0012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Barnes C., Archer D. T., Hogg B., Bush M.. Bradley P. S.. The evolution of physical and technical performance parameters in the English Premier League. International Journal of Sports Medicine. 2014;35(13):1095&#x2013;1100. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25009969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batterham A. M.. Hopkins W. G.. Making meaningful inferences about magnitudes. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance. 2006;1(1):50&#x2013;57. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19114737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourdon P. C., Cardinale M., Murray A., Gastin P., Kellmann M., Varley M. C., Gabbett T. J., Coutts A. J., Burgess D. J., Gregson W.. Cable N. T.. Monitoring Athlete Training Loads: Consensus Statement. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance. 2017;12(Suppl 2):S2161&#x2013;S2170. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28463642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M., Manouvrier C., Cassirame J.. Morin J. B.. Monitoring Locomotor Load in Soccer: Is Metabolic Power, Powerful? International Journal of Sports Medicine. 2015;36(14):1149&#x2013;1155. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26393813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bush M., Barnes C., Archer D. T., Hogg B.. Bradley P. S.. Evolution of match performance parameters for various playing positions in the English Premier League. Human Movement Sciences. 2015;39:1. &amp;. &#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25461429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casamichana D., Castellano J.. Castagna C.. Comparing the physical demands of friendly matches and small-sided games in semiprofessional soccer players. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2012;26(3):837&#x2013;843. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22310516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castagna C., Impellizzeri F. M., Chaouachi A.. Manzi V.. Preseason variations in aerobic fitness and performance in elite-standard soccer players: a team study. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2013;27(11):2959&#x2013;2965. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23442266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutts A. J., Reaburn P., Piva T. J.. Rowsell G. J.. Monitoring for overreaching in rugby league players. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2007;99(3):313&#x2013;324. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17219174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummins C., Orr R., O'connor H.. West C.. Global positioning systems (GPS) and microtechnology sensors in team sports: a systematic review. Sports Medicine. 2013;43(10):1025&#x2013;1042. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23812857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunniffe B., Proctor W., Baker J. S.. Davies B.. An evaluation of the physiological demands of elite rugby union using Global Positioning System tracking software. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2009;23(4):1195&#x2013;1203. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19528840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo D. H., Figueiredo D. H., Moreira A., Goncalves H. R.. Dourado A. C.. Dose-Response Relationship Between Internal Training Load and Changes in Performance During the Preseason in Youth Soccer Players. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2021;35(8):2294&#x2013;2301. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31008863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C., Florhaug J. A., Franklin J., Gottschall L., Hrovatin L. A., Parker S., Doleshal P.. Dodge C.. A new approach to monitoring exercise training. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2001;15(1):109&#x2013;115. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11708692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halouani J., Chtourou H., Gabbett T., Chaouachi A.. Chamari K.. Small-sided games in team sports training: a brief review. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2014;28(12):3594&#x2013;3618. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24918302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higham D. G., Pyne D. B., Anson J. M., Hopkins W. G.. Eddy A.. Comparison of activity profiles and physiological demands between international rugby sevens matches and training. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2016;30(5):1287&#x2013;1294. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27100167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill-Haas S. V., Dawson B., Impellizzeri F. M.. Coutts A. J.. Physiology of small-sided games training in football: a systematic review. Sports Medicine. 2011;41(3):199&#x2013;220. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21395363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins W. G., Marshall S. W., Batterham A. M.. Hanin J.. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2009;41(1):3&#x2013;13. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri F. M., Rampinini E., Coutts A. J., Sassi A.. Marcora S. M.. Use of RPE-based training load in soccer. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2004;36(6):1042&#x2013;1047. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15179175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kentta G.. Hassmen P.. Overtraining and recovery. A conceptual model. Sports Med. 1998;26(1):1&#x2013;16. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9739537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco I., Pereira L. A., Freitas T. T., Alcaraz P. E., Zanetti V., Bishop C.. Jeffreys I.. Maximum acceleration performance of professional soccer players in linear sprints: Is there a direct connection with change-of-direction ability? PLoS One. 2019a;14(5):e0216806. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6516665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31086386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco I., Pereira L. A., Kobal R., Kitamura K., Cal Abad C. C., Marques G., Guerriero A., Moraes J. E.. Nakamura F. Y.. Validity and Usability of a New System for Measuring and Monitoring Variations in Vertical Jump Performance. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2017;31(9):2579&#x2013;2585. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28658079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco I., Pereira L. A., Kobal R., Zanetti V., Gil S., Kitamura K., Abad C. C.. Nakamura F. Y.. Half-squat or jump squat training under optimum power load conditions to counteract power and speed decrements in Brazilian elite soccer players during the preseason. Journal of Sports Sciences. 2015;33(12):1283&#x2013;1292. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25772972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco I., Suchomel T., Bishop C., Kobal R., Pereira L. A.. Mcguigan M.. One-Repetition-Maximum Measures or Maximum Bar-Power Output: Which Is More Related to Sport Performance? International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance. 2019b;14(1):33&#x2013;37. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29809068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mclaren S. J., Macpherson T. W., Coutts A. J., Hurst C., Spears I. R.. Weston M.. The Relationships Between Internal and External Measures of Training Load and Intensity in Team Sports: A Meta-Analysis. Sports Medicine. 2018;48(3):641&#x2013;658. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29288436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milanez V. F., Pedro R. E., Moreira A., Boullosa D. A., Salle-Neto F.. Nakamura F. Y.. The role of aerobic fitness on session rating of perceived exertion in futsal players. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance. 2011;6(3):358&#x2013;366. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21911861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy A. P., Duffield R., Kellett A.. Reid M.. A Comparison of the Perceptual and Technical Demands of Tennis Training, Simulated Match Play, and Competitive Tournaments. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance. 2016;11(1):40&#x2013;47. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25849156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura F. Y., Pereira L. A., Rabelo F. N., Ramirez-Campillo R.. Loturco I.. Faster futsal players perceive higher training loads and present greater decreases in sprinting speed during the preseason. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2015;30(6):1553&#x2013;1562. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26562717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K., Sacco P.. Mawatari K.. Effects of amino acid supplementation on muscle soreness and damage. International Journal of Sport Nutrition and Exercise Metabolism. 2006;16(6):620&#x2013;635. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17342883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osgnach C., Poser S., Bernardini R., Rinaldo R.. Di Prampero P. E.. Energy cost and metabolic power in elite soccer: a new match analysis approach. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2010;42(1):170&#x2013;178. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20010116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson J. M., Marin P. J., Rhea M. R., Wilson S. M., Loenneke J. P.. Anderson J. C.. Concurrent training: a meta-analysis examining interference of aerobic and resistance exercises. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2012;26(8):2293&#x2013;2307. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22002517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong P. L., Chaouachi A., Chamari K., Dellal A.. Wisloff U.. Effect of preseason concurrent muscular strength and high-intensity interval training in professional soccer players. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2010;24(3):653&#x2013;660. &amp;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19816215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>