<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36684533</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2288-176X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of exercise rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exerc Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Improved arterial stiffness after combined aerobic and resistance training: correlation with heart rate variability change in prehypertensive offspring of hypertensive parents.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>395</StartPage><EndPage>405</EndPage><MedlinePgn>395-405</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12965/jer.2244416.208</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Prehypertensive offspring of hypertensive parents are strongly linked to pathological processes of hypertension in later life. It is observed that young adults with high blood pressure (BP) have increased arterial stiffness, which is linked to autonomic anomalies. The purpose of the present study was to assess the effect of combined resistance and aerobic exercise training on BP, brachial-ankle pulse wave velocity (baP-WV), and heart rate variability (HRV) in prehypertensive young men with hypertensive parents. Thirty prehypertensive males aged 19.6&#xb1;1.2 years were randomly assigned to either a combined exercise training group (CBT, n=15) or no exercise group (CON, n=15). The CBT group performed combined exercise for 8 weeks, 3 times per week. BP, baP-WV, HRV, peak oxygen consumption (VO<sub>2peak</sub>), and muscle strength were measured before and after the exercise intervention. Systolic BP (-5.1 mmHg, 3.9% decrease, <i>P</i>&lt;0.05), diastolic BP (-3.9 mmHg, 6.1% decrease, <i>P</i>&lt;0.01), mean arterial pressure (-4.2 mmHg, 4.7% decrease, <i>P</i>&lt;0.05), baPWV (-0.4 m/sec, 3.5% decrease, <i>P</i>&lt;0.01), standard deviation of all RR intervals (+58.5% increase, <i>P</i>&lt;0.05) and very low frequency (VLF) (+34.6% increase, <i>P</i>&lt;0.01), VO<sub>2peak</sub> (+11.7% increase, <i>P</i>&lt;0.01) and one-repetition maximum leg press (+30.3% increase, <i>P</i>&lt;0.01) were significantly improved in the CBT group after 8 weeks of training versus the CON group. Additionally, a reduction in baPWV was associated with an increase in the VLF power of HRV (<i>r</i>=0.72, <i>P</i>&lt;0.01). These findings indicate that the combined training improves BP, arterial stiffness, vagal activity, cardiorespiratory fitness, and lower-body muscle strength in prehypertensive offspring of hypertensive parents.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Korean Society of Exercise Rehabilitation.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Songcharern</LastName><ForeName>Nattawut</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports and Exercise Science Program, Department of Sports Science and Health, Faculty of Sports Science, Kasetsart University, Nakhon Pathom, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ruangthai</LastName><ForeName>Ratree</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Health, Faculty of Sports Science, Kasetsart University, Nakhon Pathom, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tumnark</LastName><ForeName>Piyaporn</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Health, Faculty of Sports Science, Kasetsart University, Nakhon Pathom, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phoemsapthawee</LastName><ForeName>Jatuporn</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8859-3899</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Health, Faculty of Sports Science, Kasetsart University, Nakhon Pathom, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>J Exerc Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101615171</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2288-176X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Concurrent training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heart rate variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulse wave velocity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>CONFLICT OF INTEREST No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36684533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9816616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.2244416.208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jer-18-6-395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aekplakorn W, Abbott-Klafter J, Khonputsa P, Tatsanavivat P, Chongsuvivatwong V, Chariyalertsak S, Sangwatanaroj S, Tiptaradol S, Lim SS. Prevalence and management of prehypertension and hypertension by geographic regions of Thailand: the Third National Health Examination Survey, 2004. J Hypertens. 2008;26:191&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18192831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson C, Quiroz R, Enserro D, Larson MG, Hamburg NM, Vita JA, Levy D, Benjamin EJ, Mitchell GF, Vasan RS. Association of parental hypertension with arterial stiffness in nonhypertensive offspring: the Framingham Heart Study. Hypertension. 2016;68:584&#x2013;589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5002314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27456526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnett DK, Blumenthal RS, Albert MA, Buroker AB, Goldberger ZD, Hahn EJ, Himmelfarb CD, Khera A, Lloyd-Jones D, McEvoy JW, Michos ED, Miedema MD, Mu&#xf1;oz D, Smith SC, Jr, Virani SS, Williams KA, Sr, Yeboah J, Ziaeian B. 2019 ACC/AHA guideline on the primary prevention of cardiovascular disease: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on clinical practice guidelines. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;74:e177&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7685565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30894318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artero EG, Lee DC, Lavie CJ, Espa&#xf1;a-Romero V, Sui X, Church TS, Blair SN. Effects of muscular strength on cardiovascular risk factors and prognosis. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2012;32:351&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3496010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22885613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonaduce D, Marciano F, Petretta M, Migaux ML, Morgano G, Bianchi V, Salemme L, Valva G, Condorelli M. Effects of converting enzyme inhibition on heart period variability in patients with acute myocardial infarction. Circulation. 1994;90:108&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8025984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutcher YN, Park YJ, Boutcher SH. Vascular and baroreceptor abnormalities in young males with a family history of hypertension. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:653&#x2013;658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19714357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brentano MA, Cadore EL, Da Silva EM, Ambrosini AB, Coertjens M, Petkowicz R, Viero I, Kruel LF. Physiological adaptations to strength and circuit training in postmenopausal women with bone loss. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:1816&#x2013;1825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18978624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chobanian AV, Bakris GL, Black HR, Cushman WC, Green LA, Izzo JL, Jr, Jones DW, Materson BJ, Oparil S, Wright JT, Jr, Roccella EJ, Joint National Committee on Prevention, Detection Evaluation, and Treatment of High Blood Pressure National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute; National High Blood Pressure Education Program Coordinating Committee. Seventh report of the Joint National Committee on prevention, detection, evaluation, and treatment of high blood pressure. Hypertension. 2003;42:1206&#x2013;1252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14656957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelissen VA, Smart NA. Exercise training for blood pressure: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Heart Assoc. 2013;2:e004473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3603230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23525435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dekker JM, Schouten EG, Klootwijk P, Pool J, Swenne CA, Kromhout D. Heart rate variability from short electrocardiographic recordings predicts mortality from all causes in middle-aged and elderly men. The Zutphen Study. Am J Epidemiol. 1997;145:899&#x2013;908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9149661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos ES, Asano RY, Filho IG, Lopes NL, Panelli P, da Nascimento DC, Collier SR, Prestes J. Acute and chronic cardiovascular response to 16 weeks of combined eccentric or traditional resistance and aerobic training in elderly hypertensive women: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28:3073&#x2013;3084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24845208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan BM, Stevens-Fabry S. Prehypertension&#x2014;prevalence, health risks, and management strategies. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2015;12:289&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25687779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evrengul H, Tanriverdi H, Kilic ID, Dursunoglu D, Ozcan EE, Kaftan A, Kilic M. Aortic stiffness and flow-mediated dilatation in normotensive offspring of parents with hypertension. Cardiol Young. 2012;22:451&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22348859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahs CA, Heffernan KS, Ranadive S, Jae SY, Fernhall B. Muscular strength is inversely associated with aortic stiffness in young men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42:1619&#x2013;1624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20195176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farinatti P, da Silva Itaborahy A, de Paula T, Monteiro WD, Neves MF. Effects of aerobic, resistance and concurrent exercise on pulse wave reflection and autonomic modulation in men with elevated blood pressure. Sci Rep. 2021;11:760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7804273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33436986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa A, Park SY, Seo DY, Sanchez-Gonzalez MA, Baek YH. Combined resistance and endurance exercise training improves arterial stiffness, blood pressure, and muscle strength in postmenopausal women. Menopause. 2011;18:980&#x2013;984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21540753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher GF, Balady GJ, Amsterdam EA, Chaitman B, Eckel R, Fleg J, Froelicher VF, Leon AS, Pi&#xf1;a IL, Rodney R, Simons-Morton DA, Williams MA, Bazzarre T. Exercise standards for testing and training: a statement for healthcare professionals from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2001;104:1694&#x2013;1740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francica JV, Heeren MV, Tubaldini M, Sartori M, Mostarda C, Araujo RC, Irigoyen MC, De Angelis K. Impairment on cardiovascular and autonomic adjustments to maximal isometric exercise tests in offspring of hypertensive parents. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2013;20:480&#x2013;485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22729292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galinier M, Pathak A, Fourcade J, Androdias C, Curnier D, Varnous S, Boveda S, Massabuau P, Fauvel M, Senard JM, Bounhoure JP. Depressed low frequency power of heart rate variability as an independent predictor of sudden death in chronic heart failure. Eur Heart J. 2000;21:475&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10681488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghiadoni L, Bruno RM, Stea F, Virdis A, Taddei S. Central blood pressure, arterial stiffness, and wave reflection: new targets of treatment in essential hypertension. Curr Hypertens Rep. 2009;11:190&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19442328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xe4;ssler B, Thielmann B, B&#xf6;ckelmann I, H&#xf6;kelmann A. Effects of different training interventions on heart rate variability and cardiovascular health and risk factors in young and middle-aged adults: a systematic review. Front Physiol. 2021;12:657274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8107721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33981251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Triplett NT, editors. Essentials of strength training conditioning. 4th ed. Champaign (IL): Human Kinetics; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawano H, Iemitsu M, Gando Y, Ishijima T, Asaka M, Aoyama T, Ando T, Tokizawa K, Miyachi M, Sakamoto S, Higuchi M. Habitual rowing exercise is associated with high physical fitness without affecting arterial stiffness in older men. J Sports Sci. 2012;30:241&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22150337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokkinos P. Cardiorespiratory fitness, exercise, and blood pressure. Hypertension. 2014;64:1160&#x2013;1164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25245388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe9;n&#xe1;rd Z, Studinger P, Mersich B, Pavlik G, Kollai M. Cardiovagal autonomic function in sedentary and trained offspring of hypertensive parents. J Physiol. 2005;565(Pt 3):1031&#x2013;1038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1464546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15774521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewington S, Clarke R, Qizilbash N, Peto R, Collins R, Prospective Studies Collaboration Age-specific relevance of usual blood pressure to vascular mortality: a meta-analysis of individual data for one million adults in 61 prospective studies. Lancet. 2002;360:1903&#x2013;1913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12493255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Hanssen H, Cordes M, Rossmeissl A, Endes S, Schmidt-Trucks&#xe4;ss A. Aerobic, resistance and combined exercise training on arterial stiffness in normotensive and hypertensive adults: a review. Eur J Sport Sci. 2015;15:443&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25251989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maslow AL, Sui X, Colabianchi N, Hussey J, Blair SN. Muscular strength and incident hypertension in normotensive and prehypertensive men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42:288&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2809142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19927030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto T, Masuhara M, Ikuta K. Combined aerobic and resistance training and vascular function: effect of aerobic exercise before and after resistance training. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2007;103:1655&#x2013;1661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen SE, Wiesmann F, Hudsmith LE, Robson MD, Francis JM, Selvanayagam JB, Neubauer S, Channon KM. Functional and structural vascular remodeling in elite rowers assessed by cardiovascular magnetic resonance. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2006;48:790&#x2013;797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16904551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phoemsapthawee J, Prasertsri P, Leelayuwat N. Heart rate variability responses to a combined exercise training program: correlation with adiposity and cardiorespiratory fitness changes in obese young men. J Exerc Rehabil. 2019;15:114&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6416511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30899746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phoemsapthawee J, Sriton B. Combined exercise training improves blood pressure at rest and during exercise in young obese prehypertensive men. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2021;61:468&#x2013;479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32975391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathnayake KM, Roopasingam T, Wickramasighe VP. Nutritional and behavioral determinants of adolescent obesity: a case-control study in Sri Lanka. BMC Public Health. 2014;14:1291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4302095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25519979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruangthai R, Phoemsapthawee J. Combined exercise training improves blood pressure and antioxidant capacity in elderly individuals with hypertension. J Exerc Sci Fit. 2019;17:67&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6430041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30949214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senthil S, Krishndasa SN. Pre-hypertension in apparently healthy young adults: incidence and influence of haemoglobin level. J Clin Diagn Res. 2015;9:CC10&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4668404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26675286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng Y, Zhu L. The crosstalk between autonomic nervous system and blood vessels. Int J Physiol Pathophysiol Pharmacol. 2018;10:17&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5871626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29593847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son WM, Sung KD, Bharath LP, Choi KJ, Park SY. Combined exercise training reduces blood pressure, arterial stiffness, and insulin resistance in obese prehypertensive adolescent girls. Clin Exp Hypertens. 2017a;39:546&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28590143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son WM, Sung KD, Cho JM, Park SY. Combined exercise reduces arterial stiffness, blood pressure, and blood markers for cardiovascular risk in postmenopausal women with hypertension. Menopause. 2017b;24:262&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27779565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JA, Carr DL, Myers CW, Eckberg DL. Mechanisms underlying very-low-frequency RR-interval oscillations in humans. Circulation. 1998;98:547&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9714112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomiyama H, Yamashina A. Non-invasive vascular function tests: their pathophysiological background and clinical application. Circ J. 2010;74:24&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19920359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Fan F, Kou M, Yang Y, Cheng G, Jia J, Gao L, Zhou Z, Chen D, Zhang Y, Huo Y. Brachial-ankle pulse wave velocity is associated with the risk of new carotid plaque formation: data from a Chinese Community-based Cohort. Sci Rep. 2018;8:7037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5935681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29728607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zebekakis PE, Nawrot T, Thijs L, Balkestein EJ, van der Heijden-Spek J, Van Bortel LM, Struijker-Boudier HA, Safar ME, Staessen JA. Obesity is associated with increased arterial stiffness from adolescence until old age. J Hypertens. 2005;23:1839&#x2013;1846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16148607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao L, Meng X, Zhang QY, Dong XQ, Zhou XL. A narrative review of prehypertension and the cardiovascular system: effects and potential pathogenic mechanisms. Ann Transl Med. 2021;9:170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7867937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>