<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25675416</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1827-1928</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of sports medicine and physical fitness</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sports Med Phys Fitness</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cardiovascular risk factors adaptation to concurrent training in overweight sedentary middle- aged men.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><MedlinePgn/></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Cardiovascular disease (CVD) is a major cause of mortality and morbidity, though it is well known that exercise training decreases the CVD risk factors of low HDL and high blood pressure. Soluble intercellular adhesion molecule--1 (sICAM--1) levels are positively correlated with high blood pressure and decreased HDL, yet the effect of concurrent aerobic and resistance exercise training on sICAM--1 is unknown. Hence, this study was conducted to assess the effects of concurrent aerobic--resistance training (CT) on soluble intercellular adhesion molecule--1 (sICAM--1) and some CVD risk factors in sedentary overweight middle-- aged men.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Thirty sedentary middle-- aged men (aged 30-50 years) were assigned to either an experimental (EX; n=15) or Control (Cl; n=15) group. EX performed three days per week of progressive CT for eight weeks whilst CL did not train. Before and after the intervention, venous blood samples were obtained for measurement of blood lipids (LDL--C, HDLC, TC and TG) and plasma sICAM--1 concentration and anthropometric measures (weight, BMI, WC, WHR, body fat percent) were made.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">CT produced a significant decrease in plasma sICAM--1, LDL--C, TC, and significantly increased HDLC in the EX group (p&lt;0.05). Further, CT induced significant improvements in body composition (p&lt; 0.05). These variables remained unchanged in the CL group (p&gt;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Eight--weeks of concurrent exercise training reduce both circulating concentrations of sICAM--1 and markers of CVD risk in sedentary middle--age men. The mechanistic role by which sICAM--1 may improve CVD risk with training remains to be determined.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aatashak</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Mahabad Branch, Islamic Azad University, Mahabad, Iran - atashak_sirvan@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stannard</LastName><ForeName>S R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azizbeigi</LastName><ForeName>K</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2015</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>J Sports Med Phys Fitness</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0376337</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-4707</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25675416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">R40Y9999N00A150039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>