<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">19421643</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2009</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1995-1892</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2009</Year><Season>Mar-Apr</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiovascular journal of Africa</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiovasc J Afr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Compatibility of concurrent aerobic and resistance training on maximal aerobic capacity in sedentary males.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>104</StartPage><EndPage>106</EndPage><MedlinePgn>104-6</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Aerobic and resistance training are often performed concurrently by inactive individuals and those patients undergoing cardiac rehabilitation, despite contradictory findings that this mode of training may impair the development of maximal aerobic capacity (VO(2max)). The aim of the study, therefore, was to compare the effects of 16 weeks of aerobic, resistance and concurrent aerobic or resistance training on VO(2max) development. Fifty apparently healthy males (25 years +/- 8 months) were randomly assigned to a non-exercising control group (NonG) (n = 12), an aerobic training group (AerG) (n = 12), a resistance- training group (ResG) (n = 13), or a concurrent aerobic and resistance-training group (ConG) (n = 13). VO(2max) was measured pre- and post-experimentally using a continuous on-line oxygen analyser. Aerobic training consisted of exercise using a combination of treadmills, rowers, steppers and cycle ergometers, whereas resistance training consisted of eight prescribed exercises performed for three sets of 15 repetitions at 60% of the estimated one-repetition maximum (1-RM). In an attempt to equalise exercise duration across all three experimental groups, concurrent aerobic and resistance training consisted of a combination of aerobic training at 60% of heart rate maximum, and resistance training for two sets of 15 repetitions at 60% of the estimated 1-RM. The NonG were found to have decreased their VO(2max) by 3.36%, whereas the ResG increased their mean VO(2max) by 13.16%. The AerG and ConG increased their mean VO(2max) by 34.12 and 29.58%, respectively. In conclusion, concurrent training did not significantly interfere with development of aerobic capacity in sedentary males when compared to aerobic training. Therefore, this investigation did not support the concept of the universal nature of the interference effect that supposes the superiority of a single mode of training.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>B S</ForeName><Initials>BS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport, Rehabilitation and Dental Sciences, Tshwane University of Technology, Pretoria, South Africa. shawbs@tut.ac.za</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>I</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>South Africa</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiovasc J Afr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101313864</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1015-9657</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072038" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiac Rehabilitation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002318" MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiovascular Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017079" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Tolerance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012016" MajorTopicYN="N">Reference Values</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2009</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2009</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2009</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2009</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19421643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3721256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Frontera WR, Merdith CN, O&#x2019;Reilly KP, Evans WJ. Strength training and determinants of VO2max in older men. J Appl Physiol. 1990;68(1):329&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2312474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balabinis CP, Psarakis CH, Moukas M, Vassiliou MP, Behrakis PK. Early phase changes by concurrent endurance and strength training. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17(2):393&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12741884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw BS, Shaw I. Effect of resistance training on cardiorespiratory endurance and coronary artery disease risk. Cardiovasc J South Afr. 2005;16(5):200&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16307157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG, MacDougall JD, Jacobs I, Garner S. Interaction between concurrent strength and endurance training. J Appl Physiol. 1990;68(1):260&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2312468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickson RC, Rosenkoetter MA, Brown MM. Strength training effects on aerobic power and short-term endurance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1980;12(5):336&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7453510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcinik EJ, Potts J, Schlabach G, Will S, Dawson P, Hurley BF. Effects of strength training on lactate threshold and endurance performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1991;23(6):739&#x2013;743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1886483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gettman LR, Ayres JJ, Pollock ML, Jackson A. The effect of circuit weight training on strength, cardiorespiratory function, and body composition of adult men. Med Sci Sports. 1978;10(3):171&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">723506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickson RC, Dvorak BA, Gorostiaga EM, Kurowski TT, Foster C. Potential for strength and endurance to amplify endurance performance. J Appl Physiol. 1988;65(5):2285&#x2013;2290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3209573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley BF, Seals DR, Ehsani AA, Cartier LJ, Dalsky GP, Hagberg JM, Holloszy JO. Effects of high-intensity strength training on cardiovascular function. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1984;16(5):483&#x2013;488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6513767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikkola JS, Rusko HK, Nummela AT, Paavolainen LM, Hakkinen K. Concurrent endurance and explosive type strength training increases activation and fast force production of leg extensor muscles in endurance athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(2):613&#x2013;620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson RE, Quinn TJ, Kertzer R, Vroman NB. Strength training in female distance runners: Impact on running economy. J Strength Cond Res. 1997;11(4):224&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet GP, Jaouen B, Borrani F, Candau R. Effects of concurrent endurance and strength training on running economy and VO(2) kinetics. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(8):1351&#x2013;1359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12165692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudley GA, Djamil R. Incompatibility of endurance- and strength-training modes of exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1985;59(5):1446&#x2013;1451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4066574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferketich AK, Kirby TE, Alway SE. Cardiovascular and muscular adaptations to combined endurance and strength training in elderly women. Acta Physiol Scand. 1998;164(3):259&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9853013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquirdo M, Hakkinen K, Ibanez J, Kraemer WJ, Gorostiaga EM. Effects of combined resistance and cardiovascular training on strength, power, muscle cross-sectional area, and endurance markers in middle-aged men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2005;94(1&#x2013;2):70&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15616847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson AG, Arnall DA, Loy SF, Silvester LJ, Conlee RK. Consequences of combining strength and endurance training regimens. Phys Ther. 1990;70(5):287&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2333326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paavolainen L, Hakkinen K, Hamalainen I, Nummela A, Rusko H. Explosive-strength training improves 5-km running time by improving running economy and muscle power. J Appl Physiol. 1999;86(5):1527&#x2013;1533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10233114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osteras H, Helgerud J, Hoff J. Maximal strength-training effects on force-velocity and force-power relationships explain increases in aerobic performance in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88(3):255&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12458369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AS, Pollock ML. Generalized equations for predicting body density of men. Br J Nutr. 1978;40(3):497&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">718832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph LJ, Davey SL, Evans WJ, Campbell WW. Differential effect of resistance training on the body composition and lipoprotein-lipid profile in older men and women. Metabolism. 1999;48(11):1474&#x2013;1480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10582560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alter MJ. Sport Stretch. Champaign, IL: Leisure Press; 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle TR, Earle RW. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. 2nd edn. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Rhea MR, Alvar BA. Applications of the dose-resonse for muscular strength development: a review of meta-analytic efficacy and reliability for designing training prescription. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;9(4):950&#x2013;958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16287373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manning JM, Dooly-Manning CR, White K, Kampa I, Silas S, Kesselhaut M, Ruoff M. Effects of a resistive training programme on lipoprotein-lipid levels in obese women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1991;23(11):1222&#x2013;1223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1766336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace MB, Mills BD, Browning CL. Effects of cross-training on markers of insulin resistance/hyperinsulinemia. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1997;29(9):1170&#x2013;1176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9309627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>