<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39074167</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Seasonal Muscular Power Changes: Considerations of Concurrent Resistance and Field-Based Training in Professional Rugby League.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1620</StartPage><EndPage>1626</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1620-1626</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004842</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Redman, KJ, Wade, L, Whitley, R, Connick, MJ, Kelly, VG, and Beckman, EM. Seasonal muscular power changes: considerations of concurrent resistance and field-based training in professional rugby league. J Strength Cond Res 38(9): 1620-1626, 2024-A rugby league player's ability to develop or maintain lower-body power will be significantly influenced by the resistance and field-based training loads completed. This study aimed to examine the power changes across a rugby league season and to investigate the relationship of concurrent training and training experience on power changes. Eighteen rugby league players participated in this study. Lower-body power was evaluated using a countermovement jump throughout the season. Four measures of external training loads were collected. A Friedman's test was used to assess differences in power throughout different phases of the season. A series of Spearman's rank-order correlations were conducted to assess the relationship between percentage changes in power during the training block, external training loads, and training experience. Countermovement jump peak velocity significantly decreased from the start ( p = 0.006) and end of pre-season ( p = 0.022) to the late competition. Correlation analysis revealed a large significant association between early competition field-based external loads (relative ( rs = -0.571) and total distance ( rs = -0.628)) and change in peak power. Very large significant negative relationships were also observed between mid-competition volume load with change in peak force ( rs = -0.825) and peak power ( rs = -0.736). Training experience was not significantly associated with changes in muscular power variables throughout this study. Coaches should seek to monitor changes in peak power when competition begins and to assist with decision-making for potential adjustments to running volume and intensity during field-based sessions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Redman</LastName><ForeName>Kellyanne J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Movement and Nutrition Sciences, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Performance Science Department, Brisbane Broncos Rugby League Club, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wade</LastName><ForeName>Logan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for the Analysis of Motion, Entertainment Research and Applications, Department for Health, The University of Bath, Bath, United Kingdom ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Whitley</LastName><ForeName>Ryan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Performance Science Department, Brisbane Broncos Rugby League Club, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Connick</LastName><ForeName>Mark J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kelly</LastName><ForeName>Vincent G</ForeName><Initials>VG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beckman</LastName><ForeName>Emma M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Movement and Nutrition Sciences, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005538" MajorTopicYN="Y">Football</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012621" MajorTopicYN="N">Seasons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064797" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Conditioning, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39074167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202409000-00012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baker D. Applying the in-season periodization of strength and power training to football. Strength Cond J 20: 18&#x2013;24, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D. The effects of an in-season of concurrent training on the maintenance of maximal strength and power in professional and college-aged rugby league football players. J Strength Cond Res 15: 172&#x2013;177, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker DG, Newton RU. Discriminative analyses of various upper body tests in professional rugby-league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 1: 347&#x2013;360, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato M, Coratella G, Stiff A, Iacono AD. The validity and between-unit variability of GNSS units (STATSports Apex 10 and 18 Hz) for measuring distance and peak speed in team sports. Front Physiol 9: 1288, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutts A, Reaburn P, Piva TJ, Murphy A. Changes in selected biochemical, muscular strength, power, and endurance measures during deliberate overreaching and tapering in rugby league players. Int J Sports Med 28: 116&#x2013;124, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cronin JB, Hansen KT. Strength and power predictors of sports speed. J Strength Cond Res 19: 349&#x2013;357, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lacey J, Brughelli M, McGuigan M, et al. The effects of tapering on power-force-velocity profiling and jump performance in professional rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res 28: 3567&#x2013;3570, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C. Monitoring training in athletes with reference to overtraining syndrome. Med Sci Sports Exerc 30: 1164&#x2013;1168, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett T, Kelly J, Pezet T. Relationship between physical fitness and playing ability in rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res 21: 1126&#x2013;1133, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. Influence of training and match intensity on injuries in rugby league. J Sports Sci 22: 409&#x2013;417, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. Activity and recovery profiles of state-of-origin and national rugby league match-play. J Strength Cond Res 29: 708&#x2013;715, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ, Domrow N. Relationships between training load, injury, and fitness in sub-elite collision sport athletes. J Sports Sci 25: 1507&#x2013;1519, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ, Jenkins DG, Abernethy B. Physical demands of professional rugby league training and competition using microtechnology. J Sci Med Sport 15: 80&#x2013;86, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG. Quantifying workloads in resistance training: A brief review. Prof Strength Cond 10: 31&#x2013;40, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris NK, Cronin JB, Hopkins WG, Hansen KT. Squat jump training at maximal power loads vs. heavy loads: Effect on sprint ability. J Strength Cond Res 22: 1742&#x2013;1749, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 3&#x2013;13, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jidovtseff B, Quievre J, Harris NK, Cronin JB. Influence of jumping strategy on kinetic and kinematic variables. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 54: 129&#x2013;138, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston RD, Gabbett TJ, Jenkins DG. Applied sport science of rugby league. Sports Med 44: 1087&#x2013;1100, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston RD, Gabbett TJ, Jenkins DG, Hulin BT. Influence of physical qualities on post-match fatigue in rugby league players. J Sci Med Sport 18: 209&#x2013;213, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston RD, Gibson NV, Twist C, et al. Physiological responses to an intensified period of rugby league competition. J Strength Cond Res 27: 643&#x2013;654, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston RD, Weaving D, Hulin BT, et al. Peak movement and collision demands of professional rugby league competition. J Sports Sci 37: 2144&#x2013;2151, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy RA, Drake D. The effect of acute fatigue on countermovement jump performance in rugby union players during preseason. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 57: 1261&#x2013;1266, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Newton RU. Training for muscular power. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am 11: 341&#x2013;368, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean BD, Coutts AJ, Kelly V, McGuigan MR, Cormack SJ. Neuromuscular, endocrine, and perceptual fatigue responses during different length between-match microcycles in professional rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 5: 367&#x2013;383, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan CP, Lovell DI. Neuromuscular responses to impact and collision during elite rugby league match play. J Strength Cond Res 26: 1431&#x2013;1440, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan CP, Lovell DI, Gass GC. Markers of postmatch fatigue in professional Rugby League players. J Strength Cond Res 25: 1030&#x2013;1039, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira A, Kempton T, Aoki MS, Sirotic AC, Coutts AJ. The impact of 3 different-length between-matches microcycles on training loads in professional rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 10: 767&#x2013;773, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor DM, Crowe MJ. Effects of six weeks of beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB) and HMB/creatine supplementation on strength, power, and anthropometry of highly trained athletes. J Strength Cond Res 21: 419&#x2013;423, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodriguez-Rosell D, Sanchez-Medina L, et al. Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on athletic performance, strength gains and muscle adaptations. Scand J Med Sci Sports 27: 724&#x2013;735, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Rhea MR, Alvar BA. Applications of the dose-response for muscular strength development: A review of meta-analytic efficacy and reliability for designing training prescription. J Strength Cond Res 19: 950&#x2013;958, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polman R, Nicholls AR, Cohen J, Borkoles E. The influence of game location and outcome on behaviour and mood states among professional rugby league players. J Sports Sci 25: 1491&#x2013;1500, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman KJ, Connick MJ, Beckman EM, Kelly VG. Monitoring prescribed and actual resistance training loads in professional rugby league. J Strength Cond Res 35: 1604&#x2013;1610, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman KJ, Wade L, Kelly VG, Connick MJ, Beckman EM. Predicting rugby league tackle outcomes using strength and power principal components. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 278&#x2013;285, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman KJ, Wade L, Kelly VG, Connick MJ, Beckman EM. Effects of the off-season on muscular power in professional rugby league. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 17: 733&#x2013;738, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman KJ, Wade L, Whitley R, et al. The relationship between match tackle outcomes and muscular strength and power in professional rugby league. J Strength Cond Res 36: 2853&#x2013;2861, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott MT, Scott TJ, Kelly VG. The validity and reliability of global positioning systems in team sport: A brief review. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1470&#x2013;1490, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speranza MJA, Gabbett TJ, Johnston RD, Sheppard JM. Muscular strength and power correlates of tackling ability in semiprofessional rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res 29: 2071&#x2013;2078, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twist C, Waldron M, Highton J, Burt D, Daniels M. Neuromuscular, biochemical and perceptual post-match fatigue in professional rugby league forwards and backs. J Sports Sci 30: 359&#x2013;367, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldron M, Worsfold PR, Twist C, Lamb K. The relationship between physical abilities, ball-carrying and tackling among elite youth rugby league players. J Sports Sci 32: 542&#x2013;549, 2014.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>