<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37254895</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2037-7452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of translational myology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Transl Myol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of concurrent training and CoQ10 on neurotrophic factors and physical function in people with Multiple Sclerosis: a pilot study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">11253</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4081/ejtm.2023.11253</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The present study aimed to investigate the effects of 8-week of coenzyme Q10 (CoQ10) supplementation alone or combined with concurrent training (CT) on functional capacity, serum brain derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) and nerve growth factor (NGF) in multiple sclerosis (MS) patients. Our hypothesis is that CT promotes improvements in the studied outcomes with higher results for the combination of CT and CoQ10. Randomized placebo-controlled trial. Twenty-eight patients with MS were randomly divided into 4 groups: CT+placebo, CT+CoQ10, CoQ10 and placebo. CT involved two resistance training sessions and one aerobic training session per week. CoQ10 was supplemented with 200 mg daily. Serum levels of BDNF, NGF and functional tests [timed up and go (TUG), 6-min walk (6MW), chest press, lateral pull down, leg extension, and lying leg curls one repetition maximum] were measured before and after the intervention period. CT+placebo and CT+CoQ10 significantly improved performance in TUG, 6MW, chest press, lateral pull down, leg extension, and lying leg curls, with superior results to both CoQ10 and placebo groups. Changes in TUG for CT+placebo were significantly higher than CT+CoQ10 (p&lt;0.05). There were no significant differences in NGF and BDNF among the four groups (p &gt;0.05). CT improves physical abilities in patient with MS, regardless CoQ10 supplementation. CT should be recommended for MS patients to increase functional capacity, but there seems to be no benefit in supplementing CoQ10.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hossein Haghighi</LastName><ForeName>Amir</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Hakim Sabzevari University, Sabzevar. ah.haghighi@hsu.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmadi</LastName><ForeName>Amin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Hakim Sabzevari University, Sabzevar. amin.ahmadi83@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carotenuto</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, Reproductive and Odontostomatological Sciences, Federico II University, Naples. carotenuto.antonio87@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Askari</LastName><ForeName>Roya</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Hakim Sabzevari University, Sabzevar. r.askari@hsu.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nikkhah</LastName><ForeName>Karim</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad. nikkhahk@mums.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bagherzadeh-Rahmani</LastName><ForeName>Behnam</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Hakim Sabzevari University, Sabzevar. b.bagherzadehrahmani@hsu.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharabadi</LastName><ForeName>Hadi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Hakim Sabzevari University, Sabzevar. h.shahrabadi@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Souza</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education and Dance, Federal University of Goias, Goiania. daniel_souza86@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gentil</LastName><ForeName>Paulo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>) College of Physical Education and Dance, Federal University of Goias, Goiania, Brazil; Hypertension League, Federal University of Goias, Goiania. paulogentil@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Transl Myol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2037-7452</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>We confirm that we have read the Journal&#x2019;s position on issues involved in ethical publication and affirm that this report is consistent with those guidelines. <b>M</b>ultiple sclerosis (MS) is the most common debilitating neurological disease among adults. MS is an autoimmune central nervous system disorder characterised by demyelination and neurodegeneration that leads to physical disability. Previous researches examined nutritional strategies that are potentially effective for MS management.<sup>,</sup> Given the important role of inflammation, oxidative stress and mitochondrial dysfunction in MS development, treatments with anti-inflammatory and antioxidant supplements have received growing attention.<sup>,</sup> Among them, coenzyme Q10 (CoQ10) is considered a promising therapeutic agent in neurodegenerative diseases. The administration of CoQ10 alone or in combination with other substances in mice with induced-neurodegenerative disease provided neuroprotective effects such as decreased brain oxidative stress and damage, as well as increased neurotrophic factors (e.g., BDNF).<sup>,</sup> CoQ10 supplementation might be of potential interest due to its anti-inflammatory and antioxidant effects in MS patients, as well as its positive effects on fatigue and depressive symptoms. Physical exercise is also a potential therapeutic strategy for managing MS, and is considered safe and effective, with positive effects in fitness, functional capacity and quality of life. Exercise exerts its positive therapeutic effects through different pathways. It increases regeneration of sensory neurons after axonal injury, stimulates the expression of genes associated with axon growth and regeneration, and improves nerve function.<sup>,</sup> Physical exercise can also reduce MS symptoms by improving motor coordination, aerobic capacity and muscle strength. Moreover, physical exercise has been shown to increase the expression of neurotrophic factors such as brain derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) and nerve growth factor (NGF).<sup>,</sup> Although many different strategies have been used, the combination of resistance and aerobic training, known as concurrent training (CT), has been shown to be particularly beneficial for people with MS.<sup>,</sup> Considering the potential benefits of CoQ10 supplementation in MS, it is plausible to suggest that it might exert additional effects when combined with CT. Therefore, the aim of the present study was to investigate the effects of eight weeks of a CT and CoQ10 supplementation on physical function, serum BDNF and NGF levels in people with MS. Our hypothesis is that CT would promote improvements in the studied outcomes with higher results for the combination of CT and CoQ10.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37254895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10388606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/ejtm.2023.11253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Noseworthy JH, Lucchinetti C, Rodriguez M, Weinshenker BG. Multiple sclerosis. N Engl J Med. 2000. Sep 28;343(13):938-52. doi: 10.1056/NEJM200009283431307. PMID: 11006371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11006371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippi M, Bar-Or A, Piehl F, Preziosa P, Solari A, Vukusic S, Rocca MA. Multiple sclerosis. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2018. Nov 8;4(1):43. doi: 10.1038/s41572-018-0041-4. Erratum in: Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2018. Nov 22;4(1): 49. PMID: 30410033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30410033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riccio P, Rossano R. Nutrition facts in multiple sclerosis. ASN Neuro. 2015. Feb 18;7(1):1759091414568185. doi: 10.1177/1759091414568185. PMID: 25694551; PMCID: PMC4342365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4342365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25694551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagur MJ, Murcia MA, Jim&#xe9;nez-Monreal AM, Tur JA, Bibiloni MM, Alonso GL, Mart&#xed;nez-Tom&#xe9; M. Influence of Diet in Multiple Sclerosis: A Systematic Review. Adv Nutr. 2017. May 15;8(3):463-472. doi: 10.3945/an.116.014191. PMID: 28507011; PMCID: PMC5421121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5421121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28507011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx W, Hockey M, McGuinness AJ, Lane M, Christodoulou J, van der Mei I, Berk M, Dean OM, Taylor B, Broadley S, Lechner-Scott J, Jacka FN, Lucas RM, Ponsonby AL; RELIEF Trial team. The effect of emerging nutraceutical interventions for clinical and biological outcomes in multiple sclerosis: A systematic review. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2020. Jan;37:101486. doi: 10.1016/j.msard.2019.101486. Epub 2019 Nov 2. PMID: 31707234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31707234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riccio P, Rossano R. Nutrition facts in multiple sclerosis. ASN Neuro. 2015. Feb 18;7(1):1759091414568185. doi: 10.1177/1759091414568185. PMID: 25694551; PMCID: PMC4342365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4342365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25694551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Laithy NA, Mahdy EME, Youness ER, Shafee N, Mowafy MSS, Mabrouk MM. Effect of co enzyme Q10 alone or in combination with vitamin C on Lipopolysaccharide-induced brain injury in rats. Biomedical and Pharmacology Journal. 2018;11(3):1215&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Calingasan NY, Wille EJ, Cormier K, Smith K, Ferrante RJ, Beal MF. Combination therapy with coenzyme Q10 and creatine produces additive neuroprotective effects in models of Parkinson's and Huntington's diseases. J Neurochem. 2009. Jun;109(5):1427-39. doi: 10.1111/j.1471-4159.2009.06074.x. Epub 2009 Mar 28. PMID: 19476553; PMCID: PMC2866530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2866530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19476553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanoobar M, Eghtesadi S, Azimi A, Khalili M, Jazayeri S, Reza Gohari M. Coenzyme Q10 supplementation reduces oxidative stress and increases antioxidant enzyme activity in patients with relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis. Int J Neurosci. 2013. Nov;123(11):776-82. doi: 10.3109/00207454.2013.801844. Epub 2013 Jun 17. PMID: 23659338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23659338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moccia M, Capacchione A, Lanzillo R, Carbone F, Micillo T, Perna F, De Rosa A, Carotenuto A, Albero R, Matarese G, Palladino R, Brescia Morra V. Coenzyme Q10 supplementation reduces peripheral oxidative stress and inflammation in interferon-&#x3b2;1a-treated multiple sclerosis. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2019. Feb 18;12: 1756286418819074. doi: 10.1177/175628 6418819074. PMID: 30815035; PMCID: PMC6381428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6381428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30815035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halabchi F, Alizadeh Z, Sahraian MA, Abolhasani M. Exercise prescription for patients with multiple sclerosis; potential benefits and practical recommendations. BMC Neurol. 2017. Sep 16;17(1):185. doi: 10.1186/s12883-017-0960-9. PMID: 28915856; PMCID: PMC5602953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5602953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28915856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oken BS, Kishiyama S, Zajdel D, Bourdette D, Carlsen J, Haas M, Hugos C, Kraemer DF, Lawrence J, Mass M. Randomized controlled trial of yoga and exercise in multiple sclerosis. Neurology. 2004. Jun 8;62(11):2058-64. doi: 10.1212/01.wnl.0000129534.88602.5c. PMID: 15184614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15184614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalgas U, Stenager E, Jakobsen J, Petersen T, Hansen HJ, Knudsen C, Overgaard K, Ingemann-Hansen T. Resistance training improves muscle strength and functional capacity in multiple sclerosis. Neurology. 2009. Nov 3;73(18):1478-84. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181bf98b4. PMID: 19884575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19884575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molteni R, Zheng JQ, Ying Z, G&#xf3;mez-Pinilla F, Twiss JL. Voluntary exercise increases axonal regeneration from sensory neurons. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2004. Jun 1;101(22):8473-8. doi: 10.1073/pnas.0401443101. Epub 2004 May 24. PMID: 15159540; PMCID: PMC420418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC420418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15159540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briken S, Rosenkranz SC, Keminer O, Patra S, Ketels G, Heesen C, Hellweg R, Pless O, Schulz KH, Gold SM. Effects of exercise on Irisin, BDNF and IL-6 serum levels in patients with progressive multiple sclerosis. J Neuroimmunol. 2016. Oct 15;299:53-58. doi: 10.1016/j.jneuroim.2016.08.007. Epub 2016 Aug 5. PMID: 27725121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27725121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbaspoor E, Zolfaghari M, Ahmadi B, Khodaei K. The effect of combined functional training on BDNF, IGF-1, and their association with health-related fitness in the multiple sclerosis women. Growth Horm IGF Res. 2020. Jun;52:101320. doi: 10.1016/j.ghir.2020.101320. Epub 2020 Apr 2. PMID: 32305012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32305012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grazioli E, Tranchita E, Borriello G, Cerulli C, Minganti C, Parisi A. The Effects of Concurrent Resistance and Aerobic Exercise Training on Functional Status in Patients with Multiple Sclerosis. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2019. Dec;18(12):452-457. doi: 10.1249/JSR.0000000 000000661. PMID: 31834177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31834177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keytsman C, Hansen D, Wens I, Eijnde BO. Impact of high-intensity concurrent training on cardiovascular risk factors in persons with multiple sclerosis - pilot study. Disabil Rehabil. 2019. Feb;41(4):430-435. doi: 10.1080/09638288.2017.1395086. Epub 2017 Oct 27. PMID: 29076386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29076386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson AJ, Banwell BL, Barkhof F, Carroll WM, Coetzee T, Comi G, Correale J, Fazekas F, Filippi M, Freedman MS, Fujihara K, Galetta SL, Hartung HP, Kappos L, Lublin FD, Marrie RA, Miller AE, Miller DH, Montalban X, Mowry EM, Sorensen PS, Tintor&#xe9; M, Traboulsee AL, Trojano M, Uitdehaag BMJ, Vukusic S, Waubant E, Weinshenker BG, Reingold SC, Cohen JA. Diagnosis of multiple sclerosis: 2017 revisions of the McDonald criteria. Lancet Neurol. 2018. Feb;17(2):162-173. doi: 10.1016/S1474-4422(17)30470-2. Epub 2017 Dec 21. PMID: 29275977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29275977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astrand I, Astrand PO, Christensen EH, Hedman R. Intermittent muscular work. Acta Physiol Scand. 1960. Apr 25;48:448-53. doi: 10.1111/j.1748-1716.1960.tb01879.x. PMID: 13794890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13794890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brzycki M. Strength Testing&#x2014;Predicting a One-Rep Max from Reps-to-Fatigue. J Phys Educ Recreat Dance. 1993;64(1):88&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kj&#xf8;lhede T, Vissing K, Dalgas U. Multiple sclerosis and progressive resistance training: a systematic review. Mult Scler. 2012. Sep;18(9):1215-28. doi: 10.1177/1352458512437418. Epub 2012 Apr 24. PMID: 22760230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22760230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petajan JH, Gappmaier E, White AT, Spencer MK, Mino L, Hicks RW. Impact of aerobic training on fitness and quality of life in multiple sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 1996. Apr;39(4):432-41. doi: 10.1002/ana.410390405. PMID: 8619521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8619521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahari F, Naghdi N, Sheikh M, Shaw BS. Effect of physical exercise on muscle strength, static and dynamic balance and resiliency in women with multiple sclerosis. South African Journal for Research in Sport, Physical Education &amp; Recreation. 2021;43(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medina-Perez C, de Souza-Teixeira F, Fernandez-Gonzalo R, de Paz-Fernandez JA. Effects of a resistance training program and subsequent detraining on muscle strength and muscle power in multiple sclerosis patients. NeuroRehabilitation. 2014;34(3):523-30. doi: 10.3233/NRE-141062. PMID: 24463236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24463236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalron A, Achiron A, Dvir Z. Muscular and gait abnormalities in persons with early onset multiple sclerosis. J Neurol Phys Ther. 2011. Dec;35(4):164-9. doi: 10.1097/NPT.0b013e31823801f4. PMID: 22052130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22052130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalgas U, Stenager E, Lund C, Rasmussen C, Petersen T, S&#xf8;rensen H, Ingemann-Hansen T, Overgaard K. Neural drive increases following resistance training in patients with multiple sclerosis. J Neurol. 2013. Jul;260(7):1822-32. doi: 10.1007/s00415-013-6884-4. Epub 2013 Mar 13. PMID: 23483214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23483214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filipi ML, Leuschen MP, Huisinga J, Schmaderer L, Vogel J, Kucera D, et al. Impact of Resistance Training on Balance and Gait in Multiple Sclerosis. Int J MS Care. 2010. Apr;12(1):6&#x2013; 12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva MH, Andre Barbosa De Lira C, Steele J, Fisher JP, Mota JF, Gomes AC, Gentil P. Cycle ergometer training and resistance training similarly increase muscle strength in trained men. J Sports Sci. 2022. Mar;40(5):583-590. doi: 10.1080/ 02640414.2021.2005282. Epub 2021 Nov 18. PMID: 34789054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34789054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeBolt LS, McCubbin JA. The effects of home-based resistance exercise on balance, power, and mobility in adults with multiple sclerosis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2004. Feb;85(2):290-7. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2003.06.003. PMID: 14966716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14966716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, &#xc1;cs P, Baumann P, Borb&#xe9;ly G, &#xc1;fra G, Reichardt-Varga E, S&#xe1;ntha G, Toll&#xe1;r J. Comparative Effectiveness of 4 Exercise Interventions Followed by 2 Years of Exercise Maintenance in Multiple Sclerosis: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2022. Oct;103(10):1908-1916. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2022.04.012. Epub 2022 May 16. PMID: 35584738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35584738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasser SL, Jacobs JV, Sibold J, Marcus A, Cole L. Using Body-Worn Sensors to Detect Changes in Balance and Mobility After Acute Aerobic Exercise in Adults with Multiple Sclerosis. Int J MS Care. 2020. Jan-Feb;22(1):1-6. doi: 10.7224/1537-2073.2018-073. PMID: 32123522; PMCID: PMC7041613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7041613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32123522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong VL, Holahan MR. A systematic review of aerobic and resistance exercise and inflammatory markers in people with multiple sclerosis. Behav Pharmacol. 2019. Dec;30(8):653-660. doi: 10.1097/FBP.0000000000000514. PMID: 31703029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31703029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toll&#xe1;r J, Nagy F, T&#xf3;th BE, T&#xf6;r&#xf6;k K, Szita K, Csutor&#xe1;s B, Moizs M, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T. Exercise Effects on Multiple Sclerosis Quality of Life and Clinical-Motor Symptoms. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020. May;52(5):1007-1014. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002228. PMID: 31876670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31876670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cakt BD, Nacir B, Gen&#xe7; H, Sara&#xe7;o&#x11f;lu M, Karag&#xf6;z A, Erdem HR, Erg&#xfc;n U. Cycling progressive resistance training for people with multiple sclerosis: a randomized controlled study. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2010. Jun;89(6):446-57. doi: 10.1097/PHM.0b013e3181d3e71f. PMID: 20216060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20216060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutierrez GM, Chow JW, Tillman MD, McCoy SC, Castellano V, White LJ. Resistance training improves gait kinematics in persons with multiple sclerosis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2005. Sep;86(9):1824-9. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2005.04. 008. PMID: 16181949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16181949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filipi ML, Leuschen MP, Huisinga J, Schmaderer L, Vogel J, Kucera D, et al. Impact of Resistance Training on Balance and Gait in Multiple Sclerosis. Int J MS Care. 2010;15(SUPPL.1):24&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbaspoor E, Zolfaghari M, Ahmadi B, Khodaei K. The effect of combined functional training on BDNF, IGF-1, and their association with health-related fitness in the multiple sclerosis women. Growth Horm IGF Res. 2020. Jun;52:101320. doi: 10.1016/j.ghir.2020.101320. Epub 2020 Apr 2. PMID: 32305012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32305012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khademosharie M, Tadibi V, Behpoor N, Hamedinia MR. The effect of 12-weeks concurent training on the serum levels NGF, BDNF, and VDBP in women with multiple sclerosis. International journal of applied exercise physiology. 2018;7(1):77&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozkul C, Guclu-Gunduz A, Irkec C, Fidan I, Aydin Y, Ozkan T, Yazici G. Effect of combined exercise training on serum brain-derived neurotrophic factor, suppressors of cytokine signaling 1 and 3 in patients with multiple sclerosis. J Neuroimmunol. 2018. Mar 15;316:121-129. doi: 10.1016/j. jneuroim.2018.01.002. Epub 2018 Jan 3. PMID: 29329698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29329698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wens I, Keytsman C, Deckx N, Cools N, Dalgas U, Eijnde BO. Brain derived neurotrophic factor in multiple sclerosis: effect of 24 weeks endurance and resistance training. Eur J Neurol. 2016. Jun;23(6):1028-35. doi: 10.1111/ene.12976. Epub 2016 Mar 16. PMID: 26992038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26992038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moccia M, Capacchione A, Lanzillo R, Carbone F, Micillo T, Perna F, De Rosa A, Carotenuto A, Albero R, Matarese G, Palladino R, Brescia Morra V. Coenzyme Q10 supplementation reduces peripheral oxidative stress and inflammation in interferon-&#x3b2;1a-treated multiple sclerosis. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2019. Feb 18;12:1756286418819074. doi: 10.1177/17562864 18819074. PMID: 30815035; PMCID: PMC6381428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6381428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30815035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>