<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40226294</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2174-0852</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Jan-Mar</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of clinical and health psychology : IJCHP</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Clin Health Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of human concurrent aerobic and resistance training on cognitive health: A systematic review with meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100559</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100559</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100559</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ijchp.2025.100559</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The rising prevalence of cognitive decline and neurodegenerative diseases, projected to affect 150 million individuals by 2050, highlights the urgent need to enhance neurocognitive health. While both aerobic and resistance training are recognized as effective strategies, their combined effects on cognition remain underexplored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study aimed to determine if concurrent aerobic and resistance training (CT) is effective in enhancing cognitive function.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Seven English and three Chinese databases were searched from inception to August 2024. Randomised controlled trials (RCTs) examining the effects of CT on global cognition across diverse populations were included. A meta-analysis was performed using a random-effects model in R and Stata, supplemented by subgroup and meta-regression analyses to explore variability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The meta-analysis included 35 RCTs with 5,734 participants, revealing a positive effect of CT on global cognition (g = 0.32, 95% CI: 0.17-0.46, p &lt; 0.001). Notably, older adults (&#x2265;65 years) exhibited greater cognitive benefits (g = 0.33; 95% CI: 0.14-0.51, p &lt; 0.05) compared to younger populations. Significant effects were also observed in clinical populations (g = 0.28; 95% CI: 0.11-0.46, p &lt; 0.001). Exercise frequency and duration positively influenced outcomes, with medium-length interventions (13-26 weeks) demonstrating significant effects (g = 0.21; 95% CI: 0.05-0.37, p = 0.011).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The findings indicate that CT significantly enhances cognitive health, particularly in older adults and clinical populations. Prioritizing strength training, implementing short- to medium-term interventions (4-26 weeks), and maintaining session durations of 30-60 minutes are crucial for optimizing cognitive benefits.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Published by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Mingyang</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport Science, Jishou University, Jishou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Wangfan</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport Science, Jishou University, Jishou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jiahong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Soochow University Think Tank, Soochow University, Suzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Spain</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Clin Health Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101237969</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1697-2600</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Concurrent training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mild cognitive impairment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Older adults</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Mingyang Zhang reports article publishing charges and statistical analysis were provided by Jishou University. Wangfan Fang reports a relationship with Jishou University that includes: non-financial support. None has patent pending to None. We have nothing to declare. If there are other authors, they declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40226294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11987655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijchp.2025.100559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1697-2600(25)00017-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>A'Naja M.N., Batrakoulis A., Camhi S.M., McAvoy C., Sansone J.S., Reed R. 2025 ACSM worldwide fitness trends: future directions of the health and fitness industry. ACSM's Health &amp; Fitness Journal. 2024;28(6):11&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna S.B., Batrakoulis A., Ghazali W.S.W., Mohamed M., Aldayel A., Alhussain M.H., &#x2026;Elkholi S. Effects of combined aerobic and resistance training on glycemic control, blood pressure, inflammation, cardiorespiratory fitness and quality of life in patients with type 2 diabetes and overweight/obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Peer Journal. 2024;12:e17525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11182026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38887616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna S.B., Rocha-Rodriguesc S., Mohamed M., Batrakoulis A., Aldhahi M.I., Afolabi H.A.&#x2026;Abubakar B.D. Effects of combined aerobic exercise and diet on cardiometabolic health in patients with obesity and type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Sports Science, Medicine and Rehabilitation. 2023;15(1):165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10696788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38049873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amatriain-Fern&#xe1;ndez S., Ezquerro Garc&#xed;a-Noblejas M., Budde H. Effects of chronic exercise on the inhibitory control of children and adolescents: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports. 2021;31(6):1196&#x2013;1208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33559271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansai J.H., Rebelatto J.R. Effect of two physical exercise protocols on cognition and depressive symptoms in oldest-old people: A randomised controlled trial. Geriatrics &amp; gerontology international. 2015;15(9):1127&#x2013;1134. doi: 10.1111/ggi.12411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ggi.12411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25407380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arrieta H., Rezola-Pardo C., Kortajarena M., Herv&#xe1;s G., Gil J., Yanguas J.J., &#x2026;Rodriguez-Larrad A. The impact of physical exercise on cognitive and affective functions and serum levels of brain-derived neurotrophic factor in nursing home residents: a randomized controlled trial. Maturitas. 2020;131:72&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31787150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babaei P., Azali Alamdari K., Soltani Tehrani B., Damirchi A. Effect of six weeks of endurance exercise and following detraining on serum brain derived neurotrophic factor and memory performance in middle aged males with metabolic syndrome. The Journal of Sports Medicine and Physical Fitness. 2013;53(4):437&#x2013;443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23828292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae S., Lee S., Lee S., Jung S., Makino K., Harada K., &#x2026;Shimada H. The effect of a multicomponent intervention to promote community activity on cognitive function in older adults with mild cognitive impairment: a randomized controlled trial. Complementary Therapies in Medicine. 2019;42:164&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30670238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle T.R., Earle R.W. Human kinetics; 2008. Essentials of strength training and conditioning.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballesteros S., Audifren M., Badache A., Belkin V., Giannaki C.D., Kaltsatou A., &#x2026;Netz Y. Effects of chronic physical exercise on executive functions and episodic memory in clinical and healthy older adult populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis protocol. Systematic reviews. 2024;13(1):98. doi: 10.1186/s13643-024-02517-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13643-024-02517-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10983622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38561810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes D.E., Santos-Modesitt W., Poelke G., Kramer A.F., Castro C., Middleton L.E., Yaffe K. The Mental Activity and eXercise (MAX) trial: a randomized controlled trial to enhance cognitive function in older adults. JAMA internal medicine. 2013;173(9):797&#x2013;804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5921904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23545598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A., Fatouros I.G. Psychological adaptations to high-intensity interval training in overweight and obese adults: A topical review. Sports. 2022;10(5):64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9148041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35622474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A., Jamurtas A.Z., Metsios G.S., Perivoliotis K., Liguori G., Feito Y., &#x2026;Krustrup P. Comparative efficacy of 5 exercise types on cardiometabolic health in overweight and obese adults: a systematic review and network meta-analysis of 81 randomized controlled trials. Circulation: Cardiovascular Quality and Outcomes. 2022;15(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35477256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beard J.R., Officer A., De Carvalho I.A., Sadana R., Pot A.M., Michel J.-P.&#x2026;Mahanani W.R. The World report on ageing and health: a policy framework for healthy ageing. The Lancet. 2016;387(10033):2145&#x2013;2154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4848186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26520231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begg C.B., Mazumdar M. Operating characteristics of a rank correlation test for publication bias. Biometrics. 1994:1088&#x2013;1101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7786990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell K.E., Fang H., Snijders T., Allison D.J., Zulyniak M.A., Chabowski A., &#x2026;Heisz J.J. A multi-ingredient nutritional supplement in combination with resistance exercise and high-intensity interval training improves cognitive function and increases N-3 index in healthy older men: a randomized controlled trial. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience. 2019;11:107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6521794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31143111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Best J.R., Chiu B.K., Hsu C.L., Nagamatsu L.S., Liu-Ambrose T. Long-term effects of resistance exercise training on cognition and brain volume in older women: results from a randomized controlled trial. Journal of the International Neuropsychological Society. 2015;21(10):745&#x2013;756. doi: 10.1017/s1355617715000673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/s1355617715000673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26581787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biazus-Sehn L.F., Schuch F.B., Firth J., de Souza Stigger F. Effects of physical exercise on cognitive function of older adults with mild cognitive impairment: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Archives of Gerontology and Geriatrics. 2020;89</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32460123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair C. School readiness: integrating cognition and emotion in a neurobiological conceptualization of children's functioning at school entry. American Psychologist. 2002;57(2):111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11899554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boksem M.A., Tops M. Mental fatigue: costs and benefits. Brain Research Reviews. 2008;59(1):125&#x2013;139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18652844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Human kinetics; 1998. Borg's perceived exertion and pain scales.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossers W.J., Scherder E.J., Boersma F., Hortobagyi T., van der Woude L.H., van Heuvelen M.J. Feasibility of a combined aerobic and strength training program and its effects on cognitive and physical function in institutionalized dementia patients. A pilot study. PloS one. 2014;9(5):e97577. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0097577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0097577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4028210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24844772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossers W.J., van der Woude L.H., Boersma F., Hortobagyi T., Scherder E.J., van Heuvelen M.J. A 9-week aerobic and strength training program improves cognitive and motor function in patients with dementia: A randomized, controlled trial. The American journal of Geriatric Psychiatry : Official Journal of the American Association for Geriatric Psychiatry. 2015;23(11):1106&#x2013;1116. doi: 10.1016/j.jagp.2014.12.191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jagp.2014.12.191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25648055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callisaya M., Daly R., Sharman J., Bruce D., Davis T., Greenaway T., &#x2026;Phan T. Feasibility of a multi-modal exercise program on cognition in older adults with type 2 diabetes&#x2013;a pilot randomized controlled trial. BMC Geriatrics. 2017;17:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5644140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29037162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cammisuli D., Innocenti A., Franzoni F., Pruneti C. Aerobic exercise effects upon cognition in Mild Cognitive Impairment: A systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Archives Italiennes de Biologie. 2017;155(1/2):55&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28715598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancela Carral J., Ay&#xe1;n P&#xe9;rez C. Effects of high-intensity combined training on women over 65. Gerontology. 2008;53(6):340&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17575465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll T.J., Riek S., Carson R.G. Neural adaptations to resistance training: implications for movement control. Sports Medicine. 2001;31:829&#x2013;840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11665911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carta M.G., Cossu G., Pintus E., Zaccheddu R., Callia O., Conti G., &#x2026;Mura G. Moderate exercise improves cognitive function in healthy elderly people: results of a randomized controlled trial. Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health: CP &amp; EMH. 2021;17:75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8493830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34733346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassilhas R.C., Lee K.S., Fernandes J., Oliveira M.G.M.d., Tufik S., Meeusen R., De Mello M. Spatial memory is improved by aerobic and resistance exercise through divergent molecular mechanisms. Neuroscience. 2012;202:309&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22155655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassilhas R.C., Viana V.A., Grassmann V., Santos R.T., Santos R.F., Tufik S., Mello M.T. The impact of resistance exercise on the cognitive function of the elderly. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2007;39(8):1401&#x2013;1407. doi: 10.1249/mss.0b013e318060111f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0b013e318060111f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalcante B.R., de Souza M.F., Falck R.S., Liu-Ambrose T., Behm D.G., Pitangui A.C.R., de Araujo R.C. Effects of resistance exercise with instability on cognitive function (REI Study): A proof-of-concept randomized controlled trial in older adults with cognitive complaints. Journal of Alzheimers Disease. 2020;77(1):227&#x2013;239. doi: 10.3233/jad-200349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/jad-200349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32804132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerrillo-Urbina A.J., Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A., S&#xe1;nchez-L&#xf3;pez M., Pardo-Guijarro M.J., Santos G&#xf3;mez J., Mart&#xed;nez-Vizca&#xed;no V. The effects of physical exercise in children with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized control trials. Child: Care, Health and Development. 2015;41(6):779&#x2013;788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25988743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Y.-K., Labban J.D., Gapin J.I., Etnier J.L. The effects of acute exercise on cognitive performance: a meta-analysis. Brain Research. 2012;1453:87&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22480735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Y.K., Etnier J.L. Effects of an acute bout of localized resistance exercise on cognitive performance in middle-aged adults: A randomized controlled trial study. Psychology of Sport and Exercise. 2009;10(1):19&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1016/j.psychsport.2008.05.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychsport.2008.05.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Y.K., Ku P.W., Tomporowski P.D., Chen F.T., Huang C.C. Effects of acute resistance exercise on late-middle-age adults' goal planning. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2012;44(9):1773&#x2013;1779. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3182574e0b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3182574e0b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22460477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Y.K., Pan C.Y., Chen F.T., Tsai C.L., Huang C.C. Effect of resistance-exercise training on cognitive function in healthy older adults: a review. Journal of Aging and Physical Activity. 2012;20(4):497&#x2013;517. doi: 10.1123/japa.20.4.497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/japa.20.4.497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22186664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F.-T., Etnier J.L., Chan K.-H., Chiu P.-K., Hung T.-M., Chang Y.-K. Effects of exercise training interventions on executive function in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Medicine. 2020;50(8):1451&#x2013;1467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7376513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32447717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow Z.-S., Moreland A.T., Macpherson H., Teo W.-P. The central mechanisms of resistance training and its effects on cognitive function. Sports Medicine. 2021;51(12):2483&#x2013;2506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34417978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciria L.F., Rom&#xe1;n-Caballero R., Vadillo M.A., Holgado D., Luque-Casado A., Perakakis P., Sanabria D. An umbrella review of randomized control trials on the effects of physical exercise on cognition. Nature Human Behaviour. 2023;7(6):928&#x2013;941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36973359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochran W.G. The combination of estimates from different experiments. Biometrics. 1954;10(1):101&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coelho-Junior H., Marzetti E., Calvani R., Picca A., Arai H., Uchida M. Resistance training improves cognitive function in older adults with different cognitive status: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Aging &amp; Mental Health. 2022;26(2):213&#x2013;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33325273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey V.G., Hawley J.A. Concurrent exercise training: do opposites distract? The Journal of Physiology. 2017;595(9):2883&#x2013;2896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27506998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colcombe S., Kramer A.F. Fitness effects on the cognitive function of older adults: a meta-analytic study. Psychological Science. 2003;14(2):125&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1111/1467-9280.t01-1-01430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1467-9280.t01-1-01430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12661673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costigan S.A., Eather N., Plotnikoff R.C., Hillman C.H., Lubans D.R. High-intensity interval training for cognitive and mental health in adolescents. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2016;48(10):1985&#x2013;1993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27187097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotman C.W., Berchtold N.C. Exercise: a behavioral intervention to enhance brain health and plasticity. Trends in Neurosciences. 2002;25(6):295&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12086747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silveira Langoni C., de Lima Resende T., Barcellos A.B., Cecchele B., Knob M.S., do Nascimento Silva T.&#x2026;Schwanke C.H.A. Effect of exercise on cognition, conditioning, muscle endurance, and balance in older adults with mild cognitive impairment: a randomized controlled trial. Journal of Geriatric Physical Therapy. 2019;42(2):E15&#x2013;E22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29738405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis C.L., Tomporowski P.D., Boyle C.A., Waller J.L., Miller P.H., Naglieri J.A., Gregoski M. Effects of aerobic exercise on overweight children's cognitive functioning: a randomized controlled trial. Research Quarterly for Exercise and Sport. 2007;78(5):510&#x2013;519. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2662758/pdf/nihms-88069.pdf</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2662758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18274222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Asteasu M.L.S., Martinez-Velilla N., Zambom-Ferraresi F., Casas-Herrero A., Izquierdo M. Role of physical exercise on cognitive function in healthy older adults: a systematic review of randomized clinical trials. Ageing Research Reviews. 2017;37:117&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28587957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira Silva F., Ferreira J.V., Pl&#xe1;cido J., Sant'Anna P., Ara&#xfa;jo J., Marinho V., &#x2026;Deslandes A.C. Three months of multimodal training contributes to mobility and executive function in elderly individuals with mild cognitive impairment, but not in those with Alzheimer's disease: a randomized controlled trial. Maturitas. 2019;126:28&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31239114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souto Barreto P., Cesari M., Denormandie P., Armaingaud D., Vellas B., Rolland Y. Exercise or social intervention for Nursing Home residents with dementia: A pilot randomized, controlled trial. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society. 2017;65(9):E123&#x2013;E129. doi: 10.1111/jgs.14947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgs.14947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28542742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deckers K., Zwan M.D., Soons L.M., Waterink L., Beers S., van Houdt S., &#x2026;consortium F.-N. A multidomain lifestyle intervention to maintain optimal cognitive functioning in Dutch older adults-study design and baseline characteristics of the FINGER-NL randomized controlled trial. Alzheimers Research &amp; Therapy. 2024;16(1):126. doi: 10.1186/s13195-024-01495-8. Article.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13195-024-01495-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11170777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38872204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diamond A., Lee K. Interventions shown to aid executive function development in children 4 to 12 years old. Science (New York, N.Y.) 2011;333(6045):959&#x2013;964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3159917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21852486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunsky A., Abu-Rukun M., Tsuk S., Dwolatzky T., Carasso R., Netz Y. The effects of a resistance vs. an aerobic single session on attention and executive functioning in adults. PloS one. 2017;12(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5404838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28441442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval S., Tweedie R. Trim and fill: a simple funnel-plot&#x2013;based method of testing and adjusting for publication bias in meta-analysis. Biometrics. 2000;56(2):455&#x2013;463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckardt N., Braun C., Kibele A. Instability resistance training improves working memory, processing speed and response inhibition in healthy older adults: A double-blinded randomized controlled trial. Scientific Reports. 2020;10(1):2506. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-59105-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-59105-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7018952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32054896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M., Smith G.D., Schneider M., Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ (Clinical research ed.) 1997;315(7109):629&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehlers D.K., Agui&#xf1;aga S., Cosman J., Severson J., Kramer A.F., McAuley E. The effects of physical activity and fatigue on cognitive performance in breast cancer survivors. Breast cancer Research and Treatment. 2017;165(3):699&#x2013;707. doi: 10.1007/s10549-017-4363-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10549-017-4363-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12257920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28677009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engeroff T., Niederer D., Vogt L., Banzer W. Intensity and workload related dose-response effects of acute resistance exercise on domain-specific cognitive function and affective response&#x2013;a four-armed randomized controlled crossover trial. Psychology of Sport and Exercise. 2019;43:55&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson K.I., Hillman C., Stillman C.M., Ballard R.M., Bloodgood B., Conroy D.E.&#x2026;Powell K.E. Physical activity, cognition, and brain outcomes: a review of the 2018 physical activity guidelines. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2019;51(6):1242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6527141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31095081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson K.I., Voss M.W., Prakash R.S., Basak C., Szabo A., Chaddock L.&#x2026;White S.M. Exercise training increases size of hippocampus and improves memory. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 2011;108(7):3017&#x2013;3022. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3041121/pdf/pnas.201015950.pdf</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3041121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21282661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espeland M.A., Lipska K., Miller M.E., Rushing J., Cohen R.A., Verghese J., &#x2026;Blair S.N. Effects of physical activity intervention on physical and cognitive function in sedentary adults with and without diabetes. Journals of Gerontology Series A: Biomedical Sciences and Medical Sciences. 2017;72(6):861&#x2013;866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6075086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27590629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firth J., Stubbs B., Rosenbaum S., Vancampfort D., Malchow B., Schuch F.&#x2026;Yung A.R. Aerobic exercise improves cognitive functioning in people with schizophrenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Schizophrenia Bulletin. 2017;43(3):546&#x2013;556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5464163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27521348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folstein M.F., Folstein S.E., McHugh P.R. Mini-mental state&#x201d;: a practical method for grading the cognitive state of patients for the clinician. Journal of psychiatric research. 1975;12(3):189&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1202204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonte C., Smania N., Pedrinolla A., Munari D., Gandolfi M., Picelli A., &#x2026;Venturelli M. Comparison between physical and cognitive treatment in patients with MCI and Alzheimer's disease. Aging. 2019;11(10):3138&#x2013;3155. doi: 10.18632/aging.101970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/aging.101970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6555450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31127076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe J.J., Bishop D.J., Stepto N.K. Interference between concurrent resistance and endurance exercise: molecular bases and the role of individual training variables. Sports Medicine. 2014;44:743&#x2013;762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24728927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallardo-G&#xf3;mez D., Del Pozo-Cruz J., Noetel M., &#xc1;lvarez-Barbosa F., Alfonso-Rosa R.M., Del Pozo Cruz B. Optimal dose and type of exercise to improve cognitive function in older adults: A systematic review and bayesian model-based network meta-analysis of RCTs. Ageing Research Eeviews. 2022;76 doi: 10.1016/j.arr.2022.101591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2022.101591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35182742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A., Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R., Ram&#xed;rez-Campillo R., Peterson M.D., Mart&#xed;nez-Vizca&#xed;no V. Concurrent aerobic plus resistance exercise versus aerobic exercise alone to improve health outcomes in paediatric obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. British Journal of Sports Medicine. 2018;52(3):161&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27986760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Soto E., Lopez de Munain M., Santib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez M. Effects of combined aerobic and resistance training on cognition following stroke: a systematic review. Revista de neurologia. 2013;57(12):535&#x2013;541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24288102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghodrati N., Haghighi A.H., Kakhak S.A.H., Abbasian S., Goldfield G.S. Effect of combined exercise training on physical and cognitive function in women with type 2 diabetes. Canadian journal of diabetes. 2023;47(2):162&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36572617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon B.R., McDowell C.P., Hallgren M., Meyer J.D., Lyons M., Herring M.P. Association of efficacy of resistance exercise training with depressive symptoms: meta-analysis and meta-regression analysis of randomized clinical trials. JAMA psychiatry. 2018;75(6):566&#x2013;576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6137526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29800984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group G.W. Grading quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ (Clinical research ed.) 2004;328(7454):1490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC428525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15205295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guadagni V., Drogos L.L., Tyndall A.V., Davenport M.H., Anderson T.J., Eskes G.A.&#x2026;Poulin M.J. Aerobic exercise improves cognition and cerebrovascular regulation in older adults. Neurology. 2020;94(21):e2245&#x2013;e2257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7357295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32404355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan Y., Yan Z. Molecular mechanisms of exercise and healthspan. Cells. 2022;11(5):872. https://mdpi-res.com/d_attachment/cells/cells-11-00872/article_deploy/cells-11-00872.pdf?version=1646295913</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8909156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35269492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hacker S., Banzer W., Vogt L., Engeroff T. Acute effects of aerobic exercise on cognitive attention and memory performance: an investigation on duration-based dose-response relations and the impact of increased arousal levels. Journal of clinical medicine. 2020;9(5):1380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7291087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32397081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han C.L., Sun W.S., Zhang D., Xi X.S., Zhang R., Gong W.J. Effects of different aerobic exercises on the global cognitive function of the elderly with mild cognitive impairment: a meta-analysis. BMJ open. 2023;13(6) doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2022-067293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2022-067293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10314475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37399446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harveson A.T., Hannon J.C., Brusseau T.A., Podlog L., Papadopoulos C., Durrant L.H.&#x2026;Kang K.D. Acute effects of 30 minutes resistance and aerobic exercise on cognition in a high school sample. Research quarterly for exercise and sport. 2016;87(2):214&#x2013;220. doi: 10.1080/02701367.2016.1146943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02701367.2016.1146943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26958898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haverkamp B.F., Wiersma R., Vertessen K., van Ewijk H., Oosterlaan J., Hartman E. Effects of physical activity interventions on cognitive outcomes and academic performance in adolescents and young adults: A meta-analysis. Journal of Sports Sciences. 2020;38(23):2637&#x2013;2660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32783695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges L.V., Olkin I. Academic press; 2014. Statistical methods for meta-analysis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henskens M., Nauta I.M., Van Eekeren M.C., Scherder E.J. Effects of physical activity in nursing home residents with dementia: a randomized controlled trial. Dementia and geriatric cognitive disorders. 2018;46(1-2):60&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6187838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30145595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hertzog C., Kramer A.F., Wilson R.S., Lindenberger U. Enrichment effects on adult cognitive development: can the functional capacity of older adults be preserved and enhanced? Psychological science in the public interest. 2008;9(1):1&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26162004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickson R.C. Interference of strength development by simultaneously training for strength and endurance. European journal of applied physiology and occupational physiology. 1980;45(2):255&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7193134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, J.P., &amp; Green, S. (2008). Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J.P., Thompson S.G. Quantifying heterogeneity in a meta-analysis. Statistics in medicine. 2002;21(11):1539&#x2013;1558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J.P., Thompson S.G., Deeks J.J., Altman D.G. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ (Clinical research ed.) 2003;327(7414):557&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillman C.H., Snook E.M., Jerome G.J. Acute cardiovascular exercise and executive control function. International Journal of psychophysiology. 2003;48(3):307&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12798990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X., Zhao X., Li B., Cai Y., Zhang S., Wan Q., Yu F. Comparative efficacy of various exercise interventions on cognitive function in patients with mild cognitive impairment or dementia: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Journal of sport and health science. 2022;11(2):212&#x2013;223. doi: 10.1016/j.jshs.2021.05.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2021.05.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9068743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34004389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huiberts R.O., W&#xfc;st R.C., van der Zwaard S. Concurrent strength and endurance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis on the impact of sex and training status. Sports Medicine. 2024;54(2):485&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10933151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37847373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung T.-M., Tsai C.-L., Chen F.-T., Wang C.-C., Chang Y.-K. The immediate and sustained effects of acute exercise on planning aspect of executive function. Psychology of Sport and Exercise. 2013;14(5):728&#x2013;736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iso-Markku P., Aaltonen S., Kujala U.M., Halme H.-L., Phipps D., Knittle K., &#x2026;Waller K. Physical activity and cognitive decline among older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA network open. 2024;7(2) -e2354285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10835510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38300618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia L., Du Y., Chu L., Zhang Z., Li F., Lyu D., &#x2026;Song Y. Prevalence, risk factors, and management of dementia and mild cognitive impairment in adults aged 60 years or older in China: a cross-sectional study. The Lancet public health. 2020;5(12):e661&#x2013;e671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33271079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahn E.B., Ramsey L.T., Brownson R.C., Heath G.W., Howze E.H., Powell K.E., &#x2026;Corso P. The effectiveness of interventions to increase physical activity: a systematic review. American Journal of Preventive Medicine. 2002;22(4):73&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11985936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaliman P., P&#xe1;rrizas M., Lalanza J.F., Camins A., Escorihuela R.M., Pallas M. Neurophysiological and epigenetic effects of physical exercise on the aging process. Ageing Research Reviews. 2011;10(4):475&#x2013;486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21624506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandola A., Ashdown-Franks G., Hendrikse J., Sabiston C.M., Stubbs B. Physical activity and depression: towards understanding the antidepressant mechanisms of physical activity. Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews. 2019;107:525&#x2013;539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31586447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S., Choi J.-Y., Moon S., Park D.-H., Kwak H.-B., Kang J.-H. Roles of myokines in exercise-induced improvement of neuropsychiatric function. Pfl&#xfc;gers Archiv-European Journal of Physiology. 2019;471:491&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30627775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer W.J., Ratamess N.A. Hormonal responses and adaptations to resistance exercise and training. Sports Medicine. 2005;35:339&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer A.F., Erickson K.I. Capitalizing on cortical plasticity: influence of physical activity on cognition and brain function. Trends in cognitive Sciences. 2007;11(8):342&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17629545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer A.F., Erickson K.I. Effects of physical activity on cognition, well-being, and brain: Human interventions. Alzheimer's &amp; Dementia. 2007;3(2):S45&#x2013;S51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19595974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K., Spitzer R.L., Williams J.B. The PHQ-9: validity of a brief depression severity measure. Journal of general internal medicine. 2001;16(9):606&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1495268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11556941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan Y., Huang Z., Jiang Y., Zhou X., Zhang J., Zhang D., &#x2026;Hou G. Strength exercise weakens aerobic exercise-induced cognitive improvements in rats. PloS one. 2018;13(10)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6179267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30304037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landrigan J.-F., Bell T., Crowe M., Clay O.J., Mirman D. Lifting cognition: a meta-analysis of effects of resistance exercise on cognition. Psychological Research. 2020;84(5):1167&#x2013;1183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30627769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang J.W., Kersting M., H&#xfc;lsheger U.R., Lang J. General mental ability, narrower cognitive abilities, and job performance: the perspective of the nested-factors model of cognitive abilities. Personnel psychology. 2010;63(3):595&#x2013;640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langlois F., Vu T.T.M., Chass&#xe9; K., Dupuis G., Kergoat M.-J., Bherer L. Benefits of physical exercise training on cognition and quality of life in frail older adults. Journals of Gerontology Series B: Psychological Sciences and Social Sciences. 2013;68(3):400&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22929394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson E.B., Bruce R.A. Health benefits of exercise in an aging society. Archives of internal medicine. 1987;147(2):353&#x2013;356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3545119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lautenschlager N.T., Cox K.L., Flicker L., Foster J.K., Van Bockxmeer F.M., Xiao J., &#x2026;Almeida O.P. Effect of physical activity on cognitive function in older adults at risk for Alzheimer disease: a randomized trial. JAMA. 2008;300(9):1027&#x2013;1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18768414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leach H.J., Danyluk J.M., Nishimura K.C., Culos-Reed S.N. Benefits of 24 versus 12 weeks of exercise and wellness programming for women undergoing treatment for breast cancer. Supportive Care in Cancer. 2016;24:4597&#x2013;4606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27312845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang J., Wang H., Zeng Y., Qu Y., Liu Q., Zhao F., &#x2026;Ying J. Physical exercise promotes brain remodeling by regulating epigenetics, neuroplasticity and neurotrophins. Reviews in the Neurosciences. 2021;32(6):615&#x2013;629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33583156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberati A., Altman D.G., Tetzlaff J., Mulrow C., G&#xf8;tzsche P.C., Ioannidis J.P., &#x2026;Moher D. The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate health care interventions: explanation and elaboration. Annals of internal medicine. 2009;151(4):W&#x2013;65. -W-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu-Ambrose T., Nagamatsu L.S., Graf P., Beattie B.L., Ashe M.C., Handy T.C. Resistance training and executive functions: a 12-month randomized controlled trial. Archives of internal medicine. 2010;170(2):170&#x2013;178. doi: 10.1001/archinternmed.2009.494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinternmed.2009.494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3448565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20101012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Ortiz S., Valenzuela P.L., Seisdedos M.M., Morales J.S., Vega T., Castillo-Garcia A., &#x2026;Santos-Lozano A. Exercise interventions in Alzheimer's disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials [Review] Ageing Research Reviews. 2021;72 doi: 10.1016/j.arr.2021.101479. Article.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2021.101479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34601135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu T. Effects of aerobic combined resistance and balance exercise on cognitive function in patients with non-dementia cognitive impairment after stroke. Medical Journal of Chinese People's Health. 2016;28(16):68&#x2013;69. https://kns.cnki.net/kcms2/article/abstract?v=aKxFI3wG76iykMluA3_-qijXtGTPYUMVflH3VjSVjwCQIY4TshOjvbfB6QiDLQcYYFoI8IkvxLYQ7eIBJQqgaFzY78kQ0L8Aa1HtkRU6kUvAhHR4Oc1dcgfYFuljTpbBB6A4f4-OkapQnjG1D1GhM_3q46ZQX4EYEdmrN56DZdTH1DsNDqLbSqeKUu5H2jMH4xrsPRv52K8=&amp;uniplatform=NZKPT&amp;language=CHS</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludyga S., Gerber M., Herrmann C., Brand S., P&#xfc;hse U. Chronic effects of exercise implemented during school-break time on neurophysiological indices of inhibitory control in adolescents. Trends in Neuroscience and Education. 2018;10:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludyga S., Gerber M., Kamijo K. Exercise types and working memory components during development. Trends in cognitive Sciences. 2022;26(3):191&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35031211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludyga S., Gerber M., P&#xfc;hse U., Looser V.N., Kamijo K. Systematic review and meta-analysis investigating moderators of long-term effects of exercise on cognition in healthy individuals. Nature human behaviour. 2020;4(6):603&#x2013;612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32231280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg T.R., Feuerbacher J.F., S&#xfc;nkeler M., Schumann M. The effects of concurrent aerobic and strength training on muscle fiber hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Medicine. 2022;52(10):2391&#x2013;2403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9474354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35476184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makino T., Umegaki H., Ando M., Cheng X.W., Ishida K., Akima H., &#x2026;Kuzuya M. Effects of aerobic, resistance, or combined exercise training among older adults with subjective memory complaints: A randomized controlled trial. Journal of Alzheimers Disease. 2021;82(2):701&#x2013;717. doi: 10.3233/jad-210047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/jad-210047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34092635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Velilla N., Valenzuela P.L., S&#xe1;ez de Asteasu M.L., Zambom-Ferraresi F., Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R., Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A., &#x2026;Lucia A. Effects of a tailored exercise intervention in acutely hospitalized oldest old diabetic adults: an ancillary analysis. The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp; Metabolism. 2021;106(2):e899&#x2013;e906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33150389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzolini S., Oh P., McIlroy W., Brooks D. The effects of an aerobic and resistance exercise training program on cognition following stroke. Neurorehabilitation and neural repair. 2013;27(5):392&#x2013;402. doi: 10.1177/1545968312465192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1545968312465192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23161865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavros Y., Gates N., Wilson G.C., Jain N., Meiklejohn J., Brodaty H.&#x2026;Fiatarone Singh M.A. Mediation of cognitive function improvements by strength gains after resistance training in older adults with mild cognitive impairment: outcomes of the study of mental and resistance training. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society. 2017;65(3):550&#x2013;559. doi: 10.1111/jgs.14542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgs.14542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28304092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McArdle W.D., Katch F.I., Katch V.L. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2010. Exercise physiology: nutrition, energy, and human performance.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuley E., Rudolph D. Physical activity, aging, and psychological well-being. Journal of Aging and Physical Activity. 1995;3(1):67&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCartney D., Desbrow B., Irwin C. Cognitive effects of acute aerobic exercise: exploring the influence of exercise duration, exhaustion, task complexity and expectancies in endurance-trained individuals. Journal of sports sciences. 2021;39(2):183&#x2013;191. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2020.1809976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2020.1809976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32822260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrae R.R., Sutin A.R. A five&#x2013;factor theory perspective on causal analysis. European journal of personality. 2018;32(3):151&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6101665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30140117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonnell M.N., Smith A.E., Mackintosh S.F. Aerobic exercise to improve cognitive function in adults with neurological disorders: a systematic review. Archives of physical medicine and rehabilitation. 2011;92(7):1044&#x2013;1052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21704783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuinness L.A., Higgins J.P.T. Risk-of-bias VISualization (robvis): an R package and shiny web app for visualizing risk-of-bias assessments. Research Synthesis Methods. 2020;n/a(n/a) doi: 10.1002/jrsm.1411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jrsm.1411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32336025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris T. Cognitive fatigue effects on physical performance: the role of interoception. Sports Medicine. 2020;50(10):1703&#x2013;1708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32661840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris T., Sproule J., Turner A., Hale B.J. Acute, intermediate intensity exercise, and speed and accuracy in working memory tasks: a meta-analytical comparison of effects. Physiology &amp; behavior. 2011;102(3-4):421&#x2013;428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21163278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNerney M.W., Radvansky G.A. Mind racing: the influence of exercise on long-term memory consolidation. Memory (Hove, England) 2015;23(8):1140&#x2013;1151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25312348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meijer A., K&#xf6;nigs M., van der Fels I.M., Visscher C., Bosker R.J., Hartman E., Oosterlaan J. The effects of aerobic versus cognitively demanding exercise interventions on executive functioning in school-aged children: A cluster-randomized controlled trial. Journal of Sport and Exercise Psychology. 2020;43(1):1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33271498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mungu&#xed;a-Izquierdo D., Legaz-Arrese A. Assessment of the effects of aquatic therapy on global symptomatology in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome: a randomized controlled trial. Archives of physical medicine and rehabilitation. 2008;89(12):2250&#x2013;2257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19061736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagamatsu L.S., Handy T.C., Hsu C.L., Voss M., Liu-Ambrose T. Resistance training promotes cognitive and functional brain plasticity in seniors with probable mild cognitive impairment. Archives of internal medicine. 2012;172(8):666&#x2013;668. doi: 10.1001/archinternmed.2012.379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinternmed.2012.379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3514552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22529236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Napoli N., Shah K., Waters D.L., Sinacore D.R., Qualls C., Villareal D.T. Effect of weight loss, exercise, or both on cognition and quality of life in obese older adults. The American journal of clinical nutrition. 2014;100(1):189&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4144098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24787497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine Z.S., Phillips N.A., B&#xe9;dirian V., Charbonneau S., Whitehead V., Collin I., &#x2026;Chertkow H. The Montreal Cognitive Assessment, MoCA: a brief screening tool for mild cognitive impairment. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society. 2005;53(4):695&#x2013;699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Netz Y. Is there a preferred mode of exercise for cognition enhancement in older age?&#x2014;A narrative review. Frontiers in Medicine. 2019;6:57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30984760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Netz Y., Tomer R., Axelrad S., Argov E., Inbar O. The effect of a single aerobic training session on cognitive flexibility in late middle-aged adults. International Journal of Sports Medicine. 2007;28(01):82&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17213965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishiguchi S., Yamada M., Tanigawa T., Sekiyama K., Kawagoe T., Suzuki M., &#x2026;Tsuboyama T. A 12-week physical and cognitive exercise program can improve cognitive function and neural efficiency in community-dwelling older adults: A randomized controlled trial. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society. 2015;63(7):1355&#x2013;1363. doi: 10.1111/jgs.13481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgs.13481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26114906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Northey J.M., Cherbuin N., Pumpa K.L., Smee D.J., Rattray B. Exercise interventions for cognitive function in adults older than 50: a systematic review with meta-analysis. British journal of sports Medicine. 2018;52(3):154&#x2013;160. https://bjsm.bmj.com/content/bjsports/52/3/154.full.pdf</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28438770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton K., Norton L., Sadgrove D. Position statement on physical activity and exercise intensity terminology. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport. 2010;13(5):496&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20005170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nouchi R., Kawashima R. Improving cognitive function from children to old age: a systematic review of recent smart ageing intervention studies. Advances in Neuroscience. 2014;2014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuechterlein K., McEwen S., Ventura J., Subotnik K., Turner L., Boucher M., &#x2026;Hayata J. Aerobic exercise enhances cognitive training effects in first episode schizophrenia: cognitive and functional gains and promising biological mechanisms of action. Schizophrenia Bulletin. 2018;44(suppl_1):S18. doi: 10.1093/schbul/sby014.042. -S18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/schbul/sby014.042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10388302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36047035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuechterlein K.H., McEwen S.C., Ventura J., Subotnik K.L., Turner L.R., Boucher M.&#x2026;Hayata J.N. Aerobic exercise enhances cognitive training effects in first-episode schizophrenia: randomized clinical trial demonstrates cognitive and functional gains. Psychological medicine. 2023;53(10):4751&#x2013;4761. doi: 10.1017/S0033291722001696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291722001696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10388302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36047035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okumiya K., Matsubayashi K., Wada T., Kimura S., Doi Y., Ozawa T. Effects of exercise on neurobehavioral function in community-dwelling older people more than 75 years of age. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society. 1996;44(5):569&#x2013;572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8617907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opdebeeck C., Martyr A., Clare L. Cognitive reserve and cognitive function in healthy older people: a meta-analysis. Aging, Neuropsychology, and Cognition. 2016;23(1):40&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25929288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization, W.H. (2015). World Report on ageing and Health.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization, W.H. (2021). Global status report on the public health response to dementia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paillard T. Preventive effects of regular physical exercise against cognitive decline and the risk of dementia with age advancement. Sports Medicine-Open. 2015;1:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5005681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26284161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pajonk F.-G., Wobrock T., Gruber O., Scherk H., Berner D., Kaizl I., &#x2026;Meyer T. Hippocampal plasticity in response to exercise in schizophrenia. Archives of General Psychiatry. 2010;67(2):133&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20124113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papatsimpas V., Vrouva S., Papadopoulou M., Papathanasiou G., Bakalidou D. The effects of aerobic and resistance exercises on the cognitive and physical function of persons with mild dementia: A randomized controlled trial protocol. Healthcare. 2023;11(5):677. doi: 10.3390/healthcare11050677. Article.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11050677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10000686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36900682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson D.H., Warburton D.E. Physical activity and functional limitations in older adults: a systematic review related to Canada's Physical Activity Guidelines. International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity. 2010;7:1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2882898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20459782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penedo F.J., Dahn J.R. Exercise and well-being: a review of mental and physical health benefits associated with physical activity. Current Opinion in Psychiatry. 2005;18(2):189&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16639173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng J., Deng X., Huang W., Yu J.-h., Wang J.-x., Wang J.-p., &#x2026;Zhang Y. Irisin protects against neuronal injury induced by oxygen-glucose deprivation in part depends on the inhibition of ROS-NLRP3 inflammatory signaling pathway. Molecular Immunology. 2017;91:185&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28961497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira A.C., Huddleston D.E., Brickman A.M., Sosunov A.A., Hen R., McKhann G.M.&#x2026;Small S.A. An in vivo correlate of exercise-induced neurogenesis in the adult dentate gyrus. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 2007;104(13):5638&#x2013;5643. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1838482/pdf/zpq5638.pdf</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1838482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17374720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piercy K.L., Troiano R.P., Ballard R.M., Carlson S.A., Fulton J.E., Galuska D.A., &#x2026;Olson R.D. The physical activity guidelines for Americans. JAMA. 2018;320(19):2020&#x2013;2028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9582631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30418471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pontifex M.B., Hillman C.H., Fernhall B., Thompson K.M., Valentini T.A. The effect of acute aerobic and resistance exercise on working memory. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2009;41(4):927&#x2013;934. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181907d69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181907d69</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19276839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess N. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2021. ACSM's foundations of strength training and conditioning.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren F.-F., Hillman C.H., Wang W.-G., Li R.-H., Zhou W.-S., Liang W.-M., &#x2026;Chang Y.-K. Effects of aerobic exercise on cognitive function in adults with major depressive disorder: A systematic review and meta-analysis. International Journal of Clinical and Health Psychology. 2024;24(2) doi: 10.1016/j.ijchp.2024.100447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijchp.2024.100447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10869919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38371396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren F.F., Alderman B.L., Wang W.G., Chen F.T., Zhou W.S., Zong W.J.&#x2026;Chang Y.K. Effects of exercise training on executive functioning in adults with depression: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Sports Medicine (Auckland, N.Z.) 2023;53(9):1765&#x2013;1788. doi: 10.1007/s40279-023-01869-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01869-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37369934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson K., Riley N., Owen K., Drew R., Mavilidi M.F., Hillman C.H.&#x2026;Lubans D.R. Effects of resistance training on academic outcomes in school-aged youth: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Medicine. 2023:1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10587249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37466900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohde T.E., Thompson L.A. Predicting academic achievement with cognitive ability. Intelligence. 2007;35(1):83&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romberg A., Virtanen A., Ruutiainen J. Long&#x2013;term exercise improves functional impairment but not quality of life in multiple sclerosis. Journal of Neurology. 2005;252:839&#x2013;845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15765197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowe J.W., Kahn R.L. Successful aging. The Gerontologist. 1997;37(4):433&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9279031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz J.R., Gil-Bea F., Bustamante-Ara N., Rodr&#xed;guez-Romo G., Fiuza-Luces C., Serra-Rexach J.A., &#x2026;Lucia A. Resistance training does not have an effect on cognition or related serum biomarkers in nonagenarians: A randomized controlled trial. International Journal of Sports Medicine. 2015;36(1):54&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1055/s-0034-1375693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0034-1375693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25329433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz J.R., Gil-Bea F., Bustamante-Ara N., Rodr&#xed;guez-Romo G., Fiuza-Luces C., Serra-Rexach J.A., &#x2026;Lucia A. Resistance training does not have an effect on cognition or related serum biomarkers in nonagenarians: a randomized controlled trial. International Journal of Sports Medicine. 2015;36(01):54&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25329433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandroff B.M., Hillman C.H., Benedict R.H., Motl R.W. Acute effects of walking, cycling, and yoga exercise on cognition in persons with relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis without impaired cognitive processing speed. Journal of Clinical and Experimental Neuropsychology. 2015;37(2):209&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25658772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuch F.B., Vancampfort D., Richards J., Rosenbaum S., Ward P.B., Stubbs B. Exercise as a treatment for depression: a meta-analysis adjusting for publication bias. Journal of Psychiatric Research. 2016;77:42&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26978184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuch F.B., Vancampfort D., Sui X., Rosenbaum S., Firth J., Richards J., &#x2026;Stubbs B. Are lower levels of cardiorespiratory fitness associated with incident depression? A systematic review of prospective cohort studies. Preventive medicine. 2016;93:159&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27765659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segabinazi E., Gasperini N.F., Faustino A.M., Centeno R., Dos Santos A., Almeida W.d.&#x2026;Pereira L. Comparative overview of the effects of aerobic and resistance exercise on anxiety-like behavior, cognitive flexibility, and hippocampal synaptic plasticity parameters in healthy rats. Brazilian Journal of Medical and Biological Research. 2020;53:e9816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7561075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33053097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimada H., Makizako H., Doi T., Park H., Tsutsumimoto K., Verghese J., Suzuki T. Effects of combined physical and cognitive exercises on cognition and mobility in patients with mild cognitive impairment: a randomized clinical trial. Journal of the American Medical Directors Association. 2018;19(7):584&#x2013;591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29153754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva N.C.B.S., Barha C.K., Erickson K.I., Kramer A.F., Liu-Ambrose T. Physical exercise, cognition, and brain health in aging. Trends in Neurosciences. 2024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38811309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sink K.M., Espeland M.A., Castro C.M., Church T., Cohen R., Dodson J.A., &#x2026;Katula J. Effect of a 24-month physical activity intervention vs health education on cognitive outcomes in sedentary older adults: the LIFE randomized trial. JAMA. 2015;314(8):781&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4698980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26305648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smiley-Oyen A.L., Lowry K.A., Francois S.J., Kohut M.L., Ekkekakis P. Exercise, fitness, and neurocognitive function in older adults: the &#x201c;selective improvement&#x201d; and &#x201c;cardiovascular fitness&#x201d; hypotheses. Annals of Behavioral Medicine. 2008;36(3):280&#x2013;291. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2748860/pdf/nihms-123440.pdf</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2748860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18825471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song D., Doris S., Li P.W., Lei Y. The effectiveness of physical exercise on cognitive and psychological outcomes in individuals with mild cognitive impairment: a systematic review and meta-analysis. International Journal of Nursing Studies. 2018;79:155&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29334638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stern Y. What is cognitive reserve? Theory and research application of the reserve concept. Journal of the International Neuropsychological Society. 2002;8(3):448&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11939702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stern Y., MacKay-Brandt A., Lee S., McKinley P., McIntyre K., Razlighi Q., &#x2026;Sloan R.P. Effect of aerobic exercise on cognition in younger adults: A randomized clinical trial. Neurology. 2019;92(9):e905&#x2013;e916. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6404470/pdf/NEUROLOGY2018917856.pdf</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6404470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30700591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stillman C.M., Esteban-Cornejo I., Brown B., Bender C.M., Erickson K.I. Effects of exercise on brain and cognition across age groups and health states. Trends in Neurosciences. 2020;43(7):533&#x2013;543. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC9068803/pdf/nihms-1589483.pdf</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9068803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32409017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stringhini S., Carmeli C., Jokela M., Avenda&#xf1;o M., Muennig P., Guida F., &#x2026;Bochud M. Socioeconomic status and the 25 &#xd7; 25 risk factors as determinants of premature mortality: a multicohort study and meta-analysis of 1&#xb7; 7 million men and women. The Lancet. 2017;389(10075):1229&#x2013;1237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5368415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28159391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stroth S., Hille K., Spitzer M., Reinhardt R. Aerobic endurance exercise benefits memory and affect in young adults. Neuropsychological Rehabilitation. 2009;19(2):223&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18609015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sujkowski A., Hong L., Wessells R., Todi S.V. The protective role of exercise against age-related neurodegeneration. Ageing Research Reviews. 2022;74</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8761166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34923167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun T., Wang Y., Hui D., Jing X., Feng W. Vertical distributions of soil microbial biomass carbon: a global dataset. Data in brief. 2020;32</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7452705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32904338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki T., Shimada H., Makizako H., Doi T., Yoshida D., Ito K., &#x2026;Kato T. A randomized controlled trial of multicomponent exercise in older adults with mild cognitive impairment. PloS one. 2013;8(4):e61483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3621765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23585901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarazona-Santabalbina F.J., G&#xf3;mez-Cabrera M.C., P&#xe9;rez-Ros P., Mart&#xed;nez-Arnau F.M., Cabo H., Tsaparas K., &#x2026;Vi&#xf1;a J. A multicomponent exercise intervention that reverses frailty and improves cognition, emotion, and social networking in the community-dwelling frail elderly: a randomized clinical trial. Journal of the American Medical Directors Association. 2016;17(5):426&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26947059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tari A.R., Norevik C.S., Scrimgeour N.R., Kobro-Flatmoen A., Storm-Mathisen J., Bergersen L.H., &#x2026;Wisl&#xf8;ff U. Are the neuroprotective effects of exercise training systemically mediated? Progress in Cardiovascular Diseases. 2019;62(2):94&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1016/j.pcad.2019.02.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pcad.2019.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30802460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira P.J., Carra&#xe7;a E.V., Markland D., Silva M.N., Ryan R.M. Exercise, physical activity, and self-determination theory: a systematic review. International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity. 2012;9:1&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3441783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22726453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaiyanto J., Sittichoke C., Phirom K., Sungkarat S. Effects of multicomponent exercise on cognitive performance and fall risk in older women with mild cognitive impairment. The Journal of Nutrition, Health and Aging. 2021;25(2):160&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33491029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmons J.F., Minnock D., Hone M., Cogan K.E., Murphy J.C., Egan B. Comparison of time-matched aerobic, resistance, or concurrent exercise training in older adults. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports. 2018;28(11):2272&#x2013;2283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29947107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomporowski P.D., Pesce C. Exercise, sports, and performance arts benefit cognition via a common process. Psychological Bulletin. 2019;145(9):929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31192623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai C.-L., Chen F.-C., Pan C.-Y., Wang C.-H., Huang T.-H., Chen T.-C. Impact of acute aerobic exercise and cardiorespiratory fitness on visuospatial attention performance and serum BDNF levels. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2014;41:121&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24495613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai C.-L., Pai M.-C., Ukropec J., Ukropcov&#xe1; B. Distinctive effects of aerobic and resistance exercise modes on neurocognitive and biochemical changes in individuals with mild cognitive impairment. Current Alzheimer Research. 2019;16(4):316&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30819077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turrini S., Wong B., Eldaief M., Press D., Sinclair D.A., Koch G., &#x2026;Santarnecchi E. The multifactorial nature of healthy brain ageing: brain changes, functional decline and protective factors. Ageing Research Reviews. 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37116664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W. Bias and efficiency of meta-analytic variance estimators in the random-effects model. Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics. 2005;30(3):261&#x2013;293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W. Conducting meta-analyses in R with the metafor package. Journal of Statistical Software. 2010;36 doi: 10.18637/jss.v036.i03.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v036.i03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voelcker-Rehage C., Niemann C. Structural and functional brain changes related to different types of physical activity across the life span. Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews. 2013;37(9):2268&#x2013;2295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23399048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voss M.W., Vivar C., Kramer A.F., van Praag H. Bridging animal and human models of exercise-induced brain plasticity. Trends in Cognitive Sciences. 2013;17(10):525&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4565723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24029446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vreugdenhil A., Cannell J., Davies A., Razay G. A community-based exercise programme to improve functional ability in people with Alzheimer's disease: A randomized controlled trial. Scandinavian Journal of Caring Sciences. 2012;26(1):12&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21564154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadsworth D.D., Rodriguez-Hernandez M., Huffman L.S., McDonald J.R., Spring K.E., Pascoe D.D. Adaptations to a concurrent exercise training program in inactive aging women. The Journal of Strength &amp; Conditioning Research. 2022;36(11):3217&#x2013;3223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36165989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welsh J.A., Nix R.L., Blair C., Bierman K.L., Nelson K.E. The development of cognitive skills and gains in academic school readiness for children from low-income families. Journal of Educational Psychology. 2010;102(1):43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2856933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20411025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitfield S., Hofmann M.A. Elicit: AI literature review research assistant. Public Services Quarterly. 2023;19(3):201&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilke J., Stricker V., Usedly S. Free-weight resistance exercise is more effective in enhancing inhibitory control than machine-based training: A randomized, controlled trial. Brain Sciences. 2020;10(10):702. doi: 10.3390/brainsci10100702. Article.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci10100702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7599796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33022911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson J.D., Espeland M., Kritchevsky S.B., Newman A.B., King A.C., Pahor M.&#x2026;Investigators L.S. Changes in cognitive function in a randomized trial of physical activity: results of the lifestyle interventions and independence for elders pilot study. Journals of Gerontology Series A: Biomedical Sciences and Medical Sciences. 2009;64(6):688&#x2013;694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2679423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19244157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu M., Zhu J., Liu X.-D., Luo M.-Y., Xu N.-J. Roles of physical exercise in neurodegeneration: reversal of epigenetic clock. Translational Neurodegeneration. 2021;10(1):30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8361623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34389067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young J., Angevaren M., Rusted J., Tabet N. Aerobic exercise to improve cognitive function in older people without known cognitive impairment. The Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews. 2015;2015(4) doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD005381.pub4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD005381.pub4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10554155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25900537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M., Jia J., Yang Y., Zhang L., Wang X. Effects of exercise interventions on cognitive functions in healthy populations: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Ageing Research Reviews. 2023;92 doi: 10.1016/j.arr.2023.102116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2023.102116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37924980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S., Zhen K., Su Q., Chen Y., Lv Y., Yu L. The effect of aerobic exercise on cognitive function in people with Alzheimer's disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2022;19(23):15700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9736612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36497772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhidong C., Wang X., Yin J., Song D., Chen Z. Effects of physical exercise on working memory in older adults: a systematic and meta-analytic review. European Review of Aging and Physical Activity. 2021;18:1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8447686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34535084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman B., Sutton B.P., Low K.A., Fletcher M.A., Tan C.H., Schneider-Garces N., &#x2026;Gratton G. Cardiorespiratory fitness mediates the effects of aging on cerebral blood flow. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience. 2014;6:59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3985032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24778617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou L., Herold F., Cheval B., Wheeler M.J., Pindus D.M., Erickson K.I., &#x2026;Owen N. Sedentary behavior and lifespan brain health. Trends in cognitive sciences. 2024;28(4):369&#x2013;382. doi: 10.1016/j.tics.2024.02.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tics.2024.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11778811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38431428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>