<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37483773</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2405-8440</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Heliyon</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Heliyon</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The preconditioning effect of different exercise training modes on middle cerebral artery occlusion induced-behavioral deficit in senescent rats.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e17992</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e17992</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e17992</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e17992</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Brain abilities decrease after brain stroke in elderly. The neuroprotective effect of exercise training has been proved in clinical trials and animal experiment. Nevertheless, it is not still clear what kind of exercise has greater protective effect. The present study aimed at investigating pre-conditioning effect of endurance, resistance, and concurrent training on learning ability, anxiety, and spatial memory in aged rats following stroke strength with middle cerebral artery occlusion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We used 50 male Wistar rats (age&#xa0;=&#xa0;24 months) that were assigned randomly in five groups; 1: sham group, 2: Control group 3: Endurance training 4: Resistance training, and 5: concurrent training. The exercise training groups received training for four weeks. Following training, middle cerebral artery occlusion was applied to induce cerebral ischemia. Using the elevated plus maze, shuttle box test, and Morris water maze, neurocognitive functions were tested in the sample rats.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">It was found that resistance training did not affect spatial memory in the acquisition phase, while concurrent training and endurance training enhanced spatial memory in the acquisition phase. On the contrary, spatial memory was improved by resistance training in the retention phase, while concurrent and endurance exercises did not affect spatial memory in the retention phase. Passive avoidance learning ability at acquisition phase was more in resistance group compared to the endurance and concurrent training in shuttle box test, but in retention phase was similar between training groups. Unlike endurance and concurrent training, resistance training reduced anxiety in senescent rats.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">All three exercise types alleviated aversive learning and memory impairment induced by stroke in senescent rats. Notably, the resistance training showed a greater protective effect compared to the other two training methods.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zarrinkalam</LastName><ForeName>Ebrahim</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Hamedan Branch, Islamic Azad University, Hamedan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arabi</LastName><ForeName>Seyedeh Manizheh</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Motor Behavior, Faculty of Sports Sciences, Bu-Ali Sina University, Hamedan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Komaki</LastName><ForeName>Alireza</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurophysiology Research Center, Hamadan University of Medical Sciences, Hamadan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ranjbar</LastName><ForeName>Kamal</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Science, Bandar Abbas Branch, Islamic Azad University, Bandar Abbas, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Heliyon</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101672560</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2405-8440</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Concurrent training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elevated plus maze</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endurance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Middle cerebral artery occlusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Morris water maze</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Old rat</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Shuttle box</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37483773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10362108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e17992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2405-8440(23)05200-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sudlow C., Warlow C. Comparable studies of the incidence of stroke and its pathological types: results from an international collaboration. Stroke. 1997;28(3):491&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9056601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go A.S., et al. Heart disease and stroke statistics&#x2014;2013 update: a report from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2013;127(1):e6&#x2013;e245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5408511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23239837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rostami E., et al. Early low cerebral blood flow and high cerebral lactate: prediction of delayed cerebral ischemia in subarachnoid hemorrhage. J. Neurosurg. 2017;128(6):1762&#x2013;1770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28574309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y., et al. Exercise preconditioning ameliorates cognitive impairment and anxiety-like behavior via regulation of dopamine in ischemia rats. Physiol. Behav. 2021;233</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33571546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x105;browska-Bender M., et al. The impact of ischemic cerebral stroke on the quality of life of patients based on clinical, social, and psychoemotional factors. J. Stroke Cerebrovasc. Dis. 2017;26(1):101&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27746082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker-Collo S., Feigin V. The impact of neuropsychological deficits on functional stroke outcomes. Neuropsychol. Rev. 2006;16(2):53&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16967344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astr&#xf6;m M., Adolfsson R., Asplund K. Major depression in stroke patients. A 3-year longitudinal study. Stroke. 1993;24(7):976&#x2013;982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8322398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eastwood M., et al. Mood disorder following cerebrovascular accident. Br. J. Psychiatr. 1989;154(2):195&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2528388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson R.G., Bolduc P.L., Price T.R. Two-year longitudinal study of poststroke mood disorders: diagnosis and outcome at one and two years. Stroke. 1987;18(5):837&#x2013;843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3629640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rost N.S., et al. Stroke severity is a crucial predictor of outcome: an international prospective validation study. J. Am. Heart Assoc. 2016;5(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4859362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26796252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu F.B., et al. Physical activity and risk of stroke in women. JAMA. 2000;283(22):2961&#x2013;2967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10865274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee I.-M., et al. Exercise and risk of stroke in male physicians. Stroke. 1999;30(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9880379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellekj&#xe6;r H., et al. Physical activity and stroke mortality in women: ten-year follow-up of the Nord-Tr&#xf8;ndelag health survey, 1984&#x2013;1986. Stroke. 2000;31(1):14&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10625709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wannamethee S.G., Shaper A.G. Physical activity in the prevention of cardiovascular disease. Sports Med. 2001;31(2):101&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11227978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F., Wu Y., Jia J. Exercise preconditioning and brain ischemic tolerance. Neuroscience. 2011;177:170&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21241780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gertz K., et al. Physical activity improves long-term stroke outcome via endothelial nitric oxide synthase&#x2013;dependent augmentation of neovascularization and cerebral blood flow. Circ. Res. 2006;99(10):1132&#x2013;1140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17038638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng W., et al. Exercise preconditioning reduces brain damage and accelerates physical rehabilitation in rats with cerebral ischemia: 296 board# 134 may 29 11: 00 AM-12: 30 pm. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2019;51(6S):72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamsaei N., et al. Neuroprotective effects of exercise on brain edema and neurological movement disorders following the cerebral ischemia and reperfusion in rats. Basic Clin. Neurosci. 2017;8(1):77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5395689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28446953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan K.J., et al. Exercise reduces infarct volume and facilitates neurobehavioral recovery: results from a systematic review and meta-analysis of exercise in experimental models of focal ischemia. Neurorehabilitation Neural Repair. 2014;28(8):800&#x2013;812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24553105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endres M., et al. Mechanisms of stroke protection by physical activity. Ann. Neurol.: Off. J. Am. Neurol. Assoc. Child Neurol. Soc. 2003;54(5):582&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14595647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Z., et al. Treadmill pre-training ameliorates brain edema in ischemic stroke via down-regulation of aquaporin-4: an MRI study in rats. PLoS One. 2014;9(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3886991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24416250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng R., et al. Pre-ischemic exercise alleviates oxidative damage following ischemic stroke in rats. Exp. Ther. Med. 2014;8(4):1325&#x2013;1329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4151673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25187848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bovim M.R., et al. 2019. Relationship between Pre-stroke Physical Activity and Symptoms of Post-stroke Anxiety and Depression: an Observational Study.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31565752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khabour O.F., et al. Changes in spatial memory and BDNF expression to concurrent dietary restriction and voluntary exercise. Hippocampus. 2010;20(5):637&#x2013;645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19530223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassilhas R.C., et al. Spatial memory is improved by aerobic and resistance exercise through divergent molecular mechanisms. Neuroscience. 2012;202:309&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22155655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarrinkalam E., et al. Effects of endurance, resistance, and concurrent exercise on learning and memory after morphine withdrawal in rats. Life Sci. 2016;157:19&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27234896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engel O., et al. Modeling stroke in mice-middle cerebral artery occlusion with the filament model. JoVE. 2011;(47):e2423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3182649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21248698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarrinkalam E., et al. Resistance training and hawthorn extract ameliorate cognitive deficits in streptozotocin-induced diabetic rats. Biomed. Pharmacother. 2018;97:503&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29091901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pin-Barre C., Laurin J. Physical exercise as a diagnostic, rehabilitation, and preventive tool: influence on neuroplasticity and motor recovery after stroke. Neural Plast. 2015;2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4670869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26682073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terashi T., et al. Neuroprotective effects of different frequency preconditioning exercise on neuronal apoptosis after focal brain ischemia in rats. Neurol. Res. 2019;41(6):510&#x2013;518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30822224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J., et al. Lasting spatial learning and memory deficits following chronic cerebral hypoperfusion are associated with hippocampal mitochondrial aging in rats. Neuroscience. 2019;415:215&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31055006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goo M.-J., et al. Protective effects of acetyl-L-carnitine on neurodegenarative changes in chronic cerebral ischemia models and learning-memory impairment in aged rats. Arch Pharm. Res. (Seoul) 2012;35(1):145&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22297753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchill J.D., et al. Exercise, experience and the aging brain. Neurobiol. Aging. 2002;23(5):941&#x2013;955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12392797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaynman S., Gomez&#x2010;Pinilla F. Revenge of the &#x201c;sit&#x201d;: how lifestyle impacts neuronal and cognitive health through molecular systems that interface energy metabolism with neuronal plasticity. J. Neurosci. Res. 2006;84(4):699&#x2013;715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16862541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colcombe S.J., et al. Aerobic exercise training increases brain volume in aging humans. J. Gerontol. Series A: Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 2006;61(11):1166&#x2013;1170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17167157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winstein C.J., et al. Guidelines for adult stroke rehabilitation and recovery: a guideline for healthcare professionals from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Stroke. 2016;47(6):e98&#x2013;e169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27145936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Tamawy M.S., et al. Aerobic exercises enhance cognitive functions and brain derived neurotrophic factor in ischemic stroke patients. NeuroRehabilitation. 2014;34(1):209&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24284463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song M.-K., et al. Effects of exercise timing and intensity on neuroplasticity in a rat model of cerebral infarction. Brain Res. Bull. 2020;160:50&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32305405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constans A., et al. Influence of aerobic training and combinations of interventions on cognition and neuroplasticity after stroke. Front. Aging Neurosci. 2016;8:164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4928497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27445801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam M.R., Young M.F., Wrann C.D. Neuroprotective potential of exercise preconditioning in stroke. Condit. Med. 2017;1(1):27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6242281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30465042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakao N., et al. Protective effects of BDNF and NT-3 but not PDGF against hypoglycemic injury to cultured striatal neurons. Exp. Neurol. 1995;131(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7895804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez-Pinilla F., Vaynman S. A &#x201c;deficient environment&#x201d; in prenatal life may compromise systems important for cognitive function by affecting BDNF in the hippocampus. Exp. Neurol. 2005;192(2):235&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15755541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minichiello L. TrkB signalling pathways in LTP and learning. Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 2009;10(12):850&#x2013;860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19927149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerberg B., Foote H.E., Van Kempen T.A. Olfactory association learning and brain&#x2010;derived neurotrophic factor in an animal model of early deprivation. Dev. Psychobiol.: J. Int. Soc. Dev. Psychobiol. 2009;51(4):333&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19308959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa Y., et al. Preservation of tropomyosin-related kinase B (TrkB) signaling by sodium orthovanadate attenuates early brain injury after subarachnoid hemorrhage in rats. Stroke. 2011;42(2):477&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21193742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duman R. Synaptic plasticity and mood disorders. Mol. Psychiatr. 2002;7(1):S29&#x2013;S34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11986993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manji H.K., Drevets W.C., Charney D.S. The cellular neurobiology of depression. Nat. Med. 2001;7(5):541&#x2013;547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11329053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamam L., Zeren T. Depresyonda serotonerjik d&#xfc;zenekler. Klinik Psikiyatri Dergisi. 2002;5(4):11&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phebus L.A., Clemens J.A. Effects of transient, global, cerebral ischemia on striatal extracellular dopamine, serotonin and their metabolites. Life Sci. 1989;44(19):1335&#x2013;1342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2469926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de la Mora M.P., et al. Role of dopamine receptor mechanisms in the amygdaloid modulation of fear and anxiety: structural and functional analysis. Prog. Neurobiol. 2010;90(2):198&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19853006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieoullon A., Coquerel A. Dopamine: a key regulator to adapt action, emotion, motivation and cognition. Curr. Opin. Neurol. 2003;16:S3&#x2013;S9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15129844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieoullon A. Dopamine and the regulation of cognition and attention. Prog. Neurobiol. 2002;67(1):53&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12126656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiebert N.M., et al. Striatum in stimulus&#x2013;response learning via feedback and in decision making. Neuroimage. 2014;101:448&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25038436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burda J., et al. Delayed postconditionig initiates additive mechanism necessary for survival of selectively vulnerable neurons after transient ischemia in rat brain. Cell. Mol. Neurobiol. 2006;26(7):1139&#x2013;1149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11520615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16612578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slivka A., et al. Increase in extracellular dopamine in the striatum during cerebral ischemia: a study utilizing cerebral microdialysis. J. Neurochem. 1988;50(6):1714&#x2013;1718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3373210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojo O.B., et al. Neurotherapeutic potential of kolaviron on neurotransmitter dysregulation, excitotoxicity, mitochondrial electron transport chain dysfunction and redox imbalance in 2-VO brain ischemia/reperfusion injury. Biomed. Pharmacother. 2019;111:859&#x2013;872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30841465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y.-H., et al. Exercise pre-conditioning strengthens brain microvascular integrity in a rat stroke model. Neurol. Res. 2006;28(2):184&#x2013;189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16551437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., et al. Effect of voluntary wheel running on striatal dopamine level and neurocognitive behaviors after molar loss in rats. Behav. Neurol. 2017;2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5735578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29358845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacco R.L., et al. Leisure-time physical activity and ischemic stroke risk: the Northern Manhattan Stroke Study. Stroke. 1998;29(2):380&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9472878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>