<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39568105</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0838</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scandinavian journal of medicine &amp; science in sports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Scand J Med Sci Sports</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Synergistic Effects of Concurrent Aerobic and Strength Training on Fitness in Children and Adolescents: A Multivariate and Network Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e14764</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e14764</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/sms.14764</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The decline in fitness levels among children and adolescents underscores the urgent need for effective exercise interventions. Aerobic endurance training (ET) and resistance training (RT) are vital for physical development in this demographic. This study employs multivariate and network meta-analysis (NMA) to assess the impact of concurrent training (CT), which integrates both ET and RT, on youth physical fitness. The objective is to identify the distinct advantages of CT over either ET or RT alone, emphasizing demographic and training-specific variables. A systematic literature review of publications from 1980 onward was conducted through ISI Web of Science, PubMed/MEDLINE, and SPORTDiscus databases, adhering to the PICOS criteria for study selection. Data were analyzed using univariate, multivariate, and network meta-analyses in Stata 17.0, focusing on cardiorespiratory fitness and muscular strength. The methodological quality and risk of bias were evaluated using the PEDro scale and Egger's test, along with sensitivity analyses and meta-regression to explore heterogeneity and publication bias. This analysis included 36 studies with 2658 participants (mean age: 14.32&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.29&#x2009;years) from an initial 11&#x2009;074 publications, indicating low bias risk (PEDro scores &#x2265;&#x2009;6). Univariate meta-analysis showed no significant differences in maximal oxygen uptake (VO<sub>2</sub>max) between CT and ET (standardized mean difference [SMD]&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01; 95% confidence interval [CI]: -0.23 to 0.25; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.93). In contrast, CT significantly improved countermovement jump (CMJ) compared to RT alone (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.19; 95% CI: 0.01-0.36; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.04). Multivariate analysis confirmed notable enhancements in endurance and explosiveness for CT compared to ET or RT. NMA indicated significant improvements in lower limb strength, CMJ, and VO<sub>2</sub>max across interventions compared to controls, with the consecutive resistance training followed by ET (CRE) group yielding the most significant CMJ improvement (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.27; 95% CI: 0.07-0.47). Isolated RT showed the highest lower limb strength improvement (SUCRA score 80.1%), while CRE excelled in CMJ advancements (SUCRA score 93.4%), and the CRED group (alternating ET and RT) led in VO<sub>2</sub>max improvements (SUCRA score 81.6%). Furthermore, high-intensity interval training (HIIT) significantly enhanced VO<sub>2</sub>max compared to team sports. This meta-analysis emphasizes the effectiveness of CT in improving muscle power and VO<sub>2</sub>max in children and adolescents, surpassing isolated ET or RT, and advocates for integrating ET and RT to optimize physical performance. Future research should explore the mechanisms underlying these enhancements. Trial Registration: PROSPERO registration number CRD42022368452.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhen</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1432-7472</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Provincial University Key Laboratory of Sport and Health Science, School of Physical Education and Sport Science, Fujian Normal University, Fuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Capital University of Physical Education and Sports, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qi</LastName><ForeName>Yuqing</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-6092-3892</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Exercise and Health, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoke</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5157-3138</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Tsinghua University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Capital University of Physical Education and Sports, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jinxi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Capital University of Physical Education and Sports, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Peiyuan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Science School, Beijing Sport University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Zhixiong</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3369-1429</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Capital University of Physical Education and Sports, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2020YFC2006200</GrantID><Agency>National Key Research and Development Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023</GrantID><Agency>Emerging Interdisciplinary Platform for Medicine and Engineering in Sports (EIPMES)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000099094">Network Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Scand J Med Sci Sports</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9111504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0905-7188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072599" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiorespiratory Fitness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010809" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Fitness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076663" MajorTopicYN="N">Endurance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015999" MajorTopicYN="N">Multivariate Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aerobic capacity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concurrent training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">youth fitness</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39568105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>S. J. Schwartz and M. Petrova, &#x201c;Fostering Healthy Identity Development in Adolescence,&#x201d; Nature Human Behaviour 2, no. 2 (2018): 110&#x2013;111, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562&#x2010;017&#x2010;0283&#x2010;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Herraiz&#x2010;Adillo, V. H. Ahlqvist, S. Higueras&#x2010;Fresnillo, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Physical Fitness in Male Adolescents and Atherosclerosis in Middle Age: A Population&#x2010;Based Cohort Study,&#x201d; British Journal of Sports Medicine 58 (2024): 411&#x2013;420, https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2023&#x2010;107663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Dong, P. W. C. Lau, B. Dong, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Trends in Physical Fitness, Growth, and Nutritional Status of Chinese Children and Adolescents: A Retrospective Analysis of 1.5 Million Students From Six Successive National Surveys Between 1985 and 2014,&#x201d; Lancet Child and Adolescent Health 3, no. 12 (2019): 871&#x2013;880, https://doi.org/10.1016/S2352&#x2010;4642(19)30302&#x2010;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Chen, D. Wang, H. Shen, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Physical Activity and Health in Chinese Children and Adolescents: Expert Consensus Statement (2020),&#x201d; British Journal of Sports Medicine 54, no. 22 (2020): 1321&#x2013;1331, https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2020&#x2010;102261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J.&#x2010;P. Chaput, J. Willumsen, F. Bull, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;2020 WHO Guidelines on Physical Activity and Sedentary Behaviour for Children and Adolescents Aged 5&#x2013;17&#x2009;years: Summary of the Evidence,&#x201d; International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity 17, no. 1 (2020): 141, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12966&#x2010;020&#x2010;01037&#x2010;z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Valanju, M. Barani, D. Mautner, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Youth Perspective on Chronic Disease Prevention,&#x201d; Lancet Child &amp; Adolescent 6, no. 7 (2022): 456&#x2013;458, https://doi.org/10.1016/S2352&#x2010;4642(22)00131&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Robinson, N. Riley, K. Owen, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effects of Resistance Training on Academic Outcomes in School&#x2010;Aged Youth: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 53, no. 11 (2023): 2095&#x2013;2109, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;023&#x2010;01881&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. B. Ortega, K. Silventoinen, P. Tynelius, and F. Rasmussen, &#x201c;Muscular Strength in Male Adolescents and Premature Death: Cohort Study of One Million Participants,&#x201d; BMJ 345 (2012): e7279, https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.e7279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Janssen, A. A. Leahy, T. M. O. Diallo, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Cardiorespiratory Fitness, Muscular Fitness and Mental Health in Older Adolescents: A Multi&#x2010;Level Cross&#x2010;Sectional Analysis,&#x201d; Preventive Medicine 132 (2020): 105985, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ypmed.2020.105985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. G&#xe4;bler, and U. Granacher, &#x201c;Concurrent Training in Children and Adolescents,&#x201d; In Concurrent Aerobic and Strength Training: Scientific Basics and Practical Applications, eds. M. Schumann, and B. R. R&#xf8;nnestad (Cham, Switzerland: Springer International Publishing, 2019), 255&#x2013;275, https://doi.org/10.1007/978&#x2010;3&#x2010;319&#x2010;75547&#x2010;2_17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. R. Mendonca, W. Ferreira de Faria, J. Marcio da Silva, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effects of Aerobic Exercise Combined With Resistance Training on Health&#x2010;Related Physical Fitness in Adolescents: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Journal of Exercise Science and Fitness 20, no. 2 (2022): 182&#x2013;189, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesf.2022.03.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Li, T. Ding, Y. Gao, X. Han, Y. Liu, and Z. Zhou, &#x201c;A Comparison of the Effects of Two Protocols of Concurrent Resistance and Aerobic Training on Physical Fitness in Middle School Students,&#x201d; PeerJ 12 (2024): e17294, https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.17294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. M. F. van Sluijs, U. Ekelund, I. Crochemore&#x2010;Silva, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Physical Activity Behaviours in Adolescence: Current Evidence and Opportunities for Intervention,&#x201d; Lancet 398, no. 10298 (2021): 429&#x2013;442, https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140&#x2010;6736(21)01259&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Markov, L. Hauser, and H. Chaabene, &#x201c;Effects of Concurrent Strength and Endurance Training on Measures of Physical Fitness in Healthy Middle&#x2010;Aged and Older Adults: A Systematic Review With Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 53, no. 2 (2023): 437&#x2013;455, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;022&#x2010;01764&#x2010;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Gao and L. Yu, &#x201c;Effects of Concurrent Training Sequence on VO2max and Lower Limb Strength Performance: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Frontiers in Physiology 2023, no. 14 (2023): 1072679, https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2023.1072679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Schumann, J. F. Feuerbacher, M. Sunkeler, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Compatibility of Concurrent Aerobic and Strength Training for Skeletal Muscle Size and Function: An Updated Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 52, no. 3 (2022): 601&#x2013;612, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;021&#x2010;01587&#x2010;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. R. Lundberg, J. F. Feuerbacher, M. Sunkeler, and M. Schumann, &#x201c;The Effects of Concurrent Aerobic and Strength Training on Muscle Fiber Hypertrophy: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 52, no. 10 (2022): 2391&#x2013;2403, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;022&#x2010;01688&#x2010;x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Jansson, A. S. Lindberg, E. Lundberg, M. Domellof, and A. Theos, &#x201c;Effects of Resistance and Endurance Training Alone or Combined on Hormonal Adaptations and Cytokines in Healthy Children and Adolescents: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 8, no. 1 (2022): 81, https://doi.org/10.1186/s40798&#x2010;022&#x2010;00471&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. D. Riley, D. Jackson, G. Salanti, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Multivariate and Network Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Multiple Outcomes and Multiple Treatments: Rationale, Concepts, and Examples,&#x201d; BMJ 358 (2017): j3932, https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.j3932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Haugen, &#xd8;. Sandbakk, E. Enoksen, S. Seiler, and E. T&#xf8;nnessen, &#x201c;Crossing the Golden Training Divide: The Science and Practice of Training World&#x2010;Class 800&#x2010; and 1500&#x2010;m Runners,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 51, no. 9 (2021): 1835&#x2013;1854, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;021&#x2010;01481&#x2010;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. J. Page, J. E. McKenzie, P. M. Bossuyt, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The PRISMA 2020 Statement: An Updated Guideline for Reporting Systematic Reviews,&#x201d; Systematic Reviews 10, no. 1 (2021): 89, https://doi.org/10.1186/s13643&#x2010;021&#x2010;01626&#x2010;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. L. Ardern, F. Buttner, R. Andrade, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Implementing the 27 PRISMA 2020 Statement Items for Systematic Reviews in the Sport and Exercise Medicine, Musculoskeletal Rehabilitation and Sports Science Fields: The PERSiST (Implementing Prisma in Exercise, Rehabilitation, Sport Medicine and SporTs Science) Guidance,&#x201d; British Journal of Sports Medicine 56, no. 4 (2022): 175&#x2013;195, https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2021&#x2010;103987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. C. Hickson, &#x201c;Interference of Strength Development by Simultaneously Training for Strength and Endurance,&#x201d; European Journal of Applied Physiology and Occupational Physiology 45, no. 2&#x2013;3 (1980): 255&#x2013;263, https://doi.org/10.1007/bf00421333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. M. Wilson, P. J. Marin, M. R. Rhea, S. M. Wilson, J. P. Loenneke, and J. C. Anderson, &#x201c;Concurrent Training: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis Examining Interference of Aerobic and Resistance Exercises,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 26, no. 8 (2012): 2293&#x2013;2307, https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e31823a3e2d.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. G. Behm, A. D. Faigenbaum, B. Falk, and P. Klentrou, &#x201c;Canadian Society for Exercise Physiology Position Paper: Resistance Training in Children and Adolescents,&#x201d; Applied Physiology Nutrition and Metabolism 33, no. 3 (2008): 547&#x2013;561, https://doi.org/10.1139/h08&#x2010;020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. D. Faigenbaum, W. J. Kraemer, C. J. R. Blimkie, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Youth Resistance Training: Updated Position Statement Paper From the National Strength And Conditioning Association,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 23 (2009): S60&#x2013;S79, https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e31819df407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Petre, E. Hemmingsson, H. Rosdahl, and N. Psilander, &#x201c;Development of Maximal Dynamic Strength During Concurrent Resistance and Endurance Training in Untrained, Moderately Trained, and Trained Individuals: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 51, no. 5 (2021): 991&#x2013;1010, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;021&#x2010;01426&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Lesinski, O. Prieske, and U. Granacher, &#x201c;Effects and Dose&#x2010;Response Relationships of Resistance Training on Physical Performance in Youth Athletes: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; British Journal of Sports Medicine 50, no. 13 (2016): 781&#x2013;795, https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2015&#x2010;095497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Nasser, &#x201c;Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions,&#x201d; American Journal of Public Health 110, no. 6 (2020): 753&#x2013;754, https://doi.org/10.2105/ajph.2020.305609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. G. Maher, C. Sherrington, R. D. Herbert, A. M. Moseley, and M. Elkins, &#x201c;Reliability of the PEDro Scale for Rating Quality of Randomized Controlled Trials,&#x201d; Physical Therapy 83, no. 8 (2003): 713&#x2013;721, https://doi.org/10.1093/ptj/83.8.713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Egger, G. Davey Smith, M. Schneider, and C. Minder, &#x201c;Bias in Meta&#x2010;Analysis Detected by a Simple, Graphical Test,&#x201d; BMJ (Clinical Research Ed) 315, no. 7109 (1997): 629&#x2013;634, https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.315.7109.629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Wood, E. Taylor, V. Ng, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Estimating the Effect of Aerobic Exercise Training on Novel Lipid Biomarkers: A Systematic Review and Multivariate Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 53, no. 4 (2023): 871&#x2013;886, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;023&#x2010;01817&#x2010;0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. P. T. Higgins, S. G. Thompson, J. J. Deeks, and D. G. Altman, &#x201c;Measuring Inconsistency in Meta&#x2010;Analyses,&#x201d; BMJ&#x2009;[British Medical Journal] 327, no. 7414 (2003): 557&#x2013;560, https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.327.7414.557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Eng, C. K. Kramer, B. Zinman, and R. Retnakaran, &#x201c;Glucagon&#x2010;Like Peptide&#x2010;1 Receptor Agonist and Basal Insulin Combination Tre Atment for the Management of Type 2 Diabetes: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Lancet 384, no. 9961 (2014): 2228&#x2013;2234, https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140&#x2010;6736(14)61335&#x2010;0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. R. White, &#x201c;Network Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Stata Journal 15, no. 4 (2015): 951&#x2013;985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. W. Ashor, J. Lara, M. Siervo, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Exercise Modalities and Endothelial Function: A Systematic Review and Dose&#x2010;Response Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 45, no. 2 (2015): 279&#x2013;296, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;014&#x2010;0272&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Monserda&#x2010;Vilaro, C. Balsalobre&#x2010;Fernandez, J. R. Hoffman, C. Alix&#x2010;Fages, and S. L. Jimenez, &#x201c;Effects of Concurrent Resistance and Endurance Training Using Continuous or Intermittent Protocols on Muscle Hypertrophy: Systematic Review With Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 37, no. 3 (2023): 688&#x2013;709, https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000004304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Gabler, O. Prieske, T. Hortobagyi, and U. Granacher, &#x201c;The Effects of Concurrent Strength and Endurance Training on Physical Fitness and Athletic Performance in Youth: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Frontiers in Physiology 9 (2018): 1057, https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2018.01057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. O. Huiberts, R. C. I. Wust, and S. van der Zwaard, &#x201c;Concurrent Strength and Endurance Training: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis on the Impact of Sex and Training Status,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 54 (2023): 485&#x2013;503, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;023&#x2010;01943&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. McNarry and A. Jones, &#x201c;The Influence of Training Status on the Aerobic and Anaerobic Responses to Exercise in Children: A Review,&#x201d; European Journal of Sport Science 14, no. Suppl 1 (2014): S57&#x2013;S68, https://doi.org/10.1080/17461391.2011.643316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Raghuveer, J. Hartz, D. R. Lubans, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Cardiorespiratory Fitness in Youth: An Important Marker of Health: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association,&#x201d; Circulation 142, no. 7 (2020): E101&#x2013;E118, https://doi.org/10.1161/cir.0000000000000866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Murlasits, Z. Kneffel, and L. Thalib, &#x201c;The Physiological Effects of Concurrent Strength and Endurance Training Sequence: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Journal of Sports Sciences 36, no. 11 (2018): 1212&#x2013;1219, https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2017.1364405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. G. Sale, J. D. MacDougall, I. Jacobs, and S. Garner, &#x201c;Interaction Between Concurrent Strength and Endurance Training,&#x201d; Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, MD: 1985) 68, no. 1 (1990): 260&#x2013;270, https://doi.org/10.1152/jappl.1990.68.1.260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. J. Bell, D. Syrotuik, T. P. Martin, R. Burnham, and H. A. Quinney, &#x201c;Effect of Concurrent Strength and Endurance Training on Skeletal Muscle Properties and Hormone Concentrations in Humans,&#x201d; European Journal of Applied Physiology 81, no. 5 (2000): 418&#x2013;427, https://doi.org/10.1007/s004210050063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Cao, J. Xu, W. Cao, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Assembly of Mitochondrial Succinate Dehydrogenase in Human Health and Disease,&#x201d; Free Radical Biology and Medicine 207 (2023): 247&#x2013;259, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2023.07.023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. B. N. Moreira, M. Wohlwend, and U. Wisloff, &#x201c;Exercise and Cardiac Health: Physiological and Molecular Insights,&#x201d; Nature Metabolism 2, no. 9 (2020): 829&#x2013;839, https://doi.org/10.1038/s42255&#x2010;020&#x2010;0262&#x2010;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Doma, G. B. Deakin, M. Schumann, and D. J. Bentley, &#x201c;Training Considerations for Optimising Endurance Development: An Alternate Concurrent Training Perspective,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 49, no. 5 (2019): 669&#x2013;682, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;019&#x2010;01072&#x2010;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Eihara, K. Takao, T. Sugiyama, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Heavy Resistance Training Versus Plyometric Training for Improving Running Economy and Running Time Trial Performance: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 8, no. 1 (2022): 138, https://doi.org/10.1186/s40798&#x2010;022&#x2010;00511&#x2010;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Matos and R. J. Winsley, &#x201c;Trainability of Young Athletes and Overtraining,&#x201d; Journal of Sports Science and Medicine 6, no. 3 (2007): 353&#x2013;367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Carazo&#x2010;Vargas and J. Moncada&#x2010;Jim&#xe9;nez, &#x201c;A Meta&#x2010;Analysis on the Effects of Exercise Training on the VO2 Max in Children and Adolescents,&#x201d; Retos 27 (2014): 184&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. R. Alves, C. Marta, H. P. Neiva, M. Izquierdo, and M. C. Marques, &#x201c;Concurrent Training in Prepubertal Children: An Update,&#x201d; Journal of Human Sport and Exercise 13, no. 3 (2018): 682&#x2013;697, https://doi.org/10.14198/jhse.2018.133.18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. J. Burden, B. D. Weedon, A. Turner, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Intensity and Duration of Physical Activity and Cardiorespiratory Fitness,&#x201d; Pediatrics 150, no. 1 (2022): e2021056003, https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2021&#x2010;056003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. C. Vechin, M. S. Conceicao, G. D. Telles, C. A. Libardi, and C. Ugrinowitsch, &#x201c;Interference Phenomenon With Concurrent Strength and High&#x2010;Intensity Interval Training&#x2010;Based Aerobic Training: An Updated Model,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 51, no. 4 (2021): 599&#x2013;605, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;020&#x2010;01421&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. L. Crawford, R. Arnold, C. McKay, and D. McEwan, &#x201c;Coaching Teamwork: Team Sport Athletes' and Coaches' Perceptions of How Coaches Facilitate Teamwork,&#x201d; Journal of Applied Sport Psychology 36 (2023): 697&#x2013;721, https://doi.org/10.1080/10413200.2023.2299203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Waldron and J. Highton, &#x201c;Fatigue and Pacing in High&#x2010;Intensity Intermittent Team Sport: An Update,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 44, no. 12 (2014): 1645&#x2013;1658, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;014&#x2010;0230&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. F. Faria, F. R. Mendonca, G. C. Santos, S. G. Kennedy, R. G. M. Elias, and N. A. Stabelini, &#x201c;Effects of 2 Methods of Combined Training on Cardiometabolic Risk Factors in Adolescents: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Pediatric Exercise Science 32, no. 4 (2020): 217&#x2013;226, https://doi.org/10.1123/pes.2020&#x2010;0016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Buchheit and P. B. Laursen, &#x201c;High&#x2010;Intensity Interval Training, Solutions to the Programming Puzzle Part I: Cardiopulmonary Emphasis,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 43, no. 5 (2013): 313&#x2013;338, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;013&#x2010;0029&#x2010;x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. R. Lubans, J. J. Smith, N. Eather, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Time&#x2010;Efficient Intervention to Improve Older Adolescents' Cardiorespiratory Fitness: Findings From the &#x2018;Burn 2 Learn&#x2019; Cluster Randomised Controlled Trial,&#x201d; British Journal of Sports Medicine 55, no. 13 (2021): 751&#x2013;758, https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2020&#x2010;103277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. J. Smith, N. Eather, P. J. Morgan, R. C. Plotnikoff, A. D. Faigenbaum, and D. R. Lubans, &#x201c;The Health Benefits of Muscular Fitness for Children and Adolescents: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 44, no. 9 (2014): 1209&#x2013;1223, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;014&#x2010;0196&#x2010;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. S. Lloyd, A. D. Faigenbaum, M. H. Stone, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Position Statement on Youth Resistance Training: The 2014 International Consensus,&#x201d; British Journal of Sports Medicine 48, no. 7 (2014): 498&#x2013;505, https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2013&#x2010;092952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Robineau, N. Babault, J. Piscione, M. Lacome, and A. X. Bigard, &#x201c;Specific Training Effects of Concurrent Aerobic and Strength Exercises Depend on Recovery Duration,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 30, no. 3 (2016): 672&#x2013;683, https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000000798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. S. Taipale, M. Schumann, J. Mikkola, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Acute Neuromuscular and Metabolic Responses to Combined Strength and Endurance Loadings: The &#x201c;Order Effect&#x201d; in Recreationally Endurance Trained Runners,&#x201d; Journal of Sports Sciences 32, no. 12 (2014): 1155&#x2013;1164, https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2014.889842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. W. Jones, N. Petersen, and G. Howatson, &#x201c;Optimization of Exercise Countermeasures for Human Space Flight: Operational Considerations for Concurrent Strength and Aerobic Training,&#x201d; Frontiers in Physiology 10 (2019): 584, https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2019.00584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. A. Dudley and R. Djamil, &#x201c;Incompatibility of Endurance&#x2010; and Strength&#x2010;Training Modes of Exercise,&#x201d; Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, MD: 1985) 59, no. 5 (1985): 1446&#x2013;1451, https://doi.org/10.1152/jappl.1985.59.5.1446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. G. Coffey and J. A. Hawley, &#x201c;Concurrent Exercise Training: Do Opposites Distract?,&#x201d; Journal of Physiology 595, no. 9 (2017): 2883&#x2013;2896, https://doi.org/10.1113/JP272270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Seipp, O. J. Quittmann, F. Fasold, and S. Klatt, &#x201c;Concurrent Training in Team Sports: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; International Journal of Sports Science &amp; Coaching 18, no. 4 (2023): 1342&#x2013;1364, https://doi.org/10.1177/17479541221099846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. D. Myer, C. E. Quatman, J. Khoury, E. J. Wall, and T. E. Hewett, &#x201c;Youth versus Adult &#x201c;Weightlifting&#x201d; Injuries Presenting to United States Emergency Rooms: Accidental versus Nonaccidental Injury Mechanisms,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 23, no. 7 (2009): 2054&#x2013;2060, https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b86712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Bo, J. Langan, and R. D. Seidler, &#x201c;Cognitive Neuroscience of Skill Acquisition,&#x201d; in Advances in Psychology, eds. A. S. Benjamin, J. S. de Belle, B. Etnyre, and T. A. Polk (Amsterdam: North&#x2010;Holland, 2008), 101&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. D. Williams, R. Ramirez&#x2010;Campillo, H. Chaabene, and J. Moran, &#x201c;Neuromuscular Training and Motor Control in Youth Athletes: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Perceptual and Motor Skills 128, no. 5 (2021): 1975&#x2013;1997, https://doi.org/10.1177/00315125211029006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Eddens, K. van Someren, and G. Howatson, &#x201c;The Role of Intra&#x2010;Session Exercise Sequence in the Interference Effect: A Systematic Review With Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 48, no. 1 (2018): 177&#x2013;188, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;017&#x2010;0784&#x2010;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Makhlouf, C. Castagna, V. Manzi, L. Laurencelle, D. G. Behm, and A. Chaouachi, &#x201c;Effect of Sequencing Strength and Endurance Training in Young Male Soccer Players,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 30, no. 3 (2016): 841&#x2013;850, https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000001164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Garcia&#x2010;Hermoso, R. Ramirez&#x2010;Velez, R. Ramirez&#x2010;Campillo, M. D. Peterson, and V. Martinez&#x2010;Vizcaino, &#x201c;Concurrent Aerobic Plus Resistance Exercise Versus Aerobic Exercise Alone to Improve Health Outcomes in Paediatric Obesity: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; British Journal of Sports Medicine 52, no. 3 (2018): 161&#x2013;166, https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2016&#x2010;096605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. J. Schoenfeld, &#x201c;The Mechanisms of Muscle Hypertrophy and Their Application to Resistance Training,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 24, no. 10 (2010): 2857&#x2013;2872, https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e840f3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Simao, A. Lemos, B. Salles, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Influence of Strength, Flexibility, and Simultaneous Training on Flexibility and Strength Gains,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 25, no. 5 (2011): 1333&#x2013;1338, https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181da85bf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. G. Behm and D. G. Sale, &#x201c;Intended Rather Than Actual Movement Velocity Determines Velocity&#x2010;Specific Training Response,&#x201d; Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, MD: 1985) 74, no. 1 (1993): 359&#x2013;368, https://doi.org/10.1152/jappl.1993.74.1.359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. J. Gibala, J. P. Little, M. J. MacDonald, and J. A. Hawley, &#x201c;Physiological Adaptations to Low&#x2010;Volume, High&#x2010;Intensity Interval Training in Health and Disease,&#x201d; Journal of Physiology&#x2010;London 590, no. 5 (2012): 1077&#x2013;1084, https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2011.224725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Bishop, O. Girard, and A. Mendez&#x2010;Villanueva, &#x201c;Repeated&#x2010;Sprint Ability&#x2014;Part II Recommendations for Training,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 41, no. 9 (2011): 741&#x2013;756, https://doi.org/10.2165/11590560&#x2010;000000000&#x2010;00000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. P. Bacon, R. E. Carter, E. A. Ogle, and M. J. Joyner, &#x201c;VO2max Trainability and High Intensity Interval Training in Humans: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; PLoS One 8, no. 9 (2013): e73182, https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0073182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. J. Suchomel, S. Nimphius, and M. H. Stone, &#x201c;The Importance of Muscular Strength in Athletic Performance,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 46, no. 10 (2016): 1419&#x2013;1449, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;016&#x2010;0486&#x2010;0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Beard, J. Ashby, R. Chambers, F. Brocherie, and G. P. Millet, &#x201c;Repeated&#x2010;Sprint Training in Hypoxia in International Rugby Union Players,&#x201d; International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance 14, no. 6 (2019): 850&#x2013;854, https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2018&#x2010;0170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. L. Nuzzo, M. D. Pinto, B. J. C. Kirk, and K. Nosaka, &#x201c;Resistance Exercise Minimal Dose Strategies for Increasing Muscle Strength in the General Population: An Overview,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 54 (2024): 1139&#x2013;1162, https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279&#x2010;024&#x2010;02009&#x2010;0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. R. Rhea, S. D. Ball, W. T. Phillips, and L. N. Burkett, &#x201c;A Comparison of Linear and Daily Undulating Periodized Programs With Equated Volume and Intensity for Strength,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 16, no. 2 (2002): 250&#x2013;255, https://doi.org/10.1519/00124278&#x2010;200205000&#x2010;00013.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>