<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37823465</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0838</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scandinavian journal of medicine &amp; science in sports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Scand J Med Sci Sports</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physical exercise improves memory in sedentary middle-aged adults: Are these exercise-induced benefits associated with S-Klotho and 1,25-dihydroxivitamin D? The FIT-AGEING randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e14519</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e14519</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/sms.14519</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We aimed to investigate the effect of three types of exercise interventions on memory (i.e., immediate memory (IM), long-term memory (LTM), and recognition). We also investigated whether exercise-induced changes in circulating S-Klotho and 1,25-dihydroxivitamin D (1,25(OH)<sub>2</sub> D) levels were related to those observed in memory in healthy middle-aged sedentary adults. A 12-week randomized controlled trial was performed with a parallel-group design. Seventy-four participants (45-65&#x2009;years old: 53% women) were randomly assigned to (1) no exercise (control) group, (2) concurrent training based on the international physical activity recommendations (PAR) group, (3) high-intensity interval training (HIIT) group, or (4) HIIT plus whole-body electromyostimulation (HIIT-EMS) group. Memory outcomes were assessed using the Wechsler Memory Scale-third edition. S-Klotho plasma levels were determined according to a solid-phase sandwich enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay kit while 1,25(OH)<sub>2</sub> D plasma levels were measured using a DiaSorin-Liaison immunochemiluminometric analyzer. IM-Verbal Paired Associates (IM-VPA) and IM-Logical Memory (IM-LM) were improved in both the HIIT and HIIT-EMS groups compared with the control group (all p&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.045). Exercise-induced changes in S-Klotho plasma levels were positively associated with those observed in IM, LTM, and recognition (all p&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.007), whereas exercise-induced changes in 1,25(OH)<sub>2</sub> D plasma levels were directly related to changes in IM and LTM (all p&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.048). In conclusion, a 12-week HIIT intervention with or without WB-EMS seems to be the most effective exercise program to improve IM. The significant and positive associations between exercise-induced changes in S-Klotho and 1,25(OH)<sub>2</sub> D levels with those observed in memory outcomes suggest that these factors may be potentially related to exercise-induced improvements of memory in middle-aged adults.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science In Sports published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>V&#xe1;zquez-Lorente</LastName><ForeName>H&#xe9;ctor</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0183-6902</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De-la-O</LastName><ForeName>Alejandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carneiro-Barrera</LastName><ForeName>Almudena</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Universidad Loyola Andaluc&#xed;a, Seville, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Molina-Hidalgo</LastName><ForeName>Cristina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AdventHealth Research Institute, Neuroscience Institute, Orlando, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castillo</LastName><ForeName>Manuel J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amaro-Gahete</LastName><ForeName>Francisco J</ForeName><Initials>FJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7207-9016</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n Biom&#xe9;dica en Red Fisiopatolog&#xed;a de la Obesidad y Nutrici&#xf3;n (CIBERobn), Instituto de Salud Carlos III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Investigaci&#xf3;n Biosanitaria, ibs.Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>CTS-363-UGR18</GrantID><Agency>FEDER/Junta de Andaluc&#xed;a-Consejer&#xed;a de Econom&#xed;a y Conocimiento/Proyecto B462</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>FPU18/03655</GrantID><Agency>Spanish Ministry of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Scand J Med Sci Sports</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9111504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0905-7188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000375" MajorTopicYN="N">Aging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072696" MajorTopicYN="Y">High-Intensity Interval Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">1,25-dihydroxivitamin D</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">S-Klotho</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-term memory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">short-term memory</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37823465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Raj D, Santhi S, Sapharina GJS. Effectiveness of neurobic exercise program on memory and depression among elderly residing at old age home. J Complement Integr Med. 2020; /j/jcim.ahead-of-print/jcim-2019-0221/jcim-2019-0221.xml.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuster V, Turco JV, Cortes-Canteli M. Paradigm shift: cardiovascular health in the elderly-beware of the brain. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2023;81:1214-1215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J, Ge F, Zeng Y, et al. Physical and mental activity, disease susceptibility, and risk of dementia: a prospective cohort study based on UK biobank. Neurology. 2022;99:e799-e813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedayati M, Sum S, Hosseini SR, Faramarzi M, Pourhadi S. Investigating the effect of physical games on the memory and attention of the elderly in adult day-care centers in Babol and Amol. Clin Interv Aging. 2019;14:859-869.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makino T, Umegaki H, Ando M, et al. Effects of aerobic, resistance, or combined exercise training among older adults with subjective memory complaints: a randomized controlled trial. J Alzheimers Dis. 2021;82:701-717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chekroud SR, Gueorguieva R, Zheutlin AB, et al. Association between physical exercise and mental health in 1&#xb7;2 million individuals in the USA between 2011 and 2015: a cross-sectional study. Lancet Psychiatry. 2018;5:739-746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makizako H, Tsutsumimoto K, Doi T, et al. Exercise and horticultural programs for older adults with depressive symptoms and memory problems: a randomized controlled trial. J Clin Med. 2019;9:99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders LMJ, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Karssemeijer EGA, Van der Zee EA, Scherder EJA, van Heuvelen MJG. Effects of low- and high-intensity physical exercise on physical and cognitive function in older persons with dementia: a randomized controlled trial. Alzheimers Res Ther. 2020;12:28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira SA, Stein AM, Stavinski NGL, Teixeira DC, Queiroga MR, Bonini JS. Different types of physical exercise in brain activity of older adults: a systematic review. Exp Gerontol. 2022;159:111672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popovic D, Bjelobrk M, Tesic M, et al. Defining the importance of stress reduction in managing cardiovascular disease-the role of exercise. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2022;70:84-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson KI, Voss MW, Prakash RS, et al. Exercise training increases size of hippocampus and improves memory. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2011;108:3017-3022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dao AT, Zagaar MA, Levine AT, Salim S, Eriksen JL, Alkadhi KA. Treadmill exercise prevents learning and memory impairment in Alzheimer's disease-like pathology. Curr Alzheimer Res. 2013;10:507-515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou XL, Wang LN, Wang J, Zhou L, Shen XH. Effects of exercise interventions for specific cognitive domains in old adults with mild cognitive impairment. Medicine (Baltimore). 2020;99:e20105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piercy KL, Troiano RP, Ballard RM, et al. The physical activity guidelines for Americans. JAMA. 2018;320:2020-2028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Global Recommendations on Physical Activity for Health. World Health Organization; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De-la-O A, Jurado-Fasoli L, Castillo MJ, Guti&#xe9;rrez &#xc1;, Amaro-Gahete FJ. Effect of exercise training on 1,25(OH)2D levels: the FIT-AGEING randomized controlled trial. Sports Health. 2021;14:518-526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calverley TA, Ogoh S, Marley CJ, et al. HIITing the brain with exercise: mechanisms, consequences and practical recommendations. J Physiol. 2020;598:2513-2530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaro-Gahete FJ, De-la-O A, Jurado-Fasoli L, et al. Changes in physical fitness after 12&#x2009;weeks of structured concurrent exercise training, high intensity interval training, or whole-body electromyostimulation training in sedentary middle-aged adults: a randomized controlled trial. Front Physiol. 2019;10:451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dote-Montero M, De-la-O A, Jurado-Fasoli L, Ruiz JR, Castillo MJ, Amaro-Gahete FJ. The effects of three types of exercise training on steroid hormones in physically inactive middle-aged adults: a randomized controlled trial. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121:2193-2206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W, Klein&#xf6;der H, Fr&#xf6;hlich M. Editorial: whole-body electromyostimulation: a training technology to improve health and performance in humans? Front Physiol. 2020;11:523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaro-Gahete FJ, De-la-O A, Jurado-Fasoli L, Martinez-Tellez B, Ruiz JR, Castillo MJ. Exercise training as a treatment for cardiometabolic risk in sedentary adults: are physical activity guidelines the best way to improve cardiometabolic health? The FIT-AGEING randomized controlled trial. J Clin Med. 2019;8:2097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belloy ME, Napolioni V, Han SS, Le Guen Y, Greicius MD, Alzheimer's disease neuroimaging initiative. Association of Klotho-VS heterozygosity with risk of Alzheimer disease in individuals who carry APOE4. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:849-862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurado-Fasoli L, Castillo MJ, Amaro-Gahete FJ. Dietary inflammatory index and S-Klotho plasma levels in middle-aged adults. Nutrients. 2020;12:281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaro-Gahete FJ, Jurado-Fasoli L, Sanchez-Delgado G, Garc&#xed;a-Lario JV, Castillo MJ, Ruiz JR. Relationship between plasma S-Klotho and cardiometabolic risk in sedentary adults. Aging (Albany NY). 2020;12:2698-2710.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang F, Ma K, Leibrock CB. 1,25(OH)2D3 in brain function and neuropsychiatric disease. Neurosignals. 2019;27:40-49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farapti F, Fadilla C, Yogiswara N, Adriani M. Effects of vitamin D supplementation on 25(OH)D concentrations and blood pressure in the elderly: a systematic review and meta-analysis. F1000Res. 2020;9:633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui C, Xu P, Li G, et al. Vitamin D receptor activation regulates microglia polarization and oxidative stress in spontaneously hypertensive rats and angiotensin II-exposed microglial cells: role of renin-angiotensin system. Redox Biol. 2019;26:26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaro-Gahete FJ, De-la-O A, Jurado-Fasoli L, et al. Exercise training increases the S-Klotho plasma levels in sedentary middle-aged adults: a randomised controlled trial. The FIT-AGEING study. J Sports Sci. 2019;37:2175-2183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Citterio L, Delli Carpini S, Lupoli S, et al. Klotho gene in human salt-sensitive hypertension. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2020;15:375-383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longoni A, Kolling J, dos Santos TM, et al. 1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D3 exerts neuroprotective effects in an ex vivo model of mild hyperhomocysteinemia. Int J Dev Neurosci. 2016;48:71-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaro-Gahete FJ, De-la-O A, Jurado-Fasoli L, et al. Exercise training as S-Klotho protein stimulator in sedentary healthy adults: rationale, design, and methodology. Contemp Clin Trials Commun. 2018;11:10-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association. World medical association declaration of Helsinki: ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA. 2013;310:2191-2194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz KF, Altman DG, Moher D, CONSORT Group. CONSORT 2010 statement: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. BMJ. 2010;340:c332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz KF, Grimes DA. Generation of allocation sequences in randomised trials: chance, not choice. The Lancet. 2002;359:515-519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slade SC, Dionne CE, Underwood M, Buchbinder R. Consensus on exercise reporting template (CERT): explanation and elaboration statement. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:1428-1437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Laursen PB. High-intensity interval training, solutions to the programming puzzle. Part II: anaerobic energy, neuromuscular load and practical applications. Sports Med. 2013;43:927-954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W, Von Stengel S, Schwarz J, Mayhew JL. Effect of whole-body electromyostimulation on energy expenditure during exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26:240-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wechsler D. WMS-III: Wechsler Memory Scale Administration and Scoring Manual. 3rd ed. Psychological Corp; 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paidas Teefey C, Reforma L, Koelper NC, et al. Risk factors associated with cesarean delivery after induction of labor in women with class III obesity. Obstet Gynecol. 2020;135:542-549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Routledge; 1988:567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakdash JZ, Marusich LR. Repeated measures correlation. Front Psychol. 2017;8:456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soko&#x142;owski DR, Hansen TI, Rise HH, et al. 5&#x2009;years of exercise intervention did not benefit cognition compared to the physical activity guidelines in older adults, but higher cardiorespiratory fitness did. A generation 100 substudy. Front Aging Neurosci. 2021;13:742587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyke W, Ifram F, Coventry L, Sung Y, Champion I, Javadi AH. The effects of different protocols of physical exercise and rest on long-term memory. Neurobiol Learn Mem. 2020;167:107128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W, Weissenfels A, Willert S, et al. Efficacy and safety of low frequency whole-body electromyostimulation (WB-EMS) to improve health-related outcomes in non-athletic adults. A systematic review. Front Physiol. 2018;9:573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X, Hussain B, Chang J. Peripheral inflammation and blood-brain barrier disruption: effects and mechanisms. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2021;27:36-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinton SM, Glover ME, Maltare A, et al. Expression of klotho mRNA and protein in rat brain parenchyma from early postnatal development into adulthood. Brain Res. 2013;1527:1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong JW, Zhan JQ, Luo T, et al. Increased plasma level of longevity protein Klotho as a potential indicator of cognitive function preservation in patients with schizophrenia. Front Neurosci. 2020;14:610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias GP, Murphy T, Stangl D, et al. Intermittent fasting enhances long-term memory consolidation, adult hippocampal neurogenesis, and expression of longevity gene Klotho. Mol Psychiatry. 2021;26:6365-6379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagai T, Yamada K, Kim HC, et al. Cognition impairment in the genetic model of aging klotho gene mutant mice: a role of oxidative stress. FASEB J. 2003;17:50-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cass WA, Peters LE, Fletcher AM, Yurek DM. Calcitriol promotes augmented dopamine release in the lesioned striatum of 6-hydroxydopamine treated rats. Neurochem Res. 2014;39:1467-1476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bivona G, Agnello L, Ciaccio M. The immunological implication of the new vitamin D metabolism. Cent Eur J Immunol. 2018;43:331-334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15a;lusarczyk J, Piotrowski M, Szczepanowicz K, et al. Nanocapsules with polyelectrolyte shell as a platform for 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 neuroprotection: study in organotypic hippocampal slices. Neurotox Res. 2016;30:581-592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morello M, Landel V, Lacassagne E, et al. Vitamin D improves neurogenesis and cognition in a mouse model of Alzheimer's disease. Mol Neurobiol. 2018;55:6463-6479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X, Yuan J, Wang J, Cui C, Jiang P. Calcitriol alleviates global cerebral ischemia-induced cognitive impairment by reducing apoptosis regulated by VDR/ERK signaling pathway in rat hippocampus. Brain Res. 2019;1724:146430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xeb;rmaku-Sopjani M, Kurti F, Xuan NT, Sopjani M. Klotho-dependent role of 1,25(OH)2D3 in the brain. Neurosignals. 2021;29:14-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuro-o M. The Klotho proteins in health and disease. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2019;15:27-44.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>