<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33298624</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2508-7576</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of obesity &amp; metabolic syndrome</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Obes Metab Syndr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lipid-Lowering Effects of Concurrent Training and Green Tea Consumption in Overweight Women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>313</StartPage><EndPage>319</EndPage><MedlinePgn>313-319</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7570/jomes20023</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Exercise conducted simultaneously with the consumption of herbal supplements is one of the suggested methods for controlling obesity and its complications. The present study sought to investigate the lipid-lowering effects of concurrent training and green tea (GT) consumption in overweight women.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this quasi-experimental study, 40 overweight women were selected and stratified into four groups: control (C), GT, concurrent training+placebo (TP), and concurrent training+GT (three tablets containing 500 mg of GT per week; T+GT) groups. Both the TP and T+GT groups performed exercise three sessions per week for 8 weeks. Fasting blood samples were collected before and 48 hours after the last training session.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Low-density lipoprotein cholesterol levels in the T+GT (<i>P</i>=0.03) and TP (<i>P</i>=0.001) groups were significantly decreased relative to in the GT group and were significantly decreased in the T+GT group relative to in the TP group (<i>P</i>=0.001). Meanwhile, high-density lipoprotein cholesterol levels in the T+GT group were significantly increased as compared with in the GT (<i>P</i>=0.01), TP (<i>P</i>=0.03), and C (<i>P</i>=0.04) groups. Finally, total cholesterol levels in the T+GT group were decreased significantly as compared with in the TP, GT, and C groups (<i>P</i>=0.001) and triglyceride levels in the T+GT, TP, and GT groups were significantly increased as compared with in the C group (<i>P</i>=0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Exercise performed simultaneously with GT consumption in comparison with either alone has a greater effect on improving the lipid profile in overweight women.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hosseini</LastName><ForeName>Zahra</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Physiology, Lamerd Branch, Islamic Azad University, Lamerd, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghaedi</LastName><ForeName>Hadi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1497-7528</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Physiology, Lamerd Branch, Islamic Azad University, Lamerd, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmadi</LastName><ForeName>Mozhgan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Science, Yadegar-e-Imam Khomeini (RAH) Shahre-rey Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hosseini</LastName><ForeName>Seyed Ali</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Physiology, Marvdasht Branch, Islamic Azad University, Marvdasht, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>J Obes Metab Syndr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101704724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2508-6235</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Green tea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lipids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Overweight</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement><b>CONFLICTS OF INTEREST</b>. The authors declare no conflict of interest. </CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33298624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7789026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7570/jomes20023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jomes20023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bays HE, Toth PP, Kris-Etherton PM, Abate N, Aronne LJ, Brown WV, et al. Obesity, adiposity, and dyslipidemia: a consensus statement from the National Lipid Association. J Clin Lipidol. 2013;7:304&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1016/j.jacl.2013.04.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacl.2013.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23890517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasdar Y, Darbandi M, Niazi P, Alghasi S, Roshanpour F. The prevalence and the affecting factors of obesity in women of Kermanshah. Jorjani Biomed J. 2015;3:82&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehi Z, Salehi K, Moeini M, Kargarfard M, Sadeghi M. The effect of resistance exercise on lipid profile of coronary artery disease patients: a randomized clinical trial. Iran J Nurs Midwifery Res. 2017;22:112&#x2013;6. doi: 10.4103/ijnmr.IJNMR_385_14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijnmr.IJNMR_385_14</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5442991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28584548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines, Obesity Expert Panel, 2013. Expert Panel Report: Guidelines (2013) for the management of overweight and obesity in adults. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2014;22(Suppl 2):S41&#x2013;410. doi: 10.1002/oby.20660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oby.20660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24961825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zachariah G, Alex AG. Exercise for prevention of cardiovascular disease: evidence-based recommendations. J Clin Prev Cardiol. 2017;6:109&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skoumas J, Pitsavos C, Panagiotakos DB, Chrysohoou C, Zeimbekis A, Papaioannou I, et al. Physical activity, high density lipoprotein cholesterol and other lipids levels, in men and women from the ATTICA study. Lipids Health Dis. 2003;2:3. doi: 10.1186/1476-511X-2-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1476-511X-2-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC194868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12852790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trejo-Gutierrez JF, Fletcher G. Impact of exercise on blood lipids and lipoproteins. J Clin Lipidol. 2007;1:175&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1016/j.jacl.2007.05.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacl.2007.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21291678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Xu D. Effects of aerobic exercise on lipids and lipoproteins. Lipids Health Dis. 2017;16:132. doi: 10.1186/s12944-017-0515-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12944-017-0515-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5498979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28679436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostrzewa-Nowak D, Nowak R, Jastrz&#x119;bski Z, Zar&#x119;bska A, Bichowska M, Drobnik-Kozakiewicz I, et al. Effect of 12-week-long aerobic training programme on body composition, aerobic capacity, complete blood count and blood lipid profile among young women. Biochem Med (Zagreb) 2015;25:103&#x2013;13. doi: 10.11613/BM.2015.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11613/BM.2015.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4401316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25672474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa RR, Lima Alberton C, Tagliari M, Martins Kruel LF. Effects of resistance training on the lipid profile in obese women. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2011;51:169&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21297577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shabani R, Jalali Z, Nazari M. Effects of concurrent strength and aerobic training on blood glucose homeostasis and lipid profile in females with overweight and obesity. Zahedan J Res Med Sci. 2018;20:e13746. doi: 10.5812/zjrms.13746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/zjrms.13746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dembitsky VM, Poovarodom S, Leontowicz H, Leontowicz M, Vearasilp S, Trakhtenberg S, et al. The multiple nutrition properties of some exotic fruits: biological activity and active metabolites. Food Res Int. 2011;44:1671&#x2013;701. doi: 10.1016/j.foodres.2011.03.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodres.2011.03.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thielecke F, Boschmann M. The potential role of green tea catechins in the prevention of the metabolic syndrome: a review. Phytochemistry. 2009;70:11&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1016/j.phytochem.2008.11.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phytochem.2008.11.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19147161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng XX, Xu YL, Li SH, Liu XX, Hui R, Huang XH. Green tea intake lowers fasting serum total and LDL cholesterol in adults: a meta-analysis of 14 randomized controlled trials. Am J Clin Nutr. 2011;94:601&#x2013;10. doi: 10.3945/ajcn.110.010926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.110.010926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21715508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugita M, Kapoor MP, Nishimura A, Okubo T. Influence of green tea catechins on oxidative stress metabolites at rest and during exercise in healthy humans. Nutrition. 2016;32:321&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2015.09.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2015.09.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26695876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amirhosein H, Elnaz E, Mohammadreza H. The effect of eight weeks aerobic training and moderate and high doses green tea consumption on body composition and lipid profile in overweight and obese women. Med J Mashhad Univ Med Sci. 2015;58:359&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asad M. Effect of 8 weeks aerobic, resistance and concurrent training on cholestrol, LDL, HDL and cardiovascular fitness in obesity male. Appl Res Sport Manag. 2013;1:57&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghasemi E, Afzalpour ME, Zarban A. Effect of a 10 week high intensity interval training supplemented with green tea on lipid profiles and body composition in overweight women. J Birjand Univ Med Sci. 2016;23:198&#x2013;210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradi H, Kolahdozi S, Ahmadi Kani Golzar F, Arabzade H, Asjodi F, Rezvan K. The Effects of eight weeks resistance training and green tea supplementation on cardiovascular risk factors in overweight men. J Shahrekord Univ Med Sci. 2014;16:77&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS. Impact of progressive resistance training on lipids and lipoproteins in adults: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Prev Med. 2009;48:9&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1016/j.ypmed.2008.10.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ypmed.2008.10.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19013187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valle VS, Mello DB, Fortes Mde S, Dantas EH, Mattos MA. Effect of diet and indoor cycling on body composition and serum lipid. Arq Bras Cardiol. 2010;95:173&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1590/S0066-782X2010005000080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0066-782X2010005000080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20585735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugiura H, Sugiura H, Kajima K, Mirbod SM, Iwata H, Matsuoka T. Effects of long-term moderate exercise and increase in number of daily steps on serum lipids in women: randomised controlled trial [ISRCTN21921919] BMC Womens Health. 2002;2:3. doi: 10.1186/1472-6874-2-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6874-2-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC65683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11846892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins RA, Ver&#xed;ssimo MT, Coelho e Silva MJ, Cumming SP, Teixeira AM. Effects of aerobic and strength-based training on metabolic health indicators in older adults. Lipids Health Dis. 2010;9:76. doi: 10.1186/1476-511X-9-76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1476-511X-9-76</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2912308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20663148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang HY, Yang SC, Chao JC, Chen JR. Beneficial effects of catechin-rich green tea and inulin on the body composition of overweight adults. Br J Nutr. 2012;107:749&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1017/S0007114511005095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0007114511005095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22032343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmaeil AM, Elham G, Asghar Z. Effects of an intensive resistant training sessions and green tea supplementation on malondialdehyde and total thiol in non-athlete women. Zahedan J Res Med Sci. 2014;16:59&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abedi B, Poorfahkimi Abarghu J, Ghadami A, Amini Rarani S. The effects of resistance training and green tea supplementation on lipid profile and insulin resistance in obese and overweight men. Complement Med J Fac Nurs Midwifery. 2017;7:1767&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathei M, Khairabadi S, Ramezani F, Hejazi K. Effect of eight weeks of aerobic training and green tea supplementation on cardiovascular risk factors in inactive overweight women. Horiz Med Sci. 2016;22:283&#x2013;9. doi: 10.18869/acadpub.hms.22.4.283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18869/acadpub.hms.22.4.283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javad V, Leila H. The effects of 8 weeks' aerobic exercise training along with green tea consumption on the cardiovascular risk factors in obese women. J Pract Stud Biosci Sport. 2015;3:78&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>