<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36159160</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Acute Effect of <i>In Natura</i> Beetroot Juice Intake on Intra-Session Exercise Sequences During Concurrent Training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1075</StartPage><EndPage>1085</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1075-1085</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The purpose of this study was to analyze the acute effects of <i>in natura</i> beetroot juice intake on intra-session exercise sequences during concurrent training. Following a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled crossover design, 20 well-trained men (21.4 &#xb1; 2.9 years; 74.8 &#xb1; 6.3 kg; 175.7 &#xb1; 5.0 cm) performed two concurrent training sessions with different intra-session exercise sequences: CT1 (aerobic exercise + resistance exercises) and CT2 (resistance exercises + aerobic exercise). The resistance exercises were bench-press, lat-pull down, and shoulder-press (three sets to failure; 2 s cadence for the concentric and eccentric phases; 90 s rest interval between sets and exercises; 75% 1RM), and the aerobic exercise was 4-km running. Each concurrent training session was randomized to placebo, beetroot juice, and control (no substances), totaling six exercise sessions. The rate of perceived exertion (RPE) was reported at the end of each exercise in each session. The beetroot juice significantly increased plasma nitric oxide concentration from 14.5 &#xb1; 3.9 mmol/L to 140.2 &#xb1; 37.5 mmol/L (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.01) and there was no significant change after placebo intake (13.8 &#xb1; 4.2 vs 15.1 &#xb1; 5.7 mmol/L). The 4-km running time was significantly less (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05) after beetroot juice intake in CT1 (17.0 &#xb1; 2.1 min) and CT2 (18.5 &#xb1; 1.9 min) than placebo (19.1 &#xb1; 3.2 and 22.2 &#xb1; 2.9 min, respectively) and control (19.4 &#xb1; 2.6 and 21.7 &#xb1; 3.0 min, respectively). No differences were identified in the total number of repetitions in resistance exercises and RPE. In conclusion, the acute intake of <i>in natura</i> beetroot juice decreased the 4-km running time independently of concurrent training exercise sequences. Our results may assist trainers in order to choose the supplement to increase performance.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DE Souza</LastName><ForeName>Diego Brito</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiology Exercise Laboratory, Camilo Jos&#xe9; Cela University, Madrid, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>J&#xfa;lio Nobile</ForeName><Initials>JN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Physical Education and Sport, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sim&#xe3;o</LastName><ForeName>Andreia Name Colado</ForeName><Initials>ANC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Pathology, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aguilar-Navarro</LastName><ForeName>Mill&#xe1;n</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Sport Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, Madrid, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Polito</LastName><ForeName>Marcos Doederlein</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Physical Education and Sport, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nitrates</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36159160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9458277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/RWZZ6847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijes-15-2-1075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bailey SJ, Fulford J, Vanhatalo A, Winyard PG, Blackwell JR, DiMenna FJ, Wilkerson DP, Benjamin N, Jones AM. Dietary nitrate supplementation enhances muscle contractile efficiency during knee-extensor exercise in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2010;109(1):135&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20466802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey SJ, Winyard P, Vanhatalo A, Blackwell JR, DiMenna FJ, Wilkerson DP, Tarr J, Benjamin N, Jones AM. Dietary nitrate supplementation reduces the O2 cost of low-intensity exercise and enhances tolerance to high-intensity exercise in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2009;107(4):1144&#x2013;1155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19661447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Borg&#x2019;s perceived exertion and pain scales. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo JL, Alorda-Capo F, Pareja-Galeano H, Jim&#xe9;nez SL. Influence of nitrate supplementation on endurance cyclic sports performance: A systematic review. Nutrients. 2020;12(6):1&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7353291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32560317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos HO, Drummond LR, Rodrigues QT, Machado FSM, Pires W, Wanner SP, Coimbra CC. Nitrate supplementation improves physical performance specifically in non-athletes during prolonged open-ended tests: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Nutr. 2018;119(6):636&#x2013;657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29553034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clements W, Lee SR, Bloomer R. Nitrate ingestion: A review of the health and physical performance effects. Nutrients. 2014;6:5224&#x2013;5264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4245587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25412154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deldicque L, Francaux M. Functional food for exercise performance: Fact or foe? Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2008;11:774&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18827583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eddens L, van Someren K, Howatson G. The role of intra-session exercise sequence in the interference effect: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48:177&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5752732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28917030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erzurum SC, Ghosh S, Janocha AJ, et al. Higher blood flow and circulating NO products offset high-altitude hypoxia among Tibetans. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2007;104:17593&#x2013;17598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2077056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17971439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flanagan SD, Looney DP, Miller MJS, DuPont WH, Pryor L, Creighton BC, Sterczala AJ, Szivak TK, Hooper DR, Maresh CM, Volek JS, Ellis LA, Kraemer WJ. The effects of nitrate-rich supplementation on neuromuscular efficiency during heavy resistance exercise. J Am Coll of Nutrition. 2016;35(2):100&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26885762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe JJ, Bishop DJ, Stepto NK. Interference between concurrent resistance and endurance exercise: molecular bases and the role of individual training variables. Sports Med. 2014;44:743&#x2013;762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24728927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoon MW, Johnson NA, Chapman PG, Burke LM. The effect of nitrate supplementation on exercise performance in healthy individuals: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2013;23:522&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23580439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones AM, Thompson C, Wylie LJ, Vanhatalo A. Dietary nitrate and physical performance. Ann Rev Nutrit. 2018;38:303&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30130468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lansley KE, Winyard PG, Fulford J, et al. Dietary nitrate supplementation reduces the O2 cost of walking and running: a placebo-controlled study. J Appl Physiol. 2011;110:591&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21071588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen F, Schiffer TA, Borniquel SJ, et al. Dietary inorganic nitrate improves mitochondrial efficiency in humans. Cell Metab. 2011;13:149&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21284982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg JO, Govoni M. Inorganic nitrate is a possible source for systemic generation of nitric oxide. Free Radic Biol Med. 2004;37:395&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15223073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg JO, Weitzberg E, Gladwin MT. The nitrate&#x2013;nitrite&#x2013;nitric oxide pathway in physiology and therapeutics. Nature Rev Drug Discov. 2008;7(2):156&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18167491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Burke LM, Dvorak J, Larson-Meyer DE, Peeling P, Phillips SM, Rawson ES, Walsh NP, Garthe, Geyer H, Meeusen R, van Loon LJC, Shirreffs SM, Spriet LL, Stuart M, Vernec A, Currell K, Ali VM, Budgett RG, et al. IOC consensus statement: Dietary supplements and the high-performance athlete. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(7):439&#x2013;455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29540367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon NF, Leveritt MD, Pavey TG. The effect of dietary nitrate supplementation on endurance exercise performance in healthy adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47:735&#x2013;756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27600147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Methenisis S. A brief review on concurrent training: From laboratory to the field. Sports (Basel) 2018;6:E127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6315763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30355976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosher SL, Andy Sparks S, Williams EL, Bentley DJ, Naughton LRM. Ingestion of a nitric oxide enhancing supplement improves resistance exercise performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(12):3520&#x2013;3524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27050244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navalta JW, Stone WJ, Lyons TS. Ethical issues relating to scientific discovery in exercise science. Int J Exerc Sci. 2019;12(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7523901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33042361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panissa VLG, Tricoli VAA, Julio UF, et al. Acute effect of high-intensity aerobic exercise performed on treadmill and cycle ergometer on strength performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29:1077&#x2013;1082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25259468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porcelli S, Ramaglia M, Bellistri G, Pavei G, Pugliese L, Montorsi M, Rasica L, Marzorati M. Aerobic fitness affects the exercise performance responses to nitrate supplementation. Med Sci Sports Exercise. 2015;47(8):1643&#x2013;1651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25412295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rimer EG, Peterson LR, Coggan AR, Martin JC. Acute dietary nitrate supplementation increases maximal cycling power in athletes. Int J Sport Physiol Perform. 2016;11:715&#x2013;720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4889556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26641379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi FE, Panissa VLG, Monteiro PA, et al. Caffeine supplementation affects the immunometabolic response to concurrent training. J Exerc Rehabil. 2017;30:179&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5412491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28503530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shannon OM, Barlow MJ, Duckworth L, Williams E, Wort G, Woods D, Siervo M, O&#x2019;Hara JP. Dietary nitrate supplementation enhances short but not longer duration running time-trial performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(4):775&#x2013;785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28251402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza DB, Duncan M, Polito MD. Improvement of lower-body resistance-exercise performance with blood-flow restriction following acute caffeine intake. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14:216&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30039986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegelhalder B, Eisenbiund G, Preussmann R. Influence of dietary nitrate on nitrite content of human saliva: possible relevance to in formation of n-nitroso compounds. Food Cosmet Toxicol. 1976;14:545&#x2013;548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1017769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trexler ET, Keith DS, Schwartz TA, et al. Effects of citrulline malate and beetroot juice supplementation on blood flow, energy metabolism and performance during maximum effort leg extension exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:2321&#x2013;2329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31343548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanhatalo A, Bailey SJ, Blackwell JR, DiMenna FJ, Pavey TG, Wilkerson DP, Benjamin N, Winyard PG, Jones AM. Acute and chronic effects of dietary nitrate supplementation on blood pressure and the physiological responses to moderate-intensity and incremental exercise. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Compar Physiology. 2010;299(4):R1121&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20702806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas-Maya NI, Padilla-Vaca F, Romero-Gonz&#xe1;lez OE, Rosales-Castillo EAS, Rangel-Serrano A, Arias-Negrete S, Franco B. Refinement of the Griess method for measuring nitrite in biological samples. J Microbiol Methods. 2021;187:106260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34090997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams TD, Martin MP, Mintz JA. Effects of acute beetroot juice supplementation on bench press power, velocity and repetition volume. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34:924&#x2013;928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31913252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Marin PJ, Rhea MR, Wilson SMC, Loenneke JP, Anderson JC. Concurrent training: A meta-analysis examining interference of aerobic and resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(8):2293&#x2013;2307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22002517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>