<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40275593</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-445X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Myocellular adaptations to short-term weighted wheel-running exercise are largely conserved during C26-tumour induction in male and female mice.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/EP092504</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study investigated whether performing a translatable murine model of concurrent training after tumour induction affects adaptations in juvenile male and female tumour-bearing mice. Male and female Balb/c mice were injected bilaterally with colon-26 adenocarcinoma (C26) cells or PBS at 8&#xa0;weeks of age. Half the mice then performed 24&#xa0;days of voluntary wheel running with progressively increased load (PoWeR training), whereas the rest remained sedentary. Deuterium oxide-based protein synthesis, muscle fibre-type composition and size, protein turnover and mitochondrial markers were assessed 25 days after tumour induction. Average gastrocnemius muscle fibre size was smaller with PoWeR regardless of tumour in males and females, concomitant with a pronounced faster-to-slower fibre-type transition. In male tumour-bearing mice, PoWeR training resulted in greater Redd1, Murf1 and Pgc1&#x3b1; mRNA content than all the other groups, along with lower overall running volume, food consumption and protein synthesis relative to control animals. Molecular measures followed a similar pattern in tumour-bearing female mice with PoWeR, but food consumption, running volume and muscle protein synthesis were maintained. PoWeR training lowered gonadal fat during cancer cachexia in both sexes, and greater heart weight was observed regardless of tumour presence. A negative correlation was found between tumour weight and running distance. Collectively, PoWeR has a similar effect on muscle cellular phenotype in both sexes regardless of tumour presence, and a training effect in male mice with cancer cachexia was present despite molecular and protein synthesis dysregulation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Experimental Physiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsitkanou</LastName><ForeName>Stavroula</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6753-5945</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cachexia Research Laboratory, Exercise Science Research Center, Department of Health, Human Performance and Recreation, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koopmans</LastName><ForeName>Pieter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4797-5265</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Molecular Muscle Mass Regulation Laboratory, Exercise Science Research Center, Department of Health, Human Performance and Recreation, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cell and Molecular Biology Program, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peterson</LastName><ForeName>Calvin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Molecular Muscle Mass Regulation Laboratory, Exercise Science Research Center, Department of Health, Human Performance and Recreation, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cabrera</LastName><ForeName>Ana Regina</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cachexia Research Laboratory, Exercise Science Research Center, Department of Health, Human Performance and Recreation, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muhyudin</LastName><ForeName>Ruqaiza</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cachexia Research Laboratory, Exercise Science Research Center, Department of Health, Human Performance and Recreation, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cell and Molecular Biology Program, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morena</LastName><ForeName>Francielly</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cachexia Research Laboratory, Exercise Science Research Center, Department of Health, Human Performance and Recreation, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khadgi</LastName><ForeName>Sabin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Molecular Muscle Mass Regulation Laboratory, Exercise Science Research Center, Department of Health, Human Performance and Recreation, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schrems</LastName><ForeName>Eleanor R</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Muscle Biology Laboratory, Exercise Science Research Center, Department of Health, Human Performance and Recreation, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Washington</LastName><ForeName>Tyrone A</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1919-5907</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Muscle Biology Laboratory, Exercise Science Research Center, Department of Health, Human Performance and Recreation, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murach</LastName><ForeName>Kevin A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Molecular Muscle Mass Regulation Laboratory, Exercise Science Research Center, Department of Health, Human Performance and Recreation, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cell and Molecular Biology Program, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greene</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas P</ForeName><Initials>NP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cachexia Research Laboratory, Exercise Science Research Center, Department of Health, Human Performance and Recreation, University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, Arkansas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P20 GM125503</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01AR075794-01A1/AR/NIAMS</GrantID><Acronym>AR</Acronym><Agency>NIAMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>AG080047</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AR075794</GrantID><Acronym>AR</Acronym><Agency>NIAMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><Acronym>NH</Acronym><Agency>NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P20GM125503</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>AG063994</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><Agency>Arkansas Biosciences Institute: Tobacco Settlement Award 2022-2023</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9002940</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0958-0670</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">catabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">colorectal cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concurrent training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle fibre&#x2010;type transition</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40275593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP092504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Adraskela, K., Veisaki, E., Koutsilieris, M., &amp; Philippou, A. (2017). Physical exercise positively influences breast cancer evolution. Clinical Breast Cancer, 17(6), 408&#x2013;417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansdell, P., Brownstein, C. G., Skarabot, J., Hicks, K. M., Howatson, G., Thomas, K., Hunter, S. K., &amp; Goodall, S. (2019). Sex differences in fatigability and recovery relative to the intensity&#x2010;duration relationship. The Journal of Physiology, 597(23), 5577&#x2013;5595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansdell, P., Thomas, K., Hicks, K. M., Hunter, S. K., Howatson, G., &amp; Goodall, S. (2020). Physiological sex differences affect the integrative response to exercise: Acute and chronic implications. Experimental Physiology, 105(12), 2007&#x2013;2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argiles, J. M., Busquets, S., Lopez&#x2010;Soriano, F. J., Costelli, P., &amp; Penna, F. (2012). Are there any benefits of exercise training in cancer cachexia? Journal of Cachexia, Sarcopenia and Muscle, 3, 73&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argiles, J. M., Busquets, S., Stemmler, B., &amp; Lopez&#x2010;Soriano, F. J. (2014). Cancer cachexia: Understanding the molecular basis. Nature Reviews Cancer, 14(11), 754&#x2013;762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballaro, R., Penna, F., Pin, F., Gomez&#x2010;Cabrera, M. C., Vina, J., &amp; Costelli, P. (2019). Moderate exercise improves experimental cancer cachexia by modulating the redox homeostasis. Cancers (Basel), 11(3), 285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bittel, A. J., Bittel, D. C., Gordish&#x2010;Dressman, H., &amp; Chen, Y. W. (2024). Voluntary wheel running improves molecular and functional deficits in a murine model of facioscapulohumeral muscular dystrophy. Iscience, 27(1), 108632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonetto, A., Rupert, J. E., Barreto, R., &amp; Zimmers, T. A. (2016). The Colon&#x2010;26 carcinoma tumor&#x2010;bearing mouse as a model for the study of cancer cachexia. Journal of visualized experiments: JoVE, 117, 54893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bordignon, C., dos Santos, B. S., &amp; Rosa, D. D. (2022). Impact of cancer cachexia on cardiac and skeletal muscle: Role of exercise training. Cancers (Basel), 14(2), 342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, J. L., Rosa&#x2010;Caldwell, M. E., Lee, D. E., Blackwell, T. A., Brown, L. A., Perry, R. A., Haynie, W. S., Hardee, J. P., Carson, J. A., Wiggs, M. P., Washington, T. A., &amp; Greene, N. P. (2017). Mitochondrial degeneration precedes the development of muscle atrophy in progression of cancer cachexia in tumour&#x2010;bearing mice. Journal of Cachexia, Sarcopenia and Muscle, 8(6), 926&#x2013;938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera, A. R., Deaver, J. W., Lim, S., Morena da Silva, F., Schrems, E. R., Saling, L. W., Tsitkanou, S., Rosa&#x2010;Caldwell, M. E., Wiggs, M. P., Washington, T. A., &amp; Greene, N. P. (2023). Females display relatively preserved muscle quality compared with males during the onset and early stages of C26&#x2010;induced cancer cachexia. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 135(3), 655&#x2013;672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canto, C., &amp; Auwerx, J. (2009). PGC&#x2010;1alpha, SIRT1 and AMPK, an energy sensing network that controls energy expenditure. Current Opinion in Lipidology, 20(2), 98&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collao, N., Sanders, O., Caminiti, T., Messeiller, L., &amp; de Lisio, M. (2023). Resistance and endurance exercise training improves muscle mass and the inflammatory/fibrotic transcriptome in a rhabdomyosarcoma model. Journal of Cachexia, Sarcopenia and Muscle, 14(2), 781&#x2013;793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courneya, K. S., Mackey, J. R., &amp; Jones, L. W. (2000). Coping with cancer: Can exercise help? Physician and Sportsmedicine, 28(5), 49&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delfinis, L. J., Bellissimo, C. A., Gandhi, S., DiBenedetto, S. N., Garibotti, M. C., Thuhan, A. K., Tsitkanou, S., Rosa&#x2010;Caldwell, M. E., Rahman, F. A., Cheng, A. J., Wiggs, M. P., Schlattner, U., Quadrilatero, J., Greene, N. P., &amp; Perry, C. G. (2022). Muscle weakness precedes atrophy during cancer cachexia and is linked to muscle&#x2010;specific mitochondrial stress. JCI Insight, 7(24), e155147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dungan, C. M., Brightwell, C. R., Wen, Y., Zdunek, C. J., Latham, C. M., Thomas, N. T., Zagzoog, A. M., Brightwell, B. D., VonLehmden, G. L., Keeble, A. R., Watowich, S. J., Murach, K. A., &amp; Fry, C. S. (2022). Muscle&#x2010;specific cellular and molecular adaptations to late&#x2010;life voluntary concurrent exercise. Function (Oxford), 3(4), zqac027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dungan, C. M., Murach, K. A., Frick, K. K., Jones, S. R., Crow, S. E., Englund, D. A., Vechetti, I. J., Jr., Figueiredo, V. C., Levitan, B. M., Satin, J., McCarthy, J. J., &amp; Peterson, C. A. (2019). Elevated myonuclear density during skeletal muscle hypertrophy in response to training is reversed during detraining. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Cell Physiology, 316(5), C649&#x2013;C654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Englund, D. A., Figueiredo, V. C., Dungan, C. M., Murach, K. A., Peck, B. D., Petrosino, J. M., Brightwell, C. R., Dupont, A. M., Neal, A. C., Fry, C. S., Accornero, F., McCarthy, J. J., &amp; Peterson, C. A. (2021). Satellite cell depletion disrupts transcriptional coordination and muscle adaptation to exercise. Function (Oxford), 2(1), zqaa033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fearon, K., Strasser, F., Anker, S. D., Bosaeus, I., Bruera, E., Fainsinger, R. L., Jatoi, A., Loprinzi, C., MacDonald, N., Mantovani, G., Davis, M., Muscaritoli, M., Ottery, F., Radbruch, L., Ravasco, P., Walsh, D., Wilcock, A., Kaasa, S., &amp; Baracos, V. E. (2011). Definition and classification of cancer cachexia: An international consensus. The Lancet Oncology, 12(5), 489&#x2013;495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvao, D. A., Taaffe, D. R., Spry, N., Joseph, D., &amp; Newton, R. U. (2010). Combined resistance and aerobic exercise program reverses muscle loss in men undergoing androgen suppression therapy for prostate cancer without bone metastases: A randomized controlled trial. Journal of Clinical Oncology, 28(2), 340&#x2013;347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasier, H. G., Riechman, S. E., Wiggs, M. P., Previs, S. F., &amp; Fluckey, J. D. (2009). A comparison of 2H2O and phenylalanine flooding dose to investigate muscle protein synthesis with acute exercise in rats. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Endocrinology and Metabolism, 297(1), E252&#x2013;E259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene, N. P., Lee, D. E., Brown, J. L., Rosa, M. E., Brown, L. A., Perry, R. A., Henry, J. N., &amp; Washington, T. A. (2015). Mitochondrial quality control, promoted by PGC&#x2010;1alpha, is dysregulated by Western diet&#x2010;induced obesity and partially restored by moderate physical activity in mice. Physiological Reports, 3(7), e12470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardee, J. P., Mangum, J. E., Gao, S., Sato, S., Hetzler, K. L., Puppa, M. J., Fix, D. K., &amp; Carson, J. A. (2016). Eccentric contraction&#x2010;induced myofiber growth in tumor&#x2010;bearing mice. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 120(1), 29&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamoui, A. V., Park, B. S., Kim, D. H., Yeh, M. C., Oh, S. L., Elam, M. L., Jo, E., Arjmandi, B. H., Salazar, G., Grant, S. C., Contreras, R. J., Lee, W. J., &amp; Kim, J. S. (2016). Aerobic and resistance training dependent skeletal muscle plasticity in the colon&#x2010;26 murine model of cancer cachexia. Metabolism, 65(5), 685&#x2013;698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim, S., Deaver, J. W., Rosa&#x2010;Caldwell, M. E., Haynie, W. S., Morena da Silva, F., Cabrera, A. R., Schrems, E. R., Saling, L. W., Jansen, L. T., Dunlap, K. R., Wiggs, M. P., Washington, T. A., &amp; Greene, N. P. (2022). Development of metabolic and contractile alterations in development of cancer cachexia in female tumor&#x2010;bearing mice. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 132(1), 58&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, J., Wu, H., Tarr, P. T., Zhang, C. Y., Wu, Z., Boss, O., Michael, L. F., Puigserver, P., Isotani, E., Olson, E. N., Lowell, B. B., Bassel&#x2010;Duby, R., &amp; Spiegelman, B. M. (2002). Transcriptional co&#x2010;activator PGC&#x2010;1 alpha drives the formation of slow&#x2010;twitch muscle fibres. Nature, 418(6899), 797&#x2013;801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lira, F. S., Neto, J. C., &amp; Seelaender, M. (2014). Exercise training as treatment in cancer cachexia. Applied Physiology, Nutrition and Metabolism, 39(6), 679&#x2013;686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livak, K. J., &amp; Schmittgen, T. D. (2001). Analysis of relative gene expression data using real&#x2010;time quantitative PCR and the 2(&#x2212;Delta Delta C(T)) method. Methods (San Diego, California), 25(4), 402&#x2013;408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morena, F., Cabrera, A. R., Jones, III R. G., Schrems, E. R., Muhyudin, R., Washington, T. A., Murach, K. A., &amp; Greene, N. P. (2024). Transcriptional analysis of cancer cachexia: Conserved and unique features across pre&#x2010;clinical models and biological sex. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Cell Physiology, 327(6), C1514&#x2013;C1531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murach, K. A., Dungan, C. M., Peterson, C. A., &amp; McCarthy, J. J. (2019). Muscle fiber splitting is a physiological response to extreme loading in animals. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews, 47(2), 108&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murach, K. A., McCarthy, J. J., Peterson, C. A., &amp; Dungan, C. M. (2020). Making mice mighty: Recent advances in translational models of load&#x2010;induced muscle hypertrophy. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 129(3), 516&#x2013;521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murach, K. A., Mobley, C. B., Zdunek, C. J., Frick, K. K., Jones, S. R., McCarthy, J. J., Peterson, C. A., &amp; Dungan, C. M. (2020). Muscle memory: Myonuclear accretion, maintenance, morphology, and miRNA levels with training and detraining in adult mice. Journal of Cachexia, Sarcopenia and Muscle, 11(6), 1705&#x2013;1722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pigna, E., Berardi, E., Aulino, P., Rizzuto, E., Zampieri, S., Carraro, U., Kern, H., Merigliano, S., Gruppo, M., Mericskay, M., Li, Z., Rocchi, M., Barone, R., Macaluso, F., Di Felice, V., Adamo, S., Coletti, D., &amp; Moresi, V. (2016). Aerobic exercise and pharmacological treatments counteract cachexia by modulating autophagy in colon cancer. Scientific Reports, 6, 26991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pin, F., Busquets, S., Toledo, M., Camperi, A., Lopez&#x2010;Soriano, F. J., Costelli, P., Argiles, J. M., &amp; Penna, F. (2015). Combination of exercise training and erythropoietin prevents cancer&#x2010;induced muscle alterations. Oncotarget, 6(41), 43202&#x2013;43215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puppa, M. J., White, J. P., Velazquez, K. T., Baltgalvis, K. A., Sato, S., Baynes, J. W., &amp; Carson, J. A. (2012). The effect of exercise on IL&#x2010;6&#x2010;induced cachexia in the Apc (Min/+) mouse. Journal of Cachexia, Sarcopenia and Muscle, 3(2), 117&#x2013;137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjbar, K., Ballaro, R., Bover, Q., Pin, F., Beltra, M., Penna, F., &amp; Costelli, P. (2019). Combined exercise training positively affects muscle wasting in tumor&#x2010;bearing mice. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 51(7), 1387&#x2013;1395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasbach, K. A., Gupta, R. K., Ruas, J. L., Wu, J., Naseri, E., Estall, J. L., &amp; Spiegelman, B. M. (2010). PGC&#x2010;1alpha regulates a HIF2alpha&#x2010;dependent switch in skeletal muscle fiber types. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 107(50), 21866&#x2013;21871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosa&#x2010;Caldwell, M. E., &amp; Greene, N. P. (2019). Muscle metabolism and atrophy: Let's talk about sex. Biology of Sex Differences, 10(1), 43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosa&#x2010;Caldwell, M. E., Lim, S., Haynie, W. A., Brown, J. L., Deaver, J. W., Morena da Silva, F., Jansen, L. T., Lee, D. E., Wiggs, M. P., Washington, T. A., &amp; Greene, N. P. (2021). Female mice may have exacerbated catabolic signalling response compared to male mice during development and progression of disuse atrophy. Journal of Cachexia, Sarcopenia and Muscle, 12(3), 717&#x2013;730.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosa&#x2010;Caldwell, M. E., Lim, S., Haynie, W. S., Brown, J. L., Lee, D. E., Dunlap, K. R., Jansen, L. T., Washington, T. A., Wiggs, M. P., &amp; Greene, N. P. (2021). Mitochondrial aberrations during the progression of disuse atrophy differentially affect male and female mice. Journal of Cachexia, Sarcopenia and Muscle, 12(6), 2056&#x2013;2068.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato, S., Gao, S., Puppa, M. J., Kostek, M. C., Wilson, L. B., &amp; Carson, J. A. (2019). High&#x2010;frequency stimulation on skeletal muscle maintenance in female cachectic mice. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 51(9), 1828&#x2013;1837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tichy, L., &amp; Parry, T. L. (2023). The pathophysiology of cancer&#x2010;mediated cardiac cachexia and novel treatment strategies: A narrative review. Cancer Medicine, 12(17), 17706&#x2013;17717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsitkanou, S., Morena da Silva, F., Cabrera, A. R., Schrems, E. R., Muhyudin, R., Koopmans, P. J., Khadgi, S., Lim, S., Delfinis, L. J., Washington, T. A., Murach, K. A., Perry, C. G. R., &amp; Greene, N. P. (2024). Mitochondrial antioxidant SkQ1 attenuates C26 cancer&#x2010;induced muscle wasting in males and improves muscle contractility in female tumor&#x2010;bearing mice. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Cell Physiology, 327(5), C1308&#x2013;C1322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsitkanou, S., Morena da Silva, F., Cabrera, A. R., Schrems, E. R., Murach, K. A., Washington, T. A., Rosa&#x2010;Caldwell, M. E., &amp; Greene, N. P. (2023). Biological sex divergence in transcriptomic profiles during the onset of hindlimb unloading&#x2010;induced atrophy. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Cell Physiology, 325(5), C1276&#x2013;C1293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsitkanou, S., Murach, K. A., Washington, T. A., &amp; Greene, N. P. (2022). Exercise counteracts the deleterious effects of cancer cachexia. Cancers (Basel), 14(10), 2512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viggars, M. R., Wen, Y., Peterson, C. A., &amp; Jarvis, J. C. (2022). Automated cross&#x2010;sectional analysis of trained, severely atrophied, and recovering rat skeletal muscles using MyoVision 2.0. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 132(3), 593&#x2013;610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen, Y., Murach, K. A., Vechetti, I. J. Jr., Fry, C. S., Vickery, C., Peterson, C. A., McCarthy, J. J., &amp; Campbell, K. S. (2018). MyoVision: Software for automated high&#x2010;content analysis of skeletal muscle immunohistochemistry. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 124(1), 40&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West, D. W., Burd, N. A., Churchward&#x2010;Venne, T. A., Camera, D. M., Mitchell, C. J., Baker, S. K., Hawley, J. A., Coffey, V. G., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2012). Sex&#x2010;based comparisons of myofibrillar protein synthesis after resistance exercise in the fed state. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 112(11), 1805&#x2013;1813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolin, K. Y., Schwartz, A. L., Matthews, C. E., Courneya, K. S., &amp; Schmitz, K. H. (2012). Implementing the exercise guidelines for cancer survivors. The Journal of Supportive Oncology, 10(5), 171&#x2013;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood, N. R., Garritson, J., Mathias, A., Haughian, J. M., &amp; Hayward, R. (2022). Moderate intensity endurance and resistance exercise attenuates cachexia in tumor&#x2010;bearing mice. Anticancer Research, 42(1), 397&#x2013;405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, X., &amp; Zimmers, T. A. (2020). Sex differences in cancer cachexia. Current Osteoporosis Reports, 18(6), 646&#x2013;654.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>