<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32282529</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Modulation of Countermovement Jump-Derived Markers of Neuromuscular Function With Concurrent vs. Single-Mode Resistance Training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1497</StartPage><EndPage>1502</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1497-1502</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003587</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Pattison, KJ, Drinkwater, EJ, Bishop, DJ, Stepto, NK, and Fyfe, JJ. Modulation of countermovement jump-derived markers of neuromuscular function with concurrent vs. single-mode resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 34(6): 1497-1502, 2020-This study assessed changes in countermovement jump (CMJ)-derived markers of neuromuscular function with concurrent training vs. resistance training (RT) alone and determined associations between changes in CMJ parameters and other neuromuscular adaptations (e.g., maximal strength gain). Twenty-three recreationally active men performed 8 weeks of RT alone (RT group, n = 8) or combined with either high-intensity interval training cycling (HIIT + RT group, n = 8) or moderate-intensity continuous cycling (MICT + RT group, n = 7). Maximal strength and CMJ performance were assessed before (PRE), after 4 weeks of training (MID), and &gt;72 hours (maximal strength) or &gt;5-7 days (CMJ performance) after (POST) the training intervention. Improvements in CMJ relative peak force from both PRE to MID and PRE to POST were attenuated for both HIIT + RT (effect size [ES]: -0.44; &#xb1;90% confidence limit, &#xb1;0.51 and ES: -0.72; &#xb1;0.61, respectively) and MICT + RT (ES: -0.74; &#xb1;0.49 and ES: -1.25; &#xb1;0.63, respectively). Compared with RT alone, the change in the flight time to contraction time ratio (FT:CT) was attenuated from PRE to MID for MICT + RT (ES: -0.38; &#xb1;0.42) and from PRE to POST for both MICT + RT (ES: -0.60; &#xb1;0.55) and HIIT + RT (ES: -0.75; &#xb1;0.30). PRE to POST changes in both CMJ relative peak force and flight time:contraction time (F:C) ratio were also associated with relative 1 repetition maximum leg press strength gain (r = 0.26 and 0.19, respectively). These findings highlight the utility of CMJ testing for monitoring interference to improvements in neuromuscular function with concurrent training.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pattison</LastName><ForeName>Kristy J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport Research (CSR), Deakin University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drinkwater</LastName><ForeName>Eric J</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport Research (CSR), Deakin University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bishop</LastName><ForeName>David J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stepto</LastName><ForeName>Nigel K</ForeName><Initials>NK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Monash Center for Health Research and Implementation, School of Public Health and Preventive Medicine, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute for Musculoskeletal Science (AIMSS), University of Melbourne, Victoria University and Western Health, Sunshine Hospital, St Albans, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Dentistry and Health Science, Medicine West, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fyfe</LastName><ForeName>Jackson J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport Research (CSR), Deakin University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072696" MajorTopicYN="N">High-Intensity Interval Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D035002" MajorTopicYN="N">Lower Extremity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32282529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202006000-00001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Balabinis CP, Psarakis CH, Moukas M, Vassiliou MP, Behrakis PK. Early phase changes by concurrent endurance and strength training. J Strength Cond Res 17: 393&#x2013;401, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben&#xed;tez-Flores S, Medeiros AR, Voltarelli FA, et al. Combined effects of very short all out efforts during sprint and resistance training on physical and physiological adaptations after 2 weeks of training. Eur J Appl Physiol 119: 1337&#x2013;1351, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtara M, Chaouachi A, Levin GT, et al. Effect of concurrent endurance and circuit resistance training sequence on muscular strength and power development. J Strength Cond Res 22: 1037&#x2013;1045, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino JG, Cronin J, Mezencio B, et al. The countermovement jump to monitor neuromuscular status: A meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport 20: 397&#x2013;402, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormack SJ, Newton RU, McGuigan MR, Cormie P. Neuromuscular and endocrine responses of elite players during an Australian rules football season. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 3: 439&#x2013;453, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. The adaptations to strength training: Morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med 37: 145&#x2013;168, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe JJ, Bartlett JD, Hanson ED, Stepto NK, Bishop DJ. Endurance training intensity does not mediate interference to maximal lower-body strength gain during short-term concurrent training. Front Physiol 7: 487, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gathercole R, Sporer B, Stellingwerff T, Sleivert G. Alternative countermovement-jump analysis to quantify acute neuromuscular fatigue. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 10: 84&#x2013;92, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley JA. Adaptations of skeletal muscle to prolonged, intense endurance training. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol 29: 218&#x2013;222, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 3&#x2013;13, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. Spreadsheets for analysis of controlled trials, crossovers and time series. Sportscience 21: 1&#x2013;4, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Vescovi JD, Volek JS, et al. Effects of concurrent resistance and aerobic training on load-bearing performance and the Army physical fitness test. Mil Med 169: 994&#x2013;999, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet GY, Lepers R. Alterations of neuromuscular function after prolonged running, cycling and skiing exercises. Sports Med 34: 105&#x2013;116, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo JL, McBride JM, Cormie P, McCaulley GO. Relationship between countermovement jump performance and multijoint isometric and dynamic tests of strength. J Strength Cond Res 22: 699&#x2013;707, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sousa AC, Marinho DA, Gil MH, et al. Concurrent training followed by detraining: Does the resistance training intensity matter? J Strength Cond Res 32: 632&#x2013;642, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiliopoulou P, Zaras N, Methenitis S, et al. Effect of concurrent power training and high-intensity interval cycling on muscle morphology and performance. J Strength Cond Res 2019. Epub ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talpey SW, Axtell R, Gardner E, James L. Changes in lower body muscular performance following a season of NCAA Division I men's lacrosse. Sports (Basel) 7: E18, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terzis G, Spengos K, Methenitis S, et al. Early phase interference between low-intensity running and power training in moderately trained females. Eur J Appl Physiol 116: 1063&#x2013;1073, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Marin PJ, Rhea MR, et al. Concurrent training: A meta-analysis examining interference of aerobic and resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res 26: 2293&#x2013;2307, 2012.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>