<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25902785</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2051-817X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physiological reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Physiol Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute molecular responses to concurrent resistance and high-intensity interval exercise in untrained skeletal muscle.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e12364</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.14814/phy2.12364</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Concurrent training involving resistance and endurance exercise may augment the benefits of single-mode training for the purpose of improving health. However, muscle adaptations, associated with resistance exercise, may be blunted by a subsequent bout of endurance exercise, via molecular interference. High-intensity interval training (HIIT), generating similar adaptations to endurance exercise, may offer an alternative exercise mode to traditional endurance exercise. This study examined the influence of an acute HIIT session on the molecular responses following resistance exercise in untrained skeletal muscle. Ten male participants performed resistance exercise (4&#xa0;&#xd7;&#xa0;8 leg extensions, 70% 1RM, (RE)) or RE followed by HIIT (10&#xa0;&#xd7;&#xa0;1&#xa0;min at 90% HRmax, (RE+HIIT)). Muscle biopsies were collected from the vastus lateralis before, 2 and 6&#xa0;h post-RE to determine intramuscular protein phosphorylation and mRNA responses. Phosphorylation of Akt (Ser(473)) decreased at 6&#xa0;h in both trials (P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05). Phosphorylation of mTOR (Ser(2448)) was higher in RE+HIIT (P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05). All PGC-1&#x3b1; mRNA variants increased at 2&#xa0;h in RE+HIIT with PGC-1&#x3b1; and PGC-1&#x3b1;-ex1b remaining elevated at 6&#xa0;h, whereas RE-induced increases at 2 and 6&#xa0;h for PGC-1&#x3b1;-ex1b only (P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05). Myostatin expression decreased at 2 and 6&#xa0;h in both trials (P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05). MuRF-1 was elevated in RE+HIIT versus RE at 2 and 6&#xa0;h (P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05). Atrogin-1 was lower at 2&#xa0;h, with FOXO3A downregulated at 6&#xa0;h (P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05). These data do not support the existence of an acute interference effect on protein signaling and mRNA expression, and suggest that HIIT may be an alternative to endurance exercise when performed after resistance exercise in the same training session to optimize adaptations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2015 The Authors. Physiological Reports published by Wiley Periodicals, Inc. on behalf of the American Physiological Society and The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pugh</LastName><ForeName>Jamie K</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport Exercise and Health Sciences Loughborough University, Loughborough, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Faulkner</LastName><ForeName>Steve H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport Exercise and Health Sciences Loughborough University, Loughborough, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jackson</LastName><ForeName>Andrew P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport Exercise and Health Sciences Loughborough University, Loughborough, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>King</LastName><ForeName>James A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport Exercise and Health Sciences Loughborough University, Loughborough, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nimmo</LastName><ForeName>Myra A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport Exercise and Health Sciences Loughborough University, Loughborough, UK College of Life and Environmental Sciences University of Birmingham, Birmingham, UK m.a.nimmo@bham.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MR/K00414X/1</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Physiol Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101607800</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2051-817X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute responses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cellular signaling interference</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concurrent exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high&#x2010;intensity interval training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">human skeletal muscle</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2015</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25902785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4425969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.12364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">3/4/e12364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Apr&#xf3; W, Wang L, Pont&#xe9;n M, Blomstrand E. Sahlin K. Resistance exercise induced mTORC1 signaling is not impaired by subsequent endurance exercise in human skeletal muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2013;305:E22&#x2013;E32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23632629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arany Z. PGC-1 coactivators and skeletal muscle adaptations in health and disease. Curr. Opin. Genet. Dev. 2008;18:426&#x2013;434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2629557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18782618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baar K. Esser K. Phosphorylation of p70(S6k) correlates with increased skeletal muscle mass following resistance exercise. Am. J. Physiol. 1999;276:C120&#x2013;C127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9886927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babcock L, Escano M, D'Lugos A, Todd K, Murach K. Luden N. Concurrent aerobic exercise interferes with the satellite cell response to acute resistance exercise. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 2012;302:R1458&#x2013;R1465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22492813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman MM, Shipp JR, Jiang J, Gower BA, Hunter GR, Goodman A, et al. Mechanical load increases muscle IGF-I and androgen receptor mRNA concentrations in humans. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2001;280:E383&#x2013;E390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11171591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel C. Slade J. Time course of molecular responses of human skeletal muscle to acute bouts of resistance exercise. J. Appl. Physiol. 2005;98:482&#x2013;488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15465884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel CS, Slade JM, Haddad F, Adams GR. Dudley GA. Acute molecular responses of skeletal muscle to resistance exercise in able-bodied and spinal cord-injured subjects. J. Appl. Physiol. 2003;94:2255&#x2013;2262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12611774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodine SC, Stitt TN, Gonzalez M, Kline WO, Stover GL, Bauerlein R, et al. Akt/mTOR pathway is a crucial regulator of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and can prevent muscle atrophy in vivo. Nat. Cell Biol. 2001;3:1014&#x2013;1019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11715023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Borg's perceived exertion and pain scales. Champagin, IL: Human Kinetics; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borgenvik M, Apr&#xf3; W. Blomstrand E. Intake of branched-chain amino acids influences the levels of MAFbx mRNA and MuRF-1 total protein in resting and exercising human muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2012;302:E510&#x2013;E521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22127230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browne GJ. Proud CG. Regulation of peptide-chain elongation in mammalian cells. Eur. J. Biochem. 2002;269:5360&#x2013;5368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12423334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgomaster KA, Howarth KR, Phillips SM, Rakobowchuk M, Macdonald MJ, McGee SL, et al. Similar metabolic adaptations during exercise after low volume sprint interval and traditional endurance training in humans. J. Physiol. 2008;586:151&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17991697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camera DM, West DWD, Phillips SM, Rerecich T, Stellingwerff T, Hawley JA, et al. Protein Ingestion Increases Myofibrillar Protein Synthesis after Concurrent Exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2015;47:82&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24870574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chief Medical Office. 2011. Physical Activity Guidelines in the UK: Review and Recommendations.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey VG, Jemiolo B, Edge J, Garnham AP, Trappe SW. Hawley JA. Effect of consecutive repeated sprint and resistance exercise bouts on acute adaptive responses in human skeletal muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 2009a;297:R1441&#x2013;R1451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19692661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey VG, Pilegaard H, Garnham AP, O'Brien BJ. Hawley JA. Consecutive bouts of diverse contractile activity alter acute responses in human skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. 2009b;106:1187&#x2013;1197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19164772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyle EF. Very intense exercise-training is extremely potent and time efficient: a reminder. J. Appl. Physiol. 2005;98:1983&#x2013;1984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15894535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuthbertson D, Smith K, Babraj J, Leese G, Waddell T, Atherton P, et al. Anabolic signaling deficits underlie amino acid resistance of wasting, aging muscle. FASEB J. 2005;19:422&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15596483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deldicque L, De Bock K, Maris M, Ramaekers M, Nielens H, Francaux M, et al. Increased p70s6k phosphorylation during intake of a protein&#x2013;carbohydrate drink following resistance exercise in the fasted state. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2009;108:791&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20187284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donges CE, Burd NA, Duffield R, Smith GC, West DWD, Short MJ, et al. Concurrent resistance and aerobic exercise stimulates both myofibrillar and mitochondrial protein synthesis in sedentary middle-aged men. J. Appl. Physiol. 2012;112:1992&#x2013;2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22492939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer HC, Fujita S, Cadenas JG, Chinkes DL, Volpi E. Rasmussen BB. Resistance exercise increases AMPK activity and reduces 4E-BP1 phosphorylation and protein synthesis in human skeletal muscle. J. Physiol. 2006;576:613&#x2013;624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1890364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16873412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer HC, Drummond MJ, Pennings B, Fujita S, Glynn EL, Chinkes DL, et al. Leucine-enriched essential amino acid and carbohydrate ingestion following resistance exercise enhances mTOR signaling and protein synthesis in human muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2008;294:E392&#x2013;E400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2706121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18056791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer HC, Fujita S, Glynn EL, Drummond MJ, Volpi E. Rasmussen BB. Resistance exercise increases leg muscle protein synthesis and mTOR signalling independent of sex. Acta Physiol. 2010;199:71&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2881180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20070283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan B. Zierath JR. Exercise metabolism and the molecular regulation of skeletal muscle adaptation. Cell Metab. 2013;17:162&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23395166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eliasson J, Elfegoun T, Nilsson J, K&#xf6;hnke R, Ekblom B. Blomstrand E. Maximal lengthening contractions increase p70 S6 kinase phosphorylation in human skeletal muscle in the absence of nutritional supply. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2006;291:E1197&#x2013;E1205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16835402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foletta VC, White LJ, Larsen AE, L&#xe9;ger B. Russell AP. The role and regulation of MAFbx/atrogin-1 and MuRF1 in skeletal muscle atrophy. Pfl&#xfc;gers Arch. 2011;461:325&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21221630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Dreyer HC, Drummond MJ, Glynn EL, Cadenas JG, Yoshizawa F, et al. Nutrient signalling in the regulation of human muscle protein synthesis. J. Physiol. 2007;582:813&#x2013;823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2075348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17478528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, Franklin BA, Lamonte MJ, Lee I-M, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1334&#x2013;1359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibala MJ, Little JP, van Essen M, Wilkin GP, Burgomaster KA, Safdar A, et al. Short-term sprint interval versus traditional endurance training: similar initial adaptations in human skeletal muscle and exercise performance. J. Physiol. 2006;575:901&#x2013;911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1995688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16825308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibala MJ, Little JP, Macdonald MJ. Hawley JA. Physiological adaptations to low-volume, high-intensity interval training in health and disease. J. Physiol. 2012;590:1077&#x2013;1084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3381816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22289907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillen JB, Percival ME, Ludzki A, Tarnopolsky MA. Gibala MJ. Interval training in the fed or fasted state improves body composition and muscle oxidative capacity in overweight women. Obesity. 2013;21:2249&#x2013;2255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23723099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad F. Adams GR. Selected contribution: acute cellular and molecular responses to resistance exercise. J. Appl. Physiol. 2002;93:394&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12070230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hameed M, Orrell RW, Cobbold M, Goldspink G. Harridge SDR. Expression of IGF-I splice variants in young and old human skeletal muscle after high resistance exercise. J. Physiol. 2003;547:247&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2342624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12562960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harber M, Konopka A, Jemiolo B, Trappe S, Trappe T. Reidy P. Muscle protein synthesis and gene expression during recovery from aerobic exercise in the fasted and fed states. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 2010;299:R1254&#x2013;R1262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20720176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heydari M, Freund J. Boutcher SH. The effect of high-intensity intermittent exercise on body composition of overweight young males. J. Obes. 2012;480467&#x2013;74:2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22720138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickson RC. Interference of strength development by simultaneously training for strength and endurance. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 1980;263:255&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7193134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapp LD. Lorsch JR. The molecular mechanics of eukaryotic translation. Annu. Rev. Biochem. 2004;73:657&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15189156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, Pennings B, Zorenc AHG. van Loon LJC. Protein ingestion further augments S6K1 phosphorylation in skeletal muscle following resistance type exercise in males. J. Nutr. 2007;137:1880&#x2013;1886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17634259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer W, Adams K, Cafarelli E, Dudley G, Dooly C, Feigenbaum M, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2009;41:687&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe9;ger B, Cartoni R, Praz M, Lamon S, D&#xe9;riaz O, Crettenand A, et al. Akt signalling through GSK-3beta, mTOR and Foxo1 is involved in human skeletal muscle hypertrophy and atrophy. J. Physiol. 2006;576:923&#x2013;933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1890416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16916907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leveritt M, Abernethy PJ, Barry BK. Logan PA. Concurrent strength and endurance training. A review. Sports Med. 1999;28:413&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10623984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little JP, Safdar A, Wilkin GP, Tarnopolsky MA. Gibala MJ. A practical model of low-volume high-intensity interval training induces mitochondrial biogenesis in human skeletal muscle: potential mechanisms. J. Physiol. 2010;588:1011&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2849965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20100740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Miranda J, Williams C. Lairon D. Dietary, physiological, genetic and pathological influences on postprandial lipid metabolism. Br. J. Nutr. 2007;98:458&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17705891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis E, Raue U, Yang Y, Jemiolo B. Trappe S. Time course of proteolytic, cytokine, and myostatin gene expression after acute exercise in human skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. 2007;103:1744&#x2013;1751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17823296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg TR, Fernandez-Gonzalo R, Gustafsson T. Tesch PA. Aerobic exercise alters skeletal muscle molecular responses to resistance exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2012;44:1680&#x2013;1688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22460475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg TR, Fernandez-Gonzalo R, Gustafsson T. Tesch PA. Aerobic exercise does not compromise muscle hypertrophy response to short-term resistance training. J. Appl. Physiol. 2013;114:81&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23104700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg TR, Fernandez-Gonzalo R, Norrbom J, Fischer H, Tesch PA. Gustafsson T. Truncated splice variant PGC-1&#x3b1;4 is not associated with exercise-induced human muscle hypertrophy. Acta Physiol. 2014;212:142&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24800995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGee SL. Hargreaves M. AMPK-mediated regulation of transcription in skeletal muscle. Clin. Sci. 2010;118:507&#x2013;518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20088830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McPherron AC, Lawler AM. Lee SJ. Regulation of skeletal muscle mass in mice by a new TGF-beta superfamily member. Nature. 1997;387:83&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9139826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mifflin MD, St Jeor ST, Hill LA, Scott BJ, Daugherty SA. Koh YO. A new predictive equation for resting energy expenditure in healthy individuals. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 1990;51:241&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2305711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller SL, Tipton KD, Chinkes DL, Wolf SE. Wolfe RR. Independent and combined effects of amino acids and glucose after resistance exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2003;35:449&#x2013;455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12618575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nybo L, Sundstrup E, Jakobsen MD, Mohr M, Hornstrup T, Simonsen L, et al. High-intensity training versus traditional exercise interventions for promoting health. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2010;42:1951&#x2013;1958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20195181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olesen J, Kiilerich K. Pilegaard H. PGC-1alpha-mediated adaptations in skeletal muscle. Pflugers Arch. 2010;460:153&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20401754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry RL. Rudnick MA. Molecular mechanisms regulating myogenic determination and differentiation. Front Biosci. 2000;5:d750&#x2013;d767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10966875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella JK, Kim J, Cross JM, Kosek DJ. Bamman MM. Efficacy of myonuclear addition may explain differential myofiber growth among resistance-trained young and older men and women. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2006;291:E937&#x2013;E946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16772322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psilander N, Damsgaard R. Pilegaard H. Resistance exercise alters MRF and IGF-I mRNA content in human skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. 2003;95:1038&#x2013;1044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12716875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruas JL, White JP, Rao RR, Kleiner S, Brannan KT, Harrison BC, et al. A PGC-1&#x3b1; isoform induced by resistance training regulates skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Cell. 2012;151:1319&#x2013;1331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3520615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23217713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandri M, Sandri C, Gilbert A, Skurk C, Calabria E, Picard A, et al. Foxo transcription factors induce the atrophy-related ubiquitin ligase atrogin-1 and cause skeletal muscle atrophy. Cell. 2004;117:399&#x2013;412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3619734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15109499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandri M, Lin J, Handschin C, Yang W, Arany ZP, Lecker SH, et al. PGC-1alpha protects skeletal muscle from atrophy by suppressing FoxO3 action and atrophy-specific gene transcription. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA. 2006;103:16260&#x2013;16265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1637570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17053067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stutts WC. Physical activity determinants in adults. Perceived benefits, barriers, and self efficacy. AAOHN J. 2002;50:499&#x2013;507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12465206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadaishi M, Miura S, Kai Y, Kawasaki E, Koshinaka K, Kawanaka K, et al. Effect of exercise intensity and AICAR on isoform-specific expressions of murine skeletal muscle PGC-1&#x3b1; mRNA: a role of &#x3b2;&#x2082;-adrenergic receptor activation. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2011;300:E341&#x2013;E349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21098736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Ferrando AA, Phillips SM, Doyle D. Wolfe RR. Postexercise net protein synthesis in human muscle from orally administered amino acids. Am. J. Physiol. 1999;276:E628&#x2013;E634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10198297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trapp EG, Chisholm DJ, Freund J. Boutcher SH. The effects of high-intensity intermittent exercise training on fat loss and fasting insulin levels of young women. Int. J. Obes. 2008;32:684&#x2013;691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18197184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trost SG, Owen N, Bauman AE, Sallis JF. Brown W. Correlates of adults&#x2019; participation in physical activity: review and update. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2002;34:1996&#x2013;2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12471307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welle S, Burgess K. Mehta S. Stimulation of skeletal muscle myofibrillar protein synthesis, p70 S6 kinase phosphorylation, and ribosomal protein S6 phosphorylation by inhibition of myostatin in mature mice. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2009;296:E567&#x2013;E572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2660146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19141683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JJM, Marin PJP, Rhea MR, Wilson SMC, Loenneke JP. Anderson JC. Concurrent training: a meta-analysis examining interference of aerobic and resistance exercises. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2012;26:2293&#x2013;2307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22002517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Creer A, Jemiolo B. Trappe S. Time course of myogenic and metabolic gene expression in response to acute exercise in human skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. 2005;98:1745&#x2013;1752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15618316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanuso S, Jimenez A, Pugliese G, Corigliano G. Balducci S. Exercise for the management of type 2 diabetes: a review of the evidence. Acta Diabetol. 2010;47:15&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19495557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>