<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33178649</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2288-176X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of exercise rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exerc Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Concurrent training and Eri silkworm pupae ingestion improve resting and exercise fat oxidation and energy expenditure in obese adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>467</StartPage><EndPage>479</EndPage><MedlinePgn>467-479</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12965/jer.2040682.341</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A randomized control trial was conducted to investigate the effects of combined concurrent training and Eri silkworm pupae ingestion on resting and exercise fat oxidation (FAO), as well as energy expenditure, and cardiometabolic risk markers in obese adults. Thirty-six sedentary, obese participants were divided into three groups: (1) placebo control group (CON, n=12), (2) Eri silkworm pupae ingestion group (ERI, n=12), and (3) combined concurrent training and Eri silkworm pupae ingestion group (CBT-ERI, n=12). Participants in the ERI and the CBT-ERI con-sumed 5-g Eri silkworm pupae/day (approximately 2.5-g linolenic acid). The concurrent training program comprised of supervised aerobic and resistance training: three 1-hr sessions/wk for 8 weeks. Body composi-tion, energy expenditure, and FAO at rest and during exercise, heart rate variability, and blood chemistry were measured before and after the 8-week interventions. Following the interventions, resting FAO, the natural logarithm of very low-frequency power (lnVLF), and high-sensi-tive C-reactive protein concentration significantly improved in both the ERI and the CBT-ERI. Only the CBT-ERI improved resting energy expen-diture, FAO during exercise, trunk and gynoid fat mass, total cholesterol concentration, the standard deviation of normal R-R intervals (SDNN), and the percentage difference between adjacent normal R-R intervals &gt;50 ms. Furthermore, there were significant correlations between rest-ing energy expenditure and FAO, lnVLF and SDNN in the CBT-ERI. In conclusion, this study demonstrates that concurrent training together with dietary Eri silkworm pupae leads to increased energy expenditure through a significant increase in FAO at rest and during exercise, as well as reduced fat mass.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 Korean Society of Exercise Rehabilitation.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klomklorm</LastName><ForeName>Andaman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Health, Faculty of Sports Science, Kasetsart University, Nakhon Pathom, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ruangthai</LastName><ForeName>Ratree</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Health, Faculty of Sports Science, Kasetsart University, Nakhon Pathom, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vaithanomsat</LastName><ForeName>Pilanee</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kasetsart Agricultural and Agro-Industrial Product Improvement Institute, Kasetsart University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sukatta</LastName><ForeName>Udomlak</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kasetsart Agricultural and Agro-Industrial Product Improvement Institute, Kasetsart University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phoemsapthawee</LastName><ForeName>Jatuporn</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8859-3899</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Health, Faculty of Sports Science, Kasetsart University, Nakhon Pathom, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>J Exerc Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101615171</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2288-176X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Concurrent training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy expenditure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eri silkworm pupae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fat oxidation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Polyunsaturated fatty acid</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>CONFLICT OF INTEREST No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33178649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7609851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.2040682.341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jer-16-5-467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Albracht-Schulte K, Kalupahana NS, Ramalingam L, Wang S, Rahman SM, Robert-McComb J, Moustaid-Moussa N. Omega-3 fatty acids in obesity and metabolic syndrome: a mechanistic update. J Nutr Biochem. 2018;58:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7561009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29621669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartlett JD, Close GL, MacLaren DP, Gregson W, Drust B, Morton JP. High-intensity interval running is perceived to be more enjoyable than moderate-intensity continuous exercise: implications for exercise adherence. J Sports Sci. 2011;29:547&#x2013;553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21360405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaak EE, Saris WH. Substrate oxidation, obesity and exercise training. Best Pract Res Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2002;16:667&#x2013;678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12468414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buemann B, Astrup A, Christensen NJ. Three months aerobic training fails to affect 24-hour energy expenditure in weight-stable, post-obese women. Int J Obes. 1992;16:809&#x2013;816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1330960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. New York (NY): Routledge Academic; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Rocha EE, Alves VG, da Fonseca RB. Indirect calorimetry: methodology, instruments and clinical application. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2006;9:247&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16607124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLany JP, Windhauser MM, Champagne CM, Bray GA. Differential oxidation of individual dietary fatty acids in humans. Am J Clin Nutr. 2000;72:905&#x2013;911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11010930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher G, Hyatt TC, Hunter GR, Oster RA, Desmond RA, Gower BA. Effect of diet with and without exercise training on markers of inflammation and fat distribution in overweight women. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2011;19:1131&#x2013;1136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3102145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21183937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedewald WT, Levy RI, Fredrickson DS. Estimation of the concentration of low-density lipoprotein cholesterol in plasma, without use of the preparative ultracentrifuge. Clin Chem. 1972;18:499&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4337382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujibayashi M, Hamada T, Matsumoto T, Kiyohara N, Tanaka S, Kotani K, Egawa K, Kitagawa Y, Kiso Y, Sakane N, Moritani T. Thermoregulatory sympathetic nervous system activity and diet-induced waist-circumference reduction in obese Japanese women. Am J Hum Biol. 2009;21:828&#x2013;835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19384859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, Wang D, Xu ML, Shi SS, Xiong JF. Toxicological characteristics of edible insects in China: A historical review. Food Chem Toxicol. 2018;119:237&#x2013;251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29649491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibala MJ, Little JP, Macdonald MJ, Hawley JA. Physiological adaptations to low-volume, high-intensity interval training in health and disease. J Physiol. 2012;590:1077&#x2013;1084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3381816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22289907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodpaster BH, Katsiaras A, Kelley DE. Enhanced fat oxidation through physical activity is associated with improvements in insulin sensitivity in obesity. Diabetes. 2003;52:2191&#x2013;2197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12941756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones PJ, Jew S, AbuMweis S. The effect of dietary oleic, linoleic, and linolenic acids on fat oxidation and energy expenditure in healthy men. Metabolism. 2008;57:1198&#x2013;1203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18702944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang J, Ratamess N. Which comes first? Resistance before aerobic exercise or vice versa? ACSMs Health Fit J. 2014;18:9&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kien CL, Bunn JY, Ugrasbul F. Increasing dietary palmitic acid decreases fat oxidation and daily energy expenditure. Am J Clin Nutr. 2005;82:320&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1314972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16087974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Park J, Zhoh C, Hong S, Ryu K. The component analysis of male silkworm&#x2019;s extract. J Korean Soc Esthet Cosme. 2010;5:37&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk EP, Donnelly JE, Smith BK, Honas J, Lecheminant JD, Bailey BW, Jacobsen DJ, Washburn RA. Minimal resistance training improves daily energy expenditure and fat oxidation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:1122&#x2013;1129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2862249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19346974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kliewer SA, Sundseth SS, Jones SA, Brown PJ, Wisely GB, Koble CS, Devchand P, Wahli W, Willson TM, Lenhard JM, Lehmann JM. Fatty acids and eicosanoids regulate gene expression through direct interactions with peroxisome proliferator-activated receptors alpha and gamma. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1997;94:4318&#x2013;4323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC20720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9113987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan S, Cooper JA. Effect of dietary fatty acid composition on substrate utilization and body weight maintenance in humans. Eur J Nutr. 2014;53:691&#x2013;710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24363161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavie CJ, Milani RV, Ventura HO. Obesity and cardiovascular disease: risk factor, paradox, and impact of weight loss. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009;53:1925&#x2013;1932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19460605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longvah T, Manghtya K, Qadri SS. Eri silkworm: a source of edible oil with a high content of &#x3b1;-linolenic acid and of significant nutritional value. J Sci Food Agric. 2012;92:1988&#x2013;1993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22290445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews DR, Hosker JP, Rudenski AS, Naylor BA, Treacher DF, Turner RC. Homeostasis model assessment: insulin resistance and beta-cell function from fasting plasma glucose and insulin concentrations in man. Diabetologia. 1985;28:412&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3899825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messina G, Valenzano A, Moscatelli F, Salerno M, Lonigro A, Esposito T, Monda V, Corso G, Messina A, Viggiano A, Triggiani AI, Chieffi S, Guglielmi G, Monda M, Cibelli G. Role of autonomic nervous system and orexinergic system on adipose tissue. Front Physiol. 2017;8:137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5344930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28344558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millis RM, Austin RE, Hatcher MD, Bond V, Goring KL. Metabolic energy correlates of heart rate variability spectral power associated with a 900-calorie challenge. J Nutr Metab. 2011;2011:715361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3136225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21773025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagai N, Sakane N, Moritani T. Metabolic responses to high-fat or low-fat meals and association with sympathetic nervous system activity in healthy young men. J Nutr Sci Vitaminol (Tokyo) 2005;51:355&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16392707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicklas BJ, Rogus EM, Goldberg AP. Exercise blunts declines in lipolysis and fat oxidation after dietary-induced weight loss in obese older women. Am J Physiol. 1997;273(1Pt1):E149&#x2013;E155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega JF, Morales-Palomo F, Fernandez-Elias V, Hamouti N, Bernardo FJ, Martin-Doimeadios RC, Nelson RK, Horowitz JF, Mora-Rodriguez R. Dietary supplementation with omega-3 fatty acids and oleate enhances exercise training effects in patients with metabolic syndrome. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2016;24:1704&#x2013;1711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27356240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peronnet F, Massicotte D. Table of nonprotein respiratory quotient: an update. Can J Sport Sci. 1991;16:23&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1645211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piers LS, Walker KZ, Stoney RM, Soares MJ, O&#x2019;Dea K. The influence of the type of dietary fat on postprandial fat oxidation rates: monounsaturated (olive oil) vs saturated fat (cream) Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2002;26:814&#x2013;821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12037652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polley KR, Miller MK, Johnson M, Vaughan R, Paton CM, Cooper JA. Metabolic responses to high-fat diets rich in MUFA v. PUFA. Br J Nutr. 2018;120:13&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29936922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potteiger JA, Kirk EP, Jacobsen DJ, Donnelly JE. Changes in resting metabolic rate and substrate oxidation after 16 months of exercise training in overweight adults. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2008;18:79&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18272935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson MD, Jackson KG, Fielding BA, Morgan LM, Williams CM, Frayn KN. Acute ingestion of a meal rich in n-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids results in rapid gastric emptying in humans. Am J Clin Nutr. 2002;76:232&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12081840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenkilde M, Nordby P, Nielsen LB, Stallknecht BM, Helge JW. Fat oxidation at rest predicts peak fat oxidation during exercise and metabolic phenotype in overweight men. Int J Obes (Lond) 2010;34:871&#x2013;877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20157319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan D, Heaner M. Guidelines (2013) for managing overweight and obesity in adults. Preface to the full report. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2014;22(Suppl 2):S1&#x2013;S3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24961822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saini RK, Keum YS. Omega-3 and omega-6 polyunsaturated fatty acids: Dietary sources, metabolism, and significance - a review. Life Sci. 2018;203:255&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29715470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schrauwen P, van Aggel-Leijssen DP, Hul G, Wagenmakers AJM, Vidal H, Saris WHM, van Baak MA. The effect of a 3-month low-intensity endurance training program on fat oxidation and acetyl-CoA carboxylase-2 expression. Diabetes. 2002;51:2220&#x2013;2226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12086953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schutz Y, Tremblay A, Weinsier RL, Nelson KM. Role of fat oxidation in the long-term stabilization of body weight in obese women. Am J Clin Nutr. 1992;55:670&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1550042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwingshackl L, Dias S, Strasser B, Hoffmann G. Impact of different training modalities on anthropometric and metabolic characteristics in overweight/obese subjects: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2013;8:e82853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3866267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24358230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanker KS, Shireesha K, Kanjilal S, Kumar S, Srinivas C, Rao J, Prasad R. Isolation and characterization of neutral lipids of desilked eri silkworm pupae grown on castor and tapioca leaves. J Agric Food Chem. 2006;54:3305&#x2013;3309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16637689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal RJ, Alberga AS, Goldfield GS, Prud&#x2019;homme D, Hadjiyannakis S, Gougeon R, Phillips P, Tulloch H, Malcolm J, Doucette S, Wells GA, Ma J, Kenny GP. Effects of aerobic training, resistance training, or both on percentage body fat and cardiometabolic risk markers in obese adolescents: the healthy eating aerobic and resistance training in youth randomized clinical trial. JAMA Pediatr. 2014;168:1006&#x2013;1014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25243536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon TP, Sistrun SN, Krishnan RK, Del Aguila LF, Marchetti CM, O&#x2019;Carroll SM, O&#x2019;Leary VB, Kirwan JP. Exercise and diet enhance fat oxidation and reduce insulin resistance in older obese adults. J Appl Physiol. 2008;104:1313&#x2013;1319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3860368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18323464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson JL, Miller MK, Skillman HE, Paton CM, Cooper JA. A PUFA-rich diet improves fat oxidation following saturated fat-rich meal. Eur J Nutr. 2017;56:1845&#x2013;1857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27193583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tartibian B, Hajizadeh Maleki B, Kanaley J, Sadeghi K. Long-term aerobic exercise and omega-3 supplementation modulate osteoporosis through inflammatory mechanisms in post-menopausal women: a randomized, repeated measures study. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2011;8:71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3212907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21999620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villarroya F, Vidal-Puig A. Beyond the sympathetic tone: the new brown fat activators. Cell Metab. 2013;17:638&#x2013;643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23583169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weir JB. New methods for calculating metabolic rate with special reference to protein metabolism. J Physiol. 1949;109:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1392602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15394301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilmore JH, Despres JP, Stanforth PR, Mandel S, Rice T, Gagnon J, Leon AS, Rao D, Skinner JS, Bouchard C. Alterations in body weight and composition consequent to 20 wk of endurance training: the HERITAGE Family Study. Am J Clin Nutr. 1999;70:346&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10479196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeo WK, Carey AL, Burke L, Spriet LL, Hawley JA. Fat adaptation in well-trained athletes: effects on cell metabolism. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2011;36:12&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21326374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>