<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39794384</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-5497</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>49</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of obesity (2005)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Obes (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of time-restricted eating with exercise on body composition in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>755</StartPage><EndPage>765</EndPage><MedlinePgn>755-765</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41366-024-01704-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The effects of time-restricted eating (TRE) with exercise on body composition in adults are not clear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This meta-analysis aimed to assess the effects of TRE when followed in combination with various forms of exercise, including aerobic, resistance, and combined aerobic and resistance [concurrent] training on body composition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Studies published up to May 2023 were searched in EBSCOhost (MEDLINE, CINAHL, SPORTSDISCUS), PubMed, and SCOPUS databases. Fifteen studies, including 338 participants, that evaluated TRE vs. unrestricted eating in individuals performing exercise were analyzed. A random-effects model was used to calculate the weighted mean effect sizes (ES) with 95% confidence intervals (95% CI's).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">According to the pooled results, TRE had a small but significant reduction of fat mass (FM) kg with an effect size of -0.20 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.28 to -0.13, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) and on body fat percent (BF%) with an effect size of -0.23 (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.35 to -0.11, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). The prediction interval ranged from -0.48 to 0.08 for FM and from -0.64 to 0.18 for BF%, respectively. TRE did not significantly alter fat-free mass (FFM) kg compared to control (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.07). Furthermore, age, body mass index (BMI), exercise type, study duration, and energy intake did not have a significant impact on the variation in effect sizes according to the subgroup analyses (p&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">TRE with exercise may reduce fat mass compared to an unrestricted eating window exercise-matched control while preserving FFM. However, more studies are needed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hays</LastName><ForeName>Harry M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Hospitality Management, University of Mississippi, Oxford, MS, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sefidmooye Azar</LastName><ForeName>Pouria</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Hospitality Management, University of Mississippi, Oxford, MS, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Minsoo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Exercise Science and Recreation Management, University of Mississippi, Oxford, MS, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tinsley</LastName><ForeName>Grant M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0230-6586</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Sport Management, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wijayatunga</LastName><ForeName>Nadeeja N</ForeName><Initials>NN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7725-2420</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Hospitality Management, University of Mississippi, Oxford, MS, USA. nadeejaw@olemiss.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Obes (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101256108</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0307-0565</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: GMT is an inventor on the international patent &#x201c;Compositions and methods of use of beta-hydroxy beta-methylbutyrate (HMB) associated with intermittent fasting.&#x201d; The remaining authors do not report any conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39794384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12095083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41366-024-01704-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41366-024-01704-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Varady KA, Cienfuegos S, Ezpeleta M, Gabel K. Clinical application of intermittent fasting for weight loss: progress and future directions. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2022;18:309&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35194176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinsley GM, La Bounty PM. Effects of intermittent fasting on body composition and clinical health markers in humans. Nutr Rev. 2015;73:661&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26374764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda S. The arrival of circadian medicine. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2019;15:67&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30602736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon S, Kang J, Kim SH, Chung HS, Kim YJ, Yu JM, et al. Beneficial effects of time-restricted eating on metabolic diseases: a systemic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients. 2020;12:1267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7284632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32365676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner L, Charrouf R, Mart&#xed;nez-Vizca&#xed;no V, Hutchison A, Heilbronn LK, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Rodr&#xed;guez R. The effects of time-restricted eating versus habitual diet on inflammatory cytokines and adipokines in the general adult population: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2024;119:206&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37865184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellegrini M, Cioffi I, Evangelista A, Ponzo V, Goitre I, Ciccone G, et al. Effects of time-restricted feeding on body weight and metabolism. A systematic review and meta-analysis. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2020;21:17&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31808043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betts JA, Richardson JD, Chowdhury EA, Holman GD, Tsintzas K, Thompson D. The causal role of breakfast in energy balance and health: a randomized controlled trial in lean adults. Am J Clin Nutr. 2014;100:539&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4095658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24898233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correia JM, Santos I, Pezarat-Correia P, Minderico C, Schoenfeld BJ, Mendonca GV. Effects of time-restricted feeding on supramaximal exercise performance and body composition: a randomized and counterbalanced crossover study in healthy men. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:7227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8303210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34299702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correia JM, Santos PDG, Pezarat-Correia P, Minderico CS, Infante J, Mendonca GV. Effect of time-restricted eating and resistance training on high-speed strength and body composition. Nutrients. 2023;15:285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9863948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36678156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowe DA, Wu N, Rohdin-Bibby L, Moore AH, Kelly N, Liu YE, et al. Effects of time-restricted eating on weight loss and other metabolic parameters in women and men with overweight and obesity: the TREAT randomized clinical trial. JAMA Intern Med. 2020;180:1491&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7522780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32986097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moro T, Tinsley G, Pacelli FQ, Marcolin G, Bianco A, Paoli A. Twelve months of time-restricted eating and resistance training improves inflammatory markers and cardiometabolic risk factors. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53:2577&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10115489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34649266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moro T, Tinsley G, Bianco A, Marcolin G, Pacelli QF, Battaglia G, et al. Effects of eight weeks of time-restricted feeding (16/8) on basal metabolism, maximal strength, body composition, inflammation, and cardiovascular risk factors in resistance-trained males. J Transl Med. 2016;14:290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5064803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27737674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark JE. Diet, exercise or diet with exercise: comparing the effectiveness of treatment options for weight-loss and changes in fitness for adults (18&#x2013;65 years old) who are overfat, or obese; systematic review and meta-analysis. J Diabetes Metab Disord. 2015;14:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4429709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25973403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger M, Hagg S, Ruderman NB. Glucose metabolism in perfused skeletal muscle. Interaction of insulin and exercise on glucose uptake. Biochem J. 1975;146:231&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1165292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">807202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaix A, Manoogian ENC, Melkani GC, Panda S. Time-restricted eating to prevent and manage chronic metabolic diseases. Annu Rev Nutr. 2019;39:291&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6703924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31180809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berggren JR, Boyle KE, Chapman WH, Houmard JA. Skeletal muscle lipid oxidation and obesity: influence of weight loss and exercise. Am J Physiol-Endocrinol Metab. 2008;294:E726&#x2013;E32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18252891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adafer R, Messaadi W, Meddahi M, Patey A, Haderbache A, Bayen S, et al. Food timing, circadian rhythm and chrononutrition: a systematic review of time-restricted eating&#x2019;s effects on human health. Nutrients. 2020;12:3770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7763532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33302500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashtary-Larky D, Bagheri R, Tinsley GM, Asbaghi O, Paoli A, Moro T. Effects of intermittent fasting combined with resistance training on body composition: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Physiol Behav. 2021;237:113453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33984329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. BMJ. 2009;339:b2535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2714657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipsey MW, Wilson DB. Practical meta-analysis: SAGE publications, Inc; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson DB, Practical meta-analysis effect size calculator [Available from: https://www.campbellcollaboration.org/research-resources/effect-size-calculator.html.]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral. Sciences Hillsdale (NJ): Lawrence Erlbaum Associates. 1988:18&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLester CN, Nickerson BS, Kliszczewicz BM, McLester JR. Reliability and agreement of various inbody body composition analyzers as compared to dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry in healthy men and women. J Clin Densitom. 2020;23:443&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30472111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira OC, Oliveira CEP, De Paz JA. Dual energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) reliability and intraobserver reproducibility for segmental body composition measuring. Nutr Hosp. 2018;35:340&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29756967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaquero-Crist&#xf3;bal R, Albaladejo-Saura M, Luna-Badachi AE, Esparza-Ros F. Differences in fat mass estimation formulas in physically active adult population and relationship with sums of skinfolds. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:7777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7660690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33114260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee RC, Wang Z, Heo M, Ross R, Janssen I, Heymsfield SB. Total-body skeletal muscle mass: development and cross-validation of anthropometric prediction models. Am J Clin Nutr. 2000;72:796&#x2013;803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10966902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA Editor(s). Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Version 6.3.(updated February 2022). Cochrane, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israel H, Richter RR. A guide to understanding meta-analysis. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2011;41:496&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21725192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval S, Tweedie R. Trim and fill: a simple funnel-plot-based method of testing and adjusting for publication bias in meta-analysis. Biometrics. 2000;56:455&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, J&#xfc;ni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, et al. The Cochrane Collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d5928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady AJ, Langton HM, Mulligan M, Egan B. Effects of 8 wk of 16:8 time-restricted eating in male middle- and long-distance runners. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53:633&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32796255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haganes KL, Silva CP, Eyj&#xf3;lfsd&#xf3;ttir SK, Steen S, Grindberg M, Lydersen S, et al. Time-restricted eating and exercise training improve HbA1c and body composition in women with overweight/obesity: a randomized controlled trial. Cell Metab. 2022;34:1457&#x2013;71.e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36198292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isenmann E, Dissemond J, Geisler S. The effects of a macronutrient-based diet and time-restricted feeding (16:8) on body composition in physically active individuals-A 14-week randomised controlled trial. Nutrients. 2021;13:3122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8465090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34578999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotarsky CJ, Johnson NR, Mahoney SJ, Mitchell SL, Schimek RL, Stastny SN, et al. Time&#x2010;restricted eating and concurrent exercise training reduces fat mass and increases lean mass in overweight and obese adults. Physiol Rep. 2021;9:e14868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8157764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34042299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Rodr&#xed;guez A, Rubio-Arias JA, Garc&#xed;a-De Frutos JM, Vicente-Mart&#xed;nez M, Gunnarsson TP. Effect of high-intensity interval training and intermittent fasting on body composition and physical performance in active women. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:6431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8296247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34198554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moro T, Tinsley G, Longo G, Grigoletto D, Bianco A, Ferraris C, et al. Time-restricted eating effects on performance, immune function, and body composition in elite cyclists: a randomized controlled trial. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2020;17:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7733258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33308259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro DE, Santiago AF, Abreu WCD. Continuous energy restriction (CER) plus 16/8 time-restricted feeding improve body composition and metabolic parameters in overweight and obese, but no more than CER alone. Nutr Healthy Aging. 2021;6:147&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson CE, Tovar AP, Davis BA, Van Loan MD, Keim NL, Casazza GA. An intervention of four weeks of time-restricted eating (16/8) in male long-distance runners does not affect cardiometabolic risk factors. Nutrients. 2023;15:985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9961388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36839342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stratton MT, Tinsley GM, Alesi MG, Hester GM, Olmos AA, Serafini PR, et al. Four weeks of time-restricted feeding combined with resistance training does not differentially influence measures of body composition, muscle performance, resting energy expenditure, and blood biomarkers. Nutrients. 2020;12:1126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7231047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32316561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinsley GM, Forsse JS, Butler NK, Paoli A, Bane AA, La Bounty PM, et al. Time-restricted feeding in young men performing resistance training: a randomized controlled trial. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17:200&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27550719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinsley GM, Moore ML, Graybeal AJ, Paoli A, Kim Y, Gonzales JU, et al. Time-restricted feeding plus resistance training in active females: a randomized trial. Am J Clin Nutr. 2019;110:628&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6735806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31268131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tovar AP, Richardson CE, Keim NL, Van Loan MD, Davis BA, Casazza GA. Four weeks of 16/8 time restrictive feeding in endurance trained male runners decreases fat mass, without affecting exercise performance. Nutrients. 2021;13:2941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8469445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34578819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothschild J, Hoddy KK, Jambazian P, Varady KA. Time-restricted feeding and risk of metabolic disease: a review of human and animal studies. Nutr Rev. 2014;72:308&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24739093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabel K, Hoddy KK, Haggerty N, Song J, Kroeger CM, Trepanowski JF, et al. Effects of 8-hour time restricted feeding on body weight and metabolic disease risk factors in obese adults: a pilot study. Nutr Healthy Aging. 2018;4:345&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6004924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29951594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill S, Panda S. A smartphone app reveals erratic diurnal eating patterns in humans that can be modulated for health benefits. Cell Metab. 2015;22:789&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4635036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26411343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang J, Ratamess NA, Faigenbaum AD, Bush JA, Beller N, Vargas A, et al. Effect of time-restricted feeding on anthropometric, metabolic, and fitness parameters: a systematic review. J. Am. Nutr. Assoc. 2021;41:810&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34491139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Tinsley G, Bianco A, Moro T. The influence of meal frequency and timing on health in humans: the role of fasting. Nutrients. 2019;11:719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6520689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30925707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voigt RM, Forsyth CB, Keshavarzian A. Circadian rhythms: a regulator of gastrointestinal health and dysfunction. Expert Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;13:411&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6533073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30874451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brum MCB, Filho FFD, Schnorr CC, Bottega GB, Rodrigues TC. Shift work and its association with metabolic disorders. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2015;7:45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4436793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25991926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng W-J, Liu C-S, Hu K-C, Cheng Y-F, Karhula K, H&#xe4;rm&#xe4; M. Night shift work and the risk of metabolic syndrome: findings from an 8-year hospital cohort. PLoS ONE. 2021;16:e0261349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8668137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34898652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulli G, Manoogian ENC, Taub PR, Panda S. Training the circadian clock, clocking the drugs, and drugging the clock to prevent, manage, and treat chronic diseases. Trends Pharm Sci. 2018;39:812&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7249726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30060890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasumoto Y, Hashimoto C, Nakao R, Yamazaki H, Hiroyama H, Nemoto T, et al. Short-term feeding at the wrong time is sufficient to desynchronize peripheral clocks and induce obesity with hyperphagia, physical inactivity and metabolic disorders in mice. Metabolism. 2016;65:714&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27085778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Grimaldi K, D&#x2019;Agostino D, Cenci L, Moro T, Bianco A, et al. Ketogenic diet does not affect strength performance in elite artistic gymnasts. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012;9:34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3411406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22835211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Q, Ash C, Mracek T, Merry B, Bing C. Caloric restriction increases adiponectin expression by adipose tissue and prevents the inhibitory effect of insulin on circulating adiponectin in rats. J Nutr Biochem. 2012;23:867&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21852089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gahete MD, C&#xf3;rdoba-Chac&#xf3;n J, Lin Q, Br&#xfc;ning JC, Kahn CR, Casta&#xf1;o JP, et al. Insulin and IGF-I Inhibit GH synthesis and release in vitro and in vivo by separate mechanisms. Endocrinology. 2013;154:2410&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3689283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23671263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrows TL, Ho YY, Rollo ME, Collins CE. Validity of dietary assessment methods when compared to the method of doubly labeled water: a systematic review in adults. Front Endocrinol. 2019;10:850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6928130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31920966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Candow DG, Forbes SC, Ormsbee MJ, Saracino PG, Roberts J. Effects of dietary protein on body composition in exercising individuals. Nutrients. 2020;12:1890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7353221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32630466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>