<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37066356</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2692-8205</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>bioRxiv : the preprint server for biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>bioRxiv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resistance Training Diminishes Mitochondrial Adaptations to Subsequent Endurance Training.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2023.04.06.535919</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1101/2023.04.06.535919</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">We investigated the effects of performing a period of resistance training (RT) on the performance and molecular adaptations to a subsequent period of endurance training (ET). Twenty-five young adults were divided into RT+ET (n=13), which underwent seven weeks of RT followed by seven weeks of ET, and ET-only (n=12), which performed seven weeks of ET. Body composition, endurance performance, and muscle biopsies were collected before RT (T1, baseline for RT+ET), before ET (T2, post RT for RT+ET and baseline for ET), and after ET (T3). Immunohistochemistry was performed to determine fiber cross-sectional area (fCSA), myonuclear content, myonuclear domain size, satellite cell number, and mitochondrial content. Western blots were used to quantify markers of mitochondrial remodeling. Citrate synthase activity and markers of ribosome content were also investigated. Resistance training improved body composition and strength, increased vastus lateralis thickness, mixed and type II fCSA, myonuclear number, markers of ribosome content, and satellite cell content (p&lt;0.050). In response to ET, both groups similarly decreased body fat percentage and improved endurance performance (e.g., VO <sub>2</sub> max, and speed at which the onset of blood lactate accumulation occurred during the VO <sub>2</sub> max test). Levels of mitochondrial complexes I-IV in the ET-only group increased 32-66%, while the RT+ET group increased 1-11%. Additionally, mixed fiber relative mitochondrial content increased 15% in the ET-only group but decreased 13% in the RT+ET group. In conclusion, RT performed prior to ET had no additional benefits to ET adaptations. Moreover, prior RT seemed to impair mitochondrial adaptations to ET.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="KEY POINTS SUMMARY" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Resistance training is largely underappreciated as a method to improve endurance performance, despite reports showing it may improve mitochondrial function.Although several concurrent training studies are available, in this study we investigated the effects of performing a period resistance training on the performance and molecular adaptations to subsequent endurance training.Prior resistance training did not improve endurance performance and impaired most mitochondrial adaptations to subsequent endurance training, but that seemed to be a result of detraining from resistance training.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mesquita</LastName><ForeName>Paulo H C</ForeName><Initials>PHC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Godwin</LastName><ForeName>Joshua S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ruple</LastName><ForeName>Bradley A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sexton</LastName><ForeName>Casey L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McIntosh</LastName><ForeName>Mason C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mueller</LastName><ForeName>Breanna J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Osburn</LastName><ForeName>Shelby C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mobley</LastName><ForeName>C Brooks</ForeName><Initials>CB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Libardi</LastName><ForeName>Cleiton A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos, S&#xe3;o Carlos, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Young</LastName><ForeName>Kaelin C</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Sciences, Pacific Northwest University of Health Sciences, Yakima, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gladden</LastName><ForeName>L Bruce</ForeName><Initials>LB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Michael D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Edward Via College of Osteopathic Medicine, Auburn, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kavazis</LastName><ForeName>Andreas N</ForeName><Initials>AN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>T32 GM141739</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>bioRxiv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101680187</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2692-8205</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateIn"><RefSource>J Physiol. 2023 Sep;601(17):3825-3846. doi: 10.1113/JP284822.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">37470322</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><CoiStatement>None of the authors have financial or other conflicts of interest to report regarding these data.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37066356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10104141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2023.04.06.535919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2023.04.06.535919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bassett D. R. Jr., and Howley E. T. (2000) Limiting factors for maximum oxygen uptake and determinants of endurance performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 32, 70&#x2013;84</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10647532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyner M. J., and Coyle E. F. (2008) Endurance exercise performance: the physiology of champions. J Physiol 586, 35&#x2013;44</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17901124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs R. A., Rasmussen P., Siebenmann C., Diaz V., Gassmann M., Pesta D., Gnaiger E., Nordsborg N. B., Robach P., and Lundby C. (2011) Determinants of time trial performance and maximal incremental exercise in highly trained endurance athletes. J Appl Physiol (1985) 111, 1422&#x2013;1430</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21885805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgomaster K. A., Howarth K. R., Phillips S. M., Rakobowchuk M., Macdonald M. J., McGee S. L., and Gibala M. J. (2008) Similar metabolic adaptations during exercise after low volume sprint interval and traditional endurance training in humans. J Physiol 586, 151&#x2013;160</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17991697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacInnis M. J., and Gibala M. J. (2017) Physiological adaptations to interval training and the role of exercise intensity. J Physiol 595, 2915&#x2013;2930</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27748956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daussin F. N., Zoll J., Dufour S. P., Ponsot E., Lonsdorfer-Wolf E., Doutreleau S., Mettauer B., Piquard F., Geny B., and Richard R. (2008) Effect of interval versus continuous training on cardiorespiratory and mitochondrial functions: relationship to aerobic performance improvements in sedentary subjects. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 295, R264&#x2013;272</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18417645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beattie K., Kenny I. C., Lyons M., and Carson B. P. (2014) The effect of strength training on performance in endurance athletes. Sports Med 44, 845&#x2013;865</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24532151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paavolainen L., Hakkinen K., Hamalainen I., Nummela A., and Rusko H. (1999) Explosive-strength training improves 5-km running time by improving running economy and muscle power. J Appl Physiol (1985) 86, 1527&#x2013;1533</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10233114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsalobre-Fernandez C., Santos-Concejero J., and Grivas G. V. (2016) Effects of Strength Training on Running Economy in Highly Trained Runners: A Systematic Review With Meta-Analysis of Controlled Trials. J Strength Cond Res 30, 2361&#x2013;2368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26694507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blagrove R. C., Howatson G., and Hayes P. R. (2018) Effects of Strength Training on the Physiological Determinants of Middle- and Long-Distance Running Performance: A Systematic Review. Sports Med 48, 1117&#x2013;1149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5889786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29249083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groennebaek T., Jespersen N. R., Jakobsgaard J. E., Sieljacks P., Wang J., Rindom E., Musci R. V., Botker H. E., Hamilton K. L., Miller B. F., de Paoli F. V., and Vissing K. (2018) Skeletal Muscle Mitochondrial Protein Synthesis and Respiration Increase With Low-Load Blood Flow Restricted as Well as High-Load Resistance Training. Front Physiol 9, 1796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6304675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30618808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim C., Kim H. J., Morton R. W., Harris R., Phillips S. M., Jeong T. S., and Kim C. K. (2019) Resistance Exercise-induced Changes in Muscle Phenotype Are Load Dependent. Med Sci Sports Exerc 51, 2578&#x2013;2585</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31306302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesquita P. H. C., Lamb D. A., Parry H. A., Moore J. H., Smith M. A., Vann C. G., Osburn S. C., Fox C. D., Ruple B. A., Huggins K. W., Fruge A. D., Young K. C., Kavazis A. N., and Roberts M. D. (2020) Acute and chronic effects of resistance training on skeletal muscle markers of mitochondrial remodeling in older adults. Physiol Rep 8, e14526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7399374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32748504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruple B. A., Godwin J. S., Mesquita P. H. C., Osburn S. C., Sexton C. L., Smith M. A., Ogletree J. C., Goodlett M. D., Edison J. L., Ferrando A. A., Fruge A. D., Kavazis A. N., Young K. C., and Roberts M. D. (2021) Myofibril and Mitochondrial Area Changes in Type I and II Fibers Following 10 Weeks of Resistance Training in Previously Untrained Men. Front Physiol 12, 728683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8497692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34630147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H., Kim K., Kim B., Shin J., Rajan S., Wu J., Chen X., Brown M. D., Lee S., and Park J. Y. (2018) A cellular mechanism of muscle memory facilitates mitochondrial remodelling following resistance training. J Physiol 596, 4413&#x2013;4426</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6138296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30099751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas A. C. Q., Brown A., Hatt A. A., Manta K., Costa-Parke A., Kamal M., Joanisse S., McGlory C., Phillips S. M., Kumbhare D., and Parise G. (2022) Short-term aerobic conditioning prior to resistance training augments muscle hypertrophy and satellite cell content in healthy young men and women. FASEB J 36, e22500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35971745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. A. (1982) Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Med Sci Sports Exerc 14, 377&#x2013;381</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7154893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruple B. A., Mesquita P. H. C., Godwin J. S., Sexton C. L., Osburn S. C., McIntosh M. C., Kavazis A. N., Libardi C. A., Young K. C., and Roberts M. D. (2022) Changes in vastus lateralis fibre cross-sectional area, pennation angle and fascicle length do not predict changes in muscle cross-sectional area. Exp Physiol 107, 1216&#x2013;1224</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9633374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36053170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruple B. A., Smith M. A., Osburn S. C., Sexton C. L., Godwin J. S., Edison J. L., Poole C. N., Stock M. S., Fruge A. D., Young K. C., and Roberts M. D. (2022) Comparisons between skeletal muscle imaging techniques and histology in tracking midthigh hypertrophic adaptations following 10 wk of resistance training. J Appl Physiol (1985) 133, 416&#x2013;425</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35771220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zourdos M. C., Klemp A., Dolan C., Quiles J. M., Schau K. A., Jo E., Helms E., Esgro B., Duncan S., Garcia Merino S., and Blanco R. (2016) Novel Resistance Training-Specific Rating of Perceived Exertion Scale Measuring Repetitions in Reserve. J Strength Cond Res 30, 267&#x2013;275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26049792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibala M. J. (2021) Physiological basis of interval training for performance enhancement. Exp Physiol 106, 2324&#x2013;2327</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32362039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinazzi M., Casarin A., Pertegato V., Salviati L., and Angelini C. (2012) Assessment of mitochondrial respiratory chain enzymatic activities on tissues and cultured cells. Nat Protoc 7, 1235&#x2013;1246</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22653162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trounce I. A., Kim Y. L., Jun A. S., and Wallace D. C. (1996) Assessment of mitochondrial oxidative phosphorylation in patient muscle biopsies, lymphoblasts, and transmitochondrial cell lines. Methods Enzymol 264, 484&#x2013;509</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8965721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen Y., Murach K. A., Vechetti I. J. Jr., Fry C. S., Vickery C., Peterson C. A., McCarthy J. J., and Campbell K. S. (2018) MyoVision: software for automated high-content analysis of skeletal muscle immunohistochemistry. J Appl Physiol (1985) 124, 40&#x2013;51</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6048460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28982947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moro T., Brightwell C. R., Volpi E., Rasmussen B. B., and Fry C. S. (2020) Resistance exercise training promotes fiber type-specific myonuclear adaptations in older adults. J Appl Physiol (1985) 128, 795&#x2013;804</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7191507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32134710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillen J. B., and Gibala M. J. (2014) Is high-intensity interval training a time-efficient exercise strategy to improve health and fitness? Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 39, 409&#x2013;412</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24552392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milanovic Z., Sporis G., and Weston M. (2015) Effectiveness of High-Intensity Interval Training (HIT) and Continuous Endurance Training for VO2max Improvements: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Controlled Trials. Sports Med 45, 1469&#x2013;1481</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26243014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang J. E., Hartman J. W., and Phillips S. M. (2006) Increased muscle oxidative potential following resistance training induced fibre hypertrophy in young men. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 31, 495&#x2013;501</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17111003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson M. M., Dasari S., Konopka A. R., Johnson M. L., Manjunatha S., Esponda R. R., Carter R. E., Lanza I. R., and Nair K. S. (2017) Enhanced Protein Translation Underlies Improved Metabolic and Physical Adaptations to Different Exercise Training Modes in Young and Old Humans. Cell Metab 25, 581&#x2013;592</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5423095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28273480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb D. A., Moore J. H., Mesquita P. H. C., Smith M. A., Vann C. G., Osburn S. C., Fox C. D., Lopez H. L., Ziegenfuss T. N., Huggins K. W., Goodlett M. D., Fruge A. D., Kavazis A. N., Young K. C., and Roberts M. D. (2020) Resistance training increases muscle NAD(+) and NADH concentrations as well as NAMPT protein levels and global sirtuin activity in middle-aged, overweight, untrained individuals. Aging (Albany NY) 12, 9447&#x2013;9460</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7288928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32369778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruple B. A., Godwin J. S., Mesquita P. H. C., Osburn S. C., Vann C. G., Lamb D. A., Sexton C. L., Candow D. G., Forbes S. C., Fruge A. D., Kavazis A. N., Young K. C., Seaborne R. A., Sharples A. P., and Roberts M. D. (2021) Resistance training rejuvenates the mitochondrial methylome in aged human skeletal muscle. FASEB J 35, e21864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34423880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy J. J., Dupont-Versteegden E. E., Fry C. S., Murach K. A., and Peterson C. A. (2017) Methodological issues limit interpretation of negative effects of satellite cell depletion on adult muscle hypertrophy. Development 144, 1363&#x2013;1365</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28400431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murach K. A., Fry C. S., Dupont-Versteegden E. E., McCarthy J. J., and Peterson C. A. (2021) Fusion and beyond: Satellite cell contributions to loading-induced skeletal muscle adaptation. FASEB J 35, e21893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9293230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34480776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobley C. B., Haun C. T., Roberson P. A., Mumford P. W., Romero M. A., Kephart W. C., Anderson R. G., Vann C. G., Osburn S. C., Pledge C. D., Martin J. S., Young K. C., Goodlett M. D., Pascoe D. D., Lockwood C. M., and Roberts M. D. (2017) Effects of Whey, Soy or Leucine Supplementation with 12 Weeks of Resistance Training on Strength, Body Composition, and Skeletal Muscle and Adipose Tissue Histological Attributes in College-Aged Males. Nutrients 9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5622732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28869573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella J. K., Kim J. S., Cross J. M., Kosek D. J., and Bamman M. M. (2006) Efficacy of myonuclear addition may explain differential myofiber growth among resistance-trained young and older men and women. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 291, E937&#x2013;946</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16772322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murach K. A., Fry C. S., Kirby T. J., Jackson J. R., Lee J. D., White S. H., Dupont-Versteegden E. E., McCarthy J. J., and Peterson C. A. (2018) Starring or Supporting Role? Satellite Cells and Skeletal Muscle Fiber Size Regulation. Physiology (Bethesda) 33, 26&#x2013;38</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5866409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29212890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joanisse S., Gillen J. B., Bellamy L. M., McKay B. R., Tarnopolsky M. A., Gibala M. J., and Parise G. (2013) Evidence for the contribution of muscle stem cells to nonhypertrophic skeletal muscle remodeling in humans. FASEB J 27, 4596&#x2013;4605</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3804745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23928822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joanisse S., McKay B. R., Nederveen J. P., Scribbans T. D., Gurd B. J., Gillen J. B., Gibala M. J., Tarnopolsky M., and Parise G. (2015) Satellite cell activity, without expansion, after nonhypertrophic stimuli. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 309, R1101&#x2013;1111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4666950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26333785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesquita P. H. C., Vann C. G., Phillips S. M., McKendry J., Young K. C., Kavazis A. N., and Roberts M. D. (2021) Skeletal Muscle Ribosome and Mitochondrial Biogenesis in Response to Different Exercise Training Modalities. Front Physiol 12, 725866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8504538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34646153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey V. G., and Hawley J. A. (2017) Concurrent exercise training: do opposites distract? J Physiol 595, 2883&#x2013;2896</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27506998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammarstrom D., Ofsteng S. J., Jacobsen N. B., Flobergseter K. B., Ronnestad B. R., and Ellefsen S. (2022) Ribosome accumulation during early phase resistance training in humans. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 235, e13806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9540306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35213791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo V. C., D&#x2019;Souza R. F., Van Pelt D. W., Lawrence M. M., Zeng N., Markworth J. F., Poppitt S. D., Miller B. F., Mitchell C. J., McCarthy J. J., Dupont-Versteegden E. E., and Cameron-Smith D. (2021) Ribosome biogenesis and degradation regulate translational capacity during muscle disuse and reloading. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 12, 130&#x2013;143</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7890271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33231914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero M. A., Mobley C. B., Linden M. A., Meers G. M., Martin J. S., Young K. C., Rector R. S., and Roberts M. D. (2017) Endurance training lowers ribosome density despite increasing ribosome biogenesis markers in rodent skeletal muscle. BMC Res Notes 10, 399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5553677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28800772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe J. J., Bishop D. J., Bartlett J. D., Hanson E. D., Anderson M. J., Garnham A. P., and Stepto N. K. (2018) Enhanced skeletal muscle ribosome biogenesis, yet attenuated mTORC1 and ribosome biogenesis-related signalling, following short-term concurrent versus single-mode resistance training. Sci Rep 8, 560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5766515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29330460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granata C., Jamnick N. A., and Bishop D. J. (2018) Training-Induced Changes in Mitochondrial Content and Respiratory Function in Human Skeletal Muscle. Sports Med 48, 1809&#x2013;1828</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29934848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs R. A., Fluck D., Bonne T. C., Burgi S., Christensen P. M., Toigo M., and Lundby C. (2013) Improvements in exercise performance with high-intensity interval training coincide with an increase in skeletal muscle mitochondrial content and function. J Appl Physiol (1985) 115, 785&#x2013;793</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23788574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan M. T., and Hoogenraad N. J. (2007) Mitochondrial-nuclear communications. Annu Rev Biochem 76, 701&#x2013;722</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17227225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S. M., Tipton K. D., Aarsland A., Wolf S. E., and Wolfe R. R. (1997) Mixed muscle protein synthesis and breakdown after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol 273, E99&#x2013;107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V., Atherton P., Smith K., and Rennie M. J. (2009) Human muscle protein synthesis and breakdown during and after exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 106, 2026&#x2013;2039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19164770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reidy P. T., Borack M. S., Markofski M. M., Dickinson J. M., Fry C. S., Deer R. R., Volpi E., and Rasmussen B. B. (2017) Post-absorptive muscle protein turnover affects resistance training hypertrophy. Eur J Appl Physiol 117, 853&#x2013;866</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5389914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28280974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carraro F., Stuart C. A., Hartl W. H., Rosenblatt J., and Wolfe R. R. (1990) Effect of exercise and recovery on muscle protein synthesis in human subjects. Am J Physiol 259, E470&#x2013;476</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2221048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson S. B., Phillips S. M., Atherton P. J., Patel R., Yarasheski K. E., Tarnopolsky M. A., and Rennie M. J. (2008) Differential effects of resistance and endurance exercise in the fed state on signalling molecule phosphorylation and protein synthesis in human muscle. J Physiol 586, 3701&#x2013;3717</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2538832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18556367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanetti R. J., Lamon S., Wallace M., Vendelbo M. H., Russell A. P., and Vissing K. (2015) Regulation of ubiquitin proteasome pathway molecular markers in response to endurance and resistance exercise and training. Pflugers Arch 467, 1523&#x2013;1537</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25104573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos S. M., and Carbone J. W. (2014) Assessment of skeletal muscle proteolysis and the regulatory response to nutrition and exercise. IUBMB Life 66, 478&#x2013;484</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25052691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>